Another property that is very important when it comes to CSS grid is justify.
Items.
And justify items.
And the default is right now stretch.
So that if I refresh this, nothing's going to change.
But if I do start.
And refresh it aligns the contents in a grid item along what we call the row axis.
So the row axis is each row.
If I do end and I refresh.
We see that there now towards the end.
But a better way to visualize this is to actually use our developer tools.
So if I go to view developer developer tools and we select our grid.
You see that by clicking on this pointing icon and hovering over it?
In Google Chrome, we actually see our grid system.
And if I scroll, you see that it actually stays in place.
But you see that we now have our items at the end of our grid system.
Our last item, which is to fr right over here, is justified to the end.
Our second column.
Is justified to the end.
And we see a bit of a gap here.
And that is because remember we have one FR and then the first item because it's auto and the size is
according to its content doesn't really move.
Whether we have end or start here.
It's already within the maxed space of the grid system and just like we have the axis around the row,
if I change this to align items.
And I save and refresh.
This one's hard to see.
So let's just do five or 300 pixels and refresh here.
We see that a line item is the exact opposite, where it's around a column axis.
And we can use start and here to move those grid boxes around.
But most of the time we want this filled and we don't want to move items around.
So I don't really like using those two properties.
So let's fix that to one far.
If I refresh.
All right, we have things back to normal.
I'm going to close this.
Now, the last thing I want to show you inside of this container is my preferred method of actually
creating a grid layout in any website that I built.
And what I usually like to do is something new that we haven't seen before.
I usually do repeat and define here how many rows I want.
Let's say I want three at one FR.
So I want everything to have the same size.
But there's a problem here, right?
Because right now this is stretching.
But as soon as we make it too small or too big, it's just it's not extremely responsive or it's not
100% responsive.
So instead, I like using auto fill.
And then autofill just to show you what it does.
If I do something like 300 pixels and I refresh.
And now I change the sizing.
You'll see that our grid system or the column system adjusts auto fills according to the size of our
viewport, which is really, really nice.
But right now I just said 300 pixels.
So again, it's not super, super responsive.
So instead we can use something else called the min max.
And I know this can look confusing, but if you remember this pattern, this is the most common pattern
I would say to use when it comes to CSS grid.
So once you get used to this, you can just copy and paste it and use it everywhere.
And here what we want to do is say, well, the minimum that we want, the size of our columns to be,
let's say I want the minimum to be 200 pixels.
So that's the smallest that's going to get the max, though.
How big do we want these to get?
And this is a common thing.
What do we want as the biggest?
Well, just one fr because as we will see by doing this, it'll automatically adjust to the size of
the viewport.
Let me just save and show you what I mean by refresh here.
I see.
I have three here at auto adjusts.
Auto adjusts based on our size.
But you also see that the container itself is also adjusting in size so that if I go smaller and smaller
and smaller.
Look at that.
As soon as we hit the 200 pixel minimum.
It adjusts and because we said one hour as the max.
As soon as the viewport is really, really small and goes below 200 pixels.
It's going to just take up one fraction.
And in our case, it will be the entire screen.
So using this syntax of repeat autofill min max giving it a minimum, we're able to make this completely
responsive.
And as you can see here, it's pretty powerful, right?
In just a few lines of code.
We've made this grid system that is completely responsive.
All right.
Up to this point, we've just focused on the container.
But what about the individual items?
What if we want something that's maybe bigger than the other item and we don't want them all symmetrical
like this?
What would we do?
Let's find out in the next video.