Holy moly.
Good job getting this far in the course.
You should really, really be proud of yourself because we've learned a lot, and now we're going to
build something really exciting.
We're going to build a startup landing page.
A landing page like this that well is responsive.
But most importantly, it has some text.
It has a button.
But check this out when you click on the button.
It takes you to a form to sign up and collect email addresses.
That's right.
We're building a startup landing page.
I'm going to show you how to do it step by step.
And you can grab the starter files attached to this lesson because we're going to build this from scratch
and see how we can put something online that you can now share with your friends.
Next time you have a big startup idea.
Let's get started.