Welcome back.
So as you can see, we're back in this little canvas that we've been working on.
We have our journey that we've been creating.
We have an assumptions, grid, stakeholders and users.
We have project goals.
And what I would like to do is I like to create a story map.
As you can tell, as I was building out this journey map over here.
I started thinking about all the different requirements that are happening along the way, all the different
things we're asking users.
And it's starting to look like a user story map.
And you may be thinking, What is a user store map?
What's a user story?
Why does it need to be mapped?
Well, this really helps a prioritization and figuring out releases.
Now, as a designer, I feel like this is super helpful even for myself when I need to think about the
types of things I need to actually design for.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to run you through how we can do this for ourselves.
So I'm going to just steal this journey map and we can start breaking that out a bit.
We can.
I'm going to just copy it here.
Okay.
So what is the user story map?
So user story mapping is how we consistently help either clients or our product team to release small
incremental portions of value with the ability to release at any time and know when the product is viable.
It is a product planning method that really helps the product owner and the team focus on end user business
outcomes when planning what to build and when to build it.
So these story maps complement a traditional flat backlog.
So if we think about the type of work that we're trying to build here, it's broken into a bunch of
different pieces and those types of things live in a thing called the backlog.
And the backlog is essentially just a long list of different types of features.
If we're thinking about like a traditional spec now by adding the context of the user's activities and
tasks to help design releases that address immediate priorities through a regular cadence of enhancements.
Flat backlogs really make it difficult to understand the different types of features and how these features
relate to each other and how do they create value for the customer.
So if I'm thinking about traditional specs, they don't really mention any of that.
The user story map really helps us focus on the activity that needs to be completed first and adds just
enough stories to allow the activity to happen in the first release, then follow up with enhancements
in subsequent releases.
So what is a story map and what does it made up of?
Now, let's take a look at this.
This is essentially a story map in a way.
But if we want to think about it a little bit more in depth story map has several different things.
It has the persona.
And it has a backbone.
So we're just going to copy this line and bring it up here.
So this is the backbone.
And the backbone is made up of high level activities the app will facilitate in order of priority.
It's made up of two elements.
Your main activities and tasks.
Now the main activity could be something like onboarding, and the task could be something like Let's
think about a task with an onboarding.
Enter personal details.
Och.
Now the activities, this is the highest portion of this backbone.
These are usually thought of as like these large epics.
That is usually like an agile term to house all the different features within like a category.
But these represent an activity the user has in relation to this application.
So like I said.
On boarding.
Tasks.
Describe the events that need to happen in order for the user to complete this larger activity.
You know, an example is like entering personal details.
Let's throw that in there.
Another one could be enter interests.
Ad products that I am interested in.
Maybe there's an education portion education around onboarding process.
So these are all the different types of tasks that need to be completed in order for somebody to complete
this activity.
So as you can see, we're starting to build that backbone.
Now, there may be more activities.
Like I said, there may be another one.
That is like what's an example of an activity?
I want to be able to find a product.
So that's a high level activity and some tasks could be search.
I want to be able to see results.
So you can start to see how we are building this kind of narrative in this backbone.
Now in the next video, we're going to be focusing on the bottom portion of a story map and what the
user story is.