And welcome back.
In this final video, I want to show you what this course is all about, what we're learning in this
course and what we're going to be able to do at the end.
You may have heard the term full stack developer, front end developer, back end developer.
And looking at this diagram, you're starting to recognize that HTML, CSS, JavaScript you see react
in there.
We'll get to that.
Don't worry about it.
But that's what a front end developer does.
The front end developer is the person who makes sure that when we open up the browser and go to Google.com,
that we see Google, we see it nice and pretty laid out beautifully, has a search bar and essentially
anything that a user sees the front end developer does, and that is using HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
React and a few other tools.
The back end developer, that's the person that works with the server.
Make sure that when a browser speaks to it, it serves up those files and it uses technology such as
Node.js, Express JS, which we're going to get into.
And then that server is going to talk also to a database.
Again, we haven't really discussed that too much, but don't worry, there is going to be a section
on it and that's going to use PostgreSQL and we're actually going to be learning that as well.
So we want to build you up as a full stack developer to be able to work with all these technologies
so that everything revolving around a web application you're able to build.
So get excited.
You're going to learn all of this.
It looks overwhelming, but trust me, just like this, how the Internet Works section, it's all going
to make sense.
So I'll see you at the next one.
Bye bye.