And welcome to the student Q&A section.
So as students take this course, usually I get a bunch of questions.
Some of them are really, really good.
Some of them I get often.
And we're going to use these Q&A sections for me to make a reply video to answer some of those really,
really good questions.
And the first one we're going to tackle for this video is index HTML.
If we go back to our example that we had, you've noticed that I've always used indexed HTML as the
first page and then we created a new page, HTML.
Now you might be asking yourself, why index HTML, why not home HTML or Apple's HTML?
And you could actually do that.
But I can explain this really well by looking at this diagram.
Most of the time there are more than a few HTML files.
You saw that with our example.
We had our index on HTML and also new page HTML.
But when we make that request to let's say Google.com, how does the server know which HTML to return
first for the home page and you could go into the server and configure it and tell it.
You know what I want about HTML to be the first page.
But by default most servers just say I'll return index.html.
If I see index.html in the servers, I'll just return that.
So this is just a common practice that you'll see in a lot of the projects that a lot of the websites
that you'll work with is that indexed HTML is usually you can think of it as the home page, the first
HTML file that the server returns.
And if anybody in the index site HTML clicks on a link, then it will return whichever link they return.
So that would be let's say they click on about anchor tag, then they'll get about dot HTML.
So that's it.
That is your answer to your question.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.