Welcome back.
Now we're going to talk about how we can create our very own form and the questions we often ask ourselves
in terms of the types of inputs we want to use.
We're probably not going to create our own components and go really deep here into what that looks like
just yet, because we want to just come up with some quick concepts in terms of what types of content
we're going to see on the page.
Step number one, where are we going to find a form on our page within our product for our client?
Habitual.
I think like you'll probably see like log in and sign up.
And I think probably like the biggest form we'll probably see is like the registration and that's about
it really.
This is a type of product that doesn't necessarily have a lot of forms, but registration is huge.
And especially with this product, I think it's going to be pretty integral to the way people kind of
like maybe talk about like why they're joining the product or maybe to pick some interests, maybe narrowing
down those interests.
So let's jump right in to how we can create some form elements for our client.
When I think about our client, they need to have a registration and I need to think about those different
types of elements.
So I'm going to just kind of create a frame.
Let's press F and we're going to just use one of these screens.
We'll just call it registration.
So we're going to kind of just create like a wireframe, just so we get a good indication of what we
want to build.
And then we can eventually get to a higher fidelity.
So when a user comes to the page, they'll probably see like an input.
Uh, let me just.
They'll probably see 48.
It's probably good.
Don't want to get too fancy just yet.
Let's give it a stroke.
We can actually start creating some pieces if we wanted to.
We're here.
I'm going to create a couple of elements that I can just easily reuse.
I know I said I wasn't going to go for grading it, but, you know, maybe maybe that's the best course
of action.
What else do we have here?
Let's make a button.
And we are just going to fill that with brand color.
I don't know if I have the brain color, but we can just kind of get close to it right now.
Oops.
Maybe that's like our primary button.
And we'll put some text in there.
Same primary.
OC.
I like.
I like a lot.
This could be like 16 pixels.
Make this bone, we'll call it primary button.
So we are kind of creating our own little components we can make this way.
I know it's probably not accessible, but I mean, we can kind of fine tune.
Like sometimes accessibility could be like a little wonky in terms of like.
What is actually readable and what isn't like this is probably like bordering that line.
It's probably not accessible.
Like if we check right now, let's do contrast.
Like it's probably not, yeah, it fails, but it may be more legible than black, which is probably
actually accessible.
So that's our primary button.
We can just go over here, we can make a secondary, so probably have a secondary like a back button.
And that frame.
We won't have anything in it.
No, Phil.
But the primary buttons color will probably be like a black.
So that's good.
We'll just call it secondary.
And remember what I said about constraints.
So you can do that?
I can do that.
Perfect.
So we have a secondary and a primary.
We have an input up there.
I think that's fine for now.
I guess let's just call this our components for now.
Just so we have some basic inputs, like we may have some checkboxes.
So it's like this is an input fields.
And we'll just call it Field.
We probably should have some text in there.
Input text, that's totally fine.
And we could bump that to regular.
Okay.
I'm not going to worry too much.
About that.
We do need to, however, create some checkboxes.
Possibly.
I'm envisioning that there will be checkboxes in our future.
30 to 40.
So I'm still using that base unit.
If eight pixels to create my components here that's a little big bump it down to 32.
Change the border radius.
I think that's fine.
We do need some text for it, though.
CheckBox.
Text.
So just do this.
So, I mean, we can start creating some of our components.
I mean, they don't necessarily need to be components.
It's good to just kind of prep before we even start.
I think that's enough.
Cool.
Let's create another frame.
Select F.
So when a user first comes to our registration, I think like the first thing we'll probably ask them
to do is maybe like we'll probably see something like welcome.
It's a type that in their.
We'll see something like welcome.
How are you?
And we'll probably ask them to possibly, like, you know, add a profile image and like in terms of
the input.
It's kind of tough because we don't necessarily have like an input for the actual like it could just
be a button that like uses their phone to find an image.
And that's all handled on like the iPhone side or the Android side.
So that's a discussion to have with your developers.
So we'll just do this
and let's just go to Icon Ify or let's use material design icons and we'll just say profile person.
It's like, okay, there we go.
So I'm going to take that.
I'm just going to detach it.
Command, see?
Let's bring that into our registration.
And there we go.
So we have, like, a thing here, like a little image.
Maybe we should have some text below because it's very fake.
Add a photo.
So other members.
I don't know if other members know who you are.
Or actually add a photo.
So.
Hmm.
Why would they add a photo?
So you can customize your experience.
This is probably, like, a nice to have feature.
Like, Do they really need a photo?
Probably not.
It's really about exploring if you need something versus like if it's a nice to have.
So the button here may say upload a photo and the secondary could be something like Skip this for now.
So we want that primary action to be much bigger, much more prominent.
I mean, we can even, like, go over here and make this a little bit less obvious.
And I think another thing is we need to let people know this seems like it's going to be a multi step
process.
So we need to let people know like what step of the process they're in and that's just change that.
So step one of four.
OC and let's just bold that.
So it's pretty obvious.
I mean, we can actually just leave it at the top.
I'm not sure about the whole layout of the pages yet.
So if we copy that, we can just change that over there.
And the next one could be like, What's your main reason for joining?
It's good to understand why they want to join.
I can just pop this up here.
We're not being too, like, crazy in terms of, like, how we structure just yet, but we could like
essentially put these items in a frame that has auto layout and thought whenever we adjust something,
it's going to bump it down and I'll show you what that looks like.
So if we select these and we do option command G, we have a frame and if you select auto layout, it
will automatically position them vertically.
You can even do it horizontally, but it's going to push it to the right over here so you can space
it any which way you want.
So if I want to like adhere to a pixel base like 24 pixels and if I add to this, it's just going to
keep on pushing the content down and you can just like keep things incredibly consistent.
It's just it's for your own sanity, to be honest.
Okay.
So this will help us make some great.
Recommendations.
So when I'm thinking about this registration, I want to get as much info about the user as possible
with kind of making it fun.
CheckBoxes are kind of hard to hit on mobile sometimes unless you make this whole tappable field like
tappable or like just easy to interact with.
So we can like do optional kind of like checkboxes or like radio buttons and I'll show you what we can
do here.
So I've taken like the primary button over here, and I'm just going to make this fill, like, white.
We're going to go in and I'm going to make that Phil Black.
Perfect.
And I am going to also apply a stroke.
And that stroke is going to be like a.
We'll just do 50% of block.
So, I mean, there you go.
We kind of have like a radio button that they can click.
So we can give them some options.
Like maybe one of them is Discover.
New and exciting.
Products.
The next one could be make month to month shopping.
Easier.
So that is like a definitely a big thing in terms of like shopping and in terms of like the usefulness
of this product.
If you do a lot of month to month shopping, you have a lot of like things that you constantly buy over
and over again.
If we know more about you, we can easily make that experience.
Much better yet.
Hmm.
Get relevant recommendations.
So there's a couple of options and like if I select one, so for this use case, I'm just going to select
it just to kind of showcase what that's going to look like.
So I'm going to.
Do that.
And that is going to be white and that's what it could look like.
So all of a sudden, we kind of have.
A nice little active state there, too, and we can create a component for that.
What I've done here is I've actually removed this skip because this is a mandatory.
I'm thinking about this actually being mandatory because it's pretty it's pretty big in terms of like
the type of question we're asking.
And if they don't fill it out, we can give them like a disabled state.
So just make sure you disable.
States are easy to read in terms of contrast and when they do select that it will move to the active
state.
Here you can work along with me and just think about the type of content we are we're creating for in
terms of the registration.
I mean, there's so many different things we can do.
We can just think about like the different types of like inputs that we need and the different types
of processes that we're going to like design for.
So I'm designing this registration process actively as I'm kind of coming up with these concepts.
I'm thinking about the different questions I'm asking users.
So like I probably at this point, I want them to just start picking some like interest.
So I'll get started by picking some interests.
And I mean, I don't even know.
I think that's pretty self explanatory.
And they can essentially like we could create like cards for them to make it a little more fun.
Like checkboxes are kind of boring.
So for something like this, we could create.
Like cards.
I'm not sure what's in the cards, maybe.
Actually, I think it would be best if we do something like this.
Let's create a frame.
For a square and we'll put a text in that frame and we'll call it something like music.
That's a little too big, but let's go down to 20 pixels.
And that's fine.
This is going to be a different type of checkbox.
And the background color.
Let's give it a fill.
So it's a little bit more interesting than it is now.
And there you go.
Like, we easily have like a checkbox that we can select.
So there it is.
Remember what I said about constraints.
So if I position this like that.
I'm going to try and make this almost a square.
So if our position is like that, there we go.
It doesn't need to be perfect.
We have a bunch of different options and if they will do the same thing over here.
Oops, I forgot to actually make that continue.
Um, this one can be continue as well for now at least.
I don't know what this is going to be.
It could be like an image.
It could be like a colored square.
I think we need to really kind of think about that a little bit more in terms of what that active state
looks like.
But that's when we get more in-depth in terms of like actually creating the component.
But now I know what types of questions I'm asking.
I'm asking them to upload a photo for customisation purposes, you know, making their experience a
little bit more delightful.
It's not needed.
So I gave them like a skip option.
I asked them why they're joining because maybe the types of products we do push to them is relevant
based off of this question.
You know, if they want to have like a month to month subscription of things like we could do something
like that, if they also discover new and exciting products, like we can push like new products to
them, but if they want relevant recommendations, it's like a little bit of both in terms of the types
of products we decide to push them.
If we think about this from a data collecting perspective, this will definitely help us kind of learn
more about our users.
So if people keep on creating this, we'll know the types of users we're getting in terms of like what
they're trying to achieve.
Are they trying to like are the majority of our users doing month to month subscriptions or something
like that?
If that's the case, then it could actually force us to pivot the purpose of the application.
It moves away from relevant recommendations to more so like a one stop shop where we constantly just
ship to you every single month, and that's constantly relevant and it's constantly based off of what
you need.
So take that into consideration in terms of the types of questions you're asking even for over here,
like getting started, I've kind of given them the option to select different types of interests.
I could have sports, I could have like tech.
Another option could be like gaming.
I've given them a bunch of different interests.
I don't know why I have four.
I mean, we could have four.
We can even go a deeper level and think about, like, now, like narrow it down.
What type of music do you like?
Do you like to listen to, like vinyl?
Do you like to listen to live music?
Are you thinking like buying speakers?
Like if you've selected something like fashion, like are you into sneakers, etc. or if there's anything
else, can you add that?
So we could even go even deeper here.
I think we're at a good spot right now just to get some basic information for from our user.
What we can do for now is what I would do is actually.
Put this together and put it into a prototype and test with users.
Immediately test fast.
We're here, we can just get started at the end.
We'll probably have like a nice little screen that just says like, woo hoo, you did it.
Like, These are your results.
Or we could show them our results if that's important.
I don't know.
It's really going to depend based off of like how we validate our assumptions.
But this is essentially how you go about like thinking through a form.
You've got to ask yourself the questions of like, well, especially with this case in terms of registration,
what types of questions am I going to ask our users?
And like, how do I break that down?
Like what types of inputs am I using based off of those questions?
Now, this is a really simple form, and I'm sure eventually in your career you are definitely going
to have much more complex forms.
So take it step by step, start with sketching, move on to like user flows in terms of like figuring
out what that process kind of looks like and then jump into like a product like Figma and really start
to figure out those details.
So that's how you create your own form within Figma.