What come back to the students in this lecture here we are going to be improving our CMAs even more
what we're going to do is we're going to build a feature a handy function that is going to prevent certain
users from accessing our users page or whatever other page we are having or application that is not
good for subscriber there is not Desta scratches was not supposed to be in there.
For example in their view all users page this page here should not be accessed by a subscriber like
Santa see Santa or her name Maria or whatever her name is.
She is a subscriber.
She should not being here so we're going to build a really handy function is going to help you even
be more functional because it's going to show you how he's done.
All right.
All right so we're going to we're going to improve this as a lot more than what it is right now.
I also want to build a feature where we are going to be checking to see the database if he has a duplicate
of CRN username or you know or our name or something like that right.
So because in real systems out there right we we can really have to user names with it.
We can really have to user names with the same username so users with the same user name.
Right.
So we're going to build that feature in a later course.
We're in the later lecture.
All right.
So let's go ahead and let's go to our editor real quick and here we do.
We are using session.
Let me show you right here.
Log in this is where we do this.
We are pulling out the value in a database.
Let me show you real quick.
We're pulling this guy right here.
They use a roll we put in this put in this value here in putting that value into a session this is how
we do in our checking for admin kind of functionality but that's not a very good one.
I think if we build a handy function that will allow us to check for it for the users and admin it would
be better and more secure and just quicker.
OK so let's do that now let's go to functions that BHP.
All right.
What we have are some of our functions when we're going to build a lot more functions.
But this is a start of a new section of improving our CMOS.
All right.
So the first thing is let's create the function call is admin.
I think this is a good name for it.
What about if we can have a parameter here like let's say for example if we take the user name I think
the user name the user is going to log in right here you see this value here.
These sessions are available through our whole application right.
So my associates use this value here to try to figure out the users and admin right.
And later on we're going to build it now you might be wondering OK what if they use it if we have another
user name basis a striver with the same name right.
Well we're going to begin to fix that in the later lecture here.
Like I told you.
All right.
So let's go here and let's just say we're going to take an argument using name argument here.
Let's set this empty string as a default.
Right.
All right.
So the first thing is we need to have a connection right.
So we've got to pull that in from the global space and let's create a quavery real quick here.
You're right so we're going to say I want you I want to select the user roll call them.
All right we're going to we're not going to be querying the whole table we're just going to query this
column here from this table from users.
All right.
And we're going to say where a user name column is equal.
We're going to put this in quotes because there's a string coming in right.
It's a têtes.
So user name.
There we go.
Now what we've got to do is send this with my ass you are like Querrey this is something else that I
want to also do we want to actually use another API ph be just to make our application a little bit
more secure.
We're going to do that in later lectures but I just wanted you guys to know that.
All right.
And for those of you that are looking for next course to take after this one I think the Logan system
is a really good one.
PH BE which I have available really good course.
Just to make your knowledge a lot better in procedural.
All right.
So let's actually save this and let's make sure that we use our function confirm Querrey which I have
above all these functions just to check that our result is good.
Does it have any errors or Querrey.
All right.
We can actually make this a little bit tidy.
Let's let's do my Eskew ally fetch array actually.
And we're going to fetch our table we are resoled of course and we are going to see that here in this
variable.
So we're going to save all that data rate and is variable there.
So let's do a check real quick let's just say if the ROE.
And of course we have the table name right here to the table column user role.
So if this user role is equal to admin which should be equal to I mean right.
If the user name is an admin if the user always an admin or if not then we do something else but we
can't return true.
All right.
Then else we are going to be returning false.
You got it.
Good job.
All right.
So I think we're done with this function this looks pretty good.
If we have some type of error we'll fix it.
All right.
Not going to check it right now.
Let's actually go to users.
This is where this is the page where we don't one regular users to be on.
Right.
We might change this in the future.
Might change is cold to make it better.
But right now let's just go to the top.
This is what we're going to have it.
And this just opened up BHB tag real quick here and we're just going to say if because we're returning
to a force from this function we can say if it's admen if it's not it is admin with exclamation in front
of it and we've got to take this from the session.
Remember that we have user name available throughout the whole application.
All right.
If if the user name if this user name is admin around these users not an admin I want you to do something
for me and this something would be Hetter of course would be to get this user out of here.
We should be a function for this like a redirect function.
And it's step BHB.
All right.
So this is what we're going to be doing right.
Super simple.
We can probably do this in one line I'll show you later on.
But let's let's check this out real quick.
So we are this is Santa Santa Maria.
She is a subscriber we refresh this is going to redirector to and it's because she's not allowed there
anymore.
Now I'm going to log out.
All right.
We've got all right low now here this Sunday I got a fix here.
You might now have this Arab What I do log out and log out that BHB make sure that you have your orbi
start right here because we are not including any Fouchier that have the orbi star in the admin header
has all the star but we're not.
All right.
And these D-B that BHP should have a all star on top as well right here.
See this is just because logging is the only follower that has this.
But anyway we'll make this a little bit more tidy for later on.
There we go.
So let's actually.
Well right now we don't have anybody logged in.
All right.
So let's log in Rico which is an admin enter.
There we go.
Rigaud is low again.
And if we go to users where we go we are able to access users.
Pretty cool stuff right.
We were even able to add users.
All right.
Cool.
Great job.
If you were to follow me.
You're doing great.
Let's jump into the next improvement on the next lectures.
Right.
If you don't see the next lecture just give me a moment.
All right.
Thank you so much and I'll see you then.
Bye bye.