All right so I mean that dashboard look then there's Rico and you can go out and logging whatever uses
you got here.
All right.
Now what I want to do in this lecture is add a profile page to this specific user that is logged in
the ready.
All right.
So later on we're going to personalize this a little better.
And you know being able to reuse some of these cold and other pages.
But right now it is going heading added profile page.
Before we go on I just want to say congratulations if you are here you are very different from a lot
of people.
And I don't know if I said this before but a lot of people give up the first couple hours the first
one or two hours when people even give up the first 15 minutes because they think it's too hard.
But you have stuck to it.
You have rewind those videos a million times until you got it and you are here.
You are special.
Keep going.
You're going to get very far in web development or any other career path you set foot or hands into.
All right.
So let's go ahead and make his profile page and let's so we can add some more functionality to our CMOS.
Perfect.
So what we want to do is we want to go ahead and click on users so we're going to do a Save As and users
says users already have these users that BHP page already has it that the header has a navigation all
that we need.
All right.
And the profile page only thing that we will be able to do is edit the user.
That's the only thing we will be able to do and his profile up each page.
And you know we don't have it yet but it's going to be very similar to the As a matter of fact we're
going to be using that same form right here.
But our CMOS is going to detect that is us is this person that is logged in and is going to be pulling
that information for this specific user into that profile that BHP so that way we can edit our own profile.
Right.
So.
Or if we in the future we have any other users they can log in to their own profile instead of they
won't be able to see this page here.
Right.
They will be able only to see their profile page because if it's a subscriber we don't want to give
them access to adding users right.
So they won't be able to probably see this page.
But.
So let's go ahead and add the profile page and I already added that link.
I'm going to show you what I did.
Go to admin and insane clues go to admin on the score navigation.
This is inside the admin folder and go to all the way down to where you see this link right here.
Profile and add profile up to that link and this is just that link right here.
All right.
That's all I did to make sure that you do that at that.
And now we're going to add the page.
So we want to do is because users already have all of that functionality uses that BHB uses it inside.
Adam the admin folder.
We're going to do Aceves here and we are going to be calling this profile that BHB.
All right.
We're going to take a couple of things out of here since we don't need it we're going to take this statement
this statement out of here and let's just check it out.
This Cliggott And now we see these pages black.
All right so we created this page.
Now what next.
Well we have two ways of actually getting information here.
Either we put a get request on the link on the admin navigation right here.
We don't have any queries.
Also we will have to make a query pull out the user's ID and then pull out fill that request right here
that parameter on the link itself so that we can pick it up on the profile that BHB.
But we also have another option the other option is actually using sessions and we already have sessions
set up already in the admin header.
If you go to the admin header you're going to see that sessions already started and we are ready said
sending sessions from log in that BHB in their old directory in the same folder we were already setting
sessions right here so we got these sessions all over our site in the Admin site so we can you know
pull that information out.
We can do a query and compare it and pull information out of that.
So let's go in the usal sessions right there right.
So let's go to profile BHB and I'm right on top actually before the wrapper if we want to check for
that session.
So let's say if it's set and actually this puts on BHB in there it would be nice if with all that's
the ending let's do the beginning BHB tagging here and right there.
So if it's set and we check in for session I'm just closes our little bit so you can see what I'm doing
better.
Perfect.
Hopefully that's clear for you session.
And what do we want to check for user name right.
And so each session has the value of user name.
I want you to echo it out right.
I want to check it out.
I want to see if it works.
I want to see if if this session is actually exists.
If it does exist.
So we're going to echo that echo that.
So I'm going to grab this because right now we won't be able to see it.
If I come to this page and refresh you can see that something happened here but we don't see it because
I'm black around it.
So I take this whole thing there and we're going to put it somewhere that we can see.
So let's just put it right here on the right there.
See that.
So we are echoing that section.
So we have the session now and we can do all the things with it.
So let's just do on do here and have it on top here.
So now that we know that session works we need to start doing some inquiry right.
Well before we do that let's actually get the form out here because we need a form and I already said
that we're going to be using a form like this if I if you that if I did not say they I'm saying it right
now we're going to be using a form just like this one here.
So this is edit user right as a user that BHB.
So let's go ahead and get that form edit user All right which is his admin includes Let's add.
Get the whole form.
So let me make this smaller so that way I could see the form whatever I'm getting out of there.
So I'm just going to copy the whole form and pasted it in that profile that BGB.
Of course we're going to get some errors now because this form and I got to make sure hold on here I'm
going to make this big so you can see what I'm doing.
I got to make sure that this whole thing is a ball.
Everything.
All right.
There we go.
That is that makes sense and that makes sense.
And this is just that let's just add it right here let's see what happens.
Now let's go back and refresh now here refresh profile and then you can see the form right here.
But one of the things that you can see that is form before we you know we would do anything just know
that we seeing these arrows and the way the reason why is because we have we don't have these variables
anywhere.
We don't have these values.
So in the next lecture we gonna fix this we're going to make where we are going to get those those values
in there so that we can pool information for this specific user.
All right so on the next lecture we're going to be doing the Querrey.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.