Hi welcome back the students on this video here we are going to find out how to collect data from forms.
This is actually really exciting.
BHP was meant to do a lot of things in this.
This is one of the things that be so great doing the right.
So let's go ahead and start doing that.
So the first thing that we got to do is do Aceves of course and that blank that BHB and I'm going to
explain a couple of things to you before we get started.
So I just going to make a file called form ph be right and get it ready on the browser there.
All right.
Perfect.
So now what's going on with this collecting data.
With a super global cold very post well post is a.
Like I said super verbal super global variable and is called Pulse non-global and this will pick up
the data that we send it to.
We send it using forms.
So we pick up data from form in a post format.
So I don't know if you've seen forms.
If you are a developer you probably seen forms before there and you've seen the data inside but you
don't know how it worked.
I want to show you in this video how it works.
So let's make a forum for it first and let's find out the ins and outs of the form.
So I'm just going to create a forum with some inputs and I'm going to explain in a minute what is key
word here is what he means.
And I just going to have a couple of inputs here.
This one is going to be full password.
The first one is going to be for names and this one is going to be just a submit button and put a B
or tag right here.
All right so we have a data form.
What's the matter.
Let's do some placeholders so that way the user knows why they have to type in there.
So placeholder and then she's going to say enter name or user name is user name usually is a user name
and password and has just finished a placeholder typed here.
Come back here.
There should be enough.
Right.
There we go.
As a matter of fact we are missing this a password right now right password not peace.
Word Perfect.
So we have this forum here right now.
This key word is key word does.
It sends this data to another page.
Usually we send the data to a function that BHB or foreign that BHB to process.
Right now we want this data to be sent to this form here.
This page form that BHB.
Right because we are going to be processing the data right here on this form.
We're going to be picking it up and the way census data is with this out you here called post with post
information post data pull data is usually usually for forms.
Jesus if I can get this right that would be nice.
That would go right.
So we are telling whoever is big in this form whoever is process in this form that the data here is
post.
So we got to we've got to extract the user name out of here we've got to extract the password values
out of there.
Ambil right now before we do we before we do this we need to find out.
This form was submitted because if we check for values and this form was not submitted we we're going
to get a narrow mph BHP is going to try to find the values is going to say to us Well something went
wrong.
I can't find this value is going to give us an error.
So now we say that we are going to pick up this information we're going to send it via polls.
And for that we need to receive it and we're going to receive it to the variable post this super global
is actually fine like this in this super global We are going to be saving all the post data from forms.
So let's go ahead and put a BHB taxing here and use the super global to get that data.
As a matter of fact what we're going to be getting is it's finding out this phone was submitted so I'm
going to show you how to do that.
So we're going to create an if statement here and we're going to find out if polls but you've got to
also keep in mind that when this form gets admitted not only does We've made this right we made the
first input.
Remember it's a super global and a super global works a little different than a super global variable
works a little different than the regular variable.
As a matter of fact this information gets turned into an associative array.
So this user here becomes the value.
All right.
Because I'll show you right now in a minute but this post here we'll pick up the value that we send
it to and we are going to show you another key that we use here to send that value to the polls to the
associative array which is a super global variable.
And it could be a little confusing but if you see I'm going to show you exactly what it is right now
so please don't get confused.
So we're going to use a function call is set right inside this if statement and we're going to find
out if the post variable super global right variable is available but we say that it gets turned into
an associate of array What do we want to check when we check for associative array we have to check
for what's inside what value is right.
So this would be the associative array post-ride would be the array.
And what are we checking for.
Well there's another key that we use code name and you're going to see that in the forums with without
this key word you can't send data to the super Global Post.
Right.
So we are going to be what do we want to send.
This is going to turn into that value right here.
We want to send this submit right we pull whatever we want in here.
But I just want to call it something because that's what it is.
So we're going to check this mid value here is set.
So this is this.
Remember this is this elmet been here actually right here.
This is the summit.
And the only way this value gets submitted is when we click it when we click it.
All right.
This guy is going to send the information to form that BHB room and we're going to pick it up because
information information's imposed via a format in post format.
We're going to pick it up right here.
We're going to.
The first thing that we're going to become is this BHB right because we are in the header of that document.
So and this is a Ph.D. So Apache is going to be looking for information.
So he runs this and says oh I got to stay here and he runs the State me he says is a set post.
So admit they don't want you to do this so he's going to run this BHB called before anything else on
that page when he gets a minute when he this action here get sent sends the data to that form ph B which
is this form via post.
Hopefully you understand is not the word we're going to recap at the end.
So I just going to say echo if the submit button was pressed.
All right yes he works
works.
There we go.
So we're going to come here we're going to click submit.
Yes it works.
You see that we got the data we got this M-ID value from down here when we clicked on submit and we
were able to do something with it.
All right.
So very simple again.
Let me recap a little bit here what we did.
We know that this is the form.
Right.
And we know that this action was going to send the data to this page here and we're going to see later
on how we can send it to another page but right now we are sending it here via post format right.
And then we've got well what are we sending right now.
The only thing we are sending is this input's right here because we're using this name keyword right
now and leave it up to you if you want to do it before you watch the next video how you can send the
rest of the information to the post right here.
Don't check for it for it if you want to check for it go ahead and use the other the other inputs and
check for that data and then say you know echo I found a user name.
I found the password.
So if you want to go ahead and do this to hear yourself do try to do it and then watch all the video
and see if you know your my answers is the same as yours.
All right so anyways I leave that up to you if you want to do that.
Remember that this gets turned into an associate array here and we'll be doing is checking for the value
here and his name matchable here.
So that's what this is why I get sent.
Anyway thank you for watching this video and the next video we're going to be extracting the rest of
this information.
All right we're going to be turning into variables and we're going to be able to process that information.
Right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching.
I'll see you in the next one