All righty to they were going to be doing something really awesome.
It's called functions right.
Functions are actually one of the most important things in programming right.
Because functions helps us organize our code into pieces of code like a block of code and then we use
that code over and over again just by naming it and referring to it by the name just like variables
we use a name and then we enclose values into it.
And when we when we refer to those values we use the name right.
So functions work very similar but they are more powerful than arrays them more power more powerful
than variables and anything else you can think of.
Let me show you exactly the syntax of a function and then show you how we use them.
So let's go ahead and let's do a save as on this blank that BHB Let's call these functions.
All right.
Perfit and going to make this tutorial.
This video here.
Short and sweet informative for right ph.
B.
We got the tax right here and you should already got used to that.
So how in the world we define a function.
Age actually what is it.
All right.
So let me just give you an example.
If I have all this code here that is printing also an array functions that with not array function array
values right that we did in resections if we want to use this code over in another page right we want
to do the same thing on another page.
We have to copy this right click it and copy it into another page right.
We want to reuse it.
And then let's say for example have 10 pages I want to use the same code and 10 pages I would have to
go physically and copy these 10 times while functions allow us to actually wrap all this in a block
in a block and then we can just name it.
Let's say for example block one.
Right.
And all we have to do if we want to use this over and over again in each of those 10 pages which is
used to block one name and all this code we get execute every time we use that name.
Right so we can wrap a lot of information in block NSEC in this in a function and we can refer to it
by its name.
Right.
It is really all some functions are really awesome.
So I'm going to go to functions that BHB back again there.
And let's use this to learn how to define it.
So the first thing that we have to type in here is a function name actually function keyword.
So we say function and you see my code that already highlighted this in blue because it already knows
that function this is reserved word word in PH BE in many programming languages use this too.
So function and then type the name of the function.
This function is going to say something and I just can't name it say something because that's what he's
going to do.
You've got to be very descriptive when you're writing functions if not when you write your code is not
going to be understood.
You're not going to understand your code very much and other people were not either.
So at the end of the name of the function you put the parentheses and the curly brackets just like we
do if statements are right.
Very similar to if statements and we put it down.
And they said this curly brackets you know what's going to happen.
We're going to have all the code that we want to run every time we use this name.
This is a name that we are going to use every time we want to refer to everything in sight here and
this could be three thousand lines of code.
All right well everything we enclose here is not going to work until we use this name here.
All right I am going to show you right now exactly what that means.
Let let's just do something very simple.
I'm going to say hello student.
All right.
Do you like like the class.
Yes.
OK great.
All right.
So we're just going to say that now if I go ahead and open this in the browser.
If we do this right we're going to get an error because I didn't put my semi-colon right here.
All right.
And by the way I found out really quick about the mistake because I've been writing code for a long
time.
So if you for some reason you get stuck here just make sure that you read your error right here with
BHB and make sure that you read the line here.
Syntax error they will tell you very clearly that you made a mistake in your sentence sometimes your
syntax error could be hundred lines above.
All right.
So make sure that you know that.
So now you see that this is not executed right here and I say to you until we use the name.
So I'm going to copy the name and I'm going to put it right below that curly bracket outside the function.
Don't put it inside because it's not going to work.
Then make sure you put a semi-colon there and save it.
Done.
See that.
Now every time we use this anywhere in our document this name here say something here I can put in 10
different pages.
All this coding here could be running in right now.
We've just got one line of code here.
But imagine we have a thousand lines of code that say we have a program that calculates the temperature
calculates gives us a message on the screen with the calendar on how the temperature is going to be
all week gives us the time for the browser that we are.
I mean this is a whole bunch of information you know gives us information about a user logging into
our Web site application whatever.
And we just say we just call the function call initialize or something like that.
So some function you know we just call some crazy function initialiser and it would initialize a whole
bunch of code for us so this is the way this is how we use functions or write to do a lot of things.
Sometimes we have very very small functions.
And each of those functions could be doing one thing at a time.
We have a big function and wrap many different functions inside and do something else like we can just
called let's say for example we have a function here call init and this is very common in BHB in many
different programming languages.
We have a function like this and then we have the little different functions inside we can call different
functions that we can call this.
All right.
So when we started this function it would echo this and they would call another function from outside
for example.
Let's just make another function here just create this and let's call this Calculate the.
Right.
And just not going to do that.
And I'm just going to echo out maybe some numbers.
I'm going to add some numbers here.
So every time I call this function here cockily is going to add some numbers for me.
All right.
So we have the neat function there.
And I want to call the cockily.
So what I do is I put the disfunctions here and I use and need to call cockily.
Right.
So every time I call in need is going to call calculate and then I'm going to make another function
here I'm going to say I'm going to call this say something say something 1 and I'm going to take this
echo out of there I'm not going to use it for that and just say something is going to be like this.
Right.
So I've got three functions here this function going I use it to code both of these functions here.
I just want to show you an example how powerful functions can be how we can use and to do other things.
All right we have a narrow somewhere right there.
All right.
So I hope you see what I'm doing here.
I have two functions here that are right.
This one is going to calculate some numbers is going to do an addition.
And this is just going to say something.
So I've got this a function that I'm going to call right now.
And when I call these functions this function is going to call this function here and is going to call
this function.
All right.
And I want to put a echo in between there because I want to send space into the data that is going to
come out on the screen.
And I'm going to call in there right here.
Boom.
Beautiful isn't it.
So we call it the first thing that it needs.
That was call that say something function and say hello right here.
This is the function.
And then the second thing that I did is that it has two numbers together and this is what it is.
So you see how we can use functions to do a lot of things.
All right I hope you see how powerful this can be.
All right.
And I'm going to leave this cold here for you cause of course exercise files and you can use it.
All right but if you did it with me you have it with you.
And great.
So I hope you were able to learn something valuable in this lesson.
See you in the next one.
Take care