Welcome back your students this is Edwin from the future so I'm already done with the Course but I come
back just to fix a couple of issues.
Now if you have notice if you go to your post page try and then you click Edit.
You're going to have a duplicate category right here.
I'll show you in a minute why that is right and your files are.
I see a mess.
My look a little different from me because I already I'm already done with the course.
Just to let you know but this is being produced because we are making two queries here and I show you
in a minute how that looks so I'm going to go and show you first.
We are making a query and this is the edit on the score pulls up BHB page by the way.
First I'm making a Querrey.
We are making inquiry to show all the categories right and then if the cat ID in the first category
ID are the same then we were making another query and we are echoing something else we need to modify
this a little bit just to make it better.
All right.
So this is going to be pretty simple right.
First of all we have to make another query for this.
All right so we know if the post category in the code ID is the same.
This is going to be the default.
All right that's good but then let's make an else statement here and let's just say that if it's not
then we just echo the regular categories which is pretty cool isn't it.
It is.
How about that.
You think that's going to work.
Let me show you save it and let's look at it let's test it real quick and then refresh it.
And now we go back we can see that is on the javascript BHB ambusher.
So there is no other duplicate here.
But we're still showing that the full category for this.
For that one.
So let's go back in trying to change this to something else let's change this Senko one one.
I would add the 1:53 to another category.
Let's change it to bootstrap and it looks different than any other page and the reason why is because
I was I had a whole bunch of duplicate called here duplicate.
A lot of clothes and you know it was something that I did manually.
But anyway.
So you can see now the category change to bootstrap.
And if I go any of this you can see that we still get the Bushrod category right here.
All right.
Let's actually update that.
So let's go back and look at it.
So we got it BUSCHER category right here.
Of course we got some crazy title like javascript which makes no sense right.
But again these are clones.
Now let's go into another one let's change the following one which is a javascript also let's change
that to I don't know BHB the nice BHB.
If we go back we can see that as BHB right now you see that.
And let's just edit that.
And you can see that speech.
All right.
So let's actually change the first one here just to make sure that it is working is BHB right now.
We edited it full BHB change changed to javascript update it.
Let's go back and then we can see that it says javascript edit javascript so this fits all right.
Beautiful so that we don't have to make all the queries there right.
Thank you so much for watching.
And I hope that helps some of you out there.
We saw that situation.
Take care and I see you featured lessons.
Bye bye.