Welcome back my students in this section here.
Well we're going to be doing is applying a more secure system to our application.
We're going to be using prepared statements.
I won't say I'm going to be explaining what prepared statements are.
I'm not going to go into that.
OK.
In prepared statements because this is not a prepared statement course and for that we can have a whole
course in prepared statements.
Now there's a bunch of the communication there and the PH be on their website.
You can Google it.
OK.
And you can find out more information but I want to show you what the first images are.
I want to show you how to use them and I'm not just basically not going to get into why each of those
special functions do because they do a lot of stuff behind the scenes.
OK.
All right.
So I mean category that BHB here and one of the first things that I'm going to do here that I see this
code that we read thing a long time ago.
Right.
What I want to do is I want to actually
I want to change this for this because we have this admin functionality that we added to our application
guys.
These couple lectures that I'm about to make here for you is because I want to add value to the Course
is not something that I was planning to but because you guys make requests all the time and I you know
even though it takes me a little while to get get them applied to the course I do.
I have thousands of students over eighty nine thousand I believe right now and you know it's just hard
to keep up on my courses up today.
But I tried my best and I keep my courses up today.
And if I if I'm not there yet I will if you taking some of my other courses that I haven't really of
data that costs something that I say I would I'm going to.
OK.
Just like I'm doing this one.
But anyway hope you guys appreciate this.
So let's just say we want to check keep this guy.
He's available.
OK.
And this is we're just making sure that this guy's not mean if he's not an admin then you know.
And of course we get that problem.
This is because we have a whole bunch of little parentheses there and there's no way it is there's line
20 if it's set at his admin.
Actually we can do this.
There we go.
And that's going to work better.
OK.
So now you can see that I'm little down.
I wasn't lower than I was and then I looked down and you could see that it is working OK.
So another way to know that this is good actually is that if I make this draft if I'm not admitting
I shouldn't be able to see that actually draft let's go here.
Migdal the one draft as well.
And now if I go to another browser
you can see that he says no poses available.
That's pretty cool stuff.
OK.
All right.
So now let's go back to here and let's see what prefers stamens are and how we can apply it to our code
and our application basically.
So this is the regular Querrey right we creating a Querrey here and we are taking all these into our
database prepared statements work in a different way.
They don't take all this in.
They don't take this in.
They take a placeholder instead.
So we put a question mark in the prepared statement and then we send that in.
And that gives process and then later on we bind the original value which is this guy in this case for
this Querrey.
Now let me show you.
We use a function call mice you lie as a prepared statement actually.
OK.
And this function is going to take two parameters.
Well you already see one parameter there.
The first parameter is going to be the connection.
OK.
And the second would be the query with a placeholder.
We're not sending those values in yet.
And this is the great stuff a bow prepared statement.
Again they are a bunch of the communication of bodies.
You want to go into that.
But I'm going to try my best to explain it here.
Remember this is an extra feature so it's not a course for it.
OK.
So this functionality though we are going to have two different statements though.
Usually we have one but because we created this little function I did to just find out if we have a
news Nazmi we're not admen we have to create two statements.
So what I want to do is I want to first of all before we go to the next line.
We don't want to say we want to get everything we want.
We want to specify what we want out.
So I'm going to specify the idea believe this below here would give me an idea what I need so I need
all of this feels okay.
So I don't want you to see me typing in so I did super fast you so that OK.
So basically what I did is I'm selecting every column here that I want to get out of my database OK
or the columns or the information that I want out later on of course because this is going to be going
to be fetching data on this case.
Sometimes we need to insert data.
So we would do the same thing but of course we change our queries right.
But anyway.
So this is statement number one.
And now we need to create them in number two what I'm going to do with them.
Number two is I'm going to copy everything to this point here and I'm going to pace stay there.
Now we have two conditions here.
We first check checking to see if the category is the same.
We replace it with a question mark and we do the same thing with this privilege static string which
we are going to be putting in a variable here because one good thing about previous statements that
it doesn't take strange in some of the functions so we need to make it a variable polish and we're going
to use this later.
You're going to see where I show you.
OK so we're doing pretty good here.
Now let's replace this let's just replace it from here and here.
Make sure that we wrap it.
Make sure that we put our connections here and make sure that we have a variable here.
Now because this is statement number two we get to make sure that it is tainment number two there.
OK so we are done with this on the next lecture.
I'm going to show you some of the functions that this uses because we're not done here.
OK we don't we can use the same functions again.
We have to use different functions since we're using a different type of format of the API of my obscure
lie.
I'll see you in the next lecture