Hi my dear students.
I told you I care.
So I'm gonna give you some tips that are going to help you finish this course successfully.
The first one is make goals for yourself.
If you don't make goals there is no way that you are going to know where you really are going and if
you don't know where you're going how you are going to get there.
So make goals for yourself for example today you want to make a goal.
Let's say you want to do one video today or maybe you want to do one video daily.
That's 30 videos a month.
Within a couple months you finish a course.
If you want to finish it faster you'll do two or three videos daily.
Maybe you do 10 videos daily depending on what type of time you have.
But make sure you write it down.
If you don't write it down all right.
You might forget and you might not really do anything on the day.
Another thing that I want to also tell you is that make sure that you do something daily even if it's
one minute of one video.
We'll make sure that you do something daily.
I want you to do one thing.
Think about it we sort of this course.
Think about what you can achieve once you learn GHB and once you are able to build a CMA system.
Are you going to be able to make more money in your jar.
Maybe find a new job and have a new car maybe get Mary maybe buy your wife or your girlfriend your boyfriend
a really nice gift.
Maybe your mom your family.
Think about it we sort.
Think about the positive things you're going to be able to get with this course that's going to keep
you motivated.
Another thing that I want to tell you is that believe in yourself nobody else is going to believe in
you.
If you don't believe in yourself make sure that you really believe in yourself that you can do it or
you have to do is make goals for yourself.
Stick with him.
Think about the resorts all the time.
Another one last thing that I want to tell you.
All right.
Make every minute count of your life all right.
Your day is not going to come back to you again.
If your days gone why do you do with that day.
All right.
Think about that you our time here on this earth is very short but it is very short because we don't
actually take advantage of it.
We waste a lot of it doing nothing.
We give up too easily.
We need to stick with whatever we want in life and we need to keep going until we achieve it.
I'm pretty sure if you follow these rules right here you're gonna be able to finish his courses as fully
and he's going to change your life because he has changed my life and I want to transmit my changes
to you my knowledge to you so that way you can also be successful not only in this course but in life
in general.
Make every minute count do something today stick with it and know you are busy because we are or are
busy right.
But make sure that you are busy in the right things in the things that are going to get you to where
you really want to go.
I really look forward to seeing you at the end of this course saying you know what instructor.
Thank you.
I finish of course successfully and this has changed my life.
I want to thank you for watching this lecture and I want to thank you for taking my course.
See you in the lectures and take here.