All right welcome back.
I'm a student so on this new section here we're going to be we're going to start refactoring.
And for those of you that don't know what are we factoring is refactoring is when we grab complex code
you know very complex code or you know a long cold from our email.
I'm going to show you in a minute we have a lot of code in this and it's that BHB so we grab all these
code and we make it into a function and we make it even smaller pieces and you know even with the same
functionality or even with better functionality.
So let's inspect this in there so that we having admin which is crazy with a lot of code.
A lot of Ph B as you can see we have a lot of queries here for each of these individual boxes and these
queries are basically the same thing right.
They were they doing is they're returning the count of the record in the database of the table records.
They're doing the same thing.
We can create a function that would take some parameters and return to count of that specific table.
Look at this here.
So let's start working on it real quick and let me show you how we're going to do this.
So the first thing that I want to do is I want to grab all these cold out a year or I am going to call
it say or control it go to functions up BHB And remember we bring in the index of BHB of admin.
All right.
So let's go to functions and right below this on a pool full function or whatever function you got there
we're going to create another function and we can call this function record count.
Right.
Then we go and this space are called in there.
Whoops.
All right.
We're going to take a parameter.
It's going to be the table name.
That's all we need because that's what we got here.
All right.
And then we'll put the variable here like this.
Now go back here we have a couple of things that we've got to take out.
If I can find where I was that would be nice.
There we go.
All right let's just take this.
We're going to need is very one a minute but let's just take that the piece base there and name every
sold
and we can even use a function confirm Querrey to make sure that our Riso goes through them.
If we if he doesn't go through he's going to give us some type of error that we can check.
And then here we have to do is return it.
All right we're going to return sort result like this in there if you can even make this smaller if
you want and you can put stuff inside functions you know and make it like that.
But I'm just doing it like this so that it's very clear to you and while we are doing it right.
Very simple so we can return this whole thing if we wanted to and you don't even need this function.
Right.
You can just return and save yourself a lot of lines of code like that.
He can even go further.
But I wanted to make like this so that way you know exactly what we were doing.
So we save it and then we grab this and paste it right here and now we are searching for their own account
in the polls table.
All right.
We can grab all of this if we wanted to take all this BHP out of here.
It does pry open another BHP tagging Here in it out like this.
All right we well the whole thing.
We need these polls calmed down here so that's what we're going to keep the very well we need it all
the way down here somewhere.
All right.
We're using it right here.
So we're going to keep it.
All right.
So we're going to save it and they will go back to our
moves.
I think I have an error somewhere on line too.
Twenty eight in functions.
Let's just check real quick with saved.
Come back here refresh.
All Not now that we make sure that you have is you a global connection.
Right.
Because we are using the connection right here the database connection save it.
Let's see we are good to go now.
All right so it looks like he's working we have a number eight.
And if we wanted to search let's say the common stable.
Let's go back to it.
That's we can say comments right here like this.
Save it.
Make sure you save your file.
Come back here and save it and refresh and look at I changed to one.
So we are able to check for each individual table that we won we won function.
That's really cool stuff right.
We don't have to repeat ourselves so much so now we can come here and paste that code in there and just
make this mortar.
All right.
This is the comment.
This update is to post
fools and just do the same thing for.
This is the users.
All right so I'm basically doing the same thing all of them just changing the table name.
This is categories
categories.
It is save it come back here and refresh.
And the last one there is we're missing a..
There we go.
All right is breaking our cold and the reason why is breaking is because those variables that I was
talking about.
All right.
We're missing those variables so make sure that you have those variables and have to go back here real
quick and know what a variable that you know very well that this is category.
So they're all going to be coming down category kown and all that.
All right.
So make sure you have those variables here that you changed this disease category count
is it.
This is where we count like that.
The last one is categories.
All right so don't make the same mistake I just made and this is the users.
So user user account.
So we got an coming can't
save it.
They see this when these users account my data helps me.
Yeah because I already have the same variable the way when the bottom so that's why my editor is auto
completing this stuff for me.
So refresh.
And now you can see that it works 100 percent.
All right.
Beautiful.
So there you have it.
We've refactor a lot of stuff.
And the next thing I guess would be to refactor this year so we've got to go to the next lecture and
work with a little bit because I think this is a lot of cold here and we don't need it.
All right.
Another thing is make sure that you comment your code.
And explain to you explain what you are doing because you might come back in a couple of months and
do not know what the heck you did on his line right here.
So I don't call me my code because it would take me twice as much to complete the lectures and this
course is very long.
So just come in your code and you're good to go.
All right.
Of course I just wanted to show you that Bill we created this function.
So you want to start commenting your code.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture I have fun