I will come back on this video here.
We are going to be learning about as an injection and you might be asking yourself why in the world
is Escuela injection as well.
Well it's a technique basically that people use attackers to attack our applications on the Web for
example.
They can come here and put a statement here for example something like this and they say drop table
and something like this.
Right.
So they use a statement like this and they can go ahead and when they submit that that can go into our
database and it can actually delete the database you know.
Now there are many of these techniques out there they can do a lot more than this.
This is just a little stretch on the surface these people.
That's what they do every single day.
They look for techniques to attack on your web sites and they will destroy you.
They will show you applications.
Now this really here is just to help you clean out some of these data.
Sanitising And how are we going to do that will BHB actually made a function for us called my ask well
I underscore real scale the string.
And what a Funches going to do is going to just going to clean things up.
Right now if you go to this little application that we made here and you say something like Edwins courses
are great for example right.
And you put this little Komer right there right.
And you put some tatts and you you're trying to create that director is not going to allow us.
And that's because we're not scaping this you see.
So right here this application right now is very proem for that for people to attack.
They can come here and put in an Easter statement and they could delete all databases right in tables.
So to prevent it let's go ahead and do something.
So I'm going to go and let's go to functions on under my S Q L directory under that directory go there.
You show out of my school folder and go there and go to functions.
All right.
So what we want to do is we want to clean up the data before we go to the database.
So we want to clean up the user name because that's what we're using in the create application we've
got there right is user name field and it's PP-ASEL field other two stream fields.
We got we need to clean them up.
We need to sanitize them scapes some strings before it gets to the database.
So how we do that is by going to go to that function right here.
So the way we do that is by cleaning this up and the way we do that it's actually used a function that
BHP offers us and we are going to be using the same user name I said my if I let me just type the function
first.
So you could see my Eskew L..
I remember this is there is a mass my.
Q Well out there but that's the old version or I were using the new version just to.
This is what we've been using all this time all righteous for your information scape and string.
There we go.
So this is a function here that is going to help us out.
And I'm just going to type it again.
You will copy and paste it there and it's got to take two parameters.
First it's going to take our connection variable right here.
OK.
And we don't need this.
Actually I was just going to show you that in these two parameters.
And the second parameter would be where you want to clean where you want escape right there.
So then I'd do two for the user name one for the boss or another one coma and then put the password
there.
OK.
And I'm also going to assign it to a to this variable here so like that and the user name also.
So that way we can use that variable right here for when he goes he is already sanitiser right.
So
let me just make it bigger so you can see what I'm doing.
All right.
So we got everything going here which is good.
You see what I did.
So I use this function here to escape all the data inside that field.
So when we have coal miners or any type of other parentheses or any type of data they're going to clean
it up for us and we're going to make a nice need to go in here.
So once we clean it up here with this function then I must sign in the same function back to the user
name so that where we can put it inside the database to here and using the same thing for the password.
All right so now we should be good.
Now if I try to do that create that Colma that I did with Edwins great coarse string which should work
now.
So let's try Edwins great courses are great right.
Some pass where you're going to click Create and you see how it works.
Now I can go to the database should be there.
Let's go to the database.
Should be I'm a Ph.D. my admin right there.
All right.
So as you can see here says those courses are great.
We can check.
You can check that it is working by just going back to the functions and
we can come and go and you can see that we can try to again just to make sure and just try something
else.
Peters we go create when we get this error.
All right.
And this comment is I like to try things a couple times just to make sure and then just go to that far
again and try Peeters create recreate it refresh.
We gather record here clean up.
All right.
So all of this stuff is going to affect or as Cuil our database and tables inside as my eyes.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this.
Hopefully this will help you make your application a little bit more secure.
And thank you.
I'll see you the next lecture