Hi welcome back and congratulations for making it this far I'm so happy that you made it.
Now before we go any further you need to understand a couple of things.
First is what is a class in O.P. and what is Olby will all be means object oriented programming and
a class is just a blueprint or definition or description of something inside your program.
Now classifies two things for this something.
It defines the properties of this something and it finds the methods that properties can be variables
arrays or any type of data for the methods we have functions that create behaviors for this thing that
is that the class is describing now.
So I can't describe what exactly what is this thing that you were talking about when you're not telling
me a knob just right and I know it is just a group of data put together by a common theme an object
can be a variable.
It can be a function the could be any data structure inside your program.
I know it could be a little confusing right but let me just give you a couple of examples.
Actually one example of an object.
Let's say for example we have a car object right for this car.
Now keep in mind that the objects in programming are very similar to the objects that we have outside
on the real world.
So for this car object we are going to define some properties let's say methods.
Let's say we have for this car my property could be wheels the wheels of the car right.
It could be the seats that could be a prop..
What about the radio that could be a prop. I mean the car has thousands of pieces right we have a lot
of properties for the car.
And just to give an example of the methods or the functions or the behaviors or I don't mean the same.
We have the wheels.
Let's say we moved a wheel that could be a method of this object move the seats.
Right.
That could be wanting if you have one of those cars that have electric seats that could be one what
about turn on the radio.
That also could be a method function behavior of our car.
All right.
The Bennet's of the benefits of using O.P. or object oriented programming are many.
It provides code organization they provide less complex you know functionality well not functionality
more complex functionality with less complex code.
All right we have more interaction within our code easily if we wanted to we were methods you know and
properties you know our code would be more muscular meaning we can change objects or groups you know
within our code without affecting other pieces of code in our program.
Right.
I mean the benefits are many if let's say for example we have we have a company right in this company
we have a lot of programmers working in a project.
We could have each programmer work in a different object of that program and none of the programs are
not the objects will conflict with the main program you see.
I mean we can separate our program into little objects we have that have the form object we can have
the navigation object we can have the header object that food or object and we can many different people
working on those modular pieces or objects and you know they would never affect each other annoying
object oriented programming is a benefit.
And on this course here I'm going to introduce you to it and I'm going to explain a couple of things
to it.
We're going to be using it a little bit on this section here but I want you to grab the major idea on
what it is.
So that way you are more prepare to start coding in object oriented programming.
Right.
It's going to be super easy the way I explain it.
And then hopefully you understand it if not for some reason you have a question.
I'm here 24/7.
You can e-mail me.
You can contact me and I can show you the way Jorge.
But anyway I want to thank you and again congratulations for making it as far as you and I love this
section.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.