Hey Guys welcome to this new section.
This new section I'm going to show you how to create a really cool like functionality for post pages.
All right.
So now I'm going to go.
I'm going to show you.
So I mean the front page right here I got the first folds.
OK I'm going to click into it and if I go down a little bit after the content we can see that he says
that he has two likes.
Awesome right.
So I'm going to go to the front page again I'm going home and going to visit the second post.
And he says he has three likes.
OK.
So he says also that we need to log in so let's go ahead and log in to be able to like this polls and
let's do it.
Let's go to the home page let's go to the first one here.
And he says that he has two likes.
So he says if I pull my mouse over it is going to tell me that I like this before so that's a really
cool functionality there.
But he also gives me this thumbs up by in here that I can click to like it.
So now when I click on like you can see now that we have the like word here OK change I mean the only
two to like.
And how one likes.
OK.
Really cool stuff.
So let's go to the second one.
And on the second pause here you can see that he has three likes.
He looks like this user like this before so he says I like did this before I click on like and now we
have two likes.
So let's go to the front again and we can see now that this one has one like and the other one has two
likes.
Awesomes is keeping track of the user likes not only this but it keeps track of all the users.
So if this post gets like that thousand times he will reflect right here and he will also detect that
this specific user is logged in like tipples really awesome.
Now it looks very simple but I'm going to show you how to.
I'm going to make it simple for you but it's not that simple.
OK.
But once you know it of course it's going to be a breeze for you to do this in any of your projects.
So if you guys are up for it let's learn how to do this.
And let's have some fun.