So how you guys did you guys did it right.
And one of the reasons I let you do your things also is because I when I don't want you guys to be forgetting.
OK.
So let's go ahead and do this.
I want to fetch.
So I'm going to fetch a resoled which is going to be that probably that user's right.
So users like that and I actually do my ask you a lie fetch re And I'm just going to get the Resul here.
So that's going to be users or the user like that because we're not looping through this like we're
not you know we just won one resoled back.
OK so if we can use my obscure lie number those we pass in the result and we say if you find more than
one than or equal than one we want to return something what is it that we want to return exactly the
user ID.
Simple that.
So user id OK.
So let's test this and let's return false here
OK.
Make sure that we return falls.
Just in case this is natural.
We don't get the user ID
right.
So how can we test this.
Well instead of testing the whole speech we can create another file here I'm going to create a BHP file.
I'm going to call this terse and I'm going to put this function right here.
But before we do that I need the header and the include for the database.
Actually I don't need a database but I don't think I do include that
right here.
And
that function is going to return either.
Actually my fax we can just echo this out
and call like that in.
Tests.
So I am already logged in.
I think let's see yeah.
So if I go to just up HP it says Can Starcastle in your head is already being send this because I got
spaces right here.
So make sure you've got no spaces.
We go and you can see that the logged in user is twenty six.
OK don't believe me we go to the 26 ID there.
OK.
That's the long user.
So as you can see we are getting that which is really awesome.
Now if we now know Dan
OK let's go back to or see a mess Ogowe and let's school again BHB.
We don't get nothing OK just because it's false.
OK.
So you can put some type of condition we're going to use later on.
So that's it we're done.
See you in the next lecture and where we are going to be detecting.
And you know changing a lot of the cool things in the link.
See you then.