All right.
So welcome back on the last lecture here.
We are catching this information this data from here right from the select.
Now we're going to do something with it remember this name actually with its value here is coming from
the values in each of the options.
So each of these options have to have some type of value for us to catch you.
Right.
If not we're going to be catching this is going to be empty right here.
So we need to provide a value.
So the first one is if it's nothing there was going to be the default for this action was going to be
there.
Well I don't want nothing to be that the fault.
To be honest with you.
All right.
So we've got to leave that empty for publish.
We're going to just say publish is going to be that is the value that we go draft.
Of course draft without a capital D and the elite is going to be deadly.
Right.
So just to test this real quick we can echo this hour right here.
And let's go back to it.
Let's check it out.
If I click here and click apply.
All I got to click one of the options publish apply.
You can see that it is saying that and if I click draft you can see that is changing.
All right so we are receiving those values.
Perfect.
So now that we got this we need to do another major thing here.
Right.
And basically it's a condition the best way to do this actually is because we only have one variable
that we've got to check.
Remember this bulk option changes every time that loops around you see every time we select that looks
around so every time we select one of these if I select publish it we have this value right here and
this value is being carried by book options.
All right.
So if I select this one on the Select right here draft it will have this value.
But remember we are receiving it with the bulk option so we can use this in a switch statement because
switch statement only they only take one condition right.
We are we only comparing one condition against multiple cases.
So the switch they may I think is a perfect candidate for why we want to do.
All right so what we want to do inside is for each loop we want to create a switch statement.
So let's to switch
here statement let's do this real quick and what we want to check is this bulk options.
So we want to say this for options is has a case that is equal to something.
Remember the case keyword publish in this case
published.
Right.
A does right now then we put the call in there.
We want to do something with it.
This put the break there so we don't forget the break key word breaks.
So if it finds this it doesn't continue doing anything else remember that.
Well we want to do is actually do a Querrey because if it's select a publish we want to be able to update
that post right.
So if you want to do an update query here go ahead and do that.
All right.
Pozieres video into it and try to see if you can do it yourself.
So we got to all day posts.
Right.
And we're going to set what the pool status.
That's what we're setting right now equals to what I'm going to give you a chance so you can do it yourself.
You ready.
Baalke options right we already have them here.
When I use it.
All right.
So and we need to make sure that it is related to that specific idea.
So we're going to put where post ID
equals what we are going to give another option what what is it.
Check of value.
Remember that.
Right.
And of course we don't need.
Remember this is always carrying the ID already.
All right.
And we can name it differently if you want.
We can name it check but false ID value if you want.
Just so it doesn't confuse you.
Remember that's what is bottes.
That's what we're sending in this box and we are sending it right here right here on this.
Here you see the post ID right here.
That's why we're sending in disarray every time we click on this select every time we click on it and
we submit the form we are sending that ID there on that Ira.
So if you want to name it like that that is fine.
That's as a matter of fact let's do that.
All right so let's say polls.
Let's check these polls I.D. polls.
Value I.D..
All right.
So that way
right.
So I think it's better like this.
Right.
All right old value ID.
Or you can say post ID if you want.
It's up to you.
I just wanted to name it differently there.
All right so once we have that then we need to send a query in.
Right.
And just organizing my query and my query a little bit there making sure that everything is fine.
Book options where.
All right.
So it's looking good.
Let's just make it bigger so you can see it again below here.
I'm going to send the query update publish
the Post publish status of day to publish
status.
All right.
And my ask you lie.
We're got to do the same thing to the rest of them.
So if you want to go ahead in and start doing that you can basically we are going to be making cases
comparing it to publish draft delete and do end queries depending on what is needed connection and then
Kohary.
All right so let's go ahead and try this out.
I think we're ready to go.
Let's just put a dollar sign there.
I mean in mind is a little bit of data published status and then break.
All right.
So let's go ahead and check this out.
Let's make one of these draft.
I should I think we could have done it from there.
Whoops.
Right.
We can do it from there.
Let's just make a draft of the post and it more post.
Let's click here and less click on draft.
Actually we don't have the draft we only have publish it.
We can make it public.
I'm sorry.
Right there publish apply and it's not doing anything right.
Publish apply.
We need to make sure that we have this spelled correctly.
We want to make mistakes.
So and then we want to also make sure that the square is being submitted because what if the square
is failing right now we don't know that it is failing.
We don't have any mistake right here.
So we want to use that confirmed Querrey function.
All right.
Just to make sure that we are not missing this query up.
All right let's check it out.
We might have a Kohary mistake somewhere publish apply.
You see that you have an arrow in your syntax neir line this one that wasn't too much help was it.
All right so we're at least we know we have a problem right here somewhere.
So let's check it out.
Buzz value.
All right.
So we have all day polls.
We have that good here then full status.
This is right then bulk options.
And this is correct.
Actually there were posts ID and that looks good to me equals
right here.
We need a dollar sign right there.
All right.
Perfect.
That's what we're messing up.
See that.
That's why he's always good to put that function there that we made of the custom function.
So let's try right now and let's click on publish apply.
As you can see is working.
Apply yourself.
You were able to do it with me.
Great job.
I think we are doing something really nice right so we can also let's do this real quick and let's make
this draft we make a draft.
OK.
At it more post made this one draft to at least try both of them at the same time write and publish.
Boone look at that.
Beautiful.
All right.
So next we're going to be adding some more functionality some more queries and then I think at the end
we're going to add the functionality that some javascript's here so you can select everything at the
same time.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture was a pleasure like always and I see you on the next
one.
Take care.