Welcome back and my this student This is Edwin from the future and I'm back here just to help you to
prevent some mistakes in the future in your code.
All right.
So basically instead of replacing the lecture I like to make videos like this so that way you know that
I'm always helping you out that I'm always coming back and helping you.
All right.
So anyway next lectures we are going to be creating a logging update functionality right.
A UPDATE functionality.
So we need some keywords right here in this select element.
We need ID right here.
All right.
So in these name much of you in the value field we are going to be putting ID we need this in order
for us to update our database.
All right.
Because we need to send this value.
So make sure that you have this set right now.
All right.
And even though you might not see me having this in the next lectures don't worry about it just make
sure that you have a set right.
You don't need to remove this because we will use this anyway I want you to say hi to my husband from
the past and you will see many of me in the future.
All right.
So many versions of me will always come to the course and help you out with anything you need or any
mistakes we have made on the course.
This is a very big course and I keep adding lectures all the time so.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lectures.
Take care