Hi welcome back my students in this lecture here we are going to be refactoring your code that it'll
be.
We're going to be condensing a code making it into modular pieces.
All right.
Just like we did with custom functions that basically that's what we're doing right here.
We're grabbing a whole bunch of code and putting it into functions right.
We have our categories here working already.
All right.
So that's working.
And let's go back to our categories.
PH be right here.
So we got all this cold right here right.
You know we have a lot HD mail here too.
So refactoring is going to come very handy.
All right.
So we are going to be doing here we're going to be creating this this file call function that BHB which
is very popular and see a Messis.
So I just going I right click on admen I'm going to make this phone call functions that BHB enter to
open up ph BTX here.
And you should know this by now because you took those foundations when we started the course.
Right.
So I'm going to go back to categories.
I'm going to take all these cold data here like this.
Right.
And then it goes back to functions are going to create a function here called insert categories.
There we go.
And I'm just going to paste all that code in there and then I'm just going to grab this function here
name.
Go back to categories and place it right here.
Put a semicolon right here and the end of that BHB tag.
Condense my code a little bit more this way.
And now we have a beautiful piece of code here which is the name of the function calling our functions
right.
With all the functionality behind the scenes.
So now he says called on the Find function insert categories or let's make sure that we save our functions
of BHP far right here.
All right.
And come back again.
Insert categories like 40 something is going on there let's just check it out.
All right.
Make sure that this code is clean.
Here let's go back to categories of BHB and we have this should be all.
OK.
One thing that you should not forget which I forgot right now is that we need to include this file right.
We need to make sure that is available functions are BHB.
Right.
So go to your admin header inside your admin folders and make sure that we include this file right just
like this.
So we want this to be
functions that BHB.
All right.
And that's what it should be their functions and we are actually we are an admin and this is in psi
actually is inside.
And we go that's what it should be right there.
All right.
For those of you that don't have these Olby start function make sure that you put it right now.
All right this is something that we are going to be needing through our CMF this is going to star output
output buffering right.
You can look it up on the net.
So basically we're going to send some information in the headers and that's for more advanced users.
But just put this Olby start function right here just in case you don't have it.
So let's go back here and let's check it out.
Now it looks like he's working right.
Look at the ad category.
Then we can test three A to find connection.
All right.
All right one thing that we need to do.
Another thing that's good that I tested that out is that we need to bring our connection has to be global.
So we need to ride the global attribute Well the global right here.
And this is just going to make our connection very well global.
All right.
So make sure that you do that.
Now should work.
There we go.
Yes.
Three category and now we have another category they're working all right.
So make sure that you have your global here every time you're using a function and you need a variable
to be available.
Make sure you bring it in with the global keyword right.
Make sure that you include your BHB your function that ph be found here.
All right.
So make sure you have the Olby star function.
Also we are going to be needing that later on.
All right.
So we are going to continue.
Refactoring the rest of this.
And I'm just going to show you a couple of them and then you should be good.
And you should be able to do it yourself on your see a mess.
All right.
So thank you so much for watching this lecture and I see you in the next one.
Keep it up keep motivated this is going to take you super far in life if you apply the knowledge.
And I'm always here to support you.
Right.
Have a blessed day.
Bye bye.