Hi welcome back on this lecture here I want to show you how to add some javascript's so that way when
we click on this little check out check box we're everything else gets selected.
All right.
Now don't get scared if you never done javascript.
If you have you already know how to do this.
But if you don't know don't worry I can't help you.
And of course I also have a course in javascript that can help you understand javascript if you're interested.
The first thing that we want to do is go to our admen underscore Hetter.
All right and that's INSIGHT admin of course inside the folder includes.
So we're going to take this out here and we are going to be placing it on there under admin under the
score footer right below the Jake way that is here.
And the reason why we're going to put this on the footers because we want our scripts to be to load
after everything else on the page.
If you put your scripts on the header most of the time well all the time they're going to be loading
on the header and that's going to make your site your markup law a little slower a lot slower depending
on what you're loading there.
All right so once we have that let's just save it.
Let's go to the folder.
Yes.
I admin and they were going to find scripts.
Yes you say here we're going to add some javascript.
All right.
And what I'm going to be doing I'm going to show you right now if I go to View polls we're going to
be targeting this input right here with this ID and that is this heading right here.
What we're going to be saying javascript is when I click on this one here I want you to make all these
checkboxes true.
And by making them true of course they're going to be checked right by making.
Actually when I click on it they're all going to be checked.
That's what I'm trying to say.
And when I take it out they're all going to be unchecked.
All right.
So that's what we're going to be doing with Javascript.
So we got the idea that we're going to be selecting this with.
And we also have I go down to it if I can find it.
There are other checkboxes.
They have a class.
We're going to also target this class right here.
All right.
So now that we know what we're doing let's go ahead and do it.
First thing is we need to make sure that Jake where he's actually working so we're going to say document
got ready.
This is a function to load this functions after the document has being loaded.
So this is going to load every function after everything was loaded.
And I just want to say Hello there just to make sure that he's working.
It would not work since I have a dollar sign here Jake where he was not installed.
All right.
So if I refresh.
Whoops.
Looks like it did not work.
By the way what am I doing.
There we go.
Actually they work.
All right.
So now that we know he's working let's target that deadheading radio button there and we're going to
target it like this.
Sound it's going to be an I.D. call select all boxes and we're going to say something and add this all
the function here called Click.
So when we click on it something else is going to happen right.
That's all we doing right here.
I'm going to bring that down to put a parameter here call event.
And we're going to say we're going to put an if statement here because we want to check if it's checked
for us.
So this is checked then.
I want you to do something right.
What are we going to do is we're going to graph that little box that has a class of checkboxes.
Each of them have this class.
And we're going to iterate through and this is what each function is going to do for us.
All right.
So we can iterate through that object when I say function
then I bring this down a little bit and we make it make all these checkboxes true checked equals true.
All right.
This this key word means that if we are referring to this object.
That's what this is we're referring to this and this this is referring to this one.
All right.
That's where we use the key word.
This should be familiar with that.
Right.
So once we have that then here we're going to say else if it's not
if we do the opposite of it right we want to grab that and actually going to grab this whole thing again
right here.
And want to grab that and I'm going to make this false.
Right.
So that's that.
That should be able to help us out.
All right.
So let's go ahead and try that right now.
Hopefully I don't mess up because that was actually kind of fast right.
So I not refreshing here.
Putting my cursor there and clicking enter.
And then when I click on it he's working now right.
So everything selecting now we can go ahead and publish everything the send time.
And you can see that everything is published or we can go ahead and draft everything.
Look at that beautiful right.
Well we can go ahead and delete but I'm not going to delete right now.
To be honest of you we put a lot of effort into making this post right.
Why are we going to be the leading them.
Right.
We already know this is the way this works right.
But anyways I hope you enjoy this lecture here and we're going to keep adding some more features.
And it was a pleasure like always.
Thank you so much for giving me the pleasure of teaching you this.
And I see you in the next lecture.
Take care.