Welcome back my students in this lecture here we are going to be learning how to do a confirmation before
we delete any item via javascript and also BHB.
All right.
So some of you have e-mailed me and message me and asked me how to do this.
I'm going to show you in this lecture how easy it is to do this thing I think is very useful to have
this feature in or see a mess.
Right.
So there we go.
Now we are in post-up DHB and I'm just I just have one post here and the goal here is to when we click
delete.
We want to have these bots here appear.
Say are you sure you want to delete this message.
Yes or no.
Right.
And if we click Cancel or no then the message doesn't get deleted.
But if we click OK then it gets deleted from our database.
So let me show you how to do that.
Let's go I want you to go to View on the score.
All polls view on the score on the score postop BHB and for me it's going to be online 166.
It might be a different line for you.
All right.
And this is insane colludes right there.
Right.
So now what we need to do is and for those of you that don't know javascript make sure that you take
my jobs who of course is going to show you a lot of useful information with javascript.
If you are in what development you need javascript there is no way around it.
And to make it better that Jake where he course that I got will make your javascript more powerful.
All right.
But anyway so what we need to do we have an anchor tag right here.
This is the anchor tack that we use to send the requests.
Right.
To delete this.
So what we need here is to add some javascript so we can to add a function call or an event handler
right on click.
So we add its own click here so that means when we click on this link something's going to happen right.
Well what they do is escape this like this.
Right.
And we want to escape the other.
There we go like this now between here I'm going to write my javascript so I was going to say I'm going
to say Java script right.
And we could say return turn and then we're going to use a function from javascript is going to be called
to confirm this function is going to pop up a box right in the middle of your screen asking you you
know the questions so we can say whatever we want we could say Are you sure you want to delete.
All right.
So let's just make sure everything is right here.
OK.
So once we do that that's it.
That's all we've got to do.
There's nothing else that we've got to fix here.
We wrote javascript everything should be working according to plans.
Let's just save it.
You see how easy that was.
Right.
So now we refresh here and we click delete.
And we're going to ask us are you sure you want to delete this message right.
Well it doesn't say Massachusetts's delete right.
I'm going to cancel.
And nothing gets deleted.
But if I click again and I say OK then this post gets deleted.
All right and I just figure out your same message.
All right.
Don't mind me.
Disregard that message word that I just said All right.
But anyway here you go.
Now you can add this functionality to anything you want.
I see a mess.
I think it's a very useful for anality thing for those students that suggest it is and I'm you know
every time you said you're suggesting I write it down and when I have time I'll add it to the CMOS.
All right.
So remember we had the on click.
Make sure that is capital right here.
All right.
That's the best way of writing it.
And then escape your double quotes and then write javascript Kallen and then returned the confirmed
function with some strings in there.
All right.
Perfect.
And make sure that you scaped here also.
So anyway there you have it.
For those of you that one of these functions I think you got it.
Your instructor cares and I want you to learn more and more every single day.
So keep motivated keep doing the course you're doing a very good job if you got this far and you're
awesome.
Thank you.
And I see you in the next lectures