All right so we were able to update this field here every time we go and make a comment right on this
specific post.
Now there is no need to do anything else here.
A few refresh.
You see that this is going to change to a different number now.
We are already displaying using that data that function in the view old posts.
So let's go ahead and check on that right now.
So we go to View Post.
All right.
We can see that we are already right have to pull the data coming out.
We are already echoing that data both coming count and that's the same color that we have in our database.
All right.
So we don't have to worry about that anymore.
Now what I will do on this video here is we're going to be adding two more columns right here.
Well two more Littlefield's says this doesn't look right.
So let's fill it up a little bit and add those two.
So let's go to the top here and we really have come in St. Louis add edit and delete.
All right.
I think we're doing really good progress on this.
See a mess.
All right.
So let's go back and we have the edit and delete right there.
All right so perfect.
I think we're doing a pretty good job like I said before we are all dating all this automatically.
And if you wanted you can just delete it and you can start from scratch about this and he will do it.
Now if you have this problem that you have to click twice here to actually update these posts.
Right.
The reason is because we need to refresh this page.
So that's another thing that I want to do right now.
Let's go to your post and cussing out meaning includes.
All right so let's let's go ahead and fix that little little bit of piece of coal that we need to fix.
Let's go to the delete.
We should have the lead right here from this is the lead.
And all we have to do is do the header and let's send the page again to the same you or else so he does
so he refreshes right.
So every time you have a problem there you're not seeing the change automatically in the page just refresh
it just do this function here and refresh it.
All right.
So now if we add another pulse they just delete this one.
Let's just refresh it here.
Whoops
sorry
it's actually pose to go to post again.
Who's right there.
Location pulse.
All right.
So with the leader here you see that that change happening automatically.
Now of course we're going to have to have some more polls and get it done and practice some more right.
But anyway I think you had enough of this lecture here and hopefully you're enjoying the course and
if you have any questions I'm here 24/7.
All right.
Thank you.
And I see you the next election.