Hi welcome back my student in this lecture here I'm going to show you how to get your certification
for the course.
This is very simple.
Once you are done with all the lectures you're going to have this checkmark right here in green.
All right.
Well actually it's a little green circle with a checkmark inside with a white checkmark.
You're going to have this for all your lections right once you finish a course.
Make sure that you have all of them checked and was all or all of them are checked.
Then you're going to get this little trophy right here.
All you have to do is just click anywhere here.
So that way you can select the page and pull your mouse over and click it once you click.
You're going to get the certification page and all you got to do is download it to your computer if
you want like this.
And you can download as a JPEG or a PTF and then print it out and that's it.
All right.
But make sure that all your lectures are completed.
They all have to be completed 100 percent for you to get this little trophy right here.
All right.
But anyway that's it for you for this lecture and hopefully you enjoy this course.
Thank you so much for for allowing me to be your instructor.
And don't forget to always leave reading my review just to show you instructor that you care also.
All right.
So take care and I see you in the next course.
Bye bye