All right so we got a lot of functionality in our site.
If you go to admen you can see right here we have new polls we can edit the lead.
Do a lot of things on it.
We get categories.
But what we don't have is in the home side right now.
Before we move to another section we need to.
When we click on this post we need to go to that specific content right to that specific post when we
click on the title or the image or whatever.
Right now we click on it.
If I wanted to go and see that the rest of the content right now even though we don't got much we don't
do that.
It just refreshes right.
So we need to add the functionality and we need to add the functionality of the blog categories there
that when we click on it goes to that specific category and we show you everything related to that category.
But we haven't done that yet.
So what we need to do is we have a post page that I want to show you and we did that in the beginning
if you remember that's like a placeholder page.
It's called pulls up.
And this is what we're going to do use for individual posts.
We want it.
I want to copy everything from it and put it here since we have the sidebar that says the cyber is the
same.
The header and footer are the same and some of this information is the same.
I'm just going to copy and paste it here but I want to preserve the comments section.
So we're going to take that off before we do that.
Copy and paste it and paste.
So let's go to line one or two on the post.
BHB which is in the same root as the index in the home page.
And let's go all the way down to divs below that nested comment section right here.
You see this comment that says that nested to this below just command Edzo control at it that's going
to be all that's the comment section.
Let's go to a new page.
Let's face it let's leave it there for now.
Let's go back to that.
Let's select everything.
That's copy it go to post select everything and paste it.
So now we have everything here we want to do a couple of things here first we want to
detect that you are able to get requests when we click on days we want to send a request to post that
BHB and catch us somewhere so we can detect the specific content from this just like we're been doing
in the back just like we did here in the View Post.
We click here we send a request here and we display some information we got sent in there and we're
going to be detecting this I.D. right here of this specific post or whatever post.
Right.
So before we do that let's go back to that title which is that section of the common that we are holding
let's assume command or control a and select everything and go back to post below the loop right here.
Let's just base this whole thing in there make sure we have that.
All right.
Perfect.
So here we want to display everything but we need to catch that somewhere.
So first let's go to end it.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
It's got to end this and let me show you what I'm talking about right here.
Here we need to get the idea from this from all the polls.
Right.
So right now we're getting all the titles that get all the IDs right here and post I.D. right here and
all here on the tide what I want to do is I want to make a link to postop DHB and I want to pass a parameter
that parameter that I'm going to pass is that P on the score ID and that is the key of the array of
that get super global for the IDs right.
And then I say equals and it's going to be this pause ID variable right.
So remember what I'm what we're doing here.
But as a matter of fact before we do that before we put this variable here we need to have a let's just
take that off a BHB right there.
BHB tag.
And we need to echo with the polls ID.
All right.
Make sure that you Agway because if you don't actually it doesn't work.
So hopefully you know what we are doing.
All right.
We are sending when people click on this title.
It's going to be right here actually on the front of the Web site.
We're going to set a parameter in there you are.
And that parameter is going to be the P on the score I.D. equals the idea of the post.
And that's the same I.D. that we got right here.
When we click on it you see this idea right here that's the ID of the post.
That's exactly what we are doing right now.
Every time somebody clicks there.
Right.
So we need to catch this before we even make it work.
So let's go ahead and catch it in the side real quick.
Let's go to the polls that BHP and let's catch it right here.
So we're going to say if set what is set can you guess before I put it in here.
What are we checking for again.
And remember the key of one of this array right on this score what the.
Remember that.
Don't forget.
And we are going to convert.
This is the key you remember and we were referencing the value of each of the polls when it's clicked.
Don't get confused.
Remember you are in the loop.
So post ID.
This is very easy to get confuse.
In the end it's because you are here in the loop.
All right let me show you.
Remember here.
This is the looping It's right here.
So this is looping through all the data in our post table.
And every time he looks around he grasps one of the ids from that specific post and he will sign it
to whatever element we use.
So let's say the first time it runs through e-zines they I.D. to one post and then when we click on
that here and on the front page they say for example here it was signed the I.D. to this content right
here because that's where it is at the moment.
All right.
So right now the first go around is going to be on that say Edwin Diaz Posetti 28.
The image black whatever the first time around it will be on my post the second time around.
It would be who says Post.
And the idea would be different.
The Post order would be different that they would be different or the image would be different.
Right.
Every time I go around all these content changes to a different post.
Remember it's a loop.
Remember we have the wild looping here right so get that straight.
So let's go to that post up here B.
And we are catching it right here but we need to make a condition right here because we are displaying
all the polls right here on this page just like we do in the end it's well we don't want to do that.
We want to say where post ID which is the column in our table equals what he calls the ID we are catching
in the L right here.
OK.
There we go.
And we can actually name it differently so that way we know what's going on.
The post ID.
All right.
And Seven Corners here actually in the second corner with us to ask you.
Perfect.
All right so let's see if it works.
Let's see if our invention works right.
So less refreshing clicking and we click on it and we get that page right here.
You see the switch but you don't see it.
If I click on it post up BHB I.D. And let me show you that it works.
I'm going to go to another one that is different.
And then right now you see we are on the home page if I scroll up and down with my mouse I get all the
posts.
If I click on this you go to it goes to the 31 if I scroll down we get the comments section.
So we are displaying individual posts now.
Right.
And we at the same function I add to the picture the functionality to the picture.
All right if you wanted to we can create a link.
We can go to edit and create a link around that picture and send it to that post.
Very easy to do.
As a matter of fact if you want to do it go ahead and do it.
I'm going to leave it there just to make it simple.
And for some reason you have any problems watch this video again.
Make sure you get it.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching.
See you in the next lecture