I welcome back my students.
So this lecture here is to kind of answer a request that I have from one of you guys this particular
student your classmate was asking me how can I make this visible only to the user that is actually creating
it or actually have created it.
Well it is very simple remember that we have already a user right when we log in when we register a
user we are setting sessions.
I remember that we set a session called username and that's what we're using here to display this.
So all you have to do is display this content or it is data for that particular user.
So let's let me show you an example how we can do this.
And you can apply this functionality to whatever you want in the sidebars here or top bar or whatever
to any part of your project.
OK.
So this is not set in stone.
Remember we're always trying to do is find out the identity of the user and we do this best by using
sessions or we can insert that data into our database.
Right.
But we're using data sessions in this.
And let's find out how to use that.
So in that particular area this is what I think is the view post.
So let's go to admin and includes your post here.
So we've got to find out where we are displaying the data and it looks like
this really doesn't matter because this basically is just updating the idea of that specific post.
OK.
So whatever post you are showing in that scream is going this is going to still apply.
You don't have to do anything else with it and you're going to see in a minute what I mean.
And let's see.
Oh I think it's right here.
This is a data.
So for example I know that my user name is Edwyn because that is what I'm using here and that's why
I'm actually seeing everything this because his admin.
Right.
So we're not putting any constraints here.
We could if we wanted to set something like this.
Well so all from polls where polls user I believe is Colomb feel equals to one marker and while we are
not going to see any difference here OK just because you see this go back actually less save and we
should see a difference.
This is not Etling is not the same as admin user.
There we go.
You see we see less posts here.
OK.
So this so you can do it.
Now we are just constraining here.
How can we find out the coring user.
Well I'm glad you were at there you ask.
We could if we wanted to create a variable here to haul that and we could just say it's a matter of
fact we have the user
Let's see.
Let me show you how to find it in the
in the session.
And that should be very simple to you.
Right.
And we can just say user name.
Simple as that.
And let's come back here.
Let's just replace here like that.
Save it let's call back here and we should see no difference.
As you can see everything looks the same.
Well now we can convert this and put it into a function or something right.
It's a matter of fact I think I already did.
Let me just come back here.
Two functions.
And as you can see I already have it done for you.
Let's check out how it looks.
So you can see we have the function current user and now we are checking here to see if that session
is set and this is the user name session right.
If it's set then we return that session if is now we return false.
But now can we use it here.
Well let's go back here and let's just do that and I'm going to use less use that function name comeback
here.
It's pretty easy stuff for you guys.
Come on.
And then instead of that we are using that right.
So that should work the same.
Now let's come back here and refresh.
And as you can see it still works and you can apply that to anything else you want.