Read before I start this lecture here you remember when we cancel when we come into Post.com and count
and we also took it out from here from the values make sure that you also take it out from here.
All right.
Because then we are inserting something that is not there and you're going to get an error just like
this I'm going to show you right now like that.
All right I try inserting a comment too at polls and you're going to get that error if you don't remove
that.
So make sure that you remove common count from the insert here and from the values here and from here
let's just remove that also there.
All right so that way you don't get this error here.
All right let's try to do that again.
Try adding a post.
All right.
And make sure that it works.
I haven't tested it right now and I'm going to do it live.
All right.
And it's going to put anything there and Javascript and some content.
Post that we went through.
OK.
So it works.
Make sure you remove that right.
So now anyways now that we can start the lecture what I really want to do is I want to be able to see
the polls depending on the status in the home page.
So if I go to the home page right here I can see the polls you see on draft of right still can't see
it.
So I don't want to display things there.
There our own draft.
All right so let's go ahead and get that feature now.
And we want to do is one to go to end it.
Actually
we've got to come back here any way too because we know we want to also make sure that nothing gets
done here.
This played all night in the insert.
But in the post section.
But anyway let's go to the inn that's on the root of those or the site right here in the case of BHP
and here when he says select from polls.
I want to say select from polls where status right is up for starters I believe is equal to what published.
All right.
So if we go to our let's go to our local polls BHP my admin.
Check out our column real quick.
See a mass post structure poll status.
All right.
So we go to this home site right now.
We don't see anything.
The post is not there anymore because we are filtering.
All right.
So what we need to do is have a back up there like if we can find this if it's not in status.
I want you to display something right.
I want you to display no polls here or something like that.
Right.
So let's think about how we can make that happen.
So right now we are picking up everything there.
And we're just displaying whatever's on Polish right we're not selling anything else.
But how can we test this.
You know if we don't have that information so why not just display everything from post and then when
we get this information down here and let's bring it down let's bring it out of the database.
And they say I don't mind if I let's just put it all the way in the end here so that we can look at
it better once we get it here for status
and for status right there.
Once we get this information here why don't we do a test and then display everything down there right.
And depending on that.
So we could say something like this once we are in the and this statement here and say if false status
is equal to or equal to may be published then I want you to go ahead and do the rest.
Right.
Or if it's
not equal to publish then do this echo something like maybe I don't know go
no post here sorry.
All right.
Like this and then else.
You know you do something else right.
So as we do the rest.
So we've got to put this else somewhere.
Let's go ahead and do that right now.
Let's do it right here.
Well this is we are inside the loop so whatever is just same thing basically here one belongs to the
if statement else.
So we've got esteeming right here.
And then the L's and then the loop here.
All right let's check that out and see how that works out.
There we go.
See no polls.
So now you can format this however you want.
You can Center it.
And as a matter of fact let's do it right now real quick.
It is really easy to do it when you have to use a class here like that center with his framework you
can use this class.
I think he will do it automatically for us.
There we go.
All right.
No polls.
Sorry.
So we can do that.
Or I just I just want to show you a good technique there.
So now let's go to AD may actually go to admin and let's change the status of this and it's changed
to published.
Now we of course want to make this dynamic there and bring it in from the from the database.
That way we don't have to be typing it all the time.
It's annoying right.
Let's go to the home site.
All the published polls started should be published now.
All right so the problem here is if is not equal to published then do it else display it.
All right.
So of course we don't fly we don't have the image here.
Let's get the image going there.
All right.
We we still have to do a couple of things to to see a mess and that will be probably in India.
There you go.
That would be an extra features OK.
So right now we're just concerned about building to see a mass later on Wistar you know making it better
fixing anything that's wrong with them.
Because when you're writing applications online before you deploy it you need to make sure that everything
is fixed that all the books are out of it and everything's working perfectly basically you know.
And then even though after you publish your content you see a mess out there on the Web you're still
going to find some errors and you still have to go back and fix it.
So this is an ongoing process of getting to you're him as better and better every single day.
All right.
And just you know extending it so hopefully you are enjoying the class and I'll see you in the next
lecture.
Take care