Welcome back my dear student in this lecture here I want to add disinflationary to that we have an edited
post right right here when we enter the polls we have this function idea where we can see we get this
information.
I want to add it to the ADD post section right here because we don't have anything like that right now
so let's go ahead and start working on that.
So the first thing that I want you to do is actually and I'm going to do myself is get this echo right
here.
All right we're going to use the same echo with the same strings.
We're going to use it in the post and then we're going to be placed in this.
Let me just fix this a little bit.
We're going to be placing this.
I mean the add on the score post up that way.
Right.
So after we create the pools and we get this information after we get this super global value here right
after the insert.
All right I'm going to be placing this call right here.
All right.
So we're going to say post created.
We're going to change that name there.
Right.
And we can view the post and we Cujus clicking added more pools.
All right.
So now if I try to to use this right now I'm going to try to use it just to show you what can happen.
I'm just going to say it's simple post and we can read whatever it doesn't matter a simple post and
alter one status publish in a name and then choose a file and just write some random stuff and click
publish.
We're going to get this undefined variable to post IDs just because we don't have the pulse ID.
So what we need to do here and this is different from the exit polls because in the exit polls we have
that I.D. available to us and this one we don't because we are creating a new record.
So what we need to do is the best idea here is to try to actually prove that last created ID the last
create a record ID and then use that.
All right.
And the way we do that would be is that we can use a function call my you a lie insert ID.
OK.
This function is going to pull out the last created ID in this table right in our database right here.
So we provide the connection that's a parameter that's what.
That's all it takes.
OK.
And then here we can grab this variable.
All right.
We can sign the function to this variable right here.
So now we have the last ID that we created right here.
Right now we can use that.
Let's go ahead and try doing that.
We can also create a query here and find out right.
We can also create and say you know what I want you to go into the database in and search for this ID
right.
We could do that but why.
When we have this function to do that for us.
Right.
So let's try to create another one example.
Was going to write whatever here and here and publish and then publish.
Then when we look at this from here we could see that it takes us to that record that was created right.
Beautiful.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture.
Hopefully we'll help you out in your journey and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care