Welcome back many students do you have an idea or request for this project that we're building now is
your chance to post it right here in this lecture.
Some of you I think most of you should have a right hand side bar on this specific lecture that you're
watching on the sidebar if you're going top.
There should be some tabs that you can click on to make a discussion on this lecture.
I want you to post your idea your requests right here and this lecture.
That way I can come and look at all the requests in this lecture.
I don't have to go and search for it all the way through the course.
So if you have a couple of seconds maybe a minute or two.
Or if you have an idea which is the main thing right.
If you don't have an idea then you can do anything right.
But if you have an idea please take a couple of seconds a couple of minutes to post it right here.
We appreciate it very much is going to help you is going to help your classmates and overall is going
to help me make everything better for everybody else.
So I want to thank you for being in this lecture for being in my course.
And I'm looking forward to see your idea your requests for this CIMS project.
Take care