All right so our searching engines is working.
We have dynamic data here from category's we have a polls right now.
Now that we finish this section here with a custom search engine Let's go and jump into the blog category
and we want to display some data there and hopefully we have time to this place and data here on this
lecture.
All right so let's go ahead and do this.
So we need to go back to sidebar while we are there.
I'm there.
So if you're not.
Make sure you are in sidebar and we need to go to where Actually this is search.
Let's go to a sidebar right here.
So we are this is a search area and below that is their categories Blug category as well and that's
find the end of that and this one has a long place there.
So right so what can we do here.
Let's first thing we will be doing is getting some ph being here.
We need to get a query going.
That way we can display some data from our database.
Now we do have a query if you remember and that is the category query.
We can go get that in the navigation size and go to navigation and we can see here that we have a little
bit here of this data so we're going to copy this.
We're going to take it back to the sidebar.
And I think I'm debating where to put these data and say Here let's just put it this is put some PH
BE TAXED for us.
Use the control Z or command Z to undo whatever mistake I make.
All right.
And as I do it while selecting it and pressing command right bracket or left bracket I can organize
data also like this.
All right.
On we will organize some of this stuff.
All right so we are selecting everything from categories and here we just going to make changes a little
bit.
Select select categories
sidebar.
I like to change the name of my query that way they are descriptive for what they are doing and that's
changed right here.
Also we're going to be displaying the category title there.
Actually yes that's what we're going to be displayed on.
We're going to put some posters in there also.
Well right now we're just going to display the category.
All right so the category will be.
And let's see.
We get some of these data here.
All right.
So we're going to have to turn off BHB again and get all this data inside there so that we can display
a categories right.
But we don't want to get the while loop around all of this because it's going to be duplicating the
whole Bhatt's want to be duplicating the Allied tax only.
So we're going to be put into a WHILE loop in there.
So let's go ahead and take that out.
Let's pull the WOW.
Right here.
Actually below the you well whoops this is right here.
Of course we're lose BHP tags again.
All right.
So
shall we fix that
title I think it's good already.
I mean we have everything we need right here right.
Oh we got to do is just delete this
and take this up with it a bit and we should be good to go right to have these data like this because
I want you to see it on the screen.
I have a really neat and nice for me.
But you won't be able to see as clear as you see it right now.
All right some of you I'm over the vices are why everybody to be able to see this.
So let's go ahead and check that out and see where we are if we see anything and if everything came
out good.
All right.
So let's go ahead and check it out.
Go to the front page.
So we have some categories right here as you can see bootstrap javascript BHB and Jawa.
They will display beautiful make this a little smaller.
And the reason I'm doing that so that way you can see that one is on the right side and the other ones
on the left side.
Right.
So we've got some categories in this plan already.
We're going to get some more.
All right so we might be displaying just some picture here on the right side later on.
But anyway I want to get this done here real quick.
I'm going to take.
Let's just see that this well right here.
So what I want to do as well is I want to be be this to be I want this to be like a widget that we can
clear whenever we want.
Right.
We can put some data or something.
So it's a matter of fact.
This is
this just take out the whole thing out of here and let's include it somewhere else.
BHP
this function include what do we want included we are in the clothes for this so let's just leave it
right here and let's call it widget widget up.
Be close.
That's it.
And I just want to make a fire and I'm going to call this widgets widget that ph be where you go and
just paste that in there.
That way we have this Widger here that we can do things with you know.
Right.
So I think we're done let's check it out to see if everything's working fine.
We don't have any errors.
So everything is looking good.
All right.
So anyways I think we're dealing with a category C or another trick I wanted to show you is that we
could limit this categories here by let's say let's limit it to three so that way you can see right
now showing 4 we can limit the categories by using another Kohary and where I we have to make an arc
where we just have to modify what we got.
So we were in sidebar and let's just see we were here right here and we were making inquiry right here
so select everything from categories.
Limit this limit this to three and see how that goes.
And as you can see we are limited into three results.
All right.
Just know that you can't limit them.
I'm not going to do that right now we probably do that later on when we have a lot of categories but
let's not set a limit for that right now.
We are displaying some data.
What I will erase is this right here.
Since we have no space for that right now let's just take that off and we might display the images here
later on or maybe some more categories.
All right but it's a matter of fact and you see just take this.
Well it's right here.
This one here and there.
So this divide this one's here
and let's just take it off take it off completely and we make this 12.
Let's make this stand all the way down to 12 sets means half and 12 means this is a column.
Great system we bootstrap and I have a course in that if you're interested.
So right now it's expanding all the way across this right here.
So our categories could be long as this.
All right.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care.