I will come back my student.
So I was playing around with the same mess that we got going on here.
And I notice that we don't have some type of fallback just in case we're not showing a picture.
So I said it will be nice if I feel some type of functionality that does that right we'd still have
a whole bunch of things that we can add to this and I'm going to keep adding as much as I can.
OK just bear with me.
So in that BHB we could if we wanted to come to the deadline where we are displaying the image and we
could write functionalities on top of this if statement or so on so or some type of 10 or every operator
here to display some type of placeholder maybe from our images folder here.
Just in case we don't have a picture I would say if not both image display is Ayles display the Paul's
image.
Right.
We could write that here.
But then that would defeat the purpose of having reusable code that we can use anywhere else.
So especially in the post page right we're not displaying anything there.
And we seem to have some type of issue there so let's actually right here is the post that is good but
if you go all the way to the bottom my Rowson diverse stuff here and there is no image here either.
So let's actually make this a little bit more re-useable by building or creating a helper function right.
That will help us do that.
So I'm going to be using one of these pictures as a placeholder but you're welcome to create your own
pictures or use HTP or place hold that it you know does show you how to do that in this course that
is some type of web site that you can use a placeholder image from their server but I prefer to have
something here for now.
OK.
So I'm going to go to functions admin right here and I'm going to add that function.
So let's just create this and then call this placeholder let's just call this image placeholder.
So until like that
and
of course this is going to take some type of image.
So I'm just going to say
and I'm going to set this to zero or two.
No it's just some type of default value here OK.
Just think.
So that way we don't have any problems.
So we could write in if they move here very simply say if not image
like that let's just put that not statement there.
Or if not M.H. then we are going to return
I'm going to use a placeholder in images like I said before.
Oh not in doubt one in the
in this file here.
I'm just going to say M.H. on this school or for it really doesn't matter.
You can use whatever you want.
Like I said before so I'm going to return that.
And if we do find a name a change is going to return.
Image itself.
OK it should be good.
So now if I grab this here come back to index and stead of this play.
Echoing that out there I'm just going to echo how the function will occur and I'm going to take the
post image here and then I pass it as a parameter.
OK so let's go back to the.
So this here make sure that this works.
Let's refresh it oh I have a problem here
of course.
Let's go back here.
Refresh
having some type of difficulty image placeholder we don't need this single currency.
As a matter of fact I just save the file.
It should be good.
We don't need to make an attack.
We are already inside quotes.
So let's refresh and there we go.
Now if I go all the way to the bottom you can see that we are displaying this as default.
If I go to this one year of course we are not.
So let's do that.
Let's use our function post aswell.
So I'm going to copy all this out.
And let's go to a post and let's see where that is.
I'm going to do a search here
file here should be.
Oh there we go.
That was easy to find.
And I'm going to piece that in there.
Let's go here and refresh.
And as you can see that we got we made this a lot more reusable.
Now I'm noticing something here we don't have our comment form.
Let's go back and see what's going on here.
OK let's look for then tag for that.
This is the where we are getting the idea for the post and an's was in there it's ending here.
I got three
oh ok I see what's going on so let's take one of these guys here and I believe this will fix the issue
right here.
So let's come back here.
Let's see this let's go back here and refresh and voila.
Commenting is good.
OK.
Perfect.
All right.
That would do it for this lecture guys.
Hopefully you know I was able to add something valuable to you to this course and I'll see you in the
next lecture.
Take care.