Or write perfect song the last video we were finally able to of day stuff from the database.
Right.
So we we did some creation and we did some updating now.
It's time for us to delete stuff from our database that there are certain things that we don't want
so let's go ahead and create something actually first.
And we're going to log in on the score create.
And I'm just going to say something like maybe
Quest men and if you ask me where I get his name don't I just I don't know.
Right.
Instead of when we clicked so me here instead and that create log and create we can have something like
Recker creator or something like that if we wanted to.
All right.
So we can come here and as a matter of fact that's what this is doing is something right here we are
connected right.
So we could actually right here used to include to include the databasing here instead array.
And let's just bring to the be here the B that BHB.
Right.
So let's just bring it here and let's just take this connect connection here.
So two to two connection right here is take it out of there.
We don't need it.
We can use include it.
All right.
So we could refactor all this and make sure that we as a matter of fact.
Let me show you how to delete stuff for us and then the end.
Just do some more refactoring.
Right.
So anyways so what we want to do is go to log in on the score update and we are going to be creating
a function to delete this with a query from the database.
All right.
So let's do some Save As and delete on the score delete save.
Now this is going to be very similar.
All right very similar.
Now another thing very similar to the update function that we have in here
functions this update right here so that's exactly what we are going to do.
But before we do that before I forget let's just change the form here because if we don't change it
we're going to have all kinds of problems.
Let's change the actions.
Action page is going to be the lead now.
So that when that's a mess say nothing of the stuff.
Again I wouldn't want to update things.
And let's go to functions now.
Actually right here I don't have to go here this is my working for us but I'm still learning with this
new coeditor how to do things.
So I'm going to copy this update table I'm going to bring it down.
I'm going to call this delete delete rows.
All right.
And what I want to change here.
Well we want to change the query because right now we're not going to be updating stuff we are going
to be deleting.
So I'm going to delete this is going to be really simple by the way.
Delete from users.
That's it.
That's what we need here.
We don't even need this deleted.
We don't even need the whole form with other the sideboard we're just going to keep her right and that's
about it.
That's all we need here.
Let's go to the live form and check it out.
Oh and we need to go to functions and make sure that we are calling that function from another site.
Delete.
And if we click on Delete we just cannot take that out.
We're not going to be updating we're going to be deleting.
All right so I think we're done with this.
Let's just check it out.
We have a couple of ideas here that we want to get rid of so we refresh here.
We got some stuff here going on some quest men Kwasman.
Oh yeah.
Out of ideas that we creating here let's just delete it.
Eleven actually.
Hold on
hold on hold on.
Hold on.
So we have a problem in the functions that's created is so the Live from users where Id Cool's ID and
we're bringing everything down.
OK.
Does this look good here.
But I'm just saving here make sure that we are calling the right.
Let's go to delete a post made then I want to have this restore check again.
I just saved some of it delete save and save.
They said to me I have a mistake on the query but I don't know about that.
Let's check it again.
The lead 10 update now of days going out to change that buntu you have an error in US you check the
manual near ID 10 line 1.
That was usually a coma on there that we were.
That's where we had a problem so let's go down to functions.
Let's go to the lead and see where the problem is.
The lead from users we need to put that space here.
Remember that.
Right.
So this can actually trip you off man.
It can just really be a problem.
So let's go to the form now.
Now we can delete right.
And we can see that that is not there.
That's just take the form and make sure that the value is delete right here.
Perfect.
All right so let's delete another one.
11 delete nine delete.
Come here.
Check it.
Now we only have two of them.
So now let me recap what we did.
All right.
So that way you can have a better idea.
All right so let's go to functions actually.
And all I did was copy this.
You see we're using the same query.
We're using a query variable and we are also using that variable there to pass it to the database with
this function right here.
Just I hope you got the general idea on this right.
This is all one query this is on one string together put together and we're using my ask you ally the
score query to pass it in with a connection and with a string which is in this case equal to his variable
rate here it is I just concatenations for this query.
Basically there is one query all put together.
All right.
So when we pass it in we pass it in and this connection here this query here is equal.
We make it equal to the variable result.
OK.
And then here we just saying if we have a problem and this is for's if the result is not good or they're
Querrey right then we have a problem like we saw there.
It's very useful.
So that's all we're saying here what you said in the query straight to the database and right here this
is all database askew language.
Ok this is a sentence you were writing there.
Well you were right.
They used a set you will go to the command line right this and you are right on data into as well which
is using BHB to do it with his function right here.
Right.
So I just basically copy this whole thing and came here and wrote another Querrey and I sent another
query to the database and this query was deleted from users.
Remember this is as well.
Don't get confused is not BHB right.
So hopefully you understand this concept.
As you can see here we win clauses in two functions and we were able to call it here on this file right
here.
We have includes here.
This function will include a file from another place into this file here.
So it would be the same thing as having the DVH would be the same thing as having this day be on the
file.
All right.
This this whole thing is getting included on top here like he was here basically.
Right.
Hopefully you can understand that.
So if you want to keep watching some more refactoring I will be doing it on after this course this tutorial.
Video.
But if you don't want to watch it on more refractory when you're done you can just jump into the other
section.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this video here and hopefully I see the next one.
Thank you