Welcome back.
My amazing students.
So in this lecture I was thinking that we should add a functionality or just a little bit of color to
our little feature that we'd learn to do on The Last Lecture right you saw that this display this alert
from the browser looks pretty ugly right.
Would be nice to have a really nice display with some really cool data or something like that.
Right.
So let me show you how to make this nice.
Okay.
So what I found online is let this little library of really cool notification stuff that looks really
cool.
Looks it sounds.
Well it is actually the name is toast are toast toast ya.
Okay.
If I go there on images you can see all the little nice notification that got a look like this.
That's a lot better.
That would be cool right to have them are.
Oh I see a mass right.
So I'm going to show you how to use it.
So I went over here and I typed in toasty ya and I found his gay hot page tells me everything about
it right.
How to do it.
But I'm going to give you a shortcut so he has a let me see right here.
We have a demo.
OK.
And if we go to that demo there and I'm going to take those musical to the other one.
I don't like this one here.
This one's on plonker.
Perfect.
So if I click here and I click try me you can see the little notifications here that are popping up.
OK so it looks here that we need toast the library that's the CFS the Stiles for this and it looks like
we need.
Well I'm pretty sure we don't need bootstrap but who knows.
Just in case we might need it and it looks like we need fun.
Awesome.
No I don't think so either but the main important thing that I see here is the toast CSX and the Toshio
says down here and maybe Jake where we make you can read more about what he needs down here somewhere.
But anyway let's play a little bit with the OK.
So I'm going to go ahead and create some type of file here.
Let's go and play around with it.
So I'm going to create a file called about.
I'm going to create about this time right.
And let's see what we can and if we can do it like this let's go and grab the toast link so I'm going
to because I want to make sure that it works with a minimal code as possible.
We don't want to put a lot of stuff in or see a mass or any other project or less we need to.
OK.
And I'm going to come back all the way down here and I want to get this see the end for the tools library
guys what I suggest you do and I think I recommended this so many times is that you go to each of these
see they see the end addresses on top.
You go there personally I put them on the browser and copy it physically and extract that to a file
ok like this.
You go there you get all the code.
Copy and paste it in another file and named your file toasty ya angels gather locally in your projects
just in case this thing does not work in the future or maybe they start charging for something.
OK.
Just always keep it with you.
So what you having in your projects
if this thing doesn't work for you make sure that you have your DCP addresses here ok like this HDTV
I think is actually G.P.S. as all of this let's just put that in there.
Now OK if I go there I can see that is HD CBS.
But anyway so it looks like we have a here.
Let's see if we can make something happen already.
I don't know if it's going to work without Jake wary.
Let me come where's my body oh the body tag.
I got this in the wrong place I got these in the body make sure that this is after the body right here
OK
usually and then you invoke it with some type of function idea down here.
So I know for a fact that we use something called toast toast our DOT success or whatever or danger
or.
Aim for that he has a whole bunch of different methods you can read more about it into the communication
of course.
OK on gay hub there is a right here you see that OK so I'm going to say hello.
Let's see this works I don't know if this is gonna work I like to play around with things like that
and then debug it right.
That's that's what I like.
I know some of you don't like that but that's OK
enter and yeah that is.
Whoops that's not working for me.
Let me check it out real quick.
Oh let me see
Not that
inspect my keys all messed up I'm going to refresh this on my network tab and then I see that everything
looks good but it's just not working we need something else.
OK.
So let's go back to this clunker page and let's try to see if he needs Jake wary okay.
Here we go and let's go back here and refresh and there we go.
That's all I need.
Jake where we see that.
That's pretty cool.
You know I close this lecture you know and I thought to myself Why didn't I show my students how to
implement this with a class feature that we included in this that section.
OK so that's what I'm going to do right now.
Let's go ahead and do that would and implement this would push and we know that this looks ugly right
here.
Right.
So let's go ahead implement toast would push you.
So let's see what we've got to do first of all in this student up BHP page or we have to do is include
R javascript stuff from toast.
First of all we include the link right.
That's the first thing that we do include this link let's go to the top here and put a wry above and
let's include the
scripts.
OK.
So right here
and what I'm going to do is I'm going to put it all the way in the bottom let's see if they work all
the way before the body ends and now yep that looks good.
And I'm going to replaces alert ugly alert function
with the toast toasty Ah.
That success and let's see if this works.
OK.
So let's go to Pusha yeah let's refresh this.
Make sure that we have the new one so refreshing that one and I come back here
it's working but we have no data.
All right.
It's working.
We have no data.
There it's not we.
Our data is now working but that's working you see that.
Come back here.
That's perfect.
Let's see it in real it's something wrong with our data but that's OK.
Come back here we might have to string ify that data
let's see here.
That's a pusher right there.
Let's come back here refresh
and push right here.
Perfect.
OK so we have to work on that data.
Let's see something right here so I'm going to maybe put this in a variable my new data
like that and then maybe use tools for that.
Let's see what happens.
Toast to or that it says
OK my now using that variable there.
Let's use implement some new
OK.
There we go.
OK so we know that toast lights strings.
OK.
All right guys hopefully that will help you implement this or maybe use it in your own projects.
And if you like you can give a thumbs up.
Right.
Anyway that with a rating works.
See you in the net select your guys take care.