All right so we have some work to do in the admin section here.
We have a lot of links here that don't belong here.
And we have a lot of elements here that don't belong here so let's go ahead and add some of this here
so that way we can get it ready for some of that dynamic data that we want to be able to display here
in the admin section.
And let's go and do that right now.
So let's go to our brackets editor right here.
And let's go to the ad men.
Remember that we made a
navigation for admin make sure that you are included navigation actually.
Add.
You see that was the wrong navigation right here.
Admin includes navigation that BHB.
All right so we have a lot of things here that we need to remove.
All right.
So this is actually the left side navigation we should divide this into let's sigh and I don't want
to complicate things I just got to leave it one navigation but just know that there's a lot of things
that we need to hear.
All right so the first thing that I want in the lead is not really we're going to leave some links actually
well delete.
We're going to leave dashboard we're going to create a link.
We're going to have to drop down.
I don't know if you remember the demo that I showed you in the beginning of the mess we had to drop
down for posts and for users.
And we're going to have to drop downs also for that.
Right.
So we're going to replicate this one and then we have a total of six links if we compare this with Demel.
So we need six links there.
So let's find out.
Let's first take this SB ad me outta here and just call it CIMS system.
Him as admin.
Save it refresh.
And we can see that that works OK.
So this is the top in the right hand side here but in here
you're right John Smith.
We're done with we're actually not done with his previews it's a preview but instead is that dropdown.
All right.
And is drub down there.
Is this one here
right here.
Joe Smith and John Smith Right.
So let's get rid of that dropdown actually and say to him I want to get rid of that want to get rid
of this drop down.
So that's all I've done is huge and we don't need it because we're not going to use it.
Why have something we're not going to use.
Right.
So let's just bring it down let's just get rid of it.
All right.
All right so refresh come back here refresh.
Done to get rid of these belt you don't need that unless you are going to need it.
You can leave it there or you can just always copy it from the template.
All right so this bill is this drop down right here.
We're going to delete this one too.
It's just gone.
It does.
And we have another drop down this where we will be using.
So I just going to leave the I just going to take the invites out of here we're going to be using e-mails
on this stuff and the settings and I used that either.
When I use Logo and profile right
refresh John Smith profile and all that.
Perfect.
Let's go ahead and finish this up.
And the left side then we have some time for that one and this go.
So the right hand side.
This is navigation.
Actually that's that's an application right here.
Perfect.
That is a whole enough bar.
And this is just that part of the left side navigation sidebar menu items right here.
All right so we are we have many links here.
One two three four five six seven eight nine and we say we only need six.
So I'm just going with the lead three charts tables and forms.
All right charts tables forms.
Save.
Come back here.
See we're broke it wouldn't break anything.
I'm going to call this pose.
I leave this dashboard.
I'm going to actually replicate that drop down because that's what we have in there.
See a mass drop down is the drop down.
So it does replicate that.
And is this one right here.
So let's make this a little smaller to see where it is actually.
So you can see right now much you know that I'm actually replicating these dropped down and replacing
it with a bootstrap elements right here.
Write this column back to it and refresh perfit work.
So actually it doesn't work if you click on it it's actually selecting both.
So let me just make it big again here.
All right so I replaced I copied this drub them right here and I replaced it with a static something
that wasn't moving.
Another element here.
This is actually opening for them right here with this pound sign is oping this well right here with
his ID.
See the data target is a javascript.
It targets javascript all right out of you.
And he's opening this into what he's saying is I want you to dig up data.
Total collapse.
This item right here.
All right so we're going to call this the polls posts.
We're going to give you an idea of polls.
Polls dropped down.
Actually let's just call it make it more meaningful draw down.
All right.
Let's just make sure that we have the same on this poll and right here on this day data target.
And this is going to be called polls.
Are we going to change names of polls.
And this is going to be at the polls.
Whoops Geez
posts view or polls.
Actually I keep making that mistake of fuel polls polls right here.
All right.
And let's say that you just savor here and refresh it.
All right perfect.
The next one is categories.
So this one here that blank this category right here categories.
Refresh it.
Actually it wasn't down in the bush track grade actually.
All right.
Post grade.
I that right here I can barely see.
Sorry guys.
That's where the categories is.
And a copy here category is perfect.
And this one is going to raise and touch so I know where I am.
So categories.
This one would be comments
and this one would be users.
I think we need one more down here for profile and I use is going to be also a drop down.
So it's a matter of fact we have a draw down here.
This is going to be users actually sorry about that.
And I just want to make sure that we take this out of here
and replace it with the users line right here.
All right.
As you know looking suppose category comments users.
And there's going to be has to be a drop down.
But actually they just put these users.
All right so
that's the dropdown right now on their comments.
And that should be name users
users.
Right.
And then one more link after this one here.
And when I do that I'm just checking to see the end tag OK.
And this is going to be called a profile.
All right.
So that's where posts category's comments users profile perfect since there space on this one here.
Separate a little bit from here.
So I think we're done with this right for now.
Later on we will be styling making this a little bit nicer but we'll leave that for last.
Since we are concerned more about the functionality.
But anyway I'm going to end this video here because it's getting kind of long and as a matter of fact
well we need this.
We will leave it the same.
We'll leave this the way it is right now.
So anyways let me end the video and I'll see a nice lecture.
Take care and keep going.