All righty.
So we are done with you Steve are we having sort of some data.
It's time for us to build the HD M-L form that is going to display that or the table.
Right.
So what we want to do is go to bracket's which is our editor or whatever editor you're using.
And what we want to do is copy the comments stop BHB page right here and do a save x ray and it's called
that.
Well there's users that BHP.
All right.
And here users.
Let's go ahead and direct this for the one to view our users.
This page is not built yet but we will build it in a minute.
And this one to edit user and this onto our user.
Okay perfect.
All right let's go ahead and build out those pages right.
So the first one view or users.
Let's go ahead and copy there from what we have another page here called view or comments right.
Why not copy this one do or save us and let's call this do all users perfect.
Say let's go ahead let's go back to the admin here and let's check it out.
Let's check something out.
Posts is very similar to what we want to do with our users right.
So this is not this one is coming.
Now we don't have an ad page and comments that might be an actual feature later on but right now it's
not so at.
Is very similar.
Let's go ahead and do a save as well not pause and call at the users right.
Or at user.
All right so outfalls should be right here.
They do a Save As and it's called this user.
Perfect.
What is the other one added.
Post should be the same thing so they just click on it and do a Save As
edit user.
Perfect.
So we got all the pages here.
Now the next thing to do is is to actually fix this link right here so when we click it it takes us
to that page right.
Right now if we click on it it doesn't take you take us anywhere.
So let's go to the admin it includes admin on the screen navigations you have that.
And let's find that here somewhere.
There we go.
So we have this one here.
Going to.
So let's make this dropdown go to all users actually.
So users Ph.D. and his job down is just going to say
you or users write
users.
There we go.
This one here let's make this one go to add the user and user that pay a fee.
We might have to do something else to it like we did with the polls and just double checking something
real quick view of polls.
And then at the polls we might have to do the same thing here.
Right.
So you all are users.
And then this one is just paste that in there an AD user.
All right.
So that would be the source.
Polls actually users that BHP sors are users.
All right.
Safe.
Let's go back and see that.
All right well we need to change the name of it.
Let's use fresh it.
First let's go to the original page.
Just click on the first one.
It's going to take us to this.
And the second one is going to take us to soar users.
All right.
Perfect.
So let's make sure that we change this drug down here that we forgot.
Well I forgot you probably did not.
So they say add the user.
All right.
Perfect.
I think we're doing a pretty good job.
What do you think.
All right.
We're doing good right.
So click on it.
View all users at user.
Perfect.
If you follow me exactly like I did it right now maybe I may if I left you behind Don't worry about
it.
Just rewind the video and do it again and do little by little.
The great thing about it is that you can follow it just by pausing the video and rewinding it right.
So this is something that you should know and what I see in the next lecture here if you follow me again
congratulations you're doing a pretty good job.
Take care.