Look back back my students in this lecture here we are going to be having some fun with the box.
Well that's the name of the section here.
But anyway so let's have some fun with the bugs right now.
One of the books that we have on the CMAs is if we have let's say for example we have a whole bunch
of pools like this and they are all in draft and apply them all in draft.
When we go back we see that we have this pagination year we should have any pagination if we have some
we don't have any post right.
So let's go and fetch this real quick.
All right so let's go to that step.
BHB that's a front page an array here where select all from pose.
We're going to actually write another statement here.
We're going to add something.
So we're going to select all from polls where poll status equals what published.
We only one polls or publish we go save it.
Let's go back to it.
We refresh.
Now we don't have that navigation there.
That's one problem.
All right.
Another thing that we should actually have is some type of indication here that we don't have any posts
right.
So let's actually do that right now.
All right.
So right now this is all selecting if we have one polls let's go and see where or polls are showing
this Querrey right here.
And then we are displaying everything down here.
All right.
He's saying right now for status is publish Gray we will show everything else.
Let's put a statement right here
and let me just make sure that that's where it goes.
All right.
That's where they all stem and goes.
Let's just say no polls let's just put this for now and let's see what happens.
All right refresh of hoops we have a lot of them there.
All right that's because it's inside a loop.
So in order for us to fix this we're going to do have to do it a little differently.
So I'm going to commend zeed to all that.
Let me fix this a little bit.
And what are we going to do is we've got the count right here.
So if the count is less than one we don't want to do anything.
That's the way we are going to be doing it right now.
So I'm just going to put a statement right here and we're going to say if count is less than one
we don't want to do anything we want to say ekal no polls
right here or else.
Then we show everything else.
All right.
And
we don't even need this guy right here to be honest with you.
We don't need that.
We don't need him anymore.
We do need the window right here because this one closes
the else for this.
This is that right now looks like we're good to go.
Let's check it out safe.
Come back here.
There we go.
No pulse.
Let's go back to add me real quick and make sure that that works.
I'm going to make sure that they will publish come back to the home saying everything works perfect.
All right so that work better than what we had last time.
All right we need to keep doing this to the other pages on this section having fun with the bugs.
We're going to keep fixing a making our see a mess a lot better than the way it is now.
But let's actually make sure that there's no polls here.
Looks a little better so let's do some H-1 And let's just say no polls vailable in this close and let's
put classing here.
And when I say tets center there we go.
Let's see how that looks.
Now refresh is called back here.
Let's do a draft.
There we go.
No polls available.
That looks a lot better right.
All right perfect.
So on this section having fun with the box.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care