I will come back on this video.
We're going to be concentrating on making our application a little bit more secure by encrypting the
passwords the users type in this field.
Now if you think about it we're already making these secure here.
We're making this feel secure against database statements ex-U.S. statements.
So if for some reason the user can't see here and say you know I don't want to insert anything into
his database I want to find out the username and password of the users.
I want to find other information they're going to come here put a software to scan this page and put
thousands and thousands of usernames and passwords every second.
Right.
They will find out your password even if it's something that has a couple of characters and if it's
not a password like this the hacker will find out your password.
So now we know that users are not going to type these passwords this long right with all the different
characters.
It's almost impossible to do that unless you have a password management software.
So we are going to make the password this long and we're going to make that possible with numbers and
symbols for the user.
Now we are not going to change their password they'll give me wrong.
They will still have a password like this but when he goes into our system is going to be really long
POS was going to be a really long password is going to be longer than this with numbers and symbols.
Right.
It's not going to change there.
It's just going to reference that file.
Now that that well that record.
Now if you see here we have a problem at passwords when we encrypt is going to be longer than this.
As a matter of fact right now we cannot go over certain characters he believes 32 characters we need
to change his field to go to over twenty two characters or thirty two characters.
So let's go ahead and go and click on structure.
We are in the user stable right here in the logging app database uses table structure.
Then we're going to change this by clicking here.
Change when it changes to 200 white to run.
And that's just a number that I wanted you know want to use you can use 100 if you want but I want I
think is a good number.
You just click safe.
And now we are good to go.
So why do we want to do so.
The first thing that you should know is that we will be using a function called crypt.
This is the page right here the manual so you can come and read it.
Now using crypt the crypt function along with just a password will create a combination of characters
so he will encrypt it.
But then he would create something really weak.
All right.
And we don't want to do that.
So we want to create something actually stronger so we need to use another parameter called assault.
Now this would be any type of string that equals to a certain amount of characters and we will see that
when we're building it but know that the major function that we will be using script.
And you can pass it a different parameters just to make it stronger.
Now they have different terms here for this type of format.
We're going to be using this here called Blowfish and this is the format right.
This is a hash format that we will be using.
And they change right and you will see that if you go down here a little bit you'll see that these four
men understand the s right has r r l hash for me.
Here if you use that then you will create a different result and if you use this format and this format
here which is dollar sign one and Dollar say we will be using this one here a dollar sign to a dollar
sign 0 7 dollar sign.
All right.
Just know that and this will be the result as you can see here.
This study will produce a pass with this short here with different numbers and dots and letters and
this one would produce this.
And then the five is the one that is very common commonly used.
Now we're now that we are in a different version Asmat Let me show you how to look into that right now.
This video here localhost.
Click on that.
Go to PH be in full and you can see that we are in five point 6.3 version of BHB that's where we are
using the newer version by it's on your watch and is you probably using another version but we are using
a new way in you API than the the one from before.
An empty file was very commonly used to commonly use and a lot of Warper sites.
Now we will be using Blowfish which is a lot longer than that as you can say you can tell.
All right.
The government I believe the government is using this all right now and this look at this one this is
crazy.
This will extend the screen shot 512.
Right.
So let's go ahead and start using this right away.
So let's go to our function that my ask you under remember that we are on their my school directory
and their functions.
All right.
So this first thing that we will create is the hash format.
Let's do that just create this hash and this call that format
right.
And it has a format that we will be using is the
show you right here
too why Actually this is the more secure right now right here.
Five point three point seven and later you use it to why.
So let's use that instead of the two.
A.
All right.
And I just know this because I read somewhere that this documentation and we've got to use it with numbers
after it.
And just to tell how many times it will run.
All right.
So let's go ahead and use that and then just put what we're supposed to put 7.
But I know that we need to put 10 because or more says this will tell.
This hash format many times tell the crypt function many times it will run the hash.
So this will change this would be like a lottery type of system where you will put a number and all
the balls we go around certain times right for a certain amount of minutes and then you will get a different
result every time you get a ball.
Well this would be very similar to that.
This was run every time he runs it would create a different result for the hash.
And right now Ades going to run 10 times right.
And let's go ahead and create the salt and this could be any amount any amount of strings you want.
Right so you can create as a matter of fact there has to be at least 22 characters.
Right.
So the salt is a string it could be anything you want but it has to be at least 22 characters.
I'm going to use something that I know that will work.
So I use some crazy strings.
This is something I made up twenty two.
I think this is 22 characters.
One two three four five six seven eight nine 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22.
All right.
Now we will need.
We need to put both of these together to pass it into the crypt function and she's going to say hash
and salt and actually hash four sold.
But then she's going to put a little effort there.
I don't want to make this too big and it's going to put us in a cutting navel for them together.
Right.
This is just going to make it really extra secure when we pass it into the crypt function.
And now we will pass it in and we will say something like encrypt and you can put whatever you want.
I'm just making this up this very well here because I'm going to use it with the function correct.
Right.
And then we pass it in the password.
This is a password that they use is going to be typing so we pass it in.
But this is first this is the first parameter.
This function is going to take.
And then we pass in the hash.
And salt here.
Right.
Perfect thing we're done with this.
All right.
So this would do that.
Now this.
OK.
So let's just go ahead and rename this to password because we will be using it right here so we don't
have this user name when it comes down.
It's now going to find his password.
There's just going to type.
It's going to keep going with this.
We need to rename And remember this goes from the top to bottom so when he finds his variable He is
going to put it in here.
OK.
So this I think we're done here.
We don't need to do anything else.
We are scaping as well.
And then we are encrypting that password with icons from there and later putting it in here.
So that's going to work really good.
So now I think we're good to go.
Let's go to our create so we make sure that we have the right so we are good here in the database with
two on your characters here.
Let's just refresh this a little bit.
All right.
And let's just type in.
I don't know my user name Edwin D.S. and I'm just going to type 1 2 and 3 create record create it let's
go and look in the database and see what happens.
Actually we need to go to the user's look at this.
I just typed one two and three and look at the type of possible we got the other side.
Isn't that beautiful.
This is beautiful isn't it.
So we did go over the characters here.
All right.
As you can see here we made this possible oblong that we can use more characters if we go here and we
use the Shah.
I think it was all the way down was it.
We in the right place.
Yes we are the one second right here.
We could use the shower if we wanted to.
We can use it just doesn't make short steps here.
But I'm not going to use in this one here I think we're good with this one.
This is actually the best one says it's really slow.
So it's going to take us.
So we're have to wait until we start the process of this pass or here.
So you see that 10 times that we run it through it.
That's why he's low because he has to go and run it 10 times to change I want two and three.
And that software if we do this one time that would be very quickly for the hacker software to to check
on this field.
But we make it 10 times harder for them.
Basically we make it impossible with this format here.
All right.
So anyway I hope you learn how to encrypt passwords.
If you did not for some reason get this Misha we want the video watch or a couple of times I'm pretty
sure you would get it right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching.
Hopefully this will make your application.
And I know it will make your application a lot more secure.
Again I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.