All right so the last lecture we copy this file here into the index I mean admin in this that BHB.
So we got all of this markup right here we need to add some dynamic data.
Let's go ahead and start doing that right now.
So let me just make this a little bigger so you can see what I'm doing.
Actually that's too big because then I can see what I'm doing that just pull these data a little bit
this way.
All right.
And then I can make it bigger so that where you can see.
So this number right here 20 is where we want to display dynamically we see here right now is counting.
It just has a static value of 20 that we wanted actually to count how many posts we got.
And right now we only got one post.
So I should say only one.
So let's go ahead and do that right now.
So I'm just going to make a open APHC tag right here
and we're going to be doing something like this.
It's a matter of fact just going to put it all the way here and they are organized right.
So let's do a Querrey and what we want to check is very simple.
We're going to select everything from polls.
All right.
And that's it.
That's what I really want to check on this one to be honest with you.
And then we want to send it in right.
So this one is going to say select or post.
And we already have this.
But for me to go and copy this is just going to take me longer to do.
Copy from another file right.
It's going to take me a lot longer than doing it myself right here.
So we can do this like this connection and then query we've done this many times so you should be getting
very used to this.
Now what we want to do with this result because we've got this information we're sending the square
we there we select everything from polls and this function is going to send that information get it
into assigned to this.
We want to make sure that when I use another function to count this and we're going to sign it to a
value for a variable.
So it's in my view as a lie.
No Rose I don't know if I show you this before but I think I have.
And we are going to count all the rules for this resultset right here.
I was going to say post counts I sign it to this very well right.
Here we go.
All right.
So post counts has the value of those rolls has a number.
So what we're going to do is we're going to be echoing that right here.
So let's just move that this has moved this whole thing up here and say it go.
And he's going to put this in the records right here
and right here pull some brackets and.
All right.
I think that's shoe work fine for us.
Let's refresh our let's go to dashboard.
As you can see we have one post now if I go ahead and make another pause for example let's go to another
polls and let's just say this is another polls.
Yeah.
The School for example and so I don't know the HP guy is the author and on BHB that's fine status.
We're going to say draft and Paul's image is going to be
just pictures image whatever it doesn't have to be anything and anything special.
Scrooge just to for illustration purposes right.
Polish post.
We go to dashboard and we can see that number just increased.
Perfect.
All right I think we're doing a really good job here.
And on the next lecture we're going to continue in the next one.
All right.
So if you already know what to do.
Basically we're going to be doing the same thing.
We're going to be doing the same Querrey to checking for the next one checking for comments checking
for users checking categories putting it into a contact with its function.
And echoing those values there and I leave that to you for now.
But on the next lectures I will be doing it so if you want to go ahead and do it before me you are welcome
to do that so you can get some practice on it.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I see you.
And that's one