I Welcome back to another great lecture.
All right now I want you to feel really grateful because you have the opportunity to be right here watching
me teaching you this.
Now a lot of people don't have the opportunity that they don't have computers.
They don't even have their health.
They can't even see.
So how in the world are they going to learn right.
They can even hear and you can hear me and you can see right.
And you have a computer right in front of you so feel grateful right now in this lecture here.
We're going to be removing something that's been for us give me a little bit and we're just waiting
for this section of the course to remove it.
And B is this button right here.
Now we are in the home page of course.
We only got two polls here but we will have more later to show off.
Right.
So anyways if I click on the title to go through the content to the polls I see that born again and
it shouldn't be here anymore because we don't want to read more everything that we want and we should
be right here.
We should have more content by the way.
But anyway so let's go ahead and remove that let's go to two polls.
Let's go to it first B.
Make sure that you are in your CMOS folder and just and right there on the end that ph be in the same
root directory.
Go to postop.
All right.
And then you're going to see this button right here.
It's got to be right below this while loop all the way down here.
And just let's just remove it out of there.
We don't need it anymore on this post.
BHB.
And let's just refresh that.
And while Law is gone awry.
So anyway I hope you're feeling grey like I'm feeling today.
I woke up a little sad but then you know I started being grateful for it and look happy.
So get in the habit of waking up with motivation.
All right.
Right now you're doing some really good.
A lot of people are not doing this so feel happy.
All right.
Feel very good about yourself.
Anyway thank you so much.
Watching this lecture and I see you the next one by