I will come back and this video here we are going to be learning how to pull information from you or
else and processing it using BHB.
Right.
So I'm going to show you right now a couple of searches here on Google a couple of examples.
So I'm going to show you an example of where you are able when Google actually sends parameters via
your URL.
All right so let's say for example high typing cars here you see the parameters right here.
They're very simple to to recognize once you know how they are how they work.
So we see a question mark here and we see source I.D. equals chrome high for an instant and then stops
here.
We have Ampere's symbol right this ampersand here divides each of these parameters.
So we see here it stops again and stops here again and we're going to be learning how to do that right
now.
All right.
So and how we do that is by using a super global called get this open our coeditor here.
Let's do a Save pass on this document here blank up here.
Let's call this.
Get that BHB.
All right.
And if I can go ahead and find out get right here.
All right there we go.
All right so we got this.
Get that BHB.
And what I want to do and how I want to show you is that we're going to go to you or else we're going
to pass some parameters and then we're going to catch you here and display it and show you how it works.
So for that we need to catch that value of those we need to catch up parameter.
All right so we are going to open BHB attacks here and we're going to use the variable super global
call yet and this is actually underscore right there.
So dollar sign on this score get this is a super global variable and meaning that is available anyway
in our document here.
We don't need to.
Is this available inside functions outside functions anywhere.
We declare this is available as long as we pass parameters on you r l.
So how we are going to display is very simple.
So when we pass a parameter that you are we going to catch it here and we're going to display with this
function print are the reason why we have to use print are printing this place was inside arrays.
Now you heard me saying that this is super global super variable global right is it has a dollar sign
right here that underscore this super global variable converts the data gets converts this data.
This BHB has this done in the background there.
They know the functions they have in the BHB language.
Convert them into an associate of Array.
All right I want to show you in a minute how that works.
So let's just go ahead and go to the browser and now you can see here that we have an array and that's
the print or that's the get super global right there it's empty right now.
But when we pass it a parameter is going to display right there.
So all we have to do is actually go here and pass it a parameter like ID equals 10 enter.
And as you can see convert it the ID part of it for the key and then the 10 for the value.
And if I divide is what it would and am Procyon right here.
And I say source like I googled it and with the example that I show you a Google search equals I don't
know true reports enter.
You see it created another key.
And set said value for reports.
We divide each of these values by an ampersand right there.
So keep that in mind.
Now we can send this information directly when the user types it in.
Or we can send it via links right.
So let's go down here and create a link and I want to send that information via links.
So let's create this link here.
And we're going to set it to go to the same page and we are on.
And here with a question mark we're going to set that information ID equals 200.
When they when the user clicks here we are going to send that I.D. of 200 you're going to send this
parameter there.
Right and we're going to display right here.
So let's go ahead and do that let's do this.
All right.
So when the user clicks we get we send that I.D. to get super global.
As you can see their marae perfect.
Now we can make this dynamic also.
All right keep that in mind we can put BHB right here and this is the way is usually done.
These IDs usually set dynamically this is not set.
You don't see users go into the browser and type in is this idea now.
Right.
When the user clicks on something this idea gets set dynamically.
So if the user goes on Google for example and searches for cars right that's get sent dynamically right.
That or that parameter was sent automatically.
I didn't go physically there and put a question mark to Hanjour.
I didn't do that.
So keep that in mind so we can send this like this open APHC and tag and close one and let's make a
variable.
It's called his I.D. let's put it equal to 10.
All right.
We're going to do something very simple here I'm going to take of this idea here I'm going to replace
it with BHB
and I'm going to echo out make sure that you Agway because if you don't like it it won't work.
So what I'm doing right now is I replace the idea that I set it that I set manually here with this dynamic
I.D. and it's going to be equal to 10.
So I was going to do basically the same thing which is going to have a different value.
All right so let's just take this out here and I click on it.
You get this idea set to attend there.
All right.
So we're missing something here because we're missing that I.D. equals.
There we go.
We need to have that I.D. equal we need to have the key right there we go.
So let's do it again click.
So we have that now the I.D. and the value is 10.
You see this is and then we can test for things like this.
Right.
We say it for a reason.
If get is equal to I.D. these I.D. which is equal to 10 then we can send a user to another page.
We can do things like this we can actually do multiple things with loops or I mean we can we can do
it there's a lot of things we can do right.
We can even change this.
This here is a ref and make it dynamically.
All right we can even change just click here dynamically if we want to be.
All right.
We can say something like button and then we can set the value of there to click here.
We can set that string here right.
We can make applications however we want and then we insert some BHB right here right.
Just grab it from here.
There we go.
And that's just a cool button here
as you can see the same thing right here.
All right.
But we can change the value here whenever we want.
Call this a minute now and you can see changing on top right.
Click.
Look at that.
See that change.
Click here now.
So there are many things that we can do with BHP but the best part is that we can get information from
there you are able and we can do things with it depending on whether user clicks we can send the user
to a different page and say OK the user click here.
All right.
If they if the ID was 10 if the value was 10 I want you to send the user to this and I want you to get
this information from the database and display to the user.
All right so hopefully this was clear to you.
If not don't worry about it you can ask me questions and discussions and we're going to be playing around
more with getting information from users.
After this lecture Right.
So take care and I'll see you in the next lecture