Hi welcome back my students.
I mean the AD user page here and I just want to you know let you know that we're going to be adding
a little feature here that will let us know when our users create it.
So for example I type in I create a user here and type in subscriber and whatever e-mail.
Right.
And some password add user.
We don't see any message here to let us know that that was successful right.
That's not pretty cool.
Even though the user is being created already we need to make sure that something is there to let us
know right.
We need to put some notifications that would be nice right.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Let's go to our user page and that we're being admin includes.
And then add underscore user right in here for me is online dirty but I don't know what line is for
you but this is the form here to the user.
And right below the square with this function confirm Querrey we're going to type in something here.
We're going to Eckl something out and we're going to Eccl. some strings saying something like user created.
Right.
Then I want to concatenate a link here.
Space actually.
So it's cutting edge space.
There we go.
And then I want to put a link and it's put a link right here.
This link is going to say something like I'm actually going to take.
It's going to take us back to users that BHP.
So that's always going to do.
And it's just going to say them just put it here.
Let me just close this before I forget.
I'm trying to figure out what he's going to say.
But we can make it say something like new users.
All right.
And you can be as creative as you want.
I think one of the videos we learn how we can put a class here and make this look like a different color
or something like that.
One of the bull street classes.
So you like I said I just want to show you that this you know this is good to do.
You know and how this is done.
And then you can be creative.
Let's go ahead and try this.
Let's make sure that we save it.
Hope you having a great day today guys.
Is a new day to start something new and to do you 100 percent everything you do.
Why give less.
You know so let's just call this roll and bow.
Name some user name and some email and password and user and we can see that user is being created and
then we can click here aved take us to the user page or to the users page.
So I think this is super useful.
You know you're welcome to play around with it.
And thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care