All right welcome back.
A student in this lecture we are going to be fitting a bug in our cloning feature.
All right.
So what is this bug.
Well as you can see something doesn't look right here.
Right.
It doesn't look right.
Well this road right here is missing some data and because it's missing some data is missing or a row
or column it's shifted to the left so it's missing the user the data from the user column.
It's not missing the caller means your music is missing that data they are supposed to be right here
for the user.
Right.
That's because I try to clone one of these guys ideas.
You're going to see we're going to have a second post 1:43 and we have the same problem.
We don't have a user.
So where is this coming from.
Well let me show you and we go to the old post.
Right.
We got the cloning feature right here.
The cloning code we're not pulling the user out of the database to be inserted back in the polls.
All right went up putting it.
So right after this.
The solution is pulling data from there.
And it's called Pulse user.
All right.
So that would be the user of the admin.
Now there are three which is the guy.
People from outside admin.
Right.
So Polsce user and then all we got to do is make sure that he's right after Port Arthur right here.
Put a coma so you don't get an error into the senting here you just copy this guy right here with a
coma and four or five years instead of samples.
Alter we make a pause user like this.
Save it.
Let's go back to it and are here.
Let's try to leave this to right here and let's try to cloning a couple of more now.
Everything is good.
Right.
So now in the future if you have some problems with this table shifting know that you're missing some
data somewhere.
And what you need to do is you could create an if statement right here and you could say something like
let's say for some reason the post tags I empty right.
We can say something like this if a..
And let's just say post-tax right here like this.
All right.
So if they empty What can we do with they empty Well we can grab full stacks and do something with it
right.
We can grab it and insert some type of generic code or something like that like this.
All right.
Or we can say no tags or something like that whatever you want doesn't matter.
But I'm just saying you can do something like that.
All right.
So you can put this variable in a loop or something or inside an array and then you can loop through
with an array separating the key and the value and put it back to value with the key.
All right.
Hopefully some of you know what I'm talking about by now you should know that.
But anyway that's a little bit more advanced.
I don't want to confuse you but some of you already know what I'm talking about.
So let's say for example I tried cloning this let's go back to the here.
This is in the cloning section OK.
So let's say I'm cloning this guy right here in the tags are empty right.
Just clone this guy real quick let's see what happens.
Apply.
And you can see that he says no tags.
All right.
That's pretty cool stuff right.
So just in case you want some type of code in your empty spaces or you don't one your column your table
to shift to one side right.
Because you need some data there.
Most of the time.
All right.
So anyway hopefully this was a good lecture for you to understand some of these things and I'll see
you know that's Bhag right that's have some fun fits in the box.
And remember this of course is mostly to teach you how to do all this stuff that we learn in the beginning.
OK.
So that's why I created this project to teach you all this stuff.
There is a lot of things that we can use to you know make this a little better or even we are a lot
more features but you know I use this to teach you more and more stuff all the time.
But anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.