All right welcome back my students.
So the last lecture I told you that we need to build this page right to catch in all the requests that
we send then from any of these folks for example if we click on this we can see that we're going to
go to a page that says comment that BHP and we send in the common ID there.
All right.
Now think about it.
I want you to think about this on that page.
We need to receive these requests.
So what is it that we want to actually know process.
Right.
Basically we want to do a query to pool all the comments related to this post.
All right.
So let's go to View or comments page right here somewhere.
Includes.
All right.
So here we need to make a copy of this right because this is where we have all those comments.
Actually yes this is a page that has all this pretty nice comments that you can do a lot of things with
it.
Let me just come back here.
So if we click and comment is going to take us to the view or comments page we're going to have this.
But here we got it we want something like this that is going to have all the resources for that specific
post.
All right.
So let's go ahead and create a Save As some of your comments and we can call this pose those comments
those comment comments plus underscore comments.
Safe.
All right.
So on this page here.
All right you can see that it's only selecting all the comments here but we don't want to do that.
All right.
Well we wanted to select a comment from a specific post.
So instead of sending this common ID here.
All right.
Instead of sending this well we need to send is the post ID.
Think about it like this.
We want to detect the polls.
Right.
And then display all the comments related to that post.
So will say select all comments where the common pulse ID equals the false ID that was sent here.
So instead of saying common pools common ID here we already have to come at the polls ID here.
So we'll just send that all right instead let's just go with that here.
All right look at that.
Perfect.
So if we go to post comments we're going to say select all comments where right comment
false ID equals and we'll do the concatenation here because we've got escaped value.
That said scaping now.
So that way we don't get on my ask you Elaine.
May I ask you injections real Scape is string.
There we go.
And we'll say get ready.
There we go like that.
All right.
Beautiful.
So now we got to figure out.
All right.
Where are we sending this speech.
Think about it like this.
Now we click on this.
We don't we can go to comment to this comment page anymore.
So what we need to do is this save us here needs to go.
This post comments page needs to go to our to this page right here all right to this directory.
So let's go ahead and move it.
All right let's go.
Here I'm going to go to see a mass and this is insane colludes I believe.
No Aardman.
And then includes.
All right.
So we need to go to where she can find it right here.
So let's grab those comments right here and put it here.
Now let's go back to our editor right.
All right.
So you see the page right here right.
Beautiful.
Let's see if it works now.
Right.
First we need to go to the polls and make sure that we change that to say polls underscore comments.
Write or post comment.
We're probably going to change the S because it makes more sense without this so safe click on it.
And now she says I'm just getting a big arrow here so I'm just saying it's just saying that I ask you
a nice gave string is all right that's because we forgot the connection.
All right undefined connection 1 0 8.
All right we get a lot of things that we need to take care of.
That's just because these polls comments come in page dozing half just
make sure that we get the right one.
All right we don't have anything here like we do in these pages like the head or any of those things
so we need to make sure that we have all those things in there in place.
All right so let's do that.
Let's go to comments and here.
All right we need to have all this information.
Copy this to post comments all the way to the bottom
it and then we need the head or write comments again and let's get all this stuff here and paste it
here.
All right.
And this you say welcome to comments.
Something like that.
All right so let's put it like this.
All right we just need a little little fixing up.
Nothing to worry about guys.
No right answer.
All right so now we got to Fitz's this connection in line 1:36.
All right.
So let's go.
And to Paul's comments line 1:36.
And once we go to Will I want thirty six right.
We need to pass in that connection right here.
There we go.
Come back enter.
And now you could see that specific comment for aspecific post.
So let's go back here and let's try this out.
Look at this one here.
Let's click on this one and look at that.
Isn't that beautiful right.
That's the comma for this and just kind of delete lead it.
And it's going to take me when I delete it it's just going to take me to comments.
All right.
Just to show me that he has another comment in there.
So if you want to just you know edit that on that page on view of Paul's comments you can it's up to
you.
All right.
The lead is right here.
So it's up to you if you want to you know when you delete a message should take it to that same page
on that.
Actually in the next election we'll count.
We'll do that.
All right we'll I'll show you how I do it.
So you see now we have zero comments here.
Let's go ahead and go to this pose for Edwin Diaz.
Let's make a comment real quick.
Let's just say India is the best.
All right.
Let's just do that.
And poor.
And this is just a test coming.
I to two men you pose.
We can see the comment right here when you click on it we see the comments for that specific post.
All right.
We can go ahead and create another comet for that specific post.
And there's going to be yours Mary.
Email Mary G.M. and jibberish stuff.
Go back your polls.
You can see one click on.
And now we have two comments for that specific post.
All right.
Beautiful.
So anyway thank you so much for allowing me to teach you this.
Hopefully you learned something really cool today and I'll see you in the next lectures.