Welcome back my student.
So in this lecture I hope to prevent many headaches.
And if you already have this headache I hope to make it better.
All right so what in the world am I talking about.
Well I'm talking about errors.
All right.
When you launch online most of the time your errors are going to be off your page is going to be mainly
blank and not going to say anything.
All right.
That is a headache that's a big headache.
OK.
You learned that the hard way sometimes.
But like I say I want to prevent that from happening to some of you and offer a solution for goal that
is really easy but forcing for other hosting providers out there you're going to have to probably put
this thing every page and what I'm talking about.
Put this I'm referring to a function that will allow you to see your errors on that page.
For example I'm going to actually show you this.
These are ph be functions that we can use to turn errors on.
All right.
You can put this function here on every page.
And that will show you all the errors.
Now you can actually look into it a little more if you do a little google search.
Stack Overflow is a really good Web site.
All right to show you some of the things that other developers are using.
All right.
You can also go to the HP on their Web site and get information about those functions so you can put
that in every single page.
You want to see errors but that could be annoying.
Right.
But again that's how you do it.
That second way of doing it.
All right.
If using Go Daddy or maybe if you're using another hosting provider because I really don't know if you're
working all the hosting providers is to basically put a file in your root directory in your public underscore
the mail where your web is a web application is right.
You put you create this file with PH called BHB die.
This has the same name as the original file in our local host.
And then you say there what you do is you place the code right here you place is called error underscore
reporting equals evil.
This is a constant so as to be capital and you have to have the underscore there and then display errors
on the right once you do that then you're going to be able to see errors there.
Now you've got to weigh a couple of minutes for that to actually work.
So give it a couple of minutes or an hour or two or so until I die sometimes within five or ten minutes
it's working just in case.
All right.
So again if you have another hosting provider besides GoDaddy check with them and ask him how in the
world can you have access to BHP DNI.
Well how can you edit the configuration of your server so that you can see errors on BHP because if
we don't see errors and when you are creating the application you're going to have a really big headache.
But anyway hopefully this will save you from my headache or will make your yours better.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture