I Welcome back.
Welcome to Section 8 congratulations.
This is awesome.
I mean I'm really happy that you made it this far and you should be learning a lot on this section here.
We're going to be doing password encryption.
All right so let's go ahead and go to our document to our file and we're going to be on practical app
on the practical app ate that BHB.
All right so here just asking us to use the crypt function to display a encrypted password right so
we need a variable with some values and then we need to put a variable inside the crypt function and
just play some random crazy encrypted password right.
So go ahead and do that pause a video.
If you don't know how to do that we'll watch the video again.
The encryption password video lecture and learn all right.
So I will be waiting right here.
Don't cheat.
All right.
Perfect.
So now that you did that let's go ahead and let me do it with you so that that way we can compare code.
Right.
So let's go to PH B.
All righty then.
And the first thing that we need is a password right.
So we need to create a password and we just we can say something like my secret password don't users
by the way.
This is a I mean don't use it in their life application.
And here we need to create a crypt function.
And we're going to pass this parameter.
Now I'm going to do something here and I'm just going to put this in a variable right now fast or encrypted.
Now I want to explain something to you we are aft before a certain version of BHB which was the old
version you've got to look it up on PH BE THAT net.
I think it was before 5.3
we used the this used to work the way it is here.
Now we get a warning when we use this since we were now using an extra parameter with some more characters
that I show you about in the lecture which were which was the salt.
The salt is a extra string of value 0 8 going to 22 characters that we use as a parameter making them
stronger.
So right now we run this like this we get a warning from BHB telling us that we shouldn't we shouldn't
use that.
So let me just show you that
right here.
All right.
So this should work fine the way it is.
But this shows you see this Nasaw parameter was specified you must use a Randol generates holding a
strong hash function to produce a secure hash.
Right we still we still got the encryption here but he gave he gives us a warning and noticed.
All right.
So we could use a strong hash function to produce a secure hash something that will randomly generate
But let's go ahead and use assault.
Right.
So let's do it the right way.
Let's use a sword.
We could leave it like this if we wanted to but this is just assault.
And let's just pull some strings into there.
And this just say something like.
To do that to do something like I use I use crazy some crazy strings some crazy strings to end it too.
I think we're equal to 22 characters.
It's closer and it's Bazin spouse in this sort way those and gives us a dozen and gifts a notice that
should work fine now refresh.
And now we got that.
But as you can see here we didn't get a big big encryption here like we did on the lecture right.
Remember on the lecture how we did it right.
We use another parameter which the house format.
Right.
So we use that.
All right so anyway we're not going to do that here.
I just wanted to show you that you can easily come in and just encrypt a password really quick.
Right so I wanted to reinforce that knowledge of that lecture.
But if you are curious about the lecture go back and look at it.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this video here and hopefully gave you some more knowledge about
encryption password encryption.
Take care and see your next lecture.