All right welcome back my students in this lecture here we are going to be learning how to join tables
and this is super important.
But first of all before I explain why it's so important let me show you what tables talking about I'm
actually referring to the database tables.
All right we've got to learn how to join any of these tables with another table right.
For example we can join the post tables and the Categories table together we can join them and then
display information in one go.
Let me show you what I mean.
So if you go to your view or post page and this is the page that we are going to be working which is
this page right here in our front end right we're back an admin page.
All right we can see that we are displaying a lot of information here which is playing information from
the post table.
We have the category title from the Categories table.
We have the comments count from the comments table so we're using a couple of tables here but we're
not joining any of those on any of these tables.
So we have to make a different Querrey all the time.
All right so let me show you right now we are making inquiry right here to display all the post information
to get that data out so we can display it right.
And then we also creating another query right here for the categories.
All right.
And then we are also creating another query for the comments table.
So you can imagine if we had an application that requires a lot more than this making queries all the
time so the database can be a problem.
All right.
So we're joining tables you can solve that problem by putting all these tables together and then explain
it in one query dummies that's going to give your server more memory is going to allow your server to
have more memory to do other stuff you know.
So let's learn how to do this how we do this.
Well first of all we just joined the Post table in the Categories table just to give an example.
And then you can actually search all the information from there is super easy to do.
And if you want to take this to another level Ph.D. then that is your best friend.
And even my Eskdale Web site is your best friend.
Right.
You just look for joining tables and you're going to be good to go once you see how I do it.
All right.
So I'm going to come in this hour because you know you might want to use it.
So if you're following me commented out.
All right.
And let's create another query here to join some tables.
So the way we refer to a table in its column name when we are joining table is by first writing the
name of the table separated by a dot and then the name of the column like this.
So the Post tables post ID column and then we separated with a comma like this.
So we separate this with a dot.
All right.
So we separate the table name and the column name with a dot.
Now we want to get the next value right.
The next value is Port Arthur.
So like this.
There we go.
And we keep separating each value in table name.
Right.
Each column name and table and in this case we want to keep pulling information from the post table
so we keep using that postop right notation right here.
We keep using this.
Now if we wanted to pull our information from another table we'd say category's dot cat I.D. or cat
title right title.
Now we pull in the title that column from this Categories table.
All right.
So we keep you we can keep pulling information from every table like this and column.
So now let's I actually copy some stuff down because this is going to get too long.
I don't want you to see me typing it but I'm going to paste this information here and I'm going to close
this and see that I have the coalman here OK.
I'm going to go to the next line concatenate is going to make this a little bigger so the way you can
see what I'm doing.
All right.
So we're going to see this concatenated string again and I have another I have another set of
table names and column names here.
All right you see that I have the comma here and a little space.
And now I don't have it right here so we keep putting values in here right.
Keep putting that.
And this is Paul's views is the last one for the business for the pool table.
Then we get to go and we're going to put information now from the Categories table.
Then I get the cat ID if we need to.
All right then coma and then we're going to get something else from the Categories table.
We're going to get to that title you know right now once we have all this information we have to tell
my as well where we want this information to be coming from in this case.
We want this information to come from the polls right.
That's what.
That's a table that's the main table that we're working with.
All right.
So we're going to we won this from pools.
There we go.
All right.
That's where we went from now.
I'm going to concatenate this because I still have some more writing to do.
So in this Querrey and make sure that this is together here we are just going to put this down a little
bit so that you can see what I'm doing.
I'm going to close this again.
So once we select this from polls and you can you know what you can separate this and just put it in
that line right here so that way doesn't confuse you.
It does and then it gets a separate line that way you know where you are.
So we we won this from polls.
So and then we brought a condition here actually from polls.
We want to say something like.
Left join.
Right we want left join this.
And we want to let join which table do we want to join.
We want to join in with the Categories table and we have joined WE HAVE LEFT JOIN AND WE GOT RIGHT JOIN.
All right you can look it up online and really look at the definition.
But basically what he says.
All right we left joining this table because we are left joining in.
We left joining the Categories table because our main table is opposed table right.
This is the table that has more and more information so we want to put everything on the left.
All right.
So we want to grab our categories table and put it you know on the left of this table right here.
One for the Categories table on the on the left anyway.
So let's join categories on.
All right and this is super important.
All right.
On polls dot what this feel right here the post category or ID is the same field and I mean just where
I put this this post category field right here is the same as our cat ID right here.
Right.
So you need to make sure that these two fields are the same.
All right.
Let me repeat that again.
These two fields need to be the same.
So these 48 51.
If you go to the polls right now you can see that the polls category right here is 48 and 51 right here.
All right.
So you need to have a common like basically a foreign key basically a common feel the common column
in both tables right this table right here is the same as this table right here.
All right.
So so Polsce let me just take that from here.
And then is equal to what the categories dot caught ID.
That's right.
So I want you to you know get this information now I'm going to divide these lectures into maybe one
more lecture so that where you can copy these down and you can digest it.
All right.
Again let me just repeat it and go over here a little bit.
For those of you that don't understand it for those of you that understood it go to the next lecture.
So we're going to select all these fields from this table pools and we also have the categories table
right here.
All right we're going to select those fields and then we're going to say the work is going to come from
polls because this is our main table and we get a left join in with the Categories table on where basically
is this on this like a where they mean in a way because it's saying on polls category ID or cat I.D..
Right.
So these two fields here have the same number the same category ID both for them.
Have the category at the right here.
And these polls kind of category I.D. We have the same number.
So this is where they are both the same.
They are related now.
So just because they are related we can point formation now and this is going to be basically like a
virtual table where we're going to have we're going to be this The state is going to be available to
us.
We're going to have all these data that we're pulling right here is going to be available all the column
names that you see here going all the column names that you see right here.
All right.
On the next election we're going to finish this off.
Thank you so much and I see you in the next lecture