Welcome back my students so now that we have our engines on OK let's go back to our editor.
Let's see if we can find our way to somewhere here.
It's actually in the back here.
Let me actually put this in a different screen.
Let me just put it right here.
Just there we go.
So now that we have this on what we wanted to do is let's go here real quick and show you I want to
replace actually whatever something in that's And we've got an arrow here because we're not we turning
our rewrite engine on make sure we save it that we go OK now it works.
So any little mistake that you make on this file here if you misspelled something here you have a space
where you shouldn't have it.
You're going to have some type of error in your server.
OK.
Make sure that you have everything correct.
So what I want to do is I want to replace that BHB I want to take it all from here.
OK.
I want to be able to just type in just the root of this file.
And they don't have to type in this here even though they can still get here because this indicates
we reroute automatically everything to our application.
That works fine.
Well what if they want to go to registration.
All right registration
like this for a tree.
OK.
That's not going to work.
So that's not going to work.
We also this Contac is not going to work either.
What if I type in the context of the HP that works great.
So let's actually write something for that and let me show you how that works.
So while whatever we are going to be writing now in our code rules rewrite rules so rewrite one word
well and then rule two words together uppercase each of them.
The start of each and now we do a space and this is where the regular expression is going to come in
handy.
We're gonna say well I won this this search of this match to start like this.
And I wanted to end it like this.
OK.
Now this is like start this match here and in the here I'm going to write something in between.
Now this is regular expression guys OK.
I'm going to put a parentheses and I say well if you find in this or that's where the pipe is for you
find contact or registration.
I want you to grab those values and I want you to subset to them with this.
Now I know you don't understand why in the world I'm actually doing.
Let me just put this here.
And then I want you to do the I don't want to be not case sensitive.
And last this is the last thing that we were writing uppercase.
Make sure there are no spaces here and see call Ma Bell.
All right.
So like I say I'm not going to show you regular expressions on this because I have a course on that
and because it's a little bit complicated to explain in one lecture.
Well basically what we're doing here is we're saying stuff like this and like this and this parentheses
OK.
Now this is our regular expression.
But this parentheses are grabbing the value ok of index or contact or registration and we're grabbing
we're using valuable we are assigning it by using this Dallas symbol here.
And number one this dollar symbol is like a variable basically gay.
And that one is saying well we only have one because every parentheses if I had another expression and
I just paste it here.
I have now two parentheses and now we have to use another variable here called Number Two.
Every time I've enclosed something like this in parentheses I'm like enclosing this in a variable so
that I can use it later in regular expressions we use it with a dollar symbol and the number one or
number two if we have more in the going order.
So one this will be one this will be two.
OK.
But anyway that's just a little bit there.
So this is in the BHB as you can see we just basically when we find this we just apply apply apply the
dot BHB to it.
So basically we are mapping every time we find in it's by itself we map it and we concatenate it basically
without BHB right here.
OK.
So that's what it is Say.
Let's come back here and let's just say well let's go to registration to see if it works.
And I thought already that we go registration that works.
I was working there.
It seems to me Good to see a mess.
There we go that works.
Let's go to contact
contact and as you can see that works as well.
OK super simple guys nothing out of the ordinary.
You have some type of error in your surveys because you mistype something here.
OK.
Make sure you have it exactly the way I have it in this Kerick symbol.
This is a ball.
You are cits.
So chiff and you sit and you should get something like this OK.
All right look at it pretty good.
And make sure you have it.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.