I will come back on this video we are going to be learning how to make a functions even way better than
the last video the last video we were passing parameters into the functions and we were you know displaying
some good information now but we want to do more thing echoing stuff out of the function more than printing
stuff out of the function.
Let me just show you on the last video here.
The Last Lecture we talked about show you defining functions let me just call the passing parameters
right.
So we have functions here that when we pass a parameter tets string we display something out of the
function.
Well this is really nice you know because we can use a function to pass parameters.
But what if I don't want to just echo the message.
What if I want to just add it to something else.
What if I want to use that message in another function I can do it with this function because all the
function is doing is printing out the message on the screen.
That's what he's doing.
I can do anything with this.
We can do anything with what how the function works outs inside unless we come physically here manually
and change it.
I want to be able to grab the value out of it whatever is inside function and then take it outside and
do whatever I want with it.
This is how you make functions really really really useful and flexible and portable and extendable
really nice.
So let's learn how to do that let's learn how to take values are solid function and then we can do other
things with it.
So just in case we wanted to echo it later on we can outside the function.
We don't have to just rely on this echo from inside the function because this is not very flexible.
All right.
As flexor was well we are going to be doing.
So let's grab the blank that BHB and say this and this code is returning values return actually return
values and then functions.
We're not going to make it bigger than that.
Ready's long enough that BHB All right.
So we're going to open them closes a little bit.
The way it doesn't get in the way we're going to open our BHB tags and then close and bring it down.
Right.
So we already know how our how to define a function that we're going to do that right now.
So I'm going to call this function I'm going to do the same function we did on the last video.
All right when we pass some parameters and I believe it was call at numbers.
If it's not then disregard that don't worry we will make a new one here but should be the same.
So this function here is in a sense thing as the other one but it's going to be a lot more flexible
and when to show you.
So we know that we can call this function whatever's inside by calling the function name right here.
And then what we did in the last video is we passed some parameters and going into the center right
here and going to say number one and number two right.
And we're going to pass some parameters here and the function is going to add some stuff out for us
right.
So we're going to have another variable here that's going to hold some of these two numbers added together.
So 1 and plus number two perfect right now I said that I didn't want to use the echo again.
I don't want to just call these functions just equities out on the screen.
I want to be able to decide what I want to do with the data once I have it.
So how do we get this data out.
Here we can.
The only way we can do it right is usually right is echoing in our right.
Print it out.
But there is another way of actually returning that calculation so you can do other things with it and
call the return statement right here.
You put a return key word there is a reserve keyword ph B and you just take the data out.
We're going to take the sum of these two numbers when I take it out of the function and then use it
here.
Now let's let's go ahead and open our browser there so that we can see the error is there don't worry
about that.
Right now we have to pass some parameters and then you're going to pass this on numbers here.
That's going to go away.
But now we don't have anything here.
Why.
Why don't we have anything happening here.
Well first of all we have no errors so that's good.
Second of all we're not doing anything with the data.
We have the calculation right here on this function.
What do we want to do with it.
Because right now we are returning to some back to this function here.
So what I'm going to do is I want I want to hold this some somewhere.
So what I'm willing to do is just because the sum is here and now could be a little confusing for you.
Right.
Just because it's here I want to save it into a variable.
I'm going to call it very will result.
Right.
That's fine.
That should be more.
Now this whole functionality these two numbers added up because it's already being added up here and
then return back to us.
The sum of this whatever this is.
All right.
Ninety of the fray here.
The sum is trapped in here.
But right now we are assigning this calculation.
This this sum right here to this variable right here and we can go ahead and go like this.
Echo resoled and of course you're not going to do anything because these are so variable.
And then we have a problem here and I want to show you right now what the problem is.
So is saying right now user of undefined constant we don't have the dollar sign right here so we confused
this with a constant save.
We have 98 as you can see here.
So now we can do whatever we won with this resort with his 98 right now this has a value of ninety eight.
So look at this.
Let's say for example that I want to do something else with this result right.
I want to go ahead and see if I can get this right.
All right so what I want to do is I want to grab the same function again.
Numbers right.
Because this function now is a function that we can add any two values to it.
So I can pass it any parameters I want here any way it up for me so I can reuse that function then save
it in the variable result again.
All right.
And I'd say you know what I want to add a hundred to 98 in this debate.
This could get very confusing right now but don't worry I'm here to help you out.
All right.
So I hope you've seen what we're doing now.
We're going to go over it right now.
So we saw it.
Look at that.
We've got 188.
All right.
All right so let me explain what happened here.
Before you get to confuse.
All right.
So this function here we know that it is function we made it so.
The last two numbers and he's going to add whatever numbers we pass it through here.
All right.
With this key we're returned some means that we are returning the calculation of whatever numbers we
pass through here.
So if these numbers are 90 the calculation of this the first number the second number calculate is 90
we get to return that calculation back here.
So now this is not going to work it's not going to be worth 64 and 38 is going to be worth 98 this whole
thing is worth 98 now because we are returning that calculation back.
And then what we do with the 98 with a value that is we all say we are saving it right here in this
variable here.
Right.
To do all the things with it.
All right.
So what we did with is is that we came the right.
We use remember we can reuse the same variable over again and we can assign the same value or even different
values.
So I re-uses very well again right here to assign it to and to use the same function again to add a
100 plus the resoled plus ninety eight.
Don't worry about what you see here.
Just know that this resoled right now right here is worth 98 you just know that this is not a yea in
this is not here because we already had this speculation right here.
As you can see there.
So remember this is from right to left.
We assign values from right to left in programming OK.
So we got 98 here and a hundred here.
And then when we call this function add two numbers and numbers is going to go over here with the 90
that I got right here.
And there are hundreds going to go here.
There are hundreds going to go here and then is going to go here is going to add it up and there is
going to return it back to us again here.
So that one return back to us and then we are we using this variable again called the resoled which
is the same as is.
And right now this variable is gets assigned to a different value of 188 and then we are echoing de-value
value out right here.
Right.
Don't let that trip you off.
We are actually using the same variable in assigning a different value.
So I come here and I say you know what.
And I'm just going to do an echo for a break.
So that way you can see the difference.
What I'm going to do here is it's simply a matter of fact I don't need this.
What am I doing let's just do a break here.
All right.
Just to let you know that this result here is different from this resort.
Right.
Remember the variables they go from the top to bottom.
So right now this is worth 98 right here and going to echo it out on the screen so you can see it.
And then when he goes to the second one is worth 198.
So watch this.
See that.
So right now this is worth 90 there.
But then I go down again they use the same function to add a hundred more to it to that 98 and we get
100 190 and we keep keep doing this over and over again.
It's a matter of fact let's do it again one more time so you can see what I'm talking about here.
And that's going to add 300 to it.
All right.
And of course we need the echo for this here.
So that way he does not look at that I can't we use that over and over again.
Let's not confuse you.
This this can add anything I can add a thousand here and look at the number right here.
Remember this function just adds up even if it does have to add up even if it does add up to the same
resoled variable here on top he added up to whatever we put it here.
All right.
Just know that.
So you see how flexible we can make or function functions how much more extendible we can make it right
just by returning it to some calculation returning the value out of the function we can do many things
to it.
Right.
And the imagination is the limit to what you can do with this type of information.
With this type of functionality.
Right.
So anyway thank you for watching this lecture.
Hopefully that gave you a really really good idea on what you can do with functions when you are returning
data to do whatever you want outside the function.
All right.
So anyway hopefully you've got some valuable knowledge and you are happy and you will fall asleep just
thinking about BHP today.
Anyways I was in the next lecture take care