All right welcome back to the students from the future.
Again giving you another great lecture on today's lecture we are going to be learning how to read the
file.
All right.
So we already know how to actually open a created and even right to it.
But now we need to know how to read it.
So let's actually create a new file right here and it's a matter of fact we can do it from the writing
files file.
And let's do a Save As and this call this reading files.
Beautiful.
All right.
So this is going to be very similar to it but we're going to have to change the W for R and R because
that's that's for reading and instead of writing We're going to do f. read it right here and we can
save whatever we got from there into a content variable into it.
You can name it whatever you want.
Right.
And instead of having this a second parameter we're going to have the bytes.
And now each of these bytes each by equals a character.
All right.
So make sure that you know that it will come in there so you know.
So right now we're going to read 10 bytes out of this document right here.
All right.
And what we can do is we can
whoops right here I was like where was I.
So what we can do is we can do an echo right here so that where we can see it on the screen.
All right.
So that's all we got to do for here.
For this to be on it let's go here let's refresh and we see this it says reading files.
Let's go ahead and try to read that arises.
I love BHB but if I take this and I say I want to read just two bytes out of it which is two characters
I come here and refresh it just reads one byte one character.
All right.
So now you might be asking yourself what if you want to read the whole entire file.
Well you can use a function that will give you the file size and this function name is file size like
this is another built in function file size which has a whole bunch of nice functions right.
So we can just read the whole file there.
And now we come back here refresh we get this and it doesn't matter.
We can write whatever we want whatever we want and we will read it for us.
All right.
There you go see that beautiful.
So this is how you read a file.
Right now keep in mind for those of you that have some type of issue reading this file make sure that
you give the right permissions to your files.
Sometimes we get the right permissions of the folder and then we have a problem when we are reading
the file because that's what that Apache doesn't have permission to redo the file.
But but everything should work 100 percent they already show you how to go and get a D.
The solution for any permission problem.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching this lecture.
It was a pleasure.
And I'll see you in the next one.
Take care.