All right so in this video here we're going to be learning about switch statements and switch statements
are very similar to her statements but we're a couple of differences.
I want to show you how they work right now.
So let's go ahead and we'll bring our co-editor right.
And for those of you out there that might be a little lost we are in the local host.
So I would say right here local host for Slash Demel.
All right that's the father that we're working on we are working with his files.
Right.
This was opening my co-editor right now as you can see right here.
All right.
So I'm going to go rather blank Doppie HP and do a Save As with my key word and you can do a save us
right here if you want and I'm going to call this switch statement let's call it switch statements state
ments.
There we go.
All righty then.
Just like what was this guy named Jim Carrey.
Right.
And if I can remember how to write this really what's going on with me today.
Hopefully you're better than me writing the BHB tax already anyways.
So what how do we use the estate switch statements and why are they so useful.
So which statements are very useful.
Let me show you why if let's say for example you have an if statement here.
Right.
And you want to test the conditions you say for less than 10 whatever right.
So you have a four here.
Let me just do it as a variable here and I have I want to test that number is less than 10 right.
And then I'm going to ask you something here and then I say Eckel this for example we already did.
I'm just giving you a quick example.
If I wanted to test number again I wanted to test this variable again against another condition I would
have to write another if statement here and another if statement here if I want to test number against
other numbers here for example 20 or you know 40 Konstanz in our program when we want to change we want
to test 1 condition against multiple values.
Right.
And that's where we switch statements with saver's are a lot of time I'll show you right now the center
of it.
So let's say I have the same variable number and I have it right here and that's create a switch statements.
So 60 Minutes would Right them like this switch keyword switch parentheses and the curly brackets.
There we go.
Now we switch statements.
We don't use anything related to ifs.
We use something called case.
So we write our case and the case could be anything we want.
In this case it's going to be a number 34 and then we put not a semi-colon board calling this two dots
right here.
And then we we put the code that we want to execute in the bottom
array for example and then all we have to do is keep writing these cases
if we want to test it against another condition.
You see that so we can say thirty seven.
Here we can start again this if you don't understand the worry I will explain it again right now.
OK.
So we have these cases here but we need to grab we need to put something right here because we need
to test these values.
These values against something right.
So we put the number right there and we test one single value.
This is that if statement right.
It says one single condition one single condition I'm sorry against multiple values so right now this
number has been tested against this case.
All right.
Is it equal to 34.
No it's not going to go to the next case if it's equal to 37 then it's going to echo this.
But if it's not going to go to the Netscape.
Netscape in that case.
All right so I'm just going to say that is equal to 30 for just for demonstration purposes only.
And let's go ahead to the browser and see how that looks.
All right.
Oh so we have a problem here.
It printed everything.
I wonder why that is.
Why did it print to everything when we already found our.
Our answer right here 34 right.
We don't have anything similar whether to print that everything out.
Well this is a very important topic right here very important thing for cases here.
All right to make sure that this works properly we need to add another statement here called break.
All right.
So it would come here.
You say it is for right.
Well is it a misspelling a here and I need to fix it.
It is 4:34.
All right but whatever and just not going to even fix that but as you can see here if they want this
to work properly you need to have this break here why this break he's doing is saying all right.
He found what he needed and then is going to break out of this and that say he's done with it not he
doesn't need to look anywhere else.
But if you don't put that break he keeps printing everything underneath because he's saying I I still
haven't found what I want and you're going to keep going.
This break here is going to make you break out of that when he finds the answer to that.
All right.
So make sure that you put your break right there.
Everywhere in the bottom of this case right below the executable code.
Right so for example let's say
I'm going to put this equal to 24.
What happened.
All right.
Come back here it is 24.
So it goes all the way.
It starts with the first case here if it doesn't finally go to the next one and so on and so on to find
this one and says break I don't need to go around anymore I don't need to go anywhere else.
This doesn't go around by the way.
It's not a loop but it will go to the end and that's it.
Now for this here we can also price a default just in case all these cases are not true enough just
in case this is not found here anywhere.
All right.
We can race on default and this default could be anything we want.
We can just say we couldn't we couldn't we could not find anything.
Right.
And they only really need to write this but I will just to keep the structure of this.
All right.
And let's just make this equal to something else so no way we can have this.
We can not find anything you see that.
So this is that before this is like similar to the statement if everything here is not met we can't
find these 100 anyway here in these cases.
Then we are going to execute that default.
All right so this switch statements.
I want you to take this out of this lecture here.
60 statements are gray when you're testing one condition against multiple different values.
All right just in case you testing maybe a form or you're testing a made entry to a database or something
like that and you're just testing one condition.
If this user has not done this if this user has done this if the user does this that you know why were
you testing a user and you're testing multiple conditions against the user in a database or a log in
page or something like that you were using you statements a lot better than using one that AIDS Day
mass switch statements.
It's a lot better than using IF statements and it's clear you can see that it's more clear to write.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.
Saker