I will come back on this video.
I'm going to show you how to extract data out of the super Global Post.
Now we already went and did something very similar when we did the form but on this very I wanted to
show you an easier way to do it.
Well not an easier way but a quick way of actually getting some data out of it.
Now we got to go and create Let's go and do a blank that BHB.
And if I could find one to you.
There we go and let's do a Save us here.
Let's call this the post right.
This call of the polls even though that has nothing to do.
Well it does have the word post there but anyway so I'm just going to create a an input that just create
a form there and is going to submit to the same page the post we already did something very similar
to this.
I'm just kind of doing a recap here and showing you that you don't actually have to hide the whole form
in order for you to get some data out of it.
All right.
And let's get this mad.
Let's make sure that he's posed the data and I'm just going to do something very simple here.
All right and this is just so you can remember that you don't need
whoops
we have a whole bunch of make sure that this there is there.
So.
All right so let's have an input here.
I am going to call this as fine touch is fine and just as a matter of fact the world is going to be
named.
All right.
And when I come here and let's do or BHB tags and you're going to do this very quickly because we already
did something very similar.
So basically what we're doing is just submitting this and getting the value all up here.
All right.
So if we do this here the superpose the super variables will pro-global here get the name out of it.
We can do this like this.
Let's just go ahead and see this in the browser here.
All right so we have this here.
Now we have an undefined name here because we're not getting any data from the form.
We need to make sure that we have we submit the form and we submit it with a submit button.
There we go.
So now this tests here actually we just go into this and submit it.
It was not found they requested.
Oh you know what.
Of course is not found because this file here has Does it have the PH extension make sure that that
is actually working.
Right.
So let's submit it again and see what happens.
All right.
So we still have the same problem here.
Let's make sure that we put the BHB extension there.
And of course he's going to say this because we haven't submitted the form.
So this is why you have to write that is if set function there to make it so you don't get this error
here.
All right.
And we did that in the forms so submit and now you see that you can get some data out of it.
What if you don't do that if you don't click if you don't check if it's a med like we did in the form
of example then you get this type of warning there because right now what you're doing is you're saying
ekal this post.
And when you're saying ekal it doesn't find it it says what where is it.
Well it's right here what we're having.
Click the submit button yet we haven't clicked that when we click it.
Then he goes in it goes ahead and pulls out information.
All right so this is a very quick way to get in the polls.
Now hopefully this was you know help to kind of remember how to get data out of the polls and super
global here post and.
Well that's it that's about it.
That's a little bit a little recap here.
Hopefully you appreciate it and see you the next lesson.
Take care.