Or write perfect we have gone very far and we have added a lot of functionalities to our see a mess.
Now we are here and the profile that BHP and the admin and what we want to do is we want to be able
to know where we click on this button here and all day to profile we want to be able to update the user
depending on what values we change right.
So for that we need to go ahead and first detect that we're getting some information from here and then
we need to run the update query right.
So let's go to that page profile that p.
And now we need to make a nother check.
Right.
So let's open another tack here and you can wrap up this into functions if you like you already should
know how to do that.
All right.
And then we probably will be doing that refactoring all of this in future lectures.
Right now I'm more concerned about you learning how this works.
Like always.
So right now we want to do is want to check if this function is working.
So let's go down and check on the button that is sending this information.
So we see that is very similar to something that we did we did before we users.
So I'm going to go let's go to that as a user of page actually and check them out real quick.
We have the same functionality right here why not pull that out.
Right.
So I'm going to pull this out
and on it added on this core user and it's got to profile and let's just drop it right here.
Perfect.
Now of course I got to leave this like this for now.
This would be an extra features.
What we're going to be adding a really cool picture there and we're going to ask some stars to all of
that.
But right now I want to finish this.
So we're getting the same functionality here.
I don't think we need to update anything.
I think the only thing that we need to update right here is this user name
because we are getting this from here.
All right.
So if that said were getting that session there.
So make sure that you do that.
So we're going to pull some quotes around here too.
So right there right there.
Everything else should be the same.
All right
let's check it out.
So if we get any errors it doesn't seem that we have any errors yet.
Let's call this guy Rickie's of the profile.
Let's check on you you all users and we see that we say Rickie's and he worked.
Let's go ahead and go to profiler again they say keys and some crazy name of the profile go back to
all users and we can see that we are all dating that information.
We didn't really need it to do anything else as we already did all that work before.
So let's go ahead and and just make sure that we fix that guy again.
Right.
Reekie whoever that person is and I'm sure he's adamant into the profile view of users.
He's a profile now admin again and he's good.
Right.
Perfect.
Now in the future Les's We also will be adding some functionality as well we know every time we update
it we need to know if everything went good.
Right.
So those are function of that are extra and they will be covered.
And just letting you know right now so perfect.
We did this very successfully if you were able to do it with me.
Congratulations.
You can see that we have added.
We have done a lot of things to see a mess and I mean all the function ideas here can be very well improved.
And you probably are working on that right now.
We will be working on the ACM asked for.
I don't I'm not going to say a long time but we will be adding features all the time there.
I think it is a good system.
It could be very well improved and it could be something that you could use for your own projects or
even your business making business well that people make you see a message for other people.
All right.
If you make something like this for somebody this will be this will be very valuable.
They will have to pay you a lot of money just to let you know.
But anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care