I welcome back on this video here.
We're going to be learning how to check how to validate some of the data coming from the forms.
We can just take any data that the U.S. sends us from this form here right.
We can just take whatever they send as a command here that will not interfere with some of the functions
in our Web site or application.
So we got to check for things like that.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Right now we have what we are doing just echoing things out.
So what I really want to do is I'm just going to do a simple validation here simple checking on the
user name.
So I going to say if they use a name
if the user name and to find out how we're going to use a function here to find out the character and
numbers because I want to find out the uses is very short so I'm going to use a function call SDR length
and if I pass this parameter to this function here this function is going to let me know the amount
of character.
So this function right here is going to be worth the amount of character that I type in here when I
submit my form.
If you don't understand don't worry I will explain it a little bit more in detail.
We finish so if the user name is less than 5 for example 5 characters I want to echo something I want
to say user name has to be longer than
right and they will say five right there.
So let's test this see what happens if we submit this for like this.
Let's go ahead and do that.
Right.
And then we're going to say one two and three characters submitted and use and it has to be longer than
five you see that.
The one where you want to do is to style this and make a read or make borders around when you display
it.
Now of course you can or you can do a demo right here and put the class on your C Ss and when the class
when this displays they display that color ok or that it would display those styles so we can also do
what we can do is set a minimum here mean the moon
Phyfe and then we can just take this off here and make it a variable.
That way we can have access to that in a more dynamic way.
Right.
And we can say this could do the same thing here.
And that was incentive right.
We could do that and we can also set a maximum if we wanted to.
All right.
What I really want to check is a maxim When you can do it yourself.
Maximun.
And we can say 10 and if we change this for the Matsumura or we got to save the username is more right.
Well on this scale was less we're making more than this.
You know we can say something else or what we could do is we can make another statement I should make
another statement right here.
We checked for maximum instead a check for both.
Here isn't a has to be long can not cannot be longer than 10 carats and not going to write correct.
So if we make or use a name it's just right here.
I made a mistake somewhere probably forgot a semi-colon or something I thought was going to see the
mistake.
Right from here.
But you see there we go.
I saw it all right.
OK.
Right here so let's make or use an in really long submit is and then can that be longer than 10.
And if I make a really short one two and three is and it has to be longer than five.
You see that how we can start testing things out once we have this into variables they are a lot easier
to manage.
OK.
So let's check out something else too.
Let's say if all right let's do another if statement here and let's check to see if the user name is
included in.
First.
As a matter of fact let's create an array.
Let's make an array right here.
This is going to be fun let's say names and this an array.
He would some names and that's create a name of the first name of course is going to be one your instructor
your name here would be a student.
Well that's not your name but that could be your name.
Let's say Peter is your name.
What about
Southmead or something.
I don't know.
What about Mohammed or Mary or Jane or Tom.
All right.
So.
So we have this array here is pretty is going to be pretty fun right.
So we have this array and what we want to check to see if when we submit the username that user name
is inside our array.
Usually will be a database it would be you know we have this in a database or something like that.
And then we would look to the database to find out if that user name is there and if it's that we would
let the user log in to the application.
But in this case we got to make like this since we're not making databases on this one here on this
lecture.
So we're going to be using on a function here that we check to see if the user is inside an array.
It's really easier to do this just this function is going to call in array array.
And what we get a pass is two parameters.
We get a pass of the user name right and we get to pass it the name of the array right here.
All right.
So right there.
So if the user name is in the array let's say if it's not let's use it not.
That way you can get some practice with that if the user is not in the array and is in in disarray right.
We're going to say sorry you cannot log in.
Sorry.
You you are not allowed to do that sorry.
You are not allowed.
We go and else we could just say welcome.
Or something like that I don't know.
Walk
walk.
All righty then.
So we have a couple names here.
So I'm just going to put some other names there let's just put Marcello.
I go with Spanish needs anyway anyway is type an address and submit.
Sorry you're not allowed.
Oh we'll it didn't let us in.
All right.
What happened.
Well he didn't let us in.
Let's say let's type in zone something like 1 2 and 3.
Use as we learn the five Sorry you're now allow.
So we are intriguing in a couple of different validations.
There you see that we try again the 1 2 and 3 1.
Let's try again something else.
Submit user can be longer than ten.
That's a first one because it was too many.
And then sorry you're not allowed either.
Right.
Well it doesn't say either but that's what it what it is.
So now let's let's do something that's there inside the array Edwin is there right.
And let's put a password here and submit.
While we were able to log in and look at that nice right and then we will catch the users information
with a cookie and do something else with it right.
Well we could do that.
We can catch the users information with a sesh or something like that but we'll probably talk about
that more later.
All right.
Right now concentrate on getting this done so practice this lecture here that I'm showing you right
now because this is very interesting right so if you don't understand it go back and rewind it.
But in the last year and the last part here what we did was we created an array right here with some
names and then here we are checking to see that value is the user name is there in their own code name.
And if it's not there we're going to say so you're not allowed if we're going to welcome to use and
let a log again.
All right.
So anyway hopefully you were able to understand.
Can we do a little simple validation and make sure that it is there how we can make sure that the data
is equal to the minimum values that we set it to or the maximum values.
All right.
So hopefully he gave an idea on how we can do this and how things are done.
So I mean there are a lot more validations.
This is not the only validation the validations will probably take up two or three pages of this file
here and it would take up many lines of code maybe 100 lies and codes or more to do a really cool validation
function program right because validations of a really important BHB you need to make sure that the
information that is being sent from here is sanitized meaning that it's clear he's not going to mess
up your programs anyways.
Thank you so much for watching this video here and I'll see you the next one.
Take care.