All right welcome back my dear student now.
So in the last lecture we were able to create this code here that would pool the ID from that specific
link.
Right.
So now that's beautiful and everything right.
But we need more than a link.
We need more than the ID to THE LEAD at night and we need to send out get requests.
So if we go up a little bit we can see that we are getting a get requests from that comment that our
link right here and the ref we're getting it from postop BHB and he has the idea of specific folks.
Right.
So we need that.
Let's copy this copy and let's go back all the way down.
All right.
So now we can create a variable here let's call it delete on the score you throw some quotes around
it and paste that in there.
Now we have this dynamic BHB data here we don't need this here.
It's not going to work for us.
What we need is some dynamic javascript data.
And I just put too close symbol here because we are going to concatenate string in a javascript variable
and that's how you do it in javascript and I have a really good course in Giac work by the way in javascript
anyway.
So now we have this delete link right with everything with you are l n d id.
And if you want to see it we've got to do is face sitting here save it.
And
I'm super hungry so in the last lecture I messed up.
So I had to recreate the lecture.
But anyway if you click on it you can see the whole linking here.
I was actually I created a lecture where I was checking for a value in this link here when I was supposed
to be checking in the Moldau and I'll show you in a minute.
But I was I'm still so hungry but I say you know why I'm going to finish it and I'm going to do it.
And then I go eating which is pretty bad idea.
When you hungry you shouldn't code.
Right.
But anyway so now that we have to delete the whole link here with the ideal we have to do is insert
it in the Moldau right here and this ref.
And we already have an ID right.
So we grab this and this is where I messed up on the last video which I was thinking I was checking
for this for this value here in the link in this one like for 20 minutes if you don't believe me sometimes
you can get really stuck on little simple things right.
But anyway let's go to our viewer polls page here.
When a piece that in there for now but what we want to do really is target that right.
And we are going to be targeting the 8 TTR a Tref.
Now we have the ATF right here it is javascript.
The beautiful thing about this little function here that not only do we grab the value of whatever attribute
we want but we can change.
We can put something in there in this specific function.
So if I put a coma here and I said you know what I want to put that value in there.
It would do it for me with a second argument right.
So now if we save this like this
come back here and we click here.
Actually this is not even work here right.
Well we don't have any events there.
If I click on Moldau here and I right click on this link right here it should give me the H ref with
the ID.
But it's not.
And this is where I made a ball when the lights video.
All right.
So should be inserting something in this Moldau link.
But it should also also be showing us them will dial when we click on it and that's not actually doing
that either.
So we need to do that.
All right.
So first of all let's check in to see what's going on with this Tref.
Let's go back to them now.
Here we get we get the refrain right here.
We've got this here.
Let's go back.
Supposed to give us this new data here.
And he's not doing it.
OK.
All right.
I think let's go ahead and let's go and open them.
Let's do that.
Let's target them all though and I think there's Mother those polled my mother now.
That's an idea for it.
All right.
Let's take this one out of that we don't need it anymore save it.
Come back here and let's target it.
And it's a specific function here Moldau.
And then we want to show it when we click on it.
All right let's do that refresh.
Click on it and it should be showing the mother for some reason he's not yet.
Let's inspect that element on it
and let's find out why he's not being optimal though.
Click on it.
Let's do a console.
Just refreshing OK I think I know why.
Let's go to that link as a naturalist but it doesn't have like a pound seemore Santina instead of a
pound symbol we're going to put javascript call in void.
I'm going to call this method and I end up with zero.
This is going to prevent that just a pound symbol from showing up and it will not go anywhere.
Refresh click on it.
Now we have them all now and when we could do inspect their on it we have the link right.
So everything is working now if we click on it.
This is this is actually ID number 46 right.
When we click on it now a deleted that ID number 45.
Let's do it again let's cancel it.
We don't want anything right.
But we can always see that keeps deleting it beautiful.
So now we're done.
All right.
I was able to do it while I was hungry which is a really bad idea and I don't recommend it.
Eat well you know quench your thirst your thirst.
Well and cold all day beautiful right.
So anyway let's see.
Everything is working right here.
There's nothing that we got to do.
If you want to go ahead adjust your tax right here you can if you want.
All right.
You can make it on H-3 to make a little smaller.
So your model could be like this on H-3.
And he says are you sure you can even make sure that this is center by putting a little class here at
Center from Bootstrap.
Pretty cool stuff.
Let's do it.
Let's see.
Click on it.
And now you can see it.
We have a really cool Moldau.
It's a lot better than that little thing that we had before.
All right.
So thank you so much for watching guys and I always have you on my mind.
I'm always thinking about writing more lectures.
I know this call of course is kind of long but some of you have finished and you come back and you learn
some more.
Why not right.
Take care and I'll see you in the next lectures or courses.