All right welcome back my students in this lecture here we're going to be updating every user page.
All right.
Since we already modified our password encryption we have to also modify that page.
So we're going to log in and I'll show you what I mean a minute if I can.
Again that would be nice.
One two and three.
There we go.
So let's go to users of your users and we have these user right here.
All right.
We also have the files right here I'm going to show you what I mean if you remember when we are logging
in.
Let me show you the log in
here.
We have this new hashing going on here.
I mean we have the PP-ASEL verify when we're when we are logging in but we are also hashing the passwords
in the registration.
So if I go to registration I mean if I can find it right here we remember that we use a password hash.
All right.
So we also need to edit that on the Edit user page.
So right here what we're going to be doing is we're going to be leading a lot of stuff here because
we don't need it anymore.
All right.
So we don't need this here.
No need this right.
And
it's fine we need is that's OK.
And we don't need this either.
All right.
All right so and
don't need this.
All right.
So if it's not empty.
All right so if the past is now empty that's fine.
Let's go ahead and do this here.
Let's query for
a password right here.
So this Querrey the NSA select we're going to select
all from
from users where and I believe his User ID equals the user ID that we got up here here.
All right.
Perfect.
And then we're going to said we're going to say get user right.
So we get the user and we send it in with my ask you lie of course.
Fetch.
Actually you mice here like Querrey which still function.
We use a connection and we use equerry.
All right.
Perfect.
And we confirm it
from a user
that's confirmed this real quick and make sure everything is OK.
All right good user equerries fine.
All right.
So what do we want to bring from the user.
What we want to bring in the user password so we could say row.
And as a matter of fact we could we just have to check our database.
And I'm going to do that right now.
Let's go to Peachi my admin and check that column there and see if I'm just right here show you.
Let's go to the database
and the user and the column is the user password.
All right.
So we can instead of actually selecting all of every day let's select just a password.
All right celestially Let's do this select user password and that's it.
Right.
And that's just going to select one from there.
So that way we get one result and we just say miss you like fetch array.
All right.
We just used this.
Perfect.
All right.
So we get one roll back and now we got to do is say this the user password.
Rowe
user password.
Perfect.
Right.
So this is the first part on the second lecture this one here we're going to complete this.
But I hope you see where this is going.
Right.
So basically what we're doing if is if if it's not empty right this field the user password then we
get to do this Querrey we're going to select user password from users where a user ID has user ID right
here actually.
Hold on.
Let me make sure it's the same idea because right now there's a lot of the same right.
I would go.
And then we send the querying with my ask you like query we confirm it and then we get the roll here
we don't need to do a loop get that the user password.
So that way we can compare it with other passwords.
All right.
So the next lecture we're going to do that.
Thank you so much.
And I see you then.
Take care.