High on this video we are going to be learning about a different kind overrates associative arrays.
This arrays are arrays that don't need to be ordered like the ones that we already did.
These arrays can be called by name we can refer to where by Nene's by labels.
And if you don't know what I'm talking about don't worry I'm going to show you right now immediately
how we do this so let's go ahead and open our co-editors.
And for those of you that don't know where we are remember that we are in localhost demo and here on
this directory OK this is what we are doing right here and this is right here in my coeditor.
All right so you're going to minimize this and let's do a Save As like we always do on a blank page
the mail now blank that the email blank dot BHB.
I don't know why I don't get used to it.
I don't even use a C mail.
But anyways.
So we're going to call this race a as a as all C for associative.
I don't want to write the whole thing.
So let's open up our BHB tags and let's go ahead and jump right to it.
We know that the regular arrays are defined like this.
We have a variable right here.
And then we can go ahead and write an array like this here.
Right.
We know that and this becomes an array regularly.
We can put our values in here say something like maybe let's just put some numbers in here.
Ten twenty forty five.
Well actually that's nine.
And then we can go heading actually like this.
We refer to it like this number with square brackets here.
And if I want to print out this number here you say 20 right.
And we go and we see this on the browser and see are actually a mistake right here.
Make sure we fix that all right on the find 20 of set.
Of course we need to.
There we go.
All right.
So we know that we can print out the values of an array like this.
Right.
All right.
This is a normal way.
Let's make an associate of array and you're going to see the difference immediately.
Let me just put a brake tag right here.
So that way when I when we call and that's the way it will be on the next line.
So let me show you what an associate of a is.
Let's call this names.
All right.
And very simple.
I'm going to create the same key we're here and we use an old version of writing this.
All right.
We can use a shorthand version like this.
Remember that it is.
But just for illustration purposes only.
I want to write it like this.
That way you know this is this is an array.
Right.
So
the array has labels.
We know that the first value here is in something called an index.
This index is zero.
This only is one and there's only two depending on the values that you got here.
We start from zero and we end on whatever amount or whatever values we got here.
Right we've got 20 values were and are not 20 values.
And this is called.
We know that this is called Zero so this needs to be in order in order for me to print this on the screen.
I need to remember way where this is and was bodices.
And right now we're printing out the third value 0 1 and 2 right here.
So I need to remember that this is in that spot right there for me to print to imagine if I have a thousand
dollars inside these array How am I going to remember where that specific value is.
Right.
And let's say for example these were names.
So if let's say this was Jose here and this was I don't know Maria.
And this was Juanita.
I don't know where I got all these names.
I think a magic or something.
All right so if I have all these names here imagine if I got a thousand names I want to go ahead and
print print out one of them.
And I said OK Jose I think he's in spy number 1000 on this one thousand.
That would be crazy.
Right well associative arrays are going to help us out.
You see we need is a raise in certain occasions.
But for when when labeling your data inside an array is important.
You need associative arrays where you don't care about the order of your data inside the array.
Then you can use a no more raise right.
But right now we care about the data.
I want to be able to find data inside my arrays by label.
For example if I have a list of names I want to be able to find it in here.
So I'm going to call this first name look at that.
So this is going to be the end in 0.
Compared to zero right here.
But the only thing is that that zero we're not showing it right here.
To show it to you right now in the browser and in the print are structured so that way you can get the
better idea.
But right here we are replacing ended at zero by this label.
This is called the key first name and then we assign a value like this.
We use this equal and the greater than symbol and we assign it whatever value we want.
For example I wanted this value to be name Edwin Right.
So if I show you this on the screen right now I'm not going to do a neck or what I'm going to do is
I want to print are just to show you array
and see right here.
All right.
Let me show you the top one too.
Let me just comment this out and this is the print are also in here.
Print
this is a really good thing because now we can refer to our data inside by name instead of by numbers.
All right so I have this array here on top.
This is a regular array.
By the way an array.
Let me put that break.
So that where you can see the difference right here.
All right so now we have two arrays on one on each line.
Right.
So this zero that you see here is the key of the normal way.
And right now what we did would associate array.
This is their Sosia array This is the second one.
We changed this key of 0.
We change it to first name.
You can see they are basically the same.
We get a little arrow here and we got a little arrow here but this there were all in there no more way
we can see it through here.
All right.
We can see it but if we use a print art function we can see that they both are the same.
The only difference is that we are doing the only different thing that we're doing is changing the name
of this key right here this is called the key.
And this is called a value.
So we are changing the name of the key the value of the key right.
Right here this is 0 for a word first name and then we are referring to the value right here.
And we use using this whole structure just like you see here in the back.
Right because this is this is something that is not available for regular people.
If I don't use the print function if I use X which you won't be able to see that.
So we are using the whole structure here.
We change in the end it's 0 for the first name the label.
So now we can refer to this by label.
For example if I want to encode this now for say Echo I just use names.
And in between brackets here I just say first name right here look at this first name and I can refer
to that value immediately you see right here says Edwyn.
Let me just take care of the print our function out and you can see that we can refer to the value in
this.
Inside this will see the array by label.
So if I have a thousand lines of data inside here I could say you know why I need the first name and
you could get the first name of that specific person.
Right.
You can get the last name.
We can also make another one here.
You know what we have to do is remember we separated by a coma.
This is the same thing as a regular way we separate by a coma.
Right.
And then we go ahead and write down again.
For example last name here let's just do on the score and then we use a little equal and a greater than
symbol and we put the name the value here and say yes right.
And I have to do here if I want to print that out is that I go ahead and write this down here and names
and then
the last name right.
Let's put a little space right here
and we are concatenating and remember that we put things together with this dot and this is a string.
This is a space that I'm putting right here as you can see here we were able to use labels to get our
data out of this array.
A lot simpler than using indexes using numbers using little as you can see here using this numbers.
If I want to refer to a regular data inside an array I would have to use numbers like numbers 0 and
you can see here for that for when I get Juanita when I put 0.
And again if you imagine if I have a thousand lines like this I would have to write.
Oh yeah I remember nine seven hundred.
I had a name John was Zale.
Peter was in 701.
That would be very confusing of course.
This is going to give me a arrow here because I don't have a number in that seven hundred one but if
I did it would print it out.
But you could see where we can use a associative of array.
Now we can refer to a data by labels instead of by numbers and so that we are going to be a lot easier
to remember if we got more uses for this.
But anyways I just wanted to give you a little introduction on associate of arrays here.
That way you don't mess around them because they are very important and you're going to be learning
about them throughout your programming career.
Thank you again for watching this lecture and hopefully you were able to get some valuable information.
And I see you in the next one.
Take care