All right on this lecture we're going to be you know fixing this links when you click on it we want
those links to go to specific pages just like this right here.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do that first link that we're going to be facing is the view polls right right
here.
And let's go to the ad man for Slash and it's so actually we are there right now and that view the tails
is on here somewhere.
So is right here.
New polls.
All right.
So
if we click on it that's going to take us to the polls right here.
So it's going to take a two post-up ph.
Now this link has all their stuff in there so we need to go to that link actually.
Let's go to the ad men navigation and let's check out the other link.
All right.
That's the best way to actually get the right values out of that link because we added some functionality
there if you remember.
So let's go to the view users view or post a link.
And as you can see right now we are directing it right here.
All right.
So let's go back to it.
And I thought we did add a.
Actually we did add it right here.
Right.
But not that's for that polls.
All right.
So we had it we did add a function right here for this one but not for this one.
So we are good Let's go to whatever page we're working on which was in that house and I thought I had
in my working files right here somewhere
right here.
OK.
And we are on post view details and make sure that we can find them right here.
So make sure that these values are going to the polls that's for and we click on it and takes us to
post.
Now we're going to do the same thing for the rest.
Right.
If you want to you can go ahead and do that.
It's very simple.
All right.
Make sure that you click on comments it takes you to the comments that BHB page right.
That's all you've got to do.
You want to go to comments that BHP and we already did is impose.
So if we go ahead and do this here what happened with click on it it takes us to the same page because
basically that is just saying that he's on that same directory.
All right.
So we didn't really need it out there.
I'm just sometimes I like to put it in there.
But anyway let's go to comment and do the same thing on comments and we have the link right here.
We're just going to say Come up here.
And as you can see right here right there I just got used to doing that.
It just says that it's on the same directory basically two dots means you get out of that directory
OK.
See that.
So you know that I do that just because I just the way I learned things from the past.
All right so now the next one is users
go to uses that BHB I think users goes to the view users and check it out.
All right.
So that's going there that's going.
All right so perfect.
And if you if you are wondering why in the world this all this is working like this.
Just remember that I when you downloaded that form I added some of those links in there already.
All right.
Just know that.
So basically that's all they are links.
There's nothing advanced there that you should learn.
It just links dashboard and categories take into the categories that BHP.
All right.
And you're welcome to check on those links.
As you can see right here this is the categories and the view dieter's is down here and we just send
out a link to the appropriate page.
Right so there is nothing there that it's advance or anything that should you should have learned you
already know that just add those links there and you should be fine.
All right.
So we have this page already.
Let's test it a little bit let's add a comment to something right.
So let's do polls.
And this is published already so I'm going to go to these polls and ask them some comment to it just
to check it out.
Right now says no poll sorry for this.
We need to.
This is part of the bog that we need to fix.
So don't worry about that we will get that done.
But right now let's just add a comment to this section to this post right here and they say something
like.
And when they alter my e-mail we're doing it 20 years that come my coming is just a comment comment.
All right.
Submit.
Perfect.
Let's go to admen and we see that we have two comments now.
We have another user here we can check that out.
We wanted to looking at another user say something like Quincy I don't know what kind of usage that
quenching which is going to give him a subscriber because I don't know who he is.
And let's just say.
Q Is his last name actually this.
This is say something like.
PETERSON
Right.
And b c it is is a user name and B C G mail that and some crazy password update at the user I mean and
that's got to dashboard and we can see that we've got three users.
So all this is working.
Let's do one more in categories and let's add another category and say HCM L5 category that's where
you can see that everything is updated successfully.
So we're doing a pretty good improvement here on dashboard.
And the next one we're going to do.
We're going to be doing some graphs.
And just to show you real quick why that is
loco's blog at men and let's go to we're going to be adding this dashboard right here.
You might be asking yourself how they were going to do that.
Well it's complicated when you're you don't know how to but don't worry I'll make it easy for you.
So anyway if you're here and you are accomplishing all this Congratulations you are really really something
right so keep going.
We're almost there.
And if you for some reason don't want to send some of the lectures.
Rewind them on your terms and to you all this information is super valuable is going to help you out
right.
So keep going.
Let's shoot for the money that makes so much careers go up some income with this existence.
This get some new clients and let's keep on going.
Right.
Anyway thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture