All right guys so in the last section we were able to you know make our phone work.
All right let me show you exactly OK.
So we were able to you know every time we select something here our form is submit and some type of
data right here on top.
Now that data right now it's not doing much because you know we don't have first of all we don't have
the right data and we're now even detecting the data right now 100 percent.
So let's start playing around with it a little bit over here on the top.
I want to start working with it right below this code OK.
As a matter of fact we can do this above.
I think this code is super important so I'm just going to he's going gonna do this sending email here
because that's how I think we got push it here.
Let's just put pusher C..
Yeah.
Push your stuff and just put pusher below and then we're doing authentication.
I'm just gonna put something here real quick.
Anyway so I'm just gonna put this right here above and here I'm just going to do something like setting
language
variables something like that and I'm just gonna check right here real quick to see the same function
we have been using a set to see if I guess some type of data.
Let me see the name of the data right here in this form.
All right.
So as you can see right now the name of the data that's coming in that variable is going to be called
Lang.
OK that's super important because that's what we're going to have all the values of the option right
here.
That's option elements I'm going to have I'm going to be recognized this is this is a value that we
want to catch the N and the yes and depending on these values we're going to be including files.
OK.
So let's take the first lesson Make sure that's coming in.
OK and once it comes in.
We want to assign that value to a session so we can play around with it.
OK.
So every time we refresh a page it we do not lose our value those values.
So we can do that.
Now the next step is we want to reload our page.
OK.
Depending on the data.
So let's say if a set let's just say session lag because right now this should be let's just put assign
it to a key here which I forgot.
And let's just put language you just to make it.
That's fine.
Lang is fine it's just too lagged for short.
Lot of people do that and I do it myself so I'm just going to copy this guy out put it right here and
let's do another check real quick as well.
Let's do and and let's put session equals to this guy right here
OK.
So we are saying here if a set session Lang and the session Lang is equal to this guy right here that's
coming in then we want to refresh a page.
All right.
So right now what I'm going to do I'm going to put some javascript MP HP stuff so I'm just gonna do
a script I'm going to close.
Let's make sure we have it open my script tax here going to close him I'm going to make sure that he's
type of JavaScript OK and that's JavaScript or something like that.
And then we see and you say here I just want to execute a function is gonna be the location that reload.
OK.
This function is gonna be in charge of refreshing the page.
OK so this should be working 100 percent all right.
And we can test this out.
But right now we're not going to see anything because our beaches refreshing anyway because of the form
data.
So the next step for us would be to write some more code that is going to include those files that we
created.
OK.
So I'm going to copy this guy out right here and I'm just gonna do this and do that like that.
So I'm going to include
those files inside includes folder inside the languages folder and I'm just gonna finish my script right
there but I don't want to attach the name of that file which is gonna be in this session called Lang
and I want to also attach the BHP extension.
OK let's make sure we got this right though languages.
And then here we have an extension.
OK.
And then here what I want to do is I want to also provide an L statement here because we want to make
sure that we have on top of the full file that we are including so else.
And then we just say listen if you can't find this here there's value.
OK.
If the session is not set then what I want to do is I want to include the English file and BHP OK so
let's check it might not work 100 percent so let's see we're going to refresh this.
And if I click on this this is not going to probably work because we've got a lot of stuff that's you
know that needs to happen before we we make this whole application work 100 percent.
All right but we need to inspect this a little bit and make sure that this is correct this looks correct
and this looks correct right here.
But you know later on we'll probably encounter some type of error here and we'll fix it.
So I'm going to leave this lecture the way it is.
I think we've done enough here and I'll see you guys in the Nats lecture where we are gonna make sure
that we have our form sending the right type of data our option elements are showing a right type of
data and everything is actually working 100 percent.
So that's where we are going to be going on the next lecture.
See you then.