Or write so now that we have our structure right we need to build a database for a system.
I'm actually located at local holes for Slash CIMS as you can see.
We don't see the in that BHB because our server knows that it's that BHB will be our home so it doesn't
display it.
But if I type here in that's BHB and I click on it you can see that it is the same thing.
All right.
So one thing before we continue that I want to make sure that we are on the same page is that I'm using
version five point six point three on this course.
Now this is the latest version.
All right in my time now if something major changes in you know the system in BHB or my ask you well
I will update the course make sure that you're using the latest software for a zap I'm using this version
right here.
So it's up to you if you want to download the same version or you want to go ahead and download the
latest version that the latest version should be fine since I will be updating the cords all the time.
One thing to make sure also that I'm using.
We're going to be using the API my Eskew.
I there is an API called my rescue L which is the old one.
All right.
We have the new one for my my Eskew L I which me the I stands for improved.
So I know that.
So if you have an older version or zap update it.
All right so let's go back here.
Let's go to our local halls ph be my admin then you can get there like this locavores BHB my admin and
you can just type it in there and go to databases.
And here we're going to create a database called CMOS we can actually create we to select the here in
the right hand side we're going to create create a database with a database I'm sorry a table and this
code is let's create a category table actually let's do that first.
And we just kind of said to
two fields for that two rows I'm going to go and the first thing that we will be doing is putting an
ID on it.
And of 3 meaning that we can have up to three characters 9 9 9.
Basically we will have probably a thousand ideas if you want more ideas and you're going to have a lot
more categories then you can go ahead and do that but I think this is not necessary.
I don't want to use more space than have to and let's go and say primary and or increment that's what
I stands for.
You can put your mouse over I think it would tell you they would go.
And then the next one is cat title which is of course short for category title.
And this is going to be of our car and it's going to say is 2:55 that's fine.
That's a match for that.
All right.
So we're good to go with that and just save it.
All right so we build the database see a mess and we have a category table in here we go to the structure
and we see that this is actually in fact good right.
Perfit so we're done with this lecture.
Thank you so much for watching.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.