Welcome back my students I hope you guys are having a really good day today.
OK.
So if you have never checked my announcements in the courses make sure that you read them sometimes
I really give really useful tips about your career life and etc..
OK.
So let's go ahead and continue on what I want to fix something real quick right now since we moved the
logon page which was in site includes show you right now where it was.
It was inside this includes folder says we move here.
Remember there are sidebars actually our form values are going to form that path right here and now
it's not there so what can we do about it.
But this is the thing since this is here.
OK.
We need the functionality in the in that space something that gets the value there because every time
this refreshes it is going to take value from where he's actually included.
So we can just take this action.
I took you out with our values and make a redirect to the same page which is in it's and let's actually
call this here and we can just write some PH BE code here and use a couple of our functions like if
it is method post then we can do something right.
Well
let's actually check to see what functions we have to help us out a little bit more.
We have another function here.
We have this go up if it is Mentha if he's logged in.
And that's that's going to help us natural certain things natural that form so we're going to use that
and in a minute and let's go and let's see OK let's go back.
So what I want to do is I want to check if it's set.
Let me just check for the log page.
I think we have that code there.
There we go.
Let's go to that here.
Let's just base that in there and then we're going to be using that code as you can see.
And if you want to go further you can go ahead and make this more reusable by you know including this
you know and the whole function.
That way you don't have to do this.
You can just put a function here and we'll do it for you and you call this a little cleaner.
OK.
So that's up to you.
So this of course is going to redirect to this page.
OK.
And we could just say in here.
I think these would do the trick.
Let's go back
go.
And if it's something gone wrong here it goes back to that page.
Great.
So that's working there.
What else do we need to do.
Let's actually make sure that it is working let's make this Logan right.
We go slow then let's logout.
So we need a buy in here or some type of link that would take us to another page where the user can
you know we said their password.
So we need to build that page from scratch and what I'm going to do is I'm going to include that code
here.
OK.
In this lecture.
So let's go and build that page right now and then you can just copy or download the code from this
lecture
I'm going to make create this in the front on it and see a mess in the main directory.
And I got to call this Forgot
forgot I just forgot you can name and whatever you want you can name it forgot password just to make
you a little bit more meaningful.
If you guys know how to use good already go ahead and start using it.
OK make sure that you're saving whatever you are creating get it's just version control is just a software
that allows you to save every version of your application.
OK.
And I have done some of my courses.
So anyway I'm going to copy a page that I got
which I'm going to provide to you in this lecture.
So make sure that you download it and we're going to be writing a lot of code in this
in this couple of lectures because we need to set a lot of things.
I'm just going to take this off
OK.
I'm going to include this on top.
And let's check out to see how this page looks.
Come back here.
Got BHP.
And as you can see it looks like this right now.
Gates go ahead and download it.
Make sure that you have it working OK.
So one thing that we don't want to do here is let anybody come in here just for the heck of it.
So let's create a link inside includes real quick somewhere here where the form is.
And let's find a good place for this.
This stiff form they form groovey here.
Let's just do it right below here.
Let's create another day of form.
Group class.
Let's make sure that this is cesse forgot boss where we get we can study later on you know and show
us something that we are not going to do.
Now we just want to build the functionality.
And what I want to do here is of course this is going to forgot that BHB
and specif parameter here and this parameter will be anything anything you want let's just make this
like a little bit more dynamic right.
I was going to put some crazy characters there that we can detect later on by writing it manually board.
I think if we use a function like Unique ID like this is going to create some random links for us.
So let's just see that
click here.
And as you can see those two forgot got Let's go back here and Ensco BHP.
OK and we go and we got some random characters here.
That's cool.
All right so we have that link there.
Now we we have to do is build the functionality and forgot that BHB.
OK.
So let me go ahead and drink my coffee because I'm kind of falling asleep and a little tired and I'll
be right back for you is going to take a second for me maybe an hour or two.
See you in the nads lecture guys.