All right so we got our form the first form on the left side on the last video right.
So what we need is we need a table here on the right hand side so we can display some of the categories
that we are going to be added in and adding into in-crowd on it and remember crowd means create read
update and delete.
That's the acronym.
So now we have the forum here.
This is a forum we want to create something else in the bottom related to this.
So I'm just going to use the same class here.
And because I want to explain things in half and that's how we do it
because remember they said we're using a framework here and this framework is helping us out style things
and make things responsive really easy.
So let's go ahead and create a table that's actually create a table inside a table we're going to create
a something called Elliman inside a TLM element and create a row.
Is going to have two pages times to th elements.
And that's about it.
All right.
And I take on tab and that does this for me and to me that's a plug in that we download with this editor.
For those of you that have this editor if you don't have this editor and you weren't able to do that
just pause the video and copy it.
All right.
So we're going to put the idea right here on the T-H and category title here.
All right let's look at that.
We should have something
refresh.
All right we do have something year but it's on style.
All right.
We'll have more styles there.
We're going to have to put some clauses in here made just a little better.
So we want to add something so.
Well yes we are looking at something right.
So inside is th list at a T body while not inside after it had to roll a roll with these times.
There we go.
And it's just something here saying something like baseball just for them striation purposes only baseball
cats Gorie
and
basketball.
All right let's just check it out.
Fresh as you can see here it looks pretty bad because we this framework stripping down some of the default
styles from the browser.
But we are going to be fixing that.
Right now it's at a class here called Table that she just helped it out a little bit and she refreshed
it and now the styling is really nice right now right.
Let's use another style here.
Let's add more data.
Add a little bit more tedious.
Right.
So actually let's add another rolls on TVs right.
It's.
This is fine the way it is.
To be honest with you that's fine.
We're good to go with this.
We will be putting more data in here.
But right now let's just leave it like that.
I want to put too much in that we don't need.
So table let's put another class here code table border and this is going to make it look nicer.
All right.
So we are squaring everything here.
Let's actually use another one too.
I think this will work fine with it.
However let's refresh it and if we put our minds over it we can see that.
All right that's being hovered over.
I mean we hover over it we can see that it's playing nice with us.
All right.
So I think we're done with this table here we will be doing some more things with it.
But right now we won't be able to do anything because this lecture is getting kind of long for you.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care.