So I wanted to actually explain to you a little bit about the project files.
So I am currently in the lecture where the files are located where it says probably the lecture that
you're watching right now is called course exercise files or reference files.
OK.
So in this current to me version I say YOU TO ME BECAUSE YOU TO ME change their interface.
You're going to see that we have some options here automatically it's going to be on 10 80 your video
that you're watching right now.
If you have a good connection 720 if you are in the lower end connection or 360 depending where you
are so you can if you wan browse the Q&amp;A any of that specific course lecture and you can ask a question
right here on that specific lecture which is very good instead of going to the discussions.
You can go to your dashboard right here of course you know that by now you can get a bookmark you can
change the speed in which I'm actually recording and here you're going to see your resources available
or some type of link here and video just in case maybe they change it in the future.
Know that your resources are here and I'm going to download my resources.
This is where I want to get to.
OK.
So they're going to be on a zip folder like there's a zip file.
Make sure that you have some type of utility to download it.
For those of you using Windows if you don't have a utility I think seven zip is a good web site to download
this program that allows you to unzip those files OK.
You can download the two version of bit or 64 bit download it and you can read right click on your files
on Zais but you can also double click on them way of a Mac operating system.
Now this is the two files that you're going to get.
You're going to get the CMOS the two folders the CMOS is going to have our application inside.
OK.
So we're going to have all those files and they're going to keep being updated as we keep growing our
application then we're going to have this Demel and inside them all you're going to have this practical
app OK.
Now this practical app you can open it up later on when I show you how to do that.
And you can open it up your installation in your program.
OK.
And if we go it if you already have installed ma'am OK.
You're going to be and that's not.
The Right here I'm using map in my case.
And of course you're going to drop of that practical map folder in the docs.
OK.
That way you can practice.
So now if you go to your browser depending on what program you're using if it's map like I'm doing right
now it's going to be this and use go to the practical and see the address of it.
Practical underscore practical app enter and that's going to basically give you the app.
And this is where we're going to be practicing our application as some of the sections OK.
This is just a little app that I created for you guys and that's pretty cool.
And then we also have enough folder.
Let's go back here.
We have the new lectures folder right here.
OK.
And in this lecture here folder you're going to have the references to some of the lectures that we
are creating in the course now.
Because I keep adding lectures to the course.
This might be out of sync.
OK.
Meaning that this here might now be lectures sits by the time you're watching it.
Just make sure that you look at the name OK.
In this case we're learning about variables here so you go to the variables lecture or you know if you
want to go to this file and you want to look at it you can look at some of the things that we are doing
in that lecture.
OK.
This is just for reference.
Basically guys that's why I included them here and I put the number there because this is how it was.
But I keep adding things to it and they just keep changing.
So don't worry too much about it.
This is just for reference if you want to take a look at it while loops the for loop for each the math
functions.
Cookie's session and things like that.
Then we have my askew L section here that's where I put this for the here to number 36 because I think
after 36 we jump into my ask as well and then you're going to have some files for the log in file create
of de files and then you can take a look at those references if you like.
Then we have all inclusive because we're doing some issues.
We're doing some something here and then we need an enclosed folder but this is just for reference.
Then you've got your practical app and then remember that you also have you see a mess.
So you can just drop your whole CMOS.
Now this is the CMOS project.
OK.
This is what we are going to be creating After you learn ph HP.
So I don't recommend you installing this right away out of the box.
I recommend you having this as a reference to your project that you will be creating in this course.
OK.
So you're going to have those two folders there.
Remember the CMOS which is going to have our project the demo which is going to have the lecture's references
that we are going to go and learn in this course.
Remember that they not we did not in sync and they may not be in sync.
So you look at the names ok if statements you want to have some information about if statements go there
switch statements variables if you need something to go by.
OK.
Anyway thank you.
Hopefully this helps you out and I'll see you in the next lecture guys.
Take care.