OK so we're doing a lot of cool stuff here we going to fast because I already went to some of the things
where you guys in the scores we already know what to do right.
So the next part is we got to jump in to comments.
Let's good to are in.
Go back here we got that taken care of.
We got this post count taken care of.
Let's go and move this
comeback and move this to the site.
Organized it's a little bit
OK.
So we got that.
I'm going to press shift command shift tab and that's Should We're back here.
Most editors that would go and hopes would go that's that's what I don't like messing around with that
right.
They should be.
This is the row.
All right.
So
that is the role I'm going to put this come in here.
That's what that is.
So let's go to the next little box here that has some data here that we want we want to select all the
user's comments.
OK that's going to be a biggie there.
OK.
So I'm going to come I'm going to.
Copy it and let's go to that user specific.
Let's see.
Let's put this up a little bit.
Indication and the user specific.
So let's create a function that is going to say get all user comments look how simple that was right.
We know we don't need all this Querrey So we're going to make this easier.
Perfit and this is going to be resold.
Now we're going to think about the querido right.
What is it.
How is our querido where Kuwaiti where the Kuwaiti that is so Spanish.
All right.
So get users get oh user comments.
So how can we achieve this.
Well we are going to select we're going to have to basically this is not just a user comments but post
user comments get all posts user comments.
OK.
That's going to be a little bit of you know problem.
But don't worry I got your back on this and just going to take all that off remember that we do have
to count it at the end.
That's fine.
So we're going to have to join the tables here because we want to access the post table.
We're going to have to enter a joint and I did this in the course I didn't do it a lot but I did at
one time.
So you should have an idea.
We're going to join these tables the posts and the comments on something they are related to.
Well we know that we have the post ID on the we know other post ID is equal to the comments.
Now when we are talking about specific columns after we join the table we need to the friends she gave
them.
Sometimes they do have the same name for the columns so might as well provide to us this syntax here.
Dot post ID OK so we separated by a dot.
Thats how we differentiate some of the columns because sometimes they have the same name.
So the post posts ID is equal to the comments and its print is down a bit.
Well thats
the comments that comment on the score ID.
OK.
So we know that in the comments table we have this column right.
Lets double check it though.
We dont want to make a mistake right.
Well we actually do want to make a mistake when our So Rousse and we can see the comment post.
Id not comment is comment.
So there we go.
But but this is comments because this is the comments table thats the name of the table.
So we were differentiating by the name of the table.
Like I mentioned sometimes they do have the same gay the same name same column name.
But we have to use a table name first separated by dots with the column names.
So we make sure that we do that.
Let's return this.
Now we're not done yet because we won all the comments.
OK.
But we won the comments for their use of that's a little den.
So we were steaming somewhere right.
So where as my Phylis bring these down.
Where the user ID equals and it's actually break this into that they love the end user.
It's such a handy function right.
We should be getting something if we didn't make a mistake.
So let's go back to the index and what we need to do.
Records count records and put that function in there and that should give us while we want.
Now let's look at this from a quick.
Right now we have two comments.
We refresh we have those two comments.
Let's come back here.
Take that away from there.
And let's bring it all the way up right there.
So
but we see the last two comments I use are.
So if we go to comments we only have 2 comments right.
But if we gave that comment a no that another poster ID that does not belong to these user issue change.
So let's go to browse and we can see that the user only has one pulls and that pulls us to comments.
But if you give that comment a different post Id like 140 it should change to one comment for the user.
So 140.
Now go back to comments browse.
And this is give a comment here 140.
Let's go back to our dashboard and let's refresh and you can see that I come in one to one
who says he has three comments here three active.
But we haven't got to that yet.
We are working on this here perfects.
Let's go and jump into the next section.
Next lecture Take care guys how fun.