High in this video we are going to be learning about global variables and scope.
Right.
And the scope when we say scope and BHB we have to scope's local scopes and global scope where we say
scope we mean the environment the context in which that specific element is available.
So for example if we have a global variable that global variable is going to be available outside the
functions and inside the functions it's going to be a global variable.
So if it's if it's available outside and inside the function we say that is available in a global scope
if it's available only inside a function we say that is only available inside is only available in a
local scope.
So let's go ahead and find out how that works.
There's open on co-editors and let's do a save as on the black that BHP follow that we always use.
Let's call this scope scope ph.
Let's close this let's open the browser.
All right.
So let's create a variable called adds here.
Let's first put a PH B tags.
OK so first we create a variable called X and then we are going to set the value for this one is going
to say outside.
Then we're going to create a function and we're going to call this function convert right.
Right.
And we are going to be using December 1 trying to change it inside its function to a value called Insight.
All right.
My thing is that I want to show you I want to echo these variable.
Outside right now and then I want to call and actually call the function and try to change it with a
function and then call it here again.
So I wait to see if the function changes the value of it.
So we see that this variable here we are echoing the first ad that means this one here because it starts
from the top right.
It's outside then we go inside the function we call the function right here.
And we try to change the variable to a different value but it doesn't change it.
So we do still get the outside again when we Agway down here.
OK.
Now remember this is the global scope right here outside.
This is a local scope.
OK so now how can we make these variable here global.
Can we make it available outside any sort of function.
So just in case I wanted to change the value of this variable later on INSIDE a function how can I make
it available because right now BHB is not even recognizing that this is where we try to change here.
It's not even taking the change.
Well the first thing that you need to do is actually right you use this keyword called Global and then
you put the variable here semi-colon.
So you declare this variable global throughout the whole script.
Now we can use a variable and change value over any way we want.
We can do whatever we want with this variable and watch what happens on the left side.
When I save my document here you see a change to inside now because now we are using the variable globally
this variable right here.
We bring it inside a function.
We change it and then we echo.
So first of all we echo the first one.
Right.
And then we go inside if we call the function right here and we go inside and change the value over
and then eggcorn here.
So if I go ahead and echo this again
we see that we get another inside because the values already change.
But they I can go ahead and make another function here and change the value of it.
All right.
So this is what we mean when a variable is global and this is what we mean when we say that is available
in a global scope meaning outside and inside.
All right.
So anyways I hope this actually gave you a the information you were looking for.
Hopefully you know you got this.
If you don't you can always ask me a question.
I'm always available for my students but this is what global variables and global and local schools
are right and local variables too.
So if this is in the local scope of course this is going to be a local variable.
Right.
But anyway thank you so much for watching this video and I see you the next one.
Take care.