Hi welcome back.
This is really getting really exciting right.
Well on the last video we saw how we created a class and we added a method inside the class.
Now we need to find a way to actually start using those functionalities right.
So let's go ahead and open our coeditor what we are.
While we will be doing this lecture here is instantiating instantiating a we're going to create an instance
of this class.
Right.
We're going to make this work basically we are going to be calling the functionality inside the class.
So we know that we have this class here called car right.
And you can call this an object already because we have the functions right.
We have we will have the properties there.
Well we don't have it yet but the way we create an object is we need to instantiating this class here.
All right.
Now we'll show you in a minute how we do that this first before I Confucianist first do Aceves here
and it's to on underscored three.
All right.
And right now I have a whole bunch of different turns turns for the things that we do in programming
and you need to learn a couple of them.
All right.
So that way you can be in sync to what's going on right.
So we have the class here and we are checking methods.
But right now we don't need to do that.
Let's just take this off.
All right.
So we created a class right here.
We create a functionality.
How do we start using this functionality.
That is the question right does the million dollar question.
Well very simple.
We use the name of this here but we first use a keyword called new and then we use that name with parentheses.
Boom.
Done that.
That way we can start using this.
Now we need another way of actually holding this value here.
This is very simple to when we create raise or create functions to that we save into variables and do
things with it very similar to that.
So what I want to do is create a variable and then I use over well to hold this this class here with
all the functionality inside.
Then I use terms that are very normal right.
Basically what we are what we will be doing is creating a new instance of this because we can create
many of them.
So I'm going to actually call this let's just call this.
All right let's just.
All right let's call the BMW.
All right.
You know I'm so descriptive with my names.
And so now I create a new object.
This is an object now.
All right.
So we created a new instance of this class here but you can actually call this an object right because
an object is you know a group of data related that you know by a common theme.
Right.
So this is an object now that we have this W of we can go ahead and you know what we can create another
one we can call this I don't know Mercedes and thus for me say these bands I like nice cars.
What can I say.
Mercedes Benz right there right.
So we create another instance of the object of this class I'm sorry and you can call these objects if
you want.
And how do we start using this.
How do we start using the most the functionality.
How do we start moving the wheels drive of the BMW for example.
So right now what I want to do is I'm want to move the wheels of that BMW right.
And this is just a figure of speech.
We know that we can move the wheels would echo.
But imagine that we had this whole bunch of functionality inside this method here.
How do we activate it.
Very simple.
We grabbed the BMW right.
We use a minus and the arrow a greater than symbol and we say you know why.
We moved house wheels.
Now BMW boom and the wheels are moving right here.
OK.
This is how you start using it so you grab that object.
The name of it the instance and you say move wheels.
All right.
So we have that what about these other Mercedes what are we going to do with this car.
We've got to raise.
Yes why not.
This race.
So I'm going to grab this one too and I'm going to say you know what I need you to race.
You need to go with this guy too.
So let's go ahead and ask for it.
Let's use the same thing here.
Mercedes and then move wheels.
Boom cities right in front of it when they're being built is going to win this race is behind right
now.
Who's going to win.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Let's win.
All right.
Whoops.
We saved it.
We're supposed to save it on the on the fall here.
I don't know why I keep saving that there.
There we go.
So be in though.
When in front of a gang and so on that's all.
So you get my point or we can call this many times and we can create as many instances as we want to.
This is how we can start using the functionality inside that class.
Right.
So anyways Hopefully you were able to learn a lot on this one here.
And if you have any questions I'm here 24/7 we're not 24/7 but I'm here for you.
So these students I know this was really exciting for you because it was really exciting for me.
Now you might not see a lot of functionality but keep this in mind we are actually creating objects
now.
We are actually creating functionality that is that you can use to create games.
Right.
There are a lot of programming languages out there that you could use like Java Sea or any other language
to create really really really high definition games.
But anyway ph are a really great language to learn and this will help you knowing all P is going to
help you create really advanced web sites.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you.
And that's one