All right welcome back.
Many students in this lecture we are going to be modifying our headers a little better to actually receive
from a parameter here.
The right way.
Right now we are sending in just a email but hitter's actually are formatted in a different way.
So let me just show you what I mean with the headers and I'm talking about the mail function.
So right now let me go to my file manager right here.
Let's go to the contact page right mortifies a little bit.
And what we need to do is show you
right here and he's had a variable year there where we need to format this is with a string that says
from without capital F F R M colon and then we concatenate this all right.
And now what we've got to get is the right way of doing it doing this.
All right so let me just go we can call college and see a mass and that this is contact contact up ph
B.
Believe us right here we go.
Now let's do it.
So I'm going to do Rico Suave a G.M. dot com or.
And then.
Hello Rico.
How are you.
All right.
It's me.
Whatever.
I'm not going to even put a girl's name or something there.
My wife would get upset.
Hi this is.
I don't know someone whatever.
There we go.
And by the way my wife would not get upset.
I was just joking around.
All right guys.
Don't laugh at me.
You might have that problem not me.
All right.
So
if I go now and look at that parameter I can assure you right now that he says Rekos Swaby email and
now is from Rico Suave G.M. dot com.
And I don't know who this guy is but I guess that's Rico Suave here.
That's his e-mail address.
All right.
But anyway as you can see now is for Madhi the right way we got whoops make this a little more.
There we go.
Now we got Rico Swaby there and we got the tetes there.
All right.
So it's working now.
Again this is in large there so what you don't see my personal information.
All right.
So thank you so much for watching this lecture and I see you in the next one.
Take care.