All right welcome back.
I'm a student so hopefully you are at the root of your directory and whatever hosting company you are
if you are here on Go Daddy.
Perfect.
If not don't worry about it we can still do it.
All right.
So we are in the public on the score.
This is going to be my web directory.
So here is where we're going to need to be or see him as follows.
But we also need to create a database right.
So let's go to our local host
them BHB my admin right in here.
We're going to do an export on our CMOS.
All right so we choose or see a mass make sure that you use click on the CMOS.
Now any any other tables you're going to see a mess.
All right then we're going to go to export and then we're going to click go and we're going to download
the database file which is going to end with a Escudo extension because that is for the sequel.
All right.
I mean sequel as well.
All right so now we got that.
So the next thing is we've got to go to our local host and we've got to compress our CMOS into a zip.
All right.
So I and my Mac I just right click and compress mass in some of you if you using Windows where you need
to do is right click and use 7 zip or think when Zip is programmed to use to compress into a zip folder.
All right.
Basically we're compressing this so that way we can all bloated to go daddy easily.
So let's go here.
Go Daddy or whatever hosting you're using and click upload.
We're going to upload it to the root directory and then along the way it is 6 4 4.
All right.
That might cause a permission problem later on but we'll fix that.
We'll see if we can fix it.
But anyway this is the permission for the full folders.
Anyone going to choose a file that I need to upload.
I'm going to go to my HD Doug's and see him as I already compress this before so that's why I have it
right here see him as that zip.
All right so make sure that you compress the whole folder from the lectures.
All right open.
I see him has already had this in the directory.
I already have it.
So that's why he's telling me that but I'm just going to say yes for you just because you don't have
it you're not going to get that pop up.
So I already completed this.
I'm going to refresh.
I think that he has something that I can refresh useful refresh if not just going to refresh it.
And we have the folder right here that zip right click and I'm going to extract and extract right there.
All right.
Now that I have extract that should see the folder now right here.
If I click on it you're going to see that I have all the files in there so I'm going to go back right
and there's a couple of things that we are going to change.
They're in the database.
But before that.
All right we need to create a database so I'm going to make this lecture very sure and let you you know
blow this to your server and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thank you so much