All righty then I hope you're having a great day.
I'm having an awesome day today and we're going to be a really cool feature to our posts edit page.
So let's go to the to any polls that you have available at school click on it.
And here we notice that every time we click Update we don't have anything that says that our post has
been updated.
So what I want to do is right here a ball.
I want to add something that says you know your post as being a day that you want to see a click here
and he will direct me to that.
Add to that post or he will direct me to view other polls to read it.
All right.
So basically some tetes with some links here.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So the first thing that I want to do is to do that we've got to go to the ad admin for Slash includes
end it on the score post postop BHB.
Just go to your edit post that page be page right now below the update quavery right here.
All right.
You see that we got all this out of the polls and then right below that of the Querrey after they confirm
function we're going to be adding that link is going to be something like this post of.
And I'm going to show you right now it is going to be a little more advance of course but I want to
show you the basic functionalities of it.
If I click update you can see that we have a test right here.
This post updated.
Of course I misspelled that a little bit.
But all right it's going to be really nice.
And then we want some callers here to actually let us know that gives a little more warning right.
That has been updated.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So let's create a paragraph right here and let's pool this stuff in there.
All right.
So this part of graph is going to say pull update it and put a dot there and then we're going to put
a link.
So let's put an H ref tag here an anchor tag.
And this one is going to say View polls
force polls updated view post.
All right so let's check that out.
See how that looks.
Update it and we can see that it says post updated.
And then if you want to see the polls we will see it.
But right now we click on it.
It just refreshes the page.
All right.
So we need to put that link there.
So the function idea that we need to do it here is a first thing is we need to take the user to post
BHB but we need to get out of here because Get out of this directory twice because we are includes all
we need to go to the root.
And that's how you go back.
And then we need to pass it in the ID because we want to go to this specific posts not to every polls.
Right.
So the idea would be so let's pass the parameter questionmark and then P underscore Id remember that
arrived and then it's going to be equal to what the polls ID and the polls ID that is going to be equal
to is this one right here.
That's the one in there you are.
All right.
So let's put some brackets right here and paste it and that's it.
That should be good to go in there.
Let's check it out.
All right.
And of the post now we got that and we click on it and we'll go to that specific post.
Perfect.
So it's working.
Let's go back to it.
All right.
Now I want to add some other something else because right now if I'm looking at all this it looks the
same like anybody could miss this right so I want to put like some colors are wrong here.
Big green or red color saying you know what.
Calling Attention So let's do that.
And I want to be using a class building class with this framework.
And one of the helper classes actually in this class is going to be called and there are many of them
but going to be just going to use this one B.G. hyphen said sess.
All right.
That's going to give me that nice green color.
And if I click up of the poster you can see now that we have this nice green color.
They're telling us that the post is being updated if you want to view it.
You can view it right here.
All right.
Perfect.
Let's go back to it.
All right.
Now I want to add something else I want to add another link.
Sane or do other polls or edit more polls.
All right so let's add the link in there and it's going to be right here in Khattak.
Ref is closing.
Let's just say View
other reports or edit.
Actually
just another link there polls.
All right.
Let's close in.
And we should put this one here before this before this one here right here.
All right.
So five of data right here we can see.
They said or all right let's just put something in between there.
So that way we can for you here.
All right.
Space and that's part of the link there.
I don't I don't want to make it part of the link.
I don't want these links to be met.
You see the one that would be part of the link so I'm going to take that.
We're out of there.
All right.
So in closing that it's going to put it right here in the middle of the anchor tags of date.
And as you can see they are always right there.
All right.
We can pull more spaces if you want but I think it's clear on what I want to do.
So I want this to take me to this page right here to all the pool speech.
All right so that HSF is going to be easy right.
So polls that PH BE
RIGHT THING WITH ME REALLY good improvement there if you can see that we go.
All right.
So click on edit of the post post of data.
Let's see if this one works and more posts and we can see more polls here.
Let's go back of the polls view polls.
Perfect.
So we had some really cool functionality here to see amassing.
I think he's going to save us a lot of time when we are.
We want to see this instead of us going going crazy.
Right.
We say we all did this.
Let's go back to it.
Now he just took out the slogan again two or three.
All right.
So if I click here of date imagine if I have this link here I will have to go to this site myself.
Go there and then click on that specific post to go so he's saving us a lot of time right.
Perfect.
So I'm glad I was able to teach you this.
Keep going you're doing great.
Be grateful all the time.
All right.
Take care and I'll see you in the next lecture