All right welcome back on this video here we're going to be talking about Constance and Constance are
dissenting as variables is like a container where we can put information in the right data but the only
difference is that it doesn't change.
And well it does have another difference that we defined it with a function.
Now let me give you an example.
You already know how we define a variable.
And if I can get this BHB tag bright We know that we define a variable like this.
Now if you don't know where I am and you are a little lost right now know that I just made a save as
on blank that ph B.
And I called a constant dot ph B.
That's all I did.
I grabbed that blank that ph B file that you have in your course exercise files or you shall have it
in your working file.
Now that you are using and I just read Aceves and renamed it.
Constance dopy.
All right just so so that you know so we know that variables have something like this.
They are like this and we can just go ahead and call them on the screen like this right we can just
print them out and we have number 10 right.
This is how we define a variable dollar sign the name of the variable we assign it a value.
Now Constance We need functions for constant we need this pre-built functions from PH B that they already
defined for us.
We need to actually use them.
So we need to use the function to define these functions going to define a variable for for us.
Well not a variable constant because it's constant.
You can't change the value once you set the value of a constant you can't change it no matter what you
do.
So I'm going to set a constant called name.
I'm going to put the name in the first parameter.
Takes is the name of the constant.
The second divided by a coma is going to be the value.
So I'm just going to name it.
Are you going to give it a value of a thousand.
I could also give it a value of a string if I wanted to.
But in this case I was going to name that and give it the value of a thousand.
Right.
So I'm just going to echo this like this.
As you can see I got a thousand there if we use a dot and it was concatenations here just to make it
go to the next line you can see that.
Now if I try changing this value here for some reason if I say name equals 2000 if I try doing that
I get an error.
Right.
So I mean that is a problem right.
Well it's actually not a problem is actually very good.
We've got variables and we can do whatever we want with variables and we can change the value of a variable
we can come here and say number is going to be equal to a thousand.
Now when you see that and then we come back here again and change your variable name to say Edwyn.
You see that what you can do that have with a constant.
Right.
So you just keep in mind that this is how we define a constant by using this function define the first
parameter is the name.
The second would be the value.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching.
And I see you in the next lecture.
Take care