All right so now we have a database.
We have a table.
We need to connect to it.
So let's go to our editor.
Let's open it up and let's create a folder.
Inside I see a mess.
All right so anyway here right click on it and let's create a folder here called includes.
And the reason why actually I was creating a file sorry about that.
Right click on the new folder includes the reason why we want to put up includes for this because we
don't want these files that we're going to be creating here into the public area.
You see all these folders going to be in the public domain where we put our CMS system so we one day
conclude to have a really secure data that in there.
All right.
So in saying it this include less right click on it and create a new file.
And I'm going to call these the b b this is the father we are going to be using to create our connection.
All right so let's open up the HP tagging here.
We don't have to close it but I always like to close it anyway.
BHB knows that every day if you're not writing the amount this file you don't have to close it.
But I like to if you don't write if you're not writing anything that needs like this file here and then
be that BHP this is going to be the connection.
I'm pretty sure we're not going to be using NEHTA mail.
But again I'm just the way I am anyways for this is for us to connect to a database we need a function
call my Eskew our connect and we need to process some parameters.
All right so we can this is really easy right now with past local holes this is always going to be the
name mostly for all servers even online or in real life.
They're going to be a local holes and then we are going to be passing it user name and then we are going
to be passing it the password in this case is empty.
And then the next one is a database name and thus it seems this is the easy way of connecting to it.
All right is not the correct way and surely the correct way of doing it.
And that's just a sign this is a variable.
It's not 100 percent correct way.
Not that bad either but I'd like to.
Another way that I think is actually better.
So we're going to use that if they here just to make sure that our connection.
It's good.
You know remember the steam is going to return true or false to us and we are assigning a variable to
it so that way we can manage it a lot easier.
All right so let's see if that connection is true.
We're going to see we are connected.
All right.
If it's not we're not going to see anything.
So let's make sure that we close that let's open this.
Click on it.
Let's first see this file right here and then just click on it.
So reason doesn't want to click on it lets you go manually here.
I don't know what is going on with my editor.
The edge is maybe a crash or something I don't know.
Let's just go ahead and google locally is this.
All right let's go ahead and include the view right here.
We are connected.
All right.
So we know we are connected there.
There we go.
Now it works.
All right so that's the easiest way to connect to a database.
Let me show you the way that I like to do it.
Let me show you two more ways of doing actually the B and probably seen this before in mine.
So we're going to say the user We're going to say localhost to this.
So we just type we just save everything in variables.
That's the way we do it.
Some of us do it and we put these values in here instead of this.
All right.
Now I always like to be very secure with my data.
I'm going to show you the most secure way of doing this.
And a more secure way of actually connected to a database and have all these information here is by
converting these values into constants.
Right now we can go ahead and convert this into variables and put these values in here just.
That just makes it easier for us to use this function right here.
Right.
Makes it more organized.
But I want to put all these value what my idea is to make this as constants but it would take me a long
time to write each constant down or I don't know I have a really cool little trick that I do and that
I put all these values into an array.
So for example I may do that Kito the array the host and I just put locavores in here.
Just copy this year.
Right.
And then you copy and paste or all of it written down.
And then of course there's the user TV pass.
And if you don't remember how to make grades go back to the lecture.
And that way you can get some more.
I know.
You know we've got lives and we get pretty busy and we forget.
So I'm just assigning the values here to the array.
So we've got to accumulate all these data all these data right here into the array called the B.
That's all I'm doing right now.
So don't get confused on that is really easy.
All right so we have the key in this array call the host is going to have this data and that the user
is going to have this data and so on and so on.
All right.
What I really want to do is convert this into constants so I'm going to use a function that is going
to loop through this array is going to uppercase this and is going to grab this value and convert it
into what is going to grab this whole thing and convert it into a constant.
I'll show you right now.
Remember the loop that loops through on the rate for each member remember that.
So that for each loop is the one that does that.
And we're going to loop through the array called D-B as what as a key we can do it like this.
And the key is going to be value right.
So we're going to have a couple of things we're going to have the key which is right here we're going
to use that.
The reason why we were using this one here right now.
I forgot the little arrow here because we're going to be uppercase in this.
Right so that's why I'm using this one this extra right here.
You probably saw this one before.
You're right and we're going to be using the keys so you can also use it for each like this.
Right.
So the function to make constants is like this if you don't remember and just writing it down real quick
and we can.
It's going to be something like this right.
If we make it a constant we make the first feel the constant.
It would be something like this local's So this would be a concept right here but I'm going to use this
function this loop here to make it for me.
All right.
So and then I use the function the fine say the function can use another function as D or 2 upper and
this is just going to uppercase the key in the key right now is this one.
Remember we need to uppercase that for a constant right to make a.
Constance.
Constance right.
Well so anyways it's actually really good practice to do the operation.
So let's convert the key that's actually uppercase and say here we just put a coma and we include the
value there also.
All right so I think we're good here.
If everything came out the right way.
Well actually before we do that we need to convert this into constants because right now this function
is doing it for us.
So right now we go like this and check it out.
Well it's actually working right now too.
It is still working.
All right.
Scott is converting it for us right now.
Actually this this is the one actually this is not this is the one connected right now so that's why
we're getting this data right here because we got this on here connecting.
So now it's not working so right now what we need to do is we need to use constants that we already
have because our loop is making it for us the host with uppercase everything because everything is uppercase
already for us the we pass and the name
you mean right.
So we go back to.
We still connect if I make any mistake here you see that we get all of this.
So right now we get this going right here and if we save it we are connected.
So this is just a little trick I learned along the way to do.
And hopefully you can use it to in your applications.
All right so now that we are connected to the database we need to go to the next lecture.
Anyway thank you so much and I see you then