All right so we have this form working with their images or images are going to the right place but
we need to put some data here and submit it to a database.
All right so we need to do the query to do that.
So we are an admin includes at pool stoppie HP right.
And we this is where we left off last last time.
All right.
Perfect.
So the next step here is to do the query.
Now I do have the equerry copy and it's kind of long.
So I just got to warn you on that and I'll paste it right here.
All right.
So all we have is just a normal query here to insert into posts and then we have the parameters enclosed
in parentheses.
As you can see all in one line divided by code my These are the fields in our table here.
And we discussed this earlier.
These are exactly the same columns actually in our table.
All right.
So that's the first part of the query.
Remember usually this goes in one line.
All of it and the rest that I'm going to be pasting here right now in a minute we're going one line
two but we don't have that much space is good to divide it especially for your understanding.
So if I faced this in here we're going to follow the same query to concatenate this with this.
All right so remember this is all usually all in one line but it's too long.
So we have to improvise.
So we're concatenating and the next step is values and we enclose that in parentheses and then we pass
it in the variables from here.
All these variables were passed down here to this call for this columns.
So we are inserting values for each of these columns down here and these values are coming from our
form.
Keep that in mind.
We are also using single calls for each of these values since they are strings.
Well this one is not a string so you don't have to use a court for that because it won't be a string.
It will be a number.
All right.
So post-Idol pulls.
Here.
There's another thing that you have not seen and is that we are sending as a value a function.
All right.
This is going to format this date right here that we are sending in and make it look good in in the
site in the database when he goes there.
All right so no that is now functioning You can also look that up in the be there and there is a lot
of functions for the date.
I mean there is a lot of ways that you can format your dates so that's a different topic.
OK.
And has you I can make a coarsen that that's how that's how much information there is on the date.
So we're sending the post image here that they feel in a database post content that's way single codes
and coma.
So remember that you can copy and paste all of this.
Another way of doing this actually would be to divide this all all these values each of them into queries
and concatenate it with an assignment operator.
But I'm not going to go into details with that right now.
Let's go ahead and say this.
Hopefully you.
You got you got it down.
Copy and let's try this form out right.
That's stuff that we've been looking for.
So let's go and do it.
All right so I'm just going to click here and we have an arrow there that's why I click there to just
make sure that we don't have any errors in saying that we have something on line 23.
We have a mistake line 23 we have an on expected.
All right.
So because we didn't copy the we don't have the dollar sign.
Here we go.
Let's get it done.
We didn't copy it right.
And you believe it.
Yes.
That's bad paste.
All right so let's just put something like javascript here.
Post category is just going to be three or whatever and others are just going to be me for now.
And my name is my last name is Flash.
Like I was about to write there the start of this is going to be draft actually to publish.
It doesn't really matter.
This is for the most patient purposes only.
We're going to set a different image so we can know that that's what we're doing.
Let's send Sontag's javascript Korsh class right.
And let's just put some content.
This course is great.
And the minute that see it on the database post we need to refresh it when he says that pulls.
And let's see if he did.
All right.
One thing that I want to show you right here before we go any further is that we have a problem we have
a mistake somewhere and we need to check for that.
And right now I'm going to take this and make a little function to check on this because we have been
making queries over and over again like this if not actually we have not send it I'm sorry we have not
send it.
I thought we did and we had a mistake but when we didn't paste this this is basically we'd make it just
like we would a category's would make a variable here and we hold the connection in my ask you I query.
I don't I copy that down.
I'm sorry about that.
Let's check it out now.
So it should work.
But anyway we're going to do that function just to check to see if the Querrey worked.
So we don't have to be doing copy and pasting all the time.
I just going to write anything here since I don't want to take your time too much.
And this I got to write my name please.
And then let's just do it right away.
Right.
Well the fields are there.
Let me see.
I think it will help me out.
Yeah it's helping me out.
And actually if I just yeah it's helping me out filling it up.
For me this is not helping me out here.
And let's get an image real quick we'll go and let's publish.
Let's see if it works.
Right working but we've still got to make that function anyway.
Refresh.
All right.
So we got the idea right here automatically we have the category and this idea might look might be different
for you.
Don't worry about it.
Javascript to push all do everything is in the right order.
That day came out good here.
Image placeholder This is the content post tags comment and publish perfit everything in our database
came out good.
Let me show you the function real quick and you should know the function.
But we're going to make it a function and there's a little piece of code actually it's not even a function
yet.
If
not quavery right remember that.
Well we've got to make a little function of me because I'm tired of typing this am I.
And you should be tired too.
You should be making this easier right.
I should be making this easy let's say Querrey failed and then we can Kartini a function to do the error
for us and we pass it in that connection.
All right.
So let's say we make a mistake right here and I just put another Colma here at the end just you know
just checking this out
and just going to do whatever here and just publish we got an area right here where we feel you have
an error in your it's near line 1 or whatever right.
Well this is working we know that already.
And what I want to do is take this to a function Yeah I'm a little tired here of salt.
I just cannot command Etzel control that's it.
And let's take it this two functions are functions fall and we have a functions right here.
All right let's take it in and let's put it all the way on top here.
Let's call this function call frm Querrey.
Right.
Actually confirms so shorter like that we don't have to write anything now but actually yeah that's
fine.
Let's leave it like this because I just don't want to write too much.
All right.
So while we need to do to call this function then we need to pass it a parameter so we need to say the
result here or something like that where resoled.
All right.
And make sure that you put it right here because we're going to be passing his parameter from somewhere
else.
Make sure that's good.
All right.
Let's check it out.
Let's go to our polls and.
All right.
Take this out with us.
First confirm
and put it right here.
Let's is make sure that this is confirmed and we're going to be confirming this guy right here right.
So we're going to pass it in that.
And there you should know how to do this.
We did this before.
And let's see if it works better.
All right.
And we have a narrow but it's not confirmed confirmed create post Querrey.
And let's go to functions whether we forget here now resort to this.
Right.
Well we need to actually return
right return result.
We need to return it back.
All right let's do it right now.
Let's do it again.
Actually I think it was fine.
But anyway let's go to this this this and publish.
Oh you know what it is.
We don't need to return actually anything.
Sorry about that guys.
We need to do the global global connection.
Why would I need to return to this.
We don't need to return it.
We can just call it like this.
All right.
So enter into this into that is foolish and that's it.
It's working.
All right.
So as you can see here what we're doing here is we created a function.
We're passing it pass in this variable and to the function which is here and these functions taking
care of that connect.
Now every time we need to call this we just call confirm and we can confirm anything.
All right.
You want to make him more descriptive.
Go ahead confer inquiry make him more descriptive and go back here and change the name of course and
that's it.
Let's take this out of here since we don't have that mistake anymore.
Refresh identify function confirm querulous save and let's make sure we save it in our functions file.
All right answer.
All right.
So it's working.
And hopefully that will help you out.
Make a little bit make this a little bit more dynamic OK.
Perfect.
It's going to speed up our production.
All right so I see you in the next lecture I think we're done for this with this for now and later on
we're going to be doing some more great stuff.
So see you in the next one.