We are displaying some data from the comments page here and we took here some of the crud for now for
the acronym And you know create a read of day in the lead.
So we are taking care the read part of it.
All right.
So what I want to do is if I go to the post right here we have a little forum here what I want to do
is add some fields like the older name maybe the email.
And when the user clicks on this form we want to submit this data to a database and then show it here
in the comments site right here perfect.
Right.
So let's go ahead and do that right now let's do this try to do it in this lecture and let's just copy
this.
They've actually just copy the whole thing so that way we don't have a mistake Ray here and I'm going
to put a name put right here.
Tets and is going to have a name of author is author actually comment author G's come in Author.
Perfect.
Let's put another div around here and let's just say this one that would be the e-mail comment.
E-mail and this just change the type on the e-mail so we have some validation there.
Automatically let's add a class of that way looks pretty
and form control we make this look beautiful and it's going to make it all across this screen across
the bottom of the container which holds that comment section.
Sure you know what I mean.
You see that it's going to make all the way across.
We can fix this later on right now.
I kind of like it.
We've got to leave it like this for now.
All right.
So let's put a label on this thing here because right now there's no label and this is for author as
do another label for email
email and make sure that we've put this on here too.
All right.
Perfect.
Right.
And let's do another level for
the tets area here and just say come here.
Maybe your comment is a great thing when you're building your own CIMS is that you can put whatever
you want right.
Comment.
There we go.
Firfir looking great.
Looking good.
All right.
This image here we're going to put a name actually of you.
We're going to get this ready for the post right.
Create comment.
We're going to call it underscore create on the score comment and that type is going to be a summit
that's fine.
Let's go ahead and catch that data somewhere so that way we can test it.
All right.
Right here.
So let's open BHB attacked first.
Right.
Looking good.
Let's make this a little bigger so you can see just in case it's too small for you.
If set are right.
All right don't fall asleep on me.
All right.
Hopefully you're getting this.
This we have done this before so I think if you're following me you're doing great.
So create common is to not create update create comment.
Where are you thinking Geez I need more coffee.
If you're getting some coffee ready you a student please give me some and send it to me with our teleportation
software that we have in our computer.
I can smell it.
All right.
If I said let's echo something out while we want to echo let's echo the altar.
Why not.
So let's echo it.
But first we need to put a name field here.
All right.
And did we put it.
No we didn't.
We just put the label.
All right.
Polls again there I go.
They are go.
So what is it again.
Comment.
ALTER I thought I did put it in there.
Unbelievable.
All right.
You see what happens when you work a lot hours you and you ask yourself a question and then you answer
back yourself.
I just ask for my own question like I was talking to somebody else.
That's not good.
We need to sleep a little more OK.
If you are working a lot hours make sure that you get some rest.
OK.
All right so
just put a name fuel here.
All this content coming content.
All right.
Let's get to
Eckel
and let's just say Walter.
All right let's check it out.
Let's check it out.
Let's do this right.
I am the author.
Yes.
And I'm going to put an e-mail and he's going to give me some validation problem.
There you see that.
That type e-mail does this for us.
Beautiful.
He's going to put a example.
G-mail submit what.
Oh of course the bull's eye the bull's eye.
He can't have that.
Let didn't check that line.
Twenty nine what are we doing here.
And we didn't even check what are we checking here what what are we doing here.
We're checking the id o polls Id like 29 What are we checking.
Of course we are submitting somewhere else right.
Whereases is this for submitting to.
Is this for submitting any.
Do we have a form.
Yes we do have a form but we don't have any action on it.
Let's put some action on it to do an action.
Let's put some method to how can we forget all this data.
I'm telling you I need my coffee.
All right.
Let's go ahead and do it again post.
All right let's cross our fingers guys and ladies too.
I know some ladies are taking this course and the male example G-mail.
There we go.
Submit Oh undefined create alter.
Are you kidding me.
Undefine
of course we're not creating an alter we are.
We have a comment there and you probably saw that you didn't even tell me.
All right.
After this lecture I'm taking and getting some coffee for sure and getting some comfort out of this.
Seriously.
But you know I like arrows anyway so I like to go and spectres and it's cool.
Submit and there we go.
We have some data coming in.
Perfect.
After like 100 tries we did it.
If you follow me and you didn't miss semi-state tons down on you because you are supposed to see the
day before I do it right.
My student.
One of the best students in the world.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this video here and on the next lecture we are going to be able
to insert some data.
All right.
So hopefully when we finish up on the next one.
Thank you.
And I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.