Hi welcome back.
I'm really happy that you made it to Section 6.
You've got to be learning some really good stuff here when you reinforce what you already learned.
Right.
So this is going to be awesome.
All right.
Lecturer So let's go ahead and do this.
So we are in less in Section sits here and you should be on the practical app and on the sets that BHB
right double checking that because I know some of you would take some time off.
All right so he asking us to make a form that's limited to one that one had to pull supernova.
Then we just want to echo that value and see it right.
So go ahead and post a video create a little form and catch it with a super super global and let's equate
that see it on the browser right.
That see it right here on the middle here.
All right so make sure you do everything right here.
All right so post a video and you should be able to do that.
It should be very simple for you since we already did it.
If not go back to the video rewind it and just keep looking at that video over and over until you learn
it.
All right so positivity don't cheat.
All right so I'm assuming that you did it and you did it successfully because I'm a good teacher.
I believe that in my heart but hopefully you believe that too.
But anyways so let's go ahead stop Edlund stop talking so much.
Go ahead and start doing this.
All right so let's create a form here and let's make sure he has a method.
Remember that those data method right there right.
And let's make sure he submits the same page sets that ph B.
Now let's create.
We just need one value right.
So I'm just going to create this input is going to be Samit types of MIT name is going to have this
is the name that we're sending into the postal pro-global.
And this is the value it's the value of the book and of course just going to make it different than
the other the rest.
So let's go back and see what we got here.
All right we have a button here that doesn't do anything.
Perfect.
Now what we need to do is make our BHB.
All right so Paul Superguy over here to catch that value and display it.
So how are we going to do that.
Us we open a BHB tag and make sure that we have that.
And
so now let's use an if statement just to make sure that this has been submitted is really good practice
to do that.
And when we check on that.
But when we sum it up once and it'll happen.
So let's use a function is set to check on that super global right here
for the value submit.
And this is the value that we got on the name right here.
That you.
All right.
So if that exist were going to be echoing on the screen that said That's all we going to be doing and
we're going to copy and paste that here and that's it.
That's all you got to do actually.
Very simple right.
We don't need anything else here unless we have a mistake.
And I think we're good.
So let's go back here let's refresh submit.
As you can see the value right here we are echoing the value.
If I go ahead and refresh again and submit we get value again.
So that's all I ask for you to do in this second year.
All right so hopefully you did this successfully.
Super easy to do and what we've done here.
So hopefully you have as much fun as I did and I see you in the next section you're almost there.
Take care.