Back to the students.
So in this lecture we're going to be facing some links and we have a little issue in the last lecture
that we click on one of these and just because it is breaking our links of course we've got our regular
expressions working.
And if you click here of course is going to be looking for pulls at me because we are creating that.
So now all we need to do is make sure that those links are relative to our whole.
You are all right here.
Our Web site.
OK.
So let's go and let's go to navigation real quick and all we have to do is add it for slashy amass so
that we can take this off if we want to hear.
And as simple as that.
OK.
And everywhere you have that OK see a mass
house
carry.
Now come back here click on this while that's working.
And it is working and that's working.
Of course we need to take care of this bad boy right here.
And can you actually tell me how we can take care of this guy.
Well guys come on we already did this super easy or we have to do is do that same thing we did to post.
Right.
So let's come back here.
Let's go to the Access file here.
I'm going to actually copy this and paste it.
That's how simple it is.
And then here what are we going to be looking for Category 1 this.
You are out to be category.
And we're going to be looking for this guy here category.
And one thing that I have to actually make sure is that I know OK.
So just say Scott to go free.
And
I think that's what he says there.
Yeah that's all we're looking for.
Let's save it.
Come back here.
Let's see.
Let's see this ng action of course that's not going to work because that's category number wise and
52.
We have to fix that link.
Let's just come back here and this just right.
Category 2.
There we go see that let's go fix the link.
I think that's an obligation and that's this guy right here.
Let's just remove all that
and
that's it.
That's all he needs to do.
Actually you can use this for a quick let's see cat I d am I doing the right.
Let's see.
Yeah let's come back here.
Category that we go up which B category and then we go we got something there.
So as you see there this is pretty pretty pretty simple.
Pretty powerful too no regular expressions.
Again I can not recommend this enough even if you don't take my regular expression course.
I always get annoyed because it's super useful.
OK.