Welcome back my dear student in this lecture here we're going to try to finish this as much as we can.
Now we have a couple of things that we've got to work on.
First of all this form right now if you try to submit it that way it is would not submit if you put
something in.
Yes it will submit it.
Well it's not going to submit but it's going to redirect us.
So let's go to functions real quick and let's check out the code responsible for that
as you can see that's the only code responsible for that.
And what we need to do is come to registration that BHB and just common to out here because we are not
working 100 percent and we don't want it.
We don't want to do anything with them now.
So if I type something in nothing happens and that's what I want.
So now the next step for us to do here is first of all I want to include a couple of features here.
One of the features is we want to give the user some type of notification that something is wrong with
their form so they could fix it.
Right.
Because right now they try to submit something in and they get the speech they don't know what in the
world is going on right.
That's one thing.
Another thing that we want to help the user complete this form.
So if he has a name that starts with a we want his foreign to you know if he types his name would a.
Or let's say his name is Alfonso.
He registers something was wrong he's password we don't want him to type in the name again.
Right let's help him out a little bit.
Elisha's autocomplete it for him.
And that's what we're going to be doing with the form.
All right.
So we're going to autocomplete this for him.
And we also want to echo out the same user name that he typed in before that.
All right.
Before the registration fail of course so we can help him mowing a couple of ways.
So let's go to this forum right here and right here on user name we are going to type in these new attribute
called autocomplete.
And we can turn it on.
We can turn it off but it's already off.
Let's turn it on.
There we go.
And now the next one here.
So now if you go back here and let's say my name is Edwin which actually it is.
Right.
And I just want to use a name like this and I type in my email address whatever.
The e-mail address is right and register.
Now if I try to type in Edwyn again guess what not then what if I type in.
Actually it's making me look really bad guys really bad.
Let's go back here.
Autocomplete is on.
So should he be making love.
All right let's let's type in there doing some crazy e-mail.
Hopefully we'll take the e-mail.
There we go.
Yeah yeah yeah I know.
And we are now typing Edwins there.
All right because I needed to refresh the browser guys so you can see that we were already helping the
user out I to do this press tab or enter and they get their name filled in.
All right.
So now the next step for us to do is to actually display back the user name for them.
All right we helping these guys out with our application we just want to make our application and user
friendly guys.
All right.
So let's open up we BHB tag here and let's do a shorthand so that way you can get used to it shorthand
if statement.
It works like this.
We're going to echo out something if we set I know this might be a little confusing you get used to
it.
All right.
So what do we have.
Well if the user name is set this is what this question mark is we want to display it.
The calling is if it's not set else statement.
Basically we want it to be empty.
So let's try that.
Enter as you can see the Edwyn is put in again.
Paolo refresh.
Watch this.
The power is going to stay right there.
You see that we help the user already with that beautiful.
So let's do that for the rest of them well enough for the rest of them.
Let's do that for e-mail and that's it.
We can do that for fast.
Well we wouldn't want to put the same password again make it easier for him right here.
For a complete Zaun this just make sure that we change this to email
and we go guys if you notice are not really holding you by the hand are the end of this.
You know because you already have taken 200 something lectures maybe 300 on lectures already and you
don't need me to hold you by your hand or this.
You already know most of this stuff.
So.
All right.
So Edwin and then Edwin according faculty are calm cool.
He would go
let's see if my brother was going to help me out.
You see how easier that is now for him now even though even if this did not have anything we could just
say Edwin and then type in you see that a lot easier for them just in case they are lazy.
All right.
So I think we're done with his lectures on this lecture with this with this lecture sorry.
Or the next lecture we're going to continue with this and just keep improving it and making it better
for you guys whole.
Hopefully you'll like in his lectures and I'll see you in the next ones ticker