All right so in the last lecture we already were able to input stuff to our database.
Right.
So now let's go to the polls and view all polls and we are able to see right here as you can see.
Now what I want to do on this video here is to include a link on the right hand side here to be able
to delete some of these information.
All right so first let's go ahead and make this available here on this link since it's not working right
now.
So let's go to the navigation and inside our includes in the admin area navigation and let's add it
right here.
So let's say What is the link here to go to that post.
We actually need to send a request.
So Ed it actually the name of the polls right and request would be source
was at post right.
So let's go ahead and check that out.
Let's check that out.
Whoops.
All right.
Come here and we say actually yes that's fine.
Post Oops we did this the wrong way we need to.
HP of course.
I hear from the HP we go.
I was I thinking.
Well.
Or what was not.
Well all right whatever it is that pulls right there as you can see we get that.
All right.
Available to us right.
I got a stumble there a little bit.
So on this one here let's at the end it
actually is not going to be and it's going to be leaked.
We wanted at least some data so we need to go to our post right here.
All right.
So where are we going to be making that request.
Well let's go from the top to the bottom right.
Let's make that request on the same page right here.
And what I want to do is I want to check if something is set
on going to do something right.
So as a matter of fact it's not even here.
Sorry.
It's we need to go to view all polls.
This is where we are right here.
Silly me you post.
Go and this is where we're going to be catching that data.
Great.
We don't want to have much information in the post section right here.
This is just going to do some of the switchin for us in that set.
As a matter of fact we could make another file called delete and have them follow the lead but we are
not going to do that.
So let's do it right here somewhere.
I'm just trying to decide where we have to select polls.
Let's do it down here somewhere.
At the end of the table where we keep our code separate.
Right.
How about that.
So the HP tax and let's check for a submission here.
So if this set
right if this is set and what we're checking is for a get super global right I get requests and we're
going to call this the lead.
And we haven't made this yet but we will right now this check for that.
First let's include a link right here the end of this and this link is going to say the least and I
show you the link in a minute there.
All right.
So the link is going to be right here.
A sheriff.
Let's close it let's open it right here closer there.
Right.
And this is just going to say the least
and if we go to our usual page we can see the link right here.
That's going to delete any of these polls right here.
All right.
And we need to delete this stuff here.
But we'll do that later.
Right now let's concentrate on this.
All right.
So
all right so we've got the lead.
Let's send it some information.
So we're going to send it to the same page.
View all polls
up here.
And we're going to send it in
some information and the information will be delete
lead if I can get it right.
That would be nice.
Delete equals what.
What do we want to this to equal the post ID right here.
Of course we go and we can close it in this if we wanted to.
All right.
So let's go to it now and check it out.
We clicked this is going to take us to another post because silly me forgot that this is going to be
here.
We're sending it to your post instead sending it to post-up.
All right here we go.
Cliggott perfect.
We got this delete one there.
So we're going to delete one.
We're going to lead to.
We're going to delete three.
Right.
All right.
So let's make the Querrey for it now that we are catching it right here let's just say something for
it right here just to check it.
Hello
click it and we get it we see the halo right here in the bottom.
All right.
So that's working.
And what do we want to do.
Well the first thing that we need to do is convert this into the what what is this what is this coming.
This is the lead.
Right.
So we just say posts I suppose Id right here as a matter of fact.
But we can just call it use to differentiate from the top post ID and then we can say let's do a Kohary
and we already have this query probably somewhere in the categories section but just going to make it
really simple to do it anyway.
Select the lead from posts where Id where post Id actually that's the name of the field in our data
table database table equals what.
This one here.
All right.
So you can close this too if you want it to.
And then we are going to send a we're going to send this query so it's going to be the query you call
my ask you Ally query
and we're going to send it in with a connection of course and the query right.
So once that's done that's it.
That's all we've got to do for this.
I think we're good.
All right so let's check it out.
Or another thing we may have to but that's fine that's just too late.
That's fine.
All right.
So I'm going to delete this one
and then delete this one.
There we go.
So he's working with one of the little that content because we need more content right to edit.
So on the next lecture here we're going to be talking about how we can edit some of this and keep going
with of course I think he's doing is going great.
What do you think.
All right.
Perfect.
Thank you so much and I'll see you on the next lecture.
Take care.