All right guys I had to go get something to eat because I was hungry.
I couldn't even record one video without hearing my stomach going crazy.
But anyway.
So here we are.
And that was still working at it.
OK.
Let's organize this just a little bit.
Now the next step is clicking here real quick.
Here.
Go the next step.
We should make is to play a little bit around with this stuff here.
OK.
So I just take this for reference only I take it to the back to the functions OK.
So let's come back here and let's say we want to get all
users publish
posts.
Actually like this how we go.
So let's think about this for a minute.
We want to get all the published polls for the user that should be very simple to do.
Matter of fact list you get one of these guys out here they say here and we just need another statement
here we just need another then post status.
I believe that's the name of the and should be equal to publish.
Shall we go.
That's And we should make one for the draft as well.
Let's now that we're here right.
Draft.
See how easy this thing is guys.
Now in the future you know if I was starting this mess from scratch.
Now I will instead of using strings to say publish and draft I will use one for those published posts
and zero for draft OK for active and instead are using POST status.
I will use status just like that.
OK.
If I was starting this from scratch I started this.
You know it was a very small project like I mentioned before and just got really big over time without
much planning to make it that big.
Just because you guys are always making requests so we can start actually coming here.
And replacing some of the stuff like that.
That's the published polls count that's my fact.
Yeah that's what it is.
But we need to make sure that he has the I always say records for us count records.
And then let's see if that changes right.
We'll pass on the fine connection that is in functions.
Let's refresh here again.
Publish.
Oh yeah I think I left that in the now fix it yeah.
That's my ADHD or something.
Here we go.
A very real connection that is in
connection function.
Eighty six with it.
Oh that's because I have all this stuff here.
I was going to say too early for that.
All right.
So active posts so they usually has one active pose.
He has one posting Torro.
And let's check out the draft let's do this for the draft.
As a matter of fact you can copy the whole thing he is very similar
Oh we have to do is change the draft here.
This is from which you srong.
Come on.
Oh right.
This refresh.
And yeah he says we don't have any draft post.
Let's see that's true user would ID number 28 come forward please one here.
And he says he has one publish post doesn't have any more.
So yeah that's awesome.
Are some guys learning a lot.
Let's take this all the way to the top.
Put it there.
Just because we can.
So awesome.
You guys are more awesome than I am.
So let's do approve and describe it in the next lecture guys just to make things short.
See you in the next one.
Take care.