Welcome back my students in this lecture here we're going to be learning a lot.
All right so pay very close attention anyway.
For those of you that are really excited about the PH be object oriented programming course that I have
coming up I'm just going to tell you that I'm getting it ready just take it a little bit more time than
I thought.
Well don't worry it will come.
And you got to love it.
All right.
So anyways let's go ahead and do what I want to do in this lecture here first of all is that I want
to put a link here for registration that PH BE ph.
And I also want to go to and this is where I am right now.
Go to your navigation BHB that should be under your CMOS and inside your includes.
All right.
Here.
Go there.
That's your navigation.
And then we're going to be adding a link here so I'm just going to copy this.
That's the first thing that we are going to be doing.
And then I called this registration
and copy the same word is we don't have to write it again.
Paste that BHB.
All right.
So let's go back and see how the if is working good and click on it and it takes us to BHB right to
the registration page.
All right.
Perfect.
Second thing that I want to do is go to your registration that BHP.
All right.
And that should be under admin and then in St. colludes actually is not and includes the restrictions
actually outside on the CMOS folder and actually on the route on the asphalt and that's it that's where
registration is.
All right.
So anyway so one of the things that I want to do is I want to take this Wildblue loop body here.
The reason is because we don't need to loop through the whole table to get its value out.
We can just get the first value.
All right the first value of the database of the end of the table right of this first value and we get
it out and that's it and we're done with it.
But we don't need to go around.
So let me show you another way of doing this or this is Neal you probably have not seen this right.
I just cannot take that off.
And that's it done.
We don't need to do anything out there.
We were doing that for demonstration purposes only.
So now what we want to do is we want to start making the Querrey to go into the inside the database.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do this.
I actually have something already that I want to copy and paste here so that way we don't take 20 minutes
writing this stuff.
All right so you're going to piece this in here.
All right.
All right so what do we got.
Here we got a Querrey.
We've got a variable holding our query like we've done so many times.
We're going to insert this into users a user the user name e-mail password and access.
All right.
That's going to be.
Let me just go back to our BHB make sure that we have that there.
We have to see if we have that Culham the array HP my admin.
Then we go to see a mass users and see if we have access.
We don't have we have a user role.
All right so that would be user role right instead of at.
So we would change this to the user actually use or underscore role.
All right perfect.
Then we have we are concatenating here we continue industry down here and then we are inserting the
user name the email the password and then the last one to make sure it is user rule.
And when I do my file we are going to be hard coding something here we're going to just name it.
So Stryver make sure that you Harcourt is.
So this is going to be a string.
OK.
By default that that's what's going to be subscriber then that means we change it right now.
Then we send the Querrey right with a connection in Querrey we've done this many times.
If the square was successful is not successful then we get this error.
Right.
All right.
That looks like we're good there right.
All right let's save it and check it out to see if it works right.
So let's go back here.
And this just make sure that we just put whatever here.
I don't know Demel 3000.
I know I come out with some strange names right.
I guess another creative and I don't know Sanjay passwords there and register then we have a long name.
All right so we have a feel that it's not the same a column field.
So let's make sure that yeah I remember now.
All right.
Email user e-mail everything Here's user and not doing that in my query.
Ooh not good not good user user name user email.
Make sure that you do that.
OK.
That's why it's always good to have those errors displayed.
User password and user role.
All right.
OK let's let's check it out let's see.
Let's see if it works.
Now what kind of error we get back.
I haven't really tested this before I showed it to you.
I like to do like this freestyle Demel 3000 4000 to 4000 now and G.M. and re-used.
There we go.
Looks like you want to do.
Now let's check it out.
Refresh.
All right.
So we went through we got the demo and we got the user password.
We got the username password ID and even e-mail.
All right we can check it out we can go to admen users.
We can see that we have this guy right here.
Damn 4000.
We have some information that person can come here and edit and enter their remaining information if
they want to.
And that's it.
That's it for that the user come back here and now everything's updated.
All right.
So the next lecture we're going to be doing some more modifications to this registration page because
what I want to show I want to show some validation.
You know I want to be able to for some reason the user or those not clicks here right now if we click
here I think it makes any record if we go back and check we make a new empty record so we want to stop
this function from happening.
And we had the sense I want to give the users some feedback saying you know this cannot be empty and
you need to fill it up right.
So on the next lecture we're going to be playing around with a little bit.
And so you know that's one take care.
Thank you.