Hi welcome back my student.
This is Edwin from the future.
That's right.
Our already completed the course.
I already finished that project but I come sometimes to help you guys I'll avoid problems in the future.
All right.
Just because I know everything is going to happen in the future because I'm from the future I'm going
to help you right now.
So I want you to go to your admin underscore Hetter that BHB file and right above here.
And if you don't you should have this includes function here already but if you don't don't worry about
it but this should be there of course.
This is our database.
I want you to actually create these BHB tag in these and open it and close it.
And then in between I want you to write this function down which is called Olby underscore start.
This is output both free and we're going to need this when we are redirecting users are redirecting
pieces of coding or application later on.
All right.
So make sure that you put it all the way in line with one of your editor again is called Olby underscore
start.
All right.
So when we use a function called Hetter like this later on to redirect that's when we need to turn this
on.
All right.
So this functions is in charge of sending a request actually buffering our requests in the headers of
the scripts.
So that way when we are done with the script it was send everything at the same time.
Right now BHB is sending each requests one by one.
So if later on we use this function header in the body it would give you an error if you don't have
this function here because it would try to send out requests in the body when all of the headers are
already being sent.
All right.
So just remember that we need this right on top of the file.
And if your father's and look exactly I don't worry all you have to have is this all the underscores
start function right here and the admin on the squarehead in the first line.
Right.
So anyway thank you so much and I'll see you in some next lectures