All right so we are continuing here.
And they add the user that BHB and I just notice that we are not going to be needing this quavery right
here since we're going to be adding a user Let's go and check it out and see how it looks first.
So I'm going to refresh on this user and we can see that we can add the first name last name admin here
we don't need this to be doing a query since we are not going to be pulling information we're going
to be putting in the information.
So we have a user name email and password and user.
Let's go ahead and I'm going to do a couple of things here.
I'm going to take that off first and then we're going to start working with the insert in getting data
from the form.
All right.
So let's go ahead and take that.
But what I really want to do I don't want to actually throw this away since we're going to be needing
this as a matter of fact and we're going to need this you know where in the end user page because we're
going to be putting information there.
So let's go to the edit underscore user.
And we're going to put this somewhere here so that where we can use it later right.
So I'm just going to put it here right here.
You can put it anywhere you want later on we were just going to.
All right.
You can even comment it out if you want.
It's up to you.
I'm just going to put it there for now.
Let's go back to user to the user right here.
And I tried I took on from here.
Let me just take it off now.
All right.
But as a matter of fact let me I need this to select and take all the ph out and lead to select because
we're going to be making some static values here.
So this one is going to be admin.
And the other one is going to be subscriber.
As a matter of fact we're just going to have one option here.
Well it's have two options for now.
We will probably activate it later on.
But actually now user subscriber I'm sorry subscriber write ups driver and an admin.
All right.
Use a row and ID nothing there let's just see how that looks.
Perfect.
But let's just put it another option be above this and just put it to say select options select options
and of the four is going to be subscriber just in case.
Reiver just in case we forget.
All right.
So let options.
There we go.
All right so let's make sure that we get some data on this forum where we submit it.
We click on it.
Right now we get no data right.
So let's go ahead and make sure that we get some data here.
This is a postpaid we might use a lead but we don't know yet.
So all right create user that is what we got to check here 3:08 user and I'm going to play some of this
and I'm not even going to take it out.
So let's just for the user id first second list to the first name and you can always put this in the
site here and that way you can know where you're pulling out.
But we're going to be putting a lot of information out actually from all this information that we've
got in our form right here.
So let's put this to this side right here.
That way we can have a little reference on why we are pulling out right there.
Right.
And let's go here make these in a smaller way.
There we go.
All right so we got the first name.
We've got ID that is not visible there but we are pulling the first name out.
So we get a user first name the name user last name
what else use or roll
this we are going to comment this all right now.
We just want some basic information for now and later on we're going to be adding some stuff.
All right now let's just concentrate on the big picture here.
Right.
Big picture.
Get that big picture e-mail.
I was just trying to be funny there but if you didn't laugh I failed.
All right so user password.
All right.
Perfect user password.
Here we go.
And the date I'm still debating on that.
But let's just come in that out for now.
One two three.
All right so let's we got four and three seven.
Let's go ahead and do some copy and paste here real quick.
This dollar sign right here is a.
I think we're doing pretty good progress.
All right.
Save it.
Make sure you save it.
Let's go down.
See we're not missing anything.
That's name for his name.
All right.
Perfect.
All right so let's cut this off right here and the next one let's check it out.
As a matter of fact this let's just check it out right now real quick and let's just see something Eckel.
We're going to equil the first name.
Let's just go ahead and comment on this because we're going to get a narrow if we don't.
So this is Square-D right here.
So let's come comment all that out and let's see if we can get some information out of it.
All right.
Let's just play whatever here in the user.
Was it a user name that we're checking going first name and when and then create an undefined user ID.
All right.
It's sending everything here is user ID is
actually now getting the user ID so we don't need it in the on the form actually.
My bad on that please.
All right.
So they're doing an echo right there.
We getting some information on the next one we're going to be finishing this form and hopefully able
we are able to insert some data in the database.
All right so thank you so much for watching.
And I see your next lecture