Welcome back my students.
So I told you that we need to fix a couple of things and we are going to do that.
First thing is that we need to fix is the access to our application.
Right now if we go to our home site and we click on Nathman you know we are actually getting through.
So that's not good.
We need to fix this.
All right.
So let's go to a file manager.
Back back to a file manager.
I'm going to go to our folder of course or if you don't have a folder go to your admin.
Then we go to our includes And then we go to go to our header because that's what we have the code to
control the access to admin.
All right here's where we have this cold here and this is now working.
All right.
The reason is because we got these Olby start right here.
We need to put it right in the beginning here of everything.
All right this is doubtful Bufferin we're going to turn that on manually.
So we're going to save it and if we go back to our site and refresh and try to go in there we can't
anymore.
So we are this is working now.
Now we need to take this off.
This is not very nice right.
And let me see if I remember where we're putting that we are putting out in the D-B.
So let's go back to the front.
I think it was in say includes.
I was in the middle to front a CMOS includes in the root directory NDB.
I think that's where we have that connected that we don't need anymore.
So we going to just come here multiline comment close on here.
We are a good saver refresh and we're good to go there.
All right so now let's Logan a Logan with the same password user that I have in the beginning and we
have a problem.
They says call to identify function password verify.
And I'll tell you what that is.
This is because this hosting provider by default gave me a older version of BHB 5 and that's because
you need to go a lot of data so that timing any hosting provider you're going to have that problem.
So we're going to go to see panel because this is super cool.
All right on panel and we're going to go all the way down the way down to our software place our software
tab and we're going to go to select BHB version right here.
And as you can see I got 5.4 right.
We need to make it five point five ladies.
All right we're not going to be playing around with this but just in case you need to have some more
options selected like PDL or anything like that you come here and select it.
All right.
So basically you can turn on some of the features that you need in BHB find just going to leave it that
way it is because all I see is that password that function.
So we're going to save it and then we're going to come back here go back and refresh.
And now we go to Rico one two and three enter he gives us that problem again.
All right let's go back pass or verify.
Should not give as a problem anymore.
Beco 1 2 and 3 enter this password verify
this go to our here because this is actually password underscore verify and that's what I got here says
sent thing.
And this came after HP five point five.
All right.
So we still need the HP five point five to make this work.
For some reason he's now working maybe take some time to work.
So.
All right.
I'm going to be actually looking into this a little more.
On the next lecture I'm going to tell you the solution because I don't want you to wait 20 minutes for
me to find out here.
So anyway.
It's probably one of these options here.
Right.
But if anything I'll let you know in a minute and I'll see you in the next lecture.
All right.
Take care.
Bye bye.