All right.
So we made our cold a lot more usable now.
Our index is looking great since it doesn't have all that extra mail that clutters everything.
So we will probably be including this in another file later on but right now for simplicity we're just
going to leave it in there.
So what we want to do right now is we have a table in our database called category.
As a matter of fact let's just change it make it more little bit a little bit more appropriate since
we're not going to be holding one category.
We're going to be holding many categories.
Let's just change a name on it and let's go to operation just click here and go to operation and click
categories and click go right there where we can rename it.
Let's go ahead.
Insert some data into that.
And let's call this bootstrap.
You don't have to call it bootstrap but you can call it whatever you want but if you want to follow
me exactly do that javascript click go.
And we have some information there that we can pool now and find out how to do this right.
So let's go to navigation.
I'm going to go to my working files right here and just to show you this field right here this header.
Am going to separate a little bit just to show you.
Remember that we are using a framework so this called all of these classes are being reproduced by the
framework of the Templi.
If I minimizers and you click I click there that is that section right here.
Right.
This next section is the links that were going to be replacing right here.
You know that right.
So we're going to be doing some BHB here to replace those links ongoing right now too.
We can just go ahead and comment this out for now.
Then later on we take it off.
All right so what we want to do right now is start with a BHB tag of course open and close BHB tag.
It is a little bigger so you can see what we're doing and let's make a query here.
Querrey if
this is going to be a variable Actually I'm going to pull this I'm going to pull this query into a verbal
and I'm going to say select and you probably see me doing this before in the database section.
I had to select all from where where we actually wanted to display here categories remember that Categories
table.
Right so we're going to select all the data from categories categories
and that's it.
Let's say that's what we want to select.
That's that's actually would make sure that we write the key we're from select all from categories.
Right.
And then we need another query here.
Actually we need to send this in.
All right.
So we're going to say Querrey category select and you can name this differently select all categories
or US
query.
This is a long name I just want you to know that that's what it is.
And actually we don't need this here.
My S Q Well I Querrey is a function we use to send those parameters out query and we got to send it
in with a connection.
Remember that variable that we used to make this a little smaller tool for the connection that is this
variable from the database and that variable is in the includes the be right here.
All right.
And we need to include this file actually there for that to work but I just finish it up right now.
Now again it's good to know again.
So we need to foster the connection and we need to pass of the Querrey that would go right here.
We also need to make an all file call functions but we'll probably do that later on since I want to
show you how to do this first and then later on we start refactoring everything into functionality like
we've done before and other lectures.
So select all categories from that and then we need to display to bring back those values.
We use a while loop.
All right so we're going to look through all that and we're going to sign that all that value all those
values to another to a variable.
But right now before we do that let's use another function here that is going to help us do that.
It's called My Eskew Well I remember we use an API my YOU ALLY fetch.
We can use a saw to this.
That's fine.
All am spending this wrong actually right there and we want to fetch what does result right there.
OK.
And then we want to assign that resoled too because it comes into our in an array and associative array.
All right.
So that's how it comes out.
And what are the names all those roles are kept.
Title is the name.
All right that's what we want to display on that kind of where we are.
And if I because this is a UL right now what if one of these planes that is UL is our ally right.
So I'm going to sign this to a variable called Cat title just to make it more a little bit easier to
see inside.
Is going to do a ekal.
And inside this egg we're going to put this variable right here to this play.
We want to display as an ally list item.
And inside this item we'll want to put that cat's title variable in there.
So Cat Fido.
All right.
So let's just make sure that the reason I put double quotes is that way I can use this.
Make sure you use double quotes when you can use brackets and make this separate from your mail in a
way.
All right.
This is the only way you can put variables in there with his brackets with double cords outside for
posting records.
I think I show you that already.
They don't work.
That's in the beginning of course I have a lecture on that lie.
All right.
So we should be able to see something here.
If I'm fighting forget it.
I started my life I almost forgot.
We need to include our D-B connection in our.
It's so we have the header but we need a connection right here also so I'm going to copy this and we're
gonna include a connection.
And this is going to be called the B.
So let's see how that works so maybe we have an error or something actually says we are connected actually.
And he's already displaying the files here we can't see it because we need links for that.
All right.
So we are connected we are displaying what we need to organize in a little bit.
And this is playing we are connected.
Let's go back to the D.B and take that we are connect the I'll just comment that for now we don't need
it.
Let's go back to navigation and we need to put this in the link right here.
He's going to copy this.
Make sure that they are on the link made this single chords.
OK.
So
now we should be able to see something nice sir nicer.
There we go.
They see navigation is not working yet.
It's not directing us to any contemn because we don't have any contact associated with this.
But as you can see here we are displaying this from the database.
All right.
So that's a start.
And if we go heading another field that's insur and I'll field say something like
BHB.
And here we're going to say Java go.
And then we go back to this and we refresh.
You can see that that's being incremented there automatically we are displaying dynamic data from our
database.
Right.
Just we are a little bit of cold here.
We are doing all that.
But anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture here and get ready for the next one.
Take care.