Perfit.
So now that we are able to log into our database and we can go ahead and log in like this and we were
able to personalize and receive that information there we need a way for this user to log out because
this user is always going to be logging now.
We go to admin is always going to be there.
What about if somebody gets into their users computer and logs into their account they see him as Indos
and does whatever they want with it right.
So we want to be able to log all of the users so that's what we're going to be doing on this lecture
here.
And if you're still with me here you are doing great.
We are almost finished with this session section of logging in and I just got to say that I'm really
proud of you that you are following through and you're going to do something great in programming or
web development whatever your course of action is after this course.
All right.
So hopefully something that you will be growing with in web development.
But anyway so what we want to do is create First of all let's create a link right here right.
When we click on it it logs everything out right.
And then we create a log out page let's first create the link and we need to go to admin on the screen
navigation and under profile right here we're going to be we're going to create that link and that link
is going to go to a page that we haven't made yet.
But we will make it is going to be insane colludes and is going to be called log out that BHB we're
going to make up right now.
So first let's test out the link let's refresh here let's click here and logout and then takes us to
include that force last log out that BHB right.
Perfect.
So let's go ahead and make that page.
Let's go to the root of our CMOS which in this case is going to be all the way down my case and I'm
going to go to Logan and do a Save As here and go into this log out log out.
Up Peachtree Now this page is not going to have that much information as a matter of fact as a matter
of fact we're not going to have all the information that we have in Logan.
We're going to have just the session.
Now that's it.
And then everything else you can delete.
Now let's go to that logging page again.
And I want to copy a couple of things from here this well.
We're going to grab these sessions here we're going to copy it to logout paste right here then we're
going to take these values out.
And what we're going to be doing is every time somebody a user comes into this page we're going to be
canceling their session.
Right.
So we're going to cancel their session by assigning a value of a boolean value of No.
That means that is not going to have anything.
No means nothing is there not even a string.
It's like nothing it's.
There is nothing because you know this is a string.
And you know no it's just not.
And so we are going to cancel those sessions one day visit here and then after we cancel it we are going
to be sending our user somewhere else right.
So we're going to send the user to the log in to the end that's that BHB and send them back to where
they came from.
Right.
Hopefully that's where they came from but anyways so now we've got these Rico here.
And if I go and refresh this.
Come here and logo.
We go to admin and the Rekos not here anymore.
Everything is cancell what we do have a little issue here that we need to fix.
You see right now.
Let me go into Admin and I notice I don't have the session.
The session is not here anymore.
Not it's on set.
But we are logging in so we don't want people to log in even after we leave.
Right.
So let's go ahead and fix that little bit.
So let's go to the admin Hetter.
And here we have this logic right here.
We want to do is change his logic and make it more simple in a way that we're not checking to see if
the role is equal to admin because what we really want to know if is the user role if he said if he's
not set then we want to redirect the user somewhere else.
Right.
So I'm just going to take all this off.
Actually not all of it just this and this and very simple.
I think the way that we can just do it like this.
We're going to say if it's not said then we're going to redirect it somewhere else.
So let's let's try this one.
Is this piece of code in C..
Refresh takes us back to the front page.
Now if I click on here we can't log in anymore but if I go here look Rico and then one two three.
Now it is set.
All right.
So if it's not set it's going to redirect us back here.
Now what about if it's set right.
What about if it's set.
We've got to do something else because if it's set we get a check if it if it's if it's admin then we
you know we allow the user but right now we're not checking we're not doing that feature of checking
if it's I mean we're going to let him see this page.
If he's not I mean we're not going to let him see this page.
We're now doing those features right now so really doesn't matter right now.
That would be probably an extra feature that we would include late on the CMOS.
But for now just this is how we prevent users that don't have the right credentials to get in here.
All right.
So we're just going to leave it for now.
Maybe an extra feature.
We're going to be checking what type of user it is.
So if it's Adamy user we let him see cerned page if he's that subscriber users we let him see certain
pages.
Right now we're not going to bother with that.
Right now I think you got the point and if maybe I think you have enough knowledge right now to check
here to come here and say you know if sesshin user role he goes to admin I want you to assign this to
it.
You know I want you to do this do it.
And I mean you can do those conditions yourself but later on we're going to be covering die probably
in the extra features if I don't make another course about it.
All right.
So just keep that in mind that we're just checking you for user role.
And if it's not said we're just going to you know take him somewhere else.
All right we don't want anybody here now to rise to this.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture.
I think this is really good right now let's just logout Let's try it out and try to submit we can because
we're not putting anything here.
We try to go to the admin.
We cannot if we put Rico.
One two three Enter we are able to log in.
So perfect.
I think we're doing really good.
I think you're doing really good if you are still following me so congratulations.
You're awesome.
And let's see if we can finish this CIMS successfully.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.