Around this video we want to display some more information we get is placed on draft pools some pending
comments or comments or sceptre accepted.
So maybe subscriber users and other extra data since this is too plain I think right.
So let's go ahead and do that.
For that we're going to have to make some queries.
So let's go to admin for Shlash in that step BHB.
All right.
So we've been working here.
And right before the javascript right here I'm going to open my ph VTX and we're going to be doing some
queries.
All right.
And let's make this a little bigger so you can see what I'm going to do is that.
Let me just put my.
All right.
I'm going to grab all the way from the top the squares from the poles and one to gravid and on to PACER
right there.
There we go.
This is going to be a little different here.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to say select from polls where For starters if you remember that as
the column there post-Arab equals to your raft.
So I'm going to pool my draft in there I'm going to say here the named is variable select all draft
balls
and I changed the name of that here and here and then post draft count that's going to be the variable
that's going to have that number.
All right.
Now to test this real quick what we need to do is come back down here.
We're going to increment the load to 5 because we're going to go all around again one more time with
a little coma here.
We're going to insert that
tetes draft pools and make these a little smaller so you can see what I'm doing.
There we go.
And we're going to put a little coma here.
That's a coma not on line where I couldn't see my coma there.
And I just kind of pace pause underscore draft count.
Perfect.
All right so let's go ahead and check to see how that looks.
Let's play there and we can see that we have one draft post right here.
Perfect.
So we're going to keep doing the same thing for comments and for the rest of this.
So if you want to go ahead and do that you can.
All you have to do is make a couple more queries right here right
right here.
And then we need one more question right there.
So the next one is comments right.
So we're going to select from where comments where comments that is I think it is equals what.
Let's check it out.
I think he's on to prove comments.
The status is on the proof right here right.
They both approve.
So there we go.
Perfect.
Right.
And select all on approved comments and that's a really long I'm just going to name this on a pool of
comments.
That was a really long variable there.
Kohary this is still a little long comment.
I'm just going to call this on improve count come and count.
That's still long but whatever.
I make sure that you change it here too.
All right.
And here selects from where what's the next one.
Let's go to dashboard for right here.
Is users we don't have any for categories anything that's pending or anything like that.
So users is and that's one we're going to settle it from users
where user is or is a role one of these flaid subscribers subscribers.
All right.
And select all you know what this is going to this could be easier.
Subscriber
subscribers and we're going to change that right here also.
And we're going to just say subscriber count
count right there.
All right.
I think we did good here less we made a mistake on this come and start there.
So let's do the first one right here and we already have the first one actually post-draft count.
Let's do the second one on a pool of common count.
All right let's go here and let's increment the loop a little bit more.
Two sets is the one at a time OK.
I don't want you to go too crazy on that.
So we're going to call this one pending comments re
comments.
All right.
And make this a little smaller there and right here after coming count and going a full coma and pool
on a common count.
All right let's go here and let's refresh it and we can see pending comments right here.
Perfit Let's go ahead and do the next one.
All right if you want you can do it yourself.
And this one is going to be subscriber count and we're going to increment the loop a little more to
7.
Let's go ahead and put that value right there right after users put a coma two quotes single quotes
or apostrophes whatever you want to call it and let's call this subscribers.
Subscribers are going to make this a little smaller again.
If I can get it right right there and after user account put a coma and subscriber on the score account
right.
That's what I put a camera here with scriber account right there.
All right so let's go ahead and do that.
Let's check it out.
All right subscribers we don't have any right now.
We are users and we have one subscribe right here but it's not really getting it right so we have a
problem there somehow.
So we have a subscriber is not detecting it.
Let's check out our Querrey user roll subscribers.
Let's take that as they're safe let's refresh this go to dashboard and we see that we got one subscriber
right here.
All right.
So all we had to do was take that s out.
So I think we did pretty good on this one here and I think this should be should be enough for this
section right here.
We don't have to do anything else.
If I do have to do something else and I forgot something.
You guys can remind me but I think we did pretty well here and now our CMAG looking great.
All right.
So we're probably going to be creating a section here just fixing issues on the mass that we may encounter
later on or just to extra features like IBM mentioning over and over again.
So don't worry this is something that's going to keep going on and on.
They're going to keep making new lectures for you so you keep learning.
I like to always give more to my students always.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.
All right.
Take care.