All right so right now we are receiving data and we can add data array so we can add some data here.
Now what we need to do is actually BE ABLE TO THE on data at a year and then after we delete that we
can go ahead.
Also edit it.
So the first thing that we need to do is create a GET request with it get super global.
Right.
So let's do that first.
Well what I want to do is put a link right here on the right hand side.
So every time we clicked we delete this roll right here of the table.
Right.
So we are going to be adding that right here with an echo right here.
OK.
And this is going to be a link and the link is going to have this.
The cat I d.
The reason why we want to pass the idea because we want to make a very same way whenever you find this
ID I want you to delete it.
All right so we're going to make like a little condition based on ID.
So the idea of course this is going to be the I.D. of that specific row right in the database so let's
do a ref and here this is just an anchor tag.
We're going to be passing in some values right in the you or else so we want to catch it in the same
actually make sure this is only single quotes and we want to pass it in.
We want to make sure that it's on the same page category's ph ph B.
This is the same page right here.
And when we click on it on this link we want to pass it in some parameters.
And of course the Parama is going to be the Katta ID but we want to say questionmark and then we want
to say delete.
So this is going to make a key in the array and they get requests and they get super global which is
a an array and associative array and this is going to be the key and this will be the value.
So let's just go ahead and say equals and let's just take this from here and put it right here.
All right.
And here was say something like delete.
That's what we're going to write here.
So we we go back to where we are good here let's go back to it and let's check it out.
Right now we see that we have a link and we put our muscle where you can see down here that it turns
into an ID.
If I take it you can see that we do have that on the browser.
So we do have for that specific row we do have a different ID.
So you see it changing up there.
So let's go ahead and make that Querrey.
I was going to go ahead and make the square right here.
But that's going to confuse you.
I want to be able to make the question well so it does not confuse you.
And that way we can maybe later on turning this into functions.
All right.
So I'm going to put this to both of these queries together right here.
Just because I want to keep it together here right now.
All right.
Let's just put it a little bit to the side here.
So this Querrey we can make a comment here and say something like fine wine or category's just want
to make this clear for you.
Why all categories Querrey.
All right.
And then we're going to make something in the bottom of here.
Here we're going to start another one.
So we open ph tag.
Make sure it's lower case.
All right.
Let's do that.
Let's go ahead and create one here.
All right.
I like this cursor going all the way down.
But that's fine.
All right so we want to check first if we see a GET request a get Super Bowl or we're around.
So if set we use the sets function within this statement and we say like we've done before in the lectures
before in the course we're checking for the delete key which is going to be right here.
Right.
And if we find it then everything is good and we can go ahead and save this ID.
Well this key right here is the value of the key actually into another variable called the Cat ID right
here.
Right.
Well we can name this something different like the cat ID name differently because this ID.
All right.
Is is is going to this right here.
All right but we don't.
This is coming already from inside the database right here.
So we could actually when we catch it right here we can name it differently.
So that way does not confuse us.
All we can say.
Get cat ID or whatever you want to call it but I like to sometimes change it that way is doing it for
you basically.
So that way does not confuse you.
All right.
It is the same idea right here.
All right so don't get it wrong.
They just using a different variable.
All right.
So when we get this we want to do something here once we get here we do a query so let's do it where
we are right here.
Let's make sure this is a line right here and there's the query that we want to do to the database.
Delete from categories
where Y was a condition where the ID.
Right.
Well actually we need to reference the column in the database which is called Cat ID.
He calls this cat ID right so we want to make sure that is in brackets just so he looks good and separated
from this little bit better.
And then we need to send this query.
Let's just put a little together a little tighter there.
All right.
So the query is going to be delete Kohary.
That's a good name.
We can name and whatever we want to remember that my Q Well is a function that we're going to be using.
Well my school Querrey we're going to pass it in.
Same thing with Pasadena peer connection and inquiry and car auction and Querrey.
All right we could easily copy some of this down but let's do it like this fine.
And what else.
So that's it.
That's about it.
Now just because we do like this you're going to see what happens.
So you right now if I clicked delete it does not.
But if I click it again it deletes the reason for this is because we need it.
If we send this request we would like to refresh that page so it will look like he's doing it instantly.
All right.
But in fact we are actually refreshing that page and right now when we click on it is now refreshing
that page should just send in the ID and then we have to have to refresh the page in order for this
to work.
So we had to click it twice for it to refresh but we don't want to do that.
So what I want to do is actually refresh Sandt once this is done.
We want to send the one to make a fresh basically So we're going to say location categories up here
it should be this is just going to refresh the page race basically.
All right.
It's going to send it again.
Go ahead and send that request back to categories that BHP in another is going to do another request
for the page and it basically is going to refresh.
Right.
So let's do it let's see how that works.
Let's see if it looks better like that.
So they let you see that we one time and you deletes it because he's refreshing.
Look at that.
You see it doesn't even have the I.D. right here because it's redirecting back to categories at BHB
before we saw the I.D. on top here.
So that's one way of doing it.
I think that's pretty cool right.
So we can add the categories again here and we could say something like I don't know Java at it and
we could delete it for if it were good with this.
For them there.
All right.
Whoops sorry.
All right so think this is looking good.
So this just put a little bit wary.
All right that's fine.
We're just going to come into a little bit there.
All right just to make a little bit neater.
All right.
So all right so we are done here.
And let's go ahead and continue with the next lecture I think this one already got too long.
Take care and I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.