Hi welcome back on this section here we are going to be learning about we're now learning more reinforcing
what we learn about cookie sessions and get super glue right.
We already did the form.
So if you did not learn enough about the form go back and watch it.
But on this one we just got Cookie sessions and they get super global right.
So if you're ready I'm ready.
Let's go ahead and do that.
So we are in Section nine here under practical Apfel are nine dopy.
HB not nine.
The HB.
Right.
That is the file.
So here is just asking us to create a link saying Click here and set the link ref to Bassem parameters
are used to get super global to see it.
So we know how to do that we know how to put a link them put some parameters in pull the data out of
the array.
We know how to set a cookie that expires in a week.
We know how to do that.
And we also know how to do sessions so go ahead and post this video.
Go ahead and do that.
If you have any problems go watch out all the video about cookies or GED or whatever you using your
sessions and make sure that you do it before you come here because we're going to compare a cold and
make sure don't do the same thing I did on the other villagers do something similar.
All right.
So it a video.
Go ahead and do it.
All right so hopefully you were able to do it.
And if not don't worry I got your back right here.
So let's go going to open our BHB tag.
And what I'm going to do is the first thing is create a link.
It's a matter of fact I'm just going to leave this here like this via a little link right here.
This link is just going to say we're just going to refer to the same page we were on because I want
to display the values here.
I'm going to pass on parameters right here.
I'm going to call these ID 100 actually.
I'm going to call this source and just kind of make this sors to be thousand.
Some number there.
Right.
All right.
Perfect.
So I think I'm good here right with the link.
So now what we need to do is we need to check for this because if we don't check we get an error.
We need to check to see if this is set.
So we are going to use this function is set and we're going to check for that super global Get remember
that and remember that this is the key in the associative array that is going to bring back.
So I'm just going to check for that key there source if the source is good.
I want to echo that source and then call this whole thing right here.
Boom.
All right so I think we're good here.
Let's check it out.
Just refresh refresh again or save it and make sure that we save a refresh.
All right.
We're getting an input here was on.
Oh I forgot to say put the words here.
Click here.
All right.
Forgot that little detail right.
Can we get it right.
Here we go refresh.
And now we're good so we see that when we click on it we get this value right here so we're pulling
information from the get.
We're sending it and we're putting it right here.
Perfect.
All right so we did the first part here.
Let's go ahead and do the second part.
Let's just first concatenate this and make sure that we have a space cut in a b or tag here.
There we go.
Now what we have when we put the other function we we have some space.
So now we need to set a cookie.
So you remember how to do that right.
All right so one of the first thing that I go into that going to delete my history of and I'm doing
this I'm sorry guys and Andrew is in they are doing this you know the monitor because I don't want to
take anything out of here on this site.
Right.
So I did it in my my my cookies and I will delete my
not my browsing data but will delete all my cooking my my browsing data and my cookies.
That's what I'm deleting and the other one.
If you don't remember that as a matter of fact you bring the page here to this site and show you how
to do that.
Let me just show you right here.
So you go to your settings.
This is chrome by the way.
I don't like to move my things from here but that's fine settings.
And we go to show event settings content settings and this is how we delete the cookies right here or
cookies and we just delete them here.
All right.
And the browsing of course we deleted by history and then we delete all right here.
Clear.
All right.
So just a quick demonstration there but now so now we need to create a cookie so how we do that.
Take this out of your screen little Cookie Cookie Cookie right here.
And as a matter of fact let's go all the way to the top of the document here and let's create one here.
I don't think it's gonna affect those in any way but it's just going to give us some more space here.
BHB All right.
So the first thing that we hear about we need to pass remember we need to use a function called Set
cookie and we need to pass it a couple of parameters three parameters either a matter of fact and then
we can pass it on any parameters we want.
So we've got three parameters we've got to pass it.
All right we need to pass the name so their name here and here we need to pass the values of why the
value is going to be this is the value.
I'm just going to pass this on.
Why not.
All right.
So and now the expiration.
We're going to pass this on numbers here multiply and this I can make a variable request just to make
it more clear than what.
That's what it is.
And actually expiration that just make it more.
That's the reason.
And I could have just made these variables too but I don't want to do that.
I don't need to.
So let's use that time function to get all of the seconds from 1972 to now.
Let's add that just like we did on the lecture right.
We're going to add some numbers here to get to seconds get the seconds for the week.
So we're going to multiply.
Sixty seconds science 60 Minutes times 24 hours in the day time seven.
All right this would give us all the seconds in one week multiply.
All right.
And then will not multiply but we multiply this and we go to seconds for the whole week.
Let's put that here.
All right so now this was set a cookie for us when we visit this page.
Why did the cookie said that we can look at it right.
So we got.
Just make sure that we have this correct and let's go ahead and visit that page.
Let's go ahead and take this.
All right.
So let's go check it out.
History actually settings
show event settings
constant settings called cookies local's one cookie with click on it the name.
That's it.
You put the name that I gave the cookie and when I click on it you can see that this says this is their
value.
Separated by this plus symbol C means it's a space.
Right so don't get that wrong.
So even the time when it was created.
Right.
Accessible.
Yes.
It is accessible to a script.
So that means applications can access this.
All right so now that we said the cookie now we see the value.
So let's go down here and let's see the value of your task here just in case.
And let's just check if that's the same function again.
It's set actually this too happy to be tagging you probably saw that radio I had a Ph.
Peter there.
All right so you guys if I'm taking too long with this.
All right so this do cookie because that's the Superguy over there was not really that super glue like
the rest but it is close to right.
And let's just check for the name.
What is the name of this cookie right here.
Perfect.
Let's check for that.
That is set.
Then we do something here.
All right.
So what do we do.
We are going to ekal can we echo that cookie dough.
Echo.
Why not right.
Let's take it out and we.
We go there we go so we echo the value of the name or that cookie.
Perfect.
So we echoing that cookie dough and we can get some more value out of it.
But I don't want to get into that in this sense.
We got to go and start a session.
All right so how do we start a session.
Do you remember that.
No.
All right.
Let me show you the store Session right here.
So the first thing that we are going to be doing is starting.
So we first have to make a function and do you remember the function is called I give you one more chance.
All right.
You got it.
You are totally right.
SESSIONS start is a function right.
Actually sesshin.
There we go.
All right.
So once you put this in the heads right here is going to start a session.
And if you go back to it and we refresh this document right here we go back.
You already have a session started in one cookie for that last count and settings cookies two cookies
you see that click on it and now we have the session BHB session I click on it.
It tells you that it's done.
This is the cookie that is set for that session for our servers for our server because we don't have
servers.
All right so how do we see the value of what we do the same thing we did here.
All right the same way we check for that so we could say something like If a set
I leave as a homework for you so you can do this.
All right.
So if it's set then we can check it right.
So now we check with we did that but we didn't.
We turned it on we turned on the follow the cookie but we how they actually set of any value to that
session.
We need to set a value for that session so let's go ahead and do that.
I almost forgot.
All right.
SESSIONS We never said anything for it.
So what we need to do is set this value for him.
So he's called his message and said it too high student.
How are you.
All right.
And we're going to check for this.
So I'm just going to do it right here.
As a matter of fact I'm going to pay here am going to use this in
for it.
And she's pleased with that.
All right.
We're good to go.
What do you think.
Let's just take this out of there good to go.
Good to go.
Yes.
There we go.
As you can see we are displaying it right here.
Hi stewarding How are you.
All right.
We can just always put a little concatenation of your tags in there and we refresh.
Whoops.
UPS UPS UPS UPS UPS disclosing.
There we go.
Hi Student How are you.
See that the GET matters right here.
The cookie right here and the center right here.
Perfect.
So hopefully this section here helped you understand reinforce some of that knowledge that you got from
the last lectures and I'm glad that I was able to help you out on that.
So take care and I see the next lecture