All right welcome back.
Student This is Edwin from the future.
So my table here my CIMS would be a lot different than yours because I'm already done with the course
so I don't want you to pay mind to any of this column here that you might not have.
Well you might now have some of it.
Don't pay mind to it.
I'm here to fix something that we created in the last lecture.
All right and we need to fix it before we continue.
So that's why I'm here.
All right.
You're going to see a little bit of Edmond from the future in some of these lectures.
Now what we're going to be facing here is post common count.
All right.
I notice that we created this to be of our car.
This is for têtes.
This is going to be a push an incremental value with numbers.
So we need to deal with his selection that type and this click here to change it.
And this is in the post table right.
Let's change it to type integer and save again.
I mean BHB my admin CMOS posts and then on the column pulls on score comment on the score count we click
on change and we change this to an integer type.
All right.
Actually let's go back here and let's change this to 11.
We don't need 255 numbers right.
I think 11 would do fine.
But if you want to go ahead and put a lot more than that.
You're welcome to do that.
Remember that I'm also I also have because I'm from the future I know we're going to have a new system
on creating pools comment counts later on but just keep following the course keep doing what you're
doing you're doing good.
And I'll see you in some other lectures.
Take care