Hi welcome back my students.
In the last lecture we improve our your registration page by encrypting the passwords that are coming
from this field to the database.
Now we need to update some of those.
I see him as a little bit to actually handle this change.
You see now that we can make users encrypt passwords I'm going to show you an example right now.
It creates a little issue if we don't they are a mess.
You see if you go to see the front of the see a mess and you try a little game with a new user that
you make.
For example you make him a admin and you try to log in.
It will now allow you to do that because now is encrypting the password and he has different fields
in the database.
So we need to adjust it a little bit.
All right.
So first let's go ahead and make our user year just to show you exactly what he's doing.
So are you going to make a simple user here and just kind of call him them all and them all at G-mail.
Well let's just say yeah.
All right let's just for just changing things you know and you've going to make the passwords super
simple one two and three I'm going to show you right now what happens.
I'm going to register that and they use is submit it.
Let's go to admin.
Let's check it out.
Now we can see that demo has been created right here.
Right.
It's going to delete this tool here.
So it's being created now when I click Edit we can see that the password has been cryptic and showing
right here.
All right.
Now let's go and log out and type in the same user name right here.
And then one two and three submit and those that allow me to get in there right now.
That's because the password and I'm just going to refresh just a little bit.
The password is a different one now because it's being encrypted so we need to adjust it.
So let's go ahead and do that right now.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go to the let's actually take this idea here.
Let's go to the log in page and right after.
All right.
Right after that we are going to be using the crypt function again.
And we are going to be passing some parameters and just going to change this salt because if you remember
our encrypt the past where has the salt has our random salt column value default value that we put in
the database.
I'll show you right now what it is.
You see he has this default value so on going to do is just use that default value with a password and
going to pass it in descript function here to reverse what we did.
So now when the script function finishes converting this again is going to turn the password to that
first pass without we first had there.
Right.
And understand the value here.
If you don't understand much about what's really going on here by the crypt function I got a lecture
on security on the security section of this course and I explain a little bit more about the function
here.
But you can always get more information on the BHB that Net Web site.
All right.
Just to know exactly how this works because you know it would take me a lecture or two to explain it.
They go deep into it you know.
But anyways so now that I have this here now it will be able to compare both passwords and he will allow
me to log in show you right now.
All right.
So I'm just going to refresh my cursor there enter.
Am going to say them all.
And then one two or three after and now is going to allow me to go in.
Right.
So this descript function will convert the password encrypted password.
Right it was a name put and they were output the same.
If you just provide the hash with a password again.
All right.
So and remember that hash is just that.
This train the 22 characters and that then the hash format.
I'll show you right now this is this is the hash for my right here.
That's the cost.
Right.
You can get up and BHB that on that Web site and that use some crazy strings 22.
Now we're going to correct one of these here because we need to actually make this 22 characters.
And I think he only has 21.
A good way of finding out is when you do you use a function call as to or lenth.
All right.
So we want to make sure that that's 22 characters I believe is you I believe is 22.
But just to make sure let's go ahead and try it out.
I'm going to do a little simple try here.
So are you just going to comment is out here.
Actually I'm going to comment all this out.
I'll show you right now how two we can test this out.
All right.
And we can just come in everything that's fine let's just comment is holding just a simple test to show
you right.
This is going to actually take us to the logon page.
All right.
So let's just test it out real quick and then just say test this just to make sure that it does take
us there.
Right.
And then lo again it takes us to the page.
All right so now we can test is going to show you real quick exactly what I'm talking about.
So
this is Zed's right here.
So let's say you have a password right and the password is secret.
And this is the hash format and just going to show you this real quick hash format in the hash format
is in the HP that Net Web sites a special form.
Is there anything you wanna write to Y and I think 700 ph be there on that Web site and you're going
to make it.
And this is how many times it is going to fliped is going to do the conversion is going to try is going
to do it 10 times.
All right.
And let's do that salt.
The salt is the strings.
And again this lecture is on the security section by the way.
And I just use whatever random character I want and I'm just going to use I use some crazy string.
You see I'm forgetting and there's there.
I have a feeling that this is only 21 characters.
When you make sure that it is 22 characters.
So I'm just going to echo this out and let let's try and let's see I'm going to submit here is 21 characters.
Let's make sure is 22 characters and I use some crazy strings with and this is the one that I were looking
for.
All right.
So what we need to do is let's go back so 22 characters.
Let's make sure that this is 22 characters in our database.
All right so it's going to go to a structure change of field and that's going to add right here strings.
There we go.
Safe.
All right.
So now we are good to go and I just wanted to show you that this is how he goes.
Let's say this is just a static password that I'm using here.
This is why you are going to get from the form usually something like that right whatever you set it
to be.
This is going to be the hash format.
And this is the salt and remember the crypt function goes like this.
Right.
It takes the password right and it takes a hash for me and the song together.
So that's what we did in the database.
All right we put both of them together.
All right.
So that way we can just save it in one field in the database because that's what it takes right here.
But I mean we can just do it like this
and this one right here.
And that's what we got in the database.
All right.
As you know you can pause this video and watch it again.
But anyway it's just going to comment this out.
I just wanted to give a little detail about how that works.
And now we are good to go right.
We can logon to our site any time we want to make sure that this works here.
Let's just say them all.
And one two three.
All right so we are good to go.
All right.
So anyway in the next lecture we're going to be helping her user page here not display them let just
go back here.
Now let's play these long password here.
All right we want it to display whatever PP-ASEL we set it to.
Right now we go ahead and do this.
It doesn't actually even encrypt the password so we need to make sure that encrypts the password and
shows only this here.
OK.
We're going to do the next lecture take here