In this lesson, we'll download the WordPress core files from WordPress.org and then explore the configuration
file that connects the files to the database.
You'll follow along as I diagram how WordPress works with the request from the user.
The database query and the web page being delivered to the browser.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how WordPress requires both files and a database hosted
physically at a hosting server.
Let's learn how WordPress works if we go to WordPress dot org, the self-hosted open source version
of the WordPress software.
The initial page you open up is just about WordPress and different sites that use it.
But if you click Get WordPress, it'll bring you to few descriptions and it immediately talks about
hosting.
Because as you'll learn in this video and this lesson, you can't just take WordPress the software and
open it up on your computer and build websites.
The software is designed to be hosted.
It needs to have a place to hold files and a connection to a database, and that's the beauty of WordPress.
It uses a web server software to be able to combine and create web pages on the fly, which allows it
to be a C, M.S. or a content management system.
But first off, let's just take a look at what WordPress is.
It actually is just a bunch of files, including some JavaScript and some other things.
So I have just clicked the download button to download the latest version of WordPress, and it's downloading
here on my Into My Downloads folder.
You could see at the bottom of the screen here just takes a couple of seconds and it downloads as a
dot zip file.
And so if you'd like to follow along, this is a great exercise in learning behind the scenes how WordPress
works, and it'll help you to understand the WordPress system, the environment that it needs the hosting,
as well as being able to troubleshoot WordPress much better, knowing how it all works.
So let's get into it.
I'll just close this back down and just leave this page open in my browser and open up my file explorer.
I usually like to open up to windows, and if you're using a Mac, you can use the Finder to store the
WordPress version zip file over in a folder on your computer where you know where it is, and then you
can double click the zip file on a Mac, or you can right click and choose Extract, all like I've done
here to open up the file.
So if I double click that there's usually a folder called WordPress inside of that unzipped file.
And then if you double click that these are all the files that make up the WordPress software.
This is all it is.
It's a whole bunch of files and three folders with some other folders and files in there.
And really, there's only two things that really get changed when you're working with WordPress.
One is the contents of the WP content folder.
That's where your themes and plugins and also your media in the media library gets stored in an folder
called uploads that gets created inside this WP content folder.
And if we go back this file right here, the WP Dash Config Dash Sample file is the one that you can
change and remove this word sample if you're installing WordPress manually, which is something we'll
do later in this section, but just now, follow along and open this up for yourself and just take a
look at these files.
You don't have to open this up in a code editor.
You can open it up in a text editor like notepad or text.
Add it on the Mac, but I'm going to go ahead and open up this file in my code editor called Adam.
I've got that open in the Adam program, which gives me a little bit of color to tell me a little bit
more about the code that's in here.
But this WP configuration file in WordPress is the one place that connects the WordPress files to the
database.
And so you've got four credentials that are needed a database name, a database user, a password for
that database user and a database host.
In many cases, the host is called local host, but depending on your hosting, it may be something
different.
And then this username and password is not the same as the username and password that you get created
for your WordPress user credentials themselves.
Now, you usually don't have to go in here and edit any of this stuff unless you're installing WordPress
manually.
But we're just in here to inspect how WordPress works and how the files get connected to the database.
Now the beauty of WordPress is that the files themselves are saved in this on the server and the content
of the website, including all the text and all the references to the images and the navigation and
everything.
The whole series of content that makes up the WordPress website is saved in the database.
And that's what enables it to be a content management system or a CMS.
So if we scroll down a little bit further in the config file, there's a security series of keys called
Salt's that usually get created by your hosting company.
And here's where the table prefix is defined.
So standardised by WP underscore.
But as you've seen when we talked about grid pain and other hosting providers, they'll often change
the table prefix prefix for for security.
And so there's other places in here where you can place some different codes in order to enable different
functionality for WordPress.
For example, if you're enabling multi-site, this is where that would be defined.
If you're trying to debug something, you can turn this to true and turn on a debug function and hosting
a good pin does that automatically.
But this is just the only file inside the WordPress file structure that really gets changed by the user,
and that you would want to go in and edit any of these other PHP files are not something that you should
edit at all.
In fact, if you did, they would be overwritten when you updated WordPress.
And so the only thing that you would change again is the WP config file in some cases, and then the
WP content folder gets changed and added to as you build a WordPress website.
Now, with all that said, let's just take a look at a diagram about how WordPress works.
And this will make a little bit more sense to you before we go into the other lessons in this section
where we're going to take apart and put together WordPress and inspect how all this works in real time
with real websites.
So as we look at my diagram here about how WordPress works, this is really how many websites softwares
work.
But the this little diagram just outlines how it works and how WordPress fits in to the server space
and how it delivers web pages to the user.
So over here, we've got the user's browser.
Now, of course, what can happen is you either go to a search window and click through to a URL or
you type a URL into the address bar of the browser.
And that is a domain you URL.
Now that domain URL gets translated automatically into an IP address, and that's what the DNS and the
domain name system is for.
And so this is the domain and URL and IP address.
It goes out to the internet, and the IP address system knows where to point it.
It points it to the appropriate server.
And so in real time, what happens is the user's browser goes out and it says, I want this domain URL
and it goes to the appropriate IP address, which finds the server.
And now living in the at the server is the WordPress web site made up of a few different parts.
And so the files are here.
The files that we just looked at are hosted at the server physically on a computer attached to the internet
called a server, and they are comprised of PHP and JavaScript files.
And so those are the files now alongside the files.
Now, the files wouldn't do anything by themselves.
They need the database.
And so those files, like I mentioned, are connected to the database through that WP config file.
And so the database is also hosted at the server.
And so that what happens is the URL tells the browser, OK, go to that server and get this particular
page.
And so in the database, that particular page URLs associated with certain content also hosted at the
database, it might go over to the files and say, I want these images from the media library, etc.
And then in real time, those two things get combined and delivered as a web page.
And then that web page in the form of HTML and CSS, which the browser can read, is sent back to the
user, and it's delivered as a web page that's visible to the user as an HTML slash web page.
And so that's the whole system, that system, that circular, you know, travel of data happens within
seconds.
You know, it's you want to have your sites open from anywhere in the world at less than two seconds
would be ideal, you know, so this is happening very, very fast.
But it's good to know that there's two different things that are happening and getting combined into
one.
Turning from PHP and JavaScript and also my sequel, which is the language that we use in WordPress
when we're working with the database.
And those two things get combined in real time into a different kind of document and HTML and CSS document,
which is what's designed to be read by the user's browser.
And that's how you get a web page open in your browser.