In this lesson, we'll export the files and database of a working WordPress site from local and look
at the resulting zip file.
You'll see how locals export can be used to bring the site to any host.
But it's easy to drag it into local on any computer to make a working copy.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how local can easily create a backup file for migration
or storage.
Sometimes you need to migrate sites from one host to another, and in the next few lessons, I'm going
to demonstrate a few different ways of doing this, and I'm going to use the local development environment
to show you a few things about doing it.
But that doesn't mean that you need to use local to migrate websites.
It just means I'm using it as a sample environment.
You can migrate a WordPress web site from any host to another host, whether it's hosted locally on
a computer or whether it's at a live host.
And I've done this quite often with lots of different client sites, from one hosting company to another.
And there's a few different methods to it.
For starters, let's just take a look at one site that I have in my local development environment.
Using local called Kadence and the reason I'm starting with Kadence is because it's just obvious when
we open it up, it's at the address cadence dot local here on my computer.
And you can also see that it is one of these starter templates that we worked on in the cadence section
of the course.
Here all the pages are here.
The About page and the blog page and the brokerage page and all everything is working, and it's just
a working site with multiple pages.
And so I'm going to show you how you can migrate this site into some different environments.
And let's just start with bringing a site and making a copy of it inside of local itself.
Now, if we use local, one thing that's neat about local is that you can right click on the site title
and you get some options.
First of all, you can save it as a blueprint and then use that when you start new sites later.
That's pretty cool to do.
You can clone the site, but I do want to show you how you can export this site.
Now I've already clicked export and chosen a name for it.
And so if I open up my file explorer on my desktop, I've got a folder called cadence.
And here is what I named it Kadence Dash Local, and it created a zipped folder with a few things in
it.
So if I were to go ahead and extract everything out of this zip file, it will just take a few minutes.
And what was it, a 40 or so megabyte zip file?
And it looks like it's going to create in about a minute, 30 seconds to a minute.
It'll show me inside this folder what it was exported out of local.
And now, interestingly, the reason I'm telling you this and showing you the export function in local
instead of just using the clone function is that we can take this zip file and the contents of it,
and we can use it to bring the website anywhere we want.
We can bring it up to site ground, for example, or grid pain or flywheel or any WordPress host.
And so soon, as this finishes, let's just take a look at what local gives us as an export for this
web site.
It's basically going to give us everything that we need to bring the web site over to any new host,
including back into local if we want to.
And so gives us three folders the app, the config folder in the logs folder from from local and then
a JSON file with the name.
But let's look under app and under app.
Here's where we have the real WordPress files and the database.
So under SQL, we have a file called local, which is a dot se que el file that is the database export.
And so you can you can export, you know, any SQL file from a working WordPress database, and you
can use that to import that site anywhere you want to.
And we're going to do that in several different ways.
And so let's go back up to app and look under public.
And now what we have is the entire file structure of the WordPress site, the way it was in that local
website.
And so I just want to show you what, what actually is there?
You know, you could look under the WP content.
Of course, under themes, I should have the cadence theme there.
Yeah.
Also under the plugins theme, I also have the cadence blocks and the cadence starter templates plugins
in there.
And so that's where the the changes live under WP content.
Now, as I've said before, the minimum that you need to migrate it somewhere else is you need the WP
content folder like this.
And then you also need an export of the database in the form of a dot SQL.
File.
And that's what this is right here.
And so it's easy to take a local website that you create just on your computer and migrate it over to
a live host if you want to, or even to a different computer where you have local installed or something
like that.
But let's start with just the easiest a local to local import or migration.
So if I have local open on my computer and I also have an export file, let's go back to Kadence and
just look at this zip file.
If I just take and drag that zip file over into local, it brings me to an import screen and it will
automatically unzip and install that whole site exactly as it was under a new name.
And so that is really just an easy local to local migration.
So I'm going to I don't want to call it Kadence.
It would be the same name, so I already have one in here called Kadence Import.
Let's call this one Kadence import two.
So I don't have, you know, I don't have a repeated site name and I'll know which it is.
And so I just click Continue.
I can choose the server type that I want, and it's just like installing a new site in local, but it's
extracting the import and it will only take a few seconds and then we'll be able to look at the results.
Now, if we go over to the original site, this is at the URL cadence dot local.
And you could see, as I showed you before, it's just, you know, working site with this real estate
starter template and let's open local back up.
And as it finishes up, it's telling me what it's doing now.
It's importing the database and it's provisioning over here and it's changing the site domain.
And in just a couple seconds, I think it will be finished and I'll pause the video and just give it
a few more seconds.
Well, he only had to pause the video for one or two seconds and this screen popped up.
And so it gives me a couple of little messages.
Sure, I could do one click admin, but when we look at it, this is cadence import two now that we're
under and the domain is cadence import to dot local and everything should be the same.
So if I click the open state now I have a site under the URL cadence import to dot local and we'll see
if that opens up the site.
There it is.
So it's an exact copy of that site and by importing the zip file that I exported from local, it's just
really easy to migrate and make a copy of that site.
It's actually the same functionality that you would get if you right click and hit clone.
It just doesn't, you know, bring the zip file on to your computer.
But having that zip file is a good way to store a copy of this WordPress web site that you could actually
bring anywhere.
You don't have to bring it back into local.
And so that's kind of the first start and easy way to migrate a site from local into local and change
the name and make an exact copy of.