In this lesson, we'll set up a new device sandbox site and import another layout pack to use while
we learn more advanced device techniques.
You'll also download a header template file from the DV website and import it into the site to match
the layout, as well as create a new default category for blog posts.
By the end of this video, you'll have an understanding of where we're going in this section of the
course and import content from a doc JSON file that you can get from the DV blog.
Let's look at where we are in the Diffie curriculum and where we're going in this section of the course.
Right now in lessons, we're really going to focus on global elements and templates within the DV,
theme builder and the theme builder, especially where we're going to be looking at over here under
Divij theme builder.
Here's a preview of some of the setups that we're going to be working with over the next several lessons
in this divvy part two section of the course not only global header and global footer, but also looking
at customizing a special header for just certain pages, as well as a custom body that we're going to
add for just blog posts that will help clients and content managers to go in and not have to learn the
DeFi ecosystem, but be able to use the traditional block editor.
And so back into here in our plan, as we look at first bringing in another set of layouts from the
elegant themes and the DeFi builder layout packs, we're going to be doing that and then looking at
post templates and global elements in this segment, including the theme builder page templates, headers
and footers, and those sorts of things that we can then leverage in order to work with our theme and
our customized design on a global level and define different places and different pages and page types
where our premium content and the content we customize can be used.
We'll also look at blog post templates and bringing a blog post template in from a separate layout pack
and using it together with the layout pack that we're customizing and bringing the colors and fonts
and the typography together in order to match.
You may have noticed that the leverage Devi website is using a pre designed layout.
I don't know if you've seen it, but there's also this custom header that's a transparent header that
changes into a sticky or fixed header when it goes up to the top.
It also has a log in button over here on the right.
It's got a nice scroll button that brings you down to this next section, as well as the learn more
button doing that same thing.
And there's a sign up button that goes to the register page, as well as an interesting footer down
here at the bottom.
It has this nice scrolling parallax effect where there's one image in front of the background scrolls
at a different rate.
And so we're going to take a look at a few different areas here and customize your own version of this
leverage dark website.
Let's get started.
Go ahead and go to leverage divide.
Com And click Log in or sign up.
If you don't have your sandbox account yet, get a go ahead and click the login button right here.
Which brings me to that login page.
Log in real quick.
And that brings me to the leverage DV profile, and if you do end up there, you can always roll over
my sites and go to the last site that you created right here.
Creating a new site is easy under.
You can either click my sites here at the top left or under home right here.
You can also look at your account page for the sandbox itself.
Down here is a list of your sites, and there's an add new site button right here now for the URL,
I'm going to use my initials again and just call this one good travel.
This layout pack is called Travel Agency under the elegant themes, layout packs and just call it GHD
travel as a site title and click Add site.
Of course, that immediately adds the site to your account, and this is the my site's page right here.
You're already inside of the dashboard of that new site that you've created right away.
And so one thing you can do is just go over to appearance right away and click themes and of course,
activate the device theme instead of the default twenty twenty two.
Now we have all the device controls that we need.
Oftentimes, I'll just go over to settings and reading and see what I have here.
Of course, I don't have any pages yet to set the static page.
As the home page.
We're going to import a couple of layout packs and create a few new pages here.
But another thing I might do is look at the permalink and I always like to change it away from the default
day and name permalink structure to make the URL a little more simple and call it post name.
So let's go ahead and do that now that we have that taken care of.
Let's go in and look at pages, all pages.
And as usual, I might just trash the sample page and start to bring in a few new pages.
I'll show you where to find the layout pack that will be working on and customizing for the next few
lessons, and then leave you to bring in a few pages of your own, if not all eight pages of this layout
pack.
So we'll just start by typing home to bring in the home page for this layout pack.
Click Use the Divvy Builder again, as you know, and let's search for travel agency under here.
Start building right there and choose a pre-made layout.
Now, as it opens up the pre-made layouts from the Elegant Themes website, the travel agency is the
one we're talking about.
And if you click home or any of the pages in the travel agency layout pack, you'll see that there are
eight pages to choose from.
And let's bring in a few different ones the home page, the landing page.
I used the landing page as the home page for the Leverage Divvy Dotcom website.
I liked it because it had a full screen, top to bottom image at the top instead of on the home page
here.
Having these four images, but let's just bring it in, as is.
What I'd suggest you do is at least bring in the home page, and let's take a look at the landing page,
as well as the what was it, the travel packages, I think.
Let's bring in a couple of these pages and we'll get them set so positive video now and bring in a bunch
of the pages, if not all of them.
Go ahead.
And as they come in here and finish to 100 percent, as you remember, they'll bring in the graphics
and images into your media library and then you'll want to click the publish page to make sure that
you save the layout after you bring it in.
So click Publish.
And then there's one page in particular I want to make sure that you do bring in, so I'll just go over
to new.
After I've hit publish, I can go straight to new page, create a new page, and again, let's look
at the well, we could open the elegant Themes Layouts page just to take a look here.
As I suggested in the previous section of the course, if we if we have this open, then it's easy to
look at which pages that we want to name before we bring in that layout pack.
And so this travel packages, it's called packages.
The reason why I want you to bring in this page or one of the light color pages is because at the top,
this area at the top is a white or light color background, and we're going to have to edit the customized
menu and global header that we're bringing in in the.
Next, few lessons, and so make sure you bring in travel packages.
I'll just call it travel, actually.
I'll just call it packages, because that's the way it's called in the layout pack itself.
And as I'm doing this, I'll go ahead and pause the video like I mentioned and let you guys bring in
your own set of pages and see you on the other side.
OK, I hope that went well for you.
I brought in all eight pages, so I have everything in the website that I need to work with, including
all the media inside of the library.
Now, if you open your media library, you can see that all of the images and everything that you need
for this layout is inside, and there is one more thing we need to go pick up before we get on with
the next several lessons and one of them is the header download.
And so let's we're going to be working with a global header, in fact, if we look at, you know, the
leverage division website itself.
This header, of course, is much different looking than the one that is by default on your current
website.
So if you open your site in a new tab, you'll notice that it's, of course, the same default header
that we had before and before we even bring in that header that we're going to import and customize
and work with.
Let's go back and customize some other things about this site before we get started.
First, of course, we could go into settings reading and choose the home page or the landing page,
if you like as our home page.
And now when we go back and refresh the page, we'll have, of course, a nicer looking site right here.
One of the great things about this also is this awesome gallery set up where each of these images opens
up in a light box so that you can click and make them larger.
Quite nice.
You'll notice the difference with the overlay here from the Leverage Divi website.
I brightened up that image and made it a lot more bright and crisp, even though it's still readable
as far as the text goes.
But one of the things we're going to be changing soon is when we go to say this page here it leverages
TV.
I've still got this travel packages page just as the default page here inside of the website for now,
but you can see that you know these menu items that I have in here just to light to contrast.
So we're going to have a conditional header where on certain pages, it shows these letters darker and
on other pages like the home page, it shows them light as they work on a darker background like this.
And so looking at your own home page, you can see that we also have the uncategorized, you know,
category here up in the menu.
It won't matter because we're going to be importing, you know, that header layout so that we can customize
it, as well as customizing the logo image if you want to read in here.
And so next, what we'll do is go into the elegant themes dot com website again, where you might have
had this layout packs page open.
And let's scroll to the bottom and go to the blog by clicking blog or clicking recent posts.
And if you search for Transparent.
Oops!
Got to spell it right.
Search for transparent, there is a transparent header tutorial right here, which is this header that
I'm using and that matches our travel agency layout pack.
And so go ahead and click that as you scroll down and look through the post a little bit if you click
the download files button.
If it doesn't download right away, just go ahead and enter your email address to join the email list.
Elegant theme scam and then click the Download the Files button.
You can move that if you like into a folder on your on your computer or leave it in your downloads folder.
Just know where that file is so that when you open up the File Explorer or the Finder in a Mac, you
can go ahead and find it and then unzip the zip file.
Right click Extract.
All like I mentioned for Windows and double click a zip file in a Mac and that will open it up for you.
So what we have inside the folder is the JSON file, and that's what we'll be importing into the website
to bring in that header layout in the next few lessons.
OK, so I think that prepares our website.
I'm also going to be leaving the post inside here, the Hello World post, and in fact, one thing you
can do to prepare a blog post and make it a little better looking for now is to add a featured image.
And so I just opened it up.
And of course, it's not using the DV builder yet to edit this post.
It's actually using the classic block inside of the editor right here.
And so I'm just going to click set featured image.
Look in the media library and just click one of the images that we have here as the featured image for
the blog post and click Update.
Last thing you can do also is if you click the classic block, you can convert the content to blocks.
And so that really just places it as a paragraph block for the initial post that we have here, and
I'll click Update and then we'll click the WordPress logo here to go back to the posts layout.
And of course, under categories.
This is under uncategorized, which isn't very pretty.
Oftentimes, I'll go in and just to show you quickly here I'll go into categories and I'll choose a
new category one.
That might be just news as some generic category that you can leave as the default category for a blog
post that's not categorized if you have categories later inside the blog, so you can choose a name
like news or something generic like that and then have that news.
If you edit the news category, then you can look at, you know what the slug is, which is the URL
name and everything down here.
And now one last change we can create, we can make that news category, our default category under
Settings rating.
And you can say that the default post category instead of uncategorized is now news this post category
that we created.
And so now under posts, we have, you know, a nicely formatted Hello World sample post with a featured
image we can click either edit or quick edit.
Quick Edit is a way to bring up just some meta information about the post or your pages and change some
of the information easily.
So we'll just change that to the news category and click Update.
And without opening the editing window, we can change a lot of that information over here.
And so that looks good.
What about the author?
In fact, I'll go right into my under user's profile and just change my display name here by putting
in a first and last.
Once I change that, then this will give me the option to display my name publicly in a little more
friendly way.
And that makes it so that the author name then will be displayed in the better information for for the
reader.
OK, let's get on to the next stages.