In this lesson, we'll start exploring the 20 22 block based theme included in WordPress, which allows
for full site editing and creating site wide templates without using any code.
We'll check out the site editor and template system and discover how the theme enables you to use content
blocks to control things like header and footer and other global elements.
By the end of this video, you'll know where to start.
As far as setting up the 2022 theme and how to get your own site set up to start building in this section
of the course, let's get to it.
So taking a look at this dashboard page, this welcome here it has a dismiss button up here at the top,
which is generally what you want to do after you've read that.
But you can always get things back to your dashboard.
Up here at the top right, you can use this little screen options dropdown and you can see if I click
the welcome checkbox that that welcome comes back.
And so once you dismiss it, it won't come back for you again, and you can control the way your dashboard
looks by checking or checking any of these screen elements in screen options here.
And so as we take a look at this, let's just go down and look under appearance themes and take a look
at what we have here.
We have the active theme showing at the top left always, and that's twenty twenty two and it'll show
customize if you have that theme activated.
Now the next theme over doesn't show customize.
It shows the Activate button and the theme details where you can open a modal window up at the top here
and get a little bit of information on the themes.
The theme that you have available inside of your WordPress installation and you can click Activate from
here as well.
You can also close the model over here at the right, and you can go to the next or previous using these
little arrow buttons.
And I'll just go ahead and use the X to close that.
And let's go to the next stage.
Now, if you hit this customize button that will open this editor and you see it's so new that it has
a little red mark here called beta, meaning that this is still being developed and actively worked
on by many, many volunteers in the WordPress ecosystem.
And it's really there's not as many active sites using this type of editor, which is a block based
theme.
But what are we going to do in this video?
And this section of the course is use the 20 22 theme to learn about block based editing, as well as
blocks within the WordPress editor.
And then let's go ahead and just take a look at what this 20 22 theme looks like out of the box.
Now this will be true of if you install WordPress as a fresh installation at any host, you will see
that it'll install 20 22 theme and activate it, and it'll just be a blank website.
Looking like this, I'll roll over my sites and under the name of the site, you can click visit site
or at the top in the admin bar here.
There's also the name of the site and the visit site link, so I'll right click that and open into the
new tab.
And when I click that new tab, you can see that here's a live site and it is pretty basic.
The way WordPress comes out of the box by default is generally, it'll show you a home page, which
shows the blog posts that are present within the WordPress installation or the website.
And WordPress comes with one sample blog post called Helloworld and just has some welcome text blog
posts or generally, you know, displayed in reverse chronological order.
So you'll usually see a date, a title sometimes and author categories or tags marking and categorizing
those blog posts.
And so you'll see the homepage of the 2022 theme has a nice little graphic, and it has a header at
the top with the name which is clickable to the home page, as well as a menu that goes to the pages.
Now a post.
Like I said, if I click the title of the post, we can see that now the header has changed a little
bit.
It's now a white background instead of that dark black.
It has the same menu and the name of the site over here on the top left at which clicks back to the
homepage and then you have a title.
You know, there's a little dividing line and some more content that we didn't see on the home page
because that was kind of an excerpt of each blog post.
Now, below the content of the blog post, you can see the date, the author and the category of this
blog post.
And there's another little dividing line and there's a comment that comes shipping with WordPress.
This is a comment, and it shows you a little icon, which.
Presents, if the person has a gravitas or their email address is associated at gravitas with their
headshot, it might show here.
And then there's a little reply button when you're logged in and then leave a reply.
This is a comments form, and so it's got the comments form here.
I'm already logged in, so it tells me, you know, that I'm replying as this person and the post comments
button now at the bottom of the website, there's also a footer.
This is present on the whole website, again out of the box.
This comes with a link back to the homepage and then a message that that links to the WordPress dot
org project, open source WordPress or otherwise known as self-hosted WordPress, which we're working
with through this entire course.
And so let me go back up, and let's talk about the difference between a post and a page.
Just briefly, a page is more of a static content page within the website.
Generally, things like the About Page, a contact us page for a business website.
You might have a projects or services page a and other general static content pages that stay the same
all the time, unlike posts.
And so in the WordPress environment, you've got posts and you've got pages you can see on this sample
page.
There's a few different things in here.
It's got a little description that comes by default.
And then again, the footer shows the same way.
Also that same header up at the top here, and we're going to be talking about headers and footers and
other global elements in WordPress that are site wide, staying the same.
So if I edit the header, for example, that header will change on every page of the website, so I'll
click back to home.
And really, that's that's all we have in a default installation with the 20 22 theme.
And so let's go back to the dashboard.
I often like to have, you know, a dashboard open under one tab in my browser and the live site open
in a second tab so I can go back and forth and refresh the page as I make changes.
But if I go back here into the WordPress dashboard under appearance now I can click ED.
And this is what's unique and new about a block based theme like Twenty Twenty Two, and that is when
you click editor, you are editing the entire site.
You're not you're not editing the content of any post or of any page, but you are editing the global
elements or what are called templates and template parts that make up the different parts of the website
and the power of a block based theme.
Is that now, without rewriting or copying and pasting any code at all, you can control all the parts
of the website using a block based theme, including the header content and the footer content.
And with this system, you can have a certain type of header like a black background header on one page
and on a different page.
You can have a white background header like all the other sample page, etc. on this website.
And so let's take a look at the controls we have here.
First up, at the top left, if I hit the WordPress logo up here, it toggles the navigation.
And so this is some navigation for editing, the different things that I can edit.
And then this is the content area showing you a sample page in this case, the home page and what that
looks like.
And as I roll over the different parts of this homepage, you can see that it gets a little highlighting
an outline in blue.
And so if I if I I, you can see that site is highlighted right here for this site.
So this is in this site.
I'm looking at the home template up here.
This is the show template details dropdown.
So if I click that little arrow, it tells me the title of the template that I'm looking at and it tells
me what areas are contained within this template that we can change.
And so this is the header you can see it highlighting.
And if I scroll down here, you could see that if I roll over this, this is the footer right here.
And then there's some other stuff in the middle here.
This is just an example of a blog post.
Now, we wouldn't edit the content of a blog post within the site editor right here.
We would edit that within the post editing page itself.
And so you may have noticed in SEO, browse all templates better that exist on this website and within
this theme.
And that's the same as clicking over here, where it says templates.
And so if I click browse all templates there can see that the templates is highlighted with in the.
Navigation panel over here on the left hand side, and you could see that the templates that exist in
this theme and in this website are right here and it says added by.
And this is the theme title 20 22.
And so you'll have all the themes by default or excuse me, all the templates by default listed here.
And you can see that they're added by the theme.
And that's the beauty of block based themes.
A theme author or developer can create any number of templates that then the user can use to customize
and make their website unique from all others.
And we're going to go ahead and move forward with customizing this, this theme and this website using
the 2022 theme.
You can also see that there's an add new button up over here on the right.
And if we get when we get to the point where we're going to create a new template for a certain purpose,
like maybe we have an event, for example, or we have say, you know, something that that the business
is going to have in their business that needs its own special web page set apart from the other parts
of the website and looks different.
And so you can click Add New to add a new template.
And then so if we add a new template, this will be used as the kind of sample to start from as the
starting starting point there.
So when you do this, this is this says front page, and then you would save it here.
Once you build the template for that type of page, then once you create pages, you can choose that
template and display them however you like.
We'll get into this later, so I'm going to go ahead and click the W to go back to the Navigator and
then all the way back to the WordPress dashboard by clicking that little dashboard with the left arrow.
And so remember that was under appearance ED, and that is a good start, a tour of how block based
themes work.
And so next, we're going to get into how we're going to customize the 20 22 theme, and we have a sample
design to go from and we're going to make it look like the sample.
And so let's get into it.
See you then.