In this lesson, we'll get a DeFi website set up and take a look at the topics covered on DeFi.
In this course, you'll create a new site in the sandbox and import some DeFi layouts into it for us
to work with.
By the end of this video, you'll have an understanding of how much there is to cover in DeFi and the
nine major topics you'll be learning in the course.
Let's get started building a new site and learning about a page builder and theme called Devi.
Now, this is the first time that we've worked with a strictly paid team and a layout system that is
really what I largely use for most, if not all of my client sites and my work on my own website lately.
Now, DeFi is made by elegant themes at elegant themes, dot com, and one of the things I really love
about it is that for either an inexpensive yearly fee or a one time lifetime fee, you can use it on
unlimited websites and it has a whole lot of features will be going over in this section of the course,
including a whole bunch of layouts.
If we look at the Layouts Library here on the elegant themes website, you can see that as that loads,
it has almost 250 complete layout packs, each of which have six or seven or eight pages to them that
are completely designed, including the license free images that you can use and graphics.
And so right now, there's a total of eighteen hundred and twenty two total layouts.
They release new layouts and new design systems every single week, and so we'll explore how to find
those and how to use them as starting points as a way to learn the divvy system.
So we will be installing and setting up.
Is this design agency layout pack at least part of it?
It comes with nine different pages.
There's a home page as well as a landing page and a bunch of other pages, including two project pages
you can use in the DeFi projects custom post type.
And so it's a really versatile layout and has some interesting design features.
But first, let's go in and I'll show you how to set this up inside of the leverage div e-comm sandbox.
If you just go to leverage DeFi Dotcom, you'll see on this website, it gives you a little overview
of what the sandbox does, etc. And all you have to do is go to register or you can click Sign up right
here, and then you can go ahead and create yourself a site and get it set up in just a couple of seconds.
You just pick a site title and then the URL will be whatever it is, leveraged VK.com.
I'm just going to write good agency for that one and continue to the next step.
Then you'll choose a username, email address and choose your password and type it two times so that
it matches and click Create Account.
You'll likely see the welcome message that you can just click Dismiss on right up here at the top and
then under appearance themes, the also likely have the default 2022 theme enabled.
And so just go here under appearance themes and click activate under the device theme.
Now what you have is for you.
Right click Visit Site under the name of your site here and click Open in a new tab.
You just have a default layout with an empty blank divvy powered website, and you could see that there's
nothing there, but your latest post that's there by default, a page called Sample Page that comes
created in WordPress by default, a sidebar with a couple of widgets in there and a logo that clicks
back to the home page, as well as a footer that has one of the areas populated with a couple of widgets.
Now we'll get in and learn how to import layout content into your new device site directly from the
device website inside of your WordPress site.
So if we go back into the dashboard here, the next place we want to go is over two pages, all pages.
And you know, what I usually do is just go ahead and put this sample page in the trash by clicking
trash right there.
If you ever want to, you could go under all pages.
And if you view the trash by clicking the tab at the top, there you can click empty trash, or you
can restore a page that's in the trash or even delete it permanently here.
And so if we go back to all pages, I also usually go back into posts and I put that hello world post
in the trash as well, and we can make some sample posts later on when we're learning how to work with
Divij and the posts archive and blog archive pages.
But let's go into pages and all pages and click Add New.
Now, when we do this in Divij, it'll give you a welcome to the Block editor message, most likely.
And the first page we want to bring in is home.
So let's just type home in the title.
And then you can type use Divvy Builder or click that button right there.
Now it saves that that page so that you can have that as your page title and the URL as the permalink.
And then it gives you a welcome to defeat builder.
Usually just click Start Building, and I'll teach you how to turn that welcome tour off.
So that doesn't bother you every time.
And then you'll generally get these three items as a welcome to starting a new empty page using Divij.
And so let's click choose a pre-made layout and then you'll notice there's a familiar screen right here.
It's the same interface, and it's actually bringing all these layouts in from the elegant themes website.
And so I'll usually have the layouts that I showed you before under elegant themes come up in a separate
tab so I can look at the layout pack that I'm importing and I can see what pages I need to import from
the layout pack itself.
So starting from the home page, just so you can see it, you can also view a live demo which will open
just a generic kind of menu and header at the top, but it lets you see the page at full size before
you import it or do anything with it.
But over here, I just use this open on another tab so that I can see the titles of each page.
You can bring all nine pages and if you like, and that'd be a good exercise now, we'll just bring
in a few that I'm going to show you around and start with our tour of div layouts and how to use some
of the controls and the features of the Divij Visual Builder here in our sandbox site.
So back at the sandbox on our new page under load from library, what we have is the pre-made layouts
tab open at first and you also have saved layouts that you might have in your TV library.
We'll go over that and then your existing pages.
You can even duplicate existing pages as a starting point.
But now let's just go ahead and click the design agency layout pack.
Click Home and then you can click this to use this layout button that'll give you a little progress
bar, and that brings in the entire layout, including all of the copyright free images and graphics
that you can use on the page.
And now what we have here is the representation of the page with the visual builder in front, and you
can see these frames around the different sections, different colors, as well as these gray colors
around the different sections.
So you can, you know, inspect that a little bit, but the next thing to do is just to go ahead and
click publish at the bottom right so that you're saving that page into your website.
And then I would suggest that you just go through and go back to new and click page and then we can
import.
Page after page, and so if we do the landing page next, I'll just type landing.
And you can refer to your other layouts page open in another tab to see which pages you want to bring
in.
And so I would suggest that you do that and let's go ahead and bring in a few different pages.
Now, I might suggest you bring in at least the home landing and case study pages because those are
the ones who are going to be going over in this section of the course.
But you might as well bring in all nine pages.
And when you do bring in the Project one and project two pages into not the pages area, but the portfolio
custom post type in divvy.
And I'll show you that in just a moment and then pause the video to give you a chance to bring in all
of these page layouts into your new DV site.
So click Choose a pre-made layout.
This is going to be the landing page.
I have to click the design agency layout and then make sure that landing is selected and click Use.
This layout usually takes just a few seconds to import the layout.
Now, the more images and the longer the page, the longer it takes.
And so it might take a few seconds longer for a longer page.
The landing page is quite a bit larger than the home pages in this particular layout, and in most of
the layouts.
The landing page in the DV layouts usually gives you a good idea of most of the different types of content
sections that are in the design.
And so I like to often use the landing page as my starting point to look at what I'm going to use as
a customized home page for a new site for a client.
You can see that this page is quite a bit longer and has some different sections as you go down.
So I'll click Publish right here.
And the last thing I'll show you before I set you loose.
Bringing in your own content layouts is that you can click the Exit Visual Builder to get back to the
dashboard.
Or, of course, you can always roll over the name of your site and click dashboard.
When you click Enable Visual Builder or Disable, it brings you back to the live version of the website.
The live version is where you can see some of the interesting scrolling animations that happen in some
of these layouts, which look quite nice.
I like this nice, transparent, sideways animation.
In any case, if you need to roll over the name of your site and click dashboard and then I just wanted
to show you under projects, all projects.
Of course, there's not going to be anything there yet.
But for this Project one and project two layouts, I would suggest you go to add new and then, you
know, build yourself a new layout and bring those projects into the projects area, which is part of
the development portfolio and projects custom post type within divvy.
So I paused the video now and do that on my own site and go ahead and let you take a chance to bring
in and practice bringing those layouts in to your new device site.
OK, so I hope you're able to import all the pages you want.
If you look at my installation under pages, all pages.
I've got the seven pages that I imported and named, according to the design agency layout that we are
using.
I also have two project pages right here.
And then what I might suggest you do is go into settings reading and just set your home page as the
home page that you created and also set your leave your posts page actually blank.
Because we're actually going to use the DV builder to design that post page instead of having WordPress
automatically populate it with posts.
And so a click save changes there.
And next, we'll get into customizing and checking out how we control all this content.
Now that it's in our web site, this is the first pre designed layout pack that we'll be exploring in
order to learn some of the systems of Devi right now.
This is the default header that comes in from Devi, and you'll see that we can use global header builder
and theme builder templates in order to build our own custom headers or import them from the DeFi ecosystem,
as well as can see as we scroll down here.
There's some interesting animation as images come up and down here, there's a footer, et cetera.
And so you can explore that just a little bit.
Each of these pages has a different set of layouts powered by Devi that's easily portable here in the
sandbox.
Or if you have your own single WordPress installation at your own hosting and you've installed the Devi
theme, you can get those.
So as we scroll down here, you can see some of the interesting animation.
This is one we'll explore a little bit later that I really like down below as this computer comes across
and has kind of a transparency.
I find it really interesting as far as a visual design goes.
And so to get started here, let's just explore a document that I have out there.
I'm going to use for the.
First time in the course, there's a, you know, an ecosystem, a theme and a builder that's so complex
that I'm going to use a document to help us organize our thoughts and the material that will be going
over in order to learn this really powerful design system that basically overlays on top of WordPress
and is really a super powerful design system on top of WordPress for building custom websites.
It's also quite fast as far as performance and loading speed, and also future proof as far as working
with WordPress and really makes for an easy and fast design system on top of WordPress.
So if you look at this pretty complex mind map that I have designed here around the Disney theme and
builder, there are nine different major topics that we'll be talking about here kind of wrapped around
the device theme and the builder.
If you look at each one has its own kind of sub topic underneath.
As far as you know, the most is there's these divvy modules and the WooCommerce modules that are available
with DV.
These are all the design tools that are available in the DeFi ecosystem.
And while we won't be making a video or a lesson on each one of these items, I will be making a lesson
on each one of the major topics.
As far as looking at over here, one of the first things one of the first things we will do is just
look at the DV overview and the options before we delve into designing specific pages and headers and
footers and things inside of DV.
But then each of these topics will have a dedicated lesson inside of the course here.
Layout packs like I showed you and importing them and using them, the divvy design tools and the modules
and elements that you can use as a sort of elements that are templated.
So they're global elements that you can use to build a style guide and to build a design system that
lays on top of WordPress that allows you to control things like colors and typography on a global sense
as far as the whole website goes, and then templates and Gutenberg blocks integration.
This is a very powerful section where we'll look at enabling, say, the blog section of a website to
be edited and new blog posts to be created by a client, for example, where they don't have to go in
and learn all of this complexity about using DV.
You can actually nest the regular block editor within a custom designed DV page so that all they have
is the regular block editor.
Like what we've been learning previously in the course, and they don't have to delve into the complexity
of DV.
And you can still customize the layout and make it beautiful and match your DV layout.
As far as blog posts or other types of custom posts, go and then WooCommerce with DV, meaning an e-commerce
site with a web store and things like that.
DVD DV marketing tools where you can use split testing and other items like opt in forms for a mailing
list, et cetera.
And then we'll look at what Divvy offers as far as speed and performance optimization.
If you took a look down over here, this is something that we'll be looking at.
As far as how does divvy do things to make the front end load very fast and not load extraneous code
that you don't need.
So let's get started looking at first degree overview and options and back in the sandbox here.
Let's take a look at the dashboard and go down to the divvy settings under theme options over here,
and you can follow along in your own site and take a look at the settings that I recommend that you
start with and learn about what each of the places does inside of Divvy.