In this lesson, we'll explore the three types of email that you might need to manage while supporting
a WordPress web site at a custom domain name.
You'll learn that regular email needs hosting.
Transactional email is outgoing only from a website, and broadcast email is all about building an email
list by the end of this video.
You'll see why the three types of email mostly don't overlap and why they exist as different systems.
Let's talk about the three types of email associated with custom websites now.
The first is called Send and receive email, or you may call it hosted email.
And this is what you probably think of as regular email email addresses that you own that you can send
email from and receive email into.
Now, those email addresses require hosting because those emails and their attachments, the data that
comprises those emails needs to be stored somewhere on a server, and the receiver is the person that's
responsible for storing those emails somewhere.
Now you might think of that email hosting is is generally free, and it is known as free at, you know,
public services such as Gmail.
Your address at gmail.com is hosted email.
It is, you know, it's it's an address at a domain name now.
The domain name is gmail.com in this example, and it's free because Gmail hopes that you'll use their
services in the future, and they also capture data that they can then use in their advertising systems
and everything that they do as a google.com.
And so email is free, but email hosting is not free when you want to do it at your custom domain name.
And so that's the big difference.
And as far as our purposes here in the course, working with WordPress and making websites for yourself
and for others hosted email is something that can be free, but it's best if it has a small expense
associated with it because that hosting is something you you want to be responsible for, and that costs
money in some way.
You know, as far as gmail.com and send and receive emails that hosted email is paid for by Google because
they like to collect that data.
But if you want to have a custom email address like you at example com, then that email needs to be
hosted somewhere.
So another thing about the first type of email send and receive email is that it's a one to one setup.
There's a sender and a receiver, and it goes in both directions.
So there's, you know, sending and receiving by one person and then either replying or sending again
and receiving back and forth.
And so that's why I call it send and receive email.
The second type of emails called transactional email now transactional email is something that you're
probably familiar with, but you've not been necessarily exposed to setting it up or managing it.
Behind the scenes transactional email is something that happens from a web site to a human.
It is one directional, so it is outgoing only email.
Transactional email is something like a forgot password link.
If you click on the login page for WordPress, for example, if you click Forgot My Password, it will
generate an email that comes from the website and is received by you.
Whatever email address is your admin account and so it is sent one to one.
But it's not from a human to a human.
It's from a computer to a human, and it's also only one direction.
And so the computer sends an email out to the human.
Generally, from an address that's not designed to receive a reply, and often you've seen addresses
like no reply at example, dot com or something like that.
And so it's not designed to have an email sent back to it, and therefore it doesn't require any hosting
for a transactional email setup.
Another example would be notifications for, say, a contact form that the user might fill out on a
website.
And then that website sends a notification to the admin that says, Hey, the contact form was filled
out, and here's what the person submitted in their contact form.
That is a transactional email, again, outgoing only.
And another example would be receipts or notifications from an ecommerce web store.
So the user might receive an email, which is an invoice or a receipt from their purchase at a website.
Again, transactional email.
Now, transactional email can be free, but it's a best practice to use a service to provide that send.
And we'll talk about that deeper in the next few lessons.
The third type of email that I'd like to define as different from the first two is broadcast or marketing
email, and you might be familiar with this email, as it has to do with building an email list.
Now, building an email list and sending email to a group is something that is again sent from the computer
and sent to a group of people.
And so, as in this example diagram right here you can see that you know, there's the website sends
email, multiple email, say the same email all at once to the members of a group, and that would be
the email list.
An example would be someone subscribes to a newsletter.
And then when the owner of the website writes that newsletter and press send, they only have to do
that once.
And it sends to hundreds or thousands or tens of thousands of participants and members of that email
list.
And so these two transactional and broadcast are both outgoing only.
They're outgoing only, but one is just sending to one person and the other is sending to a group of
people.
And so oftentimes it's referred to broadcast emails referred to as bulk email sent sent in bulk.
Many at once or a lot of people talk about marketing, email.
And so the final thing I'll say about broadcast email is that in this example, for example, someone
might fill out a form and opt in to the email list.
They might opt in to the newsletter and it's marked in green here because that first email that goes
out is actually a transactional email.
Each person gets that email right away.
It might be a confirmation email so that they can verify and double opt in into the email list.
Or it might be just the first copy of the newsletter that comes to them as a single email to a single
person right away.
But then after that, when the user, the owner of the website, writes the bulk email or the marketing
email and sends it out, then they're a member of this group.
And so that changes to this orange color.
And I would define that as broadcast or marketing email.
So those are the three types of email in then that can be associated with your WordPress website or
your client's WordPress websites.
And in the next few lessons, I'm going to go over different setups how you set up both send and receive
email, transactional email systems and broadcast and marketing email systems using best practices through
either custom domain names or transactional email providers, and also broadcast email providers.
There's multiple ways to do these setups, and there's some gotchas that you want to watch out for.
So you don't make any mistakes and have either your website go down or your IP address or domain name
banned for spamming.
Let's get into it.