In this lesson, we'll look at the file location for a local website and explore how the WP config file
connects to the database.
You'll see where themes, plugins and images are saved, as well as how the text content lives in the
database.
By the end of this video, you'll understand where files are located within a WordPress installation
and also how content is stored in the database.
Now, let's take a look at how the database and the files are connected and working together on a real
working website.
I've had has a I have one open here that we've experienced before the leverage WP site, one in local.
I'm using the local development environment and you can get in here and play with your own WordPress
sites if you're using local or another local development environment, or even do this at a live hosting
server.
If you prefer.
But if we look here, remember I can click right here to open up a folder with the WordPress files right
in the right location.
But just to remind you, if I go to just the regular hard drive, the main hard drive C colon on my
windows computer here and I look at users and then my own user name, I've got a folder called local
sites, and that's where all my sites in the local development environment are located and I can go
down to L to leverage WP site one.
And that's what would open if I click that little button inside of local right over here.
But if I open app under that site name and then public, that is where the files are.
Don't those look familiar?
And there's one difference here, which is the sample is still here, but really, the working config
file has been renamed and copied and is called WP Dash config dot PHP.
And if you double click that or open that in your text editor or a code editor, I've got that open
in my Adam Code Editor program here.
You can see that here's another tab with the original sample.
It just says database name here, username here, etc. But this actual working config file has a kind
of standardized set of credentials, and this is the way that the local development environment works,
the one called local.
And so the database name is local user is root password as root and the host is local host.
And that just allows the WP config file to connect to the to the database so that this is now a unified
WordPress working website that we can see.
And also, if I scroll down a little bit, you can see that there's also some authentication keys called
Salt's that are here inside of the WP config file as well.
Just to take note in these comments.
These slash asterisks in orange here in the code editor.
If you go to this particular link that's listed here, you can just copy it all the way over to the
Secret Key Service actually right over to this slash at the end of salt.
If you copy that and then place that into any browser, you can get an automatically generated set of
authentication keys that you can use to sort of re authenticate your website, force anybody that's
logged in to log back out, and that can be a security measure that you can take.
Many hosting companies provide that functionality.
There's even plug ins that you can get that will change that for you, say, every 30 days or every
60 days as an additional security measure.
But if we go back to local now, this is a working website.
So if I click open site, you've seen that this will open the default WordPress installation using the
2022 theme and looks like it's taking a minute to open up.
There it is, and it's just a regular website right here.
And if I go into the admin, I've got the one click admin on.
And so if I click admin now, this is going to open up the WordPress dashboard.
And if I look under appearance themes, you could see that I've got three themes available here.
And so just to compare what's happening here in the dashboard and what's happening on the front end
of the website, we've got the 2020 two theme active.
And then there's also 2020 and 2021.
Now, if you recall, we went and looked at the files before in under WP content under themes could
see that those are the three themes that I have.
And so let's look at what plugins I might have now as a default installation using local.
There's.
Generally, not any plug ins here yet.
And so let's just take a look at what it shows.
No plug ins are currently available now because I'm using local.
I don't necessarily have to be connected to the internet to work with WordPress.
However, to get new plug ins and themes, you know, from the repository, which is online, I would
need to be online.
So my computer is online right now.
And for example, if I wanted to go and get a plug in like there's a standard WordPress plug in called
a kismet that oftentimes when you install WordPress automatically through your host, it will be installed
automatically so it doesn't come with local.
But now that I've installed, I could activate that spam protection plug in and then you can actually
enter an API key and or get a free one.
But now that I've installed that plug in, I could go to plug ins and plug ins, all plug ins, and
that would be in my plug in list.
And we can see that there's a little notification that it wants to activate that.
But you can see that that that kismet plug in is now in my plug ins, all plug ins screen.
And if I go back into the files, if I go back into WP content and look at plug ins, now you can see
that the kismet plug in folder is present there.
Let's try something else.
Let's go to Media Library and check out if there's any images in the media library.
Now, at this point, if I go to the Files folder here under WP content, now that I do have I've gone
to the media library.
All of a sudden I have a folder called uploads.
Now, if I look under uploads 2022 and 02, it's got an empty folder.
Now, by default, WordPress usually creates date related folders for your media library.
Often I like to go ahead and change that setting in my WordPress sites, and so I'll just go quickly
into Settings Media, and I like to uncheck the box that says organize my uploads into month and year
base folders.
I just like to keep all of my media library into one big folder on the server just kind of easier to
find and access different items if you want to.
And so since I've done that and click save changes now, if I go to media, add new, I can go ahead
and find an image and either select it here or use the File Explorer to drag it over.
So let's see if I find I can find some images here.
Let's see.
Where do I have my images?
So if I just go into my file explorer, I've got a folder open where I have some images that I've imported
before for the 2022 theme.
And I can bring some of these images in.
If I just maybe I'll just bring the three featured images over and drop them in to upload them into
the media library.
Now, if I click the library, you could see that I've got those three images could see the URL here
is just now uploads featured image to JPEG, etc..
And now let's go ahead and let's go back and look at the File Explorer, where I can find that again.
So I know I've got it in windows and here I'll go to users good local sites.
Let's find the leverage WP site one.
There we go.
And I could have gone into local and clicked just to get into here, but into WP content and uploads.
Now you can see I've got a few different images, and this illustrates something that WordPress does
in the background related to the theme that it's using.
It brings in not only the original image, which if I roll over and get the data here, it's a 6500
by 900 pixel image and it's 47 kilobytes in size.
But WordPress creates the thumbnails associated with the theme that it's using.
And so in addition to that file, I've got a featured image one that's a 150 by 150, 300 by 169.
There's all these different files that come in that the website can then use.
That's just showing that how the feature, how the file system works in WordPress and showing how it's
connected to that database.
Now, let's take a look at one of the pages that comes in WordPress.
Let's see if we have a sample page here.
Yes, here's a sample page that's published on the web site.
And if we take a look at that sample page, here's some content.
This is an example page.
It's got a title.
It's got some content that's formatted a certain way.
These are blocks, right?
So this page exists.
Let's find out where this content actually exists in the database.
So if I go back into local, this is where I can access the database.
If I click open admin or that will open up another tab inside my browser.
And that's where I can find the database and just browse to find out where this stuff is.
So let's just find in what table the pages, et cetera, are located in all.
This content is in the WordPress database.
So the content is stored in a table called WP Posts, both blog posts and pages are types of posts.
And so let's open WP posts just by clicking that once it's showing me the database structure.
But if I click select data now, it's showing me all the different rows that are within the WP posts
table in this database.
So you can see right here the first one is welcome to WordPress.
This is your first post.
The second one is this as an example page.
Now, if I click Edit, I can see what all is part of this database.
Now these are tags that are part of the blocks system.
This is a paragraph block and this is a quote block.
And so if we go back into the page here, that's the paragraph block.
This right here is a quote block you can see right here.
And so that gives you an idea of how things are stored in the database, as well as in the files and
the way that WordPress works.
Remember, the only file that connects these two things is the WP config file that has the connection
that shows the database name, user and password and where to find that database.
In this example, it's located in a folder on my computer.
It's over here called public, you know, and that's where all the files are now.
If I go into the app folder, here's this sequel.
Here's the SQL file and this is the actual database called local that we're working with here in the
local development environment.
So that gives you an idea of how things work in the background.
Next, we'll get into taking WordPress apart a little bit and fiddling with it to learn more about the
way all this stuff works.