In this lesson, we'll go over the Disney theme options and how did he works within the customizer?
You'll see how I set up a Disney site when I first install it.
As far as the defaults in the settings, by the end of this video, you'll understand how editing a
page within WordPress has some functions, but most of what you do within a DV site is in the visual
builder.
First off, as far as DV overview and options, if we look down here, what will be going over are the
options tabs in that divvy theme options area inside of the sandbox, or if you own TV on your own personal
website and then using the customizer, which we've used in the past when we were looking at the cadence
theme.
The customizer is a place where DV does have some of its settings and then the project's custom post
type, as well as the DV controls within the WP page or post editing screen.
And so the things that we have later that we'll look at down here are the visual builder.
But outside of the visual builder, you can also edit some of the settings within a page screen.
And so if we go back to the Disney theme options that's located on the TV theme options here in the
general settings.
This is where you would set a logo for the default header if you're using the default header and then
whether that navigation bar is fixed or not like it is by default right here.
It's a fixed navigation bar that gets a little bit smaller when you scroll and this is the logo.
That's that area is referring to over there.
And then some of the things that I usually set up as I first set up a TV site.
I'll generally leave Google Fonts, but I'll turn off and cueing the Google Maps script if unless I'm
using a Google embedded map as far as using the Google Maps module in Devi.
Oftentimes, I don't use it.
As we've learned, it's pretty easy just to embed a Google map or use a separate plug in.
And then as we go down here, I'll often just I want you to take note that there's a custom CSS area
that you can use for sitewide CSS if you're going to add something like that.
There's also a back to top button that I'll sometimes enable, because that's pretty convenient as far
as when you're, you know, creating some pages or using a layout that has some links to the page as
you go down a little bit, get down certain, you know, a mount and you could see this little back
to top button appears.
So that's a real convenient user interface and good UX or user experience to use as well.
I usually enable responsive images or leave that enabled as well when you save changes in these divvy
options and also in other places in TV, but especially here, it's also not exactly clear when you
have saved the only little little indicator you get when you click save changes.
Is this little green checkmark right there so you can keep an eye on that?
The performance settings are, you know, enabled by default in Devi, and these are the things that
I was indicating before inside of our outline that we'll talk about later.
But those are all enabled, except for deferring additional third party scripts usually comes up disabled
at first.
This is a place just if you're having any kind of a plug in conflict or something that's happening.
You can use this to troubleshoot how to fix that a little bit.
The navigation as we go across the theme options navigation settings, you know, as far as the navigation
bar, this stuff is talking about the default navigation bar with Vivi, and often I'll use a different
custom made header with a navigation bar that I've created, and the built in navigation system called
appearance menus is something that's different here.
So this is just if you're using the existing pages in the default navigation menu, you can turn off
certain ones you want to and whether you display a home link or not, etc. And then when you're looking
at categories, do you put a category navigation in that default menu or not?
And then general settings, this is an interesting one.
If you are using a default menu and you have a dropdown menu, say, you know, we might have portfolio
pages as a drop down here, you could disable the the top menu.
So when you click it, nothing happens and the only thing is available are the dropdown items.
That's what this setting is for right here under the buildings builder settings.
Basically, unless you're if you're not using the project's custom post type, which is just a different
type of post.
In addition to pages and post, it's over.
Year under Divvy Projects is basically like a page, but has a, you know, a separate section as a
custom post type.
We'll learn about KPIs or custom post types later in the course, but if you're not using them at all,
you can turn off the TV builder for that custom post type.
And then as far as advanced, if there's any issues where you're seeing your changes, don't come up,
say you're on a different host or something like that.
It works as far as the sandbox here.
And if you're using grid pain like I use for hosting again, we'll talk about hosting in a future section
of the course.
But you can turn this off or clear the clear the cache of the access if you need to.
If your changes aren't being saved, and then I'll generally turn off the product, or which basically
is kind of pop ups that have links to show you around TV when you're first starting out and these two.
You can also leave disabled and then so layout some of these things.
I don't really change unless I'm, you know, changing things in the future as I set up blog posts or
things like that.
So when you're having a blog post be displayed using the post module in Devi, you can choose whether
to display, you know, the author or the date, the categories or the comments.
You can click it to grey it out or click it to bring it back again.
And then whether you show comments on posts and whether you place a thumbnail image on the posts by
default or not.
And then the single page layout, not the posts under a blog section, but as far as pages, whether
you place those thumbnails that are, you know, coming from the featured image of the post or not,
and whether you show comments on the pages or not.
And then general settings again, you know, the post info, that metadata, whether you show those
things and showing the thumb thumbnails for different dynamically generated images from index pages
like, say, the home page shows your blog posts whether you want to show that featured image or not.
As far as ads, I don't really use, you know, Google ads or AdSense ads, but this is a place where
you can control some of the things for that.
SEO is a is a good place.
This has a lot of the features that an SEO plugin like Yost SEO, which I recommend built right into
Devi.
And so there already is, you know, a custom and a title method for displaying, say, up here in the
tab.
You know, for example, this is the page title and then this is the site title after a vertical line.
And so that's where down here, if custom titles are disabled like they are right now, then what is
my, you know, what do I have here?
You have the name of the page and then the description or whatever it is so you can control that here.
Integrations are, if you want to put, say, a Google Analytics code in the header section of every
page of the website, you can enable these code sections for putting different things in sitewide that
can help you for things like Google AdSense or for doing some marketing tracking, like using a Facebook
Pixel and things like that updates.
You just leave this as it is if you're in the sandbox, but if you're using your own device version
that you've purchased on your own site, you could go in to the Devi website area and you know, in
your account area, username and API key, you can set individual API keys for your sites and different
client sites so that they can be turned on and off at will, and that enables devices to be updated
from WordPress easily.
It also enables the pre-designed layout packs to be imported, and so that's a good tour of the theme
options.
Just a couple of more things, you know, using the customizer, the projects, I showed you a little
bit what that is.
It's just another type of page, and it's organized in a separate place so that you can use it for things
like maybe its services, that a business has different types of services or projects.
If it's, say, a web design company and you want to show a project on each of those types of pages
and keep it separate from the pages of the website that are just like about or the contact page and
things like that.
But let's quickly look at the customizer and and the editing screen of a page inside of Devi.
And so if I'm here, you know, I'm here in my in my Devi website, if I open appearance, customize.
Now here is where with the default header, if I am not using the the theme builder and.
Building a customized header for using, you know, using divvy modules, then this header is controlled
here in the customizer.
So you get just like in when we were using cadence, you get a representation of the website here inside
the customizer window.
And then there's things like general settings, you know, the typography, what are the what's the
default theme font, etc. You can set that you can set the, you know, a link color wide.
I'll often do that here.
This is the default blue, but if you want it to select a color, you know, you could say, Well,
I want the link color to be, you know, red or something different like that.
And you can set whatever color you like there and then you'd hit publish, of course.
So, you know, the layout settings.
This is a forward player, or you could have a boxed layout that would have kind of a border.
And then all the content within the site is not as common these days, and you can control the website
content with the accent color.
If I want to just change that into red to kind of go and set off against this yellow.
That's something that you might change and we're just exploring, you know, the background color.
This site with this design has a white background color on all the different sections.
But if you wanted to put a background color or a background image site wide, that's something that
you could do might just change that into this white.
Not going to change anything, really.
Using this imported layout site identity is a WordPress standard, and so that's the title and the tagline,
but also the site icon.
This is where you would have.
Instead of this WordPress W in blue, you could put a 512 by 512 pixel icon in here that matches the
brand.
And I always do that for clients with either a version of their logo or something that symbolizes their
business there.
And so again, under the customize are other things that are kind of standard WordPress things like
menus.
But there's also this header and navigation.
And so when we look at look at customizing this navigation, when we look at customizing this a little
bit further, we'll look at the primary menu bar here and the fixed navigation settings as far as when
you scroll.
How tall do we want this?
So that's 40.
But if I want to make this say even a little bit smaller, 35 pixels, you saw it get smaller there
and that's called the primary menu when you're scrolled all the way up and the fixed menu height is
right there.
So that's a change that I could make right there.
They're the secondary menu is one that would be like above this menu right here, and you can control
the background color, the dropdown for dropdown menu items here, matching the website design that
you're working with their header elements.
This has the search icon over here, you can see.
So you could take that search icon out, or you could place other things, social icons over there.
That was interesting.
That brought in social icons at the top of my hamburger menu there.
And then you could put a phone number or an email up in the header if you wanted to there.
Not something I use very much that her format is, by default, this kind of left and right, but you
could have a centered one with the logo in between all the menu items or the centered with the logo
at the top.
Like that?
And just these are kind of the original divvy header formats, and I'm going to get out, you know,
I'm going to go back to the default format.
There are also there's a slide in that's what we were looking at before, where there's a hamburger
menu and a slide in.
And I can't use that with the bright red color.
But and then the a full screen menu would be something like this that would kind of be an overlay instead
of clickable buttons up at the top.
And so generally, I'll use again.
Like I said, I'll get rid of this default header and go ahead and build a header using the theme builder
and then you can control it and put different headers for different types of pages or even specific
pages, or even remove the header altogether, something that we've done a little bit in some of the
other themes, but Devi makes it easy.
So again, a bunch of the other things in here that the bottom bar is something that a lot of people
will want to edit where it says, you know, designed by elegant themes and powered by WordPress and
then these social icons.
That bottom bar is customisable down here, you could just disable the footer credits over here or put
your own.
Oftentimes, I'll just be building again a site wide global footer in a different place called the theme
builder.
And so that's what that is right here.
Footer elements and footer menus.
The layout of the footer.
And then you can use widgets, which is kind of an older, traditional style of building a footer areas
inside of WordPress using widgets.
But we'll be using a more modernized way of doing it using the theme builder.
There's a few more things the home page settings.
Of course, that's whether you're showing a static page or your latest post on the home page again available
under appearance or excuse me, under Settings General in WordPress, anyway.
And so that's an overview of the customizer.
Finally, let's quickly look at the Pages all pages section and look at one of the pages.
Let's just maybe take a look at this landing page that we have that's built with the DV builder.
And when we're in here, you could take a look at landing.
Here, it shows you with those little indicators, whether this is built with the Block editor or the
default editor or built with TV.
But it tells you right here in the content editing area that this layout is built with Divij.
And this is important if you're working with clients that open up the website to edit.
There's, you know, if one of the things that it's important to know is that if this is built with
the DV builder like it is and you click Return to Default Editor, this is actually going to erase all
the content.
That's a part of this page right here.
Now there are ways with revisions and with the editing history feature inside of Devi that you'll be
able to bring the old layout back if this accidentally happens.
But it's important to know that you don't want to return to the default editor unless you really are
aware that you're going to be throwing out the current layout.
But there are some things you might use this traditional WordPress editing page for one of which is
the title.
You could use it for the page title.
And also you can change that when you're using the visual builder using Devi as well.
But if you look on the right hand side here, this block editing settings area, you might use that
you can use the default template or there is a blank page template that you can use for landing pages.
If you want an easy way to remove the header and the footer, but still use a divvy layout, that's
if you're using the original traditional header and footer system.
Later, we'll be using the theme builder in DV.
And so this makes the template area here kind of irrelevant, but the permalink is where you would change
what the URL is for the page.
And that's something that you might want to be aware of.
And lastly, I'll just show you when you do, click edit with the DV builder or you're up here in a
page and you enable the visual builder, it puts a layer and editing layer on top, and this is something
that we'll talk about in detail in the next section.
You'll see what it does.
It actually loads the page the way it looks on the front end, and it puts an editing layer on top where
when you roll your mouse over things, you can see some of these, you know, the blue line here and
the little control bar for a section.
And these are the rows.
And then each of the design elements or sections where there's content are called modules in DV.