In this lesson, we'll export the database manually and import it into a new WordPress site using the
database manager.
You'll learn how to perform a manual site migration from any host to another using only the database
export file and the WP content folder from the existing site.
You also see how it's necessary to modify the URLs in the database after a migration to make the site
work at the new address.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how migrations work in the background and be able to do
it yourself manually.
So I'm still going to take a site from local and migrated into another environment, still on local,
on my computer.
But let's add one level of complexity here.
Instead of just doing the automatic, you know, export import from local to local.
Let's act like this could be a different place.
Doesn't even have to be local.
What we're going to do is a manual site migration from one environment into an existing site that is
happens to be in the same environment.
And so we're going to import this Kadence site and migrate the cadence site that you saw before.
And let's look at it again.
It's just the real estate starter template using the cadence, theme and cadence plug ins.
And I also have a site created in local.
That's just a, you know, I just called it migration site original.
It's just a sample site.
That is a default site using the 2022 theme.
All I did was in local.
I created a site in local using the plus button here, called it migration site original and know,
gave it a name and my login credentials, and I clicked open site here and this is what I've got.
It's just a regular WordPress website and it's basically empty, except for the default.
You know, the default sample page.
It's got a default blog post and it has, you know, a user account.
And that's basically it.
It doesn't have any plug ins.
It just has a few default themes.
So it doesn't have cadence in it or anything like that.
It's just an empty WordPress site.
And so let's do a manual migration to illustrate what it takes to take and you know, the bare minimum
that you need from the original site and bring it into a new site.
And in that way, manually migrate the site to a different environment.
And so this will work in any environment, whether you're using local on your computer or whether you're
migrating from a live host over to another live host or from local to a live host.
Basically, you just need to access the files for the original website.
And so if I look at cadence, you know, the one thing I did was I went like this.
I right clicked and exported a file that contained the whole site, including the database, right?
Well, I can also just go and find that in local if I wanted to.
But let's go to this folder where I saved that zip file and then I unzipped it.
You know that that contained, like I said in the last lesson it contained under app and public, the
WP content folder, which is the minimum that you need for migrating a WordPress website because all
the rest, the other two folders and all the files are really going to be unchanged from one WordPress
site to another.
And so you just need to get the WP content folder and you need to get the Dot SQL file, the local SQL
in this case.
And so if we, you know, like I said, I could find that in my desktop slash cadence folder, another
way to export a copy of the database in a single file format is to navigate using the database navigator.
Now I've just created a new site called 20 22, just a default installation using local.
And when I set that up, let's look at my file explorer under my local sites.
If we look under 20 22 under the app, the Dot is the sequel folders not there right now.
All that we have is the WordPress files and we don't have the SQL folder.
And so I just want to show you a different way that you can get a sequel file of the whole database,
no matter what kind of database manager you're using.
This could be from a live host or from a different local development environment like my AMP or desktop
server or something like that.
You can get these from exporting the database through the database manager.
And so in local, we are using the database manager called admin.
So I'll go to twenty twenty two here and with the site turned on if I click open admin or.
Now that opens this database manager and I can check that it's local, say twenty two and now if I just
go over here and click the export button.
What that does in my browser is it brings up an export function and you just leave the default settings,
I want the format to be Eskil and just leave these all the tables selected and click export.
And what that does is it opens up the actual SQL file in my browser.
It is a called a dump of the database, the database dump.
And so since I have this in my browser, this isn't resulting in a file, a SQL file.
And so to create that file, you can use your code editor or your text editor.
And so what I'll do is just click anywhere here and click Control A to select all and then control C
to copy.
And now I've copied all the text and code for the school file.
Now, if I open a code editor like Adam, I have another one that I export it open right here, but
I can just file new file, open a new file and I can just control V and paste that entire file into
the code editor.
So this is a dot SQL file, and it's untitled yet.
But if I just click File Save as let's go down here and click Save as and then I can navigate to desktop,
let's just create a new folder called Twenty Twenty Two.
Into there and now I need to name it, and when we name the file, we need to name it with a ce que
l'extension.
And so I'll just say 20 to 20 to Dot s QOL.
And when I save that now, that saved as a dot school file and you could see the context syntax coloration
change within my code editor here, signifying that it knows this is a school file and it knows what
kind of code each one of these lines and different things are.
And so if we look in the in my browser now, not in not in the local sites folder, but where I saved
it in desktop and 2022, you can see that there's my folder.
It's a school dot school and it has a different icon here.
So I can use that along with the WP content folder to import this site as a complete site into any hosting
area or local development environment that I need.
Let's go ahead and look in another window in the File Explorer.
And you can do this on your Mac with the Finder just open to windows.
And now I'm going to go over here and find the files that are associated with the other website with
this one, the migration site original.
And so let's see.
Let's go over here.
And so I'm just going to this will be done in a live environment by doing either using a file manager
to move the files and then import the database.
Or you can use an FTP program like we learned in the last section in order to move the files.
And then again, import the database file into the existing database.
And we'll do that in a live environment here in a minute.
But let's just do it locally for now.
So I'm looking at moving the files and the database from this cadence over into the other side, and
so the other side is still in local sites.
So I'll go here in my computer to local sites and I'm looking for migration.
I look for migration site original.
This is a working site and under app and public, I can see that I have the set of files under public
and the WP content folder is right there.
So I'm just going to go ahead and click that once and hit Delete.
I'm just going to delete the whole WP content folder out of this migration site.
Original, and I'm going to go back to the Cadence app under public and WP content here at Kadence.
I'm just going to move it over and hold control and copy it into that folder.
And so that is basically replacing the WP content folder on the, you know, WordPress site.
That's just a default site with the WP content folder that came from the cadence site.
And so that's one part of two.
Now I need to bring the Dot SQL file into the site over here in some way, and the way we need to do
that is through a database manager in this case.
So go back to local and what I'd like to do is just on this card and say I'm going to go ahead and stop
the site from running on the server because what I want is to make sure when I go to the migration site,
original and the database, I want to open admin or in my browser, and that will make sure that I'm
browsing to this migration site.
Original If multiple sites are open and you're navigating to the database tab in each one, when they're
when they're running, the browser can confuse those two and that can happen.
And so it's a good idea to turn off the original site once you've exported the database and turn on
the news site and navigate to the database tab and open admin here and do it in that way while at one
site is running that way.
When you're in here and looking at the database, you can look here and see that the local site is migration
site original.
And that's the one that I want.
And so what I'm going to do is similar to when we were installing WordPress manually.
I'm going to go ahead and select all the tables, and I want to just drop those tables.
I want to just erase all the tables of the database and bring in a whole new dot SQL file with all new
tables.
But instead of having WordPress create them like we were installing a fresh site before, I want to
import a SQL file and so I can click choose files I can choose in the folder that was exported under
app and sequel.
That was where I exported an unzipped that zip file.
I can click local and hit open and then click Execute.
And what that's going to do is bring in and import those that database.
923 queries executed.
OK, it says.
And so I can click the name of the database, I can click local.
And now it's showing me the tables are in here.
And finally, because this is at a new domain name, a new URL lets you go into WP options in the database
here and click Select Data, and we want to change this to the new You URLs site instead of the old
one, the one that's for migration site original.
And so I'll just go back to where I have it open in the browser.
Click that to highlight it and click Control.
See to copy.
And in here you can click Edit.
And under WP options, you want to replace the URLs with the New York URL to do a manual migration.
And so this will be the final step under site URL and home rows in the WP options table.
I've selected and saved those.
So now let's see what happens when we go back to the URL of the original site and refresh, or I'll
just press enter.
Let's see what the site looks like now.
As it opens, hey, look at that.
It's brought in a version of the site now.
There is something wrong with this.
You probably notice there's a few images missing from this homepage and so we can figure out what's
going on with those.
There's some images that are working.
And I think I know the reason for that because we need to do one more step.
As you saw some of these, the URLs for the site URL and the home we're already, you know, we migrated
the database in and it was an exact copy of the database from this Kadence site, right?
And so some of the URLs, particularly for these images, they might be saved in the database as the
other URL.
And I'm sure that's what's going on here.
And so one thing we can do is just let's go into local and we'll go to the migration site original and
click admin to go to the WordPress dashboard.
And here in local, you know, you could use the one click admin selection right here.
But one thing to note when you migrate a web site and bring the database over and just copy the database
over and imported into a new database, then the user credentials are stored in that database.
And so the user credentials are going to be the same credentials from the original site, not the credentials
from the new site that you had just created as an empty site.
And that's one thing to note.
So I would use the credentials from the original site and that should log me in.
Great.
OK, so one thing I'd like to do is just show you as we finished this manual migration, an easy plug
into use in order to take care of this problem that you might have with a manual migration, which is
to go through the entire database, changing the old URL to the new URL.
The migrated URL is the wrong one.
And so there's a great plugin called Better Search Replace.
By delicious brains should come up if you search for better search or better search replace.
And it's this one right at the top, yet the better search for a place plug in works really well, so
I'll just click install now and then.
When that finishes installing, I can click activate and this is a great plug in.
I'll show you as we finish this lesson, how to use it, and then we'll complete this manual migration.
And so let's go in here under tools better search replace.
And what we're doing is we're searching for the original URL.
So I just control C to copy that, and I'll put it here is included in the FTP, and then I want to
replace it with the new URL.
And what this will do is it'll go through the entire database and it'll look for this old one and it'll
replace it with the new one and we can run it as a dry run to start with.
One thing to remember is you have to select the tables you want to use.
So what I usually do is select the first one, scroll to the very bottom and hold down shift and select
the last so that I've selected all the tables.
And then first, always run as a dry run to see what's going to happen.
So it goes and looks at the entire database, and it will show you the progress as it goes.
Here's my result 12 tables, 36 were found that need to be updated.
Now, zero changes were made because I had the dry run checkbox checked.
But now that I'm like, OK, thirty six cells, one of those was probably this background image right
here and other images around the site.
So now I'll just leave it the same and uncheck the dry run and run the search and replace.
Now it's showing me what it's doing there.
It says 36 updates.
Let's see what happens if I refresh the page on the home page.
Is the are the images working again?
Yes.
All right, so now I think this is a final working migration all the way across the entire web site.
And so that's a manual migration.
And let me just reiterate.
You don't have to do that just between local installations.
You could bring a live WordPress website from one host over to a different host, which is something
I've used often in my business.
You could develop a site locally and then use this technique to migrate the site to a live host when
you're ready to take the site live.
There are a lot of different uses for migrations.
Manual migrations are a good way to learn how everything works in the background.
But next, we'll get into some easier ways to do migrations using plug ins.