In this lesson, we'll explore a few different email hosting providers and the cost levels of each from
free to several levels of cost.
You'll learn why I shared hosting that includes hosted email is not the best practice and how to host
email.
Even when you're using a shared website hosted by the end of this video, you'll understand why and
when it's appropriate to provide email hosting for addresses at a custom domain name not only to look
professional, but to take advantage of better deliverability and plenty of email storage.
Send and receive email is one to one email that requires a sender and a receiver, and the receiving
email address needs to have hosting.
And so you might think of sending receive email as traditionally a free service, and it is with companies
that provide email like Gmail, for example, from Google.
Now, if you look at Google Workspace here that I'm showing on my screen, you could see that Gmail
is also a possible paid service for your email at custom domains, so it could be, you know, your
name at your company, dot com, whatever the domain name is.
And in order to provide hosted email at a custom domain that is a paid service and it's worth getting
in order to host email at a business's domain, you can imagine it's much more professional to send
and receive email at a custom domain name like your name at business named outcome vs. business name
at gmail.com.
Now, just using your personal Gmail or a business name at gmail.com email address is something that's
done a lot.
It's just more professional to have email addresses at your custom domain name, and so we'll talk about
set ups with your WordPress website and how it set up different levels of expense and different levels
of service.
As far as send and receive email now, you know the first and free way of having business email would
be to create an email address like your business name at gmail.com.
As I said, not as professional, and there are better ways to do it now.
Gmail does provide a custom hosted service, which at this time is $6 a month per email address.
It does come with a good amount of storage, 30 gigabytes of storage, a lot of other good benefits
that it provides.
It's basically robust business email as well as other services like scheduling, calendaring, online
meetings and those types of things.
I prefer to set up all of my clients custom domain names with email addresses at Rackspace because it's
just as robust as service and it's about half the cost.
It's 299 U.S. dollars per email address per month, and that's 25 gigabytes of email storage and as
well as both professional managed IP addresses.
And we'll talk about IP addresses and website systems.
As regards your website in this video, as we talk about different setups for WordPress, for send and
receive email now, the way that I work it in my business is I include business emails, oftentimes
with my website care and hosting plans, which start at $100 a month anyway.
So another $3 a month for each email address for that business is something that I usually just roll
in as an expense of mine included in the hosting.
And you can do that, however you like Gmail, like I said, $6 a month per email address, and there
are three ways to go about doing this.
The two, there's actually three different levels of free email hosting.
One of them isn't really hosting, but it's a way to forward emails automatically to someone's personal
email address.
But the first one I'll talk about is with a shared website hosting account.
Now I do use site ground and I have in the past.
I recommend site ground for shared hosting, and here's an example of a domain name that I manage.
That includes in my in my hosting program with second email addresses and email hosting.
And there's there's kind of one issue that I'll go over with you as we talk about the different levels
of email hosting that this creates.
And as I look under this email, excuse me, this website hosting account that includes email addresses,
you can add as many email addresses as you like.
As you can see here, I've got two email addresses and you can see that there's a quota level and a
current usage level here in these graphs as psych ground.
And so they come with 250 megabytes as storage level.
By default, and then you can see that I've upped this one to four gigabytes of storage because this
user has over two gigabytes already stored after just a couple of years in business.
And so you could see where twenty five gigs or 30 gigs is a good place to be as far as hosting email
in the long term.
For somebody that uses emails and doesn't have a system that automatically deletes them if they want
to save emails on the server and be able to refer back to them and archive those for a long period of
time.
A large number of gigabytes for email storage is wise.
Now the one problem here is that if this green bar goes up and exceeds the allocated amount that affects
the website resources that are available for even just loading the website itself.
And I've had this happen to me where a client's website went down in a shared website account, and
the reason was that their email went above quota.
And so that caused the website to go down.
And so you do have to manage and watch out for your resource usage if you're using just an inexpensive
shared host and including the email.
One benefit is that it's easy to set up, and email addresses that are included with shared web hosting
accounts are just easy.
It's easy to set up and easy to manage.
It's just you have to keep your eye on it.
Another way to go that is truly hosted email that has a free level is a company called Zoho.
Zoho does offer paid email hosting, but they also provide a free email hosted solution that has a couple
of limitations.
And if you look there, they're 50 gigabytes per user.
Plan at $4 is a great price and is professionally hosted and managed IP address separate from the website,
which is a best practice.
But if you go down here, you can see that they do have a forever free plan where the users get five
gigabytes each and there's an attachment limit.
And this is the big difference here.
Web access and free mobile apps that they provide in order to check and send and receive email.
And so where most people like to use either, you know, Microsoft Outlook or Mozilla Thunderbird or
Mac mail on on the Apple Mac computers, those are called email clients, their email programs that
are installed on your computer that check your email through one of two systems pop three email or IMAP,
which can synchronize through many devices.
That's to say that they limit that access.
You can't do IMAP or pop three email when you're using the free plan with Zoho.
So I've stopped using Zoho for free email hosting for that exact reason.
I like to provide a professional service for my clients and host all my emails at a service like Rackspace.
So Rackspace provides, as I said, to ninety nine a month for twenty five gigabytes and managed professional
IP addresses.
Gmail does provide the same thing for 30 gigabytes.
You get it for $6 a month.
Again, you're separating the IP address for email, sending and receiving from the website.
So no matter what happens with email sending and receiving here, it never affects the website.
And so finally, I just want to introduce a newer service where if you're using Cloudflare for your
DNS, we've discussed this as far as website hosting and the website hosting section.
Go back and review that if you like, but this is under beta.
It's just starting with Cloudflare, so you can't find much information if you're not already a Cloudflare
customer.
But if you are and I use the free Cloudflare service, you can set up email routing, which enables
you to do out or, excuse me, incoming only incoming only email addresses at your professional website
address.
And what it does is it just automatically forwards that email to any address that you already own,
like a Gmail address in this example, or even anyone's personal email address at Yahoo or Hotmail or
anything like that.
If that is a very simple and free solution that is incoming only.
And so if you have a client that just wants to email, manage their email in their own email box for
their business of the same as they always have for personal emails, you can set up email routing,
and so it's either referred to as an email alias or email forwarding, and you can set up the professional
looking business address.
And have that just automatically forward to a personal address or a free Gmail address for the client?
And so let's just take a look at the different setups for send and receive email as we go through on
the notepad here.
If we look at this first simple example, this is just a simple example of professional, professionally
hosted email at a custom domain name.
And so the custom domain name example dot com I'll use here.
This would be the same example as the site ground shared hosting example.
So if you have the domain registered at the website host again, not something I recommend.
But if you're just starting out, it's an easy way to go.
And sometimes your client may already have a domain name registered with their host if they started
it out themselves and they just went for an inexpensive host and built that system themselves.
And so this is a simple example.
I'll go over some pros and cons for each of these examples for setups for send and receive email.
The pros here are that the DNS records and the name servers for the domain name are already set and
email is included in the hosting expense, and so there's no extra expense.
The cons, however, are that you're locked into that host with the domain attached to it.
It's a little more complicated to transfer ownership of a domain, especially when you're trying to
migrate a website away from that domain, that hosting provider.
And so the email is also hosted at the same server as the website.
And that's the problem I alluded to before with the shared hosting that includes email.
If the email excuse exceeds its allocation, then you risk having the website going down because the
email inbox is full, and so you might be forced to increase the email allocation as you go.
And that might give you a hint that you need to think about migrating email away to a dedicated email
hosting provider like Gmail or Google Workspace or Rackspace, or something like that.
And so the next set up I'll talk about is similar.
You could set this set up on a shared host.
But then you have your domain registered with an accredited registrar like Cloudflare or GoDaddy or
Namecheap, a company that registers domain names for you.
And in that way, you use name servers to point the DNS records.
You know, you point the records to the website and then the email with Amex Records goes to the email
hosting again a little bit better.
The pros It's easy to migrate websites and email together to different hosts, and it's an easy setup.
The cons The email again, is hosted with the website.
So again, if the email exceeds its allocation, then the website can go down, which is a big con.
But using the name servers, it places all the DNS record management with the website host.
So again, that means that it's easy to set up.
You don't really have to fool with the DNS records like a records and Emacs records.
It really just gets automatically pointed and routed because your shared host is taking care of that
for you.
So here's an even better type of setup.
A better setup would be you have your domain registered with an accredited registrar like Cloudflare
or Namecheap or something like that, but you point DNS records to a DNS provider like Cloudflare.
And so that means that you have to just make sure that you have the records for the website.
Traffic pointed to the website and you have the Amex Records or Mail Exchange.
Your records pointed to the email provider and that email provider is now separate from the website
host.
And so with these two not being connected, that means that you can grow email boxes as far as you like
and keep expanding without affecting the the website at all and resource usage at the website host.
So in this case, you'd be using a provider like Google Workspace or Rackspace in order to provide email
hosting, and then the website is separate.
And so there's a lot of pros here that you've separated the resource usage between website and email.
And secondly, you're using a different IP address for email reputation.
And I alluded to this a second ago.
If this mail is using a managed IP address, then those companies like Google Workspace or Rackspace,
they're actually managing the reputation of the IP address and sending email through that IP address
instead of using the same IP address that your web site.
Is using and especially with a shared host host, if you're using shared hosting, it's possible because
those are either free or cheap services that some people might take advantage of that and set up spam
and spam sending systems.
So at times, those IP addresses get blacklisted or get compromised and so email can be slow, it can
go down.
The only con there is, it takes a little bit more setup, so it takes just a little bit of setting
up, but it's not hard to do and the best.
This is the best type of service where you're using Cloudflare or another DNS service, and I talked
about that a little bit a little bit up here, really.
Up here I was talking about using the DNS at the actual website host.
And when we separate out the DNS or domain name service, like with a company called Cloudflare, we're
not only enabling the domain name to point the mix records to a different email host like this, but
we're also enabling a content delivery network so that images and other media can load fast from different
places around the world.
There is $d or distributed attacks, protection for for malware and hacking attempts in those things.
There's a firewall that prevents your website from excessive resource usage from, you know, DDoS attacks
or, you know, login attempts by bots and things like that.
And there's a very, very fast time to first byte for that domain name.
Now, that doesn't really have to do with email.
Those are all side benefits of using a dedicated DNS service, and the Cloudflare service is free,
but in enables you then to manage your DNS records so that you can point a records to the website and
then mix records to a service like Rackspace.