In this lesson, we'll check out the sample site that the designers of the 2022 theme set up as an example,
and we'll start preparing to recreate it in the sandbox or in your own WordPress site if you're working
that way.
You'll make sure you have the images you need in the media library and explore the sample site to see
what it is will be creating by the end of this video.
You'll have everything you need to begin customizing your site with the 2022 theme.
Let's go.
Now, if you opened up this 20 22 themed site within your sandbox here, then you'll you'll your dashboard
will look like this and you'll notice that you probably have some images already populated within your
media library.
But if not, and if you're working on your own server and your own hosting account, you may have an
empty media library here.
And I've provided you in the course with a link to some media files that you can get, which are prepared
from the pre-designed site here.
And so what I'm going to just show you is I'll just take in my File Explorer or the Finder on a Mac.
I'm going to select these seven images and just upload them into the media library here so that I have
something to work with to build out the different pages and posts of the website that we're building
right here.
But first, let's just take a look at this theme and where we're going to find the demo site that shows
a built out version of the 2022 theme.
And so if I go to WordPress dot org, I've got it open in another tab right here.
I'm going to click themes and then if I just start typing 20, you could see that the 2022 theme is
here.
You may be aware that all the default themes that come with WordPress start with the word Twenty-Something.
So twenty twenty twenty twenty one and here's twenty twenty two.
And so if you just click more info, you'll open a page that describes what this theme is all about.
You can download it if you're using a local development environment or if you're using your own host.
Now, of course, you can install a theme in your own WordPress website, as you probably know by going
to appearance themes and then clicking Add New.
Now in the sandbox, I am curating the themes that we're using inside the sandbox, so there's no add
new button, but this is where you would be able to add any theme that's in the WordPress theme repository
over here.
And so you don't have to open up WordPress.org and go ahead and download the theme unless you need to
do that.
For some reason in your local development environment or you want to take the theme and save it to your
computer, if you really want to look at the code and customize it and check it out.
Now over here at GitHub dot com slash WordPress slash 2022, if you just go to GitHub HOCAM, you can
also use the search function to find the 2022 repository.
It's been archived by the owner, but here's where you can find the original code and repository where
they were working on updating this before it was uploaded and accepted into the WordPress theme repository.
These are the contributors and volunteers that created this 20 22 theme during Stad, and it's been
released in WordPress 5.9 and so down in the messages here in the Read Me file in GitHub, where they
house the code, it's a code repository.
It says that this theme has been merged into the word press corps, and so it's no longer maintained
on GitHub.
And so the reason I went here, though, is so that I could come down here and find the demo site while
they were building this site.
They created a demo and they said after the theme Stable, There will be switched to automatic updates,
which is which is where it is now.
But there is a demo located at this address right here, so I clicked and clicked open link in the new
tab and you can do the same thing.
Or you could just navigate to twenty twenty two dot WordPress Dot Net, where it will show you a built
out version of a simple website for a company that has an event page and a film page, as well as an
about page and a series of blog posts.
And so let's just take a look at this theme here and see how it's different from the original twenty
twenty two that was default out of the box and how it comes in a fresh WordPress installation.
And so if you look at the fresh WordPress installation, it's got the name of the site and there's a
menu across the top and this is the header image.
It comes with by default.
And so if I go over to the sample, the demo site could see that there's a logo here now and like a
like a little pair of binoculars, and it's clickable to the homepage as well as a clickable site title.
And then there's also a series of navigation menu items that go to different pages on the site.
And so that's the only difference there.
And you can see if I go back to oops back to say no, there's really not any content as far as imagery
in this Hello World blog post, but you could see that as I scroll down here, there's a series of blog
posts with a featured image, and the featured image is also clickable to the blog post, as well as
a date and some some of the content of that blog post.
And then here's a second blog post going backwards in time and then a third blog post and then we go
down to the footer, which definitely looks exactly the same.
Of course, the name of this site is different than mine over here.
Oops.
That's as Greg Davis two, is the footer on my site, and it will be whatever you called it, in the
sandbox or on your own personal site there.
And so the homepage has three blog posts.
The biggest difference being that there's a featured image within each of those blog posts.
So we'll have to create some new blog posts and add those images.
And as you remember, back here in the dashboard, we have those images here in the media library.
And so here's this image you could see the size of the image, how big the file is and the URL of the
image right there.
One of the easy things you can do within the media library is you can open up a model window here.
You can scroll through to each of the different media library.
Items in your library can also copy the URL to the clipboard, open a new tab and just quickly paste
it to just get a version of that image.
And that could be a way.
If you want to save the image from one website and use it on another, you could right click it, say
save image as or something like that.
In any case, back here, I'll just close the media library model and let's go back and continue to
compare these.
So there's a home button and that, of course, goes to the same place as these two items.
And let's look at the about page.
Now the about page here has a larger black background with a really large, nice looking heading and
a big image on top of that black background.
And then it goes to the white content area.
And this content area is a section which shows the latest blog posts in a grid format.
And there's a view all button here, which if you look at down at the bottom left here in Chrome, you
can see what you are.
You'll be going to this view all link in the demo doesn't go anywhere because it's got just a hash symbol
right after the the URL.
So if you click that, it basically just goes to the top of the page, same page.
And so this is labeled latest posts, and each of these featured images you can recognize as the same
images that were on the homepage, and they're clickable again to the blog post.
This time, however, they're cropped into a square instead of being that rectangular image.
And of course, the title is clickable.
There's that same excerpt of content and the date.
And then here's another section that says, Watch birds are your inbox.
Join our mailing list.
And here where the line is, you would put an interactive contact form or an opt in form to opt in to
your email list.
And then there's the footer that appears the same on every page again.
So let's just take a look at the next page.
This one says event.
And so here's kind of the a page that might be created for an event.
This is a purposeful page.
Here's a section that has a heading or a title, and it has a vertical large image right here not clickable
to anything.
And then over on the right, there's an icon or an image right here.
Then some different typography, you know, some you know, some italics and then a date and location
and then an address and a name of a place right here.
And then as we go down, you know, it's basically one big section about this event.
And then the last one will take a look at is film.
This one has a different color background on the entire page, doesn't it?
And you can see there's some differences here on this particular page.
There is no header or there's no header at the top, so the menu is missing the links to the the homepage
and the site icon or logo and the name of the site are missing at the top.
This is something that you might use for a landing page or or a page where you bring the person to to
a certain page of the website that represents one thing you want them to do like a call to action and
so you don't want it to click away from.
The page, so you eliminate the navigation and you just have whatever you need on this page, and this
page is also set apart with a different background color.
And so again, a nice heading and then a second heading smaller, maybe an inch to three or four and
something there and a button an interactive button that has a nice rollover effect.
And of course, a nice image that seems to come off the edge of the page, and it shows the background
color through that image.
Down here, there's a different section on the same background color that has kind of a grid layout
with some columns, you know, a narrower column on the left of video on the right side.
And then as we go to the bottom, there's a footer, and now the footer does contain the same navigation
links.
And over here, the you know, the recognition or the signature down here in the footer doesn't have
the link able WordPress word as well as it's not in white anymore, it's in different background color.
And so you can see those are the differences.
Let's see if I go back to home.
That takes us back to the home page.
And so how are we going to make this look like that?
You can imagine what we'll have to do, but your challenge now will be to open up your own site and
begin playing around with it.
Now you might.
As we go forward here, we're going to be learning how to use the different blocks, how to create posts
and use featured images, and how to edit the templates with the site editor so that we can have different
pages like the film page that doesn't have the header and a different background, etc. And so let's
get into that next.