WordPress is a free, open source software tool that allows websites to be created and managed with
a variety of designs and functionality.
Well, it started out as a blogging tool.
It's now known as a full fledged CMS or a content management system, and powers more than 40 percent
of websites on the entire internet, according to W3 Tech's WordPress powers.
Forty three percent of all the websites on the internet, including those without a content management
system or with a custom coded CMS, the core software is free and open source built and maintained by
volunteers, and that means anyone can use or change it in any way for personal or commercial projects
for no charge.
And for that reason, there's been many, many extra tools developed in and around the WordPress software
ecosystem for both free and paid usage.
WordPress, the open source software otherwise known as self-hosted WordPress, is found and documented
at WordPress.org, and that's the software we're using in this course.
There's a commercial version of WordPress available in a curated environment at WordPress.com, but
in this course we're only learning about self-hosted WordPress from WordPress.org.
The WordPress.com version has its uses and limitations and is different from the open source version.
So if you've found yourself using that environment change over to the open source version that we use
in the course, I'll show you how to install and use WordPress in later sections.
We have a free 60 day trial from flywheel hosting available for you to build your own practice site,
and there's also two sandbox environments I make available for students that I'll tell you about in
a little bit.
In any case, WordPress Dawg is where you can download the WordPress open source software, and it's
also where all the developer documentation is available.