In this lesson, we'll talk about the other benefits of using a third party DNS provider like Cloudflare.
You'll learn how I point domains from a different domain registrar to Cloudflare using name servers
and then continue the setup to a complete website at a new domain connected with grid pain hosting.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how to connect Cloudflare to domains that you may already
own or that clients have registered elsewhere.
Let's look at how DNS systems and DNS records work to point traffic through a domain name to different
places on the internet, depending on what you're trying to do.
And I'll show you how this works with a website address that I'm not currently using and how I could
set it up if I don't have it registered as a domain at Cloudflare.
But I want to run my traffic through Cloudflare for the DNS.
And so this is just a little screen that shows you kind of what DNS is.
And basically, it's a way to point traffic.
Like I mentioned from one domain name through two different places a records point to an IP address
and sea name records point to a domain name.
And so that is convenient for pointing subdomains correctly, like something like staging dot domain,
Gqom or something like that.
And then there's something called text records, text records.
Those often are used to verify a domain with a service like if you're using an outgoing email service
like Amazon, a simple email service, you can put a text record into the DNS and then allow that company
to verify that you own that domain name and then mix record, stand for mail, exchange your records
and by controlling your own DNS records.
This is how you can separate your email hosting from your website.
And so we do need to still use name servers in a way to be able to control our DNS at a separate provider
like Cloudflare.
So let's go back to the website browser here, and I'm looking in my GoDaddy account where I have a
website domain that I have a registered called Greg Davis Dot Club.
And this isn't a domain that I've used yet, but I'll just show you as an example how I would point
this domain through to Cloudflare and then from Cloudflare, be able to bring it into my hosting company,
which I'm using now called grid pin, as you know.
And so looking at GoDaddy, what I did was I went to all my domains and I clicked on the domain name
and I went to manage the DNS.
So here under DNS is where that would be.
I can look at the different zones, but I'm on the DNS page right now for this domain name and these
are my DNS records.
So right now that a record is actually parked.
What happens is if you if you just register a domain name at GoDaddy and leave it alone, they send
it to a parking page where if anyone clicks around and goes into GoDaddy, it's like a referral.
They would get that business.
And so that's not bringing anything to me.
The name servers that are associated with GoDaddy by default, are ones that the domain control dot
com domain name.
That's a GoDaddy domain name.
And so there's other things like this si name record, like I mentioned, if anyone were to navigate
to UWW.
This allows a redirect to the regular domain name Greg Davis Dot Club.
And so that's basically the default settings for a GoDaddy registered domain name.
Other registrars would work similarly, like Network Solutions or Namecheap if you've registered domains
there.
But what if I wanted to point my domain to Cloudflare?
If you go to Cloudflare and you get an account at Cloudflare, you could click ad site up here at the
right or there's a blue button often and then you just put your domain name right in here.
So let's do that.
Let's go Gray Davis Dot Club and click ad site, and it brings you to select a plan.
And there's three paid plans.
But the free plan is what I'd recommend because it gives you so many great benefits for free.
Otherwise, it's $20 per month per website for other services that aren't really necessary, especially
if you have a great website hosts like grid pain.
And so I'm going to click that free and click Continue and then to set this up there.
The Cloudflare Company website will scan the existing DNS records, and it will build them for me inside
this DNS.
Now, like I mentioned, the DNS right now is live and being controlled by GoDaddy, and so Cloudflare
goes and sees, OK, what are the necessary DNS records that if we did point?
Traffic from there away from the DNS of GoDaddy.
What DNS records would we need to be live to have nothing change?
And that's this a record, this sea name and then this other sea name record right here.
And so generally, the minimum is one, a record and one sea name record for the W WW version.
And so, OK, that's just, you know, it's telling me that I don't have any Amex records, so I know
that I don't have any email set up right now, so I can ignore that.
And this looks correct.
So I'll click continue.
And now I get these instructions.
I want to remove these two name servers which detected Remember Over and GoDaddy.
These are what the default name servers are, and I want to change those name servers to Cloudflare
name servers here.
And these are the name servers that go to the free Cloudflare DNS controller.
And so I have to do is click to copy number one, go back to Domain Domain Manager and GoDaddy, and
I'll click change.
And then I want to enter my own name servers right here.
And so I'll go ahead and paste that first one and I'll go back and click the second one, copy it on
to the clipboard and paste into the second section.
And then I'm going to save.
And now GoDaddy will give me a warning because if you do update your name servers to an existing website,
that's up and running.
There's a chance that you could break things.
You could stop an email address from working, or you could make a website go down if your DNS records
are incorrect or non-existent in the new spot.
But as I mentioned, Cloudflare goes and has already found my existing domain DNS records, and so it
will point correctly no matter what.
So you shouldn't be fearful here, but you do have to check the box that says yes, I consent to to
updating the name servers and click Continue.
Now, GoDaddy is a pretty good registrar in that they only take just a few minutes, usually to change
the name servers and point traffic to the new place.
But they do warn you that it could take up to 48 hours to update globally because the DNS system is
a domain name system that it propagates across the world and all the different hubs where internet traffic
goes through all the different places all over the world, and it can take hours or days for the DNS
records to completely propagate through the entire world.
And so there can be a delay for existing services that are up and running to change.
And that's why when you're changing over DNS for an existing website, you would want to have that DNS
really live and correct at the new place.
If there are email addresses, sometimes emails can stop working for a few minutes and then come back
when the DNS propagates through all the places on the internet.
And so while this is happening, I can go back to name servers.
And now that I've done that, I can click done check name servers.
And now it's just kind of telling me I can configure some things or I can skip these recommendations.
And now it takes me back to this screen where I can just make sure that everything is correct.
Now I'll receive an email from Cloudflare as soon as it detects that the name servers are, you know,
pointed to the right place.
Usually that happens in a number of minutes when I'm working with GoDaddy for these changes.
If I want to later, I can come back and I could click check name servers.
I often don't need to do that because it usually takes just a couple of minutes.
And then once the DNS has moved its control from GoDaddy over to Cloudflare, then I can start to make
some changes, like adding that website to my grid pain account.
Now, for example, here is my grid pain account for one of my sites, Greg Davis dot com, which is
a life site.
And here's where I would have the the the address, the IP address of my server and other settings that
I could make for this domain name.
But in a in grid pain, really, the next thing I would do is to begin to set up a new site here at
these sites.
Add new sites section right here.
And what I would do is, I would say, Greg Davis, Dart Club and I would select the server where I
want to host that and just put that on my personal dedicated server there.
I could select that I want to auto create a system user.
That means I can separate all these for different purposes like FTP and things like that to different
users.
So none of my sites, especially if their different client sites are, you know, can see each other.
And then as we go down here, it's there's an admin email and.
Password.
Other things to choose, like if I have a bundle set up where I have my themes and my plug ins I want
to use, and then the IP version, everything I kind of leave as default.
And the one thing I do when I set up a new site is I set up my outgoing email account, which I've connected
to my free SendGrid for outgoing email and use the primary domain SSL so that I have a secure SSL certificate.
And then I want to integrate with my Cloudflare DNS.
This is the important part.
I want to integrate Cloudflare file and then choose the API key that's labeled with this funny name
inside of grid pane.
And then I can choose whether I want to set up a staging site right away or not, and automatic updates
is another feature within grid pane.
You can learn about now and click the Add site button, but not until Cloudflare sees that my site is
up and running.
So I pause the video here and I'll check my email and then see if Cloudflare sees the change in its
name servers quite yet.