In this lesson, I'll show you around one of the live email hosting systems at Rackspace that I use
in my business.
You'll learn how I set up hosted email and verify the domain with DNS records and how to get the credentials
needed for setting up an email program, as well as how you can set up email aliases at a domain instead
of creating additional paid email accounts.
By the end of this video, you'll understand the concepts around hosted email at a custom domain, including
the DNS records for verification and the email server, hostname and port numbers required for your
own or your client's email program set up.
Let's take a look at an example of how I've set up a custom domain name email address using the rackspace
service that I often use for client work.
Now this is a domain name of mine leveraged WP dot com.
You're probably familiar with, and I've set up my new domain as well as a new email address here at
Rackspace.
And when I set that up, it did force me to choose, of course, the email address, but then a password
and that.
So the email address is.
The username and password, of course, is the email password.
And so you'll need to remember those or write them down to be able to deliver those to your client.
If you're setting up email addresses for your client.
So now, once I have this email set up, this is now a live hosted email address at Rackspace.
I can go over into the setup tab over here and it you can open this client config tool, which opens
another tab and makes you log in and gives you a little information about setting up email.
And so there is a wizard that will walk you through different email clients like Mac Mail for the Apple
Mac or Mozilla Thunderbird or Microsoft Outlook, depending on your website email program, and that
that can give you the right credentials and everything.
But here on the left hand side are really the only other credentials that you need to set up an email
program like Mac, Mail or Outlook.
And so you need an inbound, secure email server Gqom hostname.
So that's the inbound host for incoming email, and it also gives you a reference to a port number and
then you'll need an outbound email host and that's the SMTP server.
And so it's either called the email server name or the email host you'll need to put into your email
program like Mac Mail or Outlook, and also on your iOS devices like your iPhone or an Android device
where you're checking your email.
Now, often clients and you might want to check emails on multiple devices and therefore, instead of
using Pop three or Pop three email, choose IMAP.
Instead, IMAP saves copies of the email on the server and it loads them on each device.
Keeping the email on the server until it's deleted and what that means is that those devices are all
synchronized with the email server so you can check email on your phone and then turn off your phone.
Open your computer.
That email can also be checked on your computer.
Now, when you delete it from your computer later, when you check email on your phone, it will also
be deleted out of your account on the phone.
So IMAP is synchronized email and it's the best way to go these days with hosted email.
So those are the only two pieces of information you need, along with the port numbers in order to set
up an email program.
So over here you also need to verify the email address and point your domain name properly.
So if I look at this domain name at Cloudflare, I have these DNS records for the leverage WP dot com
domain name and over at Rackspace, I was able to get the this information to set up the DNS.
So what I did was open up support, and I clicked how to and I've right clicked how to and opened it
in a separate tab right over here.
And then there's a get started with Rackspace.
Hosted email.
And then what I want to do is configure my domain to receive email.
And so once I did that, it scrolled me down to configure your domain to receive email and there's a
link to set up DNS records.
And so now, as I scroll down, it explains what this is all about, and then I can configure the DNS
to send and receive email.
And so I need to put these four records in my DNS for that domain name.
And all I do is use the at symbol or leave it blank at Cloudflare.
You use the at symbol to have it be for the domain name itself.
And then you can see here that I've created one text record and an Emacs record, another Emacs record
and then a C name record for Auto Discover.
And you could see that these email server Akamai reflected the host name the Amex one and Amex two that
also need a priority number Priority 10, Priority 20.
And it tells you all that over here at the The Help Document for Rackspace, Google Workspace for Gmail
set up will have this kind of information for you as well, and you need to verify and set up the DNS
entries so that sending and receiving email will work separate from the domain name pointing to your
website.
And so that's really all there is to it.
The TETO, which is time to live, you can just leave it by the default, usually as far as the way
Cloudflare works.
The TTL is on auto.
It kind of knows what it's doing as far as that.
But now I've got an email address set up at Rackspace with 25 gigabytes of storage at a protected and
managed IP address, which makes it easy for me to send and receive email and keep that separate from
my website IP address, which is here.
And so that's managed and the best practice as far as supporting hosted email for your sites and for
your client sites at custom domain names.
Now, if I wanted to, I could just go and click email Bayda here to create another address and forward
it to this existing address here at Cloudflare.
Or it could forward it to any address I like, and that's just a way to create aliases of this email
inside of Cloudflare.
But also, Gmail allows for this as well.
But inside of Rackspace, you can also add an unlimited number of aliases that will basically forward,
you know, extra email addresses.
If I want to have one that was something like info at leverage WP Dotcom and just have that forward
to my real email address that's called creating an alias.
And so I often use that to create additional email addresses instead of paying a fee for each email
address.
And so that's really the all.
All it takes to set up, send and receive email at custom domain names.
And I hope that was helpful for you.