In this lesson, we'll look at the Divvy Resources on the Elegant Themes blog.
You'll see how I usually look around the blog for the most recent new designs, as well as find the
layout packs that have matching headers and footers and custom page templates, too.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how you can find the most useful and modern resources while
using layout packs in Devi when looking around for pre-built resources, using the Devi theme and the
layout packs.
There's a couple of places that you need to know where and how to look to find everything that you might
be able to use.
Looking at this homepage here, we talked about how this is the original or traditional header layout,
as well as a widget based footer layout down here at the bottom.
Later in the course, we'll talk about how to pre build and create global header and footer templates,
as well as specialized template pages that work with specific page types like blog posts or different
custom post types, and still use the divvy layout while maintaining the ability to edit and add new
content using the Block editor.
The Gutenberg Page Editor.
With that said, I'll always keep the elegant themes XCOM Home page open, and I will often look for
the most recent and the most modern resources from the blog, which, interestingly enough, is not
accessible at this point through the top header.
But scrolling down to the bottom, there's kind of a blog section down here.
I'll generally click blog and then take a look at the most recent posts.
Often, the Elegant Themes blog has multiple posts released every day, and they released at least one
new layout pack every week, and they release headers and footers that match the layout packs, for
example, as well as customized pages.
And so the most recent posts are listed from the top.
And as you go down, you can see, for example, this accessible layout pack has been available for
a little while, but now they've recently released a free header and footer template for that layout
pack.
And so I know that they're supporting that modern design in this layout pack, and the header and footer
is a theme builder template that you can freely import and customize for this layout pack.
You can also look for headers and footers that have been custom made and adapt the colours for different
layout packs, making completely unique and customised designs.
And I've done that quite often.
The way this works is in a blog post that has the templates for header and footer.
They both teach you how to use the headers and footers or whatever they're giving you access to hear
the shoe, what they look like here at the top.
On different screen sizes.
But then there's a button that says, download the files.
And then below that, there is a whole to tutorial about how that layout was built from scratch.
And so it's a really good educational opportunity as well as it makes it really easy to go ahead and
just import this super easy into your own website without having to build it from scratch.
But you can delve into the tutorial to educate yourself on building your own custom headers and footers
and other page templates later.
Just real quick, we're not going to import and customize one of these headers and footers yet in the
course, but I wanted to show you how to access the files.
Generally, you'll click download the files, and if you haven't already signed in in this web session
right now, you can see I clicked to download the files and I ended up with a zip file that came into
my downloads folder here.
But if you're not signed in, it'll basically open a window where you can enter your email address.
Basically signing up for the newsletter at elegant themes, and if you're already signed up, you won't
get signed up again.
It'll just enable this download button here, where you can click and then download the zip file.
So if I just open this up and take a look at it here, I'll drag my file explorer over into the window
here.
You can see that inside that in inside this.
When we look at my downloads folder here, it's actually a zip file.
So if I scroll over here, you can see the type of file that it is.
It's a zipped file, a dot zip.
And so that's usually with the little zipper.
So on windows, you can right click and click Extract all, and that will unzip the file into the same
folder where it exists on a Mac, you can just double click and it'll open an archive, which is basically
the unzipped zip file.
And so I can open this folder and within that folder, what I see is a.
Jason Gesso n File, which is named for whatever it is.
And so if I were to open up that file, you'd see that it's a bunch of code.
It's a JSON file that does something when you import it into the Devi website.
And what that does is it imports all the content, puts it into the database, as well as the graphics
and the images that are pulled from the example say into your own websites, media library.
And again, all the layout, pack and graphics and images are freely available.
Copyright free for you to use when you have a DV license.
And so if I know where this this file is, I'll go back into my dashboard and suppose I just wanted
to show you quickly and we'll do this in detail later on when I'm teaching you guys about the theme
builder.
But if I were to go into the theme builder here, this is where you can have global headers, footers
and also customized body areas for custom pages, for blog posts and things like that.
But the way you bring these these JSON files in is you use this up and down arrow icon over here that
says portability.
And then you would click the Import tab, select this file and then your options here and then click
the import button.
And that would import that layout into your DV website, where you can then use it later and define
on which pages it's going to be used, whether globally on every page of the website or only on particular
types of pages.
So that's an overview about how you find some of the things that you can use and import from DV into
your DV powered website.
Also on the blog.
If I go back just one more technique, I'll often go and just search for the word header and then I
can find the header and footer layout packs that are available for all the different layout packs that
are available in DV or elegant themes.
Now, not all the layout packs have a header and footer, and so you can kind of look for which ones
have it.
And it's generally a better idea to use a customized header and footer.
And even if your layout pack that you like doesn't have one, it's a good idea to find one that has
the functionality that you want and the look.
And then you can always change the color, the size, eliminate certain items about it, but it's a
good way to go.
Also, if you go through the different posts of the blog, there are some tutorials that are useful
to know also, for instance, how to create a custom sticky header for mobile.
For example, if you wanted the menu to be available with, say, a menu button and a call to action
all the time in mobile when people scroll so that it's easier to navigate when they're when they're
visiting your website on the phone.
Different things like that.
And there's other resources in there under header and footer.
Oftentimes, I'll go and also search the elegant themes blog for like page layout or the word template
or blog.
There's let's see if I can find one right here.
There's some how tos there, but here's one a blog post template for the software layout pack.
And that's again something we'll go into later in the course.
In the next device section where we'll talk about how to build a customized template for just individual
blog posts, and that can allow you to enter content and edit content if it's you or the business owner
or their employee going in to create blog posts.
They don't have to learn everything about Divij and risk breaking the website.
They can use the standard block editor, but you can still take control of all the content they put
in there and design it to match the website for your blog.
So that's a really powerful way you might search for blog post template.
Oftentimes a category, there could be a category page template that's available in the Elegant Themes
blog.
So be if you're using a blog and you want to customize that category page to have a list of of blog
posts under a certain category and have it look really good and match the layout pack.
So that gives you a good idea of how to search around and navigate for really good resources available
at the Elegant Themes blog.