In this lesson, we'll explore the Cadence Theme Settings panel and compare the free version to what
the pro version offers.
You'll learn the nuances of installing starter templates in cadence as a whole site or individual pages
by the end of this video.
You'll know how to choose and install a complete website design, including header footer and global
elements like typography and colors in preparation for designing a custom site fast.
Well, now we have cadence activated and the cadence blocks plugin activated in our WordPress installation.
You can.
You can see that if you open your website in another tab and just press refresh, it comes in pretty
basic, right?
We've got just a header right here with the single page that is by default, included in a new WordPress
installation.
We've got a content area that has an interesting display of WordPress posts.
There's just one default post, of course, and a default WordPress installation you can see.
It's got kind of a very light gray background with a drop shadow and, you know, got a blue link here.
Read more The link and then a default footer at the bottom.
You know, if you click the the category, you've just got the name of the category.
This is just a basic blank theme that you can use, and you can use this as a starting point.
When you start to build cadence websites, and one of the things we'll go over in this section is how
there are wireframe layouts available in the cadence environment so that you can, instead of bringing
in a predesigned starter template that has images and and and pictures and different colors already
set, you can really start from scratch if you want to with the cadence theme and take advantage of
all those cadence blocks, as well as the design library, which is similar to block patterns in the
WordPress ecosystem.
But let's go back in to the the WordPress dashboard.
There's one more thing I want to just show you inside of the dashboard here, and that is under appearance
cadence.
If you just click the the cadence kind of cadence theme setup screen, you've got a few tabs across
the top that you can take advantage of.
There's a dashboard that shows you some global areas global colors branding for your logo and favicon
for your site, like the title image up here.
The typography sitewide, the header and footer, as well as the general page layout.
Now all of these will open the customizer, which by by default in a WordPress theme that is not a full
site editing theme, will be available over here under appearance customize.
And we're going to be going over all the different areas in the customizer and the very many settings
that you have over there.
But I wanted to point out also down below, there's a little, you know, an ad for the Pro add on for
cadence.
Now, cadence is a freemium plug in and theme, and it's developed by a great set of developers owned
by the IE Themes Company now, and they they do a great job of supporting cadence.
There's so much great functionality within the free version of cadence and the cadence blocks plug in
that that's what we're going to be using.
You'll see that's really all you need to start with.
If there is some functionality that is more advanced that you that you need or want.
Then there is more in the Cadence Pro add on for the theme, as well as the Blocks plugin.
And so there's an inexpensive upgrade that can be made right now.
We're just using the free version, but you can see there's more headers.
There's an ultimate menu.
Add on that that gives you, you know, multi column mega menus, hood header and footer scripts.
Hooked elements gives you more functionality as far as putting items within your website in different
places like the header.
There's just some extra stuff that comes with the pro add on.
That's pretty awesome.
And I'll be going over all those things later in the course and showing you around that, but also across
the top.
There's a getting started column and a tab where there's a video here and then links to a set of video
tutorials and the knowledge base, which is really full of awesome written articles to help you with
cadence.
If you're stuck or you have a question about how to do something that is a great place as a reference,
I often keep the knowledge base open in another tab when I'm making a site with cadence.
The changelog just tells you what's been made in the last updates, and then this is just a link to
the starter templates we already have in.
Old and so let's go ahead and open that starter template screen by clicking that blue button or under
cadence starter templates.
Let's go over how to bring in a starter template and how that works.
There's some different options that you have here and some different things that you should be aware
of when you're bringing in a starter template into the cadence environment.
And so one thing I'll show you is just if we click the first one coffee shop here, if you just click
it once it's going to open a customizer window.
There's a column on the left side with some selections, and then there's an example of what the Full-Size
site will look like if you bring it in to your website.
And now so we have not imported this design into the website as of yet.
This is just showing us a preview.
And you can go through and click the different menu items to look at all the different layout options
within any of the starter themes in cadence, for example, the contact.
You know, here's an example of a style contact form, and you can see what the footer looks like,
et cetera.
You know, here's a menu in the coffee shop one.
And so the thing you can do is just check out all of these starter templates, you know, at full size,
and then you can even click this the X at the top left to go back to where you were, and you can check
out, you know, other ones and open them up and look at what you have available.
Some of the advantages of, you know, using cadence and cadence blocks is that look at this.
You can bring in a background video in your header just by default.
By using the free cadence theme in the cadence blocks plug in, you can see what these dropdowns look
like.
Now, you know other things in each of these.
These designs are very well designed starter templates that you can then leverage in order to build
your own custom sites.
Now, this one, you might notice, has a shopping cart and you know it has a shop.
These are products you can, you know, add them to the cart.
There's these little rollover effects for these products.
A great looking store built with the free WooCommerce e-commerce plugin.
Now, some of these starter templates do have plug ins that are required to use, and they are listed
down below the color and font family options down here on the left hand side.
And so required plug ins will be installed when you import a starter template if they're not installed
already.
And so some of these do require the Cadence Pro add on the paid version of cadence.
This leather shop is one of them.
The Cadence Block Pro not installed and the Cadence Pro theme upgrade not installed.
Now those are, you know, less than $200 a year.
They do have a lifetime price for around six to seven hundred dollars for Cadence Pro and very affordable
if you're going to be using cadence to build multiple sites.
But this, for example, it wouldn't be a good option for building a real live website if you didn't
plan on getting Cadence Pro.
But you know, WooCommerce is free.
And so some of the ones that you'll see here, for example, coffee shop that we were using before are
not required to have the cadence blocks pro and Cadence Theme Pro add on.
Those are packaged together when you go to cadence and look at what the pricing is like there, but
the required plug ins will be installed on import.
And so you'll find that if you do import one of these designs that has an e-commerce shop, you'll see
that WooCommerce will be imported as well.
One more thing I wanted to show you, I think some of them have courses.
For example, here's a course website where you know you can explore the courses.
Let's see if we just look under courses here.
It'll show a grid layout of different courses that you could have.
This one uses a course plug in called LearnDash, which is a paid courses plug in for WordPress.
Again, if you weren't going to be using that plug in, you could substitute a different courseware
plug in for WordPress.
But this one has been built with LearnDash in mind, and so it styles it really beautifully for the
course itself.
You know this right here is these are examples of the way LearnDash shows the different courses and
these different materials and things like that.
It shows you, of course, progress and that sort of thing.
So just be aware that there are required plug ins sometimes associated with the cadence, starter templates.
And the final thing that I want to show you is that.
You can choose to bring in either a single page or you can bring in the full site.
And what I'd recommend generally, especially when you're practicing with cadence, is that you bring
in the full site.
Let's go back and look at one of the one of the starter templates that we are going to be looking at
and customizing it.
That doesn't take any extra plugins.
That's the real estate one here.
If I click Click Real Estate, you can get a good idea of what this might look like.
There's a lot of nice little design elements in this starter template, and you can see if we scroll
down.
It only requires that the cadence blocks plugin be activated, and so using the free versions will all
be able to get in here and customize this template and different pages, including the header in the
footer.
And so that's why I suggest you bring in the full site.
When you do that, it actually creates all the pages and it creates the custom header and the custom
footer that comes with the whole starter template.
Now, if you do bring in a single page, at some point you can just choose which page you want to bring
in, and it just imports that single page when you click on it.
You can hit the back button right here, and let's go back to that real estate.
Starter template.
I'm going to click on it and then finally, you can choose your colour scheme.
Now both color scheme and the font family are easily changeable later, but this is a nice place where
you can go ahead and maybe choose a font family and then choose a color scheme which creates not only
four but seven or eight different colors that all match and are used throughout the design.
And so it's really nice.
It saves a lot of time to be able to choose a color scheme right now.
Choose a fast family, which will give you two different themes that match four different places on
the website, like the header versus the body, text, etc. And then all you need to do is click full
site down here.
And I usually leave these as the defaults under import details tells you what color palette you've selected.
I could see there's five colors here and then what the actual font pair is the names of those.
That's useful if you want to take and make any graphics or logos within Photoshop or another program
like Canva, where you can go and find those fonts and use them in other graphics you might create for
a custom website.
And then under advanced settings, I usually make sure and have these two selected where it's importing
the customize or settings for this starter template and also importing the content itself so you can
see what it really looks like.
And now this little window is totally optional.
You can subscribe to the Cadence newsletter and hear about when something new comes out and features
for cadence, but you don't have to.
You can go to the bottom and click Skip Start Importing, and then it should only take a few seconds
and it will import the content.
It imports the menus and the header.
The footer.
The Customize content.
And then you'll get a result in just a few seconds.
All right, that took about 10 seconds when I did pause the video while it was doing it.
And now I've got a message in for complete finished view your site.
So I usually don't click that, especially if I have my site already open in another tab.
But I just go ahead and go back to, you know, just somewhere here.
I might go back to pages, all pages within the dashboard and you can see what pages it created.
It did get rid of the sample page, and it did create the labeled the home as the front page or the
home page and blog as the Post's page.
And if you remember, those can be chosen, you know, when you look at settings reading.
That's a place where you choose a static page four for your home page on your posts page and the the
under appearance.
Customize is also a place where you can choose your home page settings.
Also under posts all posts.
It also created a series of posts, six posts to be exact for this starter template, and then this
Hello World post was left here and it's just uncategorized.
It doesn't have any images or anything, so I usually go in and just put that in the trash so that it's
not visible within the theme as I'm looking around.
And so I'll go over to the live site here under my second tab and refresh the page.
And what we'll see is this website.
It's it's really awesome when you can get a fully designed website imported into your own environment
as a really great starting place.
There's this nice back to top button up here.
You can see that there's, you know, different layouts.
This is kind of a standard header with a shorter image different than the home page, but the same menu
navigation.
You know, here is the about page.
There's the blog page works to pull in each of these blog posts, as well as clickable to the blog post
itself, which has the title inside of a bigger top image, which is the featured image of the blog
post and a lot of great stuff about this starter template.
So next, we'll get to customizing this starter template within our WordPress dashboard, using all
the features of the cadence block's plug in, as well as cadence theme itself under appearance, customize
and a few other places.