In this lesson, we'll use the all in one WP migration plugin to migrate a site from one host to another
using local.
You'll learn how a plugin can make a migration easier by taking care of the required database URL edits
for you By the end of this video, you'll understand how to migrate a site between hosts using a plugin
that creates a migration file to import into the destination site.
Now let's migrate a website from one environment to another, one WordPress site to another hosted WordPress
site again.
Here between sites that I have installed using local right on my computer.
But again, this can be used between any live or local websites.
But I've got my first original site activated again, cadence, and if we look at it again, it's got
the starter template that is the real estate starter template, a complete website with all the pages.
And then I created a second site in local called Migration with a plugin, and you can see this is the
URL migration with a plug in dot local.
I have it open right up here, and it just looks like another standard default installation with the
2022 theme activated.
Now, in this case, since we're going to use a plug in, what we want to do is navigate to the login
pages of each of these sites because we need to install this plug in in each of the websites.
And it's a free plugin called All in one WP Migration, a great migration plugin that works well for
free for sites that are on the smaller side under 512 megabytes.
If they're larger than that, they do have a paid extension that you can get.
It's well worth doing if you migrate a lot of larger sites, but let's look at the free version.
So I'm going to go to local.
You know, what I can do is just turn on my one click admin to make it a little bit more convenient.
So what I'll do is have this.
Word for this, it says, is migration with a plug in, and I'll usually just slide these tabs around
so I know what is what.
And just to keep things straight.
Now open the cadence one and I'll turn on one click admin for that as well.
And click admin right here.
Now, when that opens up the WordPress dashboard and I'm logged in, then I can.
Yeah, I can slide this over to the far woops.
Slide it over to the far left here.
And now you'll see I have the dashboard for cadence on the left and then the real site just to the right,
and then the dashboard for migration with a plug in here to the left and the real site over here on
the right.
And that's the way I'll leave it so I can keep sense of everything.
So let's go into the first one and under plug ins, add new.
I'll just start searching for all in one and all in one.
WP migration is what I'm looking for.
It comes up here right on the right hand side.
It's by served mask and I'll just click install now and then.
Once that installs, I can click activate.
And great, that just brings me to the plug in page and says plug in activated.
Let's do the same thing with the migration with a plug in WordPress site, plug ins add new and search
for all in one, all in one WP migration install.
And let's activate it once that gets installed here.
Great, OK, so I have the plugin installed in both places, so I need to do is go to the original one
and I go to all in one migration and hit export.
Now the difference with the plug in powered migration and all in one WP migration in particular, is
that it's going to export a file.
It's not a zip file, it's a W press file, and it's actually a proprietary file extension that only
works between this plugin in different instances of this plugin.
And so what you'll do is go to all in one WP migration and click export.
And this will take you to the all in one WP migration settings screen with the export button here,
and then you just click the export two.
And of course, it does give you the opportunity to export to different storage areas like Dropbox or
different things.
But if you click export to file, then it's going to just go ahead and prepare the export, and then
it'll download it to your downloads folder.
Once you click this button and it gives you an idea of the size as well.
And so I'm just going to click download can see at the bottom here that's just brought itself into my
downloads folder.
And then you just click close.
And so now I'm just going to go over to plug ins at the other site, and I have the all in one WP migration
plug in activated.
I can go to all in one and click import.
Now, I just have to import from and I'm importing from a file, and so it'll open up on my computer,
I can go to downloads.
Just click this dot w press file.
It's the one in my downloads folder here and click Open.
And now it's importing and opening this file, and it's going to give us a few things.
Just a warning.
It's saying, OK, this will overwrite the website, including the database, the media, the plug ins
and the themes.
And so just a warning so that if you had an active site and you were doing this, it wouldn't leave
the things you have already in that site intact.
You know, you really should do this on a blank site or a site that you know, it's just going to overwrite
everything.
So I'm going to click proceed and then that will go ahead with the import process.
And this will give me a message once it's finished.
Tells you that you shouldn't close the browser window or your import will fail because it's actually
doing some importing through the browser itself.
So it says, may say it's been imported successfully now, similar to the last lesson where we had to
change the URLs.
It gives us a suggestion save the permalink, links structure.
And so that is a final step.
That's important.
A lot of times when you're doing a plug in migration, I'm just going to save.
I'm going to click this save permalink structure and it says it's going to open in a new window.
And because of the database import, it forces you to log in again.
And in this case, just like I said in the last lesson, you'd have to use the original site's login
credentials.
Not the new site.
And that's just important to know if they're not the same login credentials.
So I'm going to use the original site login credentials, and that should take me to the permalink setting,
which is under Settings perma links in WordPress.
All right, so I'm indoor settings permalink.
And you just leave it here and click Save and then the permalink structure's been updated.
And so what happens if we go back to the original site, the new site where we imported this into and
click refresh?
There we go.
That's an imported site.
It should all work.
It looks like the images are working right off the bat on the home page.
And you know, the interior pages are all working as well and everything works.
As you can see, using a plug in can be a little bit more simple than doing the manual migration.
And when I'm doing migrations, I generally use one of a few different plug ins that I like to use instead
of doing it manually, just because it's a little more simple and the plug in takes care of updating
everything within the database for you.
And so that's the all in one WP migration plug in.
And in the next sections, next lessons, we'll look at a couple other options for migrating WordPress.