In this lesson, I'll show you how I use staging at good pain for efficient updating and redesign projects
for my client websites.
You'll also learn how to set up redundant backup systems both locally and offsite, so that there's
always an easily restore built backup ready in case of any problems.
By the end of this video, you'll understand the best practices with WordPress backups, as well as
several ways of working with staging to update sites safely.
As you know, I love my grid pain staging area management system, and so let's just talk about it a
little bit.
I know that I've introduced grid pain and staging a little bit as far as in other lessons in the course.
But relative to managing client sites and managing multiple sites, especially as regards updating,
I often use a staging area in two different ways and at grid pain.
You know, I highly recommend grouping because one of the reasons is because of their staging management.
They automatically will create a staging area at a subdomain like staging dot domain, BCom, for example.
All you have to do is just simply turn it on if you don't have it on already when you set up the website.
It uses a plugin called Force Login to make sure that that staging domain doesn't get listed in Google
and isn't accessible to the public, meaning you have to be logged in as an administrator in WordPress
to see the site at all and to see the back end as well so you can work on it without risk of having
anybody else seeing it.
And then you can easily with one click push the site from live to staging and easily back again from
staging to live, and that makes it super easy for doing updates and for testing.
And so, as far as updates of the word press corps software, updates of plugins and themes, and even
site redesigns, or creating extra sections of a, say, changing themes and things like that, and
reconfiguring in the background without having the live site go down or the live site change at all.
Using the staging area is great for that, but for updates, I mentioned two ways.
So most of the time what I'll do is create a staging copy.
That's a clone basically of the current site at the staging subdomain just by clicking this single button
live to staging.
And then I'll work on that staging site to go in and do my update and then test those updates in the
staging domain.
And now usually what I'll do is that I'll just say, OK, well, everything seemed to work, so I'll
just go back to the live site and repeat my work there if it was easy and it wasn't too involved.
And so that's the first way.
The second way would be for a more involved redesign or something like that or changing of themes,
something that has more changes that would be more of a pain to just redo on the life site after practicing
at the staging environment.
And so in that case, like if I were changing themes or doing a big site redesign, I would do that
in this on the staging site and then use this staging to live to bring all my changes that I just made
and tested back and overwrite the live site.
And so both ways work.
Honestly, it's more of just a workflow choice that I make in the moment to say whether I want to just,
you know, make a quick update as a test and then just make that update in the life site or to make
the updates at staging and then bring the staging over to the live site, meaning overwriting the live
site as it is.
And so that's one thing I love about grid pain.
Now, if we look at other hosting environments that I use and have used for client sites, Flywheel
does include a really robust staging environment, just like grid paint does, and so recommend Flywheel
for any type of hosting for your sites or for your client sites.
And then I would limit it if you're using a shared host or you're using site ground for shared hosting.
I've mentioned it before, but only the grow big and the go geek levels of shared hosting include staging
as a part of one of their features.
And so the the the Groberg is a good place to start.
The go geek basically gives you double the amount of web space and four times the amount of visits so
that you can host more sites on Go Geek.
So I might recommend just starting with Go Geek until you get, say, more than 20 sites under your
belt and then migrating to manage WordPress hosts like Flywheel or a self-managed host like Grid Pain,
which is the lowest cost per site.
If you're up in multiple sites and so as far as staging areas, that's the way I like to do it.
Let's talk.
About backups now, it's a recommended best practice that you have multiple backups in place for each
one of your WordPress web sites.
And so if I go to the actual live sites here at grid pain and I'll show you at just an example of one
of the sites that leverage WP Dotcom, there's a backup system tab here for each one of your websites
that you're hosting with good pain, and they have a really robust backup system, both local backups
and remote backups.
And you can see that I don't have remote backups activated for this particular site.
But what I do have are remote backups backups activated using a WordPress plug in a free plug in called
updraft.
Plus, it's not related to my updraft media website, but just has a similar name and I'll show you
around that plug in as well.
During this lesson.
And so I just wanted to show you around local backups here in grid pain because it's so robust.
What you're able to do here is, first of all, if you store hourly backups, as you know, complete
restore backups in a traditional fashion, you'll really fill up your server storage space super fast.
And so they use a program called Do Duplicity.
They use a program called Do Duplicate.
See that in the background that using that software would cost you $50 dollars per year per server,
but it is something that is included in grid pain plans.
And in my site here, I am now able to do hourly backups that I choose the time of day by the minute
of what time I want those backups to run so that I can have different sites on the same server, take
their backups at different times during each hour.
And so one of the greatest things about these hourly and daily and monthly backups is that they are
self-healing and self purging.
So by default, the thing that happens, I'm just looking at one of the the knowledge base articles
about the backups configuration in grid pain.
And so it's a good way to get to know how this works a little bit.
One of the things is that they're stored in these non-human readable chunked files, and this is what
enables them not to take up a whole bunch of space on the server as far as backups.
They're also easily restore dribble.
You know, if you go back here, you could see there's a Restore tab here.
So I could just say, OK, I want the restore, what type of restore and I can go back and select my
backup to restore from once I have a list of backups by hour by day or by week or by month.
And then I can also define the purge schedule.
Basically, what I'm going to show you in that knowledge base document is that, you know, you keep
daily backups for a week, keep weekly backups for a month, keep monthly backups for a year.
And any backup that's older than three hundred and sixty days or older than a year gets purged permanently.
And so this is a self healing or self pruning backup system that's saved locally.
And that's the initial backups strategy.
So if the entire server were to go down and disappear, these local backups are also lost with the server
very, very rare.
I mean, you can prevent that by using a failover system that grid pain can offer where you have a synchronized
backup server in a different location.
But I don't use that on every one of my client websites.
It's a more expensive way to go.
It's only used.
I only use it on my highest dollar websites and mission critical websites that businesses pay for that
level of of security on their website servers.
And so, you know these these local backups are very, very often as well.
So if you have a website, a client site or your own site that has a web store, for example, where
there's always orders coming in, you know, an hourly backup is a more powerful backup to have versus,
say, a daily or a weekly backup, which would actually lose, you know, if you had a weekly backup
on a popular WooCommerce store and you needed to restore last week's backup where you would be losing
all the orders that came in since that backup was taken.
And so hourly backups are a really great advantage.
And in this way, don't take up that much storage space on the server.
And so you can enable automated backups at an hourly level at each one of your client websites, a grid
pane, which honestly is a better backup system than any other that I've found.
And so you can also multiply the the redundancy of those backups.
And give yourself a second backup copy, and you can do a second and a third and enabling remote backups
with grid pain, which can be placed on other servers like Amazon RWC and a number of others automatically
so that if the server were to go down for some reason, you could easily restore backups that are placed
on a remote server away from the website's server itself.
And so let's discuss another way to easily do on any website hosted a at an offsite backup.
And let me pause the video and bring up a website where I'm using updraft plus plug in for remote backups.
So here at Leverage WP RT.com, I'll show you how to set up the updraft plus plug in and let's just
go.
If you'd like to follow along on any one of your sites, you could do that at your flywheel life site
or your own host.
If you just type the word updraft in the add new plug ins, you'll see that this one updraft plus backup
plug in.
It's a great plug in that is free to use and has a lot of great features.
And the greatest thing about it is it can store upload backups up to a remote location and store them
and manage that storage so that it can delete older plug ins to purge your storage space in a similar
way to good paying, but not quite as robust.
Also, you can restore backups from that plug in directly and so can see.
I already have this installed and activated on my website here.
You can go down and if once you have it activated onto settings and updraft plus backups, and I do
already have this connected to my Dropbox account.
And so if I scroll down under Settings tab, you can see I've got weekly backups said I like to do on,
you know, most of my websites for this, you know, plug in based remote backup system, which is really
my my third line of defense in my backups redundancy system.
I like to keep two copies at Dropbox, but when you set it up, you want to.
As far as at least with the Dropbox remote storage option, go in another tab and log in to your Dropbox
account and and just be logged in and another tab while you're setting this up.
It just makes it easier when you click the Dropbox button here.
It will open up another tab where you can click to allow the updraft plus backup plug in to connect
to Dropbox for you.
And in that way, what it does is on the weekly basis, it will create and upload a backup to Dropbox
for you.
It'll manage that.
There are two.
There are only at any given time, so it'll delete the older one when it puts a newer one in there to
manage your storage space.
And then you can choose whether you want plugins, themes and uploads included, et cetera.
Any exclusions you'd want, then you could click save changes after you approve that to be connected.
And then once that's connected, you can go to backup restore.
And what I'll generally do is just click backup now and allow that to start.
And so it usually will take just a minute or two to create the backup and upload it into your remote
storage location, whatever that is.
And so you can see that it's doing this in batches.
It gives you these log message messages right here, tells you what's going on and a progress bar right
here, and that allows you to monitor that backup.
And then from down below, if you have an existing backup here, it just allows you to restore using
this little button.
And so you don't really have to go into your Dropbox account and see the backups, although you have
them saved here and you can bring them back to an empty WordPress website, put them in the right place.
As far as the way that updraft, media likes to see them, and then you can restore them once it sees
them there.
And so it can be, you know, basically protection against a catastrophic failure.
If you need to restore one of your backups that was either done in the last week or in the last day
if you have daily backups being saved.
And so, like I said, I like to do both the local and the remote backups on most of my sites within
my grid pain system.
You can do local backups in flywheel and then as a backup of the backup, I recommend that you do install
a backups plug in and remotely save that to somewhere other than the website's server.
And so that is really the the way to go is to have at least two redundant backups available for easy
restoration, if not three, just in case.
The worst possible case is that you lose a website and you don't have any backups of it.
And so I rarely ever have that happen.
But like in rock climbing, you always want to have redundancy in the system so that nothing catastrophic
can ever happen.
You can always restore the website from one of the backups that you have in place.
Hopefully, the most recent one.