In this lesson, we'll check out the Frost themed templates and revert the template parts for the header
and footer to correct the layout.
You'll also convert the navigation links to individual URLs like we did with twenty twenty two and correct
the addresses so they point to your site instead of the Frost demo site and add the site logo to the
header as well.
By the end of this video, you'll learn what changes you might need to make when importing content from
one state to another and fix the differences between the demo site and your own.
So let's go back to the WordPress dashboard, and we'll take a look under appearance editor.
And just like in the 20 22 theme, we'll be able to take a look at the different templates that are
in use and what they're how they're set up by default after we've imported the content into the site.
As I mentioned in the last lesson, let's go ahead and start with looking at the navigation menu and
changing it to have the correct links.
You also notice a difference here.
With that, we're looking at the the site editor template and a couple of things.
The navigation menu is on the far right, whereas when we first imported it, there's no logo and it's
on the left side here.
So right here you can see that there's a dotted line where the site logo should go.
And there's also a dropdown here which shows that this template, the site template, has no title.
So let's just leave it alone for now.
Let's go ahead and just look at templates.
So there's a template called no title that has been added by the theme, as well as a few other sitewide
templates here.
Not quite as many as are included in Twenty Twenty.
But Frost the frost theme is still under development, and you'll probably see more as time goes on
here.
And then let's look at template parts.
So there's a footer and there's a header, and I can see there's a little blue dot here, as we saw
in the 2022 theme.
It says this template has been customized, so I might suggest that we just go and go back to the three
dots and clear the customizations to revert this template part back to the default setting.
Now, after doing that, if we go back into our site right here and click Refresh, you can see that
something has changed now.
It does have the site title at the top left, no logo, but also there are a number of menu items here
and they are over to the right hand side and then down in the footer.
You can see what this looks like here.
I just noticed that the template part has also been quote unquote altered.
So let's go back to the original.
OK, so that is reverted back to the way that it comes in.
Now, of course, these are basically just like in 2020 to I'll bet this is showing all the pages on
the site and even the sample page that's included that we would want to maybe put in the trash there.
So let's just go ahead and let's look at the templates.
And again, if we go to tight, no title, this just has post content there.
And so let's go ahead and go back to.
Template parts, and let's edit this header template that was our purpose anyway, so here's the header
template part, and it's got this navigation here.
Let's look at the list view, as we did before and as 2020 two.
It's got, you know, nav a navigation block can open the settings over here, too on the right hand
side, as well as it's just a page list.
And so if we if we want to edit this without changing anything else, let's see what happens if we just
have navigation selected and then we start hitting the plus sign.
So let's see the there's a sample page.
Contact us.
Hello, world.
So there's a few in the sample site.
Let's go look back at the Frost WP sample site that we'll just match, at least to start with what this
looks like here.
So start here is the home page.
So we've got start here, our services, and so I'll just start typing start.
Here it is.
Start here and you can see it's added it here.
If I want to, I can just get rid of this page list to get it out of our way.
And so click Navigation.
And again, oops.
You have to get that plus sign.
And the next one was called our services.
Start typing it, there we go again, click the navigation.
Maybe click away from there, click now.
Oops.
So that's in the way.
If I could click navigation.
No, but I really want to do is.
I need to find that little plus button there, don't I?
Oh.
You go.
It's hard to find that little plus button.
Let's open the list to you, OK?
We have those two.
Hmm.
I wonder if I pull this over here, maybe if I move it over.
I just need to find that little plus button.
This is an interesting issue.
I could select menus.
There's header navigation.
That's a good way to do it.
Let me bring this back out.
Oops!
I'm going back out to full screen.
All right, so it added the header navigation instead of doing it a page at a time.
What I did was I selected it, selected navigation here, and then I click select menu and I chose header
navigation.
And so that put the navigation in there.
Now I can click Save.
And yeah, I'm going to save the header and the navigation menu.
Click Save there.
And now let's look at our own site.
And refresh the page.
Great.
Now.
It clear that it did bring in the wrong links in there, but it does look right.
Isn't that right?
So let's do this.
We'll take the address and copy it, so let's select the whole thing.
Hit controls, see?
And now let's edit each one of these.
So the home page link here, just while start here is selected, you can click the link.
Hit edit and instead of frost of up.
We'll click the address of your sandbox site, then you can hit enter or click the little arrow there.
Let's go through and now on our services a little bit different.
Click the link, click the edit button.
Now you want to go ahead and leave the services you URL name, which is the name of the page there,
and leave the slash.
Also, because I didn't copy the the forward slash.
So if I had paste right there, you can see that that shows, oh, it did put the slash in.
So you want to erase the slash two slashes won't work.
And so there's services.
Let's go to service plans.
Hit the link button.
Hit the edit button.
Let's take these.
The forward slash out from before plans and hit paste.
There we go.
And hit the little arrow to add it.
Design blog, which is putting the correct URL in each one of these.
It's just slash blog.
And one last one gets started.
There's the link.
Here, edit, erase the forward slash before contact paste.
And click.
That's great.
Now let me just point out, while we're here, you can see with this get started navigation link block,
it's called a custom link.
There's some styles that are included in Frost, and this is one of the benefits of frost that they've
brought in some really interesting styles that you can use that are really well-designed.
So this one's a fiddle style, so there's default fill.
You could change it to just an outline or fill with white or outline with white.
But let's just use the fill and let's click Save because we're saving that header navigation template
part.
And now so when we go back and refresh the page on our site, you can see that each of these goes to
the pages of our own website.
Great.
And now let's go ahead and put the logo in here.
If if I go back, let's see.
Let's just go back to the templates.
Now there's no title template.
You can see that it's OK, it's showing here.
What we want to do is add the site logo.
So let's see if we go to template parts and go to edit header again.
Let's see what we might be able to add here.
So there's a row.
Here's the site title.
Maybe I'll click this row, and what I want to add is a logo.
So let's add the site logo right here.
Now it added a site logo down below.
And let's see what it looks like in the list view.
Yes, site logo way down here.
So, you know, I could hit this up arrow.
You bring that up above, or I could use this drag and put it right next to before or after the site
title whips.
Now I've got it before the site title.
Looking at my options here, what's.
So the site like logo now is to the left.
Let's actually just add it in the media library.
Frost is the site logo.
Let's select that and now it brings it in in a nice size.
Right?
So let's go ahead and remove the site title now, and that's going to make it look right.
So a click, save and save again to save this template and the template parts and close this down and
click away and you can see what it looks like.
All right.
Let's go back here.
Refresh the page.
Now we've we've modified the navigation links and the logo, so it's clickable to the home page and
start here goes to the home page as well.
Great.