I've created two special versions of WordPress for you to create your own practice and experimentation
sites that I call WordPress Sandbox Environments.
Both of these are free for you to use for one year and for students and new users.
I created an expiring trial account of one full year on them, so I have a way of deleting old, unused
sites that students create over time.
The first sandbox at leverage WP Sandbox XCOM is designed for you to try out the default WordPress themes
and experiment with the most recent versions of WordPress and the other at leverage divvy.
Dotcom is for learning the paid theme and page builder tool called Divvy without the Divvy Sandbox Environment.
You would have to pay for your own license to use the DV theme and builder for WordPress.
And this allows you to freely experiment and try it out as one of the possible methods of building custom
websites.
It's important to note that the sandbox environments are built on a type of WordPress called multi-site
that allows more than one website to be built within a single WordPress installation.
Multi-Site is a controlled environment that doesn't allow for site owners to install just any plugins
and themes.
Only the ones that the multi-site administrator that's me has pre-installed.
So just so you know, the curated WordPress.com version that I referred to in the last lesson is an
example of a multi-site installation of WordPress in the next several sections of the course.
We'll be learning WordPress by creating sites in the two sandbox environments at Leverage, WP Sandbox,
XCOM and Leverage Diwekar.
Each of those allows you to create up to 10 sites for practice and experimentation.
Let's get to it.
Signing up for a free sandbox account is easy enough.
Just go to leverage WP Sandbox Dotcom and you'll see a register link up at the top right.
If you already have your sandbox account, you can click Login at the top right as well.
But once you click register, you can go ahead and choose a site title and then a URL for your site.
Your first site will be whatever name you choose.
Dot leverages WP Sandbox dot com and has to have at least four characters no spaces or dots or anything
like that.
But just choose a site.
Just choose a name for the site.
That's just the WordPress site title, and I'm just going to put Greg to.
Leverage any name you like is fine, and you'll be able to create nine more sites as well to keep practicing
with WordPress if you like.
Then you just click Continue to the next step, and that's where you'll choose a username for your sign
and credentials.
Put your email and then choose a password and type it once again.
I'll pass the video while I do that.
Now, just click Create Account, and it will come up with a logged in welcome screen.
Well, logged into my new site.
So at this point, I've got a welcome to a WordPress screen.
I can dismiss that.
And of course, you can control how your screen looks up here with the screen options.
That's the welcome screen that I just dismissed right there and then a little bit different from a normal
web WordPress site.
You'll see that you have an account menu item over here on the left, and then that's the same as this
button here.
Account summary And it gives you a few stats about your account in the sandbox.
You get 365 days to use it for free, and if you click account summary, it'll tell you how many sites
you have and what they are.
Down here at the bottom left and so you can use the Add new site button here and these buttons to either
visit the dashboard or visit the site on each one of your sites.
If you go up to my sites and then you'll see this master site leverage WP Sandbox, there's nothing
really here except a user account for the entire network.
But if you go to the site, you create it and click Visit Site.
I'll click Right Click and then click Open in a new tab.
Then you'll see that it's just a default 2022 theme powered website.
There's just a single post home page and a sample page there, and you can go on in later lessons of
the course and begin customizing that site for yourself.
That's all there is to it.
You'll see that it's the same process with the device sandbox.
Just go to leverage divvy dot com and you'll see on the Welcome Home page.
Here there's a sign up button, and there's also a register button up here at the top right.
If you already do have your sandbox account, you can go ahead and use the login button here at the
top or log in right here.
So if you click sign up, you'll see that there's a register page that looks very similar to the leverage
WP Sandbox dot com signup page with a logo here and you go through the same steps.
This time, when you get your new site set up at Leverage Divvy Accom you have the same welcome screen
and you do have the original 20 22 default theme enabled, so there's one more step you need to do.
Just go to appearence themes and go ahead and choose Divvy and click Activate.
Now your site will be a just a default installation of Deivi.
If you open it in a new tab, you'll just see it looks like a pretty plain blank site with a single
post, a standard divvy menu at the top and a standard footer, which we're going to be customizing
in detail in the two divvy lessons.
Coming up, we're going to be customizing this standard divvy layout and bringing in some free designed
layouts from the extensive Devi library.
We'll make a site that looks like the original site at DV at leverage DV dot com.
If you click Visit Site at Leverage DV dot com, you can take a look at what this nice looking site
looks like, and we're going to learn all the features about how to go ahead and build a site just like
this and learn Devi by matching the design and bringing some pre-designed layouts into your own site.