In this lesson, I'll show you my client payments website where I'm able to take credit cards for one
time, project fee payments and recurring subscriptions for my website care plans.
You'll learn how to automate your payment system so that clients can manage their own accounts and payment
methods and pay for your services online.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how to set up a professional system to charge for your
services for initial project fees and recurring subscription payments for website care and maintenance
or any other services you offer.
Let's look in detail here at my website, updrafts media and look at how I manage project fees and annual
and monthly subscriptions for client website care plans and hosting, as well as a couple of tips and
tricks for setting it up easily.
So it's easy to manage for clients and also for me as far as what's included.
Email notifications and reminders about payments and credit card expirations and things like that for
clients.
And on this website, I'll show you this up.
Draft media website is really not designed to be navigated by the public or get a lot of traffic.
I honestly just use this to give a product a link to clients so that they can go in and navigate to
their product and sign up for the payment and put their credit card in and manage their payments in
the future by creating an account using WooCommerce and the Woooo subscriptions extension or extension
plug in for WooCommerce in WordPress.
So I'll show you how all of that is set up in the back end.
But as we take a look on the front end first here.
This is an example of just a sample product page that I've created just to show, you know, the way
that I create this here and this is really just a default WooCommerce product display as well as having
the cart and the checkout just displayed the way the simple theme displays WooCommerce.
It's important that you do choose a theme that can display WooCommerce pages and checkout pages very
well, and this is just a standard WooCommerce layout.
I don't need anything fancy here, just a place for my customers to go in and make their payments.
Sign up for the recurring fees, put in their credit cards, connecting to my payment gateway and also
to be able to go in and log in later to manage their account in a certain place if they need to.
And so here's a product page, and really all I do is I set a price and either a sign up fee, which
is for the project fee itself and website care plan a subscription fee.
So per term, which is in this case per year, or it might be per month.
And I have a description here which I usually have a lot more detail here.
Some bullet points about what the product and the website care plan includes.
And then that's all there is to it, really.
I just have a footer here that has a contact form and my contact information.
The contact button up in my menu here just scrolls to the bottom to the footer area where the contact
form is on every page of the website.
And you know, you can see that the home page isn't anything special, just a page and a scroll down
button.
It describes what this website is for and where you can go to go to shop or your own personal link and
my account to manage your own account within the website.
But you can see that within shop if you if someone clicks the shop button here, they don't see their
own products.
What they see is just my consultation charge for 15 minute increments and the price.
They could access this and add it to the car and pay for a consultation period of time, which would
then send them to my calendar booking program.
I use the free calendar plug in to book times for consultations, but my clients rarely have to pay
for their consultations if they're a paid client.
They can get in touch with me via email and of course, we do our interviews for figuring out the website,
project and stuff as included in my, in my, you know, website care plans and and as a client.
And so the the shop here doesn't include private products.
And so I'll show you how I set that up.
I've gone in here in the back end of the website, you know, under products, I'm looking at all products
and I chose this design hosting for this, you know, random Acme Company, just an example, sample
company.
And the way I set up this product is I'll choose a name, usually the name of the website or the name
of the company as a project name.
And then here in the description areas where I put bullet points with what this includes.
So if I scroll down in this product, you can see the product data section here and a couple of things
that I set in order to set this for a virtual product for my customers, one click virtual that just
turns off the shipping and I can have anything to ship, so I make it a virtual product.
But the main thing is that I switch it from a simple product to simple subscription that gets enabled
when you enable the Woohoo!
Subscriptions extension, and I'll show you a little bit more about that later in this lesson.
But a couple of the things that it also enables the subscription price right here.
So I've got a thousand for every year.
You can do it by the day, week, month or the year, and then the sign up fee I use as a one time charge.
And that's the project fee that I charge for the website project.
And so those are my pricing details.
And then there's two more things that I'd like to show you first up here.
These are all about the visibility of the product inside of the website itself.
Now each of these is a private product.
This is the permalink, the link that I share for my customer, and I'll email them this link and no
one else has this link.
And so it's a hidden product.
And so what I want to do is change this catalog visibility here under I can click, edit and you know,
it's available in the shop and the search results by default, but you want to choose hidden and then
click OK.
So this is hidden from the catalog.
That means that when someone's on your website and they go to shop, it will won't show up on the shop
page.
But secondly, and potentially more importantly, I limit the visibility of this product in the Google
Google search results.
And on the internet at large by limiting its visibility using SEO.
And so I'm using the SEO Yost SEO plug in and I have that activated.
Once you have that activated, you can choose a setting which which automatically sets products as not
visible or hidden from SEO and from search engines.
And so under advanced in the Yost's selection box here on the product, you can see that allows search
engines to show this product in search results is chosen to know and that's what you want.
And currently I have that as the default for products in the U.S. deseo plug in settings.
And so I just make sure that that's correct.
And then I would click Publish and then this product is now available.
If if they were to go to this link and they would find it there, they could click sign up now and then
it would take their billing details, obviously, and they could go ahead and pay with their credit
card.
And we'll talk about the payment gateway that I use as well.
For me, I use Stripe.
It works in in that really well for me, and I do prefer it over PayPal.
But Stripe is a really popular way to try to collect payments and as a payment gateway in the SEO menu,
in the admin menu on the left here under SEO, under search appearance, you can choose content types
and then not posts.
But as you go down here, as long as you have WooCommerce enabled, you can close each one of these
under products.
You can choose the default settings and so you just toggle off under show products in the search results
and then click save changes.
And that will mean for every product that you create in the future under products, add new.
As soon as you create a new product that will then toggle that off as we look under your SEO under advanced.
It'll just always be no current default for products, and that's how you turn that off and make sure
that your product doesn't come up in the search results in Google on a product that you want to be just
private for your own client.
I've been talking about WooCommerce as the e-commerce provider plugin that I'm using, it is a free
plugin that you can use for ecommerce stores and I've used a paid attachment or extension for WooCommerce
called Woooo subscriptions or WooCommerce subscriptions.
And let me just show you a couple of things that that provides for under WooCommerce here on the site
and under settings under the Subscriptions tab over here.
On the right hand side, this is where you would choose what the button says.
I choose to say Sign up now.
And there's a few other settings that it provides for when you have the subscriptions extension enabled.
Let me just show you over here under WooCommerce scam in one of their products.
If you just search the extensions, store or search for WooCommerce products under WooCommerce subscriptions,
this is the plug in and now it does cost $199 per year, and I think it is well worth using for this
purpose with WooCommerce.
It just makes it so easy for me to create recurring subscriptions and have the customer manage their
own payment methods without having to do having me to do anything at all.
And so as we look down and under WooCommerce subscriptions, you can see that a few of the benefits
you know, you can choose multiple billing schedules to suit the needs of your customers.
As I said, monthly or yearly billing, there's over 25 payment gateways that are available and can
be used with WooCommerce subscriptions.
No matter what country you're in, you probably can find a way to use WooCommerce subscriptions to take
automatic recurring payments.
You can also do manual recurring payments and have it keep track of reminding you when you need to take
a payment.
If you have a client that prefers to write you a personal cheque then or a business check, that would
be fine.
You can just go ahead and enter that on the anniversary of their subscription.
And there's automatic rebuilding, you know, in the case where a credit card has expired, it takes
care of rebuilding on failed subscription payments, etc. Subscribers can upgrade or downgrade if you
have different levels of service, among many other different benefits.
And so the reason I love this plug in is for all those benefits and that it isn't an official plug in
supported by the company that powers WordPress, and it is an annual charge.
It only takes really one client account to feel that for me, that that really pays for this service,
and I use it on my website for every client that I charge, website care and hosting plans for.
And so it's a great thing.
Now I use the Stripe Payment Gateway because it works easily and it's it works for free with WooCommerce,
but you do need to pay the stripe fees in order to accept credit cards.
And so this is a standard fee generally standardize across the world.
As far as it's almost exactly what PayPal charges, it is exactly at 2.9 percent of the transaction
fee, plus 30 cents for each transaction.
And so I included as a cost of doing business that I pay almost three percent of the billing amount
for every time a person pays me with a credit card.
For years and years, I only did manual invoicing and took checks and where I didn't have to pay a fee
for taking those payments.
But I believe that it is well worth it for me to be able to take both automated recurring payments and
at the same time, be able to accept credit cards, especially because they can come out automatically
on a recurring basis.
And so it's an expense.
Both the Stripe Gateway fee and the subscriptions module fee to be able to take recurring payments.
Now, if you're just starting out and you don't want to take on those fees, I think that's totally
fine and you can do individual invoicing.
It's really easy to do invoicing through a free Google Doc or Google invoice, a spreadsheet that you
can manage with the Google Docs or Microsoft Word or Microsoft Excel, something like that where you
can just send an invoice and then take a check from your customer.
But I think it's really advanced way of putting together just a website for your customers to come to
where they can come over and manage their own account.
They can see their orders.
They can look at their subscriptions and when their subscription is coming due.
And there's more that you can offer them to be able to manage their payment methods, et cetera.
Now there's one more thing I want to show you within WooCommerce and that is under the Emails tab under
WooCommerce settings.
One thing I like to do for.
Webster, like mine, where you know, the the customer makes the payment, and in WooCommerce, it's
set up by default so that that turns into a processing order.
And as you remember, when I created a let me go back when I created a.
As you remember, when I created a product, let me go.
Open up products.
As you remember, when I was showing you my product for a website customer, I arranged so that.
Hmm.
When I set up a product for my website customer, I enabled that as a virtual product because there
was nothing that I was going to ship.
So it turns off the shipping system, but there is something within WooCommerce and the email communication
that I think it's smart to turn off to match with this system because I'm not going to be shipping anything.
I don't need to notify the customer that their order has shipped.
And so you may find that you have a repeated email that repeats the invoice and can be confusing for
customers that are buying a virtual product from you through WooCommerce.
And so what happens with WooCommerce is when a customer buys a product, the order is is placed and
it's listed in your WooCommerce store under orders as an order that is as a processing order, and after
the payment goes through, it turns from a new order to a processing order.
And that gives you time to prepare the item for shipping.
And then mark the order completed once you've shipped it.
And if you look at the completed order email, this completed order email is designed to notify the
customer that their order has shipped and now their order is complete.
And so if there's nothing to ship, what can happen is when you change the order from processing to
completed in your WooCommerce system under orders here, it can generate another customer email that
goes out confuse the customer because it will be almost the same exact email they got when they placed
their order and the payment went through.
And so what I usually do is I turn off the completed order email that goes out to the customer.
And we do that is under manage.
You would look at this order here and just uncheck enable this email notification and then click Save
Changes in that way that completed order email will be disabled and you'll see a grey X instead of the
purple checkbox here to let you know that that email won't go out to the customer when you change it
into a completed order.
What I usually do is I'll let that order stay as a processing order until I see that the payment has
gone all the way through to my stripe account, which usually takes just a day or two.
And then once I see that the money has gone into my stripe account and it's on its way to my bank account,
then I'll go ahead and change that order into completed and then I can have that correctly reflected
in my WooCommerce settings.
I hope that gives you a great idea about how you can manage your incoming invoices and design fees and
project fees, as well as recurring payments for your website and your website clients where you can
set up a shop where clients can manage their own accounts, have a payment processor like Stripe, and
manage your invoicing and taking payments via credit cards as a modern business should.
You should be able to take payments from clients and use this system for recurring payments on an ongoing
basis and have it pay for itself in a short period of time.
And finally, I hope you can see that you can set up these types of systems with WooCommerce, Woooo
subscriptions if needed, and Stripe to be able to set up e-commerce stores and payment systems for
your clients websites.
This is the type of website that you can charge more for and can provide hosting and website care on
an ongoing basis for client sites as well.