In this lesson, we'll customize the look and feel of the contact form and test the outgoing notification
email.
You'll customize the success message that shows after the form is submitted and also add a navigation
menu item to the contact page and explore the mobile responsive options.
By the end of this video, you'll learn how to modify the style of a form through the plug in settings,
as well as explore mobile responsive styling with the browser developer tools and the WordPress site
editor.
Now, later, in the course, we're going to talk about functionality like outgoing email systems sending
and receiving email.
Transactional email like this would be, you know, when someone fills out this form, and then the
website automatically sends an outgoing email to the administrator.
That is a transactional email.
And so we're not going to test that or set it up right now, but we'll do that later in the course.
But for now, let's go ahead and edit this, or it looks even just a little bit better.
One thing I'm noticing is that I have both labels and I have, you know, interior text here as well,
which really isn't needed.
It looks redundant to me.
Maybe we can tighten up these form fields a little bit and then also maybe edit the color and look of
this submit button as well, so that what we're looking at matches our design in 2022 and our customizations
just a little bit more.
And so let's go back into the dashboard and I'm going to go back away from the contact page and into
the fluent forms.
This time, I'm going to go to all forms and let's take a look at the form.
So contact form, contact, what do we use?
We used form number three.
These two, the contact form demo in the subscription form.
We're already in the plug in by default.
I think this is the one that we were creating here.
Let's just make sure we go and oops.
If I go to the page, you know, in the admin bar here, you can always click Edit Sight.
And actually, no, let me hit back.
It's not at its site, it's edit page.
And then that would go into the editing page for that.
So it's fluent for my ID equals three in the short code.
I just wanted to go in there in order to make sure I'm editing the right one.
And so if I go back again, let's just make sure this is no it says number three and the shortcut is
ID equals three.
So let's go to edit and the in the editor here.
There's a few different things.
This is for the form itself and for settings and integrations.
These are the form settings and the form layout gives us some options here.
Let's look, let's see the label alignment at the top.
You know?
We really maybe want to get rid of that label, so.
Hmm.
Let's see here what other options do we have?
OK, so if we go here?
The forms settings label alignment labels can be top left or right.
There's a help message.
There's an error message in case you know, you didn't fill out a required field or something and the
asterisk position, the asterisk labels the required elements.
And so let's just take a look at what this looks like.
You can hit back and look at that contact form.
So we've got the labels are above and the asterisk is to the right.
Sure.
Let's see how it message.
Wonder what happens if the label is to the left got back to the top, we can save settings.
Uh, yeah, that does look a little bit better, doesn't it?
These are for email subject and the message that it looks a little better.
It's tighten it up a little bit within this content area where the featured image is still.
There's little redundancy here.
That's something that we can.
That we can change these could also be to the right.
Let's check that out.
Just refresh the page that's justified to the right, I see.
So let's see.
Alignment alignment to the left looked the best, I think.
So just click save right there.
There's a few items that you'll see that are available only on the pro version of fluent forms, wherever
there's a mark here, say right here where it doesn't let you do it.
For example, a survey result, there's a pro version of version of fluent forms that we don't have
installed here in the sandbox.
But if we go back to you, ED, there might be some other options that we have here.
Input customization is where for the whichever label that we're whichever field, I should say that
we're editing, you can have some different input customization settings over here.
So for first name, last name, the name fields, we can have the label placement be hide the label.
That's what I was looking for before.
If we save that, let's just take a look at what that did.
I like that because it shows first name, last name inside the field.
Is that what we want?
Not sure.
Let's take a look at what other options we have there.
There's a field field label, whatever it is, there's advanced options.
It's the name attribute.
This is for submitting the form data.
So you really probably don't need to go to advanced options, but in the name fields.
So for first name, there's a label and then there's a placeholder.
And so you wonder what would look best.
I did like the look of having the label there, but then having no placeholder, potentially inside
the first and last name.
So let's do that.
Let's let's leave the label.
Let's take away the placeholder instead of hide label.
We'll say default and save form.
We're just editing the first and last name fields for now.
So let's see what that looks like.
First name, last name, email, subject and your message that looks like a nice form.
This is something that you can play around with, too.
So again, for the email address, the input customization, we have a label, but.
Let's see.
The placeholder.
Let's leave it, leave it blank, since we're using the label anyway.
This is required and this validates meaning if their email address is typed wrong and it's not an e-mail
address or has a space or something, it'll tell the person so we could save that you must do the same
for the subject, meaning we place the label by default.
But then let's take the field label or no?
Excuse me.
And do that, the placeholder.
We'll get rid of.
Say that and in the message, the same no placeholder in here.
So.
Select your message and hit back.
And then, of course, the size of the field here, we could have it be just a little bit smaller if
we want to to bring this button up a little, that might look nice.
So instead of four rows, we could bring it to three brings it up just a little bit.
Click Save Form and then the submit button.
Let's see.
Submit form, I think I'll just say.
Submit, or sometimes like to use the word send, and you could use the the default button or an image
if you had if you had an image URL, if you wanted to create a button.
Let's see.
There's some different button styles.
You could have different colors.
You know, a gray button is a little bit more matching.
I like the medium sized button.
And what do you think?
Do we want it to be centered or over on the left?
I do like it over on the left there since we have our two column layout.
And so it'll say it'll say send.
It'll be in the gray color medium to the left.
Let's save the form.
Now let's refresh and take a look.
Yeah, that match is just a little bit more first name, last name, email subject.
And your message now in the sandbox?
I do have outgoing email enabled, so this is a working form.
I'll talk about this a little bit later, but let's see.
Put my email in there.
Test message and then say hello and click Send.
This should show me a message.
Thanks for your message.
We'll get in touch with you shortly.
Now that message is editable, too, and also that form has disappeared, showing that we've already
submitted it.
And so, you know, you can go to settings and integrations and then thank you for your message.
We'll get in touch with you shortly without a period I might.
Just, you know.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Mary, thanks for your message.
With an exclamation point.
Sounds good to me.
You put anything you like there or like I said, send them to a page or even to an off site custom URL.
So refresh the page.
What will happen?
Show me the form again and looking great.
The last thing would be to add the navigation to this contact page into the header navigation.
Let's see if you can do that without messing up the layout and see if I can do it, and we'll do that
next.
Before we end this section of the course.
And so where would I do that?
That's an appearance editor.
Yeah, now if we go back into here, template parts and this header.
Go ahead and just go.
And now this this layout just messed up again, didn't it?
So we could see about fixing that later.
But if I wanted to add navigation that member, I would just put the plus sign and I could put the contact
in there as well and then click Save and save.
Let's see what happened.
All right, so it showed that, you know, a little bit different layout inside of the Block editor
here, but I'm happy to report that it did not mess up the layout.
So now we've got six different items in our in our header.
Now one thing is that this will convert into, you know, a few.
We just kind of drag this over to the left.
We can get the responsive design and see what it looks like past a certain point.
It turns into a little dropdown here where opening that up will show the mobile overlay menu instead
of the regular menu here.
At some point, you'll have to deal with that if you have too many items and it might overlap or not,
look quite right over here inside of the live website itself.
So to take a look at what your website would look like on different devices, you can just take your
edge of your browser and drag it back left and right.
Or you can use the dev tools by right clicking and clicking Inspect.
And now, you know, I've got the developer tools open on the right hand side here in the developer
tools.
You can change the settings so that they're docked at the bottom or or the side.
So here I've got the dock at the bottom, and so I'm looking at a full width inside of the recording
window here.
But one of the things that's great about the developer tools in Chrome or Firefox is you can open up
the device toolbar, which will let you drag the display window to, you know, different widths.
And so if I if I scroll up and look at the menu here as I drag this to a narrow and narrower and narrower
device like a, you know, iPad or tablet and vertical, as I get over closer to here, at some point
that menu is going to run into the the name of the site and you can see it drops down below.
That's not too bad.
It's usable.
But then at some breakpoint, this theme is set to change the menu from a menu that shows each item
over to a dropdown right here a toggle.
And so that opens up an overlay menu.
Then you can click the X and get out of it.
So even way down into this, whose phone is this narrow?
No one's well right here.
You would have an overlay menu and then you can click the X.
And so at this point, you know, if I was designing a website that was going to be a real life website,
I might limit the number of items I have in the navigation here or reduce the font size or the spacing
in some way so that I don't have the menu drop down below at some breakpoint.
That's just personal preference.
However, you'd like to do that, but one of the things about the dev tools is that it's great, is
it?
You can use this toggle the device toolbar so that you can look at different break points.
While you're designing a website, you can see what other parts of your website would look like as you
go down into mobile or tablet.
And so right down here, you can see that there's two column layout in 2020.
Two does go at some point from two columns into one column and stacks the information and the columns
instead.
So if somebody navigates to the website on a phone, for example, they'll have navigation here as an
overlay and then they can go down and it still looks great and is completely functional, including
the footer, the header and the content of the page.
No matter what size device they're using, so you can toggle that back off.
I do prefer to have my dev tools over on the right hand side, so I'm looking at the content over here
and I use it there, and then you can use the X to X out of it.
Great.