In this lesson, we'll finish creating the posts and pages needed to match the sample site and begin
editing the header template.
You'll had categories and tags for the blog posts at a site logo and explorer the list view in the Block
editor.
By the end of this video, you'll understand the power of the list view for navigating and selecting
the blocks within the design, and begin editing the site wide header template within the site editor.
OK.
Did you get it done?
If you look at my post's page here, you can see I've got my three posts.
One thing I just want to show you, I realized it didn't mention as we were creating the posts here.
When you add new, when you have your tag field here, if there's and say, you know, I was in here
like this when I was creating a new post, if I know that there's a tag I want to use and it already
exists, I just have to start typing it and it'll come up with that tag.
And when I click it, it will add that existing tag to the tag list of any given post.
And so I'm going to back out of here.
Of course, I didn't want to save any of those changes, and so my browser gives me a warning and I
can click leave so that I don't change anything.
And you can see the author name, the category and the tags and then the date and time published and
whether there's any comments in the columns here on the Post's page.
And so next, what is next?
Let's take a look at our site here.
Now, of course, this header and the blog posts in the footer are the home page, and that looks pretty
well finished to me compared to this one.
But let's look at the next page.
Of course, when we create these pages, we're going to have to add that to the header and we're going
to add this logo in here too.
And why don't we take care of this right now?
Next, I might go into here and we're going to have to go into the editor.
If you remember, this is called the site editor, not a page editor or a post editor.
And you can see there's a place holder here, a very faint dotted line so that you can put a logo in
there.
And I've gone over and used that logo.
Now, as I click around here, you could see that when I roll the mouse over different sections, there's
some different things happening here that are being highlighted.
And sometimes it's hard to know sort of where you are on a page or in the site editor.
And so that's what this list view is really good for.
I didn't show I showed you an empty list view before, but if you look here, these are nested pieces
of content or blocks that can be kind of hard to find, especially if they're overlapping.
For example, if you roll your math mouse between these two, there's a little bit of a space.
And if you hold your mouse there long enough, that will give you a plus sign so you could add a block
in between the two.
If you wanted to.
But if you go over here and roll your mouse over the different, if you click on the different list
items here, it will show you what you're looking at.
And so the header dark, small and actually you can go ahead and use these little down arrows to or
side arrows to open or close that.
And you can even go ahead and you can use the hand icon here to drag these down and reorder things even
within the list view.
And so that's just kind of a navigation lesson there.
But if I was looking at header dark small, I've got the header section right over here and within there.
There's a row and another row within that row, or you could see this row.
Here is this one at the top left as I roll the mouse.
You can see where the site title and that logo placeholder are surrounded by that blue line.
And now if you go down a little lower, you could see site logo.
So if I really wanted to target that, I could click here in the list view and it selects it for me.
Now let me click away, and if I go back up here, I can.
Also, if I click enough times, I can get to there from the regular content area too.
But sometimes it's easier in the list view to find things like that.
So I'm going to click the Add a site logo button here, and I know that this right here, the logo in
black is the one that I want, and because it matches the background color, it looks like just a little
white pair of binoculars there.
Isn't that right?
Yeah.
And this theme is set up so that that logo is clickable to the home page.
So if I go back here, I've made that change, so I want to go up here to the right and click Save.
And now this is a little different than saving a blog post this.
You can't turn this off.
It does want to make sure that you want to save what it wants to save here because I'm saving a sitewide
piece of content, the header, which is going to affect multiple pages of the website.
And so you want to make sure that you're doing the right thing.
So this is telling me that within the site, what I've changed is the icon and the logo that's going
to effect something on the entire site.
It says these changes will affect your whole site rate.
And then it says which template part am I, am I editing?
Yes, I'm editing the header template part, and that's usually going to be exactly what you want to
do.
And unless you're like splitting a certain template into multiple templates or splitting it into a different
page type, you might want to uncheck this at some points if you're doing something more advanced.
But for now, I'm just going to go ahead and click Save.
Then again, down at the bottom site updated.
That means that I can go over here to my new tab, where I have the site open hit refresh and now I
have that clickable logo right there to the home page.
Now over here, the menu isn't right, but I still don't have pages created to replace that.
If I look at the website here, hit the the logo and then go back to the dashboard, if I click pages
or click pages all pages, you can see that the only page I have is that sample page that comes with
WordPress.
And so let's go ahead and create all the pages that are necessary for this website.
One at a time.
This could be a good challenge for you if you open up the twenty to twenty twenty two dot WordPress
dot net.
You could create an about page and event page and a film page.
And that's probably the way I would do it.
I create all those pages and publish them just as empty pages for now.
And then I'll show you how I match the design that exists here in the demo site.
So you might pause the video and do that, and then I'll come back and show you how I do it.
So I'm first going to take the sample page and just stick it in the trash and then just so you know,
when you put something in the trash, it still exists in case you need to reverse that.
And I'm just going to leave that.
But if you do, click the Trash tab up here at the top, you can restore that page to the Pages list,
or you could click empty trash.
Now, this would delete it permanently.
All right, so I'm not going to do that right now.
I'll just go back to old old pages.
There's no pages here, but I'm going to create those three pages about event and film.
And so just quickly, I'll add new.
I guess it doesn't matter what order about Publish can see, it publishes it right away because I I
uncheck that box to do the pre checks.
And so then I'll hit, you know, back to the pages list.
Add new.
Next one is events.
Or is it event?
Yeah, it's just events singular.
Published that one.
Back to the dashboard from there.
One more.
Add new and this one is film.
It's going to be an interesting one to create, as you saw the there's a block pattern that gives us
that layout inside of 20 22, which is interesting.
And so hey, now your challenge is to go through and recreate these three pages looking through the
block patterns and see what you can find that would match first the about page here.
And then secondly, the event page, which goes back to white and has this layout.
And then the film page, which has no header, a different background color and also a different background
color on the footer.
Hint, hint.
So see if you can accomplish that and we'll see how you get on.
And when we come back, I'll show you how I've done it.