In this lesson, we'll look at Flywheel managed hosting and discuss what business models are most appropriate
for its pricing and services.
You'll see how to sign up and set up a site with SSTL using a temporary domain and some of the features
and benefits that come with a managed WordPress host.
By the end of this video, you'll understand why some situations are best served with a managed WordPress
hosting plan and get an idea whether Flywheel would work for you.
Let's talk about managed WordPress hosting and tours the Get Flywheel dot com website, as well as my
area at Flywheel, where I've lost a client sites and my own sites before.
So we've used Flywheel just a little bit in this course to create and make a 60 day demo site with Flywheel
in order to play with the cadence, theme and cadence blocks free versions.
And so you're a little bit familiar, potentially with Flywheel already, but let's just tour around
a little bit.
One of the things that I that I love about Flywheel is that they're one of the only managed companies
that offers a plan for a single site that's less than twenty five dollars a month.
And so the tiny is a great place to start.
If you do want to go with managed WordPress hosting, which takes care of a lot of things for you and
can make sure that you have a high speed, high performant website for your visitors.
When you start out, if you are going to have 10 or more sites or even up to 10, starting with freelance
is a great way to go because you can get your sites down to under $10 per month per site, something
which you should be charging at least $25 a month, if not 50 or $100 a month per site for when you're
when you're hosting client sites.
And so I'll just click the login button and go ahead and log into my own site control panel at flywheel
hosting and we'll take a look around.
So here are my dashboard page.
I'm logged in to Flywheel, and I have my one site here, which is a demo site setup, and you can see
that I have 14 days left.
I just created this demo site.
This is at my old flywheel account where I used to host client sites and my own, and I've since moved
to grid pain and using self-managed hosting.
We'll talk about that in a different part of the course, but for now, let's take a look.
If you did sign up with Flywheel through the link on the resources page, then you likely have a 60
day time period to play with your demo site at Flight Flywheel.
And I should also let you know that if you let that expire, or if you delete that site and then renew
and build a new demo site for free, of course, you still get 60 day periods on all of your demo sites
that you set up, so you can keep practicing with flywheel in a live environment that's really, really
fast.
And so for for building this site, you know, it took just a couple of minutes for it to set up.
And now let's just look at the control panel a little bit again.
Managed WordPress eliminates the need for a few things like using caching plugins, separate like site
ground uses or a lot of hosts.
Recommend you use WP Rocket, which is a good caching plugin, but a lot of the things that managed
WordPress Web's WordPress hosting does for you is taking care of those types of things at the server
level, which makes your websites either even higher performance because at a server level, things
happen before the traffic hits your web site instead of after.
And so security plug ins is one of those things where Flywheel recommends that you do not install any
endpoint security plugins like Word Fence or I themes security plugins.
Those are endpoint security plugins that manage security on your website if needed, and they're great
plug ins.
However, everything there happens after the person or the attacker hits your website or your login
page, and so manage WordPress.
Hosting and self-managed lets you take care of those things and also website caching, security and
caching at the server level, which is much, much better for high speed and more secure website hosting.
And so on this managed website control panel screen, there's a few tabs across the top could see that
I'm using a temporary domain that I chose, which is a subdomain of flywheels sites dot com.
It also says that the DNS is pointed so it it is working.
In fact, if I go over to WP admin, I will be able to log in to the site.
Over at, you know, in in my browser right here now, of course, because it's a demo site, it sets
up HTTP authentication, which means I've got to put in a username and password in order to navigate
to anywhere on the website, even the front end, but especially to the WP admin WordPress dashboard.
And so I'll just cancel that.
It'll give me the privacy mode indicator and tell me that I need a password.
So if I just look down here on the right hand side for this particular one flywheel and then Fortunate
Glove with let's see, that's I use flywheel and it gives me a password that's easy to remember with
a hyphen.
And then so every time you visit, it needs to authenticate you as kind of a password protection, so
both, you know, Google and the search engine bots or visitors can't find your site and so that won't
be listed in the Google directory or anything while you're working on it.
Now I'm getting a browser message here, and this is because this site is not at HTP, but it's an excuse
me, it's not secure, it's not an HDTV s, but it's at HTTP.
And so it's saying I'm submitting information and you could say, go back.
But I know where we are here.
I'm at my own web site.
I'm setting up at Flywheel, so I'm going to click Send anyway.
And now that's taking me to the WordPress dashboard login page, and I chose my username and password
when I set up this site.
That's something that you would want to remember for each and every one of your WordPress sites.
And so let's change something, though let's this does not secure.
Which means that any information like a like a username, a password that you pass back and forth or
in the future, any content of a contact form or an email address that you might pass for signing up
for an email list or anything like that is not encrypted.
And so if it's intercepted on the way, it can actually be read.
And so it's a it's a best practice that you use HTTPS on all your life websites.
Make sure you're doing that.
Flywheel makes it easy right here under the domain, under the Overview tab.
You can just click Enable SSL.
What this is doing, similar to what we saw at ground, is that it's installing a Let's Encrypt free
SSL certificate, which can and does encrypt any information sent from the user's browser to the website
and from the website to the user's browser.
So I get this message your SSL has been enabled.
It says that it's got the little green lock symbol.
That's great.
Now, if I refresh the page here, you can.
Now it's it's not showing me.
That's just because it's a cached page, potentially.
But let's see if I go back to WP admin.
Oh, good.
There we go.
And you can see that I have the lock symbol now, and it says that this connection is secure.
So anything passwords, credit card numbers even is private and cannot be unencrypted when it's in transit,
going back and forth.
So I just have a fresh WordPress installation here that I can now play with at a secure SSL with my
address, which is a temporary domain at WordPress.
And so if we go right click Visit Site, this is just going to be the default 2022 theme with a single
blog post on the home page, and I can play with WordPress over here easily in my flywheel hosting account.
But let's take a look a little bit deeper into the managed WordPress hosting and what the advantages
are here.
One of the things that we have are plug ins in the Plugins tab.
You can in this control panel, it will detect what plugins are activated on the site, and you can
actually let them auto update for a small fee if you like.
Not something that I do, but again, this is a done for you type of hosting scenario, and you can
have them keep your plugins updated at the server level from here, if you like.
And then there's a performance tab.
Again, another adding performance insights to your website is something that Flywheel can charge you
for if you like your stats for visitors.
Visitors to the website, et cetera, are right here.
Automated backups is a very powerful, automated backups and backups trimming system where there's restoring
all backups performed all day, every day.
And so if there's any issue at any time, you can use your backup system here.
And then under advanced, we have just a few different things that you may use down here, like flushing
the cache.
If when you're using a caching system, sometimes when you update your website, the browser shows you
an old version of the page because it has it's it's it's being served from the cache.
And so sometimes you want to manually refresh your cache.
There's a login attempts.
This is part of the flywheel security system.
You can reset the login attempts.
And so, you know, if you fail too many times and you can set this inside of your settings, you,
you might get locked out.
Or if?
Course, you want any kind of hacking attempt to be locked out if they're attempting to address or access
your login page one after the other.
You can eat up your resources in your web site.
And so but if you get locked out, you can reset your own attempts so that you can get back in.
You can export the logs from here and then, you know, there's some site options you can disable caching
at the time when you're developing the site.
That makes some sense from what I just mentioned up here.
You can clear the cache manually, but you can actually disable the caching while you're developing
a website, which makes it easier to see your changes instantly without running into that caching issue
at all.
And so there's a few other things that you can set down here.
The IP version, the the database prefix is something that is customized here so that you're not using
just the standard WP underscore for each database, table and database.
Part of your database that manages your WordPress website, but you have a random string right here
and you can change the database prefix right here easily, which makes it easy to do a security item,
which is to change your database prefix.
That's something that I do very often.
But if you suspected any hacking attempts, you could go ahead and do that.
And then similar to phpMyAdmin in the site ground site tools.
This is a proprietary and customized database manager that you can use.
And so this is the database.
And then there's import and export.
And if you were doing some site migrations, you have 100 percent access to your database.
These are all the database tables.
So, for example, under users, you know, this is something that will play with when we look at files
and database details in a WordPress website a little bit later in the course.
But for example, I can look at my user here, I can edit this.
And for example, it's not usually possible to change the username, which is called user log in in
the database.
That is a that is a permanent thing in WordPress in your profile page, but you can change it in the
database if you wanted to manually change the password, for example.
Yeah.
Of course, this wasn't my password.
I used a password that was memorable to me, but this is an encrypted version of the password that is
using it using the MD5 hashing method.
And so if you do change the password in the database, for example, if you couldn't get into your WP
admin WordPress dashboard and you wanted to change your own password at your hosting company here,
you could access that and you would want to select empty five.
And then, you know, type of password that you'll remember or paste, one that you can remember and
then use the MD5 dropdown here and click Save.
That's how you can do that, but it is easy to manage your entire database here using their database
manager.
And so that makes it easy.
You know, you can go I can go back to advanced using these breadcrumbs right here and then if I click
sites, that'll give me a flywheel dashboard, which will give me a list of my websites that I'm hosting
here.
I often use it used the freelance bulk website hosting plan to get my client websites under $10 a month
per site, with everything done for me in Flywheel here.
One of the things to note, and it's something that I mentioned when we were talking about WordPress
hosting in general, is that it's a best practice that you don't host your email at the same place as
your website and that you also don't host or register your domain names at the same place.
Flywheel and many of the WordPress managed hosting companies for this reason, because they're more
advanced and more in line with best practices these days and into the future, they don't even provide
email hosting, and they also don't provide domain registration.
It's not their level and their zone of expertise.
And so if you want to have email addresses, you've got to go to email hosting like Safe with Google
Workspace or with Rackspace or another email hosting provider and connected here.
And so this is strictly for your website, and that gives you a nice little tour of of flywheel.
Manage WordPress hosting a few other little things.
You can have organizations if you have different people that need to access certain websites or different
levels of access of your websites that you're hosting.
You can manage different people in your team or in your business.
Blueprints are a really powerful way of having a standardized word.
Press installation that has potentially the general themes and plugins that you always use on all websites
and have them prebuilt for you so that when you create a new WordPress website, it installs everything
for you.
OK?
And then there's some add ons and then get help.
There is great support for both WordPress itself and for your hosting plan available 24-7 at managed
WordPress hosts like Flywheel.
And so that's great.
That gives you an idea of everything within the Get Flywheel XCOM control panel here.
And a good idea of what managed hosting is and the kinds of things that you would use it for.