In this lesson, we'll migrate a live website behind the scenes using a staging area at grid pain and
only pointing the domain to the new site.
Once the site migration is complete, you'll learn how the WP Migrate DB Pro plug in works requiring
two live URLs to migrate between and how you can manage the DNS so that the original site stays up while
the migration is taking place.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how to migrate a site without any downtime by strategically
managing the domains DNS.
This next migration project I want to show you is a real life web site that I'm migrating from my site
ground account over to grid pain.
And so I've already started the process of migrating because there are email addresses involved and
I do have the DNS and the domain name registered and the DNS using Cloudflare.
And so I have easy to change Cloudflare DNS records that I can use that have almost instant change because
Cloudflare so closely connected to the internet and fast.
And so you can see the DNS records here for right now, there's an AA record for the domain name, and
it goes to this 35 dot to await IP address.
So I'll show you over at my site ground account.
Here's Elevate Animal Rehab dot com and there's the site IP 35 Dot two 08.
And so what I want to do is a no downtime migration of the website, so it's seamless for any visitors
and that website will be migrated over and then they can change the DNS once the website is live.
And I'm going to use a great migration plugin called WP Migrate DB Pro by the company Delicious Brains,
and there is a free version at the WordPress.org repository that migrates just the database.
And it's the same company that makes that better.
Search and replace plug in that we used in a previous lesson for changing the database right from the
WordPress dashboard.
But this is a database migration plug in and the paid version.
The pro version of WP Migrate DB Pro allows you to do seamless migrations, including all the files
for the website, as well as the database, including the media and the plugins and themes folders.
And so I'm going to migrate from site ground over here to grid pain.
For now, I'll just show you that I do have the email already moved over to Rackspace email hosting,
and in the next section of the course, we'll talk about the different types of email and email hosting.
But for now, just take note that I have the a record pointing at the site ground website.
And so when we navigate to the real website, this website is hosted at site ground at that IP address.
So the first thing I've done is I've gone into the website itself and under plug ins, I've installed
and activated the WP Migrate DB Pro plug in and the two associated plug ins in my pro licence, the
media files and the theme and plug in files plugins.
What that does is it gives me an opportunity to go into tools in this website and under the Migrate
DB Pro settings.
I'm going to look under settings right here and I want to give permissions from this website to go ahead
and push what this website to another website that I have hosted elsewhere, which I'll be setting up
on this in this lesson with grid pain.
I want a pull request.
I want to process requests to pull data from this install.
Copying it elsewhere.
And so I'm going to go ahead and turn on the pull permissions.
And I've already put my license key in here.
And so that allows me to use the other two plugins.
And so those that's all the settings I need to make at the origin website right now.
Now I'm going to go ahead and I've already put in the web address and, you know, auto create the system
user, and I just wanted to show you that I'm going to click the advanced options checkbox next to staging
site.
And because the way that WP Migrate DB Pro works is it works on domain names.
And so it works between two live sites that exist at two different domain names.
And because we are moving this website from one domain name Elevate Animal Rehab dot com to the same
domain name, Elevate Animal Rehab.
What we have to do is bring it into a staging environment, which is at a subdomain in great pain,
so it will be staging Dot Elevate, Animal Rehab, Dakar.
And what I'll do once I create that, I'll allow this site to be built now on the server and what I'll
do after that site is live, I'll take.
And make a DNS record for that staging subdomain.
And I'll point it at the IP address for the grid pain server.
And so as that creates right here, I know that this is the IP address right here.
And so I could just start by copying that IP address and going over to the DNS records.
What I need to do is over here in the Cloudflare DNS is actually create another a record which is going
to put the sub domain and point it to the new IP address, while the regular Elevate Animal Rehab dot
com domain name points to the site ground address.
While we make these changes and the site migration, pure staging, dot elevate, animal rehab dot com.
And I know that it's at that original IP address for the server.
Now, if I just go and click the single sign on button since I created the DNS record for staging Dot
Elevate Animal Rehab dot com that will open a subdomain and open another tab in my browser at staging
data, a little elevate animal rehab dot com.
And that's just a an empty and freshly installed WordPress site.
If we go to visit site, I'll right click and open that in a new tab.
You can see that it's just a regular empty WordPress site under appearance themes.
There's just the twenty two theme is activated, and there's another couple default themes from WordPress
here.
So now all I need to do is go under plug ins and add new.
And now remember, we're working in the staging environment here, and so the real website is not being
affected at all at the Elevate Animal Rehab dot com site.
This is still over at site ground and so under here or under ad plugins, I'm going to go ahead and
upload the three plugins that I showed you that I had on the original site, the WP Migrate DB Pro,
and I'll pass the video while I go ahead and do that and enter my license key again.
So now I've got all three plug ins, the WP Migrant DV Pro, the media files and the themin plugin files
plugins activated and I've ended my license key as well.
So if I go over here under settings or is it tools under Migrate DB Pro, I can go to Settings.
And now for this new site at the staging environment, I want to give permissions to push overwriting
the data on this install.
So here's where it describes that process.
It's the opposite as the other site, which is the origin site process requests to push data to this
install, overwriting its data.
So a click push and now that that saved, I'm ready to begin the migration process and so on the staging
site here if I click Migrate and what I want to do is I want to replace this site with another site,
I'm going to go and ahead and click pull.
I want to replace this site at staging with the other site.
And so it's asking me for on the remote site.
There's a site URL and secret key that is provided in the other plug in on that on the origin site.
So I'm going to go back over here to elevate animal rehab dot com and under the connection info under
settings.
Here's where I have the connection info, so that's all I need.
I just click copy to copy to the clipboard and then I'll go back over to the staging environment here
and paste that right here.
And now it's establishing a connection.
And since it's done that successfully, I can move down and select what I'd like to do.
And so I want to pull.
Basically, I want to pull everything.
I'm just going to use all the default settings.
It's going to do a standard find and replace because it's going to go into the database and it's going
to replace the Elevate domain with this staging dot elevate domain and the same thing here, it will
find the actual server location and then replace it with the server location of the new server at grid
pane here.
You can see that these are different structures, and so I don't have to customize anything here.
And I do want to turn on and bring all the media files, and I also want to turn on the theme files
and can bring all the themes across.
Or I could just pull only the active themes, which I'm using Devi on that site.
So I'm going to go ahead and do that.
I don't need all these extra themes from the origin site, and I also want to pull the plug in files
and there is one plug in that I don't have to do, and that is the site ground optimizer plug in.
That's not something that I need over at Grid Plant.
And so I'm going to uncheck Site Ground Optimizer and check the email encoder plugin that I have activated
over there.
Now all I have to do is click pull, and it's going to give me messages as it goes and pulls the site
across.
It'll tell me what it's doing at each stage.
It's bringing the database tables across and it's going to go ahead and bring the media files and the
theme files and then the plugin files.
OK, well, it only took a couple more seconds and it gave me a success message and as normal, it's
forcing me to log in again under a different username.
Now, because we've migrated the entire site from the regular domain name over to the staging domain
at a different place, now I need to use the login details that I have over it grid pane.
Now I just need to go to staging that elevate animal rehab dot com and click the little single sign
on button with the little W.
And that will sign me in with whatever secure password that it had created for me and grid pain when
I set up the site.
And so now it looks like I'm at staging and it's now the site titles changed, and so it looks like
everything is working.
Let's go ahead and open the site itself in another tab and I can take a look.
And it looks like all the images have come across the home page here, and there's an easy contact page.
Great.
All right.
Everything seems to be working.
And so now I have an exact copy of the original site at Elevate Animal Rehab dot com over at Staging
Dot, Elevate Animal Rehab dot com.
And now that I can see that everything is working correctly, let's just look at the Elevate website.
Ingrid Payne And while I'm here, let's look at the domains and there is an SSL certificate active for
live animal rehab.
And so that's looking good when I bring it to the live site, that's going to be working.
So before I change the DNS, if I point this domain over to the new IP address, I haven't pushed the
staging site over to the live site yet.
And so that's the last step that I have to do before I change the DNS records.
So I'll go over to staging here.
And go down to elevate animal rehab.
And then what I want to do is take the staging and take it to the live side, and the push type I want
is all files and the complete database can leave this as the default and I'll click push staging to
life.
And now what I'll do is make a check to make sure that the staging environment is using all the same
settings as the live environment.
So there's nothing different.
And then I can just click push staging to life.
So it's giving me a little green staging push started depending on the size of the site.
This can take a little bit of time now.
This is quite a small site, so it should take only a few seconds really to push it onto the live environment.
Give me a whole bunch of periodic messages to tell me how things are going, and I can also look at
the log files in great pain to see how things are going here.
Live success, everything cleaned up and I've got as I close these messages over here, I've got the
green bar that says staging push completed.
And now I know that this exact copy that I had over at staging is now live at the real server over here
at grid pain.
And so I could just go over to sites.
When I look at live animal rehab down here, I could see that it's at this IP address.
Now, I'm just copying that IP address to my clipboard.
I can go over here to Cloudflare.
And if I just go to the a record and I'll edit that a record now, I'm just going to go ahead and paste
it right into there and click Save.
And now that should be totally done, and now I have a live say at the new at the original domain name.
And I know that it's hosted in the new place so I can turn off my hosting site ground here.
I know that in the DNS, I'm pointing everything to the IP address is reflected in my grid pain account
for the server and everything is looking good.
Awesome.
Little more complex of a migration.
But oftentimes you need to figure out ways to solve problems depending on what you're trying to do in
your migration.