In this lesson will assign a custom CSI ID to a section and use that as a navigation tag attached to
a button.
You'll learn how TV allows for custom CSI IDs in the advanced tab of a module, and also how using overlapping
images can create a unique scrolling visual effect.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how DV provides the tools for both intuitive user experience
and beautiful design using transparent images and parallax.
Let's do a couple more customizations to this layout pack dealing with just a couple of really neat
effects that happen in this travel agency layout pack from DV.
First of all, we've done this using different theme in the past, but looking at the Learn More button,
if we look at the link for that, where could that go with that?
Go to the about page or something.
What if we made on this home page that learn more button?
Just go ahead and scroll down past the image gallery and end up down here at this section right here?
Could you figure out how to do that yourself using anchor tags?
That's something that would be a nice challenge for you to try out right now.
And if you'd like, pause the video and see if you can figure out how to make this, learn more button.
Scroll the user down to this Discover Unlimited beauty section.
How'd that go?
Well, let me show you how I might go about it, so we're on the home page here.
And of course, I've showed you before with the Disney Visual Builder.
Instead of going back to the WordPress dashboard, I'll often just edit sections of the content at looking
at the main website and using this Enable Visual Builder button.
And so I've just clicked Enable Visual Builder, and as you can see, I've got my control controls down
here.
The first thing I'll do is just label this section, so I'll go ahead and click the gear icon.
And then under advanced and under CC ID and classes, we want to add a CSI ID.
And so, you know, I'm just going to call it LearnDash more just so that it's easy to remember and
click save on that.
And then as we go up here, there's a module right here and this is where the button is.
And so here's an example of where we have an overlapping header that's transparent.
And because of it, I can't really get to this module editing editing bar.
You could see that gray bar right up there that I'm trying to get to now.
Every time I try to pull the mouse up to that gear icon, I can't click it.
And so it's preventing me from clicking into editing this module where I want to add that little piece
of learn more CSC so that this button will scroll the user down down to here.
So if you remember, you could use two different things to get to that module.
Let's show you both here at the bottom and on the page editing area.
The first thing what I will usually do is I know that this is at the very top.
It should be easy to find.
So I'll just go to the wireframe view here.
And when I click the Wireframe View now, I've got a representation of all the nested sections, rows
and modules so that I can find what I need to.
So at the very top, of course, I have the hero section.
It's a gray module so I can click this gear icon now.
Don't forget, the second way to do it would be to look at the layers view right here, and that can
open up.
And while you're actually looking at the, you know, desktop view here, you could look at this layers
panel and open up the Hero Section module right here.
And so either way, works.
I'll often go to the wire frame and then click the gear icon here.
Opening it up and what I want to do is find that button.
So the button number one is right here, and as I scroll down, I can go to link.
And because this is a full width header, it gives me different areas to put items.
So as far as text, there's a title, a subtitle, a button one and a button two and a body text area.
And then as far as images, there aren't any images in this full width header, but the images would
be images that sit on top of the background image.
Because if I look at content here and look at the background, there's there's a background color that
is transparent.
And then there's a background image here, and that's the image that that I that this looks like.
And, you know, while we're here, we might as well brighten that up.
I really can't see that beautiful mountain scene and you could see what it looks like right here.
So how do we brighten up that image?
Well, we could go to overlay and look at the background overlay color, and you could see that's a
point eight six of transparency.
But if we just bring this transparency slider back down, we can maybe brighten that up just enough
so that it's a little more visible.
But the white lettering is still visible.
Maybe point five?
That looks great.
OK, so back to content.
We just go to the text in this for with header module and then button.
No one says Learn more down here under link.
We could say button number one, link URL and what we would do is use the hashtag or no sign button
to indicate that this is a seaside.
And then we would type in the ID that we chose for that section.
Below it was LearnDash more so click the save button here and then over here, if you find that it has
an exit at one point, that just means that it is doing an auto save.
The DV visual builder doesn't auto save once every few seconds, it seems like, maybe even once every
10 seconds.
And so you just have to wait for that to complete until you have a save visible and then you can go
ahead and save it and you'll see the progress icon and then the checkmark showing you that you've saved
your changes right there.
So now if we exit the visual builder, it brings us right back to the live web site and we can click
Learn more.
You could see the URL down here at the bottom left in.
From when you roll over a button or link, it says the URL and then slash no sign.
Learn more.
When I click that, it scrolls down smoothly to the next section that I had to find.
So that's awesome.
That's a really nice way to have a button from a header image or a full width header or a heroes section
at the top of a page.
Scroll down to a section.
And so it's easy to do in Divij because of those advanced CSX access sections that you have there in
the module editor.
And so next, let's take a look at some of these interesting images.
There's two places here in the travel agency layout pack that have some interesting parallax overlapping
images.
Can you see how the front image with the people is overlapping the background?
And as I slide the scroll bar up and down, you can see it makes it into kind of a 3D action called
parallax.
And that's something that's included in the divvy design elements.
And it's also visible on the about page.
If we look at the about page in the hero image here, you could see that guy standing on the hill is
sliding up and over the background parallax.
And that effect is really interesting.
It's a nice visual effect, if not overused.
It's a really nice look.
So let's see how they did that.
And at the after we do that to on the home page and several of the pages, well, that has let's see,
I didn't click on here that shows at the bottom of the page with a call to action button, as well as
the page ending with this parallax finish.
Now we can get rid of this footer with these widgets.
Anyway, this is the old style footer and the footer bar by placing this section as a global footer
on the entire website.
And so let's go ahead and take a look at this layout first and then place this area as a global footer
in the theme builder.
And so what we'll do first is just take a look at the visual builder on the home page here.
And I just scroll down to the bottom and take a look at what is going on here, so here's what I have.
Let's see you can as we roll the mouse over.
Yeah, I've got a section that goes to the bottom here, and there's also a row that goes to the bottom
here, and it looks like a single column row.
If I click the columns chooser, you can see that it's a single column here and let's just see what
we have for background images.
So in the section, first of all, which, as you know, is behind the row, the section background
has a doesn't have a color, but it does have a an image.
And that image is just a blurred background image.
And it says use parallel parallax effect.
Yes.
And what type of parallax effect a true parallax or a CC parallax?
The difference is a true parallax actually moves.
It moves up and down slower than the content that is in front of it, and a CC parallax is a just completely
fixed background.
And so they work differently.
You can experiment and see what kind of a parallax you would want to use and what works for what you're
trying to do as far as the two different things.
If you use no parallax, then you can still have a sliding image.
If this front image had parallax and it would slide over the next one.
You see, now that these are lined up with each other and there is no parallax effect, it just looks
like a single image.
That's because both of them have no parallax.
And so I'll just put it back to what it was true parallax.
And then let's look at what the section.
Excuse me what the row looks like as far as the background.
Now on this background, it looks like we again don't have a color, but we do have a gradient and it's
a very faint gradient.
You can see there's just kind of echoes from white down to transparent, and you could see that it just
it's very faint, but you can see it's happening right at the top of this representation square right
here.
So the direction is 180 degrees that's up and down and the end position, it starts zero percent at
the very top and it ends at twenty two percent, not very far down the page or down the image itself.
And so basically, that's blending this image into the white background of the section above.
And so by looking, I could see that the background image is not present here.
Well, where's the background image?
It's in the column, I'll bet.
And so that column, as a part of this row has a background image.
No, no, it doesn't.
Now where's that background image?
I know where it is.
It must be in the module and not actually in the row.
And so inside this single column is an image module.
So let's close the row layout and let's look at this module.
Now here it is.
Here's the module, which is an image module.
There's that image, right?
It's just an image module that most likely does not.
It doesn't have a background, so it doesn't have a parallax or anything going on with it.
All it isn't is an image.
But you can see that the background is showing through.
Now this takes a little bit of graphic design, and you might just take a look in the media library
at this image.
And actually let me just close out of that and go to the WordPress dashboard and look in the media library.
Let's find that image.
Here it is.
Right here and now is shown just like in Photoshop and other design programs.
The gray and white checkerboard pattern denotes a transparency.
And so this is a PMG file, a transparent image.
And so using Photoshop, we're using --, which is a free Photoshop type program, or Canva is a great,
free program that does this type of thing easily.
You can erase the background and then use a file type that supports transparency, which PMG is one
of.
So dot PNG.
It's not a JPEG like this would be, but you convert this to a transparent PNG file using Photoshop
or Canva, and then you can use this to let the background show through.
And while that background was a parallax image, that's what gives us that interesting effect.
And so you just use these two images on top of each other, and we've got this interesting effect.
So let's do two more things.
Let's remove this widget area.
And actually, we don't really even have to do anything when we take this section here.
This there's actually this bottom section, including these different modules.
There's a text module, there's a button module, and then there's the image module showing those are
all contained within the row, which is contained within this section right here.
And so like we did in the last chapter, DV Part one, let's go ahead and save this whole section into
the div library so we can use it elsewhere.
OK.
And so once we use this in the theme builder as a global footer that will just replace the digitized
footer that's present right now in that grey bar and the bottom bar as well.
So I'm going to say this is the footer, I'm just going to call it, let's just call it parallax footer
and you can call it anything you want.
You can even have a space in the layout name that's just for your reference.
And then I'm not going to click make this a global item because we're going to control that within the
theme builder itself, whether it's globally controlled or not.
And so let's just click Save to library, and that finishes that part.
We can exit the visual builder here.
Sure, I can save and exit just in case I had made any changes, but I didn't, so I could have said
this card on that one.
And now what we'll do is bring that layout.
That was a section that we exported into the DV library and place it in the theme builder.