In this lesson will activate and configure the forms plug in for the contact page on the small business
design using the Frost theme.
You'll get to know the forms plug in a little better as you change the styling to match and see how
the form takes on the style of the theme.
By the end of this video, you'll be more familiar with embedding and configuring a contact form, including
the submit button itself.
Now, let's take a look at what else we might be able to do here if we click the Get Started button,
which goes to a contact page, it says Contact us, fill out the form and we'll be in touch shortly.
Well, here's a good challenge for you.
Go ahead and activate the forms, plug in and create a contact form and inserted here and style it as
you like.
So if you'd like, pause the video now, create a contact form for the contact page and see what you
can do there.
And when we come back, I'll show you how I do that.
All right.
If I go back to the dashboard first, I'm just going to click back to the dashboard and go to plug ins
on this site.
And go ahead and activate the fluent forms plug in, just like we did with the twenty twenty two theme.
And now under fluent forms, let's go to all forms.
There's a contact form demo already created as we saw before any subscription form already created.
This would be for an opt in like we we didn't set up, but there's a space for it in the twenty 2022
theme isn't there?
So what I'll do is edit this contact form and then inserted into that contact page.
And so if I want to change the name, let's just click up here and I'll call a contact form instead
of contact form demo and click Rename.
And then we've seen this before in the last section, but let's just insert it as is and see what it
looks like.
You remember how to do that?
Click the shortcode up here to copy it.
Also, if you click all forms, the shortcode is also available over here.
Let's go back right here.
So if you click to copy the shortcode, it'll be right there.
And so let's go to pages all pages and you remember what the contact us page is like.
Let's click contact us.
And now this site, it says, doesn't include support for the Ninja Forms Form block.
So that was brought in with the import when we imported the content from Frost WP Gqom and so we can
just select that block and remove that block.
And so what do we have the title of the page and then fill out the form and we'll be in touch shortly?
Sure, you can add a block.
You remember what kind of block we need to shortcode.
So I'm just going to paste that shortcut in there and click Update.
And then let's take a look at it.
All right, that's looking pretty nice, nice and fancy now on this site.
There's a few differences in design.
I can see the buttons, of course, looking different.
But one thing that's great about fluent forms and some other forms plug ins is that the text it's using
is able to be styled by the theme itself.
And the same was true of 2022.
But if you look, this is the same font that we're using in other places in the site, even though it's
a part of the forms plug in now, the button itself has been styled by the form.
And so let's go ahead and fix that and maybe make this look a little bit better.
You may have done that yourself, but I think what I might do is see, go back and let's go into forms.
All forms.
Let's see, I'll edit this.
And let's look.
So each one of these fields.
Let's look at the settings, first of all.
But for the form lap, let's see for the labels.
Think maybe what I want to do.
I do like these bold headers here, and so I might just take out all the placeholder text.
We did that before in the in the last section.
Let's see the help message, the error message, the asterisk.
Oh, looks pretty good right there.
So I'm going to go straight to the editor then and begin editing these things in here, so under the
name for the first name, I'm going to remove the placeholder.
I can probably just do this.
All at once without having to save it every single time.
So, oh, you know what, I didn't do the last name that I can see it reflected here.
So I'll do the do the last name, remove the placeholder.
OK.
So, yeah, there we go.
Uh, those are the name fields.
Let's go to the email address field.
Take out the placeholder again subject.
Remove the placeholder message.
Your message placeholder?
And let's take a look at the button.
I think what I need is something.
Let's take a look at what happens when I click no style.
I believe that I'll let the theme itself style the button and I think maybe a little bit larger since
this is such a wide open theme with a lot of white space.
And I'll leave it at the left side.
Let's click Save Form.
Go back and refresh.
OK, so new style that looks pretty good, really, it's got kind of a gray.
It doesn't have any rollover effects, though.
Yeah, that looks quite nice, though.
Let me go back.
I think what I'd like to do is style the button a little differently.
I'll just try.
Let's try Gray.
Large.
Yeah, I think that's going to give us a nice rollover effect.
Yeah, that looks nice.
All right.
You could do it however you like, but that does look nice, doesn't it?
That's a nice contact us form and it is ready to go.