In this lesson, I'll show you how to set up an Amazon AWB account and verify a domain to be used with
transactional email through the Amazon Simple Email Service.
You'll learn how to set up the free fluent SMTP plug in to connect Amazon six with a WordPress website
to take advantage of the low pricing and high quota levels available for outgoing email with ease.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how to set up fluent SMTP, verify a domain with Amazon
six and apply to get your Amazon account approved and out of the sandbox mode.
It starts with Let's go over how to set up Amazon simple email service as a transactional email provider
for your WordPress website and for client sites.
So what I've done is click sign in to the console and you know, here's where you would go just to get
your free WC developer account first.
And then you'll have to set up billing information to get that very small billing amount for any transactional
emails that get sent from you or your clients websites.
I tend to sign up all my clients under my account and go ahead and pay for those transactional emails
that they use out of my website care and hosting programs.
Just I bundle it in.
And so if you sign up for that and then I've got one of my identities here, verified open, you could
see that I've got.
The summary is the this domain is verified and I have the DKIM successful, which is something that
you do by placing more DNS records here for me in Cloudflare under the domain names in your DNS provider.
And so these sea names right here, this one, there's actually three sea name records that you place
in order and one text record in order to verify your domain ownership with Amazon and make sure that
this is successful and you can use the IP address then.
Now, let's talk about the plug in that I recommend using.
Here is at WordPress.org is the free plug in fluent SMTP.
Of course, it's got a longer name WordPress Mail, SMTP, and for all these different providers, it
certainly works and there's a description right here.
But you can install this plug in directly through your WordPress website, and once it is installed
and activated, you can go over in your WordPress website to settings and click Fluent SMTP, and then
you can begin to set up an active email connection.
And so when I've already got one set up, so we're just going to tour how this works and how this setup
works.
You can see the fluent SMTP works with all these different providers or even another one that's not
on this list.
If you click other SMTP and you just all you do is set up a few settings here and fluent SMTP will walk
you through getting this set up.
There is a little bit of setup needed with Amazon, and I'll walk you through that a little bit and
how to find that information.
But what you do is you get your access keys, a secret access key or an access key ID and then a secret
access key that you place either in the database using a form right here in the WordPress website's
settings.
Or you can copy and paste this piece of code and replace these asterisks with your kid and your secret
access key.
Then Amazon gives you inside of the WP config file, which is just a little bit more secure of a way
to put in the access keys to your Amazon account.
And then it's very important that you choose the correct region that you're sending from, and that's
defined within your Amazon settings up here when you're signed in with Amazon.
You choose where your your accounts are sending email from.
And usually you would choose the location close to where your website host is or where most of your
website users are.
And it doesn't really matter.
Email can be delivered all over the world from any of these locations, but choose the one that makes
sense for you, and then you always need to use that location in your fluent SMTP setup.
Otherwise, it won't work, and so you can.
The best help doc is under this.
Read the documentation at the fluent SMTP website.
So I just clicked right, clicked and clicked open link in a new tab.
And I've got that article up here at the fluent SMTP XCOM website, and this walks you through just
setting up the plug in itself, but then getting your Amazon six and AWG account and getting your access
key.
And the secret key.
Like I just discussed, there's some screenshots and video help.
Right here.
You need to choose your security credentials.
You need to add a user and that be for that email address and the domain name that you want to verify
and you can do this for each.
You can choose and are a different user for each of your client sites as well and separate those, but
have them use your own Amazon account.
And then you just follow these instructions here to set up Amazon and get your access key through Amazon
and then copy and paste that into either the settings here in the database or using FTP.
Opening up your WP config file and pasting that piece of code in there with your secret key and your
kid.
Make sure you choose your region properly and then there's something else you do need to do with Amazon
six.
Now one of the things is you need to choose the right region here and verify your email addresses by
sending and receiving a confirmation link in the email address.
If it's a live email address and then you can verify your domain by clicking domains in Amazon, as
I've done over here.
And then it will.
They will give you some different codes to put in your DNS provider.
It'll give you these names that you have to put in, and there's three different ones.
One.
You know this one, this one and this one where the Amazon see name records that need to be in there
so that Amazon can verify and verify your domain name so that it can begin sending email from that domain.
So continuing through the fluent SMTP help doc, here there's one more step moving out of the Amazon
sandbox.
You're starting out just in a sandbox where you can only receive email at that particular domain name,
and so you can watch these videos about moving out of the sandbox.
It really just takes filling out a certain form in Amazon and asking for a certain rate of sending.
And also a maximum number of emails per day.
And the way I have that setup at leverage WP is, you know, Amazon generally when I asked for a very
low number of emails say, you know, a thousand emails per day, and I had no idea with the rate at
first, you know, I asked for you and one email per second.
Anyway, it seems their default really.
Their lowest level is 50000 emails per day at a rate of 14 emails per second.
And so in subsequent applications, I've asked for those rates 14 emails per second, 50000 emails per
day and for 20 for a 24 hour period.
And in a day or so, you'll be you'll receive an email from Amazon MWC being approved for that amount.
And you can also ask for approval for larger amounts if you need to hear under my Amazon six dashboard,
you can see that under account dashboard here on the left.
Here are my sending limits at 50000 emails per 24 hour period and my maximum sentry at 14 emails per
second.
But here's the button where you can request a limit increase, and that just sends you to an Amazon
MWC form where you can just, you know, if you want to increase your sending quota, you can go ahead
and go ahead and come down here and click this button to request a quota increase.
And then, you know, it'll ask you what you want that to be.
And then you click the request button.
I've always received a reply within about a day when I ask for a sending quota of 50000 emails per 24
hour period and a maximum send rate of 14 emails per second.