In this lesson, we'll finish and verify the SSL certificate setup and explore email routing through
Cloudflare.
You'll learn some troubleshooting as the DNS propagates, as well as a new feature that can allow for
custom domain name email addresses without email hosting.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how the Cloudflare DNS system works from start to finish
and how to set up email routing for a quick win for client sites or custom email addresses.
So it only took a few minutes to refresh and have the DNS propagate for long enough.
That I've got a real website here at Greg Davis Dock Club with the default 20 22 theme active at a secure
domain using HTTPS.
And so, you know, if I copy that domain name, I look at it right here.
The protocol is https.
I'm getting the lock symbol showing that the connection is secure in the certificate is valid.
And so that was the entire setup.
Now, you know, I can feel free to navigate to the site here in grid pain.
And what I love about grid pain as well is the ability to just click the little WordPress logo for single
sign on, which will allow you to just log straight in to your WordPress website without having to put
in the username and password.
In fact, I'm using a very secure automated password generator when I set up new sites here at grid
pain.
And so, you know, now if I wanted to, I could go to user's profile.
And even if I change the password to something that's more, you know, either difficult to remember
or something that is easier for me to remember for this website, even if I change their profile password.
The single sign on will still work for this domain if I click the W symbol right there.
And so now I've got, you know, a real WordPress website ready to go that could go, you know, visit
site, and I open it in a new tab and begin developing a site at a secure domain here and anytime I
want to in grid pain, I could also go up to staging and I could add that as a staging domain so that
I could do that as one of my websites here at grid pain.
And so, you know, back at the iPad here, the DNS records, you know, what we've done is we've used
Cloudflare as a separate DNS provider so that we can control where a records and C records point to
what host.
And at the same time, we can do use and edit text records for domain verification, for emails, et
cetera.
And as we go into the next few sections of the course, you'll see that we need to be able to control
the Emacs records in the DNS for our domain in order to create and host email accounts, which is something
we will do in the next few sections while we're here at Cloudflare.
Let me talk about email routing a little bit.
I know that in a future section of the website, we're going to talk about the three types of email
in detail and setup and recommended best practices around email.
But for now, since we're talking about DNS domain name routing and pointing domain names correctly
under this Greg Davis Duck Club domain if we look at the DNS records, if I were to set up an email
address at this domain name, I would need to use email hosting.
We're going to talk about that in the future section, like I mentioned, but maybe I want to set up
an email like Greg at Greg Davis Dot Club.
And one of the great things about Cloudflare is their new email routing scenario, where you can actually
set up email addresses that work at a custom domain name like Greg Davis Dot Club, because it's much
more professional for a business to have domain names like info or customer service at the domain name
dot com for business, and that requires email hosting normally.
And so if you want to send and receive emails like that, you do have to set up email hosting.
However, if you only want to be able to have people send to that address and have that address on business
cards or on your website for people to access and receive mail, you can do a shortcut which is email
routing.
So under this website here, Greg Davis Dot Club at Cloudflare, I'll click email and this is the email
routing system that is recently started.
That's why it says beta right here, but it's working quite well.
All you have to do is click get started.
And basically what it does is you can create a custom email address that will receive email at the.
Dress, and it will automatically forward it to any email address that you like, so you can even just
start typing an email address like.
You know, woops, a working email address that you have at a at a different business or say it's your
Gmail address or the customer or your client's Gmail address.
It can make it really easy for you to set up a working business custom email address that without any
email hosting that you have to pay for and without having anything complicated for the user.
What this enables you to do is set up an email address that can be received by your client at their
website address, but it receives it at their regular Gmail or wherever they already check emails.
Now, one limitation is that if you set this up, it can't actually be sent from this address.
It's a receiving only, but sometimes it's a great solution to be able to set up custom email addresses
at the domain name and have them be received at a Gmail or the email address where the client already
checks their emails.
Great solution from Cloudflare.