In this lesson, we'll use the layout that we saved to the DV Library to create a global footer as well
as create a new footer to be used on different pages.
You'll learn how to duplicate a section of any layout to use for your global or page specific footers
in the DV theme builder.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how moving sections and layouts to and from the DV library
can be useful for customizing a global footer design from pre-designed layout packs.
All right, now that we've saved the parallax footer that was part of each of the page layouts in this
travel agency layout pack from Divvy, we can bring it into the theme builder and make it into a global
footer.
And so let's go back into the media, excuse me, into the WordPress dashboard and open up divvy theme
builder.
And now I can see that I can add a global footer here for the default web site template.
Here's where I can add a global footer and say I could say add from library, except what I have is
a section, you know?
So let's see what my saved layouts are.
I don't actually have a complete page layout saved inside of my div library, so that would be not the
way I'd want to bring it in.
Instead, I want to add global footer and then I can click Build Global Footer.
Now that opens up a layout where I just have an empty section and I can add a row and within that row
I could add modules, right?
And so you can build from scratch or right here under this section, I could I can go, Let's see.
Oh, you know what?
I really want to do is click this little plus sign down here so that we add a new section and I want
to add a section from the library.
Now I know I have the parallax footer section.
I needed to know that it was a section that I saved to the library because you can't really pull, say,
a saved module.
Using a section like this, you'd have to save modules as modules and sections, as sections and page
layouts as complete page layouts.
If you remember from before in a different lesson, the previous section.
In the course we used down here, we used this plus to pull in full complete page layouts from our library.
Right now, we don't have any saved layouts in the Deivi library that we had saved.
And so, like I said, we use this plus button under section.
The blue is four sections we click add from library and we can choose parallax footer.
So now here's this entire footer, right?
And we have it the whole thing there.
But there's an extra section up here that was created when we first said Build custom footer, so I'll
just click the little trashcan icon.
And really, that's it.
That's us done.
We have the entire section that we had saved the Disney library now imported as a global footer, and
if we click save right here, let that save and then use the X at the top purple bar at the right there.
And we have global footer that has it has duplicated itself across all of our templates that we have.
And so if I wanted to change the footer for the same number of pages that are the custom header or,
you know, even make a custom footer out of this global footer, I can do that.
But for now, I know that I want to have the footer the same on every single page because it's going
to look great on any page as long as that page ends in a white color.
Because if you remember that footer ends with a, it takes a blend and it uses a gradient to blend itself
back up into the white.
If you remember, we'll just check it out here under the sections and the background image.
This background image right here has a gradient over it.
Is this gradient.
This gradient isn't here.
It ends in white in any case.
And so then as far as design, um, I wonder where that gradient was.
It wasn't in the section.
It was in the row, which is interesting, so the row had a background set where it didn't have an image
at all.
But what it had was a gradient which sits on top of the section background.
And so that gradient, as you remember, was transparent all the way up to white.
And so what that means is that this layout for the whole footer really works well for a page that ends
in a white background color.
And so I'll just make sure and.
Save my changes, I don't think I did make any changes.
But what that's going to do, the last thing we have to do is take a look at the pages that we have.
For example, this homepage ends like that.
Let's just go ahead and refresh the page and see what we have.
Well, we're going to have is a duplicate page footer, so we have that footer coming into play and
then, Oh.
It looks like, let's see, it looks like it replaced.
Did it replace that footer?
No, it didn't replace the footer for some reason.
So this global footer should be working on every page of the website.
Let's see.
This is the same footer that we're editing, the global footer layout is here.
Looks like I'm still using the default footer.
Maybe I have to change, save my changes here to make sure I had saved all the way through.
That's right, I hadn't saved my changes.
So that's something that can happen to you too.
If you don't notice that right here.
If this doesn't say all changes saved, then your changes aren't saved yet, and it will reflect itself
on the life site.
So what I have is this page content has this footer already present?
But then there's another copy of it down here.
You can also see that the gray footer and the bottom bar has disappeared because this global footer
has replaced that default footer that comes with Devi.
And so what we have to do is go through all the pages and if there's a footer that is duplicated, we
have to remove it from the page content.
Pretty easy.
Just click Enable Visual Builder, let it load and then go back down to the bottom.
And when we get to the first one, that's part of the page content.
We just click the blue trashcan and there we go.
And now we see that green at her foot footer template come up just like up at the header.
We can edit edit that template when we're in the visual builder, but that footer is the global footer.
And so I'll save this page layout because I removed the duplicated page footer.
And this is us taking what was given to us as a page layout that we imported from Devi and the elegant
themes layout packs, and we duplicated it into a global footer to use on every page.
So I'll just exit the visual builder and you can go ahead and pause the video and go through this same
process.
But what I'm going to do is go into every page and make sure that the footer has is not duplicated and
looks appropriate.
So I'll pause the video now and go through and do that.
Well, have that go?
You may have noticed that some of the pages didn't have that actual footer, so you didn't have to remove
it.
But a lot of those pages didn't end in a white colored background section.
And so it just kind of ends in a line here, for example, on the contact page.
There's this.
Join our newsletter!
Call to action at the bottom of the contact page.
And so, you know, I don't think it looks bad.
So one option would be to leave this global footer on every single page and then still have this call
to action here.
But one argument would be that, well, you're kind of duplicating the call to action.
A call to action, by definition, is something that usually you'll want to only give the user one option
for the thing that you want them to do from that page.
And so there's either, you know, join the newsletter or a second option, get in touch.
Well, that's kind of, you know, two items could be confusing.
Generally, the more different options people have, the less action they take.
And so one of the things we could do is look at, you know, the contact page was in the blog page,
I think, as well.
I had a yeah, it had that same, you know, different footer, the our newsletter footer.
So one option would be to take and make a copy of this our newsletter section and make that into a DV
library item as a section and then bring that into the theme builder and make it a different section
only visible on certain pages and then make this global, you know, global footer visible on the different
pages that we want.
And so that might be a good challenge for you at this point.
And then I can come back and show you how I would accomplish that by doing it.
So what is it?
The contact page?
The blog page?
I think the shop page is that right?
The shop page also had this newsletter call to action instead.
So really, it's these three contact blog and shop.
And I think that was about it.
I think the about page, maybe, you know, there's an example even go into the gray background here.
You know, what you might try is to maybe switch these two up or even just make this background color
white instead of gray to eliminate this solid line right here.
Just an option on the team page the about page.
Let's see what the about page looks like, the about page that has a nice gallery, doesn't it?
Yeah, I love that the about page has another call to action for viewing packages.
And then below that, it has the footer.
And so there are a lot of different options here that you could do.
Do you really need to have a a footer that's only, you know, visible once on one page to be a global
item in the theme builder?
You could, but you don't have to.
You can see how it might take a little bit of thought to organize your global footer items and your
single page footer items and then arrange them.
But for now, let me give you this challenge.
Like I mentioned, go to the contact page, blog page and shop page and have the newsletter call to
action, be the footer instead of this other footer with the parallax that we created before.
Pause the video and when we come back, I'll show you how I accomplished it.
So the first thing is here from one of those three pages, I'm on the contact page here.
I want to take this section and make it something I can use from the DV library.
So I hit, you know, open the visual builder.
And I'll go down to this section.
Let's just make sure, yeah, we're that other blue border and the plus button is is where that ends.
And so that's my section.
So I'm going to use the down arrow in a circle, and I'm going to say this is the.
Newsletter footer.
Oops!
I just Typekit correctly with my space, saved the library, and then really, I'm done with the visual
builder there, so I like that the visual builder, it knows I didn't make any changes.
I just saved something to the library.
And so now I'll go back into the theme builder.
Now what I want to do is I want to leave the the global header the way that it is on all these pages.
But what I want to do is make a footer.
That's a custom footer that's only visible on certain pages, those three pages.
And so I'll go add a new template.
And what I want to do is add this template to specific pages and I want it on the blog page.
So this is assigned to another template, right?
OK.
So that's not going to work because that's going to be a different template.
It's already assigned to a page.
So we'll do this a little bit differently.
As far as let's see that you know, what I can do is let's see what pages do I have right here on this
one?
I have the team shop, blog, contact and packages.
All right, let's this is going to take a little bit of planning.
So you might have run into this if you were trying to do it on your own.
And what the shot page, the blog page and the contact page to be different shop.
Blog in contact.
So what I'll do is I'll remove shop.
And blog from here and contact, shop, blog and contact.
All right, so let me save that, and now I'm going to make a new template and I'm going to put it on
specific pages, the shop blog and contact pages.
Let's create that template.
OK, now it did that for me.
It, you know, it's got specific pages, blog and two more, and it tells me, OK, it's put the global
header on here the way that I want, and it's got the global footer as well.
But I know that I want to switch that out.
I want to change this and edit the edit the footer.
But you know what I don't want to do is edit the global footer on every page of the website right from
there.
And so really, what I want to do is I want to disable global.
And so what that will do is it will make a custom footer for me out of the global footer.
And so now I can go ahead and edit this footer for these specific pages.
So next, I'll just go into the pencil icon there.
And instead of having this section, I want to replace this section with another one so I can go ahead
and hit ad add from library.
There's my newsletter footer and I could go back up here and click the trashcan and that's it.
Now I have that footer saved as a custom footer, I can go ahead and save my layout.
Make sure that finishes and then click close on here.
Now there's one more thing I need to do, and that is that I know that certain pages I wanted to actually,
I didn't want to use the global header here.
I wanted to use this custom header that had the different color menu items.
And since all three of these pages were here using this custom header, one thing I can do is just remove
this right here.
I can just, you know, delete that custom header there, and I can take this custom header and I can
click copy and then I can right click there and click Paste.
Now I've got this customized header on this customized set of three pages and I can click save changes,
and that should have finished everything that I need.
So if I go back to home, let's just go ahead and refresh.
Of course, that should show my original global global footer great.
Now, if I look at the shop page that first of all, it shows the right color header menu colors and
then when I go to the bottom.
Great.
Look that I've got the footer there.
And as you know, I have to remove this from the page content, so I'll just enable Visual Builder while
I'm here.
And get rid of that copy of the footer, because there's two of them here, so I'll do the upper one
since that's part of the page content and not part of the footer template.
So let me go up here and just to this footer control bar and hit the trashcan.
There we go.
You may have noticed on our products this This layout pack is designed to use the WooCommerce plug in,
which is the free e-commerce plug in for for WordPress itself, which is the really awesome e-commerce
plug in.
And the shop module is one that uses WooCommerce.
And so you'd have to have that active to use products and have an e-commerce store using this layout
or the different woo modules that Devi comes with.
And we're going to talk about Wu models in Devi a little bit later.
So let's go ahead and save this layout now.
Then there's two more pages to check on and make sure that there's no more edits that we need to do.
So I'll click Edit Visual Builder.
It's shop, blog and contact that we're looking to edit.
So in the blog page, we can tell that by putting that featured image, our blog post now looks pretty
good.
Now, if we had more, if we had at least three or even six, it would look nice as a grid layout here.
But again, we have two of these footers.
I just noticed that in the animation, it was like a like a hinge hinged animation on that footer.
I don't know if you caught that, but we'll look at it on the next one.
Let me delete this one as a part of the page content and just click Save down at the bottom for the
page, then exit the visual builder.
Now I can go to contact and on this last one, as I scroll down, look at have a name.
Hinge is open for this right here.
Keep in touch and the form is a module.
A contact module that hinges open.
Looks pretty neat, huh?
OK, so let's enable the visual builder that'll force us to scroll back down again.
But we can get back down there once it loads and go ahead and edit.
Oops!
Get rid of this right there.
Now we have that other footer present and ready to go.
Awesome.
Now I've saved that page and we can exit the visual builder.
Lastly, I'll just make sure that on a page like packages, we don't have anything duplicated and that
we have the correct footer down at the bottom there.
Awesome.
So now you can see in using the template theme builder, I should say, using the theme builder in Divvy.
You can start to create these different website templates that are visible on different pages of the
website, including making a backup template that's not used at all here in red and either global or
custom footers and headers that we can use on different pages or different page types inside the website,
it's really powerful.