In this lesson, we'll continue editing the header, moving into the mobile responsive options to make
sure our design looks good on all screen sizes.
You'll also learn how to view your results in the browser developer tools using the device toolbar and
then add an anchor link as we begin editing page elements by the end of this video.
You'll be able to design for all screen sizes using cadence.
Now, if you follow it along and edited the header along with me, you may have noticed something you
might want to fix, and I sure did that.
This logo is quite close to the edge of the bottom of the header with its line in here.
And there's also one other item that I'd love to change on this 14:13 Norman Street post that will show
you a few things about how to edit content and customize the look and feel of your website within the
cadence environment.
And so we'll go back to the customizer under appearance, customize, and let's look at the header layout
here.
In fact, you can click right in the customizer.
You can click through to another page if you like, and if you're if you're done adding things to the
header over here and you want to hide that header editing area, the header builder, it's called,
you can hide it and you can always get it back by clicking this button down here.
But one thing I'd want, one thing I want to do is just change the height of this slight bit to get
this line a little more breathing room here.
My design sense says that on this header, I want to bring that down a little bit.
So is it under header design?
No, this is just shows that whether it's sticky when you scroll, we're not going to do a sticky header.
We can maybe explore those options later, but it's not under header general.
But if we bring back the header builder, I'll get more options.
As you remember by clicking the gear icon on the main row because we're only displaying the main row
here, you can see that there's items in the main row and those rows are divided into a left, right
and centre areas where you can add content.
And we don't.
We're not using the top row or the bottom row, just two areas of the main row, left and right.
And so, you know, you can really you can see how you can just drag items around if I wanted to put
the primary navigation over here.
Oops.
Over here, for whatever reason there and I could, I could bring that over to the left side if I think
that looks better.
But let's bring it back over to the right side where it's supposed to be for this layout.
And let's continue looking at the header height here.
So if I click that main road gear icon now, I'm customizing the header, but not just the header,
the main row.
And so right off the bat, I can see that there's a minimum height of 100 pixels, but let's bring that
up just a little bit.
I like about 130.
You can type in here and you can use the little up and down arrows, but to me, one 30 looks way better
and it doesn't really get in the way of the image because you can see through it.
And it definitely gives a little bit more breathing room, you know?
I actually do 126 as I look at it.
Um yeah, you can fine tune it however you like.
And now let's look at mobile responsive options here just a little bit, because this is a good place
to bring it up because you know, when you have a minimum height defined in pixels, then depending
on the person's screen size they're looking at the website on, it may change.
You may not want to have one hundred and twenty six pixel minimum height for the header.
So what you can do is use these three different screen size icons in any place that you're working with
in cadence.
If you see these three screen sizes here, it will allow you to make mobile responsive changes that
will be persistent and only be affected when the user's screen is at a certain size or below.
And so that's mobile responsive editing right there.
Very powerful.
So I clicked the tablet size and I can see that what happens with the tablet size is that the menu itself
goes to the hamburger icon and it goes to an overlay menu here instead of just a full menu.
And that's so that the menu items will fit correctly in the smaller header, and I can see that, you
know, this is a lot bigger than it needs to be.
And so it's it's the same as the desktop height right now.
But if I start to drag the slider back, I can make that height, you know, more like.
What do I like about minimum pixels about about 60 looks pretty good.
And let's look at it with.
The phone, you know, we might bring that back down to minimum height.
Well, it's actually got some padding that's not even doing anything.
So let's go ahead and take that away.
Let's look at the tablet height and 60.
Also, the logo is very close to the top, so that's not ideal either.
Might be something that we need to change a little bit.
And so since I noticed that let's look, where are our options for the logo?
This is just the design for the main row.
Let's go back and under general.
Let's look at the logo options now for the logo options, we've got a logo.
Max width.
And when that max width is selected in the tablet layout, it goes back down to 150.
And you can see the spacing is not ideal right here.
And then down to the phone, 150 looks fine for a size because it doesn't get in the way of the menu.
And so that's not something I would change, but I will go into design and look at the padding.
So there's a 12 pixel padding.
Let's see what happens if I make that a little bit less.
Actually, I can just raise that up.
I like the zero padding actually a little bit better since I've added that space.
And now let's look at it in the tablet layout.
I want to now add some padding to the top of that logo that looks better.
Maybe 10.
And then how about the phone?
Yeah, there's a little padding at the bottom that I'll reduce.
And let's bring the padding up.
Here we go.
Yeah.
Like 10, maybe 10 pixels at the top, 10 at the bottom.
And then on tablet.
Let's see, yeah, like about I think, on tablet, I want to make the the size of of the header itself
a little bit bigger, but ten pixels, I would maybe bring that up.
A little bit more, even though it's not affecting it because of the header size.
So let's leave that the way it is right now, let's actually put a little padding at the bottom.
Got to make the header minimum.
Minimum height a little bit taller.
So let's go back to the header.
Design header, general, excuse me, and for the logo.
Let's make the design.
This is where I was.
Let's see, what do we have?
We had a little more padding at the top.
Yeah.
Let's go ahead and make that padding zero.
Let's go back back to the header and back to the main row of the header and under design.
No, I want it to be the minimum height.
There we go.
So 126, I had made that a little bit bigger than 100.
So yeah, I think I like, you know, 120.
Now that I've changed, the padding looks pretty good to me.
Let's look at another tablet.
Let's bring that bigger now since the padding.
I've reduced the padding, so yeah, I might leave that at 80 for the tablet view, that looks great
to me.
And let's look at the mobile phone view.
That padding looks great, too.
I might even let's bring the the minimum height down.
We had it at 80.
Let's bring the minimum height back down to about 70 for the phone.
Great.
Now that's looking a lot better, so click publish when you're done with your changes up here at the
top left at the top of the customizer editing screen.
I just closed the customizer.
And let's look at what we have over here on our 418 Norman Street page.
Yeah, that's looking great.
All right.
And another thing that we can do is if we right click and click Inspect.
Or of course, in Chrome or in Firefox, you can you can go over to the panel for settings over here
and you can open more tools and you can go to the developer tools.
That's another way to open the dev tools.
And so when you're looking under the Elements tab here, you can click.
Right next to it is the toggle for the mobile responsive settings.
So that is the the device toolbar it's called, and that enables you to get a drag able, mobile responsive
inspector so you can see how the website acts at all device sizes so you can go out to whatever size
you want.
There's the break.
Points are actually illustrated here.
Tablet mobile, mobile apps mobile a medium mobile large.
And this is how the website is defined in the background for mobile responsiveness.
And so you can also go and open up here and say, OK, for iPhone 12 Pro, what's it look like?
And then you can see the mouse is a little shade here.
You could see what the menu looks like.
The mobile toggle, the device toolbar in the Chrome or the Firefox dev tools is really powerful.
And so you can also just, you know, you know, put responsive and then drag it and watch what happens
as you do that and you can close the DevTools with this little x ray up here.
So that's great.
We've worked with a little bit of the mobile responsiveness.
We've changed the visibility of the header, so it works on any page, no matter how light the image
is behind.
We've changed the spacing a little bit for the logo here and made it look really good.
The last thing that I'll show you within this video is this little view details button.
Now, when I when I click it, it doesn't do anything, but you can see from the URL at the bottom left
as you roll over and at the URL at the top since I clicked it, says hashtag info.
So that shows me that that's an anchor link.
And there's also another name for it.
But if you I can tell that, you know, because nothing happened to click view details, what you'd
want is for the user's browser to scroll the page down to about here to look at these details and the
description, right?
And so let's go back to the page editor and find and add that anchor tag.
Let's go ahead and go back here.
I'll go to pages all pages.
Let's look at 4:18 Norman Street again.
And as we scroll down and look here, I'm going to open the list view again to make it easy somewhere.
You know, first of all, I can look at view details.
This is just a paragraph, text link, paragraph, text block, I should say, and the link if you click
the link icon will will it'll pull up this.
You know, the link that's put in here is a hashtag info.
OK, so that you know, that's the hashtag info doesn't exist on this page, but where can it exist?
There's only a few sections or types of blocks.
I said sections, there's row layouts, and then there's headings that give you the ability to add an
anchor tag very, very easily in cadence under advanced usually.
And so let's go ahead and look at this section, not this section, but down here, there's the row
layout.
If I look at row there and look under advanced, what I have is that's what it is row layout and advanced
heading.
So under rollout, there's an HTML anchor field right here that I can add, and this link will open
enough up a new tab and it'll show you as a support page at WordPress.org about page jumps.
There were sometimes called an anchor link or an anchor tag, an HTML anchor.
And so Page Jumps give you the ability to program that into your theme.
And so cadence has taken care of it for us over here, where if there's a row layout, you can add an
HTML anchor here, but you can also add an HTML anchor to a heading.
So for example, if you had just a blog post or something with lots of text on the way down the page,
you could have each of your H 2s or 3s, each of your headings.
You could have those marked with a marked with a page jump tag or an HTML anchor tag.
And then at the top of your blog post, you could have a table of contents that's clickable and each
to each, each heading that you click, or each part of the table of contents that you click would scroll
the user down to that area.
And so that's a great thing to do for us at 4:18 Norman Street.
Let's add to the row layout the.
Info Anchor Link, and so all you have to do is go down to advanced and under HTML anchor, you just
use the word with no hash tag mark.
And so that was info, right?
Hashtag info and then just click Update.
And now if I go and refresh the page when I'm navigating, oh, I refreshed it to with the with the
info tag already there.
So if I refresh the page just with the regular URL, as it is as I'm looking at this, I can say, Oh,
click this view details that brings me right down to that section and leaves it in a nice, readable
area.
So those are page jumps and WordPress or what you might call anchor tags that we just added right here
under advanced and also in the in the list view, it conveniently marked if you do have a row layout
block or an advanced heading block that has a page jump or an HTML anchor tag on it, it'll tell you
what that is right here in the list of you.
Very convenient.
Here's one.
There's one under heading here that's came in with our with our pre-made layout.
Our starter template.
And it says I'm interested.
And what's that?
It's the heading that says I am interested above the contact form right here.
Let me just close this so we can see it a little bit better.
So this I'm interested.
I dash m dash interested is a label on this H three tag, right?
So what I can do is if I if I click that that h three tag right here and I inspect the link, is it
right here on this heading?
Yeah, it is.
Somehow it's not marked right there on it.
But in any case, that just marks when you have an anchor tag.
Just like up here, the info anchor tag on this rollout makes it work for us.
So when we click view details, it scrolls us down to that part of the page.