In this lesson, we'll delve into the types of content containers in the DV visual builder, how they
nest together and how to use them in designing and editing the page content.
You'll see how the editing window works, how to arrange it to your preference while seeing the page
content below, and look at the options for saving content types to the DV library.
By the end of this video, you'll understand the content types in DV as far as sections, rows and modules,
and how to use the visual builder to control them.
Let's look at the next section divvy design tools, and we have already covered some of this in the
previous couple of lessons the visual builder in the wireframe view what sections, rows and modules
are.
But let's delve into the editing process for going in there, whether we're editing the content, the
design or the advanced editing within each one of those sections.
And so if we open up that same example site, the agency layout and we open the Enable Visual Builder
on any of the pages, I'm just going to look at the case study page here as the first example.
Now, as you roll the mouse over, as you saw, you've got some different types of content areas here
and there, all always nested within each other in the same way.
So blue means that a section and then within sections, you always put a row layout, even if there's
no changes or backgrounds or anything.
That's where you determine the columns.
And so this little column icon only exists within the green or teal row layout editor.
So if you open that little, you know, layout selector, it'll show you a whole bunch of different
column layouts that are available to you.
And so you can use a single column as often is used.
But then, of course, a 50 50 column, you know, thirty three percent all the way up to six columns
and then different combinations of widths and how they're arranged.
And so you'll see that that's quite useful, you know, in the future as you go.
So here we have the three, the three different types.
One thing I'll show you here is also without editing using the gear icon.
Of course, every time you press the gear icon, that opens up a little modal window.
And that's what we'll be exploring in this lesson.
But before we do that, you can see another graphic opening up some of the time as I roll over.
And that's when I get close to the top or bottom edge of a section.
Top or bottom edge of a section here shows the padding at the top and bottom.
And so this is a convenient way to control that.
This is set at 67 pixels and it may or may not be locked to the top and bottom.
So if I have the little up and down arrow, I can move that up or down.
It looks like it's unlocked in this case, and so down here it's staying at 67 something.
Now, if I go back up here, I can really just I can click the lock.
Now they're locked at 73 top and bottom, and all I have to do anywhere in here is move the mouse up
and down, and I can just customize that visually without having to decide, you know what amount that
I want in there.
And you know, that's true.
Row rollouts as well, rollouts can have.
They usually come with this.
I think about 10, right?
Ten pixels.
Where is it?
Twenty, whatever it is, you know, it has that ability to do it.
And so let's click the gear icon.
And looking at this, once you get this model window above your content area, sometimes it covers up
what you want to edit, right?
And so you can move it around.
Maybe I want to move it over here and then edit that part of the page when I'm working over here and
take a look at my results.
But you can also use this little dock button.
This little icon right over here will dock the modal the editing window to one side or the other left
side.
And then you can even control the width of the editing window here, and then the entire website is
visible in the larger content area.
So I end up working kind of both ways.
Also, when this modal window is drag able, you can use this little corner piece to bring it to any
size you like to fit your working style.
And then you can either click the X or you can save it by clicking the green there, as well as let
me show you the these before or excuse me, redo, undo and redo buttons.
You can undo change a change that you made there, and you can redo a change that you made right there.
And then there's some settings.
Right here, this is kind of a right click menu and so on any of these, if you right click anywhere,
you'll get some settings that you can use.
And that's quite powerful there.
This icon right here just makes the editing window larger and brings it to almost full screen as large
as your browser with a little bit of border on the outside, so you can bring it back again.
That's if you're so you're in here and the content of this section.
Let me go close that and look at, say, a text section here.
This is a text module.
The title of the type of module is always at the top.
And as you go down and look at it, you know, sometimes there's not a lot of room, especially if you
have a lot of text inside of a text area here.
You might just bring it bigger to to give yourself more working room there.
And then finally, you don't actually have to open up the model to edit text.
Suppose I just wanted to edit this text I can actually.
You can see the cursor change into a text cursor.
Once I click there, you can see that I can actually begin editing the text, and it gives me some standard
text editing options up here, you know, like bold, italic, underline centered and things like that.
So oftentimes you'll come in and be like, Oh, this is text of the printing and type setting, you
know, change that word.
Process, anyway, if you type there, that change will persist and then to make that change, you know,
save to the page, you do have to save the entire page the same as if you were to go into here and go
ahead and change that back.
To industry now, you can see it reflected here.
And you do have to hit the green button to save it and then save your changes to the page.
And so that's a good overview of how the visual builder controls work.
Not the page controls down here that we saw in the last lesson, but the individual item controls here.
And then you'll see right down here, there's actually a new color, an orange color.
And that's the only other color that defines these different types of content editing areas within the
visual builder.
So like I said, blue is for a section.
You know, teal green is for a row and then gray is for the individual content modules.
So those are modules.
And of course, if you click any of the plus buttons, it'll add one of those.
The modules you might have seen in our content outline are very many.
You know, these are all the modules that are available to me right here.
You can also add modules from your library if you had saved any.
And so like I said before, if I go into an existing module and I just hit that down button, you know,
this might be called.
Sent Oops!
Center text centered text module, and if I save that to the library now, when I go over here to the
Divi Divi library, you'll see that it's saved here and here.
You should note under tape, it'll tell you what it is.
So this agency home was an entire page, which is called a layout.
And then the one I save just now is called a module.
So if I was in a page editing something and I wanted to come down here and I wanted to add some centered
text down here.
Of course, one thing I could do would be to duplicate this, and that would actually just duplicate
it, and I could edit the text and there's the trash.
That's one way to do it.
But what if I wanted to go down here and I know that, you know, I want to put a maybe I'll do it in
the same spot, put a new module here I could add from library, and it shows me all the modules that
exist within my DV library that I could place there.
Once I click it, it puts it in there.
And so that's easy enough.
As well as giving you a good idea.
Now the orange, let's go down to where there's a different type of layout here.
Here's here's where it is.
Orange means it's a special layout.
This section let's see if I were to go here to the blue, to the bottom of this upper section and click
Add a new section.
The orange refers to a specialty section, and all that really means is that you can now have columns
arranged in a little bit more complex of a layout if you need to.
And that means that you could have is a, you know, a single column section on the left and an additional
type of section on the right hand side.
And so what that gives you is, well, there's no row layout on the left, but on the right, I could
make a two or three column layout on the right there.
And so let me just get rid.
That's what the Orange actually labels.
And so if I delete that and we inspect this section right here.
So within this section, there's both a single column that has just one module in it.
And then over here there's a row and then below that row is another row.
And so that's where you can have a single column layout above and a dual column layout below.
And that's how they built this nice looking layout here that has the images.
If I exit the visual builder here on this case study page, you can see that that was the way they built
this nice gallery, where each of these images can open up in a light box and it has an X here, or
if you click away, it closes it back up and it animates that pick out into and out of the image gallery.
And so that's kind of a custom built gallery using a specialty section.