In this lesson, we'll finish matching the about page from the sample site using a different site template
provided by the 2022 theme.
You'll see why you can't bring a template block pattern into a page or post content area, and you'll
understand the power of the query block for bringing a series of dynamic blocks like posts into a layout.
Finally, by the end of this video, you'll learn how to use a columns block and spacer blocks to fine
tune your layout in a specific page.
OK, so if we go back into the about page, you might think that you just want to go in here and find
a pattern, and you may have recognized that there's a headers section here, and we saw before that
this pattern right here looks exactly right.
You know, it's got some.
It's got navigation.
It looks right.
So what happens if I hit update?
And then I view this page in another tab.
You may have encountered this problem.
OK, so what have I done?
I brought a pattern which is a header pattern, and I put it inside the content of the about page.
So the that, you know, the spacing is messed up.
And of course, there's a white section that says the title of the page and then the other header is
up here.
Now, since the about page has a different header and this thing is a header, we need to treat this
like a page template and then use that template for the about page.
So here we are in pages, all pages.
And if I click about which we created before all, we have the page title and the content so far is
empty.
But remember, I want to add a page template, which will be the header for the about page.
I know that over here under template, it's I open it up if you need to, but there's a dropdown here.
The default template is the one that's on every page if you don't define something different.
But I can put page large header and click Update.
And now if I look at this about page, I'll refresh and you can see that it gives me that large header
and then the content area is empty.
So it's even got the menu here for me.
So that's a really good start.
And now let's go to the about page itself and start adding the content that we need.
So on the demo site, I know that I have a section that's latest posts and it has three posts across.
I want to look and see if there's a block pattern that matches this.
So I'll go over here and let's open up the toggle and for patterns.
The first one I see here is the one featured posts.
It already shows my three posts that I have with the right pictures, and that looks great.
So next thing I'm going to add is watch birds from your inbox and join our mailing list.
Looks like a column layout, and so if we just open it up a little bit bigger, oh, the one at the
top left here, subscribe or call out.
And of course, you would put a an opt in form right here on the right hand side.
But as I look at this, you can see and let's just check on the front end and the real page, I'll just
refresh in the new tab.
And that's looking very good.
But this is a little close, isn't it?
If I look at the demo site, the spacing is a little bit bigger there.
So what I'll do is just go over here and let me look for a block to put in there for space, and there's
a spacer block that I could place right in there.
Now it's here, it's in the wrong place.
So you can either hit this up arrow or you can use this hand and and and drag it up into the spot where
you want it.
The blue line shows you where it's going to go.
Um, no, let me control Z and undo that.
I just really want to keep it on the main part of the page and move it up.
That's where I want it.
And for this space, or if I look at the height settings 100 pixels, yeah, that looks pretty good.
That's probably the default.
So if I hit update and now let's look at the spacing much better, that's pretty much it.
That's the about page.
And now the navigation is there.
It's all looking correct and latest posts and then join our mailing list.
Great.
Now looking at this latest posts block or group, let's look at it real quick in this query loop, which
is a post template inside of the query loop.
You can see that if I hit Query Loop here, you can see some of the options on the right hand side the
settings.
For this query, it's going to query the database for a certain post type.
And so that's going to be posts or it could be pages and plugins and other functionality inside WordPress
might add other post types like services or projects, and you can create your own, which will learn
later in the course.
But this is the post post type and a page is a separate type of post that then you can choose how many
columns in this query block, whether it's posted newest to oldest as in attritional traditional blog,
and whether sticky posts, which are designed to be listed always first in any post list are included
or not.
Where you can even just only display sticky posts, you can display posts from certain categories like
featured or something like that.
You can do it from tags, from authors or even with keywords.
And you can also look at one level inward as far as the post template.
We're including a featured image.
We're including a post title, including a post excerpt and including a post date in each one.
And so each one will be repeated with whichever features you choose inside the query loop here.
You also may have noticed that in this page on the right hand side on the demo, there's a view all
link where that would link to the blog page, which would be a blog archive page.
And so I can show you how to put that in there now.
The way to do that would be, let's take a look at the layout first.
If we look at what's going on here, let's see.
The first thing we have is a paragraph that's within this group, which was the block pattern that we
chose.
There's just a plain paragraph block in here.
And so, you know, you don't want to put a bunch of spaces and or tabs or something like that.
You know, you could potentially type view all.
Let's put a space right here.
View all and then just select that one.
And click Align Text, right?
But look, that's for the whole block, not just for the piece of text.
So let's put that back.
Let's get rid of view all here, and I'll show you how I would go about making this change.
So what I would do is I would add a new block right here after this paragraph block or before.
But what I'll do is hit plus and let's go ahead and choose a column block.
So if I go down here and choose columns.
Click right there now because the cursor was here it, it's going to insert this column's block right
here below the paragraph block and I want a two column block because I'm going to put, you know, the
the the title over here on the left in one block.
And then I will in one column, I should say, and then view all over here in the other column.
So I'm going to choose 50-50.
And there's two columns, each with a plus sign.
So when you click the plus sign, that will allow you to place any kind of block within the column.
So I'll do paragraph latest posts.
And now, when I choose the latest posts, I can go over here under the block selection settings over
here and under typography, I can go letter case and choose uppercase.
That's how this one was created, and then I can go ahead and select this block and remove that block.
Now I just need to fill this one with another paragraph block and I can type view all.
And now what I want to do is have this block here be aligned.
Right?
There we go.
We're getting somewhere.
Now we just need to put a link in there.
So in order to, I don't have a blog page yet created, but to make this a link, so it looks right.
You can just place a hash character and then insert that.
Oops.
Now I didn't have the the text selected, so it placed the actual hash character in there and had that
be the link.
So what you need to do is select the text first and then click the link button.
And now we're adding hash just to make it look like a link, and it's not going to go anywhere.
But now I can just click Update and as I go over here to the actual page.
Here we go.
Now I have the title here, latest posts of this section and then this view all well.
It'll just, you know, reload the same page or go to the top of the page.
But that's the way the link will look to go to the blog page once we have a core created.