In this lesson, I'll give you a high level overview and define some of the concepts, jargon and functions
and tools that WordPress users need to know to understand and leverage WordPress to the fullest extent.
These include themes, plugins, blocks.
Block patterns.
The Classic editor and classic widgets.
Plug ins and the customizer in case you're newer to WordPress.
I'll use one of the default sandbox sites here to define some terms jargon and define how WordPress
is organized.
Just to get you some familiarity with the way that it works.
And I mean, use the sandbox site here.
And also, I also have another site that I've created using local the local development environment
that you'll learn later in the course so that I could show you how to install a couple of classic WordPress
plugins that you might want to use to enable an older theme in WordPress and show you the difference
between classic themes and newer, block based full site editing themes like the twenty twenty two theme
right here.
Anyway, let's go inspect the WordPress dashboard right here.
Going down the left hand side, you know below the dashboard, the first thing you'll see is posts and
pages.
And just to define what those are, pages are static pages on the website.
Those are things like the about page, the home page.
You'll you'll find that there's always an initial sample page within WordPress that is a page type or
post type within WordPress called a page.
And now pages are a little bit different because by default, they don't have a category and they don't
have tags enabled like the other post type called posts.
It can be a little bit confusing at first because pages are very similar to posts.
Now you can think of posts as another type of page on your website, but really just designed to be
used for a blog.
And so a blog usually has posts in it that are defined by their date.
The categories and tags and they are usually listed in reverse chronological order on a blog or a blog
page on the website.
So that's the difference between posts and pages, and each of those is a post type in WordPress speak.
You can also create custom post types, which we'll talk about later in the course.
Like for something like projects or photographs, if your site is for a photographer or something like
that, you can create another post type that's different from blog posts and also different from pages
on the website that you can use for any purpose, like photographs or services for a service based business
website.
In any case, the next thing down is media, and it's called the media library because it has your images
in it.
Media is generally images.
You can also upload things like PDF files for download, but is generally where all of the images are
found in the website.
Of course, you can use the Add new button and you can click select files or you can drag an image in.
And we're going to be talking later in this lesson about the proper way to resize and compress images
for WordPress.
But this is where you upload and manage the media inside of the WordPress in a general sense when you're
inside of a page or a post.
You can also just insert media or an image inside of that page and choose from the media library from
that editing screen.
So another thing you'll find in WordPress is under this appearance menu.
There are the themes a theme is defined in WordPress as the look and feel of the website.
There's thousands and thousands of themes available for WordPress.
We're going to use learn how to use a few different themes in the course, and when you click appearance
themes, you'll see that there is a list of available themes that are already installed in WordPress.
And if this weren't a sandbox site, you would also have an add new button up here at the top, where
you could browse the themes that are available freely in the WordPress repository and look for different
themes in that way.
I do recommend that you go for a popular and well used theme, especially the ones that I recommend
in the course because there are a lot of themes, and even though they are vetted for malware or anything
like that, you never know what you're going to get, whether they're supported by the developer on
an ongoing basis and being updated and what kind of code they're using.
And you know how good or how fast and performant that code is.
And so themes being the look and feel of the website kind of the opposite or the other side of that
coin are plug ins.
Now, plug ins determine some functionalities on a website, for example, in the sandbox.
Initially, you'll see there's a forms plug in and.
There's also a Maps plug in now, plug ins, again, if you weren't in the sandbox, you could click
Add New and you can browse plenty of free plug ins in the WordPress repository.
There's also a lot of paid and premium plug ins available in the ecosystem, and we'll be talking about
that later in the course too.
But just think of it this way.
Themes are for the look and feel of the website and control the design as far as colors, typography,
things like that.
And plug ins control some functionality on the website and things like forms, maps or really any kind
of functionality that you can think of.
There's probably a plug in for that.
And so that's some of the, you know, the terms, terminology within WordPress and jargon that you
might hear.
And as we go through the course under tools, you know, there's import and export and available tools.
You can you can have an importer that you can use.
And then, of course, delete site is there under the sandbox.
You won't have that in your single WordPress installation.
Import and export is really not a backup or a migration tool for a complete WordPress website.
It really is just for the content of the website.
So it's important to know if you import or export using the WordPress importer tool here.
You're just importing the posts, the pages and the media.
You're not importing or exporting the themes and the plug ins or any of the backend code that runs WordPress,
but it can be easy to move content between sites using those tools.
Under settings, you'll have some things like the name of the site and the tag line, the different
options for reading and writing, and will be going through some of these as we customize websites as
we go through.
And that's about it for what we'll look at in the sandbox next.
Let's just take a look actually at appearance themes and click editor right here.
Now I want to point out that in the sandbox, when you have the 2022 theme or another block based full
site editing theme enabled, this editor will come up as one of the options under appearance.
And now this brings you to an area which controls the site templates, which controls things like the
header and the footer and the navigation menu.
And this is what the big difference is that I spoke in a previous lesson about where a block based full
site editing theme gives you this site editor area and a classic theme doesn't give you this.
It gives you something called the customizer instead.
And so if you're in the dashboard here in in the sandbox can see that a under appearance themes, we've
got this editor.
We do also have the customize, but there's not much available under Customize, just the site identity,
which gives you the title and the tagline line, and also a site icon that you can choose to replace
this W up here in the tab.
And the way that the browser would display a logo for your site.
And then if you hit back here, that customizer also gives you the homepage settings.
Now, both of these settings are available under Settings Reading and Settings General.
And so that's just kind of a duplicate.
Now, when we look at a theme that is a classic theme and not a block based full say editing theme,
things will change a little bit.
So if we enable this 2021, the default WordPress theme that came before 2020 to if we just go ahead
and click Activate, some things will change in the main thing being over here on the left side under
appearance.
We now have customize and we have three more selections background being determined by this theme.
But the two main default sections here that are gone when you're doing a full set editing theme are
the widgets section and the menus section.
And so that's the biggest difference between a full site editing theme in WordPress moving forward and
the new way of working with WordPress and the classic way of working with WordPress themes where you
have the customizer, the widgets area, four footer areas and sidebars, as well as the menus area
where you control navigation menus here and you'll see the way both of these work as you go through
different lessons in the course now.
Lastly, lastly, if we open Customize now, we have a lot more selections.
The theme itself determines what items over here are available for customization.
And so when we work with, you know, more developed and extensive themes like cadence in the course,
you'll see that there's a.
A lot more features and selections over here.
This particular theme has a few things like colors and dark mode and background image, but some of
the things you'll see over here are again another place to work with the menus and the navigation.
And another place to work with widgets as well.
And so that gives you an idea of the differences between a full set editing theme and a classic type
of theme in WordPress.
And that's really all we need to define as far as the different jargon and terms that you'll need to
know before we move forward.
Learning WordPress itself moving over to another installation of WordPress that I have powered by a
local development environment called local that we'll learn about later in the course.
I have just a single WordPress installation here where, unlike the sandbox sites, I have under themes
and add new button as well as under plugins.
If I look at plugins, there are no plugins currently installed in this fresh WordPress installation,
but I have an add new button and I just wanted to show you under add new.
If you go to the right hand side and click Search, you can search the repository for the many thousands
of plugins that are available, but right on the welcome screen here there are two plugins I wanted
to point out that sometimes are necessary for enabling older themes in WordPress that don't use the
block editor or the new block based widgets editor inside of WordPress.
Yet now, themes that don't use the block based editor and the block based widgets editor are eventually
going to be going away and these plugins will become irrelevant.
But at this point, it's good to know that these two plugins exist, and they're made by the makers
and volunteers and contributors of WordPress.
The first is the classic editor, so if you install the classic editor and then activate it, it allows
you to use the original editor, which we call the classic editor, also known as the tiny M.C editor
inside of WordPress instead of the new block based editor.
Some themes, if they're not using blocks, require the use of this classic editor.
So when working with old WordPress websites to make them work correctly, you may need to activate the
classic editor when you're using newer versions of WordPress.
The way it works here is under classic editor if you click Settings.
One thing you can do is you can choose the default and right here we're just under settings writing
here and you can see you can choose whether you use the Classic or block editor, and then you can allow
users to switch editors.
And if we click Yes, here and then save the changes that will enable me to show you the difference.
So if we look under pages, all pages and just look at the sample page that comes up pre-made with WordPress,
I'll be able to show you the difference.
And it'll tell you now whether it's using the Block editor or the classic editor.
There are there are two buttons here edit with the Block editor or edit with the Classic Editor, or
you can click the title just to edit it with the standard editor that it's already used with.
So we'll look at it with the Block editor to start with.
Of course, there's a welcome.
You can go through a few different tiles to read about the Block editor a little bit, and this is the
new modern way to work with WordPress, and it's preferred if the theme works with it, which most do
these days.
But the block editor you'll see works like this.
You click an area which is defined by, you know, an outline there.
This is a text block, a paragraph block, and then there's another kind of block right here if I click
down.
This is a quotation block or a quote block.
And then there are image blocks and all kinds of different blocks.
You can go and you can just click plus to take a look at what blocks are the different blocks here.
And these are the default blocks that come with WordPress.
And depending on the theme that you have activated, you can actually that theme can add many more blocks
available.
And I also wanted to mention block patterns because when you're working with the block editor, block
patterns are something that are going to be used more and more within block themes and classic themes
for that matter, where patterns are actually just sections of website content that are like pre-built
sample sections.
And we're going to be using some of these patterns that you see here in the 2022 theme as we go through
and build out a site using the newest theme with WordPress 20 22.
And so you see, there's some patterns here under the featured category.
There's also a series of.
Footers that you can use, you could see that there's all kinds of different, different block patterns
if you click Explore.
You can get a larger display of all of those different block patterns in their different categories.
Some of these looking familiar, this is the one that is being used on this standard homepage in 2022.
And there are full pages that are designed as block patterns.
These have been shipped with the 2022 theme, and they match the design.
And more and more block based themes are going to ship with patterns so that you can easily bring in
pre-designed template templating and different designs that have been made for you to give you a head
start on making custom websites.
But let's go back into the sample page here, and let's go back into the page all pages area and edit
this with the classic editor just to take a look at what it looks like when you're using the classic
editor and the tiny MSI plug in.
There's a little toolbar toggle here that opens up everything that's available.
This is the original way that we worked with WordPress pages and posts for years and years.
And so you may already be familiar with the way this looks.
Basically, the content is in one big area and then you can define different ways of working.
Similar to working with, you know, a document editor like Microsoft Word or, you know, something
like that.
And so that's just the classic editor.
The last thing I want to show you is, you know, under if I just go ahead and go under appearance themes
and because Twenty Twenty Two is a block based theme with full site editing, it doesn't have widgets
anymore.
And let's talk about the classic widgets plug in.
So if I enable either twenty twenty or twenty twenty one, these are two default themes with WordPress
that often come preinstalled, not necessarily activated, but pre-installed with WordPress when you
install a single site of your own.
Now that I have 2021 activated, you can see that I have widgets over here.
On the side, widgets are used for site wide areas like sidebar and footer areas.
This one in particular, this theme 2021 has a footer widget, and it's being used with the new block
based widget area.
Now, as we move forward in the WordPress ecosystem with block based full site editing themes, widgets
themselves are kind of going away because you don't really need them when you're working with the full
site editor, site editor feature.
But this is a block base.
You can see the blocks works similarly to the way that I showed you when the page was being edited.
Each of these blocks.
You know, this is like a it's a group.
I look at the list view and we'll explore this in the next few lessons in detail.
But this is a group that has some things in it.
It has a heading and it has a latest posts widget.
And so you can add different widgets in here by clicking the Plus and seeing what kinds of widgets you
might be able to add for the footer of the website in this case.
Now, in the case that your theme is older and doesn't use the block based widgets system, you can
yet, you guessed it, you can go to add new plugins and you can use the classic widgets plug in.
So if I click Install now and then activate under classic widgets plug in, now what happens when I
go to appearence widgets?
You'll get the original widgets area back.
And if you've worked with WordPress before, you're probably familiar with this area.
And so for this footer widget area, these are the blocks that were already present by default in the
2021 theme, but you can use any of these available widgets that have been available for a long time
in WordPress, like an image widget or a recent posts or something like that, and you just drag them
across and stick them in like that, and then they'll open up their settings panel.
Of course, you can also use the customizer, as I showed you a few minutes ago, to work with widgets
or navigation menus.
And so under widgets, if you have the classic widget plug in enabled, it'll show you that the widgets
are working in that kind of classic way.
So if you click Add a widget, it'll show you the original widgets interface instead of the new block
based widgets interface.
And so that's if you're new to WordPress potentially a little complicated, but will be working with
WordPress in all these different ways.
Moving forward as we go through the next few lessons.