In this lesson, we'll explore email lists and broadcast e-mail and how it's made up of systems that
include an opt in form, a hosted database, a way to create outgoing email and a way to send many emails
at once.
You'll learn the three ways to set up broadcast email using MailChimp, a plug in for composing email
and blog posts together in WordPress, and the advanced method for leveraging Amazon six as a transactional
and broadcast email system together.
By the end of this video, you'll understand the different options for setting up WordPress to collect
emails into an email list and sending out broadcast email in different ways.
Let's talk about broadcast, email or marketing email, also known as bulk email or email marketing
systems and so for broadcast email.
As you've learned, it's an outgoing only email system that sends from a person or a computer to a group
and also referred to as bulk email or marketing email.
It's really what you know of as building an email list, and so while there's no hosting of emails really
necessary, a service is required to be able to power the outgoing email and the database itself, which
is the email list.
And so as a diagram to go over what is really involved as far as your WordPress website.
Building the email list, designing outgoing emails in order to go out to a group and being powered
by a service.
We're going to talk about and I'm going to recommend the MailChimp service as a good place to start.
MailChimp is a good place to start because for one, there are many different services that integrate
with MailChimp for WordPress plugins that are available to be able to easily set up a web form or collect
email addresses as a part of your eCommerce store with WordPress and add those people to your MailChimp
email list very, very easily with no programming, nothing to do very much, except for just set it
up and turn it on.
The other reason is that MailChimp has a free level up to 2000 contacts where you can send an unlimited
number of emails out to your contacts all at once at any time for up to 2000 contacts or less.
And you know, when you get above 2000, that's when I would recommend either, you know, growing to
a certain extent, but then changing your service, potentially in order to save some money on broadcast
email.
And we'll talk about those systems and how they work in the next couple of lessons.
But for now, let's just look at this diagram here.
As far as broadcast email, you know, the first thing that might happen is on your WordPress site and
opt in.
You know, the the person's got a fill in their email address, potentially their first and last name
or or anything else you want to collect, but they've got to fill out a form and press submit.
And so then what happens when they press the submit button down here in the corner?
Their email address and any other information is added to a database and that database generally as
far as the system we're talking about now is managed by your broadcast email tool.
In this case, MailChimp.
And so MailChimp does the rest of these things in this case, but you've got an email list, which is
the database, and then you need some way to to create either an HTML or plain text, email or both
to be able to send those out.
And so a tool to be able to create a nice looking email with a header image with the proper spam law
compliance like having an unsubscribe button and a real business address at the bottom of the email
is required by law when you're sending out marketing or broadcast emails, and MailChimp provides all
that for you.
And so MailChimp also takes on protecting the sending IP address similar to the transactional email
systems we've been talking about.
And so you've got this inclusive system powered by MailChimp in this case, where then that system sends
out multiple emails, one to each person on the list all at once.
And so it enables you to do marketing or provide a service to a group of people as a part of a membership
or something like that.
And that is generally the gist of broadcast email.
Now let's just take a look at a few different systems, starting with number one, easy with the MailChimp
and a MailChimp plug in.
Like, there's a few different plugins that allow you to easily embed a MailChimp form on your WordPress
website and have it join the.
MailChimp list, again, you can have up to 2000 contacts in your free MailChimp account.
And so MailChimp powers the database list and it powers the email creation and then it creates the emails
that and it sends the emails through its system to the group easy and free and a great place to start.
Secondly, this is just an extra layer that you can use.
You can provide this functionality to client sites, or you can use it yourself.
If you want to have a newsletter type of scenario where maybe you want to create a blog post and then
you're also going to send an email to the email list with either some or all of that blog post content
formatted nicely in the person's email.
Right?
And so there's a plugin called Newsletter Glue that allows you to connect to MailChimp or other suppliers,
and it basically replaces this layer of the system here.
The newsletter Glue Plug In has a free version and also a paid version that has a little more functionality.
But Newsletter Glue takes care of the designing an email so that MailChimp can then take the responsibility
of sending out those emails to the group.
And so that's easy and another easy way of doing it.
Again, free up to 2000 contacts.
And if you're going to be doing a newsletter that's connected to a blog newsletter, glue is a great
plug in and a great way to go.
A more advanced way to go is to take on the hosting of the database of all the email list subscribers
inside of WordPress and then using your transactional email provider as the power to send the bulk emails
out.
Now this is the most advanced, I would say, but also the least expensive as your email list grows.
And we'll talk about that when I talk about my setup with leverage WP Dotcom because, you know, after
you get above 2000 on your contact list, MailChimp say up to say 10000 on the contact list costs upwards
of $100 a month.
And while the business may support that, you may have been collecting emails for a free newsletter
and you're not necessarily able to fund $100 a month expense or you just want to get rid of that expense
and take the power of WordPress with a good host and a good contact.
Customer relationship manager called a CRM installed into WordPress to take over, and the AWB system
that we talked about in the last few lessons is a good way to go for being able to send out broadcast
email not from your WordPress website directly, but being powered by the database in your WordPress
website.
And so there are two CRM that really these days works super well with WordPress.
One is called autonomy by the same company that makes woo funnels, a checkout experience and funnel
creation plug in for four WooCommerce and WordPress.
But they also make this autonomy CRM, which is super powerful.
Now, the same makers that made the fluent SMTP outgoing email plugin that we used in the last lesson.
They also make something called fluent CRM, which does almost the same thing.
It enables you to manage your customers or your contacts inside of WordPress using the database power
that WordPress has.
And so really, you really get to cut out the middleman as it were as far as MailChimp or other suppliers
like a Weber or drip or constant contact is another example of an email marketing broadcast email provider.
But you can do this all in WordPress.
If you have a more advanced host because you may be hosting a very large database of contacts, but
you really place the opt in forms in WordPress powered by the CRM program.
And then those contacts go into your WordPress database and they are hosted and managed with your CRM
plug in like auto NAMI.
And then these two, especially autonomy, provides a great way of designing custom emails just within
WordPress.
And then you use your transactional email supply provider like Amazon says to be able to send bulk email
to your group direct from Amazon through your WordPress website.
And so that's more advanced.
The last thing I'll do is just go over the pricing a little bit only because.
There's a big difference.
These providers for a large email list will be, you know, something like maybe $100 a month, whereas
for, say, the same amount.
If you have, you know, 10000 contacts and you send to them maybe four times a month, that only costs
$5.
And so you could see there's a big difference as your email list grows in using something like Amazon,
a simple email service instead of a company like MailChimp now, MailChimp is a great way to start,
and it's very convenient if you keep your email list, trim and and keep cleaning it.
It can be used for a good long time for that, and it has great features and it's easy to use.
But I'm going to show you in the final section of this email systems part of the course how to set up
Amazon.
See us not only as a transactional email provider, but also as your broadcast email provider.