In this lesson, we'll explore more customizations we can make sitewide to the 404 not found page,
as well as creating a custom template for a blog page.
You create a blog template and a blog page to use with a query loop block, which pulls in blog posts
dynamically by the end of this video.
You'll see how, with a block based theme, you can customize a photo for Page without editing or adding
code, as well as again, how to customize a template to use for a blog page.
One thing you might notice is that this design blog button that we went to a slash blog page doesn't
go anywhere.
There's a 404 error, which is a page not found.
And by the way, we'll take a look at the 404 page template that we can customize, which is unlike
old style editing.
This is great inside of block based theme.
You can easily customize the for a four page without using any code or a plug in or anything.
But let's fix this design blog and create a template that we can use.
But first of all, let's create a page.
There's no blog page, but we did this using the 2022 theme before just going to a type blog.
And of course, there's no blog page that that is available to us just the default template.
Now that default template lets just click publish.
I can uncheck always show the publish checks right now.
And so since I've published a page called Blog Now, this should actually go somewhere, but there's
no content in there.
The default template isn't really showing anything but the page title.
And so let's go back in the WordPress dashboard and let's look at Appearance Editor.
And we can see that.
Of course, this is the No.
Title, no title site template, I should say the no title, no title template.
Hey, here's the four oh four displays when no content is found.
And so here is the index that displays posts.
But let's take a look at this 404 template first.
This has some content they're not found.
Oops.
You know, sometimes you can see on some websites, there's sort of a funny, funny joke, and a search
is really a good thing to have or even page navigation or suggestions of places where people can go
if they've navigated to the wrong page or something like that.
But that's great that it's editable there as far as templates.
Let's look at this indexed template here that shows the posts right?
Shows the posts in reverse order, and it's got the proper header and footer.
And so let's go back.
You know, what I'd like to do is create a blog post template like we did in 2022, so we can look at
the query block.
Let's go in the pages, all pages and back to the blog page that we created.
And over here under page, and you know, with the Settings panel open, let's click new.
And I just want to create a blog of blog posts template.
Click Create right here.
And, OK, here we go, we've got the blog posts template.
Uh, let's go ahead and let's look at the list view and we've just got a few different different things
right here inside this, this group and then a second group and then a group there.
And so really, what I want to do is first, you know, inside of this group.
Or even below this group, let's look at adding the oops I spelled template wrong.
Let's look at adding the header template part with choose an existing template part.
And will choose that header.
Great first thing that I wanted to do.
Look at the list view here, and let's take this group.
Just click the three dots and remove it.
Great.
Okay, now there's the top.
We've got a separator here right there.
I can get rid of that separator.
I can have the title there.
So this has the post title.
In fact, now we don't want to have that in there.
Let's inside of this group.
Let's go ahead and get rid of this group here, so we've got the post content there.
There's nothing really there, right?
So I'm just going to get rid of that post content.
But inside of this group, what I want to add is, well, let's go to browse all that'll bring us over
here as if I hit this plus button over here.
Look at patterns and then let's look at is it query or page that I want?
I think it is.
Query open up the explorer just a little bit bigger.
A grid of posts in three columns is the one that I usually like.
That's great.
I don't have many posts in here to have.
Well, let's see what our options are over here.
Styles default or box shadow brings a shadow in there or, of course, full height.
And there's some other options over here, so let's just so for the blog posts.
Template.
Let's go ahead and update that.
This page has been modified yet, and so has this template, so if we save that?
Let's see what we have to work with here.
All right, so really, I just have two posts, a sample post and a hello world post, but what I'll
show is a three wide grid that goes down the page.
I'm missing a footer, though, so let's go back here.
Others hit back.
Let me go.
I like to edit in the site Ed itself, I know that blog page is already using the blog posts template,
so I'll toggle the navigation going to templates and open the blog posts template.
And let's just look at the list for you to see what we have.
There's that header.
All that stuff over here, OK, here's a group, and then there's a second group, so I really don't
need this group.
All right, but down below, you know, there's a spacer, there's going to be pagination here, that's
there if there's more than one page of blog posts.
But really, what I want to do is add.
I want to add that footer down there.
All right, we'll close this group and.
So what do I have?
I have a group here which goes all the way down here.
I want to add a block, I want to add something below this group.
That looks like it's a little bit wider.
Let's see what we have in the list of, you know, I have a group that's well outside.
And if I add it, I can add a template part.
Choose an existing template part.
It's the footer that's looking better.
Now that I have that, I can just save this.
Now the design blog should work correctly with the footer at the full width of the page.
Great.
All right, that's great.