In this lesson, we'll get into the content editing window interface for sections, rows and modules
in the visual builder in more detail.
You'll see how to use the three tabs across the top of the content window, which are content design
and the Advanced tab.
By the end of this video, you'll know where to find all the many controls at your disposal when editing
any one content area in the Devi Visual Builder.
And finally, as we look in the visual builder again on this same case study page, I just want to briefly
show the existence of the different options that you have under each sections modal window when you
pop them up and you may have noticed the three different tabs.
So generally you'll have the content and within that you'll have these different, you know, accordion
layout places where there's different content that you can edit and and change.
So here I've got a text editor that gives me a whole lot of options.
If I'm scrolling down, I can click Link and that will then close the above accordion and open the next
one.
That would be a link for the entire module and then whether you open it in the same window or not.
So I could have an entire module clickable, not just the text and then background.
If you want a background, a background gradient, a background image or even a background video on
any kind of a module.
Generally, those are used in larger modules like sections or rows instead of module instead of modules
themselves.
And then below that, this is where you label the admin label.
So, you know, if I have header right here, this doesn't appear to the public.
But now, once I know that I label this header right here, when I go down and open the page layout
and look at the wireframe view, then I have that labeled so I know what it is.
And so if you start to use the wireframe view a little bit, it's useful to have those admin labels
in there.
So you know what's what?
Another great thing about that wireframe view is that you can drag things around using the mouse right
here in this four sided arrow so you could bring it and place it there.
And I can bring it.
Place it down below again and then back to the visual builder desktop view would give me that same spot.
So then let's open this module once again under design.
That's where you're where you'll find things like how is the text and the heading text and the different
things in the content area styled.
And so for text, you know, it'll be set up as a default every time.
But you have so many options here, you know, the text alignment you could make centered instead of
left, for example.
And if you're using default colors, whether it's a dark on light or light on dark right here, you
know this is not changing because these colors are defined in the content area.
Over here in terms of text, color, and then because these are two different colors, these are most
likely defined inside of here.
So case study has a text color here and then online store has a different text color here.
You can also notice that this while the text is just capitalized right here, it's all caps.
Over here in the actual website.
And so that would be determined in design over here.
And so here I'm going to set that to the side to make it easy to see the whole thing.
So under design, this is a heading right under content.
If I click there, I could see that it's a heading one.
And so if I look at design under heading text, this heading font style is changed into all caps.
And so if I click that, you could see that it's shown in blue to show that that's set as all caps,
you know, italics, for example, and alignment like I showed you.
Here's the heading font monserrat.
Now, if that were in H two, I could change that styling here.
But if this is H one and I go in and I change the H2, that's not going to affect this text because
that is an H1, and that's where this little blue paintbrush comes in.
Oftentimes, it's easier to find where you want to work on this by clicking that little edit button
versus trying to figure out, OK, you know, what was it?
It was here.
It was an H1.
OK, I have to go back to design heading text h one instead.
If you're anywhere over here inside of this area and you're like, You know, I'm going through, I'm
working on this one, I'm going to click that.
And when I click that little blue paint brush, that brings me right to the design to.
And right to the H1 tab for heading text.
And so that's an easy way to get where you need to be.
And then you get these sliders for, you know, heading text, et cetera, for size heading.
Text size, spacing, line height.
Whenever you change something, you can always hit this, you know, go back to the original size.
Now this was modified up to 60 pixels, but the original size was 30.
The way this was set up, and so I'll bring that back up to 60, or I could just x out without saving
this text module.
It would go back to what it was.
Of course, there's text shadow.
Different things you could do there.
And sizing is things like max width or min width module alignment.
If I want the module, the module is already filling up the entire space anyway.
And so by centering it, it doesn't do anything.
But oftentimes that does work to center a module itself within the row or within the column.
And so spacing is, you know, padding and margin, and you can lock top item and you can lock left
right so that you can control that.
But if I wanted, some say I wanted some left margin here, I might just go in under margin left.
I can just use this little slider and I can change that number to adjust it how I want.
And of course, you can also, you know, select it and use your keyboard, or you can even go up and
down by pixels right here.
And so I'll just, you know, revert that back to what it was before.
And that's the spacing area.
And then under design, there's always border where you can round the corners of something.
If it's got a if that's visible border styles in width, you know, if I wanted to put a border on there
and define it and then if I wanted to round the corners, you know, all that stuff is available and
they come locked, but you can revert back to doing one or the other.
There are so many design options in Dili under the Design tab on all the different module row and section
areas for editing, you know, a box shadow.
If this whole thing, you want to have a shadow on there to define the area.
And then, of course, if I had a black shadow, that's where I want to add some margin or padding so
that it's not running up against the edge of my box shadow.
And then, of course, filters for color contrast, inverting the colors and blur and opacity.
Very powerful design elements transforming into, you know, shapes.
Even you can, you know, do size transformations.
You can, you know, do really amazing things with, you know, rotating and, you know, angles and
things like that.
There's amazing design work you can do under with the transform options.
We just revert that back and let's revert back there, the rotate as well.
So back to where I was.
And then finally, animations.
This is really powerful.
This one's actually a fade in.
And so let me back out of here and let's go exit the visual build there and discard the changes.
But that's where you were seeing you could see that fade when I re refreshed the page as we go down
here.
Those were coming in at a slight angle.
Here's a fade in under creative process this one.
Oh, there's the slide left to right.
Those are all, you know, CSS animations that are controlled without code and don't affect the page
loading very much at all and are amazing ways to design with Divij and then finally enable the visual
builder once again and we'll go into advanced.
You may use this just a little bit will be one thing that will teach you about using a CIUSSS class
for using anchor tags or a side, and there's custom CSS that you can put either before, after or as
a part of the element in any single section in your design.
This custom KSAZ and these other advanced places for working on either an individual module a row or
a section are super powerful, especially being able to add a piece of custom CC to a single module
without having to add that CSS sitewide.
And that saves the loading time a whole lot, because then that piece of code does not need to load
unless this particular module on this particular page is being loaded on the front end.
And so that's some of the power of the different tabs across the top of these editing windows and gives
you an idea of the power of the DV visual builder.
And I hope that gives you an idea.
We're going to be going into a lot more detail on how to create and modify layouts to build completely
unique and custom sites here in the next few sections.