In this lesson, we'll explore how you can develop or migrate a WordPress Web site at a live host before
the DNS is pointing to the domain.
This time on a Mac, you'll learn how to edit the hosts file with the terminal and the nano program
on your Apple computer to fool the browser into thinking the domain is live at your server's IP address.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how you can set up a working site behind the scenes using
the terminal on Mac OS and then point the domain with DNS after you're finished.
So let's look at how to edit the hosts file on the Mac.
Just like we did on Windows before, it's just a little bit different if we look at this.
I'm using Chrome on my Mac now and I've navigated to my test domain BCom, and you can see that it's
at a different website.
It's looks like they've got this for sale.
It's at a web developer website called Web Development XCOM.
And so what you need to do is use the terminal on a Mac computer.
And if you're not used to using it or don't have it down on your toolbar, you can just hit command
spacebar and open up the spotlight search and look for terminal.
And so I'll just hit enter when it's highlighted.
And now we have just a code terminal in order to execute commands to the Mac operating system.
And so one thing you have to do is know which code it is.
And I just have a note here on my other computer about how to do it so that I can remember.
But what you do is you type a few commands.
One is a pseudo studio space.
Nano Nano is the program we'll be using and then another space.
And then you go slash ETSI and slash hosts.
Now that might look familiar.
That's the same location that it was on the Windows operating system, the ETSI folder and then the
hosts file.
So I'll hit return and ask me for my password for this computer.
My user account on my computer.
And it won't show in the terminal while you're typing it, but you have to type it in and then hit return.
And if you've done that successfully, it will show the file at the top in the black highlighting.
And this is a program called Nano two oh six and it really can't use your mouse very much, but you
really use the keyboard to put the cursor where you need to.
And so now that I'm editing this file, it's kind of the same as the Windows one.
You can see the local commands that are in here, some of the ones that I've created at the top here.
So I'm just going to go down below the normal kind of default header inside of the terminal here.
Put a couple of spaces in here and make some space for myself.
And so now I need to know the IP address and the domain name that I want to use.
So I do have to go into grid pane and let's go to my my grid pain control panel and I will have to log
in here so that I can get that correct IP address and I can either take a look at it.
I can do it right here under servers.
I could copy it because the terminal will allow you to paste for wherever the wherever the cursor is.
So go down to the bottom here and click terminal again.
OK, so wherever my cursor is, I'm going to hit Command V for paste and then I'll put a space and then
I need to type the domain that I want, which is my test domain dot com.
I want to make sure you spell out exactly correctly.
And then again, you can use the hash mark and make a note for where this is.
I'm just going to say it points to four good pin Payne and Mitovich server, and once you have that
in there, the commands are here at the bottom for this nano program.
And so the one two things you need to do is command.
Oh, and that's to write out, you know, write out the the file, the changes that you've made here.
It's command.
Oh, and it's actually control.
Oh, I should say not command on the Mac.
So you hit control.
Oh, and then just to exit, you just hit.
You have to hit enter after doing controller and to exit, you just hit control x.
And so I'm going to do that right now.
I'm going to hit control.
Oh, and it says its file name to write slash ETSI slash hosts, and I'll just hit return.
And then it tells me that it wrote some lines.
It wrote 46 lines.
Those are the total number of lines here inside of the hosts file.
And then if I want to inside the terminal here, I can just hit Control X that will exit the nano program.
And now I'm back where I started with the terminal open.
You can go ahead and hit command queue for quit or just go up and you know, you can just go up to a
terminal and say, quit terminal.
But now when I go to my test Dominican, I'll just close the tab out of Chrome.
Maybe just in case the the browser cache would show me the old page, I'll go to my.
Test.
Oops!
No space.
My test domain.
And let's let's see where it goes.
Excellent.
So there's the site that I just installed using my Windows computer.
And so it looks like it's working.
And as I said before, if you, you know, everything should be working as if this domain was actually
hosted at that IP address.
And we know that it's not, but I can log in if I want to and develop the site.
Behind the scenes before the DNS is pointed for this domain to the correct server.
And so it's a great way to either migrate sites, update sites or do a site redesign at a new server
behind the scenes without having any downtime.