In this lesson, we'll recreate the event page from the twenty twenty two theme sample site using a
block pattern.
You'll see how sometimes editing an existing site template is a way to customize a page or a page type
by the end of this video.
You'll see how I brainstormed a solution and solve the problem of removing the page title by editing
an existing site template included in the theme.
Next, here's our event page, as it looks right now, no content in there.
So if I open the dashboard and go pages, all pages open this event page here.
That's where we'll start.
Now let's look at the demo sites as far as the event page.
I'll bet you I can find a block pattern that has this two column layout with a title, and that page
is event with the URL.
So let's see if we can find that.
Let's see.
I'll just hit add.
Let's look at patterns.
Let's look at explore and see if it pops out at us.
There's that pick, but it's a different pattern.
I see it's not one of the featured patterns.
Then maybe it's a page.
There's that pick again, but it's a different one.
It's got black on the right hand side.
There it is.
All right.
Poster with right sidebar.
So I'm going to click that.
That brings it in under event and great.
OK, now let's go ahead and click Update and see what we have.
So here.
All right, now, here's a little bit different.
The difference here is that this is showing the page title with a dividing line, which is kind of default
for the page itself.
So what I want is to not show that right there.
Let's see what we can figure out about that.
So on this page here.
Under the Settings panel, on the right hand side, the default template may be blank or maybe page
with no separators.
Let's see.
Let's just do a test.
First of all, we'll just see what happens there.
OK, so that took out the separator, but I still have the page title here if I hit page with no separators.
And that's that's going to be closer it just as event under event here, but the header looks correct,
right?
Yeah, that's the.
The same header with the menu, OK?
And we want to get rid of the page title.
And so let's see if there's any templates in the site editor that we can look at.
Open up this navigator, let's see.
Yeah, I really want to make myself a new template.
It's allow me to add a new template, but only a front page template, not a different kind of template.
You know, I could commandeer this one right here.
What if I commandeered the page?
No separators template and I just edited it.
You know, I could do is just instead of no separators, I could make a page template for myself called
Page.
No title.
And so what I can do is just remove the post title.
Save this template.
Templates not being used anywhere yet, but if I go back to the dashboard and I go to the pages now,
I can only know it's the event page.
If I go to the event page.
I can go and choose Page No title, OK, because that's I was using the no separator one before.
And so let's update that.
And see what we have.
Refresh.
There we go.
That worked, OK.
So took a little bit of discovery to figure that out.
But that's what you have to do in WordPress.
Sometimes there's there's multiple ways to do things.
Another thing I was going to do was go in here and just remove the title and save the page.
Now that's not ideal because then when you look at your your pages here, it would show no title right
here.
I've done it before, but it's not ideal.
So now I'm using a particular page template called no title.
That's great.
All right.
Let's check again, event.
Page no title.
Great.
I just kind of commandeered that, so I no longer have a page.
No separator.
And that's OK.
I don't need to necessarily use that template right now, but that made it match.
OK?
No page title in there.
That was a great solution.
And after a little bit more experimentation, I did find a different solution where I don't have to
commandeer another site template.
So if we go back to event right here, if you ever get this attempted attempt to block recovery, you
can go ahead and just click to recover.
The block usually comes right back.
But on the page settings, let's just go back to the default template for now, and I'm going to show
you how you can create your own template and customize it completely and then use that in any page or
post.
And so if I refresh the page on this event, now you you can see I have the page title and the separator
back again.
Page content is the same.
Because I'm using the default template now, and so let me go back into this event page and very small
little button right here under the page settings, whichever template you have selected just under if
there's an edit button and a new button.
So now if I click new, this gives me a modal window where I can actually create a custom template from
scratch.
And so what I'm going to do is select page and I'll call it no title, just with no parentheses.
Just to differentiate it and click Create, and now it gives me a little welcome message, welcome to
the template editor.
You just click Get Started Now is actually showing me the event page, but I'm within the template editor
here, so it's showing me the event page content, but I'm editing the actual template called Page No
title.
And you can see some differences too.
Here it's it's showing a different header than the default header.
And it's also not showing a footer at all.
And so I'm just going to click Update just to simplify and get out of this event page and go back into
the actual template editor.
So if I go back to appearance editor now I'm going to open up that actual.
Template that I created, and you can see that now it shows that it's added by me, it's not added by
the theme itself.
And so one thing I could do is I could revert this back when it has a blue dot here like you saw, it
shows that it has been customized.
So if I clear customizations now, that template is back to being page no separators.
And that default template that comes with the theme is now available to use the way the theme has designed
it.
And so that's been saved there.
But Page No title is a new one.
And you can see what it has is post title and post content.
And then there's just a header here.
So what I'm going to do is go into the plus button here to add a pattern and I'm going to look for a
header and then the default header is right here.
So if I just click default header, that adds that block pattern in and you could see it added below
the existing content.
So really, all I have to do is move it up with this little button and I can move it up again.
And now really, I can just delete this content up here.
This is the old header that came as I selected the new page template, so I'm just going to say Remove
Group, and there's also a little line up here a separator.
So let me open the list view.
You can see the separator is here, so I'll just use those three dots and click Remove Separator.
Now I'm looking pretty good.
I've got that the default header, I've got post title post content and you know, I want to remove
the post title.
And so let's see.
I don't want to remove the entire group.
The Post content is also within that group.
So really, I could just click post title here.
I could use either over here, I could remove the Post title, or you can actually click the three dots
over in the list view as well.
And so now I'm looking pretty good.
I'm showing just the post content, not the post title, but I still don't have a footer.
And so let's add a footer.
I'll go to block patterns again and choose footers that are provided by the theme and I can see default
footer right here.
That's what it's going to be.
So now I can just click Save.
And yes, I'm going to save this template.
And if I go back, you know, to pages all pages and click event and then display, I can show it.
But here I have it open in another tab.
So if I just refresh the page, here we go now I'm a lot closer, so the footer looks good as far as
spacing goes.
But you can tell that I need a separator here at the top to make it look like the default template on
every other page.
So I'm not going to edit the event page.
I'm going to go back into the editor again.
I'm going to edit my page template by clicking the Navigation Open Clicking Templates page no title
and now above the header.
I want to insert a spacer up there.
So really, I guess what I'll do is select this group and I'll click Plus, and I just want to put I
could find it by searching down the list or just start typing spacer and do spacer.
And there's my spacer, but let's move it up and move it up.
And now it's above the header itself.
And so I'll save this template again, and let's take a look.
Oh, you know what?
Let's just make sure.
That my event page, this might have been the problem with the space or under event, I didn't click.
The new page, open page, no title, it is selected because I had created it from this button new,
so that was correct.
OK.
Just because I recovered that block, I'm going to click Update.
Let's go back here and click Refresh.
Now I'm looking better.
You know, I've got the looks a little different though, doesn't it?
Let's look.
Let's look at the event page.
And so I've got the menu is even with the page title.
And how much space I have is just a little bit different, so I might go ahead and.
Go back and edit this page template again.
This is something that you may have to do.
Just to make sure everything comes out correctly.
Let's go back in there and you can see that, OK, there's these two things are now separated.
So really, what I want to do is, can I move that up?
Now it's above.
I actually want to place it inside here.
Yeah.
And.
I want to justify it to the right.
OK.
Come on now.
It says Justify left, justify right.
That justified all that, I'm sorry, because I have the group selected.
So let's see, I have this row.
And the logo, title and logo and the site title.
Oh, I think I need two different columns in here.
You know, it might be the easiest thing to do.
Potentially would let's see where is this group right here?
I'm just going to add that once again, this spacer is still here, so if I click the spacer, then
I'm just going to click to add a block pattern.
I want to add the header and I want it to be the default header.
That looks much better, doesn't it?
The space are still there and this space looks right, but let's go ahead and save and see if this solved
our formatting issue here.
Refresh the page that looks much better.
Now, of course, this heading is too large as well.
And so there's some customizations here to be done, uh.
Let's see if it's the post content.
Do I?
Let's see if I can edit some of the post content and inherit the default layout.
If I.
Change that that could change it, or I could go into the event page itself.
I could click.
At it there.
No, that's not right.
Let's go back to the dashboard.
And pages and pages.
Click the event page.
Yeah, so it's the it's the heading.
Let's see what the difference is.
I wanted to resolve the block, so if I converted to H.M. or converted to blocks after the conversion,
align it to wide.
Yeah, let's just say convert to block.
This is in each one.
I wonder if I go over to here.
Just let's do an inspection, I'm opening the dev tools, click this little arrow and I can look, and
it does say it's an H1 and it says the font is a certain size fifty seven point nine pixels right here.
So I can remember that in each 157.
So click the one.
My go over here and what could I make, I could make the size extra large so I could do a custom size
of about fifty seven pixels.
That's really going to do it, isn't it?
And it's still an H1.
So then I can click Update.
Yeah, now under Paige, I could just click permalink and click that link to open a new tab.
Now we're looking like it should, you know, let's close the dev tools like that.
And then here's my page.
It is a slight bit smaller, but you can see where you have to fool around with the layout a little
bit sometimes.
This space is a little smaller, too, so this space is a bit larger.
I could go back here and play with this spacer.
You know it might be.
I might just be able to remove that spacer.
Because this default heading has a certain amount of space in it already.
Let's see if that makes it.
No, look at that.
It removed all the space again.
And so I still do want to place a spacer in here.
Yeah.
So let's see.
Let me add.
Spacer.
Back in.
Move it up and move it up.
You can also drag the items in the list view here, but I'm going to make it just a little bit smaller,
more like 60 pixels over here tells me how tall it is can save this template now.
Let's see how that looks.
Yeah, that looks about right, doesn't it?
Because I'm logged in, it's showing the admin bar, so the spacing looks a little bit different, but
that looks right.
All right.
So this is my page, I'm just going to close that tab.
And there we go.
I can go back to the dashboard.
You can see that under pages, all pages.
Now I've created a special template by using this new button and I've selected it page no title.
So you can create as many of these new templates as you want and use them on posts and pages to do these
kinds of customizations.
So even though there's a title on the page itself so that when I go back to all pages, I can see what's
what.
When I go to the page, it doesn't show the title.
And that's the way it's supposed to look.
All right, thanks for following along with that discovery.