In this lesson, we'll find an import, a custom blog post template from the Disney website designed
to match a layout pack design.
You'll learn how to assign the dynamically generated content area to be used only on blog posts.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how the divvy, theme builder and custom body templates
work to bring dynamic content like blog post titles, body text, featured images and blog post meta
information into a customized design, allowing a content manager to later use the default block editor
for creating blog posts instead of having to learn to use divvy.
Okay, so we have a nice layout going right here with all the different pages, the custom header and
custom footer, and global and templated items here in the Divvy theme builder.
Now you may have noticed the body areas right here that we haven't used yet, and we'll finish with
the theme builder making a custom body for one specific page type.
And that would be the blog posts.
So if we look right here this, this is a really powerful thing that we can do using Deivi, meaning
that if someone's going to be entering content or editing content, especially blog posts, you may
not want them going in and trying to figure out how to use Divij or potentially breaking the website
or the layout.
But at the same time, you want them to be able to have a beautiful blog page layout that really matches
the design and looks great.
So this is a blog archive which does look great and, you know, is laid out to look really good if
we had more blog posts.
Of course, there would be three across in a nice grid layout.
But when you click through to the blog post, we're presented with kind of a traditional non divvy layout
here.
This is the regular blog post layout regular.
I should say WordPress default layout.
It's got a sidebar.
There's a line, the menu, the transparent menus not working well.
The title doesn't match the typography.
There is a featured image, but you know the buttons don't look right for the commenting form, etc.
Now the global footer is there and the global header, and we might want to, you know, we could we
could actually, you know, create a version of this global header that has the darker buttons for the
navigation in the logo and adds some space down below and still use this very, very simple template.
But still, it's better to use a special post template.
We can use a custom body template here for the blog posts themselves, and what that enables you to
do is let the content editor or content creator use the Gutenberg or default WordPress Content Editor
for blog posts and not deal with the Divij editor at all, but have all that content styled by DeFi
so that the blog posts look really good.
And so, for example, what we're going to do is actually import one from the Elegant Themes blog I've
gone in here and searched for the word blog post template for the phrase and scroll down, and you can
see that there's many blog post templates available at the Elegant Themes blog, and they're available
to match different posts, different layout packs.
And there isn't one for the travel agency layout pack, but one that looks really good I've used before
and that we can modify for this is for the home staging layout pack.
So if I just click through to that, it's similar to bringing in a header and footer template.
But this is a blog post template where you can see it's going to take some of the content and dynamically
populate it into each blog post.
So the title and categories up here at the bottom, a nice read button that scrolls you down to the
content area.
This is the featured image, among some other stuff down here.
It has a related post section.
The comments form looks really good, and what we can do is edit the typography and the colors to match
our layout pack that we have right here.
And so similar to bringing in a, you know, a header and footer template.
This time I've clicked the download button and it wants me to put in an email address to download it
for free.
No problem.
I can just, you know, put any email address and you don't have to go and verify your email or anything.
You just click that download and submit button.
Joined the email list for elegant themes where they do e-mail you not too often, but some really valuable
stuff, and then just click download the files and it comes into your downloads folder there.
And then we can go find that using the, you know, File Explorer or using, you know, downloads or
here or using in Mac, you know, the Finder.
And so here I have the home staging blog post template, right click and extract all or double click
if you're using a Mac and a finder, and then you can go ahead and there we go.
You can go ahead and open that up.
I don't know why that closed right there, but.
There's the JSON file right there that we can use to bring in to our layout.
So let's go back to the theme builder here, and I'm going to go ahead and bring it in as a new template.
If I add a new template, I want it on specific types.
So all posts is what I'll check here and I'll just click Create Template.
Now what it does for me automatically is in this template for all posts.
It brings in what I already have as the default web site template, as a global header and a global
footer.
And so that will populate really great.
I might have to bring the custom header in in order to have a white background work, as you saw before.
But let's go ahead and add a custom body in here where we could bring this in.
And so that's one way to do the bring in the all post's template.
I'm going to bring in another template by using the portability icon up at the top right there and clicking
import, choosing the file from my downloads folder under this and this.
There we go.
And then I'll import this template.
Now this is the home staging blog post template it brought in right here, and all I need to do is bring
this over and add it.
To now, this one is unassigned now because I think that it created a blog post template there.
And so you know, what I'll do is I'll just oops, I didn't want to duplicate that.
Let me just delete that one I wanted to delete.
I could either drag the global header and footer over into here or I can.
Just since I already duplicated that custom body over to here, I can just, you know, uncheck the
all posts from this one.
And now that this one that I created before is unassigned, I can create the gear icon and click all
posts and click Save.
And now I could just save changes up at the top left here.
And let's take a look at what a blog post looks like now.
Oh yeah, what a what a difference right now.
Of course, the header is overlapping in kind of a weird way.
Right?
Here is something we might want to change.
But look at this.
I do have the category name.
I've got the post content excerpt right here and as I go down, there's just a little bit of content
in there and about the author related posts, a subscribe and the comments area down here looking pretty
good, really.
So how are we going to customize this?
You know, the white copy looks pretty good honestly in this header that we have here, but it's too
close.
I need to move everything down a little bit.
And first off, let's go into the post itself.
Let's see.
Uh, let's go into posts, all posts and click the post.
And now what you would do is instruct your client or whoever is using this to not click use the device
builder, but to actually just use the Post Block editor here as the editor for this post or any post.
That is, you could even make this button disappear to prohibit the editor roll or or author role from
being able to use the DV builder.
And there are ways to do that in DV so that you don't have that mistake of somebody trying to open up
and use the DV builder when they're not supposed to.
And so I've got a another tab open with Laura miff some generator for the Bob Ross Lipscombe dot com,
and I'll just copy a group of text from Bob Ross painting show on public TV and that's copied it now
to the clipboard.
And as I go in here, I'll just select this and paste.
Now I have a bunch of paragraphs.
That's great, OK?
You know, that's that's looking good.
And you know, what I'll do is maybe just insert another one and I'll just put, you know, a heading
in here.
Oops.
If I do slash h do a heading and.
Just title it, oops, I think that's an h, too.
Yeah, that's an H2, OK?
And then update the post and another thing you can do is just maybe.
Let's have I know there's a.
An image in there already, but, you know, if I just look for an image block, let's look in the media
library and pick a nice image to put in here.
And if I want to place the alignment, maybe over to the right and have the text wrap around it, yeah,
maybe I'll change the width a little bit.
OK, so this would be the process of, you know, adding some content, just using the block editor
to make it simple for the user.
Just a caption for the image there and click Update.
And we can see what this post looks like now on the front end with a little more content.
OK, so now that there's content here, I've got, you know, oh, I don't want to have that heading
right up at the top because that puts it in the excerpt there.
So you would you would coach your your editors to actually if you're going to use a heading, is it
below the first paragraph and update that?
And then, OK, let's go ahead and take a look.
OK, see if you click, read article.
It goes down and then it shows the now it's not showing the image right in here.
I'm not sure why, but in any case, it's still looking pretty good, especially the heading of the
blog post template.
Except I need to move it down a little bit.
In fact, let's see how would we want to do that?
Let's go ahead and look at the template itself.
Remember, under Divij theme builder, you can go in and we're editing this custom body template.
And so if I open that template up, you can see that what is in here is not the contents of any blog
post in particular, but it shows that this is.
Let's look at this module right here is a text module, but in the body, what we have is a dynamically
generated item, which is the Post Archive title.
And so you can edit this.
This is an excerpt.
Of course, this is a button that's just a button module that matches the layout.
This is all the different post content.
So here we go.
This is how you would style the post content settings.
That's one big module that shows examples of all the different content types that could be part of a
blog post content, the post content.
And so if you look under design now, I can see for designing the image.
These would be, you know, the different styles for the image that would be in there.
And so to actually fix that before we go in and maybe give some space breathing room at the top here,
well, let's do that first.
As far as this, uh yeah.
Let's see, what are we going to do?
So we want this whole section to be have a little bit of space at the top.
So if I want to add maybe some, there's some padding.
Would I add what are our top and bottom padding?
I think I would add just top margin for everything.
And that would leave the background color there for this post.
We could see what that looks like.
So I'll just click Save for the row and then let me save right there after it stops doing the autosave
under here and we can click refresh here and see what that looks like.
So that's an interesting layout, too.
If I get the spacing right and I have my transparent background here ready to go with this background
color, and that's kind of interesting.
Now the green doesn't necessarily match what I have, you know in the website, if I look at the maybe
I just go to visit site and open it in a new tab over here.
It's more like that grey blue background would be more appropriate for this layout.
I would think so.
Maybe I can grab that color if I enable the visual builder here and just go into the background.
Let me go over here and get the wireframe view.
Go into the heroes section.
Maybe this module and look at the background is that where the color is located?
Knope is actually in the hero full width section background.
Yeah, that's a color that's kind of a gray blue.
So what I can do is just double click it, copy right there, and I'll close out of that and let's go
back to the theme builder here.
And so this background color is part of the section, isn't it?
Let's see where I have that green background color.
Sure.
Right there, so just click here and paste, and now I have more of that gray blue color.
And that fits a little bit better.
And I also wanted to go ahead and look at the design.
I noticed that for the spacing.
Oh, you know what?
It was?
It a different spot, wasn't it?
It was in the row.
That way, we can leave that background color visible.
I wanted to leave a little bit more space than the hundred pixels.
One hundred and seven, maybe, maybe a hundred and twenty or so.
That might look better for that menu, getting in there and being visible for the blog post itself.
All right now, let's see what that looks like.
So you can play with this.
Well, it's quite nice.
That's a nice blog post now.
It's got a lot of great functionality.
Yeah.
And maybe we can fix this image next.
Just quickly.
So a couple of changes I can make here to improve the layout on the actual post over here as a as a
single post layout with our custom template is to maybe move things down just a little bit.
I did put a different image in here.
Using a horizontal image did make it display nicely.
All I did was click replace, open the media library and chose this image and then hit select and it
brought it in there nicely.
But what I'm going to do is just take some of the text right here and move it up and move it up one
more time and hit update.
And what that did was it moved this heading, which was, you know, in an excerpt.
Heading in the styling of a heading doesn't come through as an excerpt, so it's a good idea to have
enough copy at the top of the post so that the excerpt length works and doesn't show something that
just looks weird when you're reading it.
And so I just saved that those two changes.
And let's see, I just refresh the page.
Now I've got a nice layout here with the content of this real move down a little bit away from the transparent
menu.
And then as I scroll down, you can see that here is the excerpt with the little ellipses here and the
read article button will scroll the user down to this next section, where it's goes to the first section
of copy.
One last thing will remove this subscribe from the post's theme builder, uh, custom body here.
Go back into the little pencil icon and we'll remove that.
I look for this section here.
Here it is.
So if I pull this section away, I can just go ahead and reduce it down by deleting the row.
And then of course, the image is there in the caption and the rest of this post looking great with
the comments form.
And then of course, our universal global footer is here, even at the bottom of the post's individual
template.
And so that shows you the power of bringing in dynamic content into an area that is controlled by you.
As far as the design, using the device theme builder and you're just defining that there's a custom
body and the global header and footer in the all posts area, so that every post that gets created by
a user of this website in the future will bring in the title dynamically.
The category.
It will bring in the featured image dynamically and show it overlapping these nice background colors,
the author, the date and the comments, whether or not you want to display those, and then all of
a content laid out the way that the user wants it laid out when they build the blog post.
And so it's a super powerful way of customizing your site design without giving the user the reins as
far as them, you know, messing up the site or having to learn Divij, which can be pretty complicated.