In this lesson, I'll show you local, a program for easily creating a server environment on your own
computer that you can use to play with WordPress and experiment locally.
You'll learn how you can use a local development environment to spin up as many WordPress sites as you
like to try out different things or test themes and plugins before committing those tests to a live
hosting environment.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how using a local environment can expand your ability to
play with and learn WordPress without hosting or an internet connection.
Let's talk about local WordPress hosting.
Now this is an option for you.
If you want to create an unlimited amount of WordPress sites for free just available to you on your
computer where you can practice and test things and build sites.
Even migrating sites and uploading them to a live host so that they can be live web sites in the future.
Local WP, XCOM or local is a great option for you.
This is probably the best local development tool for WordPress in the world, at least right now, and
it is completely free.
You can download it for free with this little button or even or create an account, which will give
you a few more benefits to downloading local, even to the point where you can connect it to your flywheel
hosting and use it as a staging environment or a development environment connected to your flywheel.
Hosting local is owned by a flywheel hosting, but it's provided completely free as a separate free
local development product.
And so if you download and install local WP, one of the things I should show you is that there's a
community as well that is a great place for resources, for looking up if you have any issues or anything
now, depending on the power of your personal computer, on a Mac or on Windows.
There are some limitations and sometimes some operating system conflicts that can happen when you set
up any local development environment, because what you're doing is you're setting up software that
usually powers live.
WordPress hosts servers connected to the internet, and you're installing that kind of software right
on your personal computer so that you can power a piece of software like WordPress to deliver WordPress
websites to your browser right there within your computer.
Now you can work with and practice with WordPress websites right on your local machine without being
connected to the internet, which is a really interesting way to work.
And I'll open my local program right here, and you could see that I use it for practicing and for testing
things for building sites in an environment where it's super fast to work with because I don't have
to be connected to the internet at all.
It's within my own computer, and I use it to easily spin up WordPress sites for testing things.
And so if you install local WP on your computer, you'll come up with this will be empty for you, but
you can just hit the plus button just to add a new site.
And I'll just show you how to create a new site and then navigate around local just a little bit.
If you want to use a local development environment in your practice for WordPress, and so let's see,
let's just call this.
Let's just call this a leverage WP site one.
And I have a preferred setup, or you can use a custom setup as far as a perversion type of web server
and type of database.
You can set this up to match your future live hosting if you are going to migrate your site up to any
hosting from here.
But I'll just leave it at my preferred.
You can leave it at the defaults, most likely when you install local on your own computer.
And then, you know, I'll just use a.
Username and password that I can remember, and this is important with local local uses, a kind of
a just a kind of a dummy email address.
And this enables you to be able to use the email systems that WordPress sometimes uses for outgoing
email so you can use a forgotten password.
You can test a contact form, notifications and things like that locally by using the local email catcher,
or which will enable you to check emails kind of within your local system using your browser.
And so it's best practice not to change this email to something different, but to leave it here.
And then I usually just leave this alone.
Unless you're installing multi-site, just leave that at no for advanced options.
Then you just click Add site and it goes through and it provisions the different things that it needs
to in the background to set up your site.
And here's where.
If you encounter any errors, I could say you say allow access.
If anything that your computer says, Hey, you know someone's trying to access your operating system
because it's installing a server on your local computer, you want to allow any access that it asks
for.
If you have any errors and anything happens, you can go to the community here and use this little search
to search for, you know, either part of the error message or anything that you need to.
And I'll often find solutions to how to make that work and get around any of the issues here in the
local WP community.
That's at Community Dot and local WP dot com and its link above from the local WP dot com website,
too.
And so here I'm on the local website and then opening the local program.
It's already finished, so I have the site title right up here and right here under the site title.
It gives you an indication of where on your computer the files are all saved.
And so in working with WordPress, we are going to kind of take apart a WordPress site and put it back
together.
Look at the database and the files and how they talk to each other.
If you're using local to experiment with that, here's where you would find the WordPress files.
And so this little tilde means the this means the user or the default hard drive of your computer,
but it makes it easy for you with this little arrow.
This little button will open up a file explorer window, and it will just show you exactly on your computer
where the files are located for this website.
And so for me on my C drive, my Windows C drive on this computer, I have a user named Greg Davis.
And then there is a under that user.
There's a folder called local sites.
So local sites with a capital L Capital S.
That is a local folder that gets created by this program.
And so within there you have folders with the names of all of the sites that you've created inside local,
and that's where you can find all those.
And so this one was called Leverage WP Site one, and then that's where we were before and linked,
you know, from this little button over here in the control panel right there.
So if I go back there, there are three folders within this leverage WP site one folder, which is the
site folder for local and that where the WordPress files are located, are in app and then in the public
folder.
Now let's look at the database, too.
If the next tab over here is database and so similar to like we saw in site ground, the PHP, my admin
utility is there in flywheel.
We saw that they had a browser based database editor that you could use from the Flywheel Control Panel
here in local.
There's a tool called admin here, and if I open, add Minner that will open a tab in my browser and
it will show the database for this site and give me a place where I can access it.
So again, if we go into WP users and this is showing the structure of that table and if we select data
here now, you can see that I have a user and this is the user email and you do want to keep it at that
flywheel dot local email and then the user login, etc. Just like before you could hit edit.
And I showed you where if you use the password changer, you want to change a password to something
you can remember.
Now remember, this is an MD5 hashed password password, so that's not my actual password.
It's a it's an encrypted version of it.
But if you do change it here in the database, you would select MD5 and then that would be your actual
password that you could type in later.
And so I'm just going to go back and go to my SQL.
There's, you know, you could you could go ahead and you navigate away and now have gone so far back
that I don't know if I could get back.
There we go.
I'm at the root of this database and these are all the database tables.
And so back to local.
Let's see.
I just go and open the the local utility right here.
This is just the local control panel and now under tools you could see.
Here's where you have two tools male hug and live links.
And so if this is what I was talking about with the email address, if you open mail hog now, that
will open a little tab in your browser that allows you to receive email that was sent from the WordPress
website.
And so this enables an email testing area.
And so this is an email that was sent to this email once that WordPress site was was created.
And so this is just a standard WordPress email that tells you your username and that gives you a message
about your password and it gives you a link to the login page.
But let's go back to local again, and if you did create an account with local, then you can enable
something called live links, which is a very interesting functionality.
If you are designing and developing a website locally and you want your client or someone else to be
able to view that site externally from some other computer elsewhere.
You can actually connect to your local site temporarily to the internet if you enable the live link.
It will give you a URL that you could then email or send to someone, and they would be able to access
your actual computer and view that website as if it were live on the internet.
It's an interesting and really powerful way of working if you like to work locally.
And so then finally, you know, the the overview page is where I usually remain and where it opens
up the site.
Over here, the two main buttons that you might use open your site and the admin button.
Now First VI open site, that'll open up basically a new installation of WordPress.
And when that opens up the site, you can see the address that it's trying to open.
Leverage WP Site one dot local.
And this is the way it works in local.
It creates a new domain extension called local within your home computer, and that uses what's something
called the hosts file on your computer, and it modifies that file to fool your browser into thinking
that Dot Local is a real place.
And it actually enables it to think, Oh, this is a website on the internet, where in reality it's
just browsing your own computer to the local setup, where you're using a server like a hosting company
on your own computer.
And so here's a standard 20 22 theme website.
If I go back into local, if I hit admin now, that would bring me to the login page where I could remember
my username and my password, and then I could log in to the WordPress dashboard.
But there's another convenient thing inside of local you can use, which is one click admin.
So if you if you turn on one click admin, once you do that, then you can select the administrator
that it will use when it does one click admin.
That means that when you click the admin button here, instead of having to put in your username and
password every time for each of your sites, you can set up each of them to use this one click admin.
And then it enables you to log in to the WordPress website, you know, without having to type in your
username and your password.
Really, really convenient for practicing and getting started with WordPress and playing with it.
And it's great for learning WordPress, even when you don't have to have a hosting account or even have
a site that's live on the internet at all.
And so one last time, back to the local control panel, this right here is I mentioned you can connect
to your local site to your flywheel hosting area.
And if you are a flywheel customer, then that enables local to be able to connect your local environment
as if it were a staging environment at Flywheel.
And so that's an interesting way to work.
I've not done it very much myself, but I've tested it.
It works quite well for working locally and then uploading the site and migrating it up to your flywheel
account easily.
Now there's a few other functionalities over here.
There's a Settings panel right here.
You know the the preferences.
This might be where for new site defaults, you can.
To have that admin email, whether it's a custom environment or you use the preferred environment every
time for exporting.
If you you know what kind of a zip file are allowed, you can export a site from here into the database
and then the file structure, and then you can use that to migrate this site anywhere, any live host
another local environment.
So you don't have to just use this to migrate your site to flywheel hosting.
You could migrate a site that you developed locally into site ground or into your grid pain environment
at one of your servers.
So then there's some advanced if you're your website, if your local environment's not working and giving
you some errors with the hosts file or with the domain, you can choose to use local host instead of
site domains, and that will just maybe make it work instead of using that that dot local custom domain.
And there's some other other settings here blueprints.
Just like in fly, we'll let you in install certain themes or plugins that you can use as blueprints
to make a say, you know, have all of your, you know, plugins and themes preinstalled when you set
it up.
And so that's a good overview of local.
Don't forget, you use the Plus button down here to set up a new site and then you can go through and
you can turn on or off the different sites.
Now they do have to be on and running for you to use them, and then you can stop the site server in
order to shut it down and then close local for the day or whatever you need to do.
You can multi you can use multiple sites and have them on all at the same time.
But you don't have to.
If you are working with multiple sites in your day and you're ready to shut down, you can stop them
all at the same time with this button down here on the left hand side.
You can close this little panel if you want to go in here and, you know, use some of the other controls
and kind of get that out of your way for whatever site you're working with.
That's a good overview of a local environment.
There are some others I might recommend.
You know, local, I think, is above and beyond the best.
There's one called desktop server that you could try.
There's some others that don't have WordPress installers that are kind of the old fashioned sort of
old school local development environments that use the MP initials for them.
So there's WIMP with a W.
There is a map within MMP, one that I've used quite often on Mac and on Windows and XAMPP with an X
X, a MP or X MP.
They all stand for like Apache, My School, PHP and Perl.
The computing languages and software that's necessary to run a website server.
And so that's why those are called by those weird names.
There's one more I'd recommend for windows called Larian, and that one does give you a WordPress installer
similar to local here.
But I don't think it's as powerful or as easy to use as local.
But those are some options.
If you do want to work locally and you don't have the ability to use local for some reason, you're
operating system is giving you a limitation.
You can try one of those others, and on the resources page, you'll find links to all those inside
of the course here.