In this lesson, we'll check out some advanced design elements in cadence, including controlling gutter
width between images in a gallery.
You'll learn about image overlays and setting a tiled repeating image underneath another element.
By the end of this video, you'll get more experience working with the list view using layers of content
and creating more complex layouts with cadence.
Now, let's check out the about page.
There's another really cool effect that comes in with this design, which is this background image that
is kind of a looks like a topographical map behind, you know, the featured agents or that behind this
gallery where all the images are touching.
And I want to show you how that was done with a few features to point out within the cadence, blocks
and cadence theme.
So if we look at the about page, I went to all pages and then clicked about if we if we look here,
let's go ahead again and open up the list view and just take a look at what this is here.
If I click anywhere in here, it shows me where I am.
There's a row layout here that has a background on it.
And actually, no, it's the section that has the background.
I believe now it's the row, there's the row layout and it actually is a background overlay.
There we go.
You could see that it has an image here that matches those, those topographical lines.
And I just wanted to show you that this this is a tile lable image, and it's also kind of brighter,
you know, darker black here, too, so that you might imagine that the overlay opacity is, you know,
a certain darkness.
And so if I were to just go ahead in here, let me let me close the set so we can see it a little bit
better.
Close the ListView.
But if we look and a couple of things I wanted to show you, you can find, you know, repeatable images
all over the web, ones that you can buy from stock libraries or you can find for free that you can
use as very, very fast loading small backgrounds.
And it's a really interesting effect to wear this one.
You know, if I change the opacity, I can bring that a lot brighter.
And of course, that doesn't look quite as good if we bring this back down to a three where it was.
It's a nice, dim gray, but it has this kind of neat lines.
Now this image, if we look at that image in the media library, go down here and and choose it.
It's, you know, it's a thousand pixels, but the screen with over here that I have is more than a
thousand pixels.
And can you find by looking where the repeat is, a lot of times it's hard.
But looking at this right now, I can see that right here, there's this oval.
And then the other edge you have just to the left of that oval is just right here.
So that's that thousand pixel mark.
And then it repeats, but it's a seamless repeating square image that you can find.
A lot of them are very small.
Maybe only, you know, 20 pixels or 100 pixels, depending on what the images that you're looking at.
But let's close the media library again.
I just want to show you that repeated image and the opacity is controlled because that's set as an overlay
on this section right here.
Excuse me, it's set on the row, not on this section, because that section that sits within there
is what's holding this advanced heading and advanced gallery.
The gallery is set with a gutter width of zero.
So the pictures are touching, et cetera, and the section itself has both a title.
You know, two headings, actually.
And then a gallery.
And so the row layout, I would expect this to have only one column.
So you can see how, you know, depending on how you have it designed, this has a 90 pixel padding
at the top and a 90 pixel margin at the top.
And so that arranges kind of what these two headings do this one right here and that one as far as where
they are on this background image, which is really, really cool.
So that is very cool.
And while we're here, let's just take a look at the design library.
If you remember, I talked about how you know when we open up here before I talked about block patterns.
Now here, when we're looking under what blocks you could add, there's a bunch of cadence blocks that
I talked about when we were looking at the plug in itself.
And so these are some of them.
You would click any of these to bring it into the website, but block patterns.
Aren't taken advantage of in cadence in the same way they are in 2022.
And so these block patterns don't come with the theme.
These are block patterns that are being just pulled in from WordPress.org and, you know, available.
They are just available block patterns.
These are featured ones.
There's buttons, you know, but none of these necessarily match the page layout that cadence has brought
in here.
So generally, when you're working with cadence, I wouldn't generally use these patterns unless you
kind of know what you're looking for and and you do find something that matches unless you're building
something from scratch.
But instead, what I would suggest is that you use this cadence design library button right up here.
So if you open the design library, this is a very powerful modal window and you can start to even just
imagine and see what these kinds of things are.
These are full sections.
These ones are called sections, and you can look at them, you know, either larger or smaller, you
know, and you can see what they all are in here.
So, you know, you can bring in these four sections.
These are built for cadence themes.
Some of them might match, you know, the starter template a little bit worse or a little bit better.
And also, some of them are only available with the Pro Licence.
And so they're using that a little bit to get you to upgrade if you would want some of these extra ones,
but most of them are available for free.
And then secondly, there is, you know, another starter packs area here.
This is another place where if you're editing a page, you can bring in a, you know, a full page from
one of these starter packs right into a page when you have it open.
In fact, here's the real estate page that we're working on right now.
You know, if you click that, it will just bring a page right into the website.
And then finally, I wanted to show you this wireframe.
Oh, they want you to subscribe.
In order to access the wire frame layouts, that's fine.
I'm already subscribed with another email address, but if you go ahead and enter your email address
and share it with cadence, you know they really don't send you that much email, honestly.
So you'll see that this is a really great way to kind of, well, prototype a design that doesn't have
the distraction of kind of a brand with photos or colors.
These are wireframe, you know, available wireframes that you can bring in to a page in order to design
from scratch.
And so if your design process is more like, you know, you're bringing, you're looking at potentially
designing within a user interface or user experience design program like Figma or Adobe XD or something
like that.
And then what you want is to just design the functionality and the layout of the website without the
distractions of images or anything like that.
You can use these wireframe layouts.
That is not really the way I work, but a lot of designers prefer to work this way.
It gives them kind of a better idea of what the how the website will function as far as user experience,
instead of how the website will look as far as colors and imagery and backgrounds.
And so those wireframes are really awesome.
You can see you can you can look at them all or you can, you know, look at certain ones.
There's a promotional sale, there's these image cards or cards that have different content on them.
Portfolio wireframes.
Here's a countdown numbers you can use what a form might look like without any distracting colors.
They just use these blues and grays and whites.
And so that's in the wireframe area.
It's a great thing that cadence offers as far as bringing in new things.
And so the last thing is that this right here is a quite a nice image gallery.
Let's see.
What are we looking at down here?
An advanced gallery?
Yeah.
So the the on the about page as we scroll down here, just like these images are laid out in a certain
way with no gutter down here, these images kind of look like part of the footer.
It's a good way to have a row of images, potentially, and you can even have it be scrolling across
as a slider if you want to in the advanced gallery.
And you can see that over here.
If there's all these different settings for mobile responsiveness to, you have specific.
Control about how many columns for this screen size, say, four columns, four columns, and then when
it gets down below 992, which is tablet size, it goes to three columns and then below this size it
goes to two and two.
And the gutter width is zero.
You can see it change as I make the slider in terms of the pixel number, but that's a great way to
a great thing to know as far as controlling how an image gallery looks like that.
And so I didn't make any changes here.
So when I get out, I can just click leave instead of saving my changes.
And that's another set of design examples about how we can work with cadence.
You can see that it's so super powerful as far as all the functionality and specific design options
that it gives you on top of what WordPress, the Block editor and Guttenberg gives you.