In this lesson, we'll edit the design of the custom body template to match the website's layout.
You'll change the fonts and font weights of headings and body text colors and other design elements
so that the blog post template design matches the design of the original non matching layout pack,
as well as save a divvy designed layout section for use in the DV block.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how editing the template will affect the way all the dynamic
content looks, as well as how to provide divvy designed content blocks that can be used in posts created
in the default block editor.
There's a few more things we could look at as far as this blog post template and one I mentioned before.
It's changing the font to match the rest of the layout here, and so let's just go check that out real
quick and start there.
And then, you know, I'll give you a challenge to potentially go into one of the pages that is already
in this layout, like packages, for example, and potentially use one of these pre-designed pages as
a framework to create your own blog template that absolutely does match.
Instead of adapting one that was built for a different page layout that we're using right now, but
in any case, let's go ahead and hit back and look at this one.
I know this is a serif.
It's a header.
And if we look at other pages, maybe if I just go to visit site in a new tab, I can open up a different
page here.
You know, our headings are this kind of blocky sans serif font.
And then as far as copy, this looks a little bit different than what is down here, this kind of standard
divvy font right here.
And so let's find out what our fans are and change these around to further match the layout to the layout
pack that we're using.
And so if we go back here into the dashboard, one thing I want to do is, let's see.
You know what I'll do.
I'll go right over to any page and let's go ahead and use this package as page.
And if I hit Enable Visual Builder, I should be able to go in and just quickly look at the heading
here.
This is a text module.
If I click here, I can see that's heading one and under design, under heading text.
Of course, I can go over here and if I, you know, let's attach to this to the side like I've showed
you before.
If I click the Little Blue Paintbrush here, it'll show me where I'm supposed to be.
Of course, I'm already having text each one, which is what this was.
So it's Oswald bold, all caps and 60 pixels.
And so that's maybe something we could use.
So Oswald pulled all caps is something we could change over here inside of a theme builder.
So let's take a look at it.
Let's see if I go back to my custom body for all posts.
I can go in here and edit the header right here if I look at the dynamic post title.
This is the Post Archive Pope Archive title.
And if I look under design heading text h one for this design, it's nota serif, but I want to go up
and look for us.
Want?
I found it right there.
And I want it to be bold and I want it to be all caps.
And now it's I'm going to leave it in that way.
Color, since it's on this dark gray background and leave the layout the way it is right here.
60 pixels is what it was, right?
So I just leave it to 60 pixels.
That might look just the same.
Now we can make it really whatever we want.
And so I'm going to save changes there.
And then let's take a look at the next font in travel packages here.
I'll just close this one, and let's go down to a text module that has regular body text on it paragraph
text.
So I'll do text here under design.
And it's Roboto.
It's Roboto regular in 16 pixels, so I can go back here again.
Let's change this to Roboto regular in 16.
So instead of default font, we can look for Roboto.
There's a few different versions, and this is 14, so it's bumped up to 16 and great, that's going
to match super awesome.
I do like the categories the way they're all caps right here.
But let's see if we go down here.
Are there any more kind of headings that are different?
Well, not really.
Let's see.
We do have a let's see paragraph text with Oswald in upper and lower for some of the headings right
here, so we could go back and just change some more of these.
Yeah.
Let's see Oswald right here.
I already changed.
So if we go right to here, is that the title text for an h for?
Yeah, that's what we have going on right here.
So if I just remembered Oswald for me, so I can just change that, Oswald?
Let's see.
Did I bump up the size?
I think I did just a little bit here.
Title text Oswald 18.
Let's just make sure I have the same size here and it's looking pretty good.
You can see what I'm trying to do.
Yeah, let's just bump that up.
To 18 and then over here as well do the same.
This is where this is a style that you could copy.
So if I click here and say copy module styles, I could go over here and say paste module styles.
Once I change one, I can duplicate it easily over to the next one.
And then I would go down through this whole post content settings and I would change all the fonts to
match Oswald and Roboto and just go down and change all the different sections so that it matches.
So let's just quickly see about doing that.
This could be pretty quick.
I could just use this little blueprint precious.
Change him to let's see Oswald all caps and just keep following down.
Oops.
Keep following down all the headings here.
This one?
You know, I can just keep the size and make them all caps.
Right here.
Go to Oswald.
Make it all caps looking good.
That looks pretty good.
I mean, let's see.
Let's do some of the body text, of course, and bring that over to rubato.
And it looks like all the body techs now changed over to rubato, including the italic for a black quote
and all of it.
Everything is looking pretty good now.
Now, down here, I've got a post navigation.
If we just look at the links text, let's change it back to.
Yeah, let's have it be the.
All caps heading.
Sure.
It's just making everything match and right down here, the about the author.
Of course, I want this.
Let's go to where it needs to be easy to find that way.
Make it Oswald all caps.
And then let's make right here.
Where's that?
And it must be a different module.
Yeah.
Two different modules here.
Here's one.
And that is, let's see who is it going to take me there?
Click that.
Well, let's see what it is.
That's.
Text.
Let's see what the content looks like, it's the Post author.
It's an age three.
OK, so now I know I can go to heading text h three.
Change that into what we're using for heading text, which is Oswald all caps.
Yup.
And then finally, here's somebody text we know we're going to bring that over to rubato.
Nice.
Close that off.
Almost done.
Got a few more things to do, and you can pause the video here and take care of it yourself.
And I'll do the same and come back and we'll take a look at what we got.
OK, so basically I went through and everything that was a header.
I changed into Oswald, all caps and everything that was body text or anything else that wasn't a header
changed into rubato.
And so it made it all look quite good.
I changed the color on this.
You know, you could do what you want as far as buttons.
I just left these yellow and I left these all caps the way I had before.
So here is a nice all posts body layout that now I have to go ahead and save over here, and that should
finish up our custom blog posts template.
If I close that it says all changes saved here.
So if I look at example post now, that should bring everything into line as far as the design.
Yeah, looking good.
All the body text similar to all the other pages of the website.
There's no related posts yet, but that even looks good.
And even the forms down here, this form.
Oh yeah.
You just make a comment, right?
That would be in the all caps right there if you want to, but that's all changeable and looking good.
So that was a great way to customize one of these special custom bodies inside the TV theme builder
just for blog posts.
Now, keep in mind the power of this functionality here within the device settings under theme builder
and being able to define which pages and which type page types you want these custom designed to be
on.
Remember, I said then, that what that means is that the client or the website owner can go in, and
if they wanted to just edit a post, all they do is go into that post and they can use this traditional
WordPress default block editor, which is a little more simple than using the divvy builder.
They need to remember to put a featured image in and just use headings, copy images, way they like,
and it's going to come out just looking great, no matter what the way you want your design to match.
So there's one more interesting thing that we can do as we open this, you know, block editor content
area to content managers or clients that want to manage their blog posts.
Not only can you let them use the block editor and style it how you want using the divvy builder, you
can also have them bring in pre-built sections made with divvy that can be laid inside of the content
here.
Let's take a look.
There's actually a Divvy Gutenberg block or block that you can use and style it yourself and save it
into the Devi library.
And so what we'll do is first, let's just build a sample page.
We do this because we want to use a pre-built layout and use the entire power of the Devi builder in
order to make the layout we want.
I'm going to bring in a section from one of the pre-built layouts from the travel agency pages, and
then we'll use that in the Devi library and save it as a layout so that then when you're, you know,
editing or building a blog post, you can use a Devi block and import that content in.
Let's take a look at how it works.
Let's see if I just go, so I'm going to go tour packages.
I'm just going to call this tour package and click Use the Devi Builder.
And what I'm going to do is bring a pre-made layout in, you could use an existing page, which is which
could be one of our packages.
One of our pages here called packages.
Or we could go into that travel layout and use the packages layout.
We haven't really edited it, but you, if you had this is a good place where you can bring in an existing
page from your website.
So I just brought in this whole page, and I'm going to use one of these sections here now there a row
layout.
And in order to save it as a page layout in the TV library, we need to save this entire page.
Now, of course, it doesn't include the header and it doesn't include the footer down here, but this
page content inside.
I want to basically delete everything except the one piece that I'm going to be using.
So I'm going to use the wireframe builder to make it easier to do that.
I can see that under packages this section, I've got multiple rows, each one called package, and
so I'm going to delete everything except one of the packages.
Maybe the second to last one is one that I thought looked good for this process.
And so what I'll do is go up and I'm going to leave the blue section intact, but I'm going to start
deleting these row layouts using the little trashcan.
So the title.
And now there's four of these.
I want to delete the first two one two.
Now there's two left.
I'm going to delete the bottom package right here.
And now what I have is a section with my row that I'm looking for right inside of it here.
And now this bottom section called offer.
I'll delete that and then I'll do it the more places section as well.
So what I'm left with is one single blue section with a row and a number of modules, and that is what
I'm looking to bring into the DV library so that I can use it later.
So now that I have that here, what I want to do is save this as an entire page layout.
And so instead of using either the section or the row little down arrow here, that's for, you know,
save to library.
I want to go down here to the bottom row, use this purple down arrow, which will save it as an entire
page layout.
So I'm going to call this tour package.
That might be something that's descriptive inside of the device library for a content manager to use
later.
So I'll just click Save Library, Save to Library.
Now I can just save this page as a draft because it's more of my building area that I that I was using,
and we won't we won't want to publish that as a page on the website.
So now that I've saved it as a draft, I can go back into the dashboard and let's just take a look in
the Div Library under Divvy Div Library.
Now, of course, you've seen the parallax footer and the newsletter footer that we created that were
sections in the DV library, but here the tour package is called a layout.
That's how we have to label that and and save it as an entire page layout to be able to bring that section
into a blog post in the Block editor.
So let's take a look at how that works inside of this blog post, I was thinking below the image and,
you know, maybe in the middle of this big block of text, we'll put that call to action tour package
block inside of there.
So one thing I can do, I'll just go back into the TV and the WordPress dashboard and go to posts and
I'll edit that post.
This is as if I were, you know, a content manager on the website, just using the block editor for
posts.
Maybe I'll just go in here and I can hit enter to start a new area and I can hit Plus to get a new block.
Or I could go over here and hit plus and look at the list of blocks, you know, and look for the divvy
block.
Or I can even start typing.
And if you type, Slash even says right here, if you type a forward slash and I hit the deaky, you
could see that there is a block called divvy layout.
And so, you know, if you're here and you start typing divvy, oops.
You can see that there's a divvy layout block and over.
Let's see.
Let's get rid of this slash right here over here with the plus button.
You can also just start typing Deivi and see that there's a div layout.
So now that brings in a block, which is a developer, then it's easiest just to load from the library,
especially if you're a user that doesn't know how to really build with DV and you're just using the
Block editor.
So I'll click load from library, and all I have to do is click my saved layouts here under this tab,
and you'll see that it shows me all of the different full layouts that I've saved in the DV library.
I just have one here, so a quick tour package and it brings it in just like a complete page layout
into a blank page.
And there we go now because of the content with you can see that it.
Instead of placing it to the left and right, it's got the larger image at the top.
And you can do things like, you know, you can you can edit this layout by clicking this little edit
layout button, and it opens a window where you can edit this layout, block itself.
And so while while this is right here, you know, one thing you might do is just maybe reduce the space
at the top and bottom.
Here I could lock that.
And then just reduce the space, maybe down to 45 pixels.
Go down here and click Save and exit.
Now that's editing the layout block and saving it directly into the DV library.
And by doing that, you could see that, you know, it actually did bring the image over to the left
hand side.
But if I just click Update and then go back to the blog post and refresh the page, now I've got that
really nice TV layout sitting in line inside of the text.
You can, you know, make sure that the button works.
The user can edit this text by, you know, editing the DV block, as I showed you there.
It's just a really powerful way to make inset divvy powered layouts available to the content manager.