In this lesson, we'll finish customizing the 2022 site by creating a landing page without a header,
you use a blank page template to remove the header and footer and a full page block pattern for the
content.
Finally, we'll add a footer back into the page content with a custom background color to match the
pattern.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how to remove a header for a single page and create a custom
footer as well.
Last but not least, let's take a look at this film page.
And so we have a different background color, a different layout.
Now this, I know, is a block pattern that I saw.
It was an entire page block pattern, but we've got no header and then we have a slightly different
footer because it has a different background color as well.
And so we'll have to change the templates a little bit, but let's take a look.
Right now, our film page is just a standard WordPress page inside of our site with the regular white
header and regular white footer.
Oh, also, the menu is down here on the left hand side, but let's go ahead and take a look.
First of all, film, and let's just take a look at the black patterns that are available here.
I don't think it was one of the featured ones, but it might have been a page, was it whole pages?
Here it is right here.
Page layout with image, text and video, I'm going to place that in there.
And now when I want to remove the header, that's not that hard.
I just instead of default template, I go to a blank template that's going to remove the header at the
top.
And then, of course, the footer will probably be the traditional footer down there on the blank template.
So we'll see what we have to do there.
Let's take a look at it.
All right.
Really getting somewhere now over here.
The yeah, it's a little different, isn't it?
Yeah, I wonder if I want to bring this page design into an entire template.
So actually now it's blank, so I have no footer and no header.
There might be a different strategy here for this film page.
Yeah, let's let's see about.
I'm sorry about just taking this entire group, removing it now.
And we want to use a different template.
So a blank template, maybe not.
Let's just look at the default template and hit update.
That's the way it was before.
This is going to bring it back into just a blank page like this.
Maybe I want to bring the footer into the page itself, and then let's just look at the templates that
we have.
First of all, it's an interesting problem solving task.
Click Editor.
Let's look at our templates that we already have.
Mm hmm.
That's the home template.
Single page is the template that's the.
There's page no title was the that's the the default is this page template right here.
Single post, single post.
And then there's a page with no title.
Page with a large header, so there's blank.
And I think what I what I do want to do is I think what I'll do is I can't really add a new template
except for front page template with that free me up to use this template, potentially.
Let's take a look at this home template.
And this template contains.
A bunch of things I can commandeer this template and then recreate this template as that home template,
that would be one way to do it.
But let's go back here.
Let's go back into pages and bring that page layout into the film page content area.
First of all, and use the blank template, and then I'll just add the footer to this page.
That makes sense.
I go to patterns and where was that it was four pages.
Mm hmm.
Here's the full page template that I want him back to page in the Settings panel.
I want to use a blank template.
And now, you know, I want to add a footer down here.
So if I say plus and let's see, just look for some footers, these are just a couple of footers.
Let's browse all blocks.
I'm just adding blocks here.
Now, I might want to add a pattern.
I want to find a footer pattern that matches.
No, it's not quite here.
I want a footer that has a menu on the left and then, you know, that little message on the right,
so here's a colored footer.
This is the one footer with a query block, a title and a citation.
So let's just take the.
All right, I added it.
I added it in a weird spot.
So let's just move it down and move it down again.
And move it down once again.
Now it's at the bottom of the page.
This is going to look good.
Now let's use the list view so that I can get to this group here.
And really, I don't need the post template or space or anything.
I really just need this row right here.
I might need that spacer.
But what I can do is just get rid of this query loop.
There we go.
OK, this is the bottom of the template, and then I have those two.
So update.
And of course, over here I could add a navigation menu like I have up at the top.
But let's take a look at my work so far.
So refresh that page.
Yeah, I need to make this heading a little bit smaller and then add some space at the top.
But otherwise, I'm looking pretty good.
And this at the bottom, that looks quite good.
Yeah, but I need the menu down here.
Yeah.
So I can add all pages down there at the bottom.
So right here, what is this?
It's in each one.
Make that a little bit.
Oops.
I that a little smaller into an age to an update, first of all.
Hmm.
Maybe a little too small.
And no space at the top.
So.
Say.
I could go back to in one.
Didn't seem to get as big, did it?
I wonder if that's going to be the right size now.
That's still nice and big anyway.
A little bit different, but that's OK.
I can probably really customize that each one size if I want to by looking at this block and I can customize
the size right here.
Yeah, so.
Size extra large.
Or size, custom?
See?
I still want that to be a header.
I can even add boldness if I want to.
So, you know, you can see where you can you can play with this a little bit.
See what 48 pixels looks like.
Sixty four.
Pretty close.
Sixty eight looks pretty good, let's see if that reflects the same looking size on the front end.
Yeah, just need a spacer at the top.
Oops.
Compare those two sizes.
Yeah.
You guys know how I can add a space or don't you?
Where would I add it in this?
Just above this heading.
I could just add.
Start to type, spacer, yeah, and let's bring it up and let's bring it up.
There we go.
Leave 100 pixel space are there and see what that looks like.
That's better.
Now we're getting somewhere.
Oops.
Yeah.
Compare the two.
Texas a little bit smaller.
So, you know, this is what you do, maybe go up to 70 to.
Oops!
Refresh the page that brings it up nicely.
OK.
Really getting somewhere now?
Lastly, should I add a menu down here to the bottom left?
That's going to be on the page here.
Let's go to the list view and go back down.
So in this row, we have a paragraph.
Oops!
I see, OK, so this is a roadblock.
And what do we have over here?
That is a site title block.
So instead of site title, here's the group.
Yeah.
So there's a spacer and then in this row there's a site title and then there's another row after it's
within the same row.
And then there's that paragraph text.
So I really want to take this role really right next to this site title.
Well, as a navigation.
And then I could select menu.
I've been it's the system has been creating all these additional copies of the header, a header navigation.
So I'm just going to choose the latest one.
Nice.
Let's go back to the list for you.
That navigation, that's navigation, where I added the HomeLink.
And so that's fine, that's what this one looks like anyway.
So.
Maybe get rid of this site title.
Oh, now we're getting somewhere.
Perfect update.
See what we have.
Nice looking great.
All right, I think we have a good copy of the page.
You could see how you have to experiment a little bit, especially working with this new interface,
the site editor and using templates, et cetera.
But now we have a nice copy of the page.
Now, of course, the header navigation is missing, but conveniently it's located down here navigation.
So we've got that page with the blog posts.
Each of the blog posts, the title and the featured image clickable to the blog post itself.
Very nice.
The about page has the large header.
We're using different template for that, and it also has a group or a block pattern, which was a group,
and it contained a query block looking at three posts, the three latest posts in reverse order and
then a different group where we would join our mailing list and we can add an opt in form there.
Same footer as always, the event page.
We got rid of the title by doing a little bit of sleuthing to figure out how we could make a template
that did not have a title showing and used that template.
We also used a block pattern to match.
And then finally, the film page where we used a blank pattern so it didn't have.
And then we we compensated for that blank pattern by placing the footer in here using another block
pattern within.
And this was a whole page design block pattern included in the 20 22 theme.
Awesome.
Well, that does it for matching our demo site.
I really think that was a fun project.
I hope you learn something there.
And next, we'll get into other options in WordPress for using pre-designed templates, as well as more
features that we can get if we get away from the new site editor and use the previous functionality,
which most themes are using these days under appearance, customize and different spots like that.
All right.
See in the next one.