In this lesson, we'll explore some of the more than 50 divvy modules available in the divvy builder.
You'll see how to customize several of the modules, including an image module and a couple number counter
modules, as well as see how a gradient can work in a section background to allow for an interesting,
overlapping image design by the end of this video.
You'll see the power of the various modules to hold and design any kind of content you can imagine,
all within a visual interface using TV.
Let's look a little bit deeper into the divvy modules in this next section.
Now, if you remember from the outline the mind map for the TV theme and builder, the modules was one
of the largest and longest sections with the most items in there.
These are all the different modules that are available in DV at this point.
All these modules do different things, and you can see by their titles what they are.
Now, we're not going to go through all of these individual modules because once you know how a module
works, it's easy to get in there and explore what it can do and what it's for and how to edit it using
those three tabs, the content design and advanced tabs inside of the editing window.
And so there's two categories of modules.
There is a full width module section that has just a few.
There's a four with map, four with header and menu and a slider module, as well as a portfolio module
that's designed to kind of break out of the box of the website and go full width.
It's a good way to design hero images and things like that, but a regular module, for example, you
know, an image module or even just using a section with a background image and just making that go
to the size of the full screen is another way to get a hero image or some content to stretch all the
way to the browser window.
And so I don't use the full width modules very much, but you may find them useful and quick for designing
headers or things like that.
But let's just take a look at some of the modules by going back into our layout and just look at a few
of the modules in the case study page here in your sample site in the sandbox.
And so let's click Enable Visual Builder and go in there and check out some of the modules.
Now I've showed you the text module and what that is all about.
And so as we go down a little bit further inside of this specialty section, there's a module here and
a module in each of these sections.
It's an image module.
And so I'm just going to click the Edit Section Edit button here for this image module.
And so it says image settings.
The image module is pretty self-explanatory.
You know, it's got a place to load an image.
There's a Settings panel, or if you just click the image, it will bring up a window that lets you
either upload a file to the media library or look at the media library and find an image for that area.
So there's the image module, and let's take a look at.
Let's take a look at some more down here.
Let's see what we have going on right down here.
This section, then we have I can see a row layout where it's outlined in the green and that rolling
out goes all the way down to where this green plus is.
And then this one called the numbers is overlapping, and I can see that since this is a section and
the yellow comes up here, we can try to discover why that's set up or how that setup is there a negative
margin, maybe in the sections settings here that would be maybe under spacing.
So there's a there's some padding right there and that's padding on this section that's showing just
top and bottom padding for the content going in there.
So that's not really where that is overlapping.
Let's take a look at.
So this I see that this yellow might actually be part of the upper section.
Let's take a look at this section now and see design wise or actually under the content.
What what is the background?
There's not really anything as far as the background, but what about the columns?
The left column doesn't have any background, so you can hit this back button if you're editing a.
Column within a row.
That's something to know for sure.
How about this right hand column?
No, that's not there either.
So let's go back and I'll close this row layout, and let's see, let's look at this section layout
now, see what the background looks like.
OK, I can see what's going on here.
So this right here is a gradient, and that's how they got this background section to have mostly white
and then change into the yellow background just at the very bottom.
So it's a linear gradient at a direction of 180 degrees, which is up and down and a start position
of 80 percent and an end position of 80 percent.
And what that means is that that makes a solid line instead of a gradient where the percentage is,
you know, at a different spot and it gradually fades to the color.
These are the two gradient colors.
One is white, the next one is yellow.
So it's going from white to yellow.
It's going in the 180 degree direction, so it's going from top to bottom.
The start position is a percentage up or down.
And so if they are exactly the same, it starts in one spot and then it ends in the other spot in the
same spot, I should say.
Same percentage that makes a line in a particular place instead of a gradient.
So instead of using negative margin to bring a background color of a section up, what it's done is
just it's use an illusion by matching the background color from one section to the next and used the
gradient function in background.
So that's a really interesting design method that you can do without code and make some interesting
layouts like what what happens is it appears as if this image is overlapping the lower section.
But really, it's not.
This yellow is part of the upper section.
So that's a very interesting piece of design work there in Divij in this pre-made layout and this look
at these these modules that we have here.
It says the numbers.
Now this one is a bar counter module.
And so I don't know if you noticed, but if we refresh the page and then bring back this section here,
you'll see that the bar counter animates itself.
Oops.
I've got the visual builder open, and so it's not going to animate correctly.
Let me exit the visual builder here.
And then as we scroll down, you'll see that bar counter will animate there.
And if you if you caught that and as well this, there's no counter below animated as well.
And so see if I refresh the page here, you can see there's the bar counter and the number counter.
So let's take a look at these two modules enable the visual builder, and then I'll scroll down to that
section of the page.
And let's look at those no modules.
So the the bar counter, you know, when you add a new bar counter just gives you some options.
The text of it, the percentage, how much is it going to go up?
You know, maybe it goes up to 88 percent if there's a link to that bar itself, whether there's a background
or anything within that bar, you can do a lot of design for it.
The text title goes here.
This is the number of.
Something.
Hmm.
Now, of course, that's capitalized, right?
Where do you think that's found under design title text?
And there is title font style capitalized.
Right?
And so that's what that is back here under content.
That's where you would put it in a new a new bar counter.
Let's go ahead and get rid of that one for these as well.
You know the elements that you want to show, do you want to show the percentage or not?
And that's just making it a little bit big.
The percent there in the title instead of just showing without.
Is that right?
I'm not sure what that elements.
What's changing there?
Oh, conversion rate 90 percent, right?
So that's actually in the text title itself.
And then under design for this particular bar.
Anyway, let's go back, we're doing the the module settings right here showing the percentage.
Oh, I don't know what that is.
Anyway, there's a lot of things you can discover here and then if there's a background in the entire
module itself.
But design wise, you know what, text, what the text would look like.
The bar design here as far as the background color.
In the entire settings and then all the other different settings that we went over before, also the
advanced settings in terms of the seaside etc position, scroll effects or transitions, this would
be like if it comes behind an object that's next to it or not, etc. And so that's the bar counter.
There's so many settings to play with.
Each of these is a number counter.
And so again, it animates the counting up from zero.
And then there's different things that you can that you can actually control like, you know, the the
spacing, the text size, the color, the alignment, the font, all of these things are available.
And as far as that and what elements are shown, whether the sign is shown or not in there, whether
there's a link, a background ET.
And so like I said, I'm not going to show you all of the modules that are available in DV because there
are so many.
But you can discover a lot about them by inspecting some of these pre-made layouts as well as trying
them out yourself.
Now this one's interesting if to put an embedded video in a DV page.
There's a really nice default layout in the video module where you know it has this hover overlay,
a nice play button and then a customized image.
No matter whether you're, you know, you might be just bringing in a video from a URL like this one
is you can just put the YouTube URL right in here and it will place that video in.
So, for example, I'm not going to pull one in right now, but you get what I mean.
If.
Let me just go back out of that, you can use a webcam file on your website or you can use a video actually
coming from the media library, which is not recommended if you want to put, you know, video on your
website.
You should actually hosted at YouTube or Vimeo Wistia, someplace that can host your video for you instead
of having it come from your web site.
But then there's different things like the overlay, whether that's an image and overlay image, you
can generate it from the video or not.
You can use, you know, a background if you want to and then choose the video itself.
As far as the design, you can choose the different play icon and what that size might be.
You know, you could bring that video play icon larger or smaller.
There's just a lot of design options the overlay options, for example, for that roll over.
You know what, if I wanted to actually go, you know, oof, yellow now that that went all the way
to a solid yellow.
But if I edit that and then bring the opacity down now, I could do a yellow overlay in that video instead
of a gray.
And that's interesting and matches the website.
And so that's a good overview of some of the modules that are available in DV.
There are so many more, but that will give us a good start.
And as we modify and create more websites in DeFi, as the course goes on, we'll be exploring more
of these modules and what they do and how we can leverage them in order to build unique websites quickly
and easily.