In this lesson, we'll explore global colors and presets and how to assign them so that changing a content
piece in one place can affect every instance across an entire website.
You'll assign colors and also presets for particular module types like the divider module in this example
to make both initial designing and changing designs in the future faster.
By the end of this video, you'll understand how preparing colors and content modules with global assignments
saves design time and also makes sitewide revisions possible.
Let's take a look at under the global elements section here of the DV theme and builder curriculum.
The just global colors where you can work with your layout and when you're customizing it, you can
save colors as a global element and then when there's multiple areas that use that color on the website.
If you need to make an edit in the future, or even while you're developing a website for a client,
if you're if you have areas labeled with particular colors, you can change that global color in one
place and then every version, every instance of that color across the entire website will change.
It's a good way to future proof your website and make it really easy to go ahead and change things.
As far as looking at colors, and so if we go into one of our pages here, let's look at the landing
page because it has quite a lot of content that we can use and maybe we can look at, you know, one
of the colors that we have being used inside the website.
One of them is this red, right?
This red is used in these dividing lines, as well as in the header up here inside of the website.
And so if we look back at the dashboard, let's just go back into the pages, all pages, and let's
just open up that landing page and just take a look now at it with the device builder could get here
from using the visual builder button up at the top there as well.
But once this is open, I can go down here and look at this content area right down here.
So I'm just going to open up this module, which is a divider and the divider is visible.
And if we look at the way it's designed, we can look at the line and the line color.
And so the color selector in any module, you'll see that there are a bunch of pre-selected colors that
kind of come by default in Divij.
And then there's a few other areas.
There's saved colors.
There's a global selection here.
There's a recent and then there's a settings panel for colors right down here.
And you've seen me work with this before.
If you click the color selector and you can use the opacity and the color intensity sliders, you can
use your mouse to move around and select colors on the rainbow screen.
Like this, you know, brighter and more saturated at the top.
Desaturated and down towards blacks at the bottom.
Far in know through the rainbow of colors off to the left.
Then you know you click the little checkbox to choose the color right there.
Now, once you choose that color, you can also actually open up this little three button color selector
window, and it gives you a much more widely, you know, a much wider variety of colors that are,
you know, selected here for you.
And so if you do select a color right here, let's just close that back up again.
You can go and under global, you can hit the plus button.
And so if once I've hit that plus button, I've given, you know, I've left that kind of teal color
selected and so I can just go ahead and add click that checkbox or I can make some changes if I want
to.
And what I've just done is I've saved that color to a global color and the little corner little corner
at the bottom right of the color circle.
The representation of that color indicates that it's a global color.
And then under here you can also look at saved colors.
Those are the ones that are saved by default in Devi.
And I'll show you right now where those are changeable as well as you know, it'll show you recent colors
and give you a variety of different levels of a variety of colors based on that color.
And you can see the global global colors here.
And then the Little Settings panel, you know, gives you a representation of what you've been doing.
You can then can you put that global color in the trash or say, OK, I'm going to finish editing,
finish what I was doing?
And so now if I hit the checkmark, you can see that that line is that green color.
And so if.
If I go into design and sizing, I might just bring that divider up a little bit as far as size, just
so we can see it a little bit better on the page here.
Now let's go ahead and save the page.
Now, if now, if I go down into a lower section of the page and I see that this dividing line is back
to the original color, now I can go ahead and go to design.
And I can look at the line design and I can click global and that colors available to me.
So now if I choose that color and let's go ahead and make that a little bit bigger as well back up to
that 12 pixel size.
Now, when I save the page and save the module, those two dividing lines are now connected.
Right, those those are using that global color.
And so when we change things on the website, including things in the header and things on different
pages of the website, even if there's tens of hundreds or tens or thousands of pages that are using
that global color, every single instance across the entire website will change when you change the
global color anywhere on the website.
And that's the power of the global colors.
And so suppose I'm in here, you know, I can see that these these two are the teal color.
The client is like, you know that that teal color needs to go back to red.
Let's bring that back to the red, and we'll make it kind of a bright red.
And so you could say, OK, well, I've got the entire website.
If you've prepared it like this, I've got the entire website using that global color so I could go
in here and edit it anywhere on the site.
I could go under design and find that global color area.
And I can say, you know what, I that that needs to change.
So you click the global color and now I'm editing that global color.
And so I can go back up into, you know, a different area.
I go up into this bright red up here on the right side, and when I click the little checkmark, it
gives me a modal window.
It says, Are you sure you've made changes to this global color?
It affects all instances.
And so if you're sure that that's what you want to do, you click Yes.
And then when you save that that module, you can see that everywhere that that global color was being
used, it changed it into the new color.
And so I can save this page.
And when I go to somewhere else that was using that global color, it changes it into that color.
It's a really powerful way to arrange for items on the website to be globally controlled, to make it
a lot easier to change design in the future.
Make and save your time as far as your workflow.
Not only can you define global colors to be used around the website that you can use when you're designing,
but you can also define global presets, and you can even make yourself a style guide to hold all of
those presets and edit them as you will.
So let's check out the idea of global presets before we go ahead and import one to see how it all works
if we go back into our page here.
Under this divider that we styled with a wider line and in particular a global color, if we go to the
settings of this module, you may have noticed under the title of the of the editing area on all sections
and rows and modules, there is a preset area with a dropdown.
Often they're labeled with the word default and the dropdown.
That's how they come in by default, of course.
But what you can do is you can define a preset, which basically means when you bring in a divider module.
In this case, you can choose to bring it in as a particular preset and you can define more than one
preset.
So you can be like, OK, a red divider or a wide divider, a medium divider and a skinny divider.
Or you can have a, you know, different colors and you can see that this can be extended out to typography
or full sections where you can have a preset defined to make it easy to design new pages and bring new
content into the website, especially during the design process at the beginning.
And so one thing you can do is go ahead and just choose this dropdown where it says default and click
Create new preset from default styles, from existing styles.
And is that what it said?
Yeah, create new preset from current styles.
So after you've style that, you could say, Well, now that I made this, I want to I want to be available
everywhere.
So, you know, in addition to being able to just save that to the library and then bring it in and
use it later, you can also set a preset which.
Makes your workflow even faster.
And so this one would be, you know, you would call it divider wide, read something like that, some
words that can make sense to you as you're doing your design, and then you can assign this preset to
the default preset or just leave the default as it was before, which is probably wise because this
is a new design.
And you just click the the checkbox there and you saw the control window flip over and turn gray.
That means that now we are editing the actual preset itself, not this particular module, the divider
module, but we're actually editing the entire preset.
And so you can look at design, you can make those design changes like this, you know, for this module.
But generally, once I've designed it and saved it as a preset, I'll just click the checkbox to save
that preset and then save again.
And now I have a preset available to me while I'm designing.
That's different from the default preset.
You know, if you open it back up, you can see that it shows which preset it's using.
And if I wanted to, I could go back and say, Well, this, you know, I actually if I have divider,
preset one and divider wide read, I actually did change the default preset and so I made a new one
there.
But let's see what happens when we close that we can go down to a new section here.
And, you know, if maybe I just get rid of this divider, if I go to the plus button, this is for
the presets really work when you're adding new modules from scratch, but you don't want to just build
them yourself.
So I'm going to add a divider module because I know I have a new preset available and I've just added
the divider module and it's ready for me to customize it.
But instead of doing each one by itself instead of default, I can choose divider wide read and you
could see that it put it in there now.
The divider wide read was a justified to the left, wasn't it?
And so if I'm in here and I'm like, Well, I want this to be a centered one, I might make another
preset after I've designed it, so I'll take design and on this is it.
Now, let's see.
Let's let's look at how we can edit this for that line.
I want it vertically centered.
Sure.
Um, sizing and spacing.
Here we go.
That module alignment, I want to be centered instead of left aligned.
So now that I've changed that, I can go up here and say create a new preset from the current styles.
And so this preset is going to be a new version of that same one.
And if I rename it.
I can say divider wide read Senate, and now when I click that green bar and then I click the checkbox,
I should say turns to this editor, which is a preset editor in the gray.
And then I click the checkbox again.
Now I can save that and I have a different type of preset available to me.
So suppose right here, I know that this might be I could just get rid of that module.
I know that I want to add a new module here, so I'll click the Plus button and let's make it a divider
module.
And what I want is to choose from my presets.
And so which one I want the wide read, which is left justified, which I know is this one.
So all I have to do is select that.
And now I've brought that divider in, and all the styles are preset.
And so that can show you that shows you the power of the presets and how you can use those and build
them as you go, so that later as you're building custom layouts, those presets are available to you.
So just do one more here.
This one's a left justified one.
So I'm putting in a new divider.
I want to use the left justified preset and save it.
There it is, so I can go ahead and get rid of this one.
And I have my new preset there and I can save the page that just shows you the power of presets and
you can use presets on any kind of content area.
You can have modules, you can have rows that have presets and you can label them.
For example, this might be for column links row, and the preset would look exactly like this, and
you could re-use it anywhere that you want cetera.
It's just another way to speed up your design workflow so that in DV, you really have a powerful and
fast way to design custom and unique websites.
One more quick thing to show you about using the presets.
When I first built this one, I actually did save it as the default preset.
It made it divider preset one.
But when I'm in here say I did change it into divider wide read and save it.
OK, now when I go ahead and edit this module here, if I wanted to edit the rest of those, I could
open up the presets window here and I could go to divider wide read and I could edit the preset styles.
And so that's where you can re flip the card over to the gray preset editor.
And what if I wanted to make the line the sizing of that line, not 12 pixels, but I wanted to reduce
it back down to six?
Let's say if I save the changes on that now again, just like the global colors.
This will affect all the divider modules across the entire site that are using this preset.
So if I say yes right here, divider wide read, let's look at the the the line sizing here as well.
Let's bring that back down to six.
There's the six, and that's the default four divider wide red.
So let's save that.
OK, now let's let's go ahead and look again.
If I open it up under divider wide read and I go to edit now, that design should have persisted under
sizing.
So it's six pixels and the width is 150.
Sure.
So I didn't edit anything here so I could go and get out of it.
But if I scroll back down, you can see that even this one has changed its width to six.
But what about the other one that's centered?
No, the one that centered is still 12, and so it's very similar to the global colors.
Once you have a number of different modules or sections that are using a preset, then when you change
that actual preset setting by flipping the card over using a little pencil icon, then that will change
everything on the entire site.
That's using that preset.
Again, like the global colors, it enables you to make changes in the future, even if there's hundreds
or thousands of instances of that section.
Just the power of the div builder and using it visually in the visual builder.