In this lesson, we'll check out the default header and footer settings in Devi and learn how to customize
them.
You'll learn the different locations in the WordPress dashboard, where you can edit those, including
the site logo, navigation menus and different features of the header and footer.
By the end of this video, you'll understand the simple default header and footer system included with
DeFi and how to utilize it for a simple but customized design.
Now, let's finish up with the design agency layout pack by looking at this traditional or default header
area.
Customizing it a little bit, even though knowing that we're going to be customizing a much more powerful
header design system later in the next section in Divij Part two.
But for now, just know that you know this is a usable header section that that you can use.
If you want something simple, you can customize it as far as the background color, whether it's sticky
or not, how much it shrinks, what the logo looks like and everything up here.
But let's customize this just so you know what you're doing as far as the default header in divvy.
For now, you can see that every page that we've added is in there, plus an uncategorized navigation
label, and that's for the blog post categories.
And of course, Uncategorized is, by default, the the the only category in there.
You have to have one default category, at least in the blog post system in WordPress.
You can relabeled that create a new one called news or something generic versus uncategorized, which
isn't very pretty when it appears on the front of the website.
Also, you can see by default it comes with a search function right here that is a nice little layout
that opens up a search bar instead of the navigation menu.
And we'll also look at the default widget ties to area down here at the footer and then the footer bar
down here at the bottom.
That's kind of a final customization of this layout pack that we've been using in this section of the
course.
So let's go back and look in the sandbox dashboard again or your own dashboard if you're using your
own hosting in your own device license.
But inside of the website dashboard, let's first look under.
Actually, let's look under Divij theme options.
There's a couple of places that we can replace some of the content in this header.
The first is the logo area.
This logo is really only used in the default header under appearance, customize under header settings.
And so if you do want to, you can click Upload, go to the media library.
And if you do have a small and a header.
Excuse me, a small logo image, you can upload it there and it will replace that default div logo that
you see right here.
And so I'll just close out of that and the fixed navigation bar.
You can either enable or disable that and just taking a look if we disable that and then click save
changes and look for the green checkbox there, checkmark there and reflect refresh the page on the
front here.
Let's see what happens here.
Well, that means that the label navigation header, excuse me, is no longer fixed or sticky to the
top of the page.
And so that's a more traditional, you know, navigation header.
But of course, the fixed navigation bar is a nice feature, the way it shrinks a little bit.
When the user scrolls, if you use that feature at all and recently I have used this when I didn't need
a customized or colorful or navigation header that was full of features.
It was easiest and best for the client side to just edit the font and the weight of the font and what
the navigation items are, and then edit all that into what was needed for the website at the time.
So let's let's edit what's going on here with the navigation items.
So what we have right here are under theme options navigation the right now.
There's no menu under appearance menus.
There's no menu associated with this primary navigation area.
And so it's really pulling in every page that is within the website.
And so all these pages are in there, and if we wanted to exclude any of the pages, all we'd have to
do is click the checkbox and then save.
And then that page would be eliminated from the navigation there.
And then there's a couple other options, like displaying the home link or the dropdown menus, enabling
those dropdown menus.
You can see that it shows home and that it also shows home.
And it did.
Replace and that's because we have not only this home, but we have the display HomeLink selected here.
Now this display, HomeLink will show and be correct no matter which page you have associated with home.
And so if you're going to use, it might be best to just take away this home a page called home and
then have this display.
HomeLink enabled that way.
No matter what pages you have here, the home link will work and it won't show, you know, every and
won't show double right there.
And so lastly, you know, oh, just here, it eliminated the blog post category.
But if we look here under categories, the uncategorized was enabled there.
But what you can do is just hit this checkbox.
Not sure why that disappeared there at that point?
Maybe it was because I got rid of the home navigation and also got rid of the uncategorized.
But if I say save changes, if you wanted to just get rid of the category menu items, then that would
eliminate that from there.
And then let's see what else.
Just in general settings this feature, you know, if you want to disable for something where there's
a drop down, you want to disable the top tier and you want only the dropdown items to be selectable
or clickable, then you can click this here and save it.
But let's look at appearance.
Customize a couple of different things.
Under the customizer here, the header navigation when you look at the format, of course, is a couple
of different formats we've seen before.
The default is what we have here, or Senate or senator centered with the inline logo in between the
items slide in and full screen.
All those different settings we've looked at as far as format.
Oh, and then now, excuse me, header navigation header format enable vertical navigation, which would
be like down the side or hide the navigation until scroll is interesting.
You could have no navigation until the user scrolls.
And so under primary, this is where you control your different colors and things like that, and the
different fonts and the sizing and everything and even how big that the logo gets so you can make the
logo get, you know, a little bit bigger, depending on.
Let's see if I want to just shrink that down and make it smaller, for example, while it's in the primary
menu bar.
So the menu all the way I scrolled up and extended here is the primary menu bar.
And you can make it full width so that the items spread themselves out to the full width or not.
You could hide the logo image here, and those are the settings there.
The secondary menu bar.
Now we don't have it enabled right now because we don't have a menu inside the secondary menu bar,
but that puts a smaller row or any size you want.
Really up above the primary menu bar, you can put extra menu items up there, which is often a good
way to go or a special marketing message across the top.
It's kind of like a welcome bar or a hello bar, you might say at the top of the website that you can
use and menu items can go into it and then fixed navigation settings or what this looks like when you
scroll up and it's sitting here.
And so the fixed menu height, it gets smaller when you scroll.
And so, you know, I could make it get even smaller if I wanted to, you know, way down, small if
I wanted to.
You can play with that kind of thing if you want to.
You can even hide the logo image, you know, only on scroll, which is an interesting way to go, too.
So there's a lot of different color choices and a lot of choices you can make.
And then the header elements.
Finally, this is where the search icon comes in at the top.
You can get rid of that or put it in there.
You can also put social items now that's bringing up a strange side menu over there.
But oftentimes that can be usable depending on what kind of menu you're using.
You can also put a phone number, you know, and that might that could appear, you know, over on the
side, wherever you can see that come up with after you publish or an email address, even up in the
side there.
And I'm just going to get out of here without publishing, so I don't change any of the things here,
but that's pretty much it for the traditional or default header in divvy.
Let's just look lastly at the footer area.
You know, down here at the bottom, there are two parts to this footer.
Actually, you can just barely make out a slightly different color.
One is where there's widgets across here in different columns, and then this is the bottom bar it's
called.
You can see social icons on the right and then a kind of a credits on the left hand side here.
And so that's often used.
That's under the theme custom.
Pfizer as well, so I'll reopen that customizer and under footer, you can see, first of all, the
bottom bar down here.
That would be down that, you know, you can get the color and the text color, et cetera, down here.
The footer credits.
If you just wanted to disable these footer credits that are by default pointing to elegant themes and
WordPress, you can just click that box to disable those credits.
And then whether these icons are showing or not is actually this is this is the size and color of those
social icons, et cetera.
This is that's the text color that it's using down there.
But to get to get rid of the social icons in the bottom bar you, you would actually go back to the
theme customizer.
Let's just go back there real quick.
So you know where this is located and under the theme options, not the theme customizer, but the options
under general.
That's where you have these social icons enabled or not.
This just represents a link, and you would, of course, paste the Facebook profile link, et cetera,
in here.
But if you wanted to remove any or all of these automatic ones, you could do that and then hit Save.
Look for the green checkbox here.
And of course, if we refresh the page, you'll see those disappear if you wanted to get rid of the
whole bottom bar.
You could go back to the customizer after removing those social icons.
Go to footer and bottom bar and then, you could say, disable footer credits.
And so that'll show no bottom bar at all.
But often people put a copy, right?
And then, you know, the business name and the year down at the bottom, and you can play with having
some text down there.
Sometimes people will put, you know, something like, you know, site design by and have your business
name with a link to your business in case people like the site and want to get in touch with you.
And so that's something that you can do as well.
I'll just disable the four footer credits here now in the next section.
Davey Part two, we're going to be customizing this entire footer area.
So the bottom will be irrelevant anyway.
But let's finally look at this footer area down here, and that is actually, oh, you can also put
a footer menu.
I should say, if you do have a menu enabled for the footer area over there, we'll look at what else
down here.
Oh, you can also make these social icons disappear just with this checkbox under footer elements as
well.
And then the widgets area, you can control the header size and the color of these widgets that are
in here.
But where do you control the content of those widgets?
Well, before we do that, the layout, you can control it as far as the columns.
These are just different column layouts that would be a three column layout.
The footer background color.
Of course, you could have a, you know, 50 fifty one where you could have a small and a large in there.
And so that's something that's controllable, but widgets under appearance widgets.
That's where these, you know, default footer widgets are found and there's actually six possible footer
widgets, air widget areas that are included with the device theme.
And of course, under Widget Area, Footer Area one, we have the two that are located there.
And so here I'll use the list view just to make sure I can see what's in here and be able to access
it.
So that's the sidebar.
And then here's footer area one.
I could just take this group if I wanted to and go over here and say Remove Group, and that'll just
remove that from the footer area.
It doesn't really matter if you're going to be changing it over, but oftentimes when I'm first designing,
I'll just take everything out of the footer widget areas here so that I'll just remove these groups.
And now there's nothing there in the footer area.
Um, let's see.
There's still, oh, this is the sidebar, right?
So in the sidebar, if you do use the sidebar, this is just a little bit of content in there.
We can just leave that in there for now.
And then let's just finally look under appearance menus.
And instead of using, you know, the top level pages automatically in this upper menu area, let's
define a menu to put in here so we can specifically control it.
This is really the right way to do it, even if you're using the default menu area.
So first of all, as you know, we have to create a menu.
So I'll just say, you know, header menu, and this is where you would create the different menus if
you want to have one as the primary and then a different menu as a secondary, like I said, and then
the footer menu could be something different.
As well, but I'll just create a menu name and say create menu, and then you could hit view all under
pages here and just see what you want to put in here.
So the front page or home about blog, case study, contact landing and portfolio?
Sure, maybe I'll eliminate that landing page from the navigation you could or that was the same as
select all.
But if you add to the menu here, then you have all those items, which really will be the same layout
as this.
But as you know, you can control the, you know, the order by dragging and dropping things, as well
as having a drop down, by sliding it up and having it as a submenu under there like that.
So what I'll do is just hit save menu, and then I'm going to bring in the portfolio pages that we had
created for this agency design agency layout.
They're not there aren't any portfolio items by default in the WordPress menus, but what you can do
is use a custom link.
And so what I'll do usually is just open a different page with the projects.
Right click open new tab and then I'll just.
This view is the URL so I can right click there under review and say Copy Link Address I can go back
into here.
I can put that URL by pasting it here and say the title this one was Project two click add to Menu and
then I'll do the next one.
Right click Copy, Link Address and paste it in there by clicking Control V.
And this was the Project one and adds a menu.
And now what I'm going to do is change the order of these, first of all and then actually put it under
portfolio and slide it in one so that I have a dropdown here and I click Save Menu.
That'll tell me the menu's been updated, I go up here and refresh.
Oops, wrong page.
Go up here and refresh.
And now under portfolio, I should have that dropdown.
No, that's not exactly working.
Oh, there's one more thing I have to do.
So for this menu, I didn't place it in the primary menu location, and that's that primary menu.
You know, under in the customizer, under menus, header menus.
And so now that I've done that, if I refresh the page.
There we go.
Gives me a little drop down indicator and project one and two.
You can see now my blue color for active items is showing.
So whichever one is blue, of course, I might change that to a yellow or something like this to match
the design or that bright red like I was using before, as well as this line.
And that, like I showed you before, is all controlled under appearance.
Customize.
That would be under header and navigation under primary menu bar.
You come down and say, What's the dropdown?
Well, the menu line color.
Maybe I want to have that be that red instead?
And then also the active link color.
I might do that as the red.
And then I'll probably look a lot nicer for that menu, depending on which page you're on.
And then the line for the project.
So whatever you like, that's customizing the default header in DV.
And then down at the bottom, you can see that I eliminated the widget sized area for the footer, and
there's just a remnant of that bottom bar visible here.
Even though there's no content there, you can change that to the same color as your background or your
website or just leave it.
But at this point, we're going to call this good.
And next in the Divvy Part two section, we're going to customize the header and footer and other global
elements for the website a lot more deeply.
And so we'll get to it next.