Helen will come back to the course on artificial intelligence.
In today's tutorial we're taking our first step into the world of A-3 see and as a first step we're
going to find out what disapprobation stands for.
So A-3 C stands for a synchronous advantage.
Actor critic algorithm.
This is an algorithm which was developed at Google a deep mind in 2016 by a group of researchers and
it's the cutting edge algorithm for artificial intelligence.
To date now it has multiple notifications and we'll discuss that more in the course especially in the
practical tutorials.
But nevertheless this algorithm blows everything else including deep convolutional Q learning networks
out of the water completely out of the water and it is faster.
It takes less time for training and gets better results.
So throughout this part of the course we'll be referencing and we have already referenced by we'll be
referencing even more paper on the paper that was published that first introduced A-3 sea is called
the synchronous methods of deeper enforcement learning why Vladimir minae and others from Google deep
mine which show you this paper now so that you have a introduction to it so.
So here is this paper I wanted to show you so that you can get a feel for it and ready get introduced
to it a little bit.
And of course it is highly recommended to read through the paper and understand what's what exactly
they're talking about and you'll see that throughout the practical tutorials Adlon will be taking you
through certain parts of the paper through certain paragraphs or sections which will be relevant to
what will be programming at that point in time.
And what I wanted to point out here is like as you can see a lot of research went into this but and
there's a lot of references as well but like part of the area like is that at the end and they compare
the different algorithms compare the results and this is what I wanted to point out here.
So let's zoom in a little bit.
So here as you can see the even in Google deep mine their training or they're evaluating their algorithms
on games just as we're doing in the scores.
So exactly the same principle because games are a simulated environment or a small environment a confined
environment with certain rules and they want to understand how well this artificial intelligence doing
in those games.
And here we go.
Exactly.
All those games which you can find a lot of them you can find on open a gym and the games that we've
been working with.
So for instance in this section we're working with breakouts.
It's also here as you can see that for Breakout.
They've got in bold they've got the best algorithm highlighted so Dick un that's the algorithm we've
been working with and then some other algorithms and then you've got A-3 see through see if LSD long
or short term memory.
So that's the one we'll be implementing in this part of the course will be all have A-3 see with nélisse
team which makes it even stronger.
As you can see breakout is the best result is achieved by threes you fellows.
So that's the score.
Six six point eight compared to the others.
And also you can see that for most of them so if you now take a bigger picture view you can see that
most of the bold ones are actually in this last column.
So yes indeed there are some some games where other algorithms are performing better but as you can
see deep Dijk un is actually not performing better in any of the games but you can see that there are
other algorithms other algorithms perform better sometimes but A-3 cel ystem performs the best.
In most cases you can see that this ball this ball this one these wands this one and so on.
So you can see that atresia system is a really powerful algorithm.
It is indeed at the forefront of artificial intelligence and that's exactly what will be implementing.
So a very exciting section ahead highly encourage you to go through this paper and get really get a
feel for what we're going to be talking about.
And then throughout this section and throughout the especially the practical side of things practical
side of Stroh's we're going to be going through this in detail.
We're actually going to be working with their pseudo code here which is available and we're going to
be.
So I will show you how to implement that and how we're going to be working with it.
And on that note I hope you're going to enjoy this paper and I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then enjoy AI.