uh,
hello and welcome to Microsoft Excel XML experts and excess lt Work flows My name's ground
gamble on the train on this course on what will cover is basically just about everything
you could do with Microsoft Excel involved in the manipulation of external data.
Microsoft Excel is a very XML aware application,
and there are quite a few things that you could do involved in the manipulation of XML.
We'll start the calls by covering the basics of XML.
So for those of you who haven't worked with exceptional very much before,
you may find this useful.
If you've worked with external before,
you know Alexis works.
Feel free to just get this section and move onto the next one,
where we cover the import and export operations within Microsoft Excel.
We'll look at bringing in XML data on the creation of external maps on the way that you can
link XML tables to an extent Man in the next section will move on to locate Microsoft's Web
service,
filter external functions,
which enable you to query online XML services,
return an external document and then extract data from any part of that document.
Use in ex parte statements,
I will talk about the way that experts statements are constructed.
Although these functions are meant to work only with online services,
there is a work around which permits you to use them on your own local external files.
So we'll spend some time looking at that work around on just learning how to use expert
statements in much the same way as you could use.
V.
Look up for ordinary Excel data.
We look at how you can use Filter XML to query a local XML file and call in the data that
you need for your solutions.
In the final section,
talk about one of excels less unknown external beaches,
which is the ability to apply an excess lt style sheep as you import XML Documents came to
Microsoft Excel well,
if it the way that excess lt documents are constructed and we'll learn how to use expert
statements to navigate your way through the Input XML document as you construct your help
with exiled argument.
So whatever XML work flows you're faced with this calls will equip you to deal with them
competently and efficiently.