we saw earlier that XML enables otherwise incompatible systems to exchange data.
However,
in order for data exchange to be successful,
it's important that the integrity of an XML document could be very fight in some way and
this verification is referred to as XML validation.
In order to be trusted,
an XML document has to pass to levels of Verification Festival.
It must be what's referred to as well horned.
A well formed document is simply one which adheres to the fundamental syntactical rules of
XML and secondly,
an XML document must be valid.
The term valid is reserved for those XML documents which had here to a specific set of
rules laid down for a particular type of XML document a particular XML vocabulary.
The two main tools for check in that an XML document is valid,
uh,
be TDs and XML schema documents d t D stands for document type definition and can either be
embedded within an XML document or more typically exist as an external document with a file
extension.
Not d.
T d.
DTs work well with XML documents which mainly contained textual information such as books,
journals or articles like D TDs,
XML schema documents allow you to define the nature and structure of your XML data,
but they offer a much more robust type of validation than D TDS.
Scheme is allowing to place very precise restrictions on the content of the elements within
your XML documents such as the type of data which each element may contain schemers air,
therefore ideal for validating very data centric XML documents where strict data typing
becomes very important in the next three videos,
we'll take a closer look at these three methods.
Evaluated XML firstly,
checking that an XML document is well formed.
Then we'll move on to look at DT DS and finally will get an overview of external schemer
documents.