in order to be considered well formed an XML document as to it here to the following Seven
Rules Festival,
the XML document must contain a root element and elements that contains a lot the other
nodes within the XML document.
Let's take an example of an XML document that breaks this rule in zero to XML essentials.
That's open up.
Number 10 well formed this and then 01 well honed.
And here we can see following the exile declaration,
we have an element called day and when I collapse that element,
you can see it's immediately followed by another day element.
So root element repeats.
It has siblings,
and this therefore means that it's not a well formed XML document.
Assuming that everything else is okay with the document,
this is very easy to fix.
We simply need to create a root element and put all our existing content inside it.
So to do that,
I'm going to select everything apart from the prologue,
the XML declaration,
my present control,
Fifth and the End key and then just pressing the tab key to indented everything.
And this is purely for readability.
It's not in any way of requirement in XML.
And now let's insert the open in tag of our root element.
Let's call it days.
And in the brackets environment,
the closing tag goes in automatically.
So I now I just need to cut the clothes in tag and pasted at the very end of the documents
.
And then we have it.
If I now collapse our first element,
you'll see that the entire document is collapsed,
says this document is now.
Well hold and let's just close it and say about changes.
Next.
We have some restrictions on the names of elements and attributes names cannot contain.
Spaces cannot start with a number of special character cannot start with the letters.
XML,
regardless of the case on the name,
must contain at least one character.
It can't be completely numeric.
And the game.
Let's take an example of something that breaks these rules zero to,
and here we can see that we have an element called course name,
and it's two words,
very simple breach of the rules.
No space is allowed in the names of elements or attributes,
so to make this well formed,
you simply have to take out all these spaces,
and I missed one and another.
I said,
Once the space Israel gun,
all the names are legit and we have a well formed document.
The next requirement is that element tags must be properly nested,
and this refers to the situation of where you have a parent element on a child element.
The tags off the child element must be completely enclosed within the tanks of the parent
element.
So let's have a look at examples three.
Which breaks this rule.
So here we have a root of notification state time when we have detail,
which contains recipients on message is it's child elements on recipients,
contains or other is meant to contain the two element as its child element.
So we have the open intact for recipients.
The open intact for two.
But then we closed recipients before close into.
So to correct this,
we need to have to closed here.
And then recipients closed here.
So the opening and closing tags off the child element a completely enclosed inside the
opening and closing tags of the parent element.
And again,
let's does save and close.
Next,
we have what looks like a fairly obvious one.
Every Odin in tag must have imagine closing tag.
And this tends to be broken by anyone who's designing XML but has more HTML experience than
XML experience because in HTML five it is legitimate in some circumstances.
Toe have an open in tag with no matching clothes in tag,
so on to example,
four and the culprits are in this paragraph,
and it's basically this BR tag that's been introduced.
It's taken from HTML on stands for a line break,
and in HTML five.
It's perfectly legitimate to write it in this way.
But in XML,
it's completely wrong.
If it's to be treated as an empty element with no content,
then you need to use the convention that we saw earlier but making it both an opening and
closing tag.
So,
in other words,
you need to put a forward slash just before the closing angle bracket,
and this means that it's both an open and close intact.
So it's completely legitimate if we simply copy this on paste over ALS,
the illegal ones there aren't too many of them.
Soldiers do it this way.
Just missed one here on assumes they're all gone.
That power should become a legitimate like so So this is the situation where people are
designing XML and they might all into this trap.
It's where they've got a lot of HTML experience that they make certain assumptions about
what's permissible inside an XML document.
So again,
this saving close Next,
we have the requirement that all attributes must have values and the game.
Let's taken example of something that breaks these rules,
the needs of our elements.
We have three attributes.
Two of them are perfectly legit,
but the last one consists of a single word.
So whether you take this word as the name of the attribute or as the value associating with
a nameless attributes in both circumstances,
it's not permitted in XML.
So we would have to come up with perhaps a name for an attribute and then treat low,
medium and high as the possible values for that attribute.
So let's call our attribute rating so the correct syntax would be rating equals open quotes
and then obviously closed quotes at the end.
Save my copy this on his pasted in front of each and the strain woods and then just put the
clothes in quotation mark.
They told us co create control,
see on dinners paste in.
So having done that,
we've now made all of these attributes of legitimate theater abuses called rate in on then
low,
medium and high have now become the values along that same attribute each time little and
safe and clothes Next.
We have the stipulation that all attribute values must be quoted.
We can either use double quotes,
all single quotes,
but we must use quotes.
This rule tends to be broken where people take a convention from programming languages on
moving into XML.
In programming languages.
It's always required that you quote strings,
but you normally don't need to quote any values.
If something's numeric,
you don't normally need to have quotes around it.
But in XML,
regardless of the type of data,
you always place your values inside close.
Let's have a look at example Number six.
So here we can see for each of our invoices,
we have status expected because it's textual.
We placed it in quotes,
but then we've made this erroneous assumption that because paid as a numeric value,
that numeric value doesn't need to be in spite quotes.
But in XML,
it does every attributes value has to be inside quotation once again,
I'm just gonna copy that and then just paste it around each of these numeric values,
and that's all we need to do.
So we now have a well formed XML document.
And finally,
we have the stipulation that illegal characters such as less than greater than 10% must all
be replaced with entity references.
And we've seen examples of this requirement in earlier videos.
Let's look at an example we haven't encountered that's open up 07 We've seen that attribute
.
Values must always be quoted,
but it's something you whether you use double personal single ones.
If you use double quotes,
then it's permissible to use single quotes inside them.
But if you're using single quotes,
as we are in this example,
this means you can no longer have single quotes within your content.
So using the apostrophe and Matthew Horror becomes illegal.
Let's say that there's some technical reason for using single quotes.
It makes programming in some other part of the system more convenient,
so we want to continue with that.
We have to make sure that we always use entity references instead of the apostrophe and the
character entity for an apostrophe is ember.
Send a pulse semi colon.
The ones we don't meant We now have well formed XML And again that's close and save so
those in the main criteria which need to be satisfied in order for a document to be
considered well formed XML.
However,
a document that satisfies these very basic syntactical criteria isn't necessary a valid XML
document.
So in the next video,
we'll move on to look at the criteria which have to be satisfied in order for a document to
become a valid XML document.