D T D stands for document type definition,
and it's the first method of validating in XML document.
The declarations,
which specifying what's legal within the XML document,
constitute the D t.
D of these declarations they I ever be made internally within the XML document or in a
separate external document when using an internal ET de.
The optional standalone argument has to be included in the XML Declaration and this has to
be sent to Yes,
the D T.
D is then placed in the prologue of the XML document above the root element,
and it consists off less than an exclamation mark on the key word doc type in uppercase,
followed by the name of the root element.
Then we have open square brackets,
the various declarations specifying the nature of elements in the nature of attributes,
etcetera.
And then we finish off close square brackets and a greater than sign in the case of an
external D.
T.
D stand alone is set to know,
and all we need to place in the prologue of the XML document is a dark time statement which
contains the keyword system,
and then the doc type statement is usually just one line less than exclamation mark.
Don't type as before,
the name of the root element.
As before,
then all we need to do is to reference the external D T D file that's usually done using
the keyword system,
followed by the name of the file.
So in this example,
we're assuming that we have a file called my D t d dot de TV in the same folder as the
exile document.
Inside the external DTV,
we would have an XML declaration.
XML version equals one,
etcetera.
And then we would have the D T D declarations.
And these take a special torment.
They're not regular XML statements.
The two key elements in these declarations use the keyword element to define the nature of
elements within the XML document on at least,
which is short for attribute list.
As the name employees,
the syntax enables you to define the nature of ALS,
the attributes for a particular element.
Let's take a look at an example that boasts an internal and external d t d In zero.
It's a maximal essentials.
Let's open up 11 overview of D TDs and let's start by looking at this stand alone document
that has a d t.
D embedded in the prologue of the external document.
That's a stuff stand alone.
So here we can see on line one.
We have standard early cause,
Yes.
And then he is the start of the dark time declaration.
He was a dark time,
followed by the name of the root element,
which this XML document is stuff.
Then we start with the definition off the ruse element staff and in parentheses.
After the word stuff,
we have the Children of the storm element,
and in this case,
there is only one child called staff member.
On the plus sign after start member indicates that we can have an unlimited number of these
child elements.
Then we've got a definition off the staff member with his Children and there no plus lines
next to any of them.
But what this syntax does indicate is that these Children are required and they have to
occur in the order listed in that definition.
Next,
we have the attribute department all staff member.
And even though there's only one attributes,
we still use the keyword at list.
If we wanted to add a second attribute to department We could simply split this statement
onto several lines so we could insert return here and then just having the readability.
I would have the closing angle bracket here,
and then we would just put the details off our second attribute.
So let's create an attribute called Status.
Character Data is the most popular data time,
but another is to have a Siris of options and then placed inside parentheses and separated
by the Piper character.
So let's say that the let's say,
for example,
that we have full time claim home time and again,
let's make this required.
So by doing this,
we have now invalidated this XML document because none of these people has that attribute.
So I'm just gonna have to go inside the staff member,
and it's a status equals and in quotes put either full time or part time.
So I'm just gonna copy that on,
paste it in for everyone.
That's everyone on.
Let's just leave them all this full time.
That's fine.
Moving back to our declarations,
we then move on to the elements that actually contain data so you can see the convention,
an element that contains child elements as those child elements listed inside parentheses.
By contrast,
elements that contain data simply have the name of the element and then inside parentheses
.
We specify the data type,
which is normally PC data past character data.
And then we have the photo element,
which is followed by the keyword empty,
indicating that it can't contain text in the way that first name,
last name and skills Can They have PC data as their data time?
And finally,
we have the attributes definition for the H ref attributes of photo.
So we have at least photo the name of the element that contains the attribute a treff,
the name of the attributes itself,
character data,
the data type on required indicating that it can't be admitted.
So hopefully that just gives you a flavour of what a dock type definition looks like on
this is how it's embedded within an XML document.
Let's just compare that with exactly the same thing,
but externally.
So if we open up staff that d t.
D.
We have the same definitions apart from the changes that I just made,
but that's all we have here.
We specify.
It's an XML document,
and then all we have is the element and Atmos definitions that we saw before.
So to make this current,
I'm just gonna go into stand alone and just copy the new version off these definitions and
then just replace the originals.
It's close and safe.
That's finished by a very fine that the document that we have is valid as defined by our
dog time definition.
So we'll copy everything and let's just across route browser Visit xml validation dot com
and we just paste in our code and from value dates.
No Harris have been found.
Let's just go back to the XML document and introduce an error.
So now at least we added this extra attributes called status and it's required.
So we release the status for any of these stuff.
Remember elements we have now invalidated our rules.
So when we click on Vanya late this time,
you can see that we have an era.
The attributes status is required that must be specified for the element Time start member