in this video we'll move on to look at the second method of validating XML data which is to
use a schema definition document XML schema of far more powerful in D TDs.
And this could become a very complex topic.
So we'll be doing is simply having a very brief look at some of the key aspect off a schema
document.
This is what the skeleton of a schema document looks like.
XML schema documents are always external.
Unlike de TDs,
there isn't an option to embed the definition within the XML file itself.
And unlike De TDs,
XML schema documents don't have a special definition language.
An XML schema document consists of standard XML.
This is the skeleton of any XML schema document.
Like all XML documents,
there has to be a root element on that route.
Element is schema to avoid possible conflicts with any other XML vocabularies,
XML schemers use the name space.
So here we have a name space definition which points to the XML schema definition and
specifies in this case that we use in the prefix X s And then whenever we use any elements
within the scheme of vocabulary,
we prefix the elements with excess colon.
So as you can see,
excess cool on schemer is the root element.
And then we'll have a series of definitions within that route element,
all using the same prefix excess.
The Lincoln XML document to an external schemer document the attribute.
No name space schema location is used to specify a location off.
That document on this attribute is added to the route element.
However,
the attributes itself is within a given name space.
Hence it's preceded with another name.
Space definition.
So here is pointing to the schemer instance definition on we specifying that we're going to
use the prefix excess I once we've made that name Space Declaration.
Then we can say excess.
I know names based scheme a location equals and specify the location of the scheme a
document then within the rules element,
we have our XML content,
and that content now has to it here to the rules laid out in our scheme.
A document in this case root dot access D.
So if we apply this principle to the staff document that we've seen a few times in these
videos,
the root element is called staff.
So it's here that we insert our excess I know names based scheme a location attribute on.
We specify that staffed on Excess D is the external schemer document to be used for
validating this XML document.
So here we have a diagram of our simple staff.
Example on.
Let's look at some of the key aspect off a schema definition for this document.
First of all,
the distinction between complex times,
Andi simple types within a schemer document.
Any element that contains other elements is defined as a complex time.
So in our staff,
document staff contains one or more staff member elements.
Hence,
it's a complex type and staff member contains four child elements,
so it's also a complex time.
In addition,
the photo element,
which,
if you remember,
contains no text but has an attributes is its child is also treated in a schemer document
as a complex type rather than a simple type.
So simple times are either elements that contain text or data or attributes,
which by definition always contain a valued on.
The other aspect off schema definition,
which will have a look at,
is the use of indicators.
So now stuff example.
We look at the use of an occurrence indicator to specify that the staff member element can
occur one or more times.
And we'll also look at the use of an order indicator to specify the order in which the
child elements of the staff member element must occur.
So now training folder in zero to XML Essentials.
Let's open up some folder 12 and let's begin by opening up the XML stop the next time L and
in our route element that's the stuff.
We can see the use off the no name space schema location attributes on.
The value of that attribute is staffed on XSD,
which implies that we have a scheme,
a document called Stuff that access T in the same folder as the current XML document.
And now let's switch across to that document.
And as you can see,
we have a regular XML document which has a root element called schemer.
When that element is in the schema definition name space which,
according to the name Space Declaration,
is using the prefix X s.
Hence the schema element uses that prefix excess colon schemer as a postage,
A schemer.
Now let's look at our complex Andi simple types so we'll start with complex types.
And if you remember there two occasions when you have to use complex types,
the first is for those elements that contain child elements.
So we start with staff,
the root element and inside it we have a complex time definition,
and inside that we can see the use or order indicator and in this case,
the order indicators sequence.
It doesn't really matter because there is only one child element,
so it's a sequence of one element,
basically.
Then we use excess elements to define bad element on.
We've also got on a currents indicator.
Max occurs,
equaled unbounded,
which means that we can have a Zeman any occurrences off the star pepper element within
staff as we want and you can see that we've got a Mexico's.
We haven't got a minute.
CA's by default,
the minimum occurrences one.
So simply by omitting it,
we're saying that the staff member element can occur as many times as we want,
but it must occur at least once,
which is the default.
So the use of ref implies that we have a definition all staff member on here.
It is so xsl elements,
staff member on because it contains child elements.
We don't have excess complex type.
And again we have the use of the order indicator sequence implying that the four child
elements have to occur in the specified order.
So that's how complex type one.
Before we move on to simple types,
let's find complex type two.
So if you remember the second occasion when you need to use the complex time definition is
where you have an element that has attributes at its child on,
that's the case with the photo element.
There are no child elements,
but there is an attribute.
So excess element photo.
Then we've got a complex type definition,
no elements,
and then inside it we have the definition of our attributes,
which takes us onto the definition off simple types.
So you concede it on attribute is a simple time,
and to define and attributes as a simple type,
we simply specify its name and the data type and for an attribute.
We then specify that its use is obligatory by specifying use equals required,
and we've got the same definition here for the department.
The type of string on the use is required then,
at the top.
We have the definition of our element.
Simple types,
excess element,
they medical skills type equals excess string.
So all three of our symbol types have string as the data time,
and one of the great strength of schema definitions is that it allows very robust type
definitions.
And it also allows you to specify your own custom data types.
So that sound very brief.
Look at schema documents.
And also that's the end of our very brief look at the way that XML works in the next
section will move on to look at how Excel handles XML documents and XML data.