in this video what we want to look at working with an XML document,
which has a slightly more complex structure than the one tweet clean so far.
Zero Free Excel in XML that's now going to number five multilevel import on multiple tables
.
Let's have a look at the XML file will be working with its cool branches,
and it contains information about people working at a given organization.
So we have the branches root element.
And then we have a repeat in Branch Element inside that we have branch manager,
and then we have the actual information.
So these are the elements which will correspond to the columns within an acceptable table
within Microsoft Excel.
So far,
so good,
however,
only branch managers a listed at this particular level within the hierarchy.
To get to the heads of departments,
for example,
we have to drill down into the department's element and the repeating department element.
And then within each department element we have a staff element on the first child.
Element of staff is head,
and here's where we'll find information about all our heads of department.
Then,
after the listing for the head,
we have a star remember element,
which again has exactly the same child elements.
But the thing that makes this situation selectable complex is that the child elements may
be the same,
but the parent element is not so.
We have stumped member,
we have head,
and we have Bronze Manager.
All that's slightly different levels within the XML structure that's just close this file.
Then let's just have a look at the diagram off the XML structure.
So if we have a broad interest or PdF and if you're using Adobe Acrobat,
you can type control elf to go into full screen mode and then control one to go to actual
size.
And then let's just move.
It's absolutely so we can see the whole thing so we can see that the elements that all
contain text exist at different levels within the structure.
So we want the trial elements of Bronze Manager,
head and staff member and within Excel.
The only real way of doing this it's toe have three separate tables to bring the branch
managers into one table,
the heads of departments into a second table and the staff members into assert.
So let's press escape and just close the branches.
A Pdf file.
So now let's open up the Excel file staff data and inside you'll see that we've got a
worksheet for each of the three bits of data that will be bringing in staff department
heads and branch managers.
So the first thing we need to do is to create three XML maps,
one but each of the sections of data that we want to target and as we've seen before to do
that,
we go to developer click on the source button.
This brings up the XML source task pain,
and here we click on XML Maps.
Then we click on Add on its work Out waiting to fold it five multilevel import multiple
tables and then let's base the map on the schema.
Document branches don't xsd.
Since what we create in three XML maps from the same schemer will need to rename There's
gonna be stuff.
Let me have a second.
That's cool.
This one heads remember,
third manages I mean,
we click OK and here l three XML maps.
Let's start with staff.
So here we need to navigate to the staff member parent element and we want a little bit
child elements of START member.
With the exception of voted,
let me just remind you why we don't need photo.
If we open up the XML document branches dot xml,
you'll see that photo is what's called an empty element.
In other words,
it contains no textual data.
What it does contain,
however,
is the attributes called a dress on.
This contains the location off this person's photo.
So what we need to do is to control,
click on a photo,
deactivated and then control click on age ref to activate that,
because it's a draft that actually contains the data that we want.
With that selection in place,
we can then create the XML table.
I drank in the selection into the Work Street,
and it's finished by renaming age ref photo.
And then we simply need to do the same thing all department heads and branch managers.
So that's navigate up to the head section.
The highlight the Parents,
which is an highlights.
All the trial elements control linked to de select photo and control glimpses selected a
dress.
Let me track this election into the work feet and again,
let's rename age ref and finally,
branch managers who are at the top.
So those three map pins in place,
we can now import our XML file.
And it's that one XML file that will populate along the tables very often.
When you've got these mapping set up all point into the same XML file.
Import in the XML file will populate all the tables in one hit.
But even if it doesn't,
you simply select another table and reimport the same XML file said.
To import the XML,
we go to developer on import and double click on branches dot xml.
So here we have a lot of bronze managers and our department heads and allow staff members.
So that's an example of how we can populate multiple XML tables from one XML file.
That same out changes.
And in the next video,
we'll discuss strategies for bringing in data from her multi level XML file into a single
XML table.