In the last video,
we looked at important data from different parts of a multilevel XML file into separate
tables.
In this video,
we'll look at doing the same thing but assembling all the data into a single table.
So 03 Excel in XML.
Let's open up some folder six multilevel import single table.
So let's begin by opening up.
Start data Unified and here you'll see we've got exactly the same file that created in the
last video.
So we have three separate XML maps,
heads,
managers and stuff and then is restored in the last video.
We'd use these three maps to populate three separate tables so,
naturally,
what we can now go on to do if we want to have ALS,
the data in a single table is to manually create a new table and copy and paste all of the
information into that table.
The limitation,
of course,
is that the data in the table will be static.
It won't be linked to the XML in any way,
so let's close the XML source task pain and then let's just make the profile column a bit
narrower so we can fit everything onto one screen So I'm going to select all three seats
and then just resize profile like so And then let's de select our sheets on group seats.
So before we create our unified table,
we need to identify the role,
the job role of each of these individuals.
So I'm currently in branch managers,
so I'll just add a column here called Role and just Time Brahms manager and then copy that
down into all of the other Rose.
Then I'll do the same for department heads and staff members.
So now we've got a column to specify the role of all of the individuals.
We can create another table.
I'll just move that to the end and just call it full stuff.
And we vendors copy all of the data across total staff.
So the first copy,
I'm gonna take all of the data,
including the headings and then for the other two.
I'll obviously just need the data.
I won't want to copy the headings.
Seven department heads.
I click in the first column first row of data and then used the usual keyboard shortcut,
which he probably no control shift end to select all the way to the bottom and finally we
do the same to stuff controls it and on a copy and paste.
So this is one approach.
We import all the data into separate tables so that we can access different sections of the
XML file,
and we then manually assemble all the data into a single table on.
As I said,
the limitation is that this table is in no way dynamic.
I now have all the data in one table,
but it's not dynamically linked to any XML source,
and it doesn't correspond to the structure off the original XML.
So if I wanted to export this data back into the original XML,
I wouldn't be able to do so.
So let's now save out changes,
closed the file.
And now let's look in our second example.
So let's open up stuff.
Data amplified,
and what we'll do in the second example is to create a single table,
which references the three different job roles that we've just seen staff members,
heads of departments on branch managers.
So let's go across the developer and creates an XML man.
To do that,
we take a source and then in the XML source task pain.
We click on XML maps,
then add and elects the same file.
I'm going to switch across to hold a six multilevel import single table a man DoubleClick
on branches down xsd to generate the map.
There will only be one map this time,
so there's no rolling to rename it.
So let's just like Okay,
so let's start by putting in all of the staff member data.
So as before,
I'm going to control click on photo and then control.
Click on age rest,
drag the selective elements to create the external table and then rename a dress photo.
So what we can now do is do an in the details of the heads of departments and branch
managers in the context off each staff member.
So let's begin by specifying the department and the branch at which eat start member works
say we scroll up and we've got the department name so we drag in name and we'll need to
rename the column.
Let's just call it department and then we want the name of the branch again.
The element is called name and we can just read a mitt brunch,
and now we can add in the name off the head of department on the branch.
I said Before I do that,
I'm going to switch on word Ram.
Just get back to home Special lead,
right then vertically aligned to the top.
Let's also get rid of all these Underscores.
So while that selections in place is tight control age which is a short cup,
the replace and then we're replacing under school with a space and replace all.
So now we can start with the name off the department head head section we track first name
and the same for last name.
And finally you do the same for the branch manager.
-
So
complete sound mapping.
And finally we import our XML data into that structure.
So developer,
import and branches.
So as we look at each stunk member,
we can see the name of their head of department on their branch manager.
So the staff member details occur once and obviously the heads of departments on branch
manager details are repeated as many times as necessary.
So hopefully this gives you an idea of how you might use data from different parts of a
multi level XML structure within the same table