Although the filter exceptional function is designed to work with Web services,
you may occasionally find it convenient to use it with your local XML files in this video.
We'll look at a work around for doing that.
It's going to sub folder before using Filter XML with local XML files.
Let's open up.
The Excel file will be working with expense claims.
So here we've got a bunch of expense claims by staff members.
We want to do the equivalent of a V look up to find out the I.
D first name and last name off their head of department.
But we want to do this from an XML file.
Obviously,
in some scenarios you'll be able to simply import the XML file into a table on then USVI
look up index match as appropriate to pull across the data that you need.
But as we've seen,
the all XML files lend themselves to being imported into an Excel table.
So there will be times where it's more convenient to connect to the XML file externally and
then to use the Filter XML to pull in data from different parts of that XML structure.
There are a couple of limitations.
So let's have a look of the work around that we're gonna use.
Let's create a new work Feet called XML Connections.
And the first thing I need to tell you is that this work around has one key limitation.
And that is because we use in Filter XML,
which takes as its first parameter an XML document.
The XML file that we connect to can't have more than 32,767 characters because that's the
maximum number of characters which will fit within a cell in Microsoft Excel and for the
Filter XML function to be used,
we have to have the entire XML document in one cell.
So we go across the data,
the feature that we use it,
get external data and we simply connects to the XML file as a text file on this operational
course,
excel to import the XML,
and under normal circumstances,
it will take up several rows.
What we want to do is to have it all imported into a single cell.
So the first work around is to use what's called a min ified XML file.
Let's go back into the train in folder so you can see what this means.
Here's the XML file that will be connecting to hence the XML.
But as I've said,
if we import this,
it's gonna be imported on lots of different rose rather than into a single cell.
So what we've done is to convert it into what's called a min ified XML file one with all
the spaces taken out.
So we open up heads magnified.
It's exactly the same document.
But as you can see,
all the returns,
tabs and spaces between the elements have been removed.
So it's just one long string.
This means that when you connect to a text file in this format,
it all comes in into a single cell.
So it's close.
Both of these let's get back to excel and connect to the mini find version.
So in the data tab of the ribbon,
we go suit,
get external data from text.
Let's just work out waiting to fold a number four view along files the man connect to heads
.
Many find because we treating it as a text file.
The text import was it appears so in step one,
we specify the Limited instead to will say that the delimit er is other,
without specifying what it is.
And just in case.
Let's say that the text qualify is none,
and then instead,
three we can choose.
Text is the format,
then we click on finish before clicking.
OK,
it's a good idea to have a look at the properties because there's one property which is
rather irritating on that is that every time you refresh the data,
you're prompted to specify the location of the file.
No idea why that's the default,
but let's switch it off.
And then,
as you can see,
you can specify in the frequency of the refresh and you can specify to repress the data
every time you open the file,
the data formats and of course,
worms apply.
Because we're not bringing this in in a tabular format,
we're bringing it into a single cell,
so click OK when we click OK,
again.
The entire document is now being brought into a single cell.
If I go out to the home tab and speech onward ramp,
we can see our many fine XML format.
There are several websites available which will create a unified version off your XML.
We're going to the training folder.
I have the u R l of one of them XML many fire.
So if you want to experiment with this feature,
just visit this u R L Paste in the original XML.
It's like on many fi and you'll have a unifying version off your file toe work with.
So now that we have our XML in a single cell,
we can go back to expenses and use Filter XML to navigate our way through it.
So let's open the UNM unifying version so we can have a look at the structure so we can see
that we need to navigate from heads to hand and then to stop i.
D.
Last name first name on we using underscore to split words.
So let's put the basic formula in equals.
Phil drinks ML.
The XML document is in our XML connections.
Work feet.
When we click on the cell that contains the linked document,
you'll notice that it's the name of the link document that gets put in because that name
has been applied to the cell that we put our expand statement or would slash to indicate an
absolute path.
Heads slash head slash stuff on the school i d.
Close quotation marks can be close in parenthesis.
When we enter what we've actually targeted,
we'd go back to the XML structure is the staff i d of the first of our heads of department
.
In other words,
out formulas not quite finished because we're not hoping in on a particular department or a
particular branch,
But we'll leave it like that for this video.
And then in the next video,
we'll finish it off when we talk about X path predicates.
But for the moment,
let's just copy the formula and paste it in so we could pick up the first name and last
name.
Since I've said,
these three formulas are purely picking up the details of the first person.
And if we were to copy it down,
we simply get that person's details replicated for every room.
So let's just don't do save out changes.
And in the next video,
we'll discuss the use of expert predicated,
which will enable us to complete these three formulas