in this video,
we'll carry on where we left off in the last video.
So we go into number four Filter XML,
hopefully save your changes.
So let's just be the file amoled has pasted into using predicates and then Evan it from
there enable content.
And this is where we left off.
So we've got a formula which basically only targets.
The first person in the XML document on what we need to do is to ensure that the person
that we actually target is the head of the Finance Department in this case and worse in the
London branch.
Let's just reopen the XML files from that folder for just to remind you what the structure
looks like.
So basically the things that we need to test about attributes the department attributes and
the bronze attributes off the head element.
So let's edit our function on what we want to do is to home in on the right head element,
so are predicated.
It needs to go on our middle location,
step after the head.
No test predicates are written in square brackets like so and then between the square
brackets,
you put the equivalent off the first argument Oven Excel if statement.
So in this case,
we're testing two attributes when,
right in the name of an attribute you simply preceded with an outside on that distinguishes
it from the name of an element.
So let's start with the Department Department equals and then we need to slot in Cell B two
.
So that means we've got a close quotation marks.
The news M percent.
We're working locally,
so we don't need to worry about things like you are all in code.
And of course,
so you just click on B two and per send on.
One thing I've for gotten is that B two has to go in single quotes.
So just before the close quote,
I'm going to insert single quotes.
And then,
after the ampersand,
we opened double quotes and close single quotes.
So,
in other words,
the value and be too will end up inside single quotes.
And then we do the same for bronze.
So we simply say,
and bronze equals single close close double quotes,
ampersand to slot in the value in C two emphasis end open double quotes,
closed single quotes and then we've already got the close in the square bracket so that
middle locations that now has all three possible components has the implied child access.
It has a no test,
which is head,
and now it has a pretty kids inside the Reddick.
It we just inserting two values from our excel worksheet.
Suddenly we click enter.
We now have the correct staff i D.
But the person who is head of the violence department at the London branch so we can know
can't be all of this and paste it into getting the first name and last name.
So now when we come for you down,
we have the appropriate details that each of the heads of department at the bronze
specified on each road.
So that's a very quick example of how predicates he used in an expert statement.
So if you're looking at a formula that uses filter XML and you see these statements inside
square brackets,
hopefully you know have a better idea of what's going on