as we've seen the Web service function can't be used on local XML files.
On the work around,
I've suggested,
is to use a unified XML file.
What if many find your XML isn't really an option.
If,
for example,
the XML file is over written fairly frequently,
you'll have to manually updated each time and get a unifying version.
So in this video,
we'll look at using the new contract function in Excel to enable you to import on ordinary
XML file I non men ified and then can Katyn ate all the roads that it occupies,
so it can then be treated as being inserted into a single cell.
So that's going to number six.
Then you can cat function and open up expense claims.
Let's move across to Excel connections on,
then connect to the UNMIN ified XML file that we've got here called Head Start XML.
And,
as you can see,
because it's not,
many find it will take up 363 rows within an Excel worksheet so they can Katyn eight
function can't be used because it has a maximum of 255.
Paramus is,
however,
in Excel,
There's a new function called Can Cat,
and it offers much more powerful.
Can cast a nation options.
Let's have a look at how it works,
so we go across the data,
get external data from text.
Now we work our way into folders six View along files and then import,
hence dot xml.
We important is the limited.
The limiter is other and then unspecified XT qualify and none and we form in the colon has
text on before clicking.
OK,
that's just going to properties on Switch off that pesky option problems for file name on
refresh.
Let's say we want to refresh every time we get in the file,
so we've now connected to our XML file.
But when we go back to our other worksheet,
we won't now be able to use Filter XML because our XML is distributed across 300 rose.
So what we need to do is to assemble the XML into a single cell.
So let's just merge a whole bunch of cells.
I think we need to go all the way down,
um,
emergence center vertically aligned to the top.
And then in that cell,
we use Excel 20 sixteens new can cat function equals Can cat.
And what's new is that I can now simply click on column A.
Have the function will automatically contaminate the values in each row.
And the fact that there are 363 rose is not a problem.
I don't have 363 arguments.
I only have one argument so I could put if I wanted to another 254 arguments within the cat
function so you can see how much more powerful it becomes than the classic Can Katyn,
a function that we've had for some years.
So when I enter my function and special lead wrap,
you'll see that I have my XML file sitting in a single cell.
I won't bother repeating the creation off the formulas.
All I wanted to show you basically is that if the trick of many find your XML isn't really
possible,
you can still assemble all the lines of your external document into a single cell.
Use in that very useful can can't function.
But what if you don't have Excel 2016?
Unfortunately,
you'll have to do it the hard way,
but it's still not super difficult Let's have a look at how it would work.
I'm gonna make this column narrower.
And then here I'm just gonna put in a column of numbers.
We know that there are 363 rows,
but let's say we want to go all the way down to 500 encase the XML ends up growing,
so I go down to about 500 on.
What I can now do is to get Excel to build a really complex formula automatically.
So I'm using a series of formulas to build another formula.
You'll see what I mean in a moment.
So we start with equals on.
We want to pick up a one.
So we put the A in quotes,
and then we say ampersand and click on the one which contains one.
So that gives us a one.
And then we want an ampersand.
So we say Ampersand quotes,
ampersand close,
close.
When I press enter,
you'll see we now have a 1%.
In other words,
are formula needs to say a one m percent a two and percent a three etcetera.
It's on the second row,
we can now say equals the cell above followed by Okay.
Ampersand de to Anderson quotes Empress end.
Hopefully you can see where I'm going with this.
As we copy it down,
it's gonna take the cell above and then just add on the reference for that road so I can
just double click to copy it them myth to the bottom on This is now gonna be my completed
formula.
So I can just copy that into note pad time equals,
paste it in there,
lose the trailing ampersand,
and we've got ourselves a formula.
So not a huge amount of work to created,
likened a little of this.
Let's just make another one of these big cells.
So let's win this a bit.
Select a bunch of cells and then Myrdal of these cells left the line aligned and hopefully
my clipboard is still intact.
Suddenly placed all of that in and so on.
World run and we've got exactly the same results.
Very untidy formula.
But as you can see,
not so much work to create.
So if you haven't got Excel 2016 this is the approach you can take.
But if you have 2016 and I'm sure that they can cat function is one that you'll be very
keen to start using