and all the examples with you.
So far,
we've only been working with one axis the child access,
which is the default and therefore doesn't need to be specified.
In this video,
we'll talk about another access that you'll encounter,
which is the descendant or self access.
So let's going toe hold of five where we finished up our expense claims.
Examples.
Let's just copy that and paste it into folders seven and then open up the completed file.
So here's the formula.
We ended up creating and all I want to show you in this video.
It's how you can avoid having toe always use an absolute pass,
which,
if you remember,
is one that starts with a forward slash,
and that's fine use in the descendant or self access.
So let's look festival at the longhand if I deletes.
Forward slash heads forward slash and time descendant iPhone along hyphens Self Colon
Coghlan's That's the longhand way of specifying the descendants or self access.
And if I presenter,
you'll see I get exactly the same result on what the descendant or self access enables you
to do is in this case to find head elements wherever they occur.
within the document without having to navigate through the XML structure,
starting with the root element and then working your way down so you'll find Descendant
ourself used quite a lot.
What you won't find is the longhand that I've just written.
I rose it like that just to emphasize that this is the access that we working with.
But the shorthand way of writing it is to forward slashes.
So whenever you see these two forward slashes,
just remember that this is what's going on.
Instead of having an absolute path which starts at the document,
Root goes to the root element and works its way down.
You simply use the descendant or self access to find that element wherever it occurs within
a document.
So because it is such a useful shorthand,
you'll encounter this in tax quite a lot.
So hopefully that's just given you more of an idea of what's going on when you see an
expert statement containing these two forward slashes.
So that completes our initial look at Expo in the next section will move on to look a xsl t
on will continue using X path in the context of xsl transformations