An XML document consists of two principal parts.
The prologue and the root element.
The prologue is optional that the root element is compulsory.
The product contains information about the XML document as a whole.
The root element contains all of the content off the XML document.
Let's take an example,
have created the simplest possible XML document in zero to XML Essentials.
Open up number two structure of an XML document,
and inside it you'll find a file called Hello well,
that XML open that in your editor.
Let's go ahead and create our file to create a valid XML file.
The only content we need to place in the file is the root element.
The name of the root element can be anything you like in XML.
It's entirely up to you to define the names off the elements within your external structure
.
But for simplicity,
let's call it route to write an element.
We put an opening tag,
which consists of the left and bracket,
the name of the element on the right angle bracket.
And in the case of most editors,
the closing tag will automatically be inserted for you anything between the opening and
closing tanks is regarded as the content off.
The element on that content could be very varied,
and we'll discuss the various types of content in the rest of this chapter,
and you'll notice that there's a distinction between the way that the opening tank is
written on the closing tag.
The left angle bracket of the closing tag is followed by a forward slash.
So in our super simple example,
let's just put Hello World and that,
believe it or not,
is now a valid XML file.
To put it to the test,
you can either use the XML validator built into your editor.
Or if your editor doesn't have an XML validator,
you'll find the U.
R L in this file.
External validation,
which you can just copy and paste into your browser.
And then we can just paste it into this box control.
Be and click on validate,
and you can see we have landed XML.
Let's just go back to the editor and let's add in the optional prologue.
The only compulsory element within a prologue is the XML declaration,
and it looks like this left and bracket question Mark XML,
and then the only thing we have to specify is the version,
which is one point north,
and we can then optionally specify the encoding,
which for English is utf eight.
And then we close the declaration with question mark on a right angle bracket.
And let's just check that out.
XML file is still valid.
Control me to paste on Valley Days,
and as you can see,
we still have valid X amount.
So that's a quick look at put in the bare bones,
the two essential elements into an XML file.
In our simple example,
we put text straight into the root element.
This is fairly unusual.
What typically you'll have a hierarchy off child elements within the root elements,
and you have to drill down several levels deep before you find the actual textual content.
As you can see from this diagram,
there are a number of different types of objects that could be placed both inside the
prologue and in the root element,
and we'll be discussing these various objects throughout the rest of the chapter.
In the next video,
we'll take a closer look at what is perhaps the most important of these objects.
The XML element