in the last video,
we looked at the centre acts for copying elements from the input document to the output
document without any modification in this video will live on to look at how you can
transfer elements from input to output.
Modify the contents that you have inside the element.
So let's move into folder four years in xsl text and xsl value off.
Let's live in the branches don't xsl and this is the style sheet that we finished up with
at the end of the last video.
So just to recap what we've got so far in our first template,
we especially find that we want people as the root element and as the output we want.
Branch manager Ed and staff combined into one note set and then,
in our second template,
was specifying what we want to do to each element within that note set.
And what we do want to do is to create a person element for each of them and then place all
of the child elements of branch manager,
head or staff member with the exceptional staff I D and photo photo.
We want to suppress all together,
so that's taken care off,
but with staff.
I d we actually do want the staff.
I d We simply want the contents to change.
So this time we can't news copy off.
Because if we do that,
we have both the exterior and interior,
um,
modifiable.
So we always get a replica of the original element.
So what we have to do is to create the exterior of the element and then use a different
technique to put stuff inside it.
So we know how to create an element use element.
Xsl element name equals Stop I d And let's just go back to branches.
Let me just remind you what we're trying to achieve.
We basically want to have an apostrophe in front of the stop i d.
So the next cell will store it as text as opposed to a new marrying value.
So to do that,
we can use the text element.
This basically enables you to insert any literal string,
thanks a cell text.
And then between the opening and closing tax,
you can put any literal string that you want.
In our case,
we want a solitary apostrophe,
then going back to branches that xml what we now want is the original contents of staff.
I'd be intact and as we said,
we can't use xsl copy off because this will coffee,
not just the value.
It will also copy staff.
I d so in excess.
Lt,
when you want the text inside an element,
you use xsl value off.
So after xsl text xsl value off and then select equals whatever output you need at this
particular stage.
So we want the contents of stop I d.
So here we need an expert statement and we put in an expert statement in the context set by
the template that were inside.
So the context is either gonna be a branch manager head all staff member element.
And from that starting point,
we want a child element.
So we're going along the child access,
which is,
you know,
can be written like this,
but it's normally simply admitted because it's the default axis.
So they go along,
the child access on.
We look for an element called staff I d.
So that's the technique.
We reconstruct the elements step by step,
starting with the shell xsl element Name equals start by Deeble.
Create the shell of the element and put nothing inside it.
Then we use xsl text to insert a literal string so we can have the apostrophe and then xsl
valuables.
Well,
look inside stuff I D.
On output,
that text that it contains.
So let's save a man.
Just go across to exult.
Attest that it's working.
So file open.
There we go to number four and branches use the style Sheen's and here's our stuff I D.
And as you can see,
we've got an apostrophe.
So Excel will now stole of these numbers as text.
So that takes care of all the elements that we want in the output.
And in the next video,
we'll move on to look at creating attributes.