Let's now move on to look at the two conditional statements that you can use with xsl style
sheets,
the first of which is xsl.
If let's move into under six and then open up branches,
don't xsl where we can see our file as we left it in the last video.
So he got out two attributes,
and the third attribute was the more complicated one.
Because we go back to our XML,
we want to process the branch manager element differently to the way in which head and
staff member elements of processed there are two conditional elements in xsl xsl.
If an xsl choose excess,
I live is the simpler of the two.
It is similar to excels if function,
but it's simpler with excels.
It function.
You have a test,
a value of true value,
false with xsl.
If you have a test and then you do something.
If the test is true,
if the test is false,
nothing happens.
So in other words,
you can only do something.
If the test is positive when the test is negative,
nothing occurs.
So let's have a look at how it works.
So we created our third attributes which has a name of departments on what we want to do,
is to test the name of the context element.
Is it staff member,
head or branch manager?
And if the name is not branch manager,
then we want to move up the ancestor access to find the name attribute of the department
element.
So we use xsl if and then instead of select used test.
And then we can use the name function that we've seen a few times Name of the current
context element not equal to which we've also seen.
Men in single quotes Franch under school manager Close single.
Close.
So you close out if and then between the open and close in tanks.
We specifying the output that we want xsl value off and then select,
will equal ancestor access for which there is no shortcut.
This time we're looking for department end of location steps forward slash switch to the
attribute access by using the at sign and again the attributes is called name.
And that's all we can do with the If statement,
he is out test.
And here's what we want to do if the test is true.
But xsl if doesn't provide a mechanism for saying what we want to do if the test is false.
So we happy to say that if the name is equal to branch manager,
do nothing.
In other words,
leave the value empty,
then we're home and dry.
But if we want to put a value,
for example,
you want to say not applicable or administration.
Ben will need to use the other conditional provided by xsl,
and that's xsl choose.
So that's it for this video.
Let's save and just test that it's still work in.
So they were in number six,
Uh,
so if we look at the branch managers by filtering on the roll,
we can see that none of them have a value inside the department.
Where is everyone else?
Does have a value.
So that's how xsl if works in the next video,
we'll move on to look at it slightly more sophisticated partner in crime xsl choose