in this video,
we'll take a look at the xsl choose element,
which allows you to happen if else if functionality.
So it's going to number seven using excess old shoes and again open up branches.
Don't xsl where you can see the file as we left it in the last video.
So so far we have a single test,
but we have no mechanism for test into the alternative occurrence.
This is where xsl choose becomes useful so we can still use although code we have so rather
than the late in it,
I'm just gonna tablet in and then above it,
we'll put xsl choose an xsl chooses just a shell,
so we'll need the clothes in tag off the excess and live.
And the mechanism that xsl choose uses to do its test in is to have a child element called
xsl when so we now need to change this if to a when and it caused the clothes in.
Tak needs to be changed as well,
so this becomes the equivalent of our if statement.
But what we can now do that we couldn't do with the xsl if is to repeat xsl when as many
times as necessary to test for different possibilities.
On this occasion we only need one test.
But what we can also do inside xsl choose is to put a cattle which will only kick in if all
the preceding xsl went tests proved to be false.
So obviously,
on this occasion there is only one xsl went test.
But the point is we could have as many as we like and then to say if all of them are falls
due the following we used xsl otherwise And of course,
this is not a test We've done all the test in so xsl otherwise simply means if all of the
tests proved to be false so obviously out test Waas name is not equal to branch manager.
Hence the otherwise will pick up the circumstance when name is equal to branch manager.
And in that circumstance,
let's say that we want to display the text not applicable.
So because this is a literal string,
we don't need xsl value off.
We can just use xsl text and then we have opening and closing tags on.
We don't need any double quotes weaken Just put the literal stream.
So that's how xsl choose works.
The xsl choose itself is just a shell on then xsl,
when with test equals is used to test for all the possible values that you're interested in
,
check in for and then you use xsl.
Otherwise is a cattle which will only kick in if all of your xsl went tests are false.
So again,
let's save on test.
So this time,
when we display,
only the branch manager rose older than have not applicable as the department entry.
So that completes our look at condition ALS and to finish off this section and indeed to
finish the course will stay with attributes that never look at a very useful feature called
attribute found you template.