in this section,
we looked at the basics of working with excess lt style sheets,
and we've done so in the context of imported XML data into Microsoft Excel excess.
Lt is a very deep topic,
and excess lt style streets can be extremely complex.
And as you can imagine,
we're only just scratching the surface.
But no look at excess.
Lt is complete without the final topic that we're gonna cover,
which is attribute value templates.
So that's going to sub folder number eight and just have a look at how they work.
So the local branches,
the xsl and this is where we left off in the last video.
And let's focus on the section of the style sheet where we specifying the output that we
want to generate and the two elements that leave used to do that xsl element on xsl
contribute as well as using these two elements access.
Lt also permits you to use literal elements,
so to create a person element instead of sane xsl element name equals person.
You can simply type a person tag like said,
and then obviously you need to close that person tang on the bottom and that will produce
exactly the same result.
So let's do that for the other elements that were output in stuff I D.
And then we'll stroll to the top and do the same with the root element.
The main benefit of using literal tags in this way is that your code tends to be shorter
and it begins to resemble the output that you're created.
So you've got a better idea of what the output will look like as you're creating your style
sheet on.
This becomes even more the case when you do the same thing for attributes.
So instead of using xsl attributes,
you can actually write the attribute inside the opening tag of the element to which you
want to attack it.
So here we would just put the name of the attributes,
which is role equals double quotes.
Then we can do the same for Branch.
And then inside the double quotes,
we have the option of inserting the expats that we have inside xsl value ALS.
So I can now copy this expert statement.
But if I was simply to paste it inside these double quotes,
I would be implying that I want literally what it says inside the quotes.
So I need to find a way to tell the excess lt process er that what's inside these double
puts is actually an expanse statement that needs to be processed accordingly.
On the mechanism for doing this is called an attribute value template on the syntax for
indicated an attribute value template.
It's curly braces,
so you find now paste my expert inside those curly braces.
I've indicated that this is X path as opposed to a literal string,
and I can do the same with the value off the branch,
Elhanan said.
It's copy all of that and then paste it inside curly braces.
So now these to attribute declarations are surplus to requirements,
I could get rid of them.
So now,
as I'm looking at the xsl code,
I can get a much better idea of what the output documents gonna look like.
So here I'll have,
like people root element,
then inside that have a person element inside of which have role and branch.
Now,
as you can imagine,
I can't do the same thing with the department attributes because I've got a complex
definition of what needs to go inside,
so we'll need to leave my xsl True's intact inside the xsl attributes element.
But wherever I have a simple xsl value off statement that I can use this mechanism of doing
a literal definition off my attributes and then using this very useful attribute value
template mechanism to specify the experts that will generate the content for that attribute
.
So that's what attribute value templates are,
and that's how they work.
Let's just save and do one final test in Excel to make sure that everything still works.
Uh,
and as you can see,
everything is still working on.
We go across to developer.
Look at our map were still there all three attributes.
So just bear that in mind.
You've got two ways of working.
You can either use xsl element and xsl attribute,
or you can use literal strings to define your elements and your attributes and then used
attribute value templates to specify the value off each of those attributes.
So that completes our look at excess.
Lt.
And indeed,
it completes the course.
Hope you found it useful.
I'd appreciate any feedback that you have.
And if you have any questions,
feel free to ask.
So thank you very much for your time.
And I hope to meet you again on another calls.
Goodbye