an XML document is essentially a hierarchical tree structure,
consistent and what are normally referred to.
As knows,
each node is of a particular type and perhaps the most important type.
Certainly the most frequently encountered within the tree structure is the element load
elements have to may functions.
The first is to define the structure of the XML document by containing other knows,
in this example,
the root element.
It's called tools,
and within this route element,
we have the tour element,
and this would typically be a repeated element inside each tour element.
In turn,
we have name,
destination region on price,
and it's inside these child nodes that we find the actual text,
the main content that the XML document.
This is the logical structure of the XML document.
Let's now look at how that structure would be written in our training folder were working
in zero to Excel.
Many Central's Let's now go into sub folder three elements.
If you'd like to have a go it creating the XML document for yourself.
Double click on the file call tools don't J.
Peg.
I just use that as a guide and then see if you can actually create this from scratch.
If you'd like to do that,
just pause the video on,
then go ahead and have a go of lice.
Let's do it together.
It's just double take on tools that XML,
which is just a blank file.
Let's begin by putting in the XML declaration.
Okay,
Okay.
When creating an XML document,
it's normal toe work in the same hierarchical fashion as we can see in this diagram.
So we start by creating the root element,
which is we've said it's called tools.
XML is case sensitive,
so it will work into a specification.
We need to take that into account,
say most editors.
If you create the opening tag as soon as you finished it,
the closing tag has created for you automatically,
and here we can just press enter twice.
Press the up arrow to position the cursor between the opening and closing tax of the root
element.
A bad press,
the tab key to in dent,
indicating that what we're about to create is an element inside tools,
and this is done purely for readability.
It makes absolutely no difference how much mind space you put into an XML document and next
we need the tool element and again we'll create a blind line moved back up and tabbing to
indicate a child element.
Then we have name,
Destination,
region and Price.
I've just pressing the end key to get to the end of the line each time.
And finally we have our text.
Five day guided tour,
San Diego,
South America 2595 Okay,
and let's say we now want to create another tour element.
Obviously we do the logical thing,
which is to copy this entire structure,
paste it and make the necessary changes.
Let's say we have another five day guided tour to Caracas again in South America,
but slightly Chiba.
So things to note elements can either contain child elements.
All the actual text,
your content of an XML document elements and normally written by placing an open intact
among the start of the element content and the closing tag to indicate where the content
actually ends.
Any text or any elements place between the opening tag on the closing tag are the contents
or Children off that element.
Elements then are perhaps the most important no type within an XML document.
In the next video,
we'll move on to look at what is probably the second most important after abuse