continue Now look at the different types of node that you can find in an XML document in
this video will move on to look at attributes on how attributes differ from elements we saw
in the previous two videos.
But elements are the most important nodes within XML documents they used both to contain on
their elements and to contain the actual data that the XML document is.
Story.
By contrast,
attributes are normally used to store metadata.
That is to say,
information about your data here in the tools example which we worked with in the last
video.
We want to add an a tribute to the tour's element,
the apparent element called Season On.
We want to give that attribute a value of 2017 on.
We're doing this because we regard it is meta data.
It's information,
which is important,
but which isn't part of the data set.
That's,
for example,
if this XML was going to be used to produce a brochure,
the season probably wouldn't appear as part of the data.
That's what we're implying by using season as an attribute rather than having it is an
element which contains data and let's take another example,
we have a price element.
Let's say that we want to clarify that the currency being used is pounds sterling tpp.
But we don't necessarily want to indicate this in the brochure itself.
So again we have metadata rather than data.
And for that reason we want to implement.
This is an attribute rather than as an element.
So that's the logic behind that tributes.
Let's now have a look at how they're written.
Attributes have written inside the Oaten in tag often element.
So this generic example.
We have an element called My Element,
and we want to assign an attribute to it called My Attribute.
In the opening tag we write,
my attributes equals.
And then,
in double quotes,
we put the value that we want to assign to the attribute.
Then we have the content of the element,
and we have the clothes in tag.
It's when you implemented an attribute,
only the open in tag off.
The element is affected.
Nothing happens to the content,
and nothing happens to the close.
In tack.
Let's get some practice on.
Working with attributes in zero to XML essentials,
open up some folder Number four attributes And then let's open tools dot xml,
which is the file that we created in the last video.
And let's create the two attributes that we've just been discussing.
The first was season on.
We want to put this into the root element tours simply click after the name of the element
,
put his space and then put the name of your attributes.
In this case,
we call in its season equals.
The spaces are optional,
input in them in for readability only.
And then in double quotes,
we put out 2017.
And then let's do the same for price.
Nothing happens to the close in Tak.
It's always the opening tag.
We click after the name of the Element,
which is price but a space.
And then we put our attribute.
This time we want currency equals,
and we always use the double quotes CBP.
So let's say about changes.
The very first example of XML that we looked at on this course was a file called Basic.
And here's a diagram representing the XML structure in that file,
and you'll notice it contains two attributes.
We have an attribute inside the staff member element called department and We also have an
attribute inside the photo element called Age Ref.
There's one important difference between the stump member on the photo element.
Staff member has contents.
It has child elements.
Photo has no child elements and it has no textual content.
Theeighties ref attribute is its only content.
This type of element is normally referred to as an empty element.
Empty implies that it has no child elements and no textual content,
empty elements that have an attribute normally written with one tag only.
So using generic syntax,
we would say my element space,
my attributes equals.
And then,
in double quotes,
we have the value.
And then to indicate that this tag is both an opening and closing tag,
we put it forward slash before the close in angle bracket.
Let's have a look at the file to remind ourselves in zero to XML essentials.
Some folder four attributes Couple quick on staff dot xml and this is what the Fire looks
like is our first attribute in the staff member Element department equals accounts.
Staff member is an element that has child elements,
but in contrast,
photo has no trial elements,
so you'll notice that it's written as a single tag.
Hey,
Trev equals then we have a file path,
and then we have a forward slash in front of the close in angle bracket.
So that's the difference.
Let's just closed the file.
Let's implement the same structure in our tools.
Example.
You know,
folder.
You'll notice that we haven't images Sub folder and inside.
We've got a couple of photos matching the two destinations that we've inserted into our XML
so far,
and I'd like to say a quick thank you to pick sabei dot com for supplying these energies.
So let's go back to our XML on Let's add in images element to our structure,
says Reach to We have image.
And then we'll put an attribute,
which points to the photo.
We can call the attributes anything we like.
I'm going to call it S R C,
which is taken from HTML equals quotes and then I'm just gonna put a relative path to the
file.
So images is the name of the folder forwards.
Laugh,
Santiago,
don't drink,
Peg.
And then to finish off,
we put forward slash on the clothes in angle brackets and then we could just copy this
whole line three clicks to select the entire line,
and then we can copy by use in control and drag.
This works in most editors apologies.
If it doesn't work in the one you're use it.
And here we just change Santiago to Caracas,
and that completes our look at the use of attributes and just to summarize.
Attributes tend to be used for metadata rather than data.
The attributes is always inserted into the open in tag oven element.
When the element has no content,
a single tag is used.
The attribute is inserted into that single tag on.
Then the single tag is closed with forward slash,
followed by the close in angle bracket.
And just to point out that currency equals G V,
P will probably be inserted on a low price elements.
Even though I didn't do this in the demonstration.