In the last video,
we discuss the use of entity references to enable you to use illegal characters within the
content of your XML documents where you want to make frequent use of these characters
Within an XML document,
the XML specification offers another approach called a C data section.
See data stands for character data,
and what it does is to enable you to create an entire section in which you can use illegal
characters as many times as you wish.
All sections within your XML document normally treated his PC data or past character data.
And when rent by an XML passer,
illegal characters can only be used within XML marker.
Your data cannot contain any illegal characters.
But by using C data sections,
you're telling the XML Parsa that this particular section contains character data only.
There is no markup within this section.
Once the pass,
it knows that it will automatically converted legal characters to the corresponding
entities.
This is the syntax that's used to demarcate a C data section.
The open intact consists of a left angle bracket,
followed by an exclamation mark and square brackets.
On the key word see data,
another case and then it ends with another opening square bracket.
When to terminate a C data section,
you simply close the two square brackets and then close the open in angle bracket with a
corresponding close in angle bracket between the opening and closing tags.
You can then have whatever characters you like.
So in this example,
we've got the Hello World XML document that we created a few videos back and because it's
nested inside a C data section,
all the legal characters which normally wouldn't be allowed Ah,
um,
is it so Let's get some practice on Working with C data sections in zero to XML Essentials
.
Let's open up six C data sections.
Are we going to stay with the same tutorial theme that we saw in the last video?
So if you open up tutorial that J.
Peg,
this is the XML structure,
but we're working inside.
They have Tutorial is a ruse element,
and the child elements are author,
title and topic.
Then inside the topic element,
we have a title which is the first child,
followed by as many parent elements as we want.
But this time we want to submit a tutorial on excess.
Lt So let's open up tutorial dot txt So we've got a tutorial fragment which is you can see
includes an XML document.
This is,
in fact,
a very short excess lt style sheet.
So rather than convert in all of these illegal characters into entity references,
what we can do is to demarcate the section as a C data section.
So let's create our XML document.
That's open up tutorial dot xml.
This time,
I've created a skeleton off the document for you since we've already practice creating this
structure.
So let's just copy in First of all,
the title element Control V,
the author now the topic title.
So here we have two illegal characters.
It's manually changed them into entity references.
So we have ampersand lt for less than semi Coolum.
And then here come percent GT for greater than semi cola.
Then we can copy that across.
And now we have two paragraphs.
No problems here and finally we have our code which we want to embed inside a C data
section.
So the syntax is left angle bracket,
exclamation mark open square brackets.
See data in upper case square brackets once more that I'll use control V to paste.
Now I need to close square brackets twice because I've opened square brackets twice and
then put the right angle bracket to finish.
So there's my see data section,
and if all is well,
I should have a valid XML file.
So let's go across to code Beautify Dog.
We've got the U.
R L in the tractor,
too,
so just copy that you're l and paste it into your browser.
Let's grab our code on controlled vita paste in our code and validates.
And as you can see,
we have pilot XML.