continue.
Now look at the various objects which could be placed inside an XML file.
We now come to comments and you'll notice that comments can be placed both in the prologue
and also anywhere inside the root element.
Comments are useful feature found in all coded environments,
which enabled you to insert text anywhere within the document,
which will not be treated as code and will be totally ignored.
So comments of purely for the reference of the person working with the XML file to look at
how comments are implemented in XML in zero to XML essentials.
That's going to number seven comments and I know tools dot xml to insert a comment in the
prologue.
Place the comment after the XML declaration,
it can't proceed the XML declaration and above the rigs element in terms of the appearance
of a comment.
If you worked with HTML XML comments are identical left angle brackets,
exclamation mark,
two hyphens,
then your comments and then to close to hyphens and a right angle bracket.
So in this document,
we might say these files can only contain five day tour listed,
so that's an example of a comment in the prologue and I'm just gonna copy that.
And let's place one in the root element.
For example,
Special offer expires with the August.
Another frequent use of comments in all code in environments is to comment out a section
off your code.
For example,
if we didn't want this element to be taken into account when we use the XML file on this
occasion rather than delete in this section,
we could simply turn it into a comment so it will be ignored when any XML process in its
done so.
All we need to do is to put the open in tax here,
but closing tags where we want the comment to stop,
and then everything between the opening and closing tax effectively becomes a comment and
is therefore temporarily disabled.
And that's all there is to an XML.
Comment.
If you've encountered comments in your HTML code in as you can see,
a completely identical in XML