Now one thing that can confuse people
new to Android studio are the templates
that Google include with it especially
as they sometimes change them when they
release a new version. Now I try to keep
the course up to date but with new
versions of Android studio coming out
every few months there will be times
when it looks a little bit different to
how it appears in these videos so I'm
going to create a couple of new projects
using some of the templates that are
currently shipping with Android studio
and show off some of the ways that they
differ from each other, now remember
that these are just templates though
they're provided to save you having to
type in some of the basic code the
projects need but there's no reason or
you can't change any of the code that
the templates create if you use a
template that includes a menu for
example but decide that you don't want
to provide a menu in your project then
you can just delete the menu code and if
you've used a word processing program
such as Libre Office or Microsoft Word
and you may be familiar with the concept
of templates and these are really no
different. Alright so let's have a look
at the templates and we're going to
start by creating a new project now if
you're watching this video in the Kotlin
course make sure that the included
Kotlin support box is ticked that's the
default and probably already will be
ticked. So let's start off anyway click
on start a new android studio project we
can see this button that I'm talking about
down here include Kotlin support so
again that's the default it probably is
already clicked and if you're in the
Kotlin course make sure that is clicked
but if you're watching this video in the
java course you need to add tick that box
leaving it ticked will cause Android
studio to generate Kotlin
rather than Java code, now I've mention
that each time we create a new project
at least for the first few projects so
whether you generate the correct code
for the language you're using. Now I'm
going to an tick the box and that's
because Java programmers don't need to
know anything about Kotlin but Kotlin
programmers will need basic familiarity
with Java.
So whenever a video shows code in both
courses I'm going to show the Java code
don't worry though if we need to write
any code at all there'll be separate
videos for each course so in the Kotler
course, keep their box ticked then you
can compare the Kotlin code on your
screen with a java code that's going to
appear on mine so leave everything else
on the screen as I said for this
particular application of doing something a
little bit different and then including
and I've unchecked the box I'm gonna
click on next we leave everything I said
it as it is and on this next screen
we're going to leave everything else as
it is as well now we're going to be
explaining these screens in the next
video but for now I just want to focus
on the templates so I'm gonna click on
next. Now at the time I'm recording this
Android studio sits with 13 templates
and the images on this selection screen
try to give you an indication of what
they contain. Now add no activity this
one here is the most basic but I
generally don't use that for most apps
because we normally need at least one
activity now I'm not going to go through
describing all the templates because a
lot of the explanation won't make much
sense just yet anyway and in fact you
may be wondering what this activity that
I've just mentioned is but don't worry
I'll be explaining all that next now
once you're comfortable with Android
studio and you've worked through a few
of the apps in this course by all means
have a go at creating projects based on
each of these templates to get a feel
for what they provide for now the only
ones we really need to use are the basic
activity and the empty activity so basic
in empty now you can see from these
images that basic activity contains a
little bit more than the empty activity
template you can see the icon for the
drop-down menu at the top right and it
also has a floating action button this
little yellow button at the bottom right
so if your app will include a menu or a
floating action button or both then
you'd probably be best off starting with
the basic activity template but if you
don't want either of those then use the
empty activity template instead but what
if you want to menu but not a floating
action button well in that case you can
either start with an empty activity and
at the menu code or and this is probably
easier start with a basic activity and
delete the code for the floating action
button, so I'm going to start by choosing
this empty activity over here so that we
can see what that provides. Now on the
next screen as I click that I'm going to
leave everything as it is and accept the
default values, so we'll see this
activity name and layout name used in a
minute so just remember that they're
called main activity and activity
underscore main click on finish. Now
Android studio takes a little while to
create the project then you should end
up with something that will look a
little bit like this once this is finished
so I'll just fast forward this alright
so you should end up saying something
that looks a little bit similar to this
now the version of Android studio that
I'm using to record this video starts
off in what's called Android view after
creating a new project, you can see this
Android tab up here in the top left hand
corner and Android was the default mode
that's been selected. Now some people
prefer to work in project view but it
really doesn't matter which one you use
we can switch to project view by
clicking project and then we can expand
the selection of folders and expand the
details out of our application. Now some
of the other views won't show most of
the files we need so I would be using
them in this course now the app that
we've created is called my application
what's actually called my application -
and that's because I already created one
previously called my application and I
expanded that view and you saw that we
saw there was this app folder expand
that click that open and this is where
most of the files were interested in
they're located now in Android view you
switch back to that the app folder was
at the top level this one here and I can
expand that out and this is why many
people prefer to work in that view more
files are visible in project for you but
most of them are the ones that you don't
generally need to worry about the main
files we have to change or create are in
this Java or res folders or it's just
back to project view we can expand that
out we've still got the source main
we've got the Java and res folders here
they're just a little bit in a slightly
different location when in project view
compared to Android view that's the same
set of files essentially just presented
in a different way so choose whichever
view you're most comfortable with
I'll be mainly using the Android view in
this course now over on the right-hand
pane up here there's two files open
activity underscore maintain XML and
mainactivity.java.
Now these are the names of the activity
in the layout from the earlier screen
now if we close these we can open them
up we're just opening the particular
folder in the case of the Java folder we
can double click main activity to open
them up and the activity in the school
made you can look at the layout folder
and double click that and open it up like that
and again going back to Android view
you can see essentially the same thing
opening up we can see that main activity
file was there that in the res folder
and the layout folder there's our
activity_main.xml. Now the
activity_main.xml
defines what the screen for the activity
will look like and if I go into this
design tab which is selected currently
anyway you can see that it looks very
similar to the template image there's no
menu icon showing a no failing action
buttons just a text hello world as you
can see there. Now main activity also it
doesn't contain very much we have a look
at that don't worry about what any of
this code means at the moment I'm just
showing you what the templates look like
so you don't get stuck when Google
changes them again in the future and
also don't worry that this is Java code
if you're watching this in the Kotlin
version of the course anything we do
with the screen layouts is the same
regardless of the language used, so some
of the videos have the same for both
courses. Now we can see that we've got a
class here called main activity and
that's got a single method called on
create, a class named method named make
a mental note of that and then we'll see
how the next template differs, so what
I'm going to do now though is in the
video and in the next video, we'll go
ahead and we'll create a second project
this time based on the basic activity
template. So I'll see you in the next video.