Google of Neil made Kotlin of top-level
language for Android development which
means that it's fully supported in
Android studio and they'll also be
publishing example code using Kotlin as
well as Java at the moment though most
of their code samples are still in Java
now turns out that's not a huge problem
because we kind of look in this section
of how Android studio can convert Java
code to Kotlin for us so in this section
we're going to look at the Kotlin
programming language just to give you an
overview and introduction to it so let's
get started now Android studio is
designed for Android development which
means that the projects it creates are
intended to be run on an Android device
and not on your computer now it is
possible though to get Android studio to
compile and run pure Kotlin code it is
very fiddly so we've created a project
for you this that Android studio
projects been specifically configured to
run pure cotton code that will run on
your computer now before I show you how
to get that working there's another
alternative now if you're already using
IntelliJ as your IDE and I recommend
using that for these tutorials instead
now Android studio is based on IntelliJ
IDEA so everything will work just as is
in the videos now you may also be taking
Sarah at ratures Kotlin for Java
developers course in which case you'll
see how to install IntelliJ IDEA in that
course for everybody else that I'm going
to go through the steps to get Android
studio to run pure Kotlin code now the
project we've created is in a zip file
in the resources section of this video
so let's just move over now and I'm
going to show you how to get that sim
phone how to unzip it and get it ready
for use on your computer
all right so the project we've created
is in a zip file in the resources
section of this video and this is the
file that so we're going to be using for
our Kotlin tutorial and if you move the
mouse over the video
a pop up balloon will appear at the top
left and just above that you'll see a
menu icon and if you click on that and
scroll down to this video in the list
you'll actually see an area where you
can download the file and the file that
you want is called Kotlin tutorial does
it so you can check that out and
download that file because we'll need
that file to actually work on these
tutorials there Kotlin tutorial if
you've got any problems finding the
Kotlin tutorial file just look in this
lecture of the lecture that you're
looking at now basically just go into
the top left of the screen and you
should see a resources section but also
the last lecture of the course has got a
list of all the downloads so you can
grab it from there as well and what you
need to do is download for that file
Kotlin cheeto road of zip and put it
somewhere on your computer and you can
see in my case I want a mac and I've
downloaded into a folder once you've
done that you need to unzip it now in my
case of a Mac I can just double-click
the file to unzip it and you can see it
creates a subfolder now if you're on a
Windows machine or Linux machine you
most likely have to right-click that
file and select expand all or uncompress
or words to that effect and expand that
directory out and make a note of where
that directory is because we'll need
that when we go back to Android studio
alright so let's go back to Android
studio now alright so now that we've
downloaded and unzipped the Kotlin
tutorial files next step is to open it
in Android studio so click on open an
existing Android studio project you want
to navigate to the folder where the file
has been unzipped in my case it Scotland
tutorial so I'm going to double click on
that to open it and click on open now
Android studio will load the project and
it may take quite a while the first time
while it builds the project on Windows
in particular be prepared to wait about
a minute before the project fully loads
and the wallets loading you may get an
error like this or a warning like this
basically saying that the path and
whatever the path is that we've
actually used to create the zip file
doesn't belong to a directory just click
OK to that and Android shit is then
going to use the setup or configuration
that you've done in your version of
Android studio
all right so Neal got the project open
in Android studio now you may actually
be asked if you want to upgrade the
version of the Kotlin plug-in or Gradle
used by this project so if you do get
asked that don't do it now we normally
suggest that you accept all the updates
Android studio offers but don't update
anything in this particular project the
reason is that we spent a lot of time
hacking the Gradle files around to make
this work updating Google or the Kotlin
plugin will break those changes now if
that happens the program won't compile
you'll need to delete the project
directory and extract it from the zip
file again alright so if you look up
wrote the project open in Android studio
now the main part of the window is the
edit window which is currently empty
that's as part here and it shows some
useful lost shortcuts but there's no
file displayed because we're not editing
anything yet over to the left here is
the project panel or project pane and it
shows the files making up our project
and at the moment we're only interested
in what main dot katie's over here so so
just before we go into there I'm going
to explain briefly what these other
things so the Gradle scripts folder that
heading there contains various
configuration options for the Gradle
build system so I can open that up then
have a look there now granel's
responsible for things like compiling
our Kotlin code and producing the
executable that we can run it's great or
that we had to change to get Android
studio to cope with plain cotton rather
than the Android project structure that
was designed for now we're going to be
looking at a couple of the files in
there later but for now you can safely
ignore everything in this section now
the top of the project pane is our
project Kotlin cheetor which you can see
highlighted and expanding that if you
haven't already and again it should be
it shows a job a subfolder here so you
can see and I know this is a Kotlin
course but historically everything was
written in Java so consequently
Android studio once that directory to be
called Java now below that is the Kotlin
source code file we're going to be
creating more of these but the moment
there's only the one Kotlin file in the
project and by the way it's possible to
mix Java and Kotlin source code in the
same project and if you do that
the Java files will have a dot Java
extension and the Kotlin files will have
a dot Katy extension as you can see in
this example here now to edit a file you
just need to double click it so we can
open main by double clicking it there
which I'm going to do mundo Katie that
shows some cotton code on the screen
there now this is a very simple Kotlin
program and we're going to be going
through what it all means shortly for
now though we have to get it working now
let's try running the program now it
turns out there's four different ways to
do that and they all do the same thing
now we could go to the run menu up here
you click on and select run Katie and
run main Katie we can also right click
on the entity here and choose run main
Katie there from the context menu
now by the way sometimes the menu
doesn't appear there but it does when
you right click on main dot Katie in the
project pane same I need to click on
that right click and run
main Katie there to get it to show the
fourth way to run is to use this green
triangle in the toolbar now what that
does can vary and the drop-down list on
its left will tell you what it's going
to run so you can see over here it's
telling you it's gonna be running main
Katie so in other words it's set to main
Katie so it's going to run our main or
our current Kotlin file but watch out
for that because we're gonna be using
different files as we work through these
videos so keep an eye on what it says
over here in that Dropbox to make sure
that you're running the correct file
alright so we've got four different ways
to run this program but none of them
will work as I said we had to hack
around with the project files to get
this to work with Android studio but
there's one final step we couldn't get
past so use any one of these four
methods and run the program in my case
I'm going to right click via main duct
Katie over here in the project pane and
she's run Katie from there
now the prototype will be built as it
was there but you'll actually get an
error and you can see this error could
not we'll find or load main class main
Katie now this will only happen the
first time we try this so just follow
along and run the program and you'll get
the error like I've got here now once
that's happened and you see the error as
you can see in the screen there could
not find the load class main Katie go to
the build menu up here and click on
rebuild project then when you do that
nothing really seems to happen but now
the project will run using any of the
four methods now it's a tradition that
the first program you write in a new
language should print HelloWorld and
that's what this program does so let's
try running I don't think I do the same
way try and run at the same way select
run main Katie and you can see in this
case now that we've done that we're
successfully getting the text to output
on the screen hello world all right so
that's our project set up and working
then we're going to use this same
project throughout these tutorial videos
and add new files as we go along as you
start each new video make sure you've
got this project open in Android studio
and again as a recap the reason we've
done all this is because it's much
easier to explain Kotlin where we can
just run our programs directly rather
than having to run them as an Android
app in an emulator now there are two
ways to close the project if you just
close the Android studio using the close
that icon at top left up here or top
right on windows then the project will
open again automatically the next time
you start Android studio personally I
prefer to go to the file menu and clue
and choose close project first so we
need to that Android studio starts up on
the welcome screen as you can see here
but it also remembers the last projects
you've opened so you come over here and
click on Kotlin tutorial in the list to
open the project again
alright so we're all set up now so I'm
going to stop the video here and in the
next video we'll start looking at the
Kotlin language and what we can do with
it see you in the next video