Okay, so moving on with the Kotlin
tutorial I'm going to go into a bit more
detail. Now with classes and look at them
more in depth now an important thing to
understand and it took me a while to get
the hang of this when I first added
object-oriented programming is that a
class is like a cookie cutter or a
template and from that you can create an
unlimited number of player objects or
player instances and at the end of the
last video we created four instances
from our player class so we're going to
do is delete the commented out code
firstly these four print lines because
we don't need those anymore and then
just run the program again even though
it's still showing on the screen just to
remind ourselves what it was doing you
can see it's outputting the four player
instances there and their values so
we're getting four totally separate
objects displayed but they were all
created from the same template class our
player class in this case now they all
have the same properties they have a
name and lives level and score
properties but each instance or object
has different values for those
properties now they also all have a show
method or show function they mean the
same thing you know Colin tends to use
determine function by the way but the
object oriented team term is a method so
you hear me use both ways to refer to a
function that's part of a class now if
we look at the show method in the player
class it just prints out the values of
the properties as you can see from Lyons
are seven through water him now each
instance of the player class has
different values for the properties
which is why calling Tim show on line
three of our main method here prints
different valleys to the Eloise not show
on line six
okay so let's extend our player class
now a little bit further so we look at
our player class again so we've got name
lives level and score and we've used a
string and three int types but you're
not restricted to using just those types
of variables we could use an object as a
type in a class in fact in Kotlin string
and into our classes so we're already
using objects now that'll make more
sense if I create an example so I'm
going to create this new class called
weapon to show what I mean there first
before when creating a new class you
click on a right click on the Java
folder or Java Java directory new and
select Kotlin file class and I call this
one weapon we're going to leave this set
to file this time just to show you what
you'd have to do if you didn't select
the class and you can see that it just
created a comment but it hasn't actually
created our class declaration so I can
actually just type that in manually a
class weapon in this case we're going to
give it some properties in the primary
constructor remember that we define them
in parenthesis immediately after the
class name some of the parentheses there
so the properties that we weren't for a
weapon we're going to start with val
name colon string comma then var damage
inflicted colon int closing parentheses
and I'm going to open the code block
create a block of code using the left or
right curly braces so weapons gonna have
a name like axe or sword and we'll store
that in a string field then we have a
need to show how much damage this
particular weapon does now I haven't
used any default values there so we'll
have to specify both values when we
create our weapon objects note that I've
made damage inflicted of our property
now it probably wouldn't change in the
normal course of a game like this but I
want to use it to demonstrate something
else soon so imagine that there's some
magic spell in the game that can make
weapons more deadly or something okay so
moving on and we've now got a very
simple class that can be used to
represent a weapon in a game so let's
use this class in our player class we'll
let the player have weapons so we need a
property in the player class to store
the weapon in and if you usually declare
properties before methods so I'm going
to go back to the player class we're
going to add this at the start of the
class so just below the class definition
on line 5 I'm going to come over here
tab over and type var weapon colon then
weapon with a capital W I'm going to
press Enter
now you see that sort of thing done a
lot in Kotlin programming
the class name normally gives a good
indication of what it represents
so weapon with a capital W tells us that
the class represents a weapon so that's
the type of the property and we call it
weapon with a lowercase W now we could
have you called it something else such
as player's weapon or something but
weapons a good name for the object now
because variables in Kotlin are
case-sensitive weapon with a capital W
and weapon with a lowercase W are
referring to different things
so here weapon with a capital W is W is
the name of the class and weapon with a
lowercase W is an object or instance of
that type or it will be once we create
the weapon so you'll see that sort of
thing done a lot when we use Android
classes and you'll see things like I'm
just going to type some code in
temporarily vowel recycler u adapter
colon recyclerview adapter that's an
example of code that you'll actually see
in Android so it's very common to use
the class name for the variable name but
with a lowercase initial letter alright
so I'm going to delete that line and now
let's give the player a default weapon
when the player objects or instances are
created now at the moment we've got an
error in the declaration of our weapon
and that's because Colton wants
everything to be given a value when it's
declared now you'll see ways to avoid
doing that and of deferring the initial
value until later but for now we're
going to give everything a value so when
a player's first start playing I won't
have found any weapons so we're just
going to give them the fist to start
with so we've typed var weapon colon
weapon then we can put after an
assignment so equals weapon with a
capital W parenthesis double quotes fist
comma one and ending parenthesis so now
each time we create a new player the
code will automatically create a new
weapon object which in this case will be
a fist now they're going to be finding
more weapons as they play the game so
that's why I've made weapon of are there
now we want to assign different weapons
to ultimately hopefully you know you're
starting to see when to
his Val I went to use var no don't worry
though if it's still unclear just
remember that you can always change your
declarations if you decide that you
should have used bar for example instead
of Val so let's actually check this all
works by printing out the name of aces
weapon and the damage it can do in our
main function so we're gonna come over
here to main and we're going to after
this one to watch dot show we're going
to put print 'ln parentheses want to
watch dot weapon dot name then on the
next line print 'ln want to watch darts
weapon dot damage inflicted first run
the program and we can see down the
bottom of here we've got fist and one
printed so notice how we're still using
dot notation to access the properties of
the two classes so one to watch dot
weapon gives us a reference to aces
weapon object and we can access the
properties of the weapon by using more
dots so dot name gives the name of the
weapon and dot damage inflicted gives
the amount of damage that weapon does
now the name he is a string and i
mentioned that string is also a class so
we can expect the string class to have
some functions of its own and it turns
out that it does so i'm not going to
list them all here but a useful one
converts the string to uppercase so we
could come over here to weapon dot name
and on the end of that we can add a dot
to uppercase select that and press enter
now we're using one to watch dot weapon
to access the weapon then using dot name
to get the weapons name and finally
calling the names to uppercase function
to convert the name string to capitals
so you can chain these property and
method accesses as far as you want to go
so let's actually just run that to
confirm that it actually works you can
see about fish snails showing in upper
case and this chaining is something that
you see a lot of in Android programming
in fact in common programming in general
as well many of the built-in Java
classes have been designed to be used in
this way now I'm not going to go into
any more complexity at this stage
but suffice to say that when we read the
program as you saw on the screen we've
got fish nail printing out in capitals
so before I finish we're gonna have a
look at a couple of ways that we can
give our place more impressive weapons
now the first way is to create a new
weapon object then assign it to the
player's weapon property let's actually
have a go at doing that so we're going
to come down here after the one to watch
drop weapon damage inflicted live I'm
going to type valve x equals weapon and
capital w parentheses and axe in double
quotes comma and then 12 then we can
type gr8 dot weapon equals ax then you
can type Ritalin gr8 dot weapon dot name
it's a typo and on the next line print
l'm an axe dot name so we've created a
new instance of weapon and we assign it
to the variable X then we saw an axe to
generate weapon property so gr8 neil has
an axe as her weapon which we can see
when we print it out so let's just run
that to make sure that it works and you
can see axe is showing there now X also
exists within our main function
and so we're printing out the value of
the name property from axe on line 18 as
well so we've got two references to the
same object one reference is we're using
the X variable and the others by using
the gr8 or weapon so it's important here
to understand that they both refer to
exactly the same object the X now if
that seems complicated keep in mind that
we do the same thing in normal speech so
someone might refer to my my sons wife's
father-in-law or they may refer to meet
in bachata so it's the same person
unless my son has another wife that
we're not aware of now we can check that
they're the same object by casting that
spell I mentioned earlier on the X and
will increase the damage inflicted by
the axe to 24 so let's actually add the
code so atop X
dot damage inflicted equals 24 print 'ln
ax dot damage inflicted let's run that
so no surprise is there we get 24
printed but before I run the program
again after making this next change
however think about what should be
printed so I'm going to type in the code first
so print 'ln gr8 darts weapon dot damage
inflicted so have a think about what you
think that should print out the code on
line 22 alright so let's run that and
you can see it also shows the value of
24 so remember that these are two
different ways to refer to the same
object the same acts in effect so when
we change the damage inflicted by ax on
line 22 24 generates weapon now it has
24 points of damage so if you did work
out that the program should print 24
again well done and if you're not sure
why that's worth watching these last
couple of videos again alright so I'm
kind of finished with the other way of
assigning a weapon to one of the players
will give me a sword so I'm going to
come down here you're going to type Tim
dot weapon is equal to weapon
parenthesis double quotes sword 10 and
you're going to print Len Tim dot weapon
dot name so this time we're creating a
new weapon and assigning it directly to
my weapon property now we can still
refer to it as Tim dot weapon but we
don't have a direct reference to it in
our main function
so to run the program you can see it
correctly prints out a sword so which
way should you use well the answer is
that it depends we're going to be seeing
one reason for using the first method in
a later video the important thing to
consider is where the weapon in this
case belongs you know obviously you
won't just be dealing with web
objects in your code but the principle
is the same in other words does the axe
belong to the player generate or is it
part of the game so another way to look
at that is to ask can the axe exist in
our program without the player generate
so things like the names Tim Louise one
to watch and so on don't have any
meaning without the player that they're
attached to the X on the sword on the
other hand are part of the overall game
you know I could be forced to drop my
sword at some point in which case
another player might pick it up so if I
drop the sword let's say I pick up a
spear instead so adding that to the code
Tim that weapon is equal to weapon for
int disease spear comma 14 and print 'ln
again Tim daunt weapon dot name so if we
run this so I'm now got a spear and
there's no trace of the sword anyway so
the reference to Tim dot weapon no
longer refers to the sword and we can't
assign that to another player now don't
worry too much about this it's one of
the decisions we have to make when
creating our code at this stage I just
want you to be aware of the difference
and that you can have more than one
reference to the same object we'll come
back to this in a later video when we
provide a way for our players to drop
things that they picked up so I'm going
to stop the video here in the next one
we're gonna have a challenge to let you
practice some of these techniques, so see
you in the next video.