This short video is a challenge to give
you a chance to practice some of what
we've done so far. So the first part of
the challenge is to modify this show
function in the player class so that it
also prints the details for the weapon
that the players have now as well as
printing the players name lives level
and score it should also print the name
of their weapon as well as the damage
that that weapon inflicts now use the
modified show function in main to print
out Tim's details including the weapon
instead of just the weapon so in other
words instead of just printing Tim dot
weapon dot name use the modified show
function there was a hint review the
video or string concatenation and
interpolation to remind yourself how to
include more complex expressions in a
string now for the second part of the
challenge modify the code in the main
function so that Louise gets the sword
before Tim replaces it with a spear so
the point here is to give Louise the
same sword that Tim had not to create a
new one and use the show function to
display the details for Louise to check
the two codes working so that's it
that's the challenge pause the video
here and see how you go at the challenge
and I'll see you when you get back
that is very rarely one way to write
code so your solution may well be
different to mine the real test is that
the weapon details are displayed when
you call the show function so for my
solution I'm going to include the two
properties of the weapon in the output
stream so I'm gonna go back to the
player class I'm gonna come down here
below score and you need to go to type
weapon : then the dollar sign left or
right curly braces weapon dot name but
on the next line it's going to be
damaged so damage :
dollar sign yep to write curly braces
weapon dot damage inflicted now remember
that we need to enclose more complex
expressions in curly braces as I've done
here so if you try that without the
curly braces it'll actually print out
the dot name as a literal string so the
code for example on line 14 without
precarity braces you'll get a dot with
the characters in am e printed out
instead alright so now that we've done
that in our main function let's go back
to that and what we want to do is
replace the print in statements with a
call to Tim's show function so let's do
that first
so this is the one down here now you can
see on line 25 so I'm going to come at
that law and 25 out then on the next
line I'm going to do with Tim dot show
so let's run the program to make sure
that it's actually working now if you
get this situation pop up or you can see
what's happened here it's not actually
printing at the full values and it seems
to be not taking the changes that we've
made make sure that you do go back and
do a clean project and go back and make
the module again and then go back and
right click here and select run learn
Katie that should fix it general and you
can see it has done that now we're
seeing the new code output so appears to
have been cached of the previous version
of running the code was cached and by
doing it this way we're clearing it out
and making sure that we're running the
latest version then you can see the
output is showing you on the screen
we've got the revised show function
which is also working at the top if we
scroll up as well the weapon and the
damage and that I clearly wasn't working
before he made the change
but the change we're looking at here is
tim has got weapons sword and damage
showing alright so that's the first part
of the challenge the second part of the
challenge what we can do is we could
assign or we should have solid Tim's
weapon to Louise but before Tim picks up
the spear so the code for that we're
going to come down here after the Tim
show line we're going to type Louise dot
weapon is equal to Tim dot weapon you
know the next line Louise dot show so
I'll just make a bit of space there
alright so you can think of this as
Louise taking the sword from Tim so
we're assigning Tim's weapon to Louise's
weapon property on line 28 and then
obviously line 29 is showing it now it's
important to do that before assigning
the spear to Tim it won't work if we try
to do it the other way around because
there'll be no reference to the sword
once Tim gets the spear so let's just
try running this to make sure that it
works and again you can see that we've
got these funny caching issues which may
or may not come up for you we can't see
any outputs showing from Louise so we
can actually just try running it here
first that doesn't do any good we can
just try and doing a clean again we can
make the module again it's frustrating
having to do this I hope Google will fix
this soon we'll try running it again
this time we're getting the right output
you can see we're getting Louise's
outputs showing on the screen there now
and again you can see in this case that
we've got Tim showing the sword Louise
is now seeing we're seeing the sword
from Louise then we're getting the
output of the spear only and that's
because at the moment we're just
printing the weapon name on line 32 so
we could fix that as well let's do that
let's comment that out and we'll put Tim
showed we'll run that and see whether
that works for us and fortunately it
doesn't work together really happy much
fun with his Howie so I will actually
plane again make the module
try running it again that's better now
you can see we've got the output and
this time we've got the first one the
first line which was this output line
here on line 26 we're seeing tangent up
the sword then the output on line 29 is
louise output and then finally the
output on line 33 we've seen the weapon
and the temperatures will all right so
that's the challenge solved now there
are other ways you could have solved
this you may have created a new sort of
variable for example when a saw and
Tim's weapon to that first that would
also work and as long as the louise has
the sword when you run the program then,
Congratulations. Alright, so that's
the challenge completed so I'm going to
stop this video here. In the next video
we're going to let our players have more
than one instance of an object some loot
that they'll be picking up, so I'll see
you in the next video.