Alright so I've no going to class
Lieut as you can see to represent the
various items of loot that the players
may find and the player class has got an
inventory object that we've added
concealed on on line seven that can be
used to store a list of the players loot
now notice that we haven't specified how
many items we can put into the inventory
the ArrayList class manages all the
complexity for us we'll just add or
delete loot items and the list will take
care of everything else for us now in
the last video we saw that the ArrayList
class has an ADD function so we can use
that in our main function and add loot
to the list that way now there's a
couple of reasons why we shouldn't do
that but let's start by seeing that
working so I'm going to go back to the
main function and after the last line
after the Tim BOTS show I'm gonna create
a new bit of loot and give it to myself
so let's just try that so I'm going to
type Val red potion is equal to loot
parentheses red potion double quotes
comma then loot type dot potion comma
and we'll assign a value of $7 50 and
then the next time we're going to type
Tim dot inventory dot add parentheses
red potion so we created a new loot type
the red potion and then we add the
object to Tim's inventory list and I run
the program to make sure that it
actually works but of course we're not
going to see anything different because
we haven't got any output yet so what we
need to test this properly is some way
to display a plays inventory now we can
do that by adding a show inventory
function to the player class so that's
how to look at doing that back to the
player class and below the show a
function let's have another one fun
space show inventory parentheses left or
right curly braces and within there
we're going to type Linde parentheses
double quote and dollar name single
quote yes so we like Tim's
inventory then on the next slide print
'ln inventory dot get then in the
parentheses we're going to put zero then
on the next line we're gonna type print
line double quiet to despoil whole
series of equal signs just so we can
break up the screen output a little bit
now we saw that get function in the
documentation in the previous video so
it returns to the item at the index
position we specify now remember that
things are indexed starting from zero in
Kotlin and in fact that's true of most
programming languages which is why we're
using zero here on line 22 so basically
get then zero in parenthesis gives us
the first item in the list but to what
if there's more than one item in the
list that's why we're using a list after
all now there are two things I don't
need to cover at the same time here
which is impossible so I'm going to come
back to dealing with more than one item
after we've got this bit working first
though let's use our show inventory
method in main to make sure something
has been added to the list I'm going to
go back to main and below the Tim
inventory deadline I'm going to type Tim
dot show inventory we're going to call
that function so we just Rob that little
see what happens and again if we get in
that situation where for whatever reason
no output is coming out which is
happening for me you'll need to go up
and do a build clean build make module
and hopefully that you won't have to do
this but just in case it doesn't work
for you to do that then we'll run it
again and we can see that we've got
something output else
so we've got something printed out but
it doesn't look like our red potion but
we can tell that it's got something to
do with the loot it's clearly that code
that we added to the player down here
for the show inventory is actually
working it's just not giving us the
results that we were expecting so we
need to clear this up and get some
decent output before dealing with more
than one item so what's actually going
on here what are we getting that loot at
and that strange number on the end of it
well what's happening is that Kotlin
doesn't really know how we like our loot
objects to be displayed you know it's
obvious to us that we want to see the
name at the very least we may also want
the type and the value displayed but we
haven't told Kotlin that so cotton was
just using a default function then it
knows about and that it uses whenever we
want to print objects now unless we tell
it otherwise the function is going to
print the class name and that strange
hexadecimal number that you can see
after the at so-and-so at and in this
case that takes it a small number there
now that's strange numbers called a hash
code by the way but don't worry about it
at the moment you know it'll do the same
actually for our player objects as well
just to show that print illan Tim and
parentheses run that and I'm just going
to do what I've done before clear clean
build so we make and you should find
that well then work for me you can see
there the player object output the code
that I just printed out from Lauren 38
is doing the same thing with a different
number as you can see you know I said
that column uses a default function with
printing out objects that function is
called to string know that to string
method or function produces a string
representation of an object and the
default representation is the class name
followed by this unique number and in
that song now that's not a very useful
representation but we can override the
to string function to get it to produce
something a lot more interesting
so let's actually do that for our player
class we go back to our player class
we've already got this show function but
I'm just going to copy the code that
we've used in show so I'm going to take
a copy of everything all that code in
show and in between the show on the show
in the tree I'm going to type override
space fun space to string and that's
when I've done that cottons
automatically coming up with that some
code for us and the press enter there it
has actually added the rest of the
function definition for us but we're
going to change this a little bit to
delete that file and paste in our code
which again is the same code from the
show function I'm going to change the
first line where it's got to print 'land
we're going to do a return there I'm
going to type return
get rid of the parentheses they go down
to the end and get rid of the
parentheses for that as well
so we've now overwritten the two string
function you know the two string
function returns a string so I've just
got it to return the same string that
our showed method was printing then when
we run this program again back to main
and I'm just going to get into the habit
now of actually running doing this
process of cleaning and making the
module you can see now that I've done
that this time though we get a much
better representation of Tim printed out
at the end of the output so let's go
over what we've done here so in main we
used print lint on line 38 to print out
Tim so Cotton's looking at Tim's class
the player class to see if it's got a
two string function that can be used to
display the Tim object now when we ran
the program last time there wasn't a
string function in player because we
just added that so Kotlin used to
default to string function that every
objects got then that wasn't pretty
we have someone that gave us the
hexadecimal number so what we've done
here in player is added our own version
of the DES string function now the
keyword override there on line 20 that
tells Kotlin that this function is
replacing one of the default functions
that classes get automatically now it's
probably a bit of jargon classes inherit
that's a string function from their base
class now I don't worry too much about
where that default to string function
came from because we're going to be
looking at inheritance in a future video
now if we want to replace the default to
string function with our own
implementation of it we override the
function with our own version using that
override keyword as you can see then so
that's another bit of object-oriented
programming jargon when you override a
function or method to use the object
oriented programming term for it when
you override a method you write your own
version of the method that does things
differently so our two string function
returns a string that's a bit more
interesting than just the class name and
that hash code now when overriding a
method
the method signature must be the same as
the method that's being overridden the
OU method signature means the name of
the method to string here any parameters
that it declares inside the parentheses
and the type of value that it returns
now the signature for the show function
is quite simple you can see up here on
line 9 it's called show and there's no
parameters defined inside of the
parentheses so it also doesn't return a value
straight as prints bellies out it
doesn't return anything to the calling
code but our two string function doesn't
do any printing it just sends a string
back to whatever calls it we've got the
colon string here of the Declaration to
indicate that the type of value returns
then it returns is a string
so back in main when we print Tim a line 38
cotton is automatically calling for to
treat the to string function in a player
class to get the string that should be
printed now we can be explicit about
that if we want and specify two strings
so we can go back to there and put Tim
dot T string which does the same thing
but just makes it a bit more explicit so
that's not necessary because Kotlin
calls it for us if we don't specify it
and if we just run the program again you
can see we're getting the very same
output so the printing function needs a
string to print and Tim isn't a string
138 it's a player because of that
Conklin knows it has to call to string
so that it's got a string to print and
that's what it's doing here ok so now
that we've got a better two string
function for our player objects we don't
need show to do the same thing so I'm
going to change to just print out
whether the player is alive or not let's
go ahead and do that so back to player
shouldn't delete that code then within
there we're going to put if parentheses lives
it's greater than zero that's where my
curly braces we're going to be print
'land parentheses double quotes dollar
name is alive we're going to close down
the code block and then else another
code block there it's gonna be pretty in
double quotes dollar name is dead so
there's our revised to show method so
let's just clean make the module and
we're going back and try running the
code you can see the output now is a lot
tidy than what it was before so all our
players as you can see are alive and we
can get the information on the players
by just printing them out alright so now
you can produce more interesting output
for our loot objects by overriding the
just string function in the loot class
and that sounds like a good challenge, so
we'll do that in the next video.