In this video we're going to look at
extending the vampire class to create a
super vampire. Now it's going to be very
similar to what we've already done but
there's a couple of other things we need
to know how to do so we're going to
create a vampire King subclass of the
Empire now a vampire king is going to be
incredibly powerful and any points of
damage inflicted will be divided by for
event parking objects we'll also start
off with a hundred and forty hit points
and as you see that's what we need to
look a bit deeper into Kotlin
inheritance so going to start by
extending vampire to create a vampire
king class with those additional
properties first thing we need to do is
start by making the vampire class open
so let's do that so that it can be now
inherited from and then we need to
create our new vampire king class so I'm
going to do that right click Java fold a
new cotton class save a bit of top top
in my selecting class and the name of
your vampire king now we need to pass
the name to the class and provide that
to the vampire class so at the end of
the definition add parentheses name
colon string then outside the right
parenthesis colon vampire and in
parentheses name that's straightforward
but where it gets tricky is setting the
vampire kings hit points to 140 now if
we look at the vampire class it passes
the fixed value 20 to the enemy
constructor now we need to change that
to 140 somehow now one way we could do
that is to use a default value and we
can modify the vampire class to have a
hitpoints parameter with a default value
of 20 that we can then pass to the enemy
constructor so let's try that first so
we'll add the parameter hit points it
points colon int then set the default
value of 20 then we need to change the
hard-coded value here to hit points so
now that we've done that we can go back
to the vampire constructor in the
vampire king class
and we can change that to 140 so let's
see if that works before we talk some
more about it so I'm gonna go back to
our main function
and let's add or create a vampire King
instance so Val Dracula is equal to
vampire king parentheses Dracula and
let's put the value of that as well so
print 'ln Dracula so let's run that and
see if it works okay so that's good we
can see that it does work Dracula as you
can see down the bottom here has got 140
hit points so that's one way to do it
and it's a perfectly acceptable solution
but you can probably tell that I'm
itching to show you another way. So
what's wrong with what we've just done
well it's compromised our vampire class
slightly because we can now create
vampire instances with less than 20 hit
points so if we go and modify the code
on line 8 that creates Vlad we can use
that second argument now and say set the
hit points to two now before I run the
program again notice in the output that
Vlad started off with 20 hit points and
they drop to 16 after we inflicted the
damage but if we run it again now what's
happened this time is because he only
started out with 2 hit points poorer
Vlad's lost her life with the damage
that's been inflicted on him now the
change we made to the vampire class now
allows the vampires to be created with a
different number of hit points and that
may be fine depending on your
application sometimes though you'll want
to provide a default but allow the users
of your class to change it sometimes
though it'll be very important that some
properties can't be altered in this way
you know it's an example consider an art
class that draws an arc through a
specified number of degrees now we may
override this to create a circle class
which will have the number of degrees
fixed at 360 now we certainly don't want
to draw circles that don't have 360
degrees because of course they wouldn't
be circles so getting back to our code
though we can define our enemy objects
to be whatever we want
there are inventions if you like but
when we're modeling real physical
objects we want our classes to really
respect those physical constraints and
that's why sometimes this approach won't
be appropriate and another important
reason is that we might be extending
someone else's class and if we don't
have the source code available then we
can't make changes to it and that would
rule out this approach so what I'm going
to do is undo these changes and
command-c is a very useful shortcut it
undoes the last change you made and a PC
that's controls it
so rather than editing my changes I'm
going to use control Z to undo them so
firstly in main I'm going to undo the
changes to bled to get rid of the extra
line there that was passing the number
of hit points and back in the vampire
class that's undo those changes as well
will remove hit points in the default
value as well and that will mean that
when we go back to the vampire king
class of course we have no kind of error
because we're using the hundred and 40
so I'm going to undo that as well so we
had a pact to how we had it before so
how can we now set the hit points for
our vampire King to hunt to 140 what we
can do instead is to use it in an init
block in vampire king to change the hit
points value so we can type in in it
then left or right curly braces and
within like the code block we can assign
hit points equal to 140 now what that
does is changes the value of hit points
whether an object gets created now in it
codes executed at the time that we
create the instance and it's done
automatically so we don't have to
remember to do anything special so if we
run this program given that we've
deleted those changes we can see that
Dracula is now still dedicating his hit
points set to 140 but we haven't
compromised the vampire class in any way
basically we've extended the vampire
class and changed the hit point for our
vampire king without having to modify
the vampire king's sleeper class all
right so all that remains now is to
override the take damage function to
divide the damage by four now if you
recall already done something similar
with a vampire
use the tape damage so let's do
something similar here we have vampire
king class over I'd take damage and what
I'm going to do is set that damage and
we'll divide it by two there remembering
that we're trying to overall change the
damage by 4 divide the total damage
taken by 4 and in fact that's exactly
the same code now that we've got into
the vampire class that's the if you
recall that vampire class well that's
already setting the damage of dividing
that damage by 2 and we're doing the
same thing here and take damage for the
vampire king class so we ready dividing
it again by 2 here and not by 4 so it is
important to understand exactly which
class is the superclass here no vampire
king extends vampire so the super method
of recording is the vampire method and
not the enemy method so what happens is
that the vampire king take damage method
calls the method in its superclass which
is vampire now the vampire class take
damage method then calls its superclass
method or function so that it calls the
enemy take damage function now Android
studio has a really useful feature to
help understand all this so back in the
vampire king class which I've got open I
could hold down the command key on a Mac
and control on a PC and click only take
damage in this call to super take damage
and I click on that you can see there's
automatically jumped to the vampire
class or rather they take damage
function in the vampire superclass and
if I do that again in this class you can
see it's now jumped to the take damage
function in the enemy class so basically
that's the superclass of vampire so you
can follow the trail back and that's
great for checking exactly what these
overridden functions are doing ok so we
only have to divide the damage by 2 in
their vampire King class again and
that's because it'll be divided again
when the vampire take damage methods
called so in other words when this code
is executed which has also got the
divider by 2 so let's see if it works by
inflicting some damage on Dracula in the
main function, so to a Dracula dot take
damage 12 you'll run that so when we
round the program you can see that
Dracula starts off with 140 hit points
we've been inflicted 12 points of damage
but that gets divided by 2 in the
vampire king take damage method then
divided by 2 again in the vampire class
so we only divide when he inflict a
total of three hit points of damage on Dracula
so Dracula ends up with 137 hit points
left 3 points of damage which is correct.
Alright so I'm going to stop the video
here and in the next one we're going to
look at using loops to repeat a section
of code we're actually going to use a
loop to repeatedly inflict damage on
Dracula so that hopefully we can slay
that prude, see you in the next video.