Alright so continuing on now we need
to add our text view to our layout.
Now the text view goes below the plain text
widget and let's go ahead and do that so
text view I'm gonna put it directly
below. Now this should have constraints
to the left and right edges of the
screen so let's go ahead and do that so
you can see that the left constraints
have been added for me automatically so
I'm going to add a constraint to the
right edge of the screen as well for it
then we're also going to constrain its
top to the bottom of the plain text
widget and then the bottom to the bottom
edge of the layout so let's go ahead and
do that and by the way auto-connect
probably won't create the right hand
bottom constraints it has in my case so
we're going to be doing that manually
and then it will probably be the case
for you as well so I'll start off with a
top constraint or constrain it to the
plain text and the bottom constraint to
the bottom of the layout like so now we
want to feel what's left on the screen
so the horizontal or vertical sizes for
this textview should both be set to
match constraint now when I go back to
our normal view of attributes instead of
the extent of view and you've seen me do
this before but we can change these here
and click on Matt's constraint and do it
that way or if it could have gone up and
actually clicked on the button the inner
lines as we've done in we could have
clicked on the inner lines up here and
to do the yo to achieve the same thing
as well you can see here that we also
want to check the margins the margins
are set correctly to 16 for top left or
right and bottom and by the way might
seem quicker to set all rather than each
one separately but don't do that at the
moment anyway there's a great way to
fall foul of the bug I've just mentioned
in the previous video because right and
start won't be explicitly set so to see
what I mean I'm going to come back over
to go back into the extended attributes
again and if we look in our margins
layout margin again there's this option
I'm talking about a setting all so we'll
do that and I'll show you what I mean so
you click on that and type in 16 DP
press Enter and you can see that right
and start weren't actually updated so
everything's still looking okay though
but if I go back to our normal
attributes
and then if I change the left margin' to
ATP you can see that the margin was
immediately set back to 16 and try it
again now it may or may not be changed
immediately like it is for me here if
you click on another control and then go
back to the text view again or the
locker you'll find that it will have
changed back to the original value 16 in
this case by doing that in other words
it gets reset back to 16 DP again so the
better way of doing it is to go back in
to the extended attributes again and
have a look and you can see still see
here that we've got the full bottom and
left and top set but right and staff
aren't set to anything and you might
find that things work slightly
differently for you and again this is
probably partially due to the fact that
we're currently running in these videos
a preview version of Android studio so
it's a bit annoying and hopefully
they'll get it fixed at some point but
at least you know saved from the
frustration of working out what's going
on and you can just set the margins in
in here so I'm going to change all of
these back now
to 16 DP and that should cure things and
there won't be any problems later on now
because of that all right go back to our
normal attributes now all right now for
our textview we know what the widget to
be centered it should start at the top
of the screen and the text should flow
down from there as necessary so we're
going to drag both the horizontal and
vertical sliders to left so first one
top for vertical and then left for
horizontal to achieve that and we've got
this bug here that will pop up from time
to time where I went allow me to change
the bias I was a little biased a zero
but we'll leave that as it is for now
anyway and one of those bugs that we
hope will get fixed soon by Google all
right now we need to check the margins
which we've done to make sure that both
sets left and right left and started
writing in we're all set to 16 DP now
you saw me set those just a minute or so
ago in this video so now that they're
correct so that's almost it at this
point the only other thing we want to do
is make the textview to be scrollable so
what we need to do
expand the property pane and we need to
go down to scroll bars and we'll set the
scroll bars to vertical and then we want
to set the scroll indicators to write an
end so scroll bars first to vertical as
you can see that's been sent now and
then scroll indicators I want to set
those to right and end like so right so
this point we can now run the app and
although it doesn't do a lot we should
find that it does display correctly
hopefully in both portrait and landscape
all right so let's try running the up
here and obviously at this point in time
the apps not going to do a lot but we
can hopefully determine that it does
look okay in both portrait and landscape
all right so there's our app in portrait
mode and if I go into landscape mode
just click on done there so you can see
what it looks like you can see that it's
looking okay in both portrait and
landscape so I'll just return that back
to portrait mode it's working well all
right so there's one final change that
we want to make and that's to the IDs
that are used for the widgets if I go
back to the button click on the button
over here back in the blueprint and we
want to have a look over in the
inspector I'm just going to go back to
our normal attributes we can see here
that the buttons been given an ID in
this case the IDS button - and it may
have a number at the end or it may not
you might just have the ID button there
Android studio generates IDs
automatically and uses the type of the
widget and a number if there's more than
one or if you've deleted one and added
another now that's not often the best
name to use for things though so
throughout the course we're going to
change these IDs that are given to the
widgets automatically you know for this
example button is an acceptable ID
because we really only have one of each
kind of widget in this layout and it
will be useful to easily tell which one
is which while we're learning now
there's no need to have the number at
the end though if there is one as IMI's
in my case so I'm going to go through
each widget and look for a number and if
there's a number that I'm going to
remove it so in this case I'm going to
just change button to - button and press
enter now you may get this prompted you
can see on the screen there now asking
if you want to update usages as well you
know clicking yes to that will make sure
that anything relating or referring to
the ID will also be updated now it's
very rare that you won't want to do that
so we want to click on yes and in fact
we'll look at one reason why you may
want to answer no later in the course so
I'm going to click on yes to that I'm
going to do the same for the two other
widgets I'm going to do the edit text
it's got to always been labeled as edit
text too so let's delete the two on the
end of that press ENTER and click on yes
I'll click yes and likewise for the
textview textview too so I'll get rid of
the number on the end let's enter now
that one has an actually actually asked
us to update so that's fine
all right so we've done that but till
you might be out wondering now what is
this ID well when we come to writing
code to get the button to do something
we're going to have to refer to the
various widgets now it's this ID that we
use so that Android knows which one
we're referring to in the code so as you
saw I change I made sure that the IDS of
the edit text and text few widgets are
set to edit text and textview
respectively and obviously button as
well so let's actually go and have a
look at the XML code for this layout now
to see the XML code come over here to
the text tab and click on that you can
see here that it appears in an XML
Android ID attribute it's over here for
button and one for inner text and is
also one for the textview as well
so looking at the button we can see the
android ID the value for the button
widget is the ampersand plus ID slash
and in button I'm looking at the code on
line 13 now you'll see the use of the @
symbol a lot when referring to resources
and it's just the syntax that Android
uses to refer to a resource that's
stored in the res folder although some
resources are part of the Android SDK
that as well Android SDK to you know
ampersand + ID just means that whatever
follows is an ID rather than any other
type of resource well actually it means
a bit more than that the @ ID would mean
that it was an ID but the + tells
Android that it doesn't already exist
and that this is the resource that
defines it
so Android studio will automatically
make sure that the ID button in this
case appears in the relevant file so
that it can be found and the same goes
for the other two widgets so that we've
got in our layout the other text and the
text view and you can see in the XML how
the ids are used in the constraints so
the button is constrained to the top of
something with the ID parent to
constraint top to top off here on line
20 I'm looking at now although that used
to be the name of the layout activity
and that's called main in this case now
the edit text widget we're going to only
have a look at that there's kind of
constraint layout constraint right
underscore to left off so you can
see off you can see their online 35 or
maybe and underscore to start off as
well and that refers to the ID button
you can see here on line 34 ampersand +
OD / button so the right edge is
constrained to the very left of the
button now there's a bit of
inconsistency here and the constraint
attribute might be layout and a score
constraint end underscore to start off
as it is in my particular case it
doesn't matter which and there's no need
to duplicate these lines as we did for
the margins now if you're wondering why
it's not necessary here there were no
constraints in earlier Android versions
so they weren't expecting any attributes
so the constraint layouts been added to
the older Android versions and works
with either left / right or start / end
now don't worry if that doesn't make
much sense I'm gonna be seeing it in you
soon and it should become much clearer
there's also no need to change the XML
directly as everything can be done from
the designer now now you may or may not
see this on your screen but I've
actually got some warnings in the XML
for the button and the textview Android
studio is complaining about layout on
school Martin right being redundant
because we've already specified the
layout and it's got margin end and we're
targeting API 17 so I can just hover
over this then hover over a particular
line there that's giving you some live
information about that so it's true
actually because using write is only
necessary for API 16 and earlier but if
that's the case why don't we get the
same warning for the duplicated settings
in the inner text so it's a little bit
inconsistent at the moment and as I said
that's the nature of bugs that's not
something we really need to worry about
at this point in the course all right
now before I finish in the XML view I'm
gonna go up to the code menu and I'm
going to choose on reformat code or
select rather free format code and
didn't get anything changed because it
says the codes are really properly
formatted but you may or may not get that.
Now their option obviously reformats code
based on the name and it uses standard
indenting and it also sorts the various
XML attributes so that for example the
ID appears first so I'm going to be
reformatting the code at the end of all
the earlier videos because it'll make it
much easier for you to compare your
with mine and we'll talk a bit more
about that later when I show you how you
can get Android studio to help you check
your code. Alright so let's finish the
video here in the next video we're going
to start writing code to add some of
functionality to our design so I'll see
you in the next video.