In the previous video we created layout
that we're going to be using for our
button counter app to show how to make a
button to do something in Android.
So open the project if you haven't already
and then we're going to have a look at
the code in the main activity class.
Now Android studio often opens up with most
of the screen blank with the project
panes shrunk away to the left now I
showed you how to get back by clicking
them on the tab over to the left here
you can also go to the View menu and
choose tool windows and select project
from the list and obviously because the
project was selected that's then
disabled it's I'm gonna go back again
and select project and bring it back on
the screen again so if you don't see it
that's how to activate it and you saw
that there was a shortcut there as well
in my case I'm a Mac its command 1 that
would be control 1 on a PC running
Windows and also the same for Linux but
it is actually worth checking anytime
you see these menu options just to have
a look at what they're relevant to
keyboard shortcut use for your operating
system because you will find that it's a
lot more efficient as you go through
learning Android app development to be
using those keyboard shortcuts but the
quickest way to open the project pane is
just to click on the tab up here at the
top left hand corner but I wanted to
show you how to do it from the menu and
also show you that the menus have that
reminder of the keyboard shortcuts
alright so now that the project pane is
open to get to our code we need to
expand the app menu which it's now
expanded but if it wasn't expanded it
would look like that click on that and
then also come down to here and click on
Java and you see that the package name
that we created using the reverse domain
in this case is Academy learn
programming dot but encounter app this
is where all our classes that contain
the code for the app pub will actually
eventually live and I'll just expand
that out so we can see the main activity
there now there's two other directories
in Java as well and these ones down here
Android tests and tests you can see them
in parentheses when I hover the mouse
over them and they're actually for our
unit testing both locally on the
computer and also on an Android device
or emulator now we're not going to be
using those two directories in this
course so you can safely ignore
just focus on the first one the one that
hasn't got anything in parentheses so
make sure you've opened the correct
folder and working that rather than
those other two and also don't be too
concerned that the directory or the
folder was called Java you actually are
in the right course if you remember
Kotlin code is compiled to bytecode that
runs in the java virtual machine so it's
pretty much the same bytecode that an
equivalent Java program would produce
now historically this fold has been
called Java now of course Google main
will change that in the future so if you
don't see main activity in a Java folder
then expand your Kotlin folder instead
but here we've got a comment class
called main activity that extends app
compat activity and you can see the code
relating to this main activity class
over here in the right-hand side if you
don't see that you can just double click
it to open it up so again here we've got
a class a Kotlin class called main
activity and you can see by this code up
here that it actually extends app compat
activity now remember that I said that
although we're using the latest version
of the Android SDK we can still create
apps that run on older versions well
it's the app compat library that makes
that possible
now when I first recorded this video
before updating this course there
weren't any devices being used that knew
what to do with a constraint layout
because Android n wasn't released then
when it was released Google sent an
updated app compat to all other
supported devices to an able code using
the new constraint layout to work on
those devices as well so all supported
devices this time means everything
coming back to Gingerbread and that goes
all the way back to API 9 so what that
means is that to us as developers we can
take advantage of the latest features or
still allowing our apps to run on older
devices and that I'm sure you would
agree seriously cool alright so in the
import section here I'm just going to
click on the plus and do that if that
you can't see the list we can see here
that app compat activity is imported
from the android support v7 dot app
library and that's the code that Google
updated back in 2016 now this particular
our class this main activity is really
simple there's just a simple function here
on create you can see them on line 8 now
when it's called by the android
framework it gets passed something
called a bundle when you can see the
reference to the bundle here again on
line 8 and that's a Java class that's
part of Android for passing data around
now don't worry about it just yet we're
going to be looking at bundles in detail
a little later and that's because our
app is going to be doing something
strange when we when we rotate it we're
going to cover this bundle thing though
with when we look at how to fix that but
notice that I said that a bundle is a
Java class at the moment most of the
android framework is actually written in
Java so we're going to be using a lot of
Java classes in this course even though
the code we write will be Kotlin when we
look at the Android source code from
time to time it's going to be Java that
we're going to be looking at but don't
worry you certainly don't have to be an
expert Java programmer you just need to
understand some very basic Java syntax
relating to method declarations and
that's because functions are called
methods in Java ok so the first line of
the function calls the super method you
can see this on line 9 and it's passed
to it the bundle passing toward the
bundle that is uncreate method received
the save instance state or saved
instance state and that means that if
our on create method here doesn't do
anything with the bundle the super
method still gets a chance to do
whatever it has to do with it again
we'll be seeing that a little bit later
and the last thing that this particular
method does is called a setcontentview
method telling it which layout we want
to use for this activity now we saw that
briefly in a previous video when we
changed the layout that the playing app
displayed now what are the things that
set content view does is inflate the
layout we're going to be talking about
layouts being inflated at various points
in the course so what does actually mean
to inflate a layout well it just really
means that Android takes our xml
definition for the layout then creates
all the widgets that we've defined in it
it then positions them on the screen
taking note of all the constraints
margins and other settings that we've
defined so where as you can probably
imagine there's some pretty complex
calculations going on while it does all
this but from our perspective as far as
we're concerned inflating a layout just
means creating a screen display from
the XML in the layout file so in our
code here we've told to use the layout
our dot layout dot activity underscore
main now that means it's going to look
in the layout folder for a file called
activity underscore main dot XML and
then use that to create the screen
display all right so we're only a few
minutes into this video and I've already
thrown a whole lot of jargon at you
Kotlin class activity support libraries
super methods it's probably on a bit
confusing so I better explain some of it
now one of the great things about
Android programming is that the
framework does a great deal of work for
us there's still more than enough for us
to do though so don't worry that you're
going to have lots of time on your hands
but loads of fiddly things that have to
be done are actually done for us by
Android so a good analogy is to think of
the android framework it's a bit like a
pancake mix so making good pancakes
takes some skill but before you can
start you have to mix up eggs flour
water and probably some other stuff that
I don't know about but it's tedious and
hard work getting it all mixed just
right and that's before you start the
important business of actually cooking
the pancakes so it's much easier to buy
a pancake mix and use that all the
weighing and mixing has been done for us
so that we can concentrate on getting
our pancakes light and fluffy and cooked
on both sides so the android framework
actually does a similar job now in the
old days programmers had to do
everything themselves so that spent
hours writing courage' doing basic
things like for example checking if a
key had been typed on the keyboard and
working out where to display lines on
the screen and where text should be
printed so it fits nicely in the boxes
so all the way that sort of stuff had to
be done before they could get around to
creating the application that did the
useful stuff and in fact if you go back
a bit further it was even worse and that
even have to write code to do things
like debouncing the keyboard their
keyboards are mechanical switches and
when a key is pressed the mechanical
contacts don't immediately connect they
sort of make him break quite a few times
until the contact is fully made and the
mechanical parts are just pressing
firmly against each other so it happens
with life switches in a house as well
and if you've ever operated a badly worn
light switch it can spark when the
connection has been made of course the
voltages are much higher that gets back
from a keyboard but it's really the same
type of thing so all that happens too
quickly for us to notice the light
flicker as it's turned on but fast to
humans excruciating ly slow to a
computer and the computer can detect all
those contacts while the mechanical
keyboard switch settles down now if the
keyboard wasn't debounce you'd press
acade you'd get eight or twelve
characters perhaps appearing on the
screen now nowadays with USB keyboards
it's all done on the keyboard itself of
course so the android framework is
running all the time doing a great deal
of work for us again all the time so as
a result we don't have to write code to
detect when a character was typed or a
button is pressed we actually leave that
to Android and we just respond when
Android tells our program that something
interesting has happened now another
example is orientation change if we have
to include code to monitor them the the
motion detectors and included in all
your apps you get a little bit bored
instead Android deals with orientation
changes and we don't have to worry too
much about them and the way that to
Android does deal with a change from
portrait to landscape is pretty cool
we're going to be looking at that a
little bit later on and that in fact is
why we need to use bundles alright so
the Android documentation is pretty good
for most things so you can check out
more information on the framework and
I'm going to just go into a browser here
and they'll be linked in the resources
section of this video and anytime I
mention the link almost certainly it
will be in the resources section on the
video and here's the Android website as
you can see they're basically Google's
site for all things Android so you can
consider anything on there on this side
us that's a definitive word on how
Android works there's a link on this
page to activities from down here you
can see learn more activities and click
on that and that gives us a bit of an
overview of what an activity is all
right so what is an activity well
firstly an application is made up of
activities which can launch other
activities to perform different tasks
now there are normally launched when the
user clicks a button or activates an
option on a menu for
so when you launch your phones dollar to
make a phone call that's an activity
when you're say viewing your contacts
list that's also an activity and when
you go on to where editor contact that
could be another activity although
Android has something called fragments
that can also be used to display user
interface but we're going to be looking
at those later in the course they'll
actually perform different actions in an
app you generally move from one activity
to another in Android it keeps track of
which activities you've used and when
you tap the back button it closes the
current activity and displays the
previous one on the screen now we're
going to be creating lots of activities
so you'll get plenty of practice at
creating and using them for various
things and if you've never programmed in
Kotlin before you might be wondering
what a Kotlin classes now we covered
this in the Kotlin tutorial in the
previous section now that will give you
an introduction to the basics of
programming in the Kotler language and
will explain what things like classes
are and how to create them at the moment
though think of them as building blocks
that you can use to perform a function
or a group of related functions when
creating your programs now classes can
be extended to add more functionality to
change their behaviors so for a non
programming example you could take a
wooden pallet and extend it to make a
packing crate now it's still got the
properties of a pallet and you can pile
cartons in it and lift with lift it with
a forklift truck but it's been extended
so now we could fill it with footballs
and lift it without all the balls
rolling off you know trying to transport
footballs and a wooden pallet wouldn't
work out too well but by extending the
pallet by adding sides we can reuse it
for more than a basic pallet allows and
extending it further by perhaps adding a
lid and we could use it for transporting
chickens without them all jumping out
all right so the same principle applies
to classes and in our simple code as you
go back to our Android studio and into
our class the simple code here the basic
activity class has been extended and
some additional code has been created in
this case one line that displays our
layout so a new class called main
activity is now an activity that
displays a particular layout.
Now it's app compat activity that's
being extended not activity as I
mentioned earlier so the principle is
exactly the same but the thing that's
been extended can support other devices.
Now all that code was generated by
Android studio when we chose the
template so what I'm going to do is end
the video here and in the next video
we're going to start by making a code do
a little bit more, so let's work on that
in the next video.