Alright so let's make our code do a
little bit more. Now currently our layout
contains three widgets so I'm going to
add some variables to store a reference
to those widgets so that we can do
things with them in the code. Now at this
point I should point out that there are
better ways to do what we're about to do
and you'll be seeing those in the next
section but it's important to understand
what's really going on when you use
those other techniques they still do
basically what we're about to do here
the difference is the Kotlin has some
extensions that make coding it all a bit
simpler so please don't take this next
bit of code that's the definitive way to do things
in Kotlin there are easy ways to do this
but I think it's important to want to
say much really going on so we're going
to do it the quote-unquote longhand way
if you liked here. Now it's also far easy
to understand what this code is doing
and that's because there's very little
magic now the methods that I will use
later and for the rest of the course do
rely on behind the scenes magic to make
the code simpler if I started with that
you wouldn't really know what was
happening under the hood so we'll go
ahead now and add three lines of code so
I'm going to start by putting this under
the line six under the class main
activity line and I'm gonna start with
private space VAR space edit text space
: then edit text with a capital e and it
text question mark equals null making
sure you get your capitalization correct
with this next line private space VAR
space button colon and capital B this
time for button again question mark
equals null then on the third line
private VAR this time it's text view
text the capital V for view colon and a
capital T for text views I'll repeat
that word question mark equals null
alright so at this point now we've got
three properties now edit text with a
lowercase e and you can see that on line
10 well that can store a reference to an
edit text widget and notice that the
capitalization of the
two words there and that's actually very
important that you do pay attention to
that to the cases of names in Kotlin and
it text with a capital e isn't the same
as edit text with a lowercase e now with
a capital e edit text is a class so it
represents the type of object that we're
going to be dealing with now if we look
at the import section up here on the top
table to scroll up so we can see all the
code you can see here that inner text
has been added and it's coming from the
Android dot widget package so edit text
effectively is a widget and similarly
button is a button widget and textview
is a textview widget now edit text with
a lowercase e is a property that can
store a reference to a widget we can
create a new widget and refer to it
using the name edit text or and this is
what we'll be doing here we can find the
edit text widget in our layout and
assign it to the inner text property so
that we can refer to the widget that's
been created when the layout was
inflated now for some reason Google
referred to an edit text widget in the
designer as plain text but it's typing
code is edit text so we can search the
layout for our plain text which you
didn't refer to it via the field in a
text and we can also do the same with a
button than the textview as well so we
come back open it open the the layout
designed you and if I click on some of
these things he said we're going to text
you there and over to the left hand side
and then the text we've got plain text
there but essentially plain text is the
analytics that we're referring to here
alright I'm back to our Kotlin class
alright so I've also done the same with
a button and the textview so we've now
got three properties that we've created
here and incidentally it's very common
in Kotlin to give the field the same
name as as type or class but with a
lower case initial letter now if we had
several edit text widgets in the lamp
then we'd have to give them more
meaningful names such as address text
perhaps or gnome text and so on but
that's there's only one top of each type
of widget I'll just use these names for
the button and the textview but just so
there's no confusion now what I'm going
to do is rename the edit text field to user input
you'll see why in a minute where we have
the word button three times on the same
line or with different meanings
let's just go to line tenderness changes
edit text and I'm going to change that
to user input user input with a capital
F for important the rest in lowercase
now another thing to note is that you
have to initialize variables in column
now we don't yet know what values to
assign to these properties because we
can't look them up in the layout until
after that setcontentview functions been
executed this is the one here on line 16
until then there's no layout which means
that widgets don't yet exist so they're
from actually initializing all three
properties to Knohl to start with in our
declarations on line 10 through 12 so
this means we have to declare them as
nullable types and that's what the
question mark after the type means
alright so how do you link these fills
up with the widgets in the layout
well the android framework provides a
method called find view by ID that you
used to check a layout to fetch a widget
with a particular ID from it now if you
remember from when we were creating this
interface we made sure that each widget
had an ID and we remove the numbers from
the inside IDs because they weren't
necessary it's actually those IDs that
we use when calling for your by ID so
I'm going to type the code in first and
then we'll go through it so you come
down here below the setcontentview line
I'm going to type in user input it's
equal to five view by ID let's then sign
then edit text with a capital e and a
capital T and a greater than sign then
in parentheses we're going to type in
our dot ID capital while that was and
then lowercase ID dot edit text press
ENTER there then on the next slide we're
going to type button equals find view by
ID and I can type the less handsewn
again this time it's going to be button
and a greater than sign then in
parentheses our ID button and the last
line text view notice I'm typing Android
geo is helpfully trying to give us some
shortcut so I could just press ENTER to
select those two say
at a time and let's then sign again text
view rather than silent in parentheses
again capital re ID dot text view okay
so you can see that those three lines
are very similar they each call the find
view by OID method to find what's called
a view now I think I mentioned in an
earlier video that all widgets are views
so a view in Android is the class that
all widgets extend so all widgets share
some common behavior such as being able
to be placed in layout and having size
etc but different widgets extend view in
different ways to provide their own
specific functionality so an edit text
is a view that you can type into and a
text view is a view designed for
displaying text for example so for view
by ID returns a view object and we have
to tell Kotlin what type we really want
before assigning the results to our
properties the view with your ID and a
text is an edit text I've have to
specify that that is the kind of object
we expected before we can assign it to
the user input field on line 18 and the
same for button and text you so
hopefully now you can see why I renamed
the edit text to a user input now it
could get very confusing otherwise now
on line 19 the first button refers to
the property and button surrounded by
the less than than the greater than sign
here well that refers to the type of
object object that we want the view to
be treated as before we can assign it to
the property and finally the last user
button over here to the right-hand side
that refers to the ID of the button that
were used in the layout now on line 18
we can see that they're different things
there we look for an inner text widget
with the ID in a text that's what the
edit with a lowercase e then assigning
their reference to its property called
user input all right so the last thing
to look at is the way the IDs themselves
have been specified now it's easy to see
how they relate to the IDS we gave to
the widgets in a previous video but what
is this r dot ID dot all about well if
you remember when we set the IDS in the
layout we used a plus to tell Android studio that
is the this is where the ids were being
created and that causes Android studio
to create a class that it calls R
capital R where it stores all the
information on resources in the app so
in other words R here is for resources
now there's a really cool feature of
Android studio that lets you jump to
where something's defined by holding
down the ctrl key or the command key on
a map when on a Mac when you click the
item so if I come over here and click on
and command click the edit text again
control click on a PC they have it here
on line 18
click on that you can see I get taken
straight to the XML for the layout where
the init text is defined now that's
really useful when we're going to be
using that a lot in this course to check
out all sorts of things so what you can
see now now that I've clicked that is
that the ID really is referring to the
widget in our layout now the R class is
created automatically by Android studio
to store all resources as I said and we
can have a quick look at that now I'm
just showing you this to explain what's
going on here and I wouldn't normally
edit the the R class and you certainly
shouldn't be going but going about
making any changes to it and in fact the
Android studio doesn't even show the R
class in the project pane when it's in
Android view what I'm going to do is
come over here and click on project view
and once I do that we get some other
options if I expand the window out again
and what I'm going to do is comment down
here because basically project view is
giving us all a list of all the files in
the project even the ones we shouldn't
be messing with or changing so under app
going to click on app then build
generated and source then AA lowercase R
there then debug these are all files and
folders are created automatically by
Android studio for us then I'm going to
go into this Academy to learn
programming button killer app expand
that out and here now we've got this R class
I'm just going to double click that now
again there's no reason for you to edit
this file and in fact you can see at the
top there is actually a warning that the
file shouldn't be edited
they also scroll through though you can
see there's quite a bit of information
in here and it really creates all sorts
of things that
probably make a lot of sense and it's
all stuff that Android needs in order to
build the app and to track all the
various components of the application
now rather than trying to find the ID
section by scrolling I'm going to search
for class ID just doing a search of
typing class space ID and there it is
there on my case on line two six nine
four but it might be a different line
number for you now looking through this
class here contains all sorts of IDs but
the identification numbers that Android
studio has given them now most of these
aren't used so they won't appear in the
final compiled version of the app but if
we scroll down and have a look here we
can see that our buttons there button is
there we've also got an edit text
showing here and we should be able to
see the text views as well with a bit of scrolling
and see there's a textview there as well.
So these are in a class called ID and
start inside another class called R so
which is why now our closest you can see
now that's why we use going back to our
class r dot ID dot then whatever the
name we want to reference so that's the
reason we're doing that we're telling
Android studio where to look to find
that particular reference and the method
wants the numeric ID essentially alright
so I haven't aggressed a lot here but we
were trying to connect the button up to
some code. So let's end the video here,
in the next one we're going to start work
on doing just that, so see you in the next video.