Alright so I digress the pit in the
previous video, we were trying to connect
the button up to some code. So now that
we've actually got references to the
widgets, let's have a go at doing that.
Now I said that the android framework
takes care of watching for user input
and notifies us when something
interesting happens you know the way it
notifies our code of events that happen
is by calling special methods that we
write called callbacks so when a button
is clicked the android framework will
call an on click method if we'd written
one and told Android that it's attached
to the button now we can't just go
creating any hold method and call it on
click and expect Kotlin to be able to
cope though Kotlin is a strongly typed
language which means that you have to
provide exactly the right kind of object
or method that something expects now the
way that's defined in Kotlin is using
interfaces and Android uses an interface
called onclicklistener
now this makes sure that only the
correct type of object is attached to
the button to respond to clicks and once
again I'm going to type the code in and
then explain what it's doing so first
thing we need to add a line on line 13
and we're going to type private VAR
space numtimesclicked and put equals a
zero on the end of that and when you're
typing on with this next bit pay careful
attention to the suggestions then
Android studio is popping up and you
might well find that Android studio
complete some more of the code for you
than it does for me and Google I'm
improving this autocomplete all the time
and at the moment the autocomplete for
Kotlin doesn't do nearly as much as it
does for Java but I fully expect that it
will as time goes by so keep an eye on
what's happening and also it's a good
idea to watch the autocomplete carefully
anyway you know just because Android
studio is suggesting something first
that doesn't mean that it it's what you
want in all situations at the moment you
probably won't know what to choose so
you really want to compare the options
you're getting to what appears on my
screen don't worry though as it all
starts to make sense you'll know which
of the options you want the first thing
when I come down here now below the last
line here on line 21 animator type button
question mark dot I'm gonna top set on
click and eventually I've got this first
option so I'm gonna press ENTER to that
one I can try that and I could do some
typing or I can also come back here
again double dot set on click select the
first option so with the parentheses
were created automatically as you can
see there and it's a type object space
colon space the the couple of you with a
capital B you dot on click click this
term I'm going to present to their next
we're going to type a left curly brace
the press ENTER and then I'm going to
type on the next line now override press
ENTER there because that's the way we
want fun if you end space on click and
you can see you've got this option that
has appeared on the screen there now if
I press ENTER there you can see that's
actually generated some code for us and
it's just saved a bit of typing there
but you're probably wondering now what
does all this mean well firstly I
started by uh this is our code on line
14 adding a variable called num times
clicked and that's there to keep track
of how many times we click the button
now I've initialized that to zero
because to start with the button
obviously hasn't been clicked now in the
oncreate method starting on line 24 we
call the set on click listener function
of our button now as the name suggests
this function is used to tell Android
what to do when the button is clicked
and I then created a new object of type
on listener as the argument to set on
click listener in fact its view dot on
click listener because the interface is
defined in the view class now because
our widgets extend view they'll all know
about this interface now we can tap
things other than buttons as you will
have seen using your Android phone if
you've got one in the past I then added
the unclick method to our on click
listener and it's this method that's
called when the button is clicked now
Android studio doesn't know what we want
to do to one click and that's why it's
out of this to do not implement it and
we have to replace that with our own code.
So let's go ahead and do that so it's going
to delete that line now just to do now
this is quite a simple method it's just
going to increase the number times
clicked variable by one and then add a
message to the textview widget now
remember that we've now got a reference
to the widget in the textview field so
we can call it's a pin method to add
another line of text to it so I'm going
to go ahead and write the code for that
so we're going to start by topping
numtimesclicked select that one then
type space plus equals one enter then
we're going to type textview question
mark dot append and in parentheses
double quotes /n I'm going to type the
button got tapped in space then the
dollar sign number times clicked space
time so again we've got a reference to
the text field and that's why we're able
to call the pin method there on line 27
and the /n that you can see here sorry
the backslash n I said for /n the
backslash n at the start of a message
causes a new line to be started before
the message is displayed that way each
new message starts on a new line and
without that the message would just
display one after the other
wrapping when they reach the end of the
the right edge of the textview then
you can use the special character
backslash n in strings whenever you want
to insert a line break although it's
more usual to put it at the end of a
message rather than at the beginning so
looking again if code on line 24 that
codes using that button set
onclicklistener method to tell the
button then we want to use our own click
listener when it's clicked when the
button is clicked it causes the unclick
method that we've created now it may
look complicated but this is the
standard pattern for attaching code to
an event so that your method is used
when the event happens now our code
doesn't have to worry about checking the
button the onclick method will be called
for us when the button is clicked and
that's known as event-driven programming
and it's used by most GUI frameworks
including Microsoft Windows
gnome or KDE or Linux and the Mac OS X
GUI aqua now in fact you wouldn't
normally write this code in this way
this is like another longhand version of
the code that we'd normally use once
again though I've done it this way just
so you can get to see what's really
happening in the next section we'll see
the more usual way of writing this code
and we're going to look at an
alternative way of setting a none click
listener and why you'd want to use that
alternative the important thing though
is that however the codes written what
we've got here is what really happens
when we call sound click listener we're
given an object as guaranteed to have an
on click function that Android can call
and remember from the Kotlin tutorial
section that this means the object must
be of a type that has the only click
function all must implement an interface
that defines the function all right so
with passing an object of type viewed or
unclick listener to the center and click
listener function so we have to define
its own click function and we do that by
overriding the function with the same
name that's defined but not implemented
in the interface so does it work>
Well let's end the video here and in the next
video we'll compare a bit of a test run
and see what happens so I'll see you in
the next video.