so and at the last video by asking the
question does it work
so let's actually try running this
program to make sure that it does work
so we're going to run it on the emulator
now I'm going to go over here and click
on this little green arrow on the
toolbar to run the app then I'm going to
choose the emulator now I've probably
got a lot more emulators than you've
actually got in your system and you can
actually see that some of these are
missing a system image the one that I've
got connected and currently using is
this nexus 4 api 26 which of course is
android 8 so you want to select your
android 8 device your emulator and I'm
doing that now we're going to click on
OK
and I've already got it started so I'm
going to come over here and we'll have a
look at what the app looks like on that
device you can see down the bottom of
the screen there that Gradle build is
running and we've got a progress bar
that hasn't updated but it is actually
processing away for the first time and
generating the build the Android
application and then sending it to the
emulator so that we can actually see
what it looks like and keep in mind that
if you've got a slower computer and he's
short of memory it's definitely worth
starting the emulator before you start
coding so it's up on running and ready
for when you want to test your app and
you can see that in my case I had the
emulator already running
okay so you can see the app is now are
on screen and there's a couple of things
I should explain about it in case you
think that you messed up creating the
layout in the challenge firstly there
let's test it and when I click the
button the message is added or should be
added to the textview down here so I got
the in name there if I just put in my
name
and click on button you can see the
button got tapped one time and if we
kick it again the button got tapped to
time and then one more time you can see
that the text this time is the button
got tapped three time so the actual
concept is working well the text is
being added to the textview successfully
what we should have done is cleared the
original text first so we're going to do
that when we go back to the code I'm
going to click just a few more times to
see what happens once we get to the
stage of filling things up and I'm
tapping and you can see now rather you
can't see what's happening and that's
because the text is now over
disappearing behind the on-screen
keyboard now that's the first thing you
might think you've got wrong but it's
okay and that's actually normal behavior
on Android now the plain text widget
that we used when working in the
designer is an edit text and what an
inner text is is basically a textview
that's been extended to allow editing
now obviously on an Android device you'd
normally need the keyboard when typing
so the edit text widget has been
designed to cope when the keyboards on
the screen now because you can't type
into a text view it doesn't help that
behavior so there's nothing wrong with
the layout as such it's working as it
should now if you did want to text you
to shrink to accommodate the keyboard
you could do that in your code although
it may well be easier to use and enter
text then disable it so that text Kirby
typed that way you get the benefit of
the added functionality and edit text
has the dealing with the keyboard while
still having something behaved that
behaves more like a text view now we'll
be doing that in a later section just so
you can see how it's done but the second
thing I want to show you is if I now
dismiss the keyboard by clicking on this
down arrow and I'll tap a few more times
or rather because I'm you're running an
emulator I'm beating my mouse
what till we get to the bottom of the
screen and my emulator and I'm still top
still tapping now but you notice that
the text view doesn't scroll so once
again you haven't done anything wrong in
your layout the multi-line edit text
widget Scrolls when you set the
scrollbar but to make a text view scroll
there's an extra step we need to do in
the code now the final thing that needs
to be fixed is that the message itself
isn't very good the button got tapped to
time got tapped to three time etc well
that isn't very good English so overall
though the program seems to be working
fine so far and we've successfully
linked code to a button so that it
responds to clicks and that it actually
does something
but let's fix those three issues though
that we've talked about and we'll do
that by going back to the code now
firstly clearing the existing text from
the textview when the program starts is
really easy but before you switch to the
layout to delete the text property I'm
going to show you another way so
clearing it in the layout is a perfectly
good way to do it by the way but
essentially when you're starting out it
can be very useful to leave text in the
text few widgets as otherwise it can be
really hard to tell that they're there
without looking at the blueprint or
selecting them I'm going to show you a
way around that later but another way to
clear it is to set its text property in
code and provide an empty string so what
I'm going to do is add a few lines of
code now we're going to just scroll up
here to the original definitions of the
well actually we've got the original
declarations up here but then when we've
added our find view by ID calls for each
below that textview we were going to
initialize it so we're going to put text
view question mark dot text is equal to
+ two double quotes now unlike append
which adds text so to any already
they're setting the text property
replaces all the texts in the textview
with the new text by providing a blank
string which we've done here on line 23
that's three sets of speech marks with
nothing between them two double quotes
in other words we replace any existing
text with nothing and that effectively
clears what's already there on screen
all right the next thing to do is to add
an S after the word time if the buttons
been clicked
more than once so that the English is
correct and what we can do is add the
code for that I'm going to start by
adding some code to line 29 so what I'm
going to do is put an if clause in there
is I can if parentheses numtimesclicked
if that is not equal to the exclamation
mark equal one and curly braces then
we're going to put textview question
mark dot append parentheses in double
quotes yes
so rather than checking for a number of
clicks being greater than one I've
checked it for not equal to one that way
if we ever change it to record to zero
before the button is clicked it would
still read correctly that's because in
English you'd say zero times and not
zero time now that's not true in all
languages though in fact Android has
full support for dealing with
translations into other languages
including the different way of phrasing
things when there are zero one or more
than one of them so it's a good idea to
design programs with international users
in mind now I'm not going to do that
right there though because we've already
got enough to think about at the moment
but we will be coming back to this
because it's one of the reasons for some
of the warnings we didn't resolve in the
layout designer all right so at this
point that's two of our problems sorted
there's just a scrolling to handle now
now I mentioned that the textview
doesn't automatically enable scrolling
just because we turned on the scroll bar
but the inner text widget does in fact
the inner text just does what we're
about to do automatically when scroll
bars are enabled and that's one of the
ways that it extends the textview so
what we're going to do though is we're
going to add some code back up here onto
line that 24 and this is just going to
make the textview scroll so we're going
to type textview Westermarck dot and
select movement there finis you can see
they're equals and then we're going to
top scroll or scroll English the same
movement method and parentheses on the
end and they were starting a new
scrolling movement method to the text
views movement method property is all
that's needed to make the textview
scroll now this only works because we
added a vertical scrollbar in the layer
out so that step was still needed all
rights at this point now it's time to
test the program again just to make sure
that we've hopefully I'd out all these
problems now the emulator was running
before but this time now that we've got
a deployed version of the program the
instant run should automatically update
the app for us on the virtual device and
restart the app for us fairly quickly so
I'm going to run that and then tab over
to our web you later
we should find it's a lot faster to
start this time all right so there's our
app again now firstly notice that we're
starting with a clear area now so
clearly the the dot text setting that to
an empty string worked and we click the
button a few times the button got tapped
one time and we don't notice we've now
got the correct s being added on the end
two times and tapped a few more times
and fr you dismiss the keyboard and
let's see what happens if we get down to
the bottom will that actually scroll for
us and you can see that still not
scrolling at this point for us however
we can scroll it as you can see here and
see the rest of the text by scrolling it
up and down disappears if we haven't
selected it in other words if you didn't
have a finger and moving it up and down
if you're using a real device on my case
I'm using the mouse we can see that it
does now scroll for us keep in mind
though that emulators are just that
emulators they're not real devices and
it's rare to control a really Android
device with a mouse it is possible that
of course most people won't do that
so the mouse here is behaving like a
finger on the phone's screen and again
I'm mentioning that because the scroll
indicators you can see clearly doesn't
appear until I click and hold down the
mouse button on the text you when I did
that we were able to then scroll up or
down depending on where we are on the
screen and the other thing on a point
out here is that what we can see on the
right hand side that's a scroll
indicator not a scroll bar on your
operating system Windows Mac or Linux he
scrolled by dragging the scroll bars but
on Android you scroll by dragging the
screen so keeping the mouse button down
and moving up and down as I'm doing now
the contents of the text view are
scrolling so that's how you'll do it all
right so I think overall that's looking
at
better there's still a slight problem
though and if we go back up to the top
you may have noticed it we still have
this blank line up here I was putting a
blank line before the first message and
actually think that would make for a
good challenge alright so the challenge
is to change the code so that a blank
line isn't printed before the messages
but is printed after them so that's your
our challenge I'm going to pause the
video now see how you go about making
that change and come back and you can
actually see our solution see you when
you get back alright so there's always
more than one way to code things even a
simple change like this one so the real
test with all the challenges in the
course is does it work so if your
messages print out fine with each one on
a new line and no blank line at the
start then you've completed the
challenge so my solution want to have a
look at that what I'm going to do is
actually change the output I'm going to
get rid of the /n at the start of the
string what I'm going to do is make a
change to add it at the end I'm going to
come down here to our give test we're
going to add a backslash in there then
what I'm going to do is change the code
for an else else textview question mark
dot append double quotes and in
parentheses backslash N and obviously I
remove the backslash n at the start as
well so we're consequently making sure
there's the backslash n will appear on
any text that at the end of the line of
any text that is showing or as being
output it onto the screen all right so
let's go ahead and run the program now
it's and check that till the challenge
does actually work all right so we're
going to just press the button
it's a button a few more times you can
see it seems to be working a lot better
now we still got a bit of a gap there
but that's just a normal gap spacing now
between controls as opposed to the
problem before we had a much larger gap
and that was caused by the initial
backslash n that was at the start of the
line before we actually started
outputting
so that's the challenge sorted out there
is still a problem though and I'm going
to show you how to fix that in a later
video so what I'll do first is just make
sure that we can still scroll these
you're still scroll out so that's still
working as well all right but again I
mentioned that there's still a problem
though and I'm this problem about to
show you I'm going to show how to fix in
a later video now remember that I said
you should always test your code in both
portrait and landscape now when I go
ahead and rotate this so I'll rotate the
emulator until landscape you can see
over here I'm going to do that you'll
see soon as I did that all the messages
disappeared and just to confirm that if
I had a few more now in the landscape
mode and I can still scroll as you can
see there before then just move this
over so we can see it a bit better and
if I rotate back to portrait see we've
got the same problem the messages are
disappearing again I'm going to show you
how to deal with that in the next video
for now though I'm going to tell you
that the reason it happens is that
Android destroys your activity when the
device orientation changes then creates
it again in the new orientation now that
might take a moment to sink in because
it sounds like a very strange way to do
things
destroying the activity just because the
user rotates a phone seems a bit drastic
but in fact it's a very elegant solution
to a problem that's more complex than it
may appear to be now it's true that
that's that is what Android does and you
know it works because you've rotated
your phone loads of times and your apps
have carried on with the new screen size
with no problems now in the next video
we're going to start extending the app
so it does something a bit more useful
and then we have a look at how to cope
with changes as an orientation when your
app is running so I'll see you in the
next video