so just before we continue on with
working on our butt encounter app I want
to have a look at a potential warning
warning that we're actually getting when
we open the application when we open the
project now we get this error over here
out at outdated Kotlin runtime and
that's because we updated the plugin but
we haven't updated the Kotlin runtime
and so there's a bit of a conflict
between the two and at the moment I want
to try and click on update runtime we
get an error here basically warning
saying that we need to do it manually
and when the future this who may well be
updated automatically for us but as of
the time of shooting these videos we
need to do it manually so you can
continue on if you see that time warning
we don't have to change it but it's a
good idea to do it so to fix it what we
want to do is we need to open our Gradle
file and come down here now there's two
Gradle files in the project there's this
build up Gradle and we will be changing
that you'll see this in the course as
we're adding new versions of libraries
and so forth that's not the one that we
need to change him we need to change the
second one build da cradle down here
double click on that and you can see
here it's currently got to the cutland
version of one point one point 3-2 and
you can see heat see down here that this
is the one that it relates to so what
I'm going to do is come over here and
take a copy of this one point one point
four and I'm going to replace that so I
basically pasted over the top of the old
version so I'm going to click on sync
now so what should happen is that the
new version should be downloaded and our
Android studio project updated and then
we should be able to continue on without
getting any warnings so if you see
something like that do the same thing as
I've done there and update manually but
at some point in time it'll probably
become an automatic process all right so
you can see it down the bottom there are
working away so okay you can see now
that it seems to have finished we've got
the build the Gradle build finished and
if I close down the project again it was
a good way of testing here and then open
it again and have a look at this now
we're actually running one point one
point four but now it's actually saying
that it the
versus one point one point four -
release - Studio 3.0 - - don't think we
actually are running the same version
but it's got to do with the fact that
Android studio is still beta as at the
time that I'm recording these videos
because if we actually take a copy of
this I suspect it probably won't work
it's not try and update this now to that
exact string I would say probably we'll
get an error and you can see we've got
an error there that it essentially can't
find the file when that relates to the
version being wrong so I'm going to put
a dot on the end there just in case that
was significant try that again again I
suspect we'll get an error here same
error so we go back now to the previous
version that I added in this video one
point one point four and try again we
can see that that's been accepted but
we'll still get that warning each time
we actually load up so I'll just close
the project down and open it up again
we're still getting a warning here but
you can see clearly now that we're
actually running one point one point for
the new version and the plug-in version
is one point one point four - release -
to do three point zero - - so in this
case I could we can click on ignore
because we know that we're running the
right version and then if a future
version comes up we can then update that
all right so I'm going to close down
these two files now the to build Gradle
files were opened and I'll end the video
here and keep this separate and in the
next video we'll actually move on then
and continue working on our app and
we're going to start by discussing the
activity lifecycle so I will see you in
the next video