I mentioned towards the end of the last
video that the Android jenea can also
compare entire directory trees as well
as comparing individual files
now if the directories don't have the
same structure though you will struggle
to getting any year meaningful
comparison from it and that's why I
suggested or have suggested that you use
the same company - main as me when
you're creating the projects for this
course you know to see why they should
match when I click on the activity that
main dive XML in the project pane we can
see the path to the file with the
project at the top up here here you can
see that it's a p-- slash sauce / main /
res / layout so if we want to compare
resources in two different projects we
can actually just compare the res folder
and everything will work fine now I've
made a copy of this project earlier so
I'm going to click on the res folder
here and then I'm going to use to
compare with from the View menu so this
time we get something different
it's a directory picker rather than the
file picker so I can navigate to the res
folder from the other project so we'll
go ahead and do that and I've got this
on my desktop and the calculator app
source main and res they know that I've
selected that two directories and click
on open so you can see that the Android
studio dev tool displays the directory
structure at the top of the screen for
both on the left hand side and on the
right hand side and the two same panes
comparing the currently selected file in
the bottom pane now you may just get a
message that or a screen that I've got
saying nothing to show because the diff
tools only showing differences so if
that happens both directories are the
same as mine is here because I've taken
a copy of the project that's it existed
at the end of the last video now you can
show all the files if you want to by
clicking on the equals button up here
you can see that that's popped up that
will show files that are the same as
well as ones that are different now it
doesn't bother displaying empty
directory
so there's not really much else to see
here but if the projects contained other
resources you'd be available that'd be
available for comparing as well and once
again it can be a good idea to use the
COG menu in the lower pane down here to
turn off code inspections in the
highlighting level menu choosing syntax
instead just makes it a bit easy in
terms of all the red all right so I'm
going to close this to get back to
Android studio and then I'm gonna try
and do the same thing but this time for
the Java folder up here Java directory
now when I click on view you can see
there's now no compared to option now
it's tempting to try comparing the app
directory instead so going up one level
here and indeed to pick up to view
compared with has got an option to do
that but I definitely advise against it
the reason is that there are a lot of
files in the build directories over 2000
actually and we're not interested in
comparing any of them so you'll just end
up with a very confusing display instead
I suggest you actually compare it at
package level so in this case the
Academy don't learn programming
calculator now that's a bit boring but I
will do it anyway so I'll click on that
and click on View compared with then go
to the same level project in the copy
that I've expanded on my computer so I
calculate then it'll be app source main
Java and I'm going to do Academy so
basically at that level and if you're
wondering which were which part that I'm
actually testing you can always see that
from with a path that you're actually in
so I'm going to go to learn programming
and to calculator you click on open and
then I can click on equals if I want to
see all the files whether there's the
same or different and in this particular
case it's a bit boring because you've
only got the one file but that would be
a good way of doing it but instead what
I'll do is I'll close this down and I'm
going to go into project view up here
select project and actually going to do
a comparison from the app source main
instead so I'm going to open an app
source and then main I'm going to select
that view compare with then I'm going to
go to my other
version and select main as well so we're
basically in this at the same level you
can't open and you can see we're in apps
or main app source main and I can see
the very as far as if I wanted to now
whenever directories match here the diff
tool will show their files side-by-side
and you can click the file you are
interested in to see it compared to the
corresponding file from the other
project so I can actually just come over
here and select a file and you can see
that the other phone was actually come
up their activity underscore main
scrolling down a bit further
I see launcher you can see as I'm doing
that the other side is automatically
being opened and we can compare the
contents on both sides now this works
fine if the company domain was the same
for both projects but often that might
that may not be the case though and this
can actually cause problems the
resources will still match that's
because they both live in there for
slash main slash res directory off
source but the package name is used for
the directory structure and the package
name comes from the company domain that
we used when we created the project so
in this particular example our main
activity code file is in the directory
main Java dot Academy don't learn
programming dot calculator and you can
see that when the new directory has been
created for each pile and the package
name and we can see that a new package
name has been created for each so if you
come back here and actually have a look
main Java you can see up here we've got
source main Java Academy learn
programming calculator now if I have a
project called org dot example dot
calculator then obviously the
directories won't match and therefore I
won't be able to compare the Java source
files so the solution to that in that
case there is to choose the package
directory when starting the comparison
so to see what I mean I'm going to
compare the source code from this
project with the source from the YouTube
app from the previous version of this
course so I'm gonna George studio and
they're going to go back into Android
view then we're going to explain expand
main Java so I've got you can see there
that I've got the Java package open
basically so that I can see the package
name in this case
learn programming calculator then I'm
going to use ctrl D to get the directory
chooser dialog and navigate to the
YouTube directory I want to say
basically said I need to actually click
on that so that that's the folder that
I'm actually comparing then I'm going to
do my ctrl D or command D on a Mac
that's kind of open up the dialog the
directory picker and I'm going to
navigate to the YouTube directory or the
other project so we're going to go back
to that for the other application the
other project and we go into app source
main Java comm noticing the package is
different here timber Cherica eg player
so that's the equivalent level I'm going
to click on open now this is not a
really a very sensible thing to do
because they're completely different
projects but it does show how you can
match the source code files from one
project with those from another so
that's how to compare your source files
against the source code from the videos
all of which is available from the
resources for each video it is pretty
straightforward particularly once you've
done it a few times and it's really only
slightly more complicated if you're
using a different company domain name -
the one that I've used when creating my
version of the project and if you get
problems with your layouts or code and
can't work out what the differences are
this diff tool can actually save a lot
of time and frustration now the last
thing I mentioned is that the ctrl D or
command D shortcut only works if you've
clicked on something in the project pane
and if you're editing a file ctrl D will
duplicate the current line of code so
what's out for that alright so let's
finish the video here in the next video
we're going to create the code to make
our calculator work so we'll see you in
the next video