all right so as I mentioned the
calculators working pretty well and I
think it was a nice touch that there's
no need for a Clear button to start a
new calculation when you want to stand
in your calculation you just press
equals to finish the current way and
then top the new number and press equals
again the new new number is transferred
up to the result ready to add to it or
multiply or what if you want to do next
but as I mentioned it's not necessarily
very intuitive so to see what I mean
it's going to bring back the emulator
and if we actually type something like 6
equals just start afresh so next time I
type divided 2 I click on divided 2 then
I deduct I take 3 and then equals we get
the answer 0.0 but if I want to multiply
9 by 5 now enter 9 times because it
tries to multiply 0 by 9 it doesn't work
so what I actually have to do is type
equals 9 equals then the multiply 5 and
now when I press equals I'll get the
answer
45 basically when I press the next
operator button but again that's not
very intuitive and could actually
confuse people do they get used to it
but I'll come back to that later but
also notice that when you click on the
result header text the soft keyboard
doesn't appear because if you recall we
made it not focusable but if you want to
you can use the soft keyboard in the
data entry edit text so in here we can
do that you can see the keyboards popped
up for us there automatically now we
could disable that as well but if the
user really wants to then there's no
good reason to stop them and they can't
always dismiss the keyboard if they
don't want to if they don't want anymore
so I can come down here and get rid of
it if they want now remember that they
might also be using an external keyboard
so don't restrict what your users can do
unless there's a really good reason for
restricting them now there is one bit of
validation that we need to perform
though despite having used a numeric and
a text widget now we can't enter more
than one decimal point in the input
widget we've tried that previously but
we can enter nothing but a decimal point
and unfortunately that will cause the
program to crash at that moment when it
tries to convert a full stop to a valid
number so to demonstrate that if I type
the button or press the button and top
equals we can see what calculator has
stopped and if you go back to Android
studio now and look in the logcat and
just scroll up I'll have a look there we
can see that we've got a number format
exception for input string and then the
just the dot or the period then you say
that the error there is actually
happening online 86 and the code for
line 86 is this operand 2 equals value
got to double and just to confirm that
if I just close down the logcat
and run this again and now that the
emulator is running again if we enter a
dot equals just the very first input
we'll get the same error so dot equals
same error but then looking at logcat
this time it's actually on line 84 alone
84 is for operand 1 now what we could do
I just close that logcat so we could put
in a test for valley being just a dot
but if the program was changed to allow
the input number to be negative for
example it would then have to check for
dot and minus dot both of which would
cause an exception so the way we're
going to prevent the program crashing
here is to catch the number form an
exception that's being raised but before
we can do that though we have to decide
what action to take
when invalid input is used now we could
interpret invalid input as 0 which sort
of makes sense but may not be what the
user expects but what we'll do here I
think has changed the program's slightly
so that it performs the conversion from
string to double before according the
perform operation method then if the
conversion raises an exception will
clear the input window so first what we
want to do is change the perform
operation method which I can see on the
screen there now now its first parameter
will be a double which is which is
assigned directly to up around 1 or up
around 2 without conversion so I'm going
to go ahead and change value to a double
and then we can to change it so it said
assigned directly to operand operand one
or offer n2 without conversion because
it's now of top EE so we're going to
change this now so operator 1 equals
value if operand 1 was no otherwise
operand 2 is going to be equal just to
value instead of value double because of
course the definition the type has been
changed from string to double up here
alright so the conversion from string to
double was then performed in the on
click method and the input field cleared
if an exceptions raised now if there is
an exception raised when attempting to
convert the string into a double the
perform operation method won't actually
be called at all so let's go back up to
that code so back up here in the
opposite of the code and what we want to
do here is introduce a try-catch block
so after the first line here on line 65
the value opie we're defining that we're
going to introduce a try block and
within the try block we're going to
firstly copy that line the definition of
value paste that in there and then what
we're going to do is also copy that line
and paste that in there as well then we
can get rid of this set if test outside
of here we no longer need that anymore
and in fact what we'll do is to try or
finish it off to try with a catch the
catch it's going to be an e : there's
going to be a number format exception
and the code block in there will be new
number dot set text parentheses and then
two double quotes to set it to an empty
value the other thing we need to do
though we've got this vine here Val
value equals number dot txt to string we
need to do one other thing there we need
to do a dot to double because of course
we're converting the string to the
double here because we've changed the
type and perform operation and we also
removed the conversion that was
originally in here in the perform
operation function all right so now even
if there is an exception the code still
sets the pending operation
because the kodan still be executing
down here in line 72 and 73 because
otherwise the user wouldn't be able to
change the type of operation they want
to perform without entering some number
and performing the current pending
operation now if you're not sure about
that you can move these two lines here
into the try block and see what happens
if you press divide when you really want
it to multiply but with the code as it
is here
you just press multiply and carry on or
I'm going to leave that code where it is
and let's just try running it again and
see if things work so we're just doing
our dot equals we find now that it's in
fact not crashing anymore that's how we
fix that so obviously the try-catch is
working but we should still be able to
do something else like seven equals and
people a ten plus you can see that's
working and there's doing it dot equals
again and that's still working nicely
all right so now we've fixed the crash
and we're now are no longer causing the
app to crash if a decimal point is
entered by itself now the last thing I'd
like to discuss before I finish this
video are the warnings and we just go
back to Android studio that are
sometimes showing in the right-hand
margin and as I mentioned in the last
section it's always a good idea to keep
an eye on these and pay attention to
what they're saying now support for ik
Kotlin in android is very new and the
lint checks are evolving all the time
and I'm sort of guessing ahead a bit
here because I haven't got any warning
showing there's just this one suggestion
here a solvent can be lifted out of this
now you may also not have any warnings
it depends on whether Google have
included the checks in your version of
Android studio but even without the
checkered flag of warnings a careful
review of the code shows something that
we should look at up around to now if we
look through the code the only place
it's used is in the perform operation
method
so again operate an operand - we defined
that here originally on line 17 it's
only really used
in the perform operation function now
Android studio makes it easy to check
that we can select up around to where
it's declared on line 17 or just go back
up there again you can select up by
double clicking it and a pink or purple
tick will appear in all the places it's
use you can see over here to the
right-hand side and if I just click on
the first one you can see the first one
is actually in the perform operation
function and all the other ones are
below that so in other words that's the
only place other than the definition
which I can click to go back up to that
it's used in this particular class now
operand 1 has to be a property because
it's used in both our both of our
functions the operand 2 though isn't
used anywhere outside the perform
operation function now it's a good idea
to keep the scope of variables as narrow
as possible and that means not making
them available in places where they're
not needed that way they can't be
accidentally changed by code that
shouldn't be touching them in the first
place so what I'm going to do is on line
17 I'm going to delete that definition
the declaration for operand 2 you know
the first place it's used in perform
operation is to give it the value of the
beli parameter so let's just scroll down
to that code again you can see there's
the first time it's been used currently
online
87 so there's actually no need to use a
separate variable at all we can just
change all the places where it's used in
the method to use value instead value
being an argument to this function so
I'm going to go ahead and do that I'm
going to delete this line completely
leaving the if yeah we've got these
errors with operand 2 we just need to
change operand 2 to be value instead so
I'm just going to do that I'm just going
to literally change all of these by
selecting them and pasting belly okay
and you can see we've got a little green
box here which means there's no errors
as such we've fixed all those errors and
I think you'd agree that's a lot tidier
and it also makes the code easier to
read now in fact
it's got another write another way of
writing the code that we've currently
got here on line 93 the if value equals
equals zero zero now these Li Lin checks
are changing all the time but as of the
time I'm recording this the reason it
has suggest that assignment can be
lifted out of if so as you can see there
is a suggestion now assignment can be
lifted out of if I'll just like that
again go to the command if one so you
can see it on the screen there and you
can you notice I can click on this line
of code this little tick mark on the
right hand side the right hand menu does
it'll check and Tim goes directly to the
line of code now what we think and then
do is we click on the light bulb and
click on lift to summon out of if and
you can see it's actually changed the
code for us so after clicking on the
line of code we actually get this
different assignment we've got the
double quotes and a slash and then the
dash greater than sign operand 1 equals
if parentheses value equals 0 dot 0 / n
thesese and then the code block and
we've got the double na in else operand
1 where we're dividing it by value this
is a lot more idiomatic Kotlin rather
than Java now you may have another
warning or the result the result dot set
text line this line here it's possible
you'll see a warning of course that's
right at the end of the perform
operation function and it's not really a
good idea to use to string to display
numbers because it doesn't really handle
internationalization what that means is
if the numbers will always display with
a decimal point even in countries like
France for example where a comma is used
instead to separate decimals but we're
not really yet ready to talk about
internationalization at this stage so if
you do get that warning just ignore it
for now
and let's just test the app one more
time before we finish the video
well that's working but I'll see I'll
just go into landscape and just check
that still working that's working nicely
as well all right so you'll find the
source code for this app in the
resources section for this video and
before we put it up there what I'm going
to do is I will just go back to portrait
mode there back to the code and then I'm
going to go up to the code menu and
click on reef or select a reformat code
and you can see didn't do much at this
reformatted things and I suggest that
you do the same with your code then if
you need to use Android studio to
compare it to mine the diff tools that
we've talked about previously will have
an easier time of it and you should get
better results now in the next video
we're going to fix a bug in the
calculator app when it changes
orientation well when I say we I mean
you because the next video is a
challenge the bug is quite subtle so
don't worry if you don't spot it all
right so I'll see you in the next video