all right so apart from the to edit text
widgets and the position of the
operation text view the portrait layouts
tentacle to the landscape version as is
often the case though there are several
ways to achieve the same effect so let's
look at two different ways of adding
this neck button to our portrait layout
now the first slide here is showing a
similar approach as in the landscape
layout the buttons in the second column
that's 8 down to the dot are constrained
to the left of the button to their right
but it's the same otherwise the
important thing is that all the buttons
are constrained towards the key button
which in this example is button 9 now
the buttons in the first two columns
have a constraint from their right edge
to the button on their right and a
baseline constraint also to the button
on their right and the buttons in the
last two columns go the other way so
their left edge is constrained to the
buttons on their left and the baseline
constraint is also to the left so that
way all the columns are being
constrained towards the central column
now constraining the buttons like this
makes make sure that they're a fixed
distance from their neighbor and aligned
correctly within neighbors baseline now
the overall horizontal and vertical
alignment is handled by constraints in
the central column each button has a
vertical constraint from its top edge to
the bottom of the button above which
takes care of the spacing between the
rows of buttons now to keep the columns
in a straight line
each button in the central column has
its left edge lined up with their leaf
with the left edge of the button above
it now one disadvantage of this approach
is that you'd have to change 13 margins
if you wanted to allow the space in
between or if you wanted to auto rather
the spacing between the columns all the
constraints from the right edge of one
button to the left edge of its neighbor
would have to be changed and vice-versa
for the buttons to the right of Center
so let's look at a slightly different
approach to this in the next slide now
here the rows are still lined up
vertically by their baseline constraints
and the row spacing set by vertical
constraints in the central column now
the columns are lined up by constraint
the edge of a button to the edge of the
button above now I've used the left edge
but the right edge would do just as well
because all the buttons are the same
size now the column spacing is set by
the horizontal constraints in the top
row now you'd only have to change the
margins on four constraints to alter the
column spacing in this scenario and
three constraints to alter the row
spacing and as I mentioned there's
nearly always more than one way to do
things so it's worth looking at
alternatives to see if there's any
advantage to be gained from choosing one
way or the other in this video we're
going to use that second approach or
this second approach for the portrait
layout it's probably not a good idea to
do things differently in a landscape and
portrait layout unless you have to so
I'm just doing it in this example just
so you can see the different approaches
in your own app so you really want to
try to be consistent wherever possible
okay so I'm editing the portrait layout
in activity underscore main dot XML and
can obviously see up here in the tab its
layout slash activity and as its germane
and it's not the land which was our
landscape one and obviously clearly we
can see that this is a portrait layout
anyway all right so the first thing we
need to do is clear all the constraints
from the buttons there's only three
widgets that out buttons so it could
actually just make sense to use the
clear all constraints button and
recreate the constraints on the Edit
views and the textview
now if the layout was more complicated
that could be a bit of a pain so there's
another way that's not obvious but it's
a bit quicker than selecting each button
in turn and clicking it's clearly
constraints button so what you need to
do is draw a rectangle to enclose all
the buttons taking care to avoid the
other three widgets so I want to come
down here and click and I'm going to be
very careful just to include the 16
buttons so I haven't touched the
textview or either of the two edit texts
and by the way you can confirm that
looking in the component tree that both
edit texts and the text views haven't
been selected here but all the other
buttons have been selected and again
remember when you're doing that you
don't have to fully enclose a button to
select it another alternative to that
one was that I can just
click that or deselect that I can
actually click on one button and like a
right-click and click on select and
select same top that will then select
the rest of the buttons or in this case
all the widgets on screen of the same
type which is button in this case now
once all the buttons are selected if we
hover over that we can see that the
clear constraints button for each one
becomes visible as we move over it so we
just need to carefully click each one I
just need to come over here just click
each one as we go through now if you go
a bit fast you might find that the
buttons get unselected that's fine just
take seconds to select them all again
using either the methods that I've shown
you so I'm going to continue through and
clear the rest of the constraints for
the buttons in the last for now alright
so that's now their constraints cleared
do I miss that one yes I did so you can
see now on the screen that looks to me
like we've actually no successfully
deleted
all the constraints from the buttons
nothing I've done there I'm just going
to click on a blank area and because
we're in portrait what I'm going to do
is just bring back the designer as well
obviously with the landscape perversion
when we're editing that it made more
sense just to have the blueprint because
we can fit both on there I like to see
them both at once c'est possible
although I still do my work in the
blueprint but just if you did why we
have just the one another alternative is
just to go back to the blueprint and you
can then increase the size and get that
bigger obviously that's too big for my
monitor now if you want to see it in a
larger size and in this case we've got
enough screen real estate for both so
I'm going to have both of them on the
screen alright so I need another button
and I could just drag one in from the
palette and said it's all its size
properties etc but again when you're
working with a group of widgets that are
all very similar it's often easier to
just copy and paste one of them s we've
seen in previous videos so again going
to choose a divided button I'm just
going to right click that and choose
copy then I'm going to right-click on a
blank area of the blue
and she's pasted that's before you
briefly saw another button animate and
appear over the top of the divide they
want to make sure that it's selected in
the component tree we've got this button
divided too so I'm going to click on
that
so it's selected and we're going to
change a few things we're going to call
it button neck like we called it in the
landscape version the lens in landscape
layout a button neck and we also have
the text here we're going to change that
and the text will say neg it's into
there and the other thing we're going to
do if you recall we change the text
properly or sorry the text size property
to 12 SP so let's go ahead and do that
as well 12 SP this start fits in a
little bit nicer with the rest of the
buttons now the here the ID is very
important it has to be the same ID that
we've given it in the landscape layout
and we just briefly go back to the
landscape layout and egg button
we call it button neg back here button
there in the portrait version and
remember that our codes already
referring to a by ID in any event
alright so what we need next is a
baseline constraint from each button in
the two outer columns to the button on
its right or left working in towards the
central row
so let's go ahead and do that so I'm
going to start over here with the 7 I'm
gonna set a baseline constraint and set
that to 8 and 8 I'm going to set to 9 so
select 8 constraint it set that to 9 and
the other thing I haven't done you know
haven't moved the neg button so I'm
gonna move that briefly so we can see a
little bit there
now with the neg button we want to set
the constraint to the left in this case
I'm going to select that select the
baseline constraint constrain it to the
divide then the d'void button I'm going
to set a constraint to that that's going
to be constrained to the 9 I'm going to
do the same no for the rest of the
button so I'm going to do the for
baseline constraint to the 5 the 5 based
on constraint to the 6
and then the asterisks we're going to a
baseline constraint to the six and it's
going to continue right now with the one
based on constraint to the - try that
again and the - we're going to constrain
to the baseline whoops I'll just undo
that change based on constraint to the
three and the minus sign based on
constraint to the three and in the last
line now based on constraint for the
zero to the dot and select the dot based
on constraint to the equals and the plus
we're going to do a baseline constraint
to the equals and then the neg I need to
do a baseline constraint to that I'll do
that when I try to move it and then I'm
going to base local straight to the
division / button alright so that's the
first step done next on the top row only
we need a right or left constraint on
each button in the outer two columns
again working in towards the central
column they're all actually little bit
close together at the moment so standing
at seven this is the top row only we
want that we need a right or left
constraint on each atom into the button
in the outer two columns again working
in towards the central column so I'm
going to add the constraint to the eight
and eight I'm going to add a constraint
to the nine and the other sort of going
to add the constraint for the neck to
the divide and then click on the divide
constrain that to the nine and they are
pretty close together so it's a good
idea to check the inspector as you're
doing that just to make sure that they
are constrained so we've got eight and
seven both constraint as you can see
their neck is constrained as is the
divided you know known at the moment
hasn't got any constraints we're going
to know moving up working up from the
equals button up down here each button
in that central column effectively needs
its top edge constrain to the bottom of
the button above so I'm going to click
on that constrain the equals to the
three I can see at the top there where
they've added the constraint or not from
the three I'm going to constrain to the
six
again I'm looking at the margins in the
inspector to say that that is working
and from the six I'm going to constrain
that to the nine and you can see that
we've added the constraint at the top
there for that as well now but no one
will have its top edge constrained to
the bottom of the new number in a text
widget and if you recall you never see
second one so I'm gonna click on nine
and constrain that to the new number you
can see we've got a constraint on there
now
all right so finally every button in the
bottom three rows needs to have its left
edge constrained to the left edge of the
button above with a margin of zero and
you can make that easy if you like by
changing the default margins to zero
using the button on the toolbars and I'm
going to go ahead and do that and change
that to zero so again what we're doing
is for every button in the bottom of
three rows we want its left edge
constrained to the left edge of the
button above I'm going to start with
four and strain that to the seven the
one I'm going to constrain to the four
and the zero constrain that to the one
and I'm going to do the same for the
next row because if we were doing this
for the bottom of three rows now or if
everything in those three rows to there
the two and for the two we're going to
constrain that to the five the five I'm
going to constrain to the eight the
equals I'm going to constrain to the
three a 3 to the 6 and 6 to the 9 and
then the plus we're going to constrain
to the minors the - I'm going to
constrain to the multiplication one and
the multiply multiply I'm going to
constrain to the divide and I'm not sure
whether I did the bynars there did I
yes that's constrained and again when in
doubt you can click on any control and
just check that we've actually got a
margin there and that it has been
constrained
you
okay now I know that I deleted all the
baseline and edge constraints just to
recreate some of them again but it's
often safer to work with a clear slate
when you're making significant changes
to constraints like we were here
deleting just aside constraints for each
button individually would have been very
fiddly as well and a good way to make a
mistake so the layout now should match
that second slide which I'll just put on
the screen briefly and I can test that
now now we're back in Android studio by
dragging the button 9 around let's go
ahead and do that and you can see when
I'm moving button line around everything
is actually moving correctly so
basically all the other buttons are
following it if any don't follow it's
very easy to spot and fix up their
constraint because you'll know the
button that's not moving that needs to
be actually adjusted you know I didn't
actually increase all the margins when
producing the slide so it was easier to
see the constraints clearly but apart
from the spacing our layout should match
that slide if any buttons look out of
line then check the top and left or
right constraint margins that's
appropriate alright the final step now
is to center button 9 in the layout
we're going to do that by creating
constraints from its left and right
edges to the edges of the layout and
then making sure that it's a horizontal
slider is set to 50% so I'm going to
start by doing that so I've got the 9
constrain that to the left first and you
can see that it's all moved off screen
but that's fine we're gonna click on 9
again and constrain the right hand side
that brings it all back nicely and we
just want to make sure that the
horizontal slider up here in the
inspector is set to 50 which it is in
this case now button is top constraint
margin should be 8 DP at the moment is
much larger at set to 20 so let's change
that to 8 DP so it's closer to the edit
text and as you saw me do it there it's
a lot easier to do that in the inspector
rather than trying to drag it into
position all right now that we've done
that I'm gonna drag the button neg in
the component tree so that it's just
below the button divided as I did for
landscape our version of this layout and
now I'm just going to reformat the XML
code we format code the lines needed to
be changed there and importantly let's
now run the app to make sure it works in
both portrait and landscape
okay bearing in mind that last time when
we went into portrait mode we had a
crash and now it's working nice as you
can see so I should be able to press an
egg button 55 equals that's working
nicely and I should be able to go to a
landscape mode again and put an egg
twelve times and that's working nicely
now if he up happened to crash in
portrait mode when you tapped an egg
button use the option back here in
Android studio and a build to rebuild
project and that's because instant run
tries to update the app on the device
rather than installing it from scratch
and it can sometimes run into
difficulties and cause problems but
rebuilding the project will fix that and
in my testing I did find it fail to
update the portrait layout correctly on
Windows sometimes but rebuilding the
project solved that problem all right so
let's see actually the end of the
calculator app and this section for now
anyway I want to show you how to use the
change in the constraint layout and a
grid and our grid of buttons is a great
way to demonstrate that so I'm going to
be coming back to this app a little bit
later but in this section we covered
layouts and the layout designer in
greater detail as well as looking at
ways to constraint groups of widgets
together and to position the group in
the layout and then we also looked at
the guidelines that are available in the
constraint layout we created code to
respond to button clicks and use the
same listener for groups of buttons
which is generally more efficient when
the buttons performs similar tasks we
also saw how to create different lanced
layouts for both portrait and landscape
modes to handle situations where widgets
just wouldn't fit comfortably in both
orientations and I also showed you a
technique for testing a layout with your
code before creating all the layouts
that are required that way you can be
sure that you're on the right track
before investing a lot of time creating
multiple layouts all right I've got some
homework now to finish off this section
and to do that we need the calculator
runs I'm just going to run that again
and we'll hover over to it so a strange
quirk of the calculator is that you have
to use the equals button to clear
everything off in order to start a
completely new calculation
for example if I type in six divided by
two minus three three equals zero but if
now I want to multiply 9 by five I enter
nine multiplied but because that tries
to multiply zero by nine it doesn't work
so what I actually have to do is type
equals or press equals nine equals
star five and now I get the answer 45
when I press the next operator button
that's not very intuitive and it might
be better to have some sort of Clear
button to clear the result and start
again so as an exercise your homework is
to add a Clear button to the calculator
you know I'm not going to be going
through that solution to that in a video
the real test that you've got here is
does it work when you try to implement
your solution alright so moving on in
the next section we're going to start
looking at downloading xml data from the
internet and parsing it to display the
information and we're also going to look
at performing slow operations such as
downloading on a separate thread so the
app remains responsive even if it's busy
downloading so let's move on now to the
next section