in this section we're going to create an
app to process an RSS feed then display
the data on the phone or tablet screen
now in the process we're going to be
looking at the following so going to be
downloading data over the Internet
we're going to be running tasks in the
background using an async task and we're
also going to discuss why you should
actually avoid using async tasks in
cotton next we're going to be parsing
XML to extract data from a downloaded
feed and we're going to be using the
ListView widget for displaying a
scrollable list of items and we're
beginning familiar with adapters for
providing data to list views and also
other objects and we're also going to
see how to create our own custom adapter
contexts is something we're going to be
talking about what that is what they are
and why we need them and then finally
I'm gonna be creating a menu for our app
ok so RSS stands for rich site summary
or Really Simple Syndication but neither
of those are particularly descriptive
and the term RSS is probably more
informative these days so RSS is a way
to present web data in a standard format
so that users can subscribe to the RSS
feed and receive updates automatically
now data isn't pushed out from other
websites though it's the responsibility
of the feed reader program to monitor
the site and pull down updated
information as it changes so we're gonna
start off here by having a look at an
RSS feed now if you haven't seen them
before they're actually very common now
you can find RSS feeds on just about any
subject you can think of by searching
online and in fact we're going to do
just that we're going to switch over
down to a browser in fact we're going to
do that now and I've got my browser open
so I'm going to do a search for Apple
RSS feed and the first result that comes
up here is for Apple com slash RSS or
depending on your country and might also
have the country in my case it's got
slash ru but in any event I'm going to
click on that and that actually gives us
a list of all the public RSS feeds that
to Apple maintain now there's a lot of
feeds with information from the iTunes
Store so you can get lists of the top 10
or 25 songs or albums and the top apps
both paid and free as well as
information on movies and TV programs
and as you can see there's even
information that you can get on the
latest press releases news that might be
of interest to developers and even
documentation now keep in mind that the
RSS itself is not the full information
it generally contains a summary and was
intended as a way to get notifications
of changes to the content of sites that
you might be interested in without
having to keep visiting the sites in
your browser to see if something's
changed now we're going to be working
with the top 10 free apps that's this is
a link this RSS feed over here but once
you've got the app working with that
you'll actually be able to modify it to
use any of these feeds you can see or in
fact any RSS feed you want anywhere on
the Internet so the Apple that we're
going to be creating in this section of
the course is going to read the data
from the top 10 free apps feed you know
then decipher the contents so that we
can display selected bits of the
information on the screen
so let's actually have a look at the
contents to see what we're going to be
working with so I'm going to click on
the top 10 free apps link here and the
feed will load in the browser now if
you're using Google's Chrome browser as
I'm using here you can see that it shows
raw XML rather than a formatted display
what I'm also going to do those startup
Firefox I want to show you what the
equivalent thing looks like in Firefox
as well I will just go back to chrome
initially and I'll get the URL then
we'll paste it into Firefox you can see
that Firefox on the other hand is giving
us some more formatted view of the same
output so in other words it's got sort
of a built in RSS feed program that can
take the XML that we saw over here in
Google Chrome and converted it to
something that's a bit more readable and
that's because Google's Chrome browser
hasn't got a feed reader built in
although you can't download a plugin if
you want but you don't need to worry at
this stage because it's the raw XML that
ultimately we want to look at anyway
so as you can see I've got the RSS feed
rented in Firefox here it has two
display the information that starts with
the title at the top here Archie in
store top free apps and below that down
here there's a series of entries each
one starting with a title the day that
was updated as well as a summary of what
the app does so let's just go back to
google chrome now and actually have a
look at the actual RSS feed the XML data
behind all this just to see what it
looks like and as I mentioned there's a
few ways to do that if we're using
Google's Chrome browser you can already
see the XML and Microsoft's edge browser
will also display the XML but in if
you've got Firefox so you've got a
browser that doesn't directly show the
raw XML what you can generally do is
right-click somewhere on the page that I
found in Firefox a view page source and
that will actually give you the same XML
anyway so in this stage I'm going to
close down Firefox because I'm not using
that I just wanted to show you the
formatted output and we'll go back to
google chrome which has got the raw XML
without the us needing to right-click
and view source but generally speaking
if your browser doesn't have the option
to view the page source check its view
menu or use Chrome as you can see here
or Firefox where you can actually right
click and the new source you saw me
doing that one way or the other you want
to get the XML showing up on the screen
here alright so in the XML again if you
look carefully we can see here that
under the title we've got I to install
top free apps so an RSS feed is
delivered as XML and that's got standard
tags such as author and title etc and
there's a separate feed standard called
item but it's basically very similar and
the term RSS feed also includes atom
fees and in fact looking at this
particular feed here this actually uses
the atom namespace and that's this bit
of code up here you can see wwww 3 org
slash 2005 slash atom so it's using the
atom tag names rather than our system
but there's very little difference as
far as we considered though now even if
you're not familiar with XML it's still
not too hard to work out what the
information represents there's an
updated tag for our for example here
that contains the date and time of the
last update to this fee
there's also a closing updated tag
that's his part here so the information
about whether fate the feed was updated
is everything between the opening and
closing tags this is a closing tag of
highlighted and the opening tag for
updated that I've highlighted there to
the left
and scrolling down we can also see this
other links their ID title summary and a
bit further down there's things like
pricing and so forth so we look down the
page now you don't have to understand
too much about this this is just a way
to share data with the tags describing
what the data actually means so that
computers can manipulate that data and
in this case displayed on the screen now
or in the case of when I was on Firefox
at least to be able to display it on the
screen obviously in this cat in this
particular view with Google Chrome we're
just looking at the raw and formatted
XML now for our application we're only
interested in some of this data so the
application that we're going to write in
this section of the course is going to
extract the data from some of these
fields or tags and display it in the app
then we're going to be using the entry
tags and you can see there's an entry
tag here and the entry tag you can see
if you look further along or further
down contains things like a name for
each app and a summary we're also going
to display the artist and release date
and we'll actually load the image URL as
well now in this app we won't be
displaying the image but you'll be able
to see how to do that in the next step
now notice how each entry repeats so
we've got the section here in treatment
if I scroll down there's another entry
down here and scrolling down there's the
third entry so basically it is one of
those for each of the top ten apps and
you can see it better if I go up and get
back up to the top again advise you
start collapsing some of these entries
by clicking on the arrow check down a
few times
and you can see that there's 10 entries
there now one for each of the apps in
the top 10 free apps in the App port the
Apple App Store as of the time that I'm
recording this video now not all
browsers will let you do that which is
why I'm using Google Chrome here to
demonstrate this and obviously we can
open it up at any time again if you want
to see the details or just that one
entry so basically though the data that
we're interested in will be everything
that's in between these two entry tags
so once we find a starting entry tag we
can keep loading the information we want
until we find the closing entry tag that
matches the start tag so basically we
get everything from in this case this
first entry right through down to the
last closing one which is the slash
forward slash entry that's what we're
going to be dealing with in this
application we're creating this section
of the course alright so with that said
let's switch over to Android studio now
and get started with our app now we're
going to create a new project obviously
so just go ahead and do that and I'm
going to call this one top 10 downloader
I'm going to leave the company domain as
it has been set to previously learned
programming economy just as we did for
the previous apps once again remember if
include Kotler support isn't checked you
want to check that if you want the
Android studio to generate Kotlin code
and you want to make sure it's antiqued
if you want Java code so I'm gonna click
on next there and on this next screen
I'm gonna leave the minimum SDK set to
17 again we've done that in previous
apps and leave everything else I'm
ticked click on next and we're going to
use the empty activity here template as
we've done before click on next and then
finally we go and accept the suggested
names for the activity and layout and
again you want to make sure that both
checkboxes here are checked so that the
Android studio generates a layout for us
and also so the apps compatible with
previous versions of Android so I'm
going to click on finish now and that's
our project created or what's actually
in the process is being created so I'm
going to stop the video here and in the
next video we're going to start creating
the code to download the feed data and
extract the information from it so I'll
see you in the next video