in the last video we looked at how to
use the Android async task class to run
code in a background thread so that we
didn't cause our app to block while
waiting for a long-running process such
as downloading data from the Internet
now I wouldn't think that I didn't
mention about that doing background
method was the VAR arc modifier in the
parameter list now variable length
argument lists allow you to provide
several values for the parameter now all
the arguments you provide must be of the
same type so there must all be strings
in this particular case but we could
pass in several URLs and have them
downloaded one after the other if we
wanted to do so
though we're not actually going to do
that but the options there if you need
it so we're only going to use a single
string value when we get to doing
background method to do our downloading
but you can pass a multiple parameters
tool if you want to now because it's
specified as far arc and this is here
you can see a lot of 30s when I'm
talking about the p 0 parameter is
accessed as a string array inside the
function so the first item in the array
is Pio with 0 in square brackets and
that's the value we included in the
logcat which is effectively the first
parameter now if several euros were
provided when calling the execute method
we can access them as Pio square
brackets 1 PA square brackets 2 and so
on so what I mean by that is I can we
can access them something like po1 po2
so on and so forth now Pio is an awful
name for a parameter so I'm going to
rename that to URL which makes a lot
more sense now Android studio will
rename or occurrences for us when we
right-click and choose refactor rename
so I'm gonna go ahead and do that it's
not to refactor then rename and they're
going to call that URL and press Enter
and you can see conveniently it's also
changed the reference to what was p0 on
line 31 now hopefully the code generator
will use a better name in future the
more usual args would have been better
than p0 now we saw how to start the
background task which just involves
creating an instance of our download
data class and call
it's execute method with any arguments
that it needs when the async task
classes execute methods called it takes
care of setting up all the
multi-threading and then runs doing
background on a separate thread passing
it whatever arguments we gave to the
execute method now when the task
completes the async task gets the
returned value from the other thread and
then calls the on post execute method
with the return value so with that said
now let's get our background thread to
do something a little bit more useful so
we're going to make some changes to the
code now and I'm just going to close the
logcat for now to make a bit more I'll
give you a bit more screen real estate
so we're going to leave the first log
there the log get message we're going to
come up here and type in Val space RSS
feed is equal to download XML
parenthesis URL square brackets with a
zero in the middle and then on the next
line I'm going to type if parentheses
RSS feed dot is empty then open a code
block you know top log dot e tag and in
parentheses do in background :
space error downloading so let us know
there was a problem and obviously that's
closing off the country code block then
on the last line instead of returning
doing background completed as a string
we're going to return the RSS feed so we
reuse of our argh parameter the actual
values get passed into the method as an
array and the array of strings in this
particular case and because we're only
going to call this method with a single
parameter we won't actually bother
writing code to get more than one string
the one we're interested in will be the
first one in the array and that's this
URL 0 which you can see me referencing
which we've talked about previously now
of course we haven't written the
download XML method yet but that'll take
care of downloading the feed and it'll
return a string containing the XML when
it's finished now if anything goes wrong
it's going to return an empty string so
that we can check to see if the return
value is empty and login error if
is no normally would use lagdi for
writing a debug information to the log
but this will actually be an error the
log D entries shouldn't appear in the
log cat when we release the production
version of our apps the build process
removes them from the code but in this
particular case we don't really want
this message to remain so I'm using
logged on e instead of log D to lock
this message as an error rather than a
debug level of course I'm referring to
the entry on line 34 all right so all
the code we put in doing background will
run asynchronously on a background
thread and then it also includes any
methods that it calls so that means
download XML will also be running on the
background thread
now when the download XML function
returns we'll either have the XML in the
RSS feed string in which case we'll just
return it or forgot an empty string in
which case we're going to log an error
before returning now the download XML
function will take a fairly typical
approach that's pretty well common when
you're reading from a stream of data
such as data over the internet or data
stored in a file on disk so we're going
to start by opening a HTTP connection
which we use to access the stream of
data coming over the internet from a URL
know the connection provides an input
stream so we're going to be using an
input stream reader to read the data
from it now whenever you're dealing with
a stream that's coming from a slow
device such as a disk drive or an
internet connection it's actually a good
idea to use a buffered reader you know a
buffered reader as the name suggests
buffers the data coming in from the
stream so instead of repeatedly
accessing the hard drive or network a
block of data is read into a buffer in
memory and our program can read from the
buffer so that's the recommended way to
read data from an input stream so our
app will use a buffered reader now I'm
going to type the code for that inside
the download data class and then we'll
actually discuss the actual reading
now I've already horrified any Java
developers taking this course so now I'm
going to turn the tables and I'm going
to horrify any Kotlin developers in the
course now don't worry this next bit of
code
temporary we're gonna be rewriting it
into more idiomatic Kotlin shortly the
entire block of code that I'm about to
type in in the rest of this video can be
written in just a few lines as we'll see
but it is much easier to understand if
we use and see the long version first so
let's go ahead and do that so I'm gonna
start with the new function private fun
download XML and as an argument it's
gonna be a URL path colon string
question mark colon string and then
we'll use the lip to write curly braces
and we're going to start by typing Val
XML result equals string builder I'm
gonna do a try then within the try and a
type Val URL equals URL URL path val
connection colon HTTP URL connection
make sure you actually type here the
HTTP URL connection in the past students
have actually typed HTTP which is an
entirely separate thing so make sure you
choose the correct one so that's equal
to URL dot open connection the
parentheses then space s HTTP URL
connection and again not HTTP next and
the next line and Val response is equal
to connection dot response code log D
tag and double quotes after the comma
download XML : the response code was in
dollar response then the next line we're
going to type a sort of a space there
and the line after that val input stream
is equal to connection dot input stream
then val input stream reader equals
input stream reader input stream and val
reader is equal to bufferedreader
parentheses input stream reader oops
parentheses there then input stream
reader alright so starting off on line
forty-six I'm just using a string
builder because we're going to be
appending to the string a lot as we read
characters from the input stream now a
string builder is more efficient than
just concatenating strings and you'll
see how that works in a minute so the
next thing you may find strange is the
try block when dealing with data from an
external source which basically means
anything that isn't the computer's
memory there are actually a lot of
things that can go wrong the device may
not be connected to the Internet or the
connection may drop while you're
downloading data it's possible that the
Apple website might be down with which
is rare but you can't count on any
websites being available 100% of the
time and it's also possible that the URL
passed into the method isn't valid which
would prevent the connection from being
made in the first place so a try block
is a way to wrap up a section of code
and catch any exceptions that occur
while it's executing now the first
exception that would be strong in that
code is when we create a URL from the
string that was passed in to download
XML there's no guarantee that our
download XML method will be given a
valid URL in the URL path parameter and
if the method isn't valid and malformed
URL exception will be thrown you know
the way we deal with the exception is to
catch it using a catch block so so what
we're going to do is just move up here a
little bit more and after the write
curly brace which closes off the try
block we're going to need to type catch
parentheses ecole n' and malformed URL
exception and select that from the list
you'll open a code block and then type
bolt on e parentheses tag comma space
download XML so invalid URL dollar left
or right curly braces a dot message now
if you slog a gal log e again there
rather than log D because this is an
error and not just debug information and
you'll see that
entry behind being logged to lock cat
when we come to run the program because
at the moment we're calling the async
the async tasks execute method with a
very invalid URL the string URL goes
here now the next exception that we make
it that's an i/o exception
now the first place we make an exception
is on this line here line 51 when we try
to open the connection in fact an i/o
exception can be strong
whenever code performs an input or
output operation such as reading or
writing to a disk file or like here
accessing the Internet
now although we have a valid URL URL if
the code hasn't got that far it may not
be possible to open the connection if
there's a problem with our internet
connection now it's also possible that
the URL may refer to a server that
doesn't exist now for example if we
spoke to Apple incorrectly as a ppl so
we're going to add another catch block
here under the first one to catch IO
exceptions I'm going ahead and do that
so after the closing curly brace catch
parentheses ecole an IO exception and
then closing parentheses and then open
the code block I've got B because it's
an error again tag in parentheses comma
space then double quotes then it's gonna
be download XML :
io exception reading data :
then dollar then left or right curly
braces eat up message again so as you
can see you can have multiple catch
blocks and Winona's and exceptions
throwing : we'll go through them in
order until it finds the first one that
matches the exception that was thrown
now the order that you catch the
exceptions is important because in our
code here and malformed URL exception is
a subclass of I our exception then we
can check that if we hold down the
command key and click on the malformed
URL exception and on a PC running
Windows or Linux that will be the
control key so I come down there get it
to now form exception in there click and
we can jump to the source for the
exception class as you can see here and
we can say that it extend
I owe exception so malformed URL
exception the line ten extends IO
exception
so if we'd caught these exceptions the
other way round we actually never see
the message invalid URL we just get IO
exception reading data which would make
finding the cause of the problem a lot
harder all right so let's just close
that file down again at class fall down
again let's go back to where we were now
that's actually even more important if
you add another catch block to deal with
all other exceptions so let me come down
here and view that and a lot of catch on
the next line key : exception another
code block again it's gonna be logged on
e parentheses tag comma space double
quote and no one ever no one error :
Donna sign after write curly braces
edict message so if we put this last
catch block first then that would be the
only one executed because all of our
other exceptions are ultimately a
subclass of exception all right so let's
end the video here now in the next video
we'll start talking more about the HTTP
connection and how the server sends back
a response code so see you in the next
video