all right so moving on when you open a
HTTP connection these server sends back
a response code so our code is going to
get the report does get the response
code for the connection and logs it in
the log cap and that's this so code here
on line 53 now you may have seen HTTP
response codes when you try to visit a
page that doesn't exist on a website and
you see 404 not found in your browser
now 404 is the response code that a web
server returns if it can't find the page
that was requested now if you want to
check the HTTP response codes then
google HTTP response codes will just do
that quickly now you get a lot of
information HTTP response codes so you
can see here we've got one from
Wikipedia this the HTTP response codes
but there's also another one and it's
when here status code definitions that's
actually the definitive reference so I
click on that just briefly and open it
though I don't expect you to memorize it
but with that said the Wikipedia entry
which I'll just go back to you now
that's more accurate and a bit more
readable so I'd suggest that that would
be a good place for you to start and we
can see if we just scroll down here the
various areas 404 the requested resource
couldn't be found or could not be found
but maybe available in the future
subsequent requests by the client are
permissible so basically going back to
our code the code itself creates an
input street that's this line here line
56 and then uses it to create an input
stream reader on the next line now the
input stream reader is then used to
create a bufferedreader on line 58 now
this can look a bit horrible but these
io classes have been designed to work
together in this way and they're part of
the java dot io package so this is
standard java not android specific code
now we're going to be using a lot of
java classes from our Kotlin code
especially as most of android is still
written in java now reading the code
upwards the bufferedreader buffers the
inputstreamreader and it'll be the
bufferedreader that we'll use to
actually read the
XML now the input stream reader uses an
input stream object as the source of its
data and the input stream is created
from our open HTTP connection now you
wouldn't normally see the code written
like that because these classes are
designed to work together it seemed more
usual to chain the method calls together
so what I'm going to do is make a change
so that you can see the more usual way
and comment that and comment out the
current code so that you can compare it
so I'm going to come up here before the
these three down here input stream
inputstreamreader and reader and you're
going to comment those out and it's
still going to replace that with one
line which will be well reader equals
buffered reader an input stream
parentheses input stream reader then
another set of parentheses connection
dot input stream and close the two
parentheses there
so the previous three lines of code can
be replaced with a single line that does
exactly the same thing
now one other neat thing about the way
that these i/o classes are designed to
work together is that closing the
bufferedreader will automatically close
the inputstreamreader and when the input
stream reader closes it'll close its
input stream and we'll see that working
later when we add the code to close
things down now if you need to you can
find out more information about the
bufferedreader for android so i'm going
to take a copy of a link and paste it
into the browser and as usual as always
the links are in the resources section
for the video so that's the Android
documentation that have pointed you to
but the bufferedreader is a Java class
so you'll also find the Oracle
documentation on the java dot io package
useful if you want to find out more
information now there's one more
exception that we should deal with
now this one's necessary because Android
requires an app to be granted
permissions to do certain things such as
accessing the Internet now Google
changed the way that permissions worked
into Android marshmallow so to deal with
them properly isn't always just a trivia
change to the manifest now I'm going to
deal with the permissions and also cover
catching the security exception in a
later video
so we've now got a connection to the
Internet and we've set up the reader so
we can read in the download at XML all
we have to do at this point is read the
data in and append it to our string
builder until there's no more data left
to read now a buffered reader actually
reads characters not strings so we need
to set up a character array that's going
to be filled with characters from the
buffer so I'm going to add the code to
read the data inside the try block after
lyin 59 down here so I'm going to start
with a bell input buffer equals char
array 500 in parentheses then we're
going to do VAR Charles read equals 0
then we're gonna do a while parentheses
Charles read greater than equal to 0
closing parentheses and open a code
block then we knew Charles read equals
read it read input buffer and on the
next line if Charles read is greater
than 0 code block XML result dot append
string parentheses input buffer comma
space 0 comma space Charles read I'm
putting an extra space between all these
variables just for ease of reading and
readability but you don't necessarily
have to do that now I made a mistake
there while Charles read is less than
equal to 0 should of course be greater
than equal to 0 but you want to keep
testing and reading data while there's
some data there so basically I've
created the input buffer character array
you're in line 61 to store 500
characters now that numbers a bit
arbitrary and if you expected a large
download you may be able to improve
performance by increasing it the size of
the buffer used internally by the
buffered reader on Android is currently
90 bytes which is okay but if we were
reading from disk than a larger value
would be a good idea TCP packets are
typically much smaller than 8k so we
read 500 characters at a time and let
the bufferedreader deal with getting the
data off the input stream and holding it
in the buffer for us now the while loop
which was starting on line 63 they don't
keep going around until the end of the
input streams reached you know if the
buffered readers read function returns a
value less than zero then that signals
the end of the stream of data and the
loop terminates so that's why we've got
the condition on line 63 chars read
greater than equal to zero we only go to
Lupus longest of his data available once
there's no more data we in the input
stream we're going to stop otherwise
chars read will hold a count of the
number of characters read from the
stream now it is possible for this to be
zero but just because there was nothing
currently available to read that doesn't
mean more data when it come down later
so we don't stop looping if nothing was
read but there's also no point appending
nothing to XML result so the code checks
that chars read is greater than zero
during this online the 65 before
appending the characters to the result
now technically that check for chars
read greater than zero is redundant with
the Java classes were using if there's
no data available but we haven't yet
read at all the reader will block well
that means it'll wait until there is
more data available so with these
particular classes will never get zero
bytes returned however not all readers
work the same way and 0 may be returned
even though the end of the stream hasn't
been reached so I've coded this
defensively so that we don't stop
reading just because there's no data
currently available more may turn up a
few milliseconds afterwards now although
we're writing this code for a particular
purpose in this case to download an RSS
feed from Apple you may actually want to
reuse it for different purposes so
that's why I've catered for the
possibility that there's nothing yet
available to read and note also that we
don't try to copy 500 characters from
the input buffer this is the code on
line 66 and
because there's no guarantee that 500
characters were available instead we're
only copying the number of characters
read which is the value of Charles Reed
or the Charles V Charles Reed variable
so each time around the loop more
characters will be appended to the XML
result until there's nothing left to
read when the end of the input seems
been reached the loop terminates and we
close the bufferedreader yes I mentioned
earlier that will automatically close
the input stream reader and the input
stream and we can check the source for
the buffered readers close method by
holding down the command key on a Mac or
ctrl key on a PC or Linux machine so we
click buffered reader first to open that
and if we come down and have a look for
the close method now unfortunately I'm
recording this video before Google that
way of the APR 26 source available but
by the time you watch this you should be
able to jump into the source until then
I've got a couple of slides that I want
to show you of what it would look like
with the current source code so this is
the source 10-1 screen for the
bufferedreader showing it's closed
method so the comic does state that it
closes the source reader and we can't
see the call to end up closed in that
method no the reader variable I n is
actually of type reader but till we're
using an input stream reader so we can't
just click on the induct closed method
here to check the source we can go back
to our source and command click or
control-click on the input stream reader
class to see the source for that and
then search for the close method well we
could do that if we had the source code
but instead what I'm gonna do is show
you on the next slide what that would
end up being so once again looking at
that code you can see that it closes the
source input stream all right so let's
move back to Android studio
so as you can see there's no one need to
close all the i/o objects that we've
used closing the bufferedreader takes
care of everything else for us so let's
go ahead and add the code for that so if
I come down here and add read of dot
close and that's the method to close the
bufferedreader all right so the last
thing we need to get our download XML
function to do is to return the results
now if everything went well
we can just return the XML result but
this is a string builder we need to
first convert it to a string and I'm
also going to log the number of bytes
receipt from information and to help
debugging if things go wrong so below
that reader dot close method call let's
add lagdi and in parentheses tag and
then double quotes received dollar sign
and after write curly braces XML result
dot length then outside of the write
curly brace the word bytes and then we
go to return XML result dot T string
okay so you can see that we've actually
done that now now if there is any errors
caught in our catch block we should
return an empty string so we saw the
doing background function check for an
empty string after calling download XML
so what we're going to do is down here
bearing in mind that we've already
returned the results if we found some
but after the closing catch block we're
going to return an empty string two
double quotes so basically if the
comment will add there it gets to here
there's been a problem
return an empty string that just tells
us there's some error that has been
caught by our try catch blocks and we're
going to return an empty string for that
reason what we're doing now is we'll try
giving this a bit of a test run so let's
go ahead and do that
now I'm actually kind of error here and
the error is unresolved reference
download XML some first glance you might
be looking at that and wondering well
clearly I've got the names correctly
entered here why do we have this error
well the reason is that we need to have
this private function inside our private
class our download data class and I've
actually got it outside of it so I'm
going to take a copy of that entire
function I'm going to do a cut to take
it out of its current location they're
going to come up here now make sure
that's now in our companion object our
private class for download data and we
need to paste it in our private class we
need to come down here after the doing
background method and paste it down
there and once we do that we should find
the error disappears the profit function
download XML there is okay and we
haven't got any other errors showing so
we should now be able to try running
this again so I'm just going to well
actually I'll leave I'll close this down
because we're going to open logcat and
we'll try running it again and we should
find this time it'll work but we are
going to get errors the first time all
right so we've got 30 app working but if
we open logcat and take a bit of a look
though we've still got the filter set so
that's a good thing at the moment so as
I mention we're gonna get errors and we
have got errors and that's a good thing
at the moment because we're getting a
chance to test the catch blocks in
download XML so you can see we've got
the uncreate called uncreate done doing
background starting with a URL goes here
but then we've got this message here
download XML invalid URL no protocol URL
goes here error downloading and on post
execute parameter is an empty string so
the error we're getting error
downloading if we come back and have a
look at our code all the one be the one
above it is invalid euro no protocol
that relates to the malformed URL
exception that's the error message that
is being generated on line 73 and that's
a result of that the doing background
function is also reporting error
downloading for the for the fact that
because it's filed ultimately because of
that invalid URL so let's actually go
back
and provide the correct URL to the Apple
10 top feed they'll free apps I'm going
to go back to the browser I'm gonna go
back go back here I'm gonna go back
until I find the link which was several
videos ago there it is there you can go
back to the original Apple link if you
haven't got on your browser which I had
in the previous video and I'll also put
this link in the resources section I'm
taking a copy of that back to Android
studio and we're gonna go back up now to
the folio execute method call and they
send the right arguments at the moment
is here at download data dot execute
that's pasted in there correct or value
there which is that URL
it's basically that's in the oncreate
function which is the dead load data
don't execute which invokes or starts
the async task so the uncreate uncreate
method creates a new instance of the
download data class then cause it's dot
execute method and that causes android
to call that due in background method on
a separate thread and passes this
parameter that we've just pasted into
the execute function call into the doing
background function now i haven't given
the app permission to access the
internet yet so if i run it now we
should see the security exception being
thrown and it's caught because we've
finished our catch box while catching
any exception that hasn't been listed
earlier but before I run it again I'm
going to clear the logcat by clicking on
this trashcan over here on to the left
of the logcat pane just so it's easy to
find the results from this run rather
than building up a huge log and having
to scroll in general it's a good idea to
clear the logcat before testing your app
especially for going to be pasting it
into the QA discussions that way you're
only posting in entries that are
relevant to the current problem now the
current version of Android studio now
clears the logcat will apps run but that
doesn't always work so clearing it
manually isn't a bad habit to get into
so we go ahead and rerun this again now
we should finally get the security
exception and you can see here
permission denied missing internet
permissions in parentheses so that
doesn't look good but it is because we
haven't given the app permission to
access the internet yet now it's worth
seeing what
looks like and if I hadn't included this
catch-all and this is the occurred I'm
talking about here down for the catch
exception on line 76 if we hadn't have
added that we would have got a complete
stack trace and the app would have
crashed so it's worth seeing what that
looks like so I'm going to comment out
the code that catches all other
exceptions so let's go ahead and do that
so I'm just going to come at those two
lines out there and I'll leave the
bottom closing code block so make sure
the code is still valid and if you run
that again there this time the app is
crashed as you can see there and then we
look at the logcat we've never got a
stack trace the fatal exception for
async task 1 now all this stuff in the
logcat is a dump of what happened when
the program crashed the entrance the
entries in red are a stack trace and
although it probably looks very
confusing it's also extremely useful to
find out why your program crashed so
this first entry I've mentioned at the
top is fatal exception async task has
one now the hatch one is just a number
generated by the Android code if it's
set to background tasks away then
there'd be attached to and so on so
don't worry about the actual number you
see there it'll just keep counting up if
you restart the app without terminating
it first the big we want to look at is a
bit further down and the quick way to
spot what's immediately relevant is to
look for the block of code of code that
contains blue links as I scroll down and
then what I need to scroll across to see
it you can see these blue blue links
over here to the right-hand side so
these relate to line numbers in our own
code so much of the rest of these
entries are coming from the android
framework or the java runtime but the
blue links relate to our code so they're
the bits we should really be focusing on
so that block that starts here let me
scroll scroll up and have a bit of a
look permission denied missing Internet
permission and then we can see that if
we can't scroll down here and main
activity Katie law and 51 in our main
activity so that in turn was called from
line 38 as you can see here and
sometimes it's useful to track back
through the code like that to see how
you got to the code
that actually caused the error in this
case though it's a little bit simpler
there's no need to trace back because it
wasn't the way that doing background was
called that causes the error it was the
lack of internet permissions so make a
note of that exception security
exception and in the next video we'll
actually catch that exception to prevent
the program from crashing and we'll also
have a look at Android permissions a
major change was introduced in Android
six marshmallow and continues to apply
an Android seven and eight and we'll see
how to fix the cause of that error so
see you in the next video