all right so in main activity we need to
add the code to use the menu that we
created in the previous video now if you
chose the basic activity template when
creating this project then you'll
already have a stub for the two methods
we need but so we can get Android studio
to generate them for us anyway so what
I'm going to do is I'm going to go back
to our main activity and I'm going to
put the key the cursor after the
oncreate method down here and then I'm
going to do a control oh and the methods
that we want here are the uncreate
options menu and also the on options
items selected so here the search
feature in this dialog is really helpful
so if I type on options menu it finds
matches even if it this actually
represents two different words there's a
few actual entries with an options menu
in their names and the highlighting
makes it very easy to spot the ones we
want so I'm just gonna press the down
arrow until you get to the one we want
we've got on create options menu on
options menu on prepare options menu so
on create options menu is the one we
want then the other one we want is on
options item selected
that's this one here so I'm actually
going to come and click that on a Mac
and I've got that one selected and I've
also got the other one selected you do a
ctrl click and fueler Windows or Linux
clicking ok and we've got our two
functions now created or overridden for
us now uncreate options menu that
functions called when it's time to
inflate the activities menu and that
means that which means create the menu
objects from the XML file now we've got
this basics tab now so I need to change
it slightly now when we try to inflate a
view in the adapter we have to get an
inflator from the context but an
activity or app compat activity is a
context so we can just call get menu
inflator
to get an inflated directly then call it
inflate method and give it the resource
ID of the XML file containing the menus
XML so let's have a look at doing that
so this is in the oncreate options menu
and what I'm going to do here is remove
this super call so the core is going to
be menu inflator dot inflate and then
parentheses are dot menu dot just going
to be feeding score menu comma space and
it's gonna type menu it's the second
argument there we're going to return
true now as this is Kotlin we don't have
to use the getters and setters when
calling the Java code in the android
framework we can refer to the menu
inflator property directly and use its
or call rather it's inflate method we
then have to return true to tell Android
that we have inflated a menu and let's
just try this we're going to run the app
in the emulator and just confirm that we
can actually see the menu
okay then we come over here now and
click on the little were three buttons
because see our menu is actually showing
up there now so that's good we've got a
menu in our application alright so back
to the code so creating a display the
menu is really very easy now the menu
doesn't do anything yet we have to write
some code just you know specify what
happens when the various items are
selected but we're well on the way now
you've probably guessed that the place
to specify what the menu items do is
that unselected on options rather items
selected function now it's called
whenever an item selected from the
options menu now as different options
are selected we're going to be changing
the URL that's used to access the feed
so we need to store the URL in a
variable so let's have a look at doing
that okay what I'm going to do is remove
the return call we're gonna start on
this with Val feed URL colon string then
I'm gonna type on the next slide when
parentheses item dot item id write
parenthesis and open a code block but as
you can see we're actually getting an
error here so continents objecting
because we're accessing a property of a
nullable type their items passed in as a
menu item question mark type so it can
be null now once again it wouldn't
surprise me if google and an at non no
annotation to that so you may well not
be getting this error depending on when
you're watching this at the moment
though we can either use the safe call
operator when accessing item ID or we
can modify the function signature now I
previously said that modifying these
functions of signatures isn't something
you should do without a lot of thought
so now I'm suggesting we do it for a
second time how can you be sure or how
can we be sure that it's a safe thing to
do here if you go ahead and modify the
function signature so that the item
parameter is of type menu item rather
than the nullable menu item question
mark that's the one with the question
mark after it appear then we need to be
absolutely certain that item can never
be null
can we be certain well actually yes we
can this on options item selected
functions called when a user selects an
item from the menu you
they've selected the item and there must
be an item otherwise they could have
selected it in the first place but but
that said I was saying again don't go
changing these override function
signatures without a full understanding
of what's happening behind the scenes if
you're not sure then the best thing to
do is call the safe call operator
alright so I'm going to come back up and
do that I'm going to put the question
mark after the item down here in the
wind call and that actually removes the
error basically cotton is going to
ignore this wind expression if item is
null and that's perfectly acceptable so
if you're working with other framework
functions use the save call operator on
nullable types all right now I'm going
to modify the signature here though so
I'm going to undo that change but I'm
just sort of showing you there was an
alternative to this so I'm going to undo
that change and instead what we're going
to do is remove the question mark from
the menu or from the parameters that was
passed to this method we talked about
the reason why they let's spell it all
right so let's fix the error and we can
now add the branches to the win now
let's go ahead and do that so we're
going to go through each menu option and
what to do so I'm gonna start here so if
in the wind clause itself win it's gonna
be our dot ID dot we're gonna do menu
free first an error arrow token then the
next slide and put feed URL is equal to
now I'm just gonna copy this link okay
I'm going to paste it in there like so
so that's the top ten free applications
the next one's gonna be our dot ID dot I
mean you paid no token again feed your o
equals and you can get these links from
either the RSS feeds folder
alternatively what you can do is just
will have a link I have them accessible
as in a text file and the resources
segment for this video and you can do
the same thing there
it just forgot that they were there
alright so that's for the top ten paid
applications as the last one ID dot a
menu songs or a token and it's going to
be feed URL equals and for that one I'm
going to
the top songs Paris's feed link and
paste that in so that's three options
we're going to edit else arrow token and
it's going to be returned super dot on
options item selected item and then
you're going to delete this line and
outside of the win we're going to do a
return super dot on offers item selected
per item
now again with the URLs how I copied
them off-screen but you could just go to
the apples website and paste them in the
RSS feeds that we've looked at
previously or there's going to be a text
file in this video videos resource
section that you can just grab them from
there so now that we've done this when a
menu item selected feed URL will hold
the address of the corresponding RSS
feed so we can then pass that URL to a
download URL function to download the
data I'm going to write that in a moment
but first let's just finish off the on
options item selected function so in
fact what we're doing here is we're get
rid of this return and we're going to
change it to download euro
parentheses feed euro and then we're
going to return true
now this else branch is very important
and you should always include it when
creating code to react to menu choices
now at the moment it should never
execute and that's because on the three
lines above we've matched every one of
the weights are the possible entries in
our menu but it's possible to create
submenus though I'm actually going to be
doing that soon now when you go into one
of those sub menus Android triggers a
call to this method when the submenu is
opened if you don't return from the else
branch then any code after the wind will
execute which could cause problems and
here in fact it would call the download
your URL method with an empty string
which isn't very good which isn't good
at all so definitely want to check for
that to have that else branch present
all right so what's this download URL
function for well what we're going to do
is once the URL has changed is exactly
what we currently do with
on create method we're going to create a
new download data object we're going to
call its execute method with the new URL
and because duplicating code is a bad
idea I'm actually going to move those
few lines into their own method and call
that method in oncreate and also here in
the options item selected so let's have
a go at doing that now I'm going to
actually put this above the actually put
it just below the uncreate menu and it's
going to be private fun download URL
parenthesis is gonna be feed URL :
as a string alright so what we're going
to do then is actually move these three
lines here out of the oncreate method
the cut those out okay so move them out
of there and paste them into the
download URL method let's change the
text here or the message and we'll go
with download URL starting async task
and instead of oncreate done just go
with download year-old and the other
obvious change is to change the
hard-coded parameter here or execute I'm
going to delete that and that there'll
be feed URL what our two is before that
I'll undo that change because I need
that string you'll see why shortly then
I'll just go back and delete it again to
put feed URL in there and then back in
here you know uncreate still we still
want to call this function so what I'm
going to do is to a download URL
parenthesis and I'm going to paste that
in there like so so recording that
method there going to add a log DT it's
a log D tag one create them
I think it's a cool effect in the
instead of topping it again okay so you
can see what we've done there now
they've changed the to logging lines to
log the name of the new method but
otherwise you can see it's pretty much
the same code that we had with the URL
Nell parameterised now if that last bit
looked a little bit too easy to be true
well it is we should now be able to
choose one of the three feeds from the
menu so I'm going to try and test that
and see that that works no app running
all right so there's our app running so
so far so good it's working okay what's
not so good though is what happens when
I select one of the menu items so I come
up here and you just click on one of
them free apps you can see we've got a
crashed right away
and the problem is that you can't use an
async task more than once
there's no way to restart one they can't
create as many instances as you want but
each instance can only be used once and
just to confirm that if we go back to
the log cut and have a look you can see
the error message there cannot execute
tasks the task has already been executed
tasks can only be executed once only
once so fortunately though we can fix
this easily by just creating a new
download data instance each time we want
to run the task
the only real complication here is that
so we need download data to be visible
throughout our activity so that we can
cancel it if necessary in the
undestroyed method what that means is we
can initialize it when we declare it
back up here up here on line 35 now we
have to set it to null here because
variables have to be initialized to
something in Kotlin there's some times
and this is one of them you just can't
avoid using nullable types in Kotlin and
generally that's when you're using java
classes now the async task class was
written in Java world before Kotlin was
created so if you want to be able to
cancel out tasks when the activity gets
destroyed we're going to have to use a
nullable type here for that so I'm go
ahead and change that now so private val
download data : we're gonna change this
hawk all here let's just delete that
entire reference there so it should
they'll be private Val download data :
download data question mark equals no
the other thing that should also be is a
ver now and not a vowel now that we've
done that we can create a new instance
in the download URL function so we come
along here and put download data equals
download data this an XML ListView
then the next time we can change there's
a dead load data question mark don't
execute feed URL so whenever we call
functions on our download data instance
we have to use the safe call operator
and that's because it could now be null
so you can see that I've added the safe
call in the download URL on line 48 and
also it need to go down to the
undestroyed function do the same thing
after that as well safe call operator
with the question mark there so as a
general rule we should avoid using
nullable types wherever possible but
sometimes as I mentioned we just have to
use them alright so with those changes
now the code should work then let's just
check our app to see that it does so at
the moment we've got the free one
working let's try another paid app or
paid apps I should say you can see we've
got a different set of output there
songs going back to free apps so you can
see that's now working nicely I'm
choosing I've chosen different Fiza as
you saw in the app displays the data for
the free apps paid apps and songs now
that's working fine in case you wondered
when I selected songs the songs fate
doesn't have a summary tag but the
program doesn't crash so it doesn't put
any text and it just doesn't put any
text into it so that's how easy it is to
implement and implement a menu in your
apps so I'll stop the video here and in
the next one we'll add options to toggle
between in the top 10 and top 25 fades
so see you in the next video