in this video we're going to add two
options to the menu so that we can
choose between the top 10 and top 25 now
this will be slightly different to the
menu items we've already got because
once you've chosen either top 10 or top
25 that choice will remain in effect
until you change it and also when you
select the top 10 it will automatically
select the top 25 and vice versa so I'm
going to edit the feeds menu to add
these new options so open the fees and
it's called menu layout if you haven't
already and let's see how to add these
menu items with the option buttons now
the way we do that is to use a menu
group so the first thing we're going to
do is grab is drag a group from the
pallet onto the design this time there
you have to be more careful and watch
the orange highlighting because we don't
want to place it between any of the
existing items and I'll just show you
what I mean by that they're gonna select
the group that new to be careful where
you're placing it and in fact what I
want to do is what I find much easier is
to drag it into the component tree
rather than the design the reason is
it's not like clear as to what's
happening now to show you how you can
arrange the menu options though I'm
gonna place the group between the first
two buttons over here between menu free
and menu paid and you can see that line
there and that's actually showing you
where the new item or group group in
this case because that's what I've
selected will appear so I'm going to
release the mouse button
and you can see group was actually added
there in the componentry so I've now got
the group in the wrong place and note
that the group doesn't show in the
design so this is where the component
tree is really useful so what you can do
is you can move items up and down by
just dragging them in the design but
it's actually easy to do that in the
component tree and with a group you've
got no choice because it doesn't appear
in the design unless you want to end up
the XML directly of course so what I'm
going to do is drag the group down to
the bottom of the component tree notice
the horizontal lines that appear where
it can be dropped it basically shows you
where it's going to appear now gets more
interesting when we have items that can
be nested into other items such as a
group so I'm going to release that first
put the group in there down the bottom
then I'm going to add two more menu
items to the bottom
the menus right so I'm gonna get a menu
item and I'm gonna drag the first menu
on to the bottom of the component tree
but watch what happens before I let go
so it's natural to aim for the various
elements in the list so that your mouse
pointer will naturally be over to the
right below group and this in the list
but if I move over to the left still
while keeping the mouse button down
notice what happens over to the right to
the left and to the right you can see
the little mouse pointer changes over to
the right the new menu item will be
dropped inside our group over to the
left it's going to be a peer it's going
to basically pee below the group so in
other words the guides providing a
visual indication the where the items
are going to end up but this one I'm
going to keep right I'm gonna move over
to the right because we want to put the
drop it inside the group and you can see
that we've never got this little one
menu here and the item is actually in
that group now for the second menu item
I'm gonna select that again and I'm
gonna move down this time I'm going to
keep left so it ends up below the group
rather than inside it now that's not
where I want it but I want to show you
how you can move these items around that
should be easy but let me just drop this
first you can see we've now got one menu
item that's in the group and an item
that actually appears outside and it's
actually showing in here as well now it
should be easy to move things around but
to the guides let us down here so a
future update might fix this but at the
moment I can't get this bottom item and
drag it into the group you can see it's
not actually working when I try and do
that you can see that the it's really
hard to see but there's an arrow key
there it's trying to put into the group
but it's not actually letting allowing
me to move anything so the menu deserves
a bit flaky when working with groups and
that's been there's been problems with
it for over six months now and it does
seem to be working okay generally now
with groups but as I said it has been
flaky but if it breaks again you need to
edit the XML so the fix to get this to
work is to click on this little arrow
here to expand it out and now I want to
do that I can drag this into place okay
you can see that's now worked so you can
see that to the menu design is a little
bit flaky when working with groups and
there's actually been problems for over
six months
now I seem to be working okay apart from
that model problem which we resolved by
expanding the group but if it breaks
again then you'll need to edit the XML
so it's worth having a quick look in
there just to get familiar with that if
you need to for some reason go into and
make changes to the XML so I'm going to
click on the text view now what we're
interested in here is this group so
notice the two items are nested inside
the group there's a group start opening
tag and the group closing tag and if you
get problems placing items inside a
group just drop them at the bottom then
edit the XML to move them where they
should be
now watch out for the group being
created as a self closing tag when it's
empty so in other words if you saw
something like this I'll just clean up
that on the line first so if you see
something like that like that with the
closing slash there if that happens and
it's perfectly valid for an MP Tatem
e-cell crazy like this and you should
delete the closing slash like so and
then just type in the closing tag itself
this one down the bottom but I'm just
gonna undo everything there and leave it
back to how it was before that's how it
wasn't we got there and we'll go back to
the design alright so I'm going to give
the first of these new menu items the
item the ID rather mini 10 they click it
in the group they're now a menu 10 I'll
call that 1 and the title will be top 10
and for the second one there surprises
were guessing a menu 25 and top 25 it's
also a good idea to keep the group and
ID so let's go ahead and do that as well
I'm gonna select the group I mean you
will be the ID and when you GRP limit
that's the ID now at the moment these
look just like any other menu items and
there's no way to telling of telling
which ones currently selected what we
really want is for them to behave like
radio buttons so that if one is selected
the others automatically unselected and
we get a visual indication of which one
is being applied to the feet and that's
the purpose of the group here so if I
select the group which it is selected at
the moment in
as you can see I can actually change it
checkable behavior property to single
and that will allow any one of its items
to be selected
now checkable behavior here we've got
options of none all or single and what
we want a single that allows only one of
its items to be selected you can see
what happen when I do that we
automatically got these radio buttons
showing so that's the purpose as a set
of the group here to confirm that only
one can be selected at a time but if we
change this signal to all those that's
now a checkbox there next to the two
items and that would give you the option
of choosing one or two or none but in
our case we want single which allows
only one of them to be selected at time
right so the last thing we need to do
here is we need to have the top ten
option as the default so make sure the
top 10 is selected either here or in
their component tree then we're going to
use the double arrow icon to the top
right to expand the properties pane the
property one here is checked then these
strange and squares with a dash through
them a tri-state controls they let you
toggle from on or true to off or false
to default which is what the dash means
they'll just see what that means I'm
going to toggle the checkable property
so what is ticked we get a checkbox next
to the top two so I'm going to click on
that now you can see that we've got that
we click on it again we get a radio
button click on the dash again we get
the default and back again so the tick
gives us the radio button and notice is
a bit of a delay when a ticket between
when it gets updated by clicking it
starts off and back to default again but
the one we would want would be checked
and we want that one because that's
going to be the default for this
application so by default it's going to
used to top 10 feeds all right so before
actually writing any code to respond to
these new items I'm going to reformat
the text let's go ahead and do that or
we format code I should say and go back
to the designer so what we'll do is
we'll add the code for these options in
the next video so although they won't be
doing anything we can actually
run the app to make sure that those
options appear in the menu let's
actually do it run the app bearing in
mind of course that nothing should work
when we try to tap them because we
haven't written the code or what added
the code to do that yet as you can see
in our top 10 is the default and when I
click on it nothing happens again
because there's no code but their editor
the menu and it's looking good alright
so I'll stop the video here and we'll
add the code to get those working in the
next video