all right so going on to the solution to
the challenge that we talked about at
the end of the last video the first
thing that we're going to do is add the
Refresh option to the menu now that's
very simple I'm just going to drag a new
item into the design to make sure that
it's below the group and not a member of
it and we talked about that previously
so menu item and you can either do it
here or come down here so it's easy to
do it down here in the component tree
usually and you can see there that I've
dragged it so it's actually in the wrong
place but I can move that out to make
sure then it's no longer in the menu
anymore and no longer in the menu group
anymore which is what we want here next
we want to change the ID the ID is going
to be a menu refresh and the title will
make refresh alright so that's it for
the menu and we'll go back to the code
alright so if we go to track the gyro so
that we can compare the previous one to
the one that we're about to download
then we need a variable to store it in
now we're also going to be storing the
URL and a limit in a bundle so we were
to find two constants to use as the keys
we're going to do that at the top of
main activity just below the feet limit
and feed gyro that we worked on in the
last two videos so we start with a
private their feed cached URL is equal
to and we'll start with double quotes
invalidated in private Val state and the
school URL is equal to feed URL and
private Val state let's call limit
equals feed limit now I've initialized
the feed case URL string to a value that
can't possibly be a valid URL you know
anytime we want to force a download to
happen such as when the Refresh option
is chosen from the menu we just need to
set it to some value that isn't a year
roll you know anything would do but I've
just used the word invalidated now to
prevent the same URL from being
downloaded unnecessarily
we just need to compare the cached URL
value with the one that we're about to
download and if they're the same there's
no need to download again so let's go
down to at the download URL function to
do that so down here we're going to wrap
this in some code we're going to put an
if test here to say if parentheses feed
URL is not equal to feed cached URL
we're going to wrap that code so we're
going to copy this code paste it in
there okay and I'm going to then put an
else in there so else block dot d
parentheses tag I'm a download URL URL
not changed so now with that code when
download URL is called it first checks
the euro it's given against the stored
value now if they're the same and
there's no need to download the data
again you just log the fact so that we
can see the code working in the logcat
but of course if the euro is a different
there's going to go through and execute
normally and importantly the other thing
we need to do is we need to update the
value at the end of that feed cached URL
is equal to feed URL so basically after
downloading the data as usual we're
stirring the URL that's just been
downloaded in the feed cached URL field
ready to be compared next time all right
so onto the refresh menu option now all
that has to do is set feed cached URL to
something different to the last URL so
that's pretty straightforward so let's
have a look at the option the heavy on
options item selected we're going to use
the string invalidated because we've
used that before so we're going to put
this code here outside of the either
Aidid up menu 10 and menu 25 tests
I don't ID don't a menu refresh or a
token when I put feed cached you
equals to validate all right so I'm
using that string and validated it'll
actually validate it'll be consistent so
using that string again as that helps to
document what we're doing so the case
URL has been invalidated
so the download will then meet and we
were be performed again all right so
that's one part of the challenge
completed the app should now shouldn't
now download the data again if we select
the same menu item again so it's worth
testing the app at this point to make
sure the code works if you leave testing
into you've made loads of changes it
gets much harder to find bugs you've got
far more code to check through running
your app after making each change is a
good habit to get into and it really
does make debugging a lot easier so
let's actually run this I'm going to go
back to portrait mode
all right so far so good the app loads
the first URL fine so that's a good
start
so just to confirm that the menus to
works we'll try doing a different type
with songs well that still works we
still get the top ten songs all right
open the logcat and we're going to do a
search we're going to rather select the
same option again songs and you can see
here in the logcat
download URL URL not changed so that's
working as well so things seem to be
working pretty good but to make sure
that the app still uses the same URL and
feed limit after being rotated we need
to store the values of the URL and the
feed limit when the activity is
destroyed so let's go back in there add
the code for that and what I'm going to
do is just put the cursor below the on
options item selected method function
and let's say get Android studio to
generate the on savings and state
function so I'm going to do my ctrl o
and we were on save instance State
they're remembering there's two versions
of this function we want the one with
it's just got a single parameter that
we're looking at currently that's got
two options I'm gonna press the down
arrow to go to the second one with the
single parameter press Enter
alright there another end of that
between of e on options aren't selected
and on destroy so that ondestroy ends up
being the last function in the class so
we're going to now write some code in
there so we're going to start by
removing the question mark from bundle
we're going to leave the super diamonds
on savings and state line in we're going
to put our state dot put string and it's
going to be state let's call euro comma
and feed euro then on the next line out
state dot put string state on this call
limit feed limit and that shouldn't be
in the string it should be an int let's
change it to an it because of course
feed limit is a number okay that fixes
that now we saw code like that before in
the calculator map it just
towards our two fields so that we can
call them back again when the activities
recreated now the bundles passed in as a
nullable top but we know that it won't
be no and as a result I changed the
function signature by removing the
question mark after bundle now remember
that dates are stored in a bundle using
key value pairs we specify a key when
saving something and use the same key to
get it back again and do we see that
Delta keys state underscore URL and
state underscore limit being used again
when we retrieve the values shortly now
when we saved a restored values
previously we used the on restore
instance State and function
now in that app though we weren't doing
anything in oncreate other than
inflating the calculator layer so it's
probably a good idea just to review the
activity lifecycle all right so all
restore instance state is called after
the oncreate method however we do the
initial download in oncreate so when the
device is rotated we need to retrieve
the saved bundle in the oncreate method
rather than in on restore instance date
because if we wait for own restore
instance state we won't have the URL
available when we need it all right so
when the activities first launched there
won't be a bundle but if the activity's
restarted because of device rotation for
example then the bundle passed to
uncreate we non null and we can restore
our fields there so let's actually write
some code now in the oncreate method to
achieve this so there's our one create
method and we're going to put some code
after the last logging well actually
what we'll do is we'll put it after the
start so we've got the super duck on
create and the set content view or put
it on log entry they're logged on T
tagged parentheses uncreate called and
then we're going to put our code in here
with parentheses save instance state is
not equal to null or the code block then
we're going to put feed URL is equal to
save instance state dot get string it's
going to state underscore euro
we feed limit is equal to save instance
state dot get int state and it's got a
limit now when we're dealing with the
bundle in oncreate we have to Kate it
for it being no and that's because it
definitely will be at least some other
time now I know Kotlin tries to do away
with no checks but sometimes they're
valid even in Kotlin so here now is a
valid value for the bundle it signifies
that there's nothing to restore now
because we've performed a null check
Collin can perform a smart cast so save
instance state is cast to be an unknown
bundle and we don't have to use the safe
call operator when accessing the get
string and get into methods all right so
we're now ready to test the program to
make sure it meets all the requirements
of the challenge so let's actually run
this again so what I'll do is open up
blog cat and run it if a lot cat doesn't
clear for you then you want to have
Berkeley it up but you can see in my
case I did and then we've got the data
and we've got the log cat showing so
let's first check a few URLs with
different limits to make sure we haven't
broken anything that was working and
then we go back to the emulator so we've
got the top 10 feeds in there so that's
a good start and you can see that we've
got the 10 entries in there
okay so that's working alright let's do
a change that and go for a limit of 25
okay clearly we've got more apps showing
here so that's working like okay as well
the top 25 if I go ahead and choose
songs now we should get 25 songs and
that's because for the top 25 was
selected so click on songs and what we
can do is just do a filter for main
activity you can see that there's a feed
limit was set to 25 and it hasn't been
reset since if we have a look at the
songs clearly there's more than 10 there
so that seems to be working nicely as
well and in terms of the year well if we
go back and remove the filter we can see
here by looking in the XML that clearly
that is talking about albums and so
forth so clearly that song so that's
correct now well we've got a top 25 feet
it's a good point or good time to rotate
the device to make sure it doesn't
revert to the default top 10 that it was
doing before so let's go back and rotate
now to have a look it looks to me we've
still got two heaps of songs this
everything seems to be working nicely as
well we've got 25 songs there if I
scroll down a little bit more we can see
that it's definitely still the songs and
we can see that on the screen anyway so
that's working nicely now if we go back
and choose songs again and we can just
do a filter here main activity again we
can see that download URL URL is not
changed which is correct so that's
looking good and now the last check is
to check songs again to make sure that
the data is read downloaded when the
same type of feed is selected for the
second time so let's try that Souls
and again download euro not changed so
that's looking good as well
now you may well have solved a challenge
in a different way but if it passes
these tests then well done and
everything's working so that's the end
of this section well we've actually
covered quite a lot in this section so
we used an async task to download data
without blocking the main UI thread and
also use the built-in HTTP classes to
download data from the internet then we
looked at the supplied XML parser
classes to parse XML from the downloaded
data and store the values we want it in
our own objects now the ListView widgets
designed for displaying lists of data
and we saw how to connect that to a
basic adapter we then went further and
created our own custom adapter to give
more control over how the data is
displayed in the ListView and we
finished by creating our own menus and
many groups and writing code to respond
to the different menu items being
selected all right so now you have a
basic app you can have a go at changing
things to improve it so some ideas you
might want to try at this point are
adding some more of the Apple feeds such
as the albums or new releases feeds you
could try passing out the feed title
from the downloaded XML and displaying
that in a text view above the list so it
users have a reminder of which view
they're seen perhaps you might want to
try figuring out how to display the
image URL in a text view and searching
online for how to make the links
clickable so that they open in the
devices browser now it's helpful to
watch these videos a few times to really
understand what's happening and while we
coded the app in this way now you'll
find you pick up different things each
time you watch the videos remember also
that there's a wealth of information
available online so if you're not sure
how to do something then a quick search
will usually provide loads of
information now the Google documentation
is also very useful even if most of the
examples are currently written in Java
but I suspect over time that will change
and we'll start seeing Kotlin examples
as well so I'll stop the video here and
in this section and in the next section
we're going to create an app to view
YouTube videos using Google's YouTube
API see you in the next video