In the previous video you can add code writing data to the database.
Next we're going to look at how to get the data back again to do that.
We're going to use a cursor in database terms a curse allows us to access individual records in the
database.
We can move backwards and forwards in the cursor and it takes care of retrieving the rows for us want
to position the cursor at a particular row.
We can then use it to rate the individual columns all fields of data.
Now you often use a curse.
Even if you only expect to get a single row back from a query you don't have to worry about how many
rows will be retrieved they're all accessed via the database cursor you turn based query could return
thousands of rows and that could be a problem because smart phones have limited amounts of memory all
that data possibly wouldn't fit in the memory with code available.
But of course it takes care of this and points to just a single row at a time.
So you can access and manipulate the data without having to light it all into memory.
And this avoids the performance issues of having to retrain thousands of records into memory a cursor
and I was asked to manipulate the data but I only retrieved at one record at a time.
As you say when we start writing code.
So Android comes with a cursor clasp brought in so we can use that.
So let's get that to go now.
What I'm going to do is come down here after al.
Last time we had it which was the Vout generated all day from the database and so it went on to talk
query is equal to database wrong query in parentheses and double quotes.
Select staw from contex.
Then the second argument required to pass NULL to through a query method returns a Kassa the first parameters
the query that we want to use to retrieve to Tida and offset the second argument to now.
Now if you want to know what the second argument is let's have a look at the documentation
and you can say that that second argument is the selection OGs.
This provides values that we can include in a WHERE clause to ask know query or into his query and we'll
have a look at that a little bit later.
Now if I said that to no balls why with these windows.
These are documentation of Windows that I think contain more text and will fit in them and they always
seem to start up the same size when you first type one regardless of the contents.
So make sure you either resource them or scroll down so that you get to see all the information.
In this case the information didn't require me to scroll.
And by the by we can also say that we have looked look at the return information for all query.
We can see that it's a curse or object positioned before the first record.
That tells us hey that's position before the first entry.
How the thing tonight there is a sequence screen string must not be semi-colon terminated as you would
normally do when you're recreating Siku source card.
What you done earlier in this and this section of the course when using a sequel like three commands
on a program.
So that's wrong query is also a query method as well with several query methods to be precise and they
allow you to specify order by clauses as well as more filtering and grouping.
And it's definitely worth checking those methods out when you come to write your own apps.
We're going to be using something similar lighter and you'll understand what the various arguments are.
Once we've done that but I'm using ral queering here just to keep things simple.
My Actually if I hover over that you notice that we've got this warning from intrench Judaea that this
cursor should be freed up after use with close hash Klores.
Now if you're familiar with Java you'd probably use a try with resources to achieve that.
More importantly if you're converting Java card that uses try with resources you might struggle to do
that in Scotland.
That's because cotland doesn't use the same syntax is Java and there isn't actually a try with resources
syntax as such in Codlin.
Instead Cottenham provides a use function to achieve the same thing.
So let's just top of it and then we'll check up the documentation.
So it's a query not yours.
Notice that it's adding a card block after that.
Have a look at the documentation but yours basically executes the given block function on this resource
and then closes it down correctly.
So in this case it will close the cursor whether or not an exception is thrown.
So you can use the use function with any close object in the same way that job will last try with resources
to be used with any closetful object.
It's not hard now.
I need to put all the code to do with how Kaisa inside that block.
Now inside the car block that vanity we refer to the object that was called on it as it and he can say
that I intended to hopefully tells us that as well.
Calling cursor.
It's adding that for us as a reminder of what you need to do.
So to run the card is something like.
If this is in the code block parentheses artfully move to first.
So again the reason that we're using it and we're not using that query here is that we're referring
to the object that it was cold on.
I see it and that's why we've kept it up move to first here rather than query.
Don't move to first.
Queries a cursor and we're telling it to move to the first record.
It's actually quite possible that a sequel query didn't return any records in which case the move to
first method would return false.
So that's why we're checking that it did manage to move to the first record before we do any more processing.
And just to confirm that you want to check that.
Have a look at the documentation for move to first.
It tells us specifically that this method will return false if the cursor is empty.
OK so if it returns true and the cursor is positioned at the first record and we can stop reading the
Deiter.
So let's put some code in that code block.
Knowing that at this point we guarantee to have at least one record.
I'm going to comment here that we are soft with all the records
with parentheses query and part of what we are talking through all records I'm about to do a little
bit light but for now I'm going to query a single record using with query with in the query book vow.
Hi Dave you was get long parentheses around that when I get string parentheses one Vau find equals get
it to and Val came out.
It was a string theory so good when I saw Queen through all the records yet.
Were going to do that in a minute.
Hence the comment.
For now that we're just reading the values for the first record.
Not that we're using the get method which need the index of the column in the title and obviously is
it.
And then the top of data.
So got long he got a.
He needs.
Cetera.
So these all of these functions need an index of the column in the title so I remember that compute
is index the first Autobus index 0.
So that's why we're reading the first column bought into IDEI the second into the third into fine and
the last into any amount and the order is a lung value where its name and email are strings and because
mistaught the far number as an integer.
We get rather than get string but it works the same.
In reality we really shouldn't have used an integer for the find number but I just wanted to show you
how to retrieve different types of data.
And that's also what I meant in an earlier Vidia when I warned about siecle like columns not really
having a time to talk.
There's nothing to prevent us from storing the string in the Find field but that break out Cartland
card when it tried to read it.
All right.
So for a simple example we kind of display the data in the low.
That's what I'm trying to do.
Is blurring the lines that betrayed the data we're going to talk Val.
Result equals in double quotes.
Heidi Collins Rajai 9 Akos dollar 9 fired because telephone and email equals salary.
Not going to talk to a parentheses.
Tag comma on Create call on creating tighter ta'ala result and you can see that intelligence is helpfully
telling us that this is all attached to the With that we've actually set up this query and the appropriate
card but so far what I wanted to do here now I want to close the database the database got Klores recording
the closed method closing the database is a good idea but you'd normally do that when the app is closed
rather than here.
That way the database is available while the apps running and you don't have to keep opening it.
And we could also repped all this code up in a database to use block just like we did for the cursor.
I didn't do that here because as I've said it's more usual to keep the database open until the app finishes.
In fact if you wanted to use his basic approach in a real app you'd probably create a separate class
to handle all the database accesses.
We don't care to do that.
We're going to be using a content provider instead.
At the moment we're just saying how to run Sekou statements from our calling card.
So at this point to talk we're not ready to run this simple app now run it now.
I'm going to select the same ones that I read about them last Tom Chi-Chi just fast forward this until
it gets to the stage of running.
All right so I could say we've got an era immediately when that happens.
Up to look can't step and see what we can see there and we might have to remove the filter there so
that we can say all the information yourself that is that sometimes Android studio continues to show
unrelated log entries which show any selected application either here to the right selected.
That happens just select your application again in a second dropdown from the left.
This one here.
Mark I need to do that the reason I'm not sitting on the app here is because I've got such minor activity
so shocking that I get I could just like that again.
And not just by doing that now and actually keep the log of all that unrelated information.
And we're back to looking and seeing why our application crashed.
Now one technique for rating these tech traces is to rate the first bit that describes the era did ignore
the rest of the block or the lines starting with that.
In other words it down up to he would have to look at this first long table contacts already exists
in Kampala and he gives us the sequence it was executing.
So that's pretty clear as to what the problem was.
And again just to be clear the
considering here that was caused by sequela exceptions are not told fairly quickly anyway even if we
didn't already know that it was complaining about the create table statement.
You did say that to the right of the screen there now.
So basically we knew that there was a sequel that exceptions to the code.
So the problem was probably relating to a database card we probably guessed that anyway because we haven't
added any other card but it is always useful to check these logs just to make sure that's the case.
So basically you have the same culottes.
Exception is complaining about the create table statement.
And if you skip to the next block eventually say some card here that we can click anything and blue
is the code that we've been working on so you can click on that to navigate to the line of code that
is actually causing the problem and you can say that that's the line that caused the secret method which
means the problem is going to be in the statement a couple lines further up.
Launch 24 in fact.
Basically the type of contacts already exists and that's why we're getting that crash.
Now fortunately while testing there's an easy way to fix that we can just come up here and change the
sequel code slowly.
And at the words If none exists after the create table statements create table if not exists.
Contex So in other words the type A won't be attempted to be recreated.
If it's already found.
So I'm just kind of click on and run
close look I know I would just go back and check out this time out has worked.
I haven't got a creches Thomas So that's a good sign.
I mean we'll get back to our blog again and make the top slushed mind making quickly say that we've
got some data showing on the screen and now it's just doing what we expect.
Well it's sort of these we get the details for the first row appearing.
But the idea for the right that's just been created is now four rather than two.
And that's because our code keeps adding those two records every time we run up.
Now normally you'd be adding new rise when the user does something such a saving and you contact you
wouldn't normally run these search queries each time the app runs.
And we don't want to keep adding the same two rows.
We can easily prevent that part dropping the title.
That's just my quick change of the code today that will add it immediately after our database is being
defined on 123.
We know the top database dot Sakal imprint to say he's going to talk to for quite some time.
It exists contex it's going to drop the time every time.
If it exists let's actually run that again.
Confirm that that works.
This time you could say we've got record at it our data and that confirms that the time it was dropped
immediately after we got access to the database object.
Now generally I prefer to put the sequence type into a string variable like I did for the Create type
all along line 24th.
This makes it easy to log the sequel which makes debugging easier if you make a mistake.
You can just include the sequel as a string as we're doing here.
But I do recommend using a variable and logging is value especially while developing your app.
You can it is too late to logging later once the apps working.
Also be aware that they used to bug logging commands are stripped out by the build system when you create
the release version of your app basically when you use log Doughty the looking lines are removed automatically
so that won't affect you rap's performance.
All right does one last chance to Mike before we stop this video.
We can loop through all the rows in the cursor by using move to next instead of move to first remember
that the cursor is positioned before the first record.
And that means that move to next will do the same thing as move to first the first time it's used.
So let's go ahead to make a simple change to a card to check that.
So I'm going to close that look at first.
And the change you want to make here at the moment we've got a statement here 14 on it will change the
ease to while creating a wallet.
And instead of going to change this card here I'm going to remove some of this now because we in fact
have added the cardinals to Socko through all records.
So now when we run this we should find that we've got two entries showing on the screen so let's run
this stop they up and run it again.
Let's have a look and say what gives us
never say if I take this someone I'm going to do is stop that.
Stop hope and see what I've done that basically didn't change this property or put Wall ATI's up moved
to first.
So it always continually circled back to the first record and therefore the wall statement never became
false.
We never exited the loop.
Of course I talked about it but we didn't do it.
We need to move to next.
Bearing in mind that we move to next.
It does the same thing as move to first the first time it's you said way up to the first record then
automatically progressed to the next record and so on.
Let's run it again.
We should find this time or see bicycle's
this time you can say now we've got reading tauter day one not a tear when cleaning the values are different
there on the screen as well.
Basically look at showing price records correctly and very simple apps working fine.
So this isn't like an incredibly basic app but we've seen how to create a database using the Siku lot
database class.
We then created a table and inserted records by executing the appropriate sequence statements.
And I have said several times that you wouldn't want to rule out this way at the very least it create
a class to handle all the database access.
You'd also want to make sure that your query isn't performed on the main thread.
That's not a good idea because database operations can be slow.
You know there are ways to handle this using things like content providers and case alert and we're
going to be looking at both of those.
But the basics of executing statements from Cartland card will still be needed.
Now we know how to do that.
We're ready to look at more suitable ways of dealing with databases in the next video that we could
have a look at where that database is stored on the device so that we can open it using the sequel command
line and check that it's been set up correctly when debugging it's very useful to be able to examine
that data that's been stored in your database.
So in the next video you find out how to do just that.
See you in the next video.