Know we've got some contact details on Army lighters we can have a look now at how to access those contacts
using a content provider.
Now the contex app has registered a content provider that allows apps to access the phone's contacts
provided they request the necessary permissions and the ransom of.
And we're going to be saying how to do that as we wrought this app is going to start a new androids
Judaea project.
So let's call this one content provider example
that's always include content support next.
So make sure that IP I-17 next for this example where we're not going to bother to create our own patents.
We're going to keep things really simple.
And we're used to floating action button to load the contacts.
So I get to choose a basic activity and click on next and this is just the names on this Laska configuration
screen in my case I'm going to click on Finnish Now once it finishes creating the project we're going
to start work on the content mine.
Ex-MIL fall and the only thing we really want to add to this content and it's called Meindert ex-MIL
file is the list view and that list is going to be used to display the contacts that were going to grab
from the content provider.
I guess I could say that content tells comment that accident was loaded automatically for some reason
it hadn't.
Then just open it as you would normally open it from here from the resources section in the folder.
And I'm going to just close and the project painter to make a bit more spice.
And the other thing I'll do is I just I found by design and the blueprint so you can say both.
Now we're going to be first is to late the hello world.
The text widget so I won't be using that.
And as I mentioned we're going to be using enlistee widget.
So let's grab that this you a piece down here and the legacy that's probably an indication Barnabei
that Google is planning to deprecated at some point but that's not something I'm worried about.
For this simple app but you might want to consider that possibility when writing your own apps.
Are going to rebel to view.
Bring it here and release.
So went to Lescure to fill the available space.
These buttons up here in the inspect that make it easy to add at the constraints for us automatically.
So we got to use the file all the values spice and the other thing we need to do then is to set the
lay up and lay out heart.
I suppose both within that constraint.
So if we just sit and Streitz or the next we want to check the scrollbars and want to make sure that
that set to vertical.
So I'm going to come over here and click on scrollbars not set for me in this case I'm going to click
on vertical.
So I've got a vertical scroll bar there for Eliz to you.
OK.
So I lay with the last heart by a set to match constraint.
So the next thing to do is to change your day.
We want to actually cause one contact tonight because we'll be needing to refer to that in our code.
And now there's one other thing to check and we can tell this by looking at the screen whether it's
said or not.
And that's the layout of the school behavior property of the constraint lab.
So obviously want to come over here and click on the constraint layout that would be where you said
it.
But it is a toolbar saw space at the top of the lap which you can see there obviously is in both the
design and the blueprint that we know that everything's fine.
But for some reason you need to set that so it's not something you actually clicked on the constraint
out you come over here you will attributes and you do a quick search for this or you can just scroll
down to the relevant section.
So search and going to search for life behavior of
behaviors and lay it on margin.
This is the behavior and you can see in this case you can't quite read it all.
But it is actually set to by scrawling the lowest scores scrolling and it's called view on the score
behavior.
So it's not set for some reason that click there and then click on the little ellipses button and you
could choose the APA and score scrolling go to school behavior.
But in my case because I can see the toolbar at the top we know that that is set.
So that's good to go.
Right so that's the lay up finish to this point.
So I'll come back in here and just
just make sure that they're set correctly.
Era
that's a bug or what's going on there but we seem to have two versions of much constraint showing the
slide back and select the other one
that seems to fix it so I'm not sure what's going on there.
But if you do see something like that looks like a bug to me.
Just make sure you set the other constraints how that actually works and fixes the text that fixes the
Exxon-Mobile.
So I can select that X and now click on code and does select reformat code even though there wasn't
really much to format it's there so that when you get to the stage of needing to compare your as it's
going to be the same or what's another format of the kite.
We can move onto the layout for the individual items that will appear in the list view.
Now if you want to experiment with displaying Moorfields from the contacts database once we finish this
up then please do so is a good idea to experiment.
That's a great way to further your understanding of Android app development or any programming language
or environment for that matter.
And it really will help you make sure that you really help make sure you understand these videos.
But I'm just going to display a single file.
Context name.
So this next line we're about to create when I opened the project pane first then we're got to right
click on the layout you're going to select lab resource fall so because we just playing just a single
context nine.
We only need the one field and we're just going to use a text.
So I'm going to call this one contact on a school day.
So the read element I'm going to change is not going to be because layout is literally just going to
be a text view.
So I'm going to select text you because it's the single name that society is having to change again
anytime later.
Or what's the first thing you want to do is come over here and click on the text you are going was going
to close a pain so we're going spice back selecting text to adhere to the left and the componentry the
ID Initially I would call that name and also add some sample text text few in the tools text property.
We talked about what that was before so that way those still show up in the lap of the text you weren't
containing the sample text.
When the app runs so the width and height width is correct on Match parent but her heart should be changed.
We want that to be content to and that's the reason we're doing that is to allow very long names to
still feel OK.
So that's all we really need.
But what I will do is to one last thing and change the text size to 18 like to be bigger than normal.
The text size doesn't try to make sure you're expanding the text appearance section.
He so that you can see that what's that.
So you say it's a very basic layout.
What I'm doing now is I'm going to get access to the text to the ex-American select that I'm going to
reformat the code you know back to design again and I'm going to close this up for now because I want
to close that because other continents coal as well just leaving just purely out Cartland code.
OK so we're now ready to add the common code to retrieve the context data using a content provider and
we'll do that in the next video.