all right so let's talk about the
database for this application so the
structure of the database is fairly
simple but it does use joined
tables and that makes it a good example
for learning how to implement a content
provider now once you've learned how to
perform the basic insert update delete
and query operations on our joined
tables if you need to work with a single
table then that should be easy so let's
have a look at the structure of the
database that we'll be using now you may
want to refer back to the diagram I'm
about to show so I'll add it to the
resources for this video all right so
we've got two tables here firstly tasks
that's going to hold the information on
the tasks and then timings which will
store the date times that the tasks were
started and the amount of time spent on
each task I mentioned earlier that the
table must have an ID field called
underscore ID if we want to use it with
the cursor adapter class which we'll be
doing and it's a good idea to always
call your integer primary key fields
underscore ID when working with Android
databases that way you'll always have
the option of using classes such as the
cursor adapter even if you didn't
originally intend to well use it to be
completely accurate it's the underlying
cursor that must have the owner score ID
column if your primary key column has a
different name then you can alias the
column name in the query or view and we
saw how to do that using the S keyword
in the videos on sequel earlier in the
previous section but why complicate
things if you know you're developing a
database for Android then include an
underscore ID column as a primary key
all right so the tasks table just stores
the task name and the description as
well as a column called sort order that
can be used to list the tasks in a
different order instead of just
alphabetically by name now you may want
to add extra fields once the apps
working it may be useful to be able to
group tasks together for exam
by adding a category field for this
example though we'll stick with just
those three columns and the ID
now the tonics table stores a number of
start times and durations for each task
and it uses the task ID column as a link
to the tasks table now you may be
wondering why the start time column is
an integer dealing with dates and times
it can be very complicated when you
start to consider the various ways that
dates can be represented and different
time zones around the world and so on so
the easiest way to store date and time
information in a database is to store
the number of milliseconds since some
base dates now at the base date is known
as the epoch and in the Java classes the
epoch is midnight on the 1st of January
1970 now we're not really interested in
millisecond accuracy so our code will
divide the millisecond values by 1000
and we'll store seconds instead the
duration will be worked out by
subtracting the start time from the time
that the task is stopped again will
store seconds in the integer duration
column so that's the basic tables will
store the task information in one table
and the timings in another and link them
together using the task ID column now
I've shown of you on the slide and we'll
be using it when we come to Medusa
reports showing how long was spent on
each task it's just used to join the two
tables together and have shown that join
the join clause on the slide our reports
will come from the task durations view
which converts the integer seconds into
a date format so that we can display it
and it also totals up the second spent
on each task which is much easier than
trying to do it in our column code but
we'll be looking at that view later in
the section for now we're just
interested in the two tables and we're
going to start by getting me app to add
and edit tasks and display them in a
list okay so let's have a look at
creating the database and the tasks
table that will be starting off with
now we'll be giving our app to create
the database in code but it's a lot
easier to sort out the sequel statements
using the sequel like three command-line
interface rather than trying to debug
both our code and the sequel statements
at the same time so we'll run sequel
like three and get our sequel working
from the command-line before trying to
use it in Kotlin code but before that
though let's start a new Android studio
project so I'm going to click on start a
new androids do your project and call
this one task timer we've quite Kotlin
support click there we're going to leave
API 17 set up as per normal we're gonna
leave everything else on ticked as we
normally do click on next we're going to
choose basic activity here and that's
because we don't need or won't be using
a floating action button so choose the
basic activity or whichever template
includes a menu if Google happens to
have changed then by the time you come
to watch this video and click on next
now we can leave these names on screen
as they are but we are going to be using
fragments in this app so we want to
check on check the user fragment
checkbox and then click on finish you
know we'll be looking at what fragments
are and why they're useful West we build
this app so don't worry about why we
took that box just yet alright so I'm
going to make it a bit more space here
and now that the project's finished
building I'm going to click over here to
the terminal tab and we're going to
start doing some sequel and what we'll
actually do is I'll take the opportunity
just to move this into floating mode so
I can just drag it up the screen a
little bit and resize it so that it
doesn't affect any sub Tyra's if you
happen to be watching this video with
subtitles so it's not need for you to do
that this can be useful they by the way
if you've got two monitors so you can
drag the floating windows into your
other display alright so let's start
using so you call out three and we're
going to create a new a new database a
sequel like three and we're going to
call the database task timer dot DB
now this does rely on the path having
been sent properly so make sure you've
followed through the earlier videos in
this course for your operating system to
set the path alright so now that we're
in sequel r3 we can enter the sequel
commands to create our tasks table so
I'm going to type create table tasks
then parentheses underscore ID space is
going to be integer space primary space
key space not space null comma space
enemy name text space not no not space
no comma in description space text comma
and space sort order space integer the
right parenthesis and semicolon that's
our task stable now sequel light doesn't
confirm that commands have worked so as
long as you don't get an error then
everything's fine and you can check that
it's worked using the dot schema command
that shows the commands used to create
any objects in the database and you can
see our tasks table so that's worked
fine now I'm going to set a couple of
rows just to make sure that everything
is working as it should I might be
interested in tracking how much time I
spent on this section for example as
well as my various udemy courses so I'm
going to create some tasks for those so
insert into tasks space prep two seasons
can be names come a space description
right parenthesis space values
parentheses in a single quotes double
quotes should work okay we're going to
type task timer in single quotes comma
space and single quotes again task timer
app creation placing a single quote
right parenthesis and semicolon we're
going to use a slightly different
statement for the second third tasks and
I'll talk about that shortly so we'll
insert into for this next line tasks and
in space parentheses can be name comma
description karma and sort order
space values parentheses we're going to
go with Angela Java comma space single
quotes Android Java course it's a Java
version of my course knowing for comma
to the right parenthesis and semicolon
so for the first entry the task timer
entry we didn't specify the field sort
order so therefore we got a null sort
order but in the case with the second
entry I've specified sort order as the
field to insert into and a value in this
case too so that we can contrast and see
the difference now we're not going to
insist that users enter a sort order for
this application so it's important to
test that the database copes if that
valleys left out and the actual values
are arbitrary larger values will sort
down the list so it's really up to the
user how they organize the tasks but
let's do the last entry I'm going to do
an up arrow here and we'll get the
information back again I can just
overwrite that you don't specify this
array for the sword order and for
description I'm going to specify Android
cotton course this of course is this one
and we'll put Android Kotlin for the
first part for the name alright so I've
got three entries there now now by
default by the way ordering in a
database is undefined unless there's a
primary key and because we have to find
a primary key the rows should be
returned in the order that we've added
them so we just type it select space
staff space from tasks was from space
tasks you can see we've got the three
entries showing in there in primary key
order now we can't use an order by
Clause to sort them differently so we
could do something like select space
star space from space tasks and I'm not
going to read ahead and type space
anymore I think you'll know when you
where you're meant to into a space nil
order by name semicolon you can see
that's now ordered by name and the third
example just to select star from tasks
order by sort order semicolon you can
see the water than this tight
this case my sort order alright so by
including the sort order column we're
providing a way for the user to show the
tasks in any order they want the idea is
that they'll probably want the tasks
they're performing most often to be near
the top of the list but our database
seems to be okay and it can cope with
null values for the sort order so now we
can leave I was writing the Kotlin code
to create the database in this tasks
table so let's quit the sequel like
command-line interface type dot exit
then I'm going to type exit to close the
terminal session and we'll finish the
video now and in the next one we're
ready to start running some database
code for our app and we'll start with
the contract class so I'll see you in
the next video