all right so the tasks contract class is
a topic for this video now when we use
the content provider in the previous app
we didn't know what the real columns in
that database were called in fact we
didn't even know that the data was
coming from a database the content
provider abstracts the underlying data
and prevents a standard interface that
we used to access the data we want now
if you remember we use constants to
refer to the actual fields so our
content providers are going to allow the
same thing so we'll start by creating a
contract class to define the names that
are used to access our data now google's
contacts contract class uses an
interface to provide the column name
constants you can find a lot of argument
online about whether using an interface
just to provide constant values is a
good thing or not in this case I think
using an interface in a contract class
is perfectly valid the fact that we're
talking about a contract here is an
indication that an interface is a
suitable way to implement this an
interface is a contract and guarantees
that it will always provide the fields
and methods that it publishes however
Kotlin provides another way objects so
you can find more information on object
declarations of the Kotlin documentation
I'm just going to briefly bring that up
that's a good resource link to check out
but one important use is to implement
the singleton pattern if you only ever
want to have a single instance of
something then an object in Kotlin may
be a good way to do that
it does however have one limitation you
can't pass arguments to its constructor
but actually we don't need to do that
here if you put an object inside a class
it becomes a companion object which
we've looked at earlier now that's also
documented on this page just after this
section you can see the discussion there
about companion objects okay so I'm
going to use objects for the contract
classes for our app so I'm going to go
back to IntelliJ and what I'm going to
do is create a new Kotlin class so I'm
going to go to our package right click
new
and file class we're going to call this
one tasks contract now creating an
object is very similar to creating a
class we just used the word object
instead so I'm going to type object
tasks contract then left or right to
oculi braces now we'll start with a
string to store the table name we'll be
referring to our table in a few
different places so this is a good place
to define the name of the table now
remember that external apps don't have
to know anything about how we're
implementing the underlying storage
which means the name of our table should
only be visible inside our package so
I'm going to use the internal access
modifier to achieve that we're going to
type internal Const Val tape on the
score name equals tasks and double quote
double quotes rather now note that we
can use the Const keyword inside an
object something we couldn't do in the
class all right so that's the table name
next we need to figure out our column
names now what we'll do is we'll put
them inside another object in the tasks
contract object now this is effectively
the same as a companion object but we
don't need the companion I'm going to
type it anyway and we'll see what
Android studio is link checker has to
say about it and I'll just put a comment
down here tasks fields we type companion
object columns left-to-right curly
braces we get an arrow there and if we
have a look at the error modifier
companion is not applicable inside
object and so we can delete the word
companion near the keyword and just
declare an object and I let the
constants for the field names inside
this object will start with Const val ID
and uppercase equals double quotes
underscore ID and in the next line
constable and uppercase task chemical
name equals name double quotes next line
constable
Tech our task rather than task or
description enough a case again equals
an in double quotes description and
lastly Const vowel task Alice call sort
underscore order is equal to sort order
capital S kept away there in double
quotes and obviously you can see I've
capitalized the name description and
sort order and I was 14 through 16
so our columns object behaves almost
exactly the same as if it was defined in
its own column stock kt file the only
difference is that we can't refer to as
directly as columns we have to use tasks
contract columns now one advantage of
this is that we can have several columns
objects now we're going to need to
define the columns for our timings table
and that object would be referred to as
timings contract columns all right so
this can this is a columns object is
just to provide the constants we'll be
using to refer to the column name in our
tasks table so we're going to add more
code to this task contract object later
to provide everything that we'll need
for our content provider but that's
enough for now except there's one change
that I want to make and I want to make a
change to our code so that we can have a
look at what base columns is so if we
come down here and change the OID I'm
actually going to add the word base
columns those columns dot underscore ID
I'm going to delete out four double
quotes that comes from ID that we had
there so if we click on this now we can
check out the source code and you can
see there that base columns is an
interface that defines two constants
underscore ID and underscore count now I
mentioned that Android makes use of a
primary key called underscore ID and
this is where that names defined now we
could have left it hard-coded in our
code but if Google provide a constant to
use then we really should use that
constant so that way if they change
things in future our code will still
work and won't break now I can't really
imagine any reason why they might decide
to rename this field it could break too
much existing code for one thing so if
you prefer to
used a string literal underscore ID or
just closes down in your code instead of
base columns dot underscore ID that
we've got here that's probably fine but
I've done it this way because you'll see
this base columns interface being used
like this in a lot of code on the
Internet
alright so that's enough to be getting
on with in the next video we'll start
looking at creating the database class
so I will see you in the next video