all right so we're going to talk about
singleton classes and specifically the
app database class so our app database
class should work and we'll be able to
test it soon before that though there's
a change I want to make I want to make
it a singleton now a singleton class is
one that only allows a single instance
to be created we've used a few singleton
so far the most recent is the content
resolver there's only a single content
resolver instance or though it's hard to
check that from the source code because
content resolve was an abstract class
and the implementations provided by
Android now we also created a singleton
our tasks contract object in Kotlin
opportunities automatically a thread
safe singleton unfortunately though we
can't make our web database class an
object and that's because we can't pass
arguments to an object constructor the
reason for that is because objects don't
actually have a constructor we can use
an object in our class to return a
single instance of it there's two stages
to making a class into a singleton the
first steps easy we mark the constructor
as private so that nothing else can
instantiate our class so let's go ahead
and do that now so we've got two up here
and our definition internal class app
database constructor we're going to put
the private key word before constructor
so we're now marking that as private so
now the only thing that can create an
instance of app database is app data
base itself either var its own functions
or functions in an in a class or
companion object now the reason I've
done that is because we only want a
single instance of this class to exist
as well as creating a database this
class also provides the connection to
the database
sukh a lot can support multiple users
but it locks the entire database when
writing to it how app is a single user
but if we allowed many instances of this
app database class to be created then
each one would effectively be a
different secret user with its own
connection to
database now that's not the end of the
world and the app would probably
function just fine most of the time as
long as several instances didn't all try
to execute the code to create the
database tables simultaneously of course
now what we see if you allow instances
of a class to be created at will then
there's no way to guarantee that there's
only one instance so making the
constructor private is the first step in
creating a singleton class it'll equally
obviously if there's no way to create
any instances of a class it's not going
to be much used to anyone unless all its
fields and methods are available without
creating an instance as we saw with our
columns object in the tasks contract so
how do we allow that single instance to
be created well you'll find many
examples of how to create Singleton's on
the internet there mainly in Java and
unfortunately many of them are flawed
Android is a multi-threaded framework
and class instances can be created on
more than one thread any attempt to
implement a singleton has to cater for
the same object being created at the
same time from different threads in Java
one solution is to use a static inner
class which has a method returning an
instance of the singleton class now the
obvious solution of checking if the
instance is no than creating a new
instance only if it is doesn't work if
another thread calls the method before
the first call has created the object so
that method has to cope with being
called from multiple threads at the same
time and a common solution is the double
checked locking algorithm so that
basically does a null check twice and
locks the instance variable after the
first check now there's a bit more to it
than that and as I've mentioned
multi-threaded programming is extremely
difficult to get right so let's have a
look at how we might implement that in a
companion object and then I'll show you
a reusable solution so our companion
object will have a get instance function
to return an instance of app database so
I'm going to go ahead and add this at
the end of the class
all right so I'm going to come down here
now right at the bottom of the class
before the last right curly brace we're
gonna type companion object and press
ENTER there you can see that Android
studio fills out the rest for us then
I'm going to type private fire instance
: f database question mark equals null
then also what I'm going to do is add
the volatile annotation to that
definition there and I'm going to create
a function called get instance one get
instance and parenthesis we're going to
pass a context a context : context then
outside of the parenthesis : app
database is equal to then the next one's
going to talk instance question mark :
synchronized in a parenthesis this yeah
left or right curly braces and then
we're going to type within that curly
brace within those curly braces instance
question mark : F database and in
parentheses it's going to be context and
then outside of the right parenthesis
dot also and then we're going to
introduce left to right curly braces
again the type of instance equals it
alright so what are we done here well
we've used to Elvis operators which are
our to null checks on the first line we
return instance if it isn't null
otherwise the synchronized block of code
is executed so that locks the variable
to prevent access from another thread
inside that block we once again return
instance if it now isn't null so if
another thread has managed to create it
in other words but if it is no we create
a new app database instance and then
return that know the also function calls
the specified block a simple assignment
here and returns it we assign the new
instance represented by it to our
instance variable now whenever this
function is called again
instance won't be no and will be
immediately returned now don't worry too
much about exactly how this codes
working as I've said a few times
multi-threaded programming is very
difficult fortunately though Android
gives us things like async tasks and
loaders take to take care of a lot of
the complexity most of the time it's not
something we need to worry about I mean
do you really want to worry about
synchronizing threads and using the
volatile annotation you can't click to
get a description of why that volatile
annotation is there it makes changes to
instance immediately available to other
threads is one of the many things that
people get wrong ok so that code as
we've written it will work but frankly
it's horrible having to modify it to
create different singleton classes could
be a good way to introduce bugs what
would be really useful is some class
that we could use to do this all for us
now the good news here is that such a
class exists there's a link to the
article about it in the resources
section for this video and actually
you'll see that in a moment
I'm not going to open the link in my
browser though and that's because the
article isn't licensed for our
commercial use so I can't really go
through it all in this video now the
article may not be available for
commercial use but we've had
confirmation from christophe bells the
author that the code is you know if you
want to use his singleton class in your
own code that's fine so what I'm going
to do now is create a new cotton file
class I'll go ahead and do that and I'm
going to call this one singleton holder
and what I've been going to do is paste
in the code and what I'm going to do is
make sure that I delete these default
comments because I'm certainly not
trying to claim any credit for this
codes gonna place that in there now and
this is the code there from christophe
barrels as i said so as you can see
though i have a dedicated to show who
wrote the code and also the URL for the
article have a read through the article
especially if you want to learn a bit
more about how all this works so the
only change that of mater Christoph's
code is to add the usual logging our
usual logging there's only and that's
only they're ready to make it easier to
understand what happens when we run the
app and you'll probably want to delete
the constant logging line if you use
this class in your own apps so this
class is basically basically a generic
version of the code I've just added to
our app database class in the companion
object alright so what I'm going to do
is go back to that code and comment out
my companion object and what we're going
to do is use this singleton class
instead so what I'm going to do is above
that commented out code I'm going to
type companion object then what I'm
going to do is delete the left to right
clearly braces you don't need them and
you see I'm going to put : the top
singleton holder and in less than it
greater than sign now I'm going to type
app database comma context and then I'm
going to type parentheses two colons and
app database now that's a lot easier you
can use it in any class that has a
single argument constructor just by
changing the two occurrences of the
class name now passing just one argument
to the constructor is normally all
you'll need you love to need a pass just
a single argument a context for example
to your Singleton's you know I said
that's normally all you need but I don't
want to employer that creating
Singleton's is normal they're not
something you need to create very often
but when you do need to create them you
now have a way to do it right whenever
another class needs an instance of this
app database class it calls the get
instance method the first time that's
called
instance will be null and a new instance
of the app database class will be
created and every time it's caught after
that the caller will get a reference to
the single instance of the class that's
stored in the instance field all right
so in the next video we're going to add
some code to the on upgrade function and
then run a very basic test of the up
database class see you in the next video