all right so moving on now we're going
to talk about on upgrade the function
and also some testing so the other
function we had to implement if you
recall to our out in our web database
our class was on upgrade and if we take
a look at that looking at the
documentation let's scroll this up so
you can see it it gets past the version
of the database that Android finds so
the documentation explains that this
function is called where the database
needs to be upgraded
now wouldn't be a functions called it
gets passed the version of the database
that Android finds and the current
version so we passed the current version
number into the super method in the
constructor so the sequel Lite open
helper class can track the versions for
us you know reverse these are starting
out so this is version 1 so there's
nothing to upgrade we'll be adding some
more tables and views as we develop the
app so I'm going to be discussing the on
upgrade function in more detail when
we've actually going to upgrade to
perform for know that what we're going
to do is we're just kind of add some
dummy code and some logging all right so
going to start with some logging hooked
up d parentheses ter comma double quotes
on upgrade colon starts all right and
we're going to type when in parentheses
old version then open the code block and
then we have type 1 - greater than sign
and code block and that's going to put a
comment in there upgrade logic from
version 1 and outside of that what we're
going to do is do an else that's greater
than and we're going to a throw a legal
state exception in the parentheses an
upgrade parentheses in double quotes
with unknown new version colon space and
that's going to be dollar new version
alright now we can create a new instance
of our app database class in main
activities on create method and request
the database connection to test that it
works so let's go back to our main actor
and specifically the uncreate method
we're going to do just that so I'm going
to start talking this code below the set
to support action bar give it a space
there so I'm going to start talking now
epic database equals epic database dot
get instance then this in parenthesis
then we're going to type Val DB equals F
database dot readable database then next
line Val cursor is equal to DB or or
query and in parentheses I'm going to
type select star from tasks comma then
oh that's the second argument then I can
do a log table T parenthesis tag comma
and what's going to do a series of
asterisks is there and I'm gonna take
the opportunity now to add our tag the
style files are private Const Val tag
equals mainactivity okay and then below
the log entry we're going to do cursor
don't use open a code block and then
we're going to type on the next line
while parentheses i teed up move to next
another code block in a comment here
they were going to cycle through all
records and they're going to type with
parentheses cursor opening in another
code block and type Val I D equals get
long zero in parenthesis and val name is
equal to get string one in parenthesis
thou description equals get string 2 in
parentheses and then sort order Val sort
order equals get string 3 in parenthesis
and I'm going to type the result is
equal to in double quotes ID
space and Donna ID . and name : spaced
on the name then I'm gonna go space
there then description : dollar
description in sort order : dollar sort
order then we never add another lock
there so lock d parentheses ter comma
there's nobody on create reading data
dollar result and then finally what I'm
going to do is take a copy of this these
Astrix a--'s and I'm going to add that
just above the Fabiano click list of it
alright so what is this code doing well
after getting an instance of up database
we run a query and log the task details
this is very similar to the code we've
seen previously we won't be performing
queries like this in the upload this is
just a test that our web database class
is behaving as it should now I've added
a row of asterisks is as you saw there
before and after our data because the
new lock cap makes it harder to spawn
our data alright so now let's run our
application so I'm going to click on the
button to starlet and we're going to
open a lock at just so we can take a
look and see what's happened so firstly
the get instance function returns a new
instance of our singleton app database
class and we can see the constructor
being called appear we've got our app
database initializing on the next line
and then on create starting and if you
recall on create that function is called
for us because the android framework
detects that the database doesn't
already exist so uncreate was called as
we can see there and there's our siegel
code that's the code that creates the
database when that on create two
functions called for us because the
android framework detected that the
database didn't already exist so so far
so good this is really showing us what
we expected to be show on or in other
words the functionalities working as
expected but what we want to do now is
check that the database really was
created and does in fact contain our
tasks table so what we're going to do
now is close a look at
I'm going to open terminal we're going
to have a look at the database on the
emulator so gonna start by topping adb
devices now most of the time when you do
that you'll only have a single device
showing here but I've got an emulator
and my oneplus Android phone connected
and I've done it that way just so you
can see how to use adb shell when
there's more than one device available
but you'll get an error if you try to
use adb commands with more than one
device connected to the computer whether
they're emulators or physical devices
now the reason for the error is that ADB
doesn't know which device you want to
use if there's only one it doesn't have
a problem but if you've got more than
one then you have to specify which
device you want to use we do that with
the - s switch so my emulator is showing
up as emulator - triple v 4 so the
command I need to type here is a TB
space - yes space emulator - triple v 4
space shell so basically you can see
that's connected now to the emulator and
whenever you've got more than one device
connected just use - yes and the device
ID
immediately after ADB and which
specifies which device should be used
all right so we connected now to shell
on our emulator so let's top this you we
need that to super user mode and that
probably won't work if you're using a
physical device unless you've got root
access and you've also installed the SU
command so if you're testing this app on
a physical device you'll probably have
to skip this step but don't worry they
were already confirming that the
database has been created if it hadn't
been then we would have seen errors in
the locker you know we saw in an earlier
video that the database so the databases
are created in the apps directory in
slash data / dat are in a database
directory so make a note of your package
name because that's also the name of the
apps home directory if you are using a
different package name to me in my case
I'm going to type CD slash data that's a
forward slash slash data again that's
going to be learn programming to McAlary
that task trauma
you can see that coming up automatically
when I clicked when I press tab and I'm
gonna go into databases alright so now
that I've done that in the top sequel
like three tasks timer drop DB and then
I'm going to type dot schemer and
there's our tasks table now remember
that Android is a Linux operating system
and the file and directory names are
case sensitive so if your task time a
database didn't open
make sure you've used the correct case
for the name now this should be exactly
the same as the database underscore name
field in the up database class now while
we're here I'm going to add some records
in the database now we're going to write
the code to display the tasks before the
code to add them so these sample rows
will let us see that the display codes
working when we get to that point in
development so I'm going to type part
insert into tasks parenthesis now come a
description in values parentheses task
timer and single quotes comma single
quote for task timer app creation and
close off the single quote right
parenthesis and semicolon then next one
we'll do insert into tasks again
parentheses it's gonna be name
description in sort order separated by
commas and another parentheses to close
it off the right one then in values
parentheses we're going to go with
Android Java you can single quotes comma
single quotes again Android Java course
single quote comma two right parenthesis
and semicolon alright the third I'm
going to type insert into tasks
parenthesis name comma description comma
and sort order cover right parenthesis
values in parentheses again there's some
on top Android Colin and I'm gonna top
android Coughlin course which of course
is this one comma zero right parenthesis
and
: then you do a search star and tasks to
make sure that the records are there you
can see the records are there so at this
point our database is looking fine so
we're going to quit sequel light by
typing directs it then we going to leave
CP is a mode by typing exit without the
doctor's time then we're going to log
out at the Android sure by typing it
once more look at our exit one more time
and that closes the terminal window all
right so now there's some data in the
database we should see it logged in the
logcat when we run the up again so let's
go and try running that and see that it
works well open look at all right so
that's looking good our web database
class created the database and is now
providing a database connection that we
can use we've now got the tasks contract
and app database classes working the
next step is to create the content
provider that we use to access the data
in the database and we'll start work on
that in the next video