all right so we're talking about the URI
matcher in the last video and there's
the link to that euro match a class in
the description under content your eye
patterns on the documentation page for
creating content providers so it's going
to click on that but open it in a new
tab let's have a look at this your I
match a class so this class maps
different content you rise to integer
values that we can use to decide what
code to execute for various your eyes
you can see down here that it's
described as a utility class to aid in
matching your eyes in content providers
you can see there that the example
defines a number of constant in values
people is one people underscore ID is
two and so forth most of that Google's
example code is still in Java but it
should be easy to see what's going on
here if the euro just referred to the
people table the Euro matcher would
return one if the Euro also had an ID on
the end then matcha would return to now
we can't do that magically so further
down in the example code we scroll down
there there's a lot of calls to the add
euro method these associate the various
you're right patterns with the values
that we want the matcher to return for
the people table without an ID the match
is told to return the value of the
people constant which is one but if an
ID is provided and this code tells it to
return people a mask or ID which is two
so I'll talk about that hash in a minute
but it's just a wild card that'll match
any number and in this example goes a
bit further and allows all the phone
numbers for a specified person to be
returned that's people underscore phones
or a specific phone number for that
person people underscore phones
underscore ID so you might be asking why
do we need an integer value for each URI
well if we didn't use the euro matcher
then it would have to do things like
counting how many segments the Euro path
contains then checking the value of each
segment to decide what action to take
now a bit further down the page for I
scroll down you can see over here that
Google provided an example
of how we can use a switch statement
with the values returned by the matcher
compared to an alternative if we don't
use the matcher I can't quite get that
all on the screen but you can see the
gist of it there and Java uses switch in
case instead of Collins win and the
arrow the right arrow but hopefully you
get the general idea with his code even
if you don't know Java now don't you
worry about these would turn values at
the moment are we coming back to those
in a minute
the important thing here is that the
code that doesn't use the euro matcher
is a lot more complicated so there's a
you or I match a code and I scroll down
you can see there I think clearly you'll
agree that so it looks a lot more
complicated and that's because it has to
check the number of segments then check
specific segments against a table name
so it's just more complicated the Euro
matcher is making our lives easier by
taking care of the matching and just
giving us an integer value to use in the
switch statement and obviously in the
wind' statement if we're talking : so
now that we've been through that we can
add the code for the build your I match
a functional or rather add the rest of
the code
now Google have done it slightly
differently here in the car just above
this as well up and have a look there
you can see here they've added a static
initializer block to call the edit your
I method it'll be interesting to see
what they suggest when they produce a
Kotlin version of this example but I
suspect they'll do the same as what
we're about to do so go back to our code
so our lazy delegate that we defined on
line 34 make sure that the Euro match of
instance is created when we need it and
lazy also ensures that there's only one
instance created now if you read that
article by Christopher Belle's you'll
see that he based the singleton holder
class on the Kotlin lazy code right so
let's write a bit of code here now and
expand on that build it your I match a
method so at the moment we've got just
pretty well an empty bit of code there
and a start you know first they will
look at the first your i we want to
match and it'll be EG content colon
forward slash forward slash learn
programming don't academy
dot task timer top provider slash tasks
for the capital T so to add that to the
match show we're going to type matcher
dot head your eye and then in
parentheses we'll start with our content
under Authority comma then it'll be
tasks contract dot tables table own
school name comma then tasks then the
next thing we want to match if I'll just
copy that comment this time it'll be for
a specific task forward to that eight
for argument's sake and that would be
mature dot add URI and in parentheses
content answer authority comma this time
it's going to be in double quotes dollar
sign left or right curly braces tasks
contract dot table name then right
closing off the curly brace the right
can erase their sports slash and the
hash for the world card combat this time
it's going to be tasks underscore ID and
what I'm going to do just take a copy of
these we're going to change this instead
of tasks contract here we're going to go
with in this next part
timings contract and that'll be timings
on the in there
I don't worry about these errors I'll
talk about those shortly and in the
string is going to be timings contract
table name and instead of tasks ID is
going to be timings Alice for ID and
we'll add one more group here and this
will be further durations contract
moments are there sort of situations
rations contract and then on the end
instead of timings it's going to be
tasks underscored durations and the end
here I'll just make that change that's
tasks underscore durations and score ID
and then the actual string instead of
timings contract there's going to be
durations contract
okay again don't worry about the errors
I've included your eyes for the timings
and durations table that we'll be using
later because without them it's less
obvious what this function is doing all
right so what the function starts it
creates a new euro mature object and we
can see that on line 38 the Constructors
parameter is a value to return if the
route your eyes matched now we don't
want to imagine a table name must be
specified in the URL well that's why
we're specifying no underscore match as
the argument on line 38 alright so then
we're adding the your eyes that we want
to match so if the tasks table is
specified without an ID the matcher will
return 100 the value of our tasks
constant that's the code on line 41 and
if an ID is also provided it'll return
101 the tasks I was greedy constant and
that's the code online 44 and for the
timings table we'll get 200 in 201 which
is the value of timings and timings
underscore ID the constants that we've
defined now we can scroll up and see
those values again the ones that we've
defined up here earlier in the file at
the top of the file now just to be clear
here these numbers are totally arbitrary
we could have just set our constants to
1 2 3 etc which is what that Google
example we just looked at does now
obviously we shouldn't use negative 1
because that's the value of the Euro
match no one has gone much constant and
if you're wondering you can see that
I'll hover over it and click you can see
there that no matter is set to find to
be negative 1 and if you haven't already
done so what I suggest you do is click
on the documentation for one of these
links so I'm going to do the one for the
first add your eye and it gives us some
information so you can see that the
first parameter here's the authority and
the second one is the path that we want
to match so a path that we want to match
can't contain wild cards either a hash
or an asterisks in this example we used
a hash because we want to match any
numerical ID if you want to match any
text then you could use in asterisks
which will match numbers as well as text
now the use of the hash here is maybe
unfortunate as I mentioned in the
this video when we're looking at your
eyes because the hash character is used
to separate a URI fragment in the
specification that we looked at so here
though the hash is something that the
urimatcher class interprets to mean any
numeric value and it's not used in the
same way as the hash that separates a
fragment from the rest of the URI that
we again we saw in the specification
relating to your eyes now there's no
confusion as far as the class is
concerned because this second parameter
is only matching the path part of the
euro so the third parameter is the code
that we want the matcher to return if it
matches the Euro so go back to our code
here if the URI just refers to the tasks
table then the matcher would return 100
and if there's an ID on the end of the
URI
it'll return 101 and I've also included
the code to match the timings and
duration you arise just so you can see
how we get different values returned
when dealing with a different in your
eyes now at this point we haven't
created the timings contract and
duration contract classes so I'm going
to comment out those lines just to
remove the errors but well uncomment
this code once the classes have been
written in later videos so hopefully now
the reason for these constants that we
defined at the top of the file should
now be apparent they're the values that
the urimatcher will be returning for us
to ultimately match the euros against
alright let's go down and look at the
code start implementing some code now
and we'll start by getting the oncreate
method out of the way then we can see
how to use this your eye nature now
although it's not important I prefer to
arrange these in these functions in a
more logical order so on create to mind
should come first and I expect to find
it to the top of the class code so I'm
just going to move these functions
around a little bit so start with
uncreate so I'm just gonna put that
right at the top here and the next one
I'd expect to see there is get type grab
that as well
and put that below then create and the
next one would be query then we're going
to remove that and then the other three
insert update and delete are fine in
that order and again that's more a
personal preference thing but generally
I would expect to be using things in
that order and therefore seeing the
functions defined in that order as well
and what I also do is take the
opportunity to remove the nullable type
marker from all the uro parameters let's
go ahead and do that now these functions
might be called with a null you're right
if they are something's gone wrong
and I'd much rather that was picked up
by the compiler rather than having the
up crash and the same is actually true
of the content value parameters these
ones here in the insert and update two
functions there's really no point
passing null for the values to insert
for example which is not going to work
so I'm going to remove the question mark
there
the nullable type marker from both the
insert method for content values as well
as the content values for update rights
they get it back to our uncreate
function it's very simple very very
simple I'm not going to do anything in
fact in the code but I'll start by
deleting this to do now we could create
our database class in here but as we've
implemented it as a singleton we'll just
use the get instance function whenever
we need a database instance but this one
create function has to be implemented
though and should return true and just
out of interest is worth demonstrating
that we can't create instances of app
database so I'll try and do that now but
I'll start with a log-log dot d
parentheses tag comma on create call on
starts just to be consistent I'm going
to add a colon up here build your eye
matcher colon starts as well for the
year log well I said try to our create
instance of our app database Val app
database equals F database and in
parentheses contexts and for hover over
it you can see you cannot access an it
it's
rather than that database so that's
actually what we want here any attempt
to create an a database instance will
fail and that's because we have to use
the get instance function so I'm going
to delete that line now just to remove
that hero what I will do is return true
all right so I mentioned that I'm
creating it certainly was about logging
so that we can see the flow events in
the log cap but let's get back to using
the urimatcher this time in the query
function which is the third implemented
function and I'm going to get back to
get type do get type function later so
the first parameter in the query the
query function here I'll delete the to
do so get in the first parameter either
you arrived so we're gonna start by
using our urimatcher to work out what
kind of your way we've been given here
so we're gonna type block type T
parentheses tag comma that's a comment
query colon called with your I dollar
your I so I can see and look at what it
looks like but the actual code we've
they'll match equals your I match a dot
match in the parentheses you're right
they will do a log for that as well log
deputy parentheses ter comma and it'll
be query again :
matches dollar match alright at this
point now we can use the value of match
to decide which euro I was passed into
this query method so that we know which
table we should be using for example so
the next thing we want to do is use a
query builder to build the query that
will be executed against the database so
to do that I'm going to talk about query
builder : and it's movie sequel Lite
query builder equals that's going to be
sequel Lite query builder now to get the
documentation for the sequel Lite query
builder
make sure you click on the top over here
and not the constructor call and you can
see here that the documentation tells us
that this is a convenience class that
helps build sequel queries to be sent to
sequel Lite data
subjects so that's pretty useful it's
always easier to use a built-in object
for building things like your eyes or
queries the alternative is parsing and
concatenated strings which while not
being terribly difficult can quickly get
messy all right to see how we use the
sequel at query builder I'm going to
paste in the rest of the code for this
function so that we can see what it does
while I explain it so let me just grab
that code and we'll actually get some
errors here and I'll deal with them once
we've talked about what the codes doing
I'm gonna put this below the query
builder a variable variable definition
there now I'm also going to take the
opportunity up here to remove the
redundant type declaration I only added
that so we had something to click on to
see the documentation so I mentioned
we're going to get some errors there
there mainly because mostly because this
includes the code for querying the
timings and durations tables that we
haven't created contract classes for and
by the way if you want to grab the code
for this that I've just the code for
what I've just pasted in it is in the
resources section for this video if you
don't want to go ahead and type that in
so again I've added the code here for
the timings in duration tables because
if there was only one table it may not
have been as obvious why we need to
bother with the year right in the first
place I'm going to comment out the
timings and iterations code in a minute
but seeing all the code does make it
easier hopefully to see whether your I
match a class is so useful all right so
we're using a win here when statement to
choose different blocks of code
depending on the result of matching the
Euro I if the Euro just contained a
table name the basic query is pretty
simple it's just a sequel select with a
table name you can see that there the
code on line 74 and same for timings
line 82 and durations line 90 so
basically when the Euro matches tasks
timings or tasks considerations we just
cause a set tables method to tell the
query builder which table we want to
query so the Euro matches tasks timings
or tasks runs for durations we're just
using we're just setting the tables
property here to tell the query builder
which table we want to
and if you check the documentation there
for that you'll see that we can also
specify more than one table and we could
perform a join so that's certainly one
way of doing things but another approach
is to perform the join in the database
using of you so you think if you made
life easier in the sequel tutorial
earlier in this course and it also
simplifies the code here in the provider
now you can't do it either way of course
but there's really no reason why the
content provider should care about how
the data is organized in the database
implementation details like that really
belong in the database so the less our
code relies on knowing about the
implementation the easier it is to
change things in the future this code
though as it stands does have a
potentially serious flaw though using
query builder don't pend where like
we're using here for example on line 79
may introduce the potential for sequel
injection attacks in fact if you've
uploaded code like this to the Google
Play Store you'll get a warning and be
told to fix it so rather than using a
pen we're bouys the suggestion is to use
a pen where escape string so I'm going
to change that and I'll take the
opportunity to do that for all three so
let's call the call up the documentation
that function so the relevant part and
the difference from the European where
method that we're using is this final
sentence of the documentation it will be
escaped to avoid sequel injection
attacks now at the moment the lint
checker doesn't pick up on this and
allows as I calls to append where to get
through with no warning until that
changes be vigilant and use the append
where escape string function instead of
a pen where all right so I'm moving on
now if an idea is included in the euro
then the matcher will return tasks files
for ID time exams for ID or tasks and
let's call durations underscore ID so in
that case we call the get by D method of
our contracts class as an example there
on line 78 and that'll extract the ID
for the URI for us now this is another
example of delegating responses
ability where it belongs our contract
classes have intimate knowledge of the
euros so it should be down to them to
pass information out of the your eyes
there's no need for the content provider
to know that the ID appears in the
second segment of the path it just needs
to get the ID from the euro now let that
be well let that function to the
contract class in the next video now if
there's an ID included in the URI or
call the booty billed as a pin wear
escape string function and this adds a
where clause to the query and here the
where clause will just be a no score ID
equals whatever the actual ID value was
I so I'm going to take this opportunity
just to comment out the code now for the
tables that we haven't created yet and
in the next video we'll start work on
getting that get ID function in a task
contract class written and make a few
other changes so we'll see you in the
next video