So thanks again for rolling in this course and actually congratulations for getting to the very end.
I hope you actually enjoy this course and got a lot of value from it.
Now I don't know whether you know perturbs actually got a lot of other programming courses what I've
done is a complete list of all my courses along with a special discount link for you in the very next
lecture.
So we're I feel confident that if you've enjoyed this course that you're going to enjoy the enjoy these
other courses that I've got.
So I'm going to edit video here now and ask you to move onto the next lecture and you get to see a list
of all these courses and you can click through to any of them to find out more information.
The key is for the.