Welcome to this course.
I'm super excited to have you onboard and to start this journey together with you,
my name is Max and I'll be your instructor in this course.
I'm a freelance web developer and I've worked with Javascript for years and ages. Now by the end of this
course,
you will also be an advanced Javascript developer capable of applying for Javascript jobs, working on your
own project or simply dive deeper into the Javascript landscape and ecosystem and explore all the very
advanced and niche features Javascript offers.
Now this course is for everyone,
we start at the very basics, no prior knowledge is assumed but we'll also then build up knowledge and
explore the more advanced and also experts topics.
So no matter if you already have some Javascript knowledge or if you're just getting started,
this course is for you.
Now I'll not bore you with entire overview of what's in the course in this lecture because for that,
I'll have a separate lecture later in this module.
There, you will also learn about different entry points you can use based on your level of knowledge
because this is not just a complete guide,
it's also a complete reference in the end.
This course also is not a theoretical course,
of course we have all the theory but it's a practice-oriented course,
there are plenty of opportunities for you to apply what you learned.
There are quizzes and assignments and a lot of exercises and demo projects because I strongly believe
that you'll learn the most if you can apply things in real world scenarios.
You're also not alone, in this course,
I'll always be there and I'll do my very best to ensure that you get out of the course
what you want to get out of it.
And with that I'd say let's not waste any time,
let's dive into the most important question right away and let's find out what exactly Javascript is.