Let's explore third-party libraries in this module, a concept which makes sure that we don't reinvent
the wheel because reinventing anything typically is not the best idea.
So this module, we'll have a look at what third-party libraries are and why you might want to use them
in Javascript but actually in programming in general. We'll have a look at a couple of example libraries
and specifically, I'll also show you how third-party libraries or one specific third-party library can
make working with HttpRequests easier.
Now we covered HttpRequests in great detail in the HTTP module and it's important to know all of
that and using a library is not a must do.
Nonetheless in this module, I'll show you an alternative and you'll see why you might prefer this over
manually implementing all the HTTP things you learned about.