Let's dive into browser support.
I talked about this a couple of times in the course already when we used one feature or another, I sometimes
mentioned that
this has better browser support,
this only works in modern browsers.
Now in this module, I'll dive deeper into this,
I'll explain what exactly browser support is all about and why it matters and how you can ensure that
your code, your scripts work everywhere you want them to work. In detail,
we'll have a look at what exactly browser support means, what that is, how you can find out which kind
of browser support you need, which browsers you want to support in your application and how you can of
course also find out which features are supported in which browser.
Now of course we'll not just find out which features work where but we'll also explore what you can do
to write an application, to write code that works in a broad variety of browsers or in all the browsers you
want to support and there, we'll dive into of things like feature detection and fallback code,
we'll have a look at polyfill, so what that is and
how that can help us and we'll have a look at code transpilation, which allows us to write modern
code and ship older code which works in older browsers as well.
So a lot of things to cover,
let's not waste any time and dive right in.