This is a groundbreaking course section,
we'll have a look at Javascript modules and knowing about Javascript modules will
and this is really no exaggeration,
change the way you write your Javascript code or your Javascript projects.
It is a super important feature,
it's natively supported by modern browsers and in the next module, you'll also learn how to build up
on that and make it work in all browsers
but let's first of all learn about it,
I'm talking about Javascript modules, a key concept that helps you organize your scripts and writing
multi-file code. In this module you'll learn what exactly I mean with modules and how that works and
why we use that
and of course then you will learn how to use it with many examples showing the different syntaxes you
can use there.