In this module we'll also have a look at a couple of new features or to put it in better versions, new behaviors
I should say but we'll not introduce that many new features as in the previous modules.
This however is a very important module because we'll have a look behind the scenes of Javascript, we'll
understand more how it works, what the browser does with our code, how it executes our code.
We'll also have a look at a couple of weird parts in Javascript and how it evolved over time and we'll
have a look and that's related to the involvement process.
We'll have a look at ES5 and ES6 and what that is and how that differs.
Now to be precise, we'll actually start with that ES5 versus ES6 thing and I'll explain what
that is and how the syntax changed in these different versions of Javascript which it effectively is.
We'll have a closer look at how some of the syntax, especially when it comes to creating variables, changed
over time and what a key difference is between how we create variables now, which is how you learned
it in this course thus far and how we did it in the past.
We'll then have a look at how Javascript works,
so what the browser actually does with our code, how it parses and interprets this and then also how
it executes the code, so once it interpreted it or once it started interpreting it what it's doing with
the code. We'll have a look at a couple of weird parts with Javascript that can be confusing but that
actually aren't that confusing, you just need to be aware of them and I'll dive into all these important
things in this module.