We're getting more and more advanced and now that we have an understanding of HttpRequests and also
third-party libraries,
we're well-prepared for this module where we'll talk about browser storage.
Now this is a general Javascript course but as it was the case already throughout this course, of course
the focus lies on the browser because that's the first place where you typically work with Javascript.
Now in the HTTP module, we had a look at how you can store data and also fetch data from inside
Javascript to and from a server,
so how you can basically attach your user interface to some backend, to some server which then might
also talk to a database where the data gets stored and retrieved.
Now some data however can also be stored in the browser, so directly where your user is, not all data
is suitable for this storage and we'll explore what browser storage is and for which kind of data we
might want to use it in this module.