So how could we fix this here and find an object in an array index of doesn't work?
Well you have another method or two other methods which you can use in such a situation. So let's say
Manuel is the person I want to find,
well then you can use person data and then there is a find method,
that's also a method which is available on every real array
and now find is an interesting method.
It takes an argument but the argument it takes is actually another function.
Now this is a typical use case for an anonymous function, though of course you could also define a function
somewhere and then just pass in a reference to that function,
so the function name but since this often is a function which you only need to run in this place and
which you never call from anywhere else in your code, this is a perfect scenario for an anonymous function.
Now of course it's not just a function like this which does nothing,
instead it's a function that can accept up to three arguments.
The first argument will always be a single object of that array,
so we could name this person,
you can choose any name you want here.
The second argument will always be the index of that single element,
so you could name it index or idx or whatever you want.
The third argument will be the full array,
so persons for example. Now who is calling that function? Javascript that will call it for you
so to say, find executes on this array and what it does is it executes this anonymous function which you
pass to it
or this function in general what you pass to it on every element in person data.
So it will execute this function here on every element in person data and will then for every execution
pass in
that element it's currently looking at, then the index of that element and then the full array.
Now of course, you can also use find on any array, even if it's an array full of numbers or text, it's
not restricted to arrays full of objects, that's just a use case where it's particularly helpful because
it can help us identify an object or a value if it's a reference value
because for primitive values, often index of helps us get what we want, though that of course returns the
index
but then we could use that index to easily access the value behind that index,
right?
But back to find,
so we execute this on every item in person data and it then expects that this function which you pass
to find returns true for the element you're looking for,
so for the element you are trying to find and false for all other elements.
So in here, we have to return something and that should be a boolean,
so typically in here you have some kind of comparison.
So we could compare person.name because we know we execute this on an array of person data,
so we have a bunch of objects in there which have a name property
and this is a single element of the array,
don't forget that
so it will be an object with a name property and we can check whether that is equal to Manuel for example
in this case
and this should find us that one object where the name is Manuel.
Now if you have multiple objects with a name of Manuel, it will still stop after the first hit, just like
index of, it will stop after that and not return all fitting elements but only the first one. So find
returns us Manuel, here therefore I'm not even using that index or that entire array and quite often,
you'll not need that but if you need it for some reason, in that function, you have it available and therefore
now if I console log Manuel here, we hopefully console log a Javascript object which is having a
name of Manuel.
So if we now reload, that's looking good.
Now one important note about find, it returns the same object as you have in the array here,
it does not copy it or anything like that.
So if I then would manipulate Manuel's name here and set it to Anna
which is pretty drastic change I guess but let's still do it, then I will not only see that here when
I log Manuel but also if I log the entire person data array again. If I do that though and I reload,
you see here we have Anna but we also have that here in the array because we're working with the same
reference value, with the exact same object, that's important to understand,
find does not create a copy.
Now just like find, you also have find index, so you can get Anna or max index here by using person data
find index and then it takes the exact same function,
so exactly in the same way,
now I just want to look for Max here and the difference is that it will not return the matching item
of the array but the index of that item.
So if I now console log max index down there, we should see 0 because that max object is the first element
of that array and therefore has an index of 0.
So if we save that, reload, indeed here we see 0 being printed
so that also works.
So let's find and find index.