Thus far every class works kind of standalone.
Yes
we returned the created element and use that in other classes
but for example, that event listener on the add cart
button, it triggers this method and there, nothing happens.
Well now we have to make sure that when this method is executed, we actually do something which leads
to our cart class, to update our cart class we'll need to re-render. Now,
as it turns out, that's rather difficult right now. In our cart, in our shopping cart class,
you could certainly add an add item method or something like that where we expect to get a new product
in the end, we could of course therefore also name this add product, probably a better name and then we
could refer to this item,
so to this field which we initialize to be an empty array,
so to this property which initially is an empty array and push our product onto that array, that's something
we could do for sure. Thereafter, we could call render again to re-render this but that for example wouldn't
work because it returns a new cart element, not something we want here,
we want to update the existing content instead.
Well that's something that could be done though,
we could go to render where we render our content and simply make sure that we store this place where
we output that number, so that we get access to this h2 element.
Here we could say this total output or however you want to name it and therefore add a new property
and you can add new properties anywhere in your class, in your object, doesn't have to be inside of the
constructor
as you learned earlier in the course, you can always dynamically add new properties to an object.
So here we add a new total output property to the object which is created based on this class and set
the value equal to cart
el referring to that element we're creating here and then query selector h2, so we get access to that
h2 element and store a reference to this element here in the total output property.
Now here in add product, we could then set this total output equal to and now basically copy that code
here,
therefore use this template literal notation here with the back ticks and now set this to the
old total plus the new total based on the items we have here. For the moment, I'll just set it to 1 and
we'll add a real dynamic solution later,
for now I just set it to 1 so that we see that it changed at least.
So now we would have an add product method that probably should update what we see on the screen,
the problem is how can we call that add product method from inside of product item?
Well you could think, I just call cart add product,
well that won't work,
cart here is not a variable you have available here, cart like this or to be precise, shopping cart
so referring to the class itself like this won't work,
you have to instantiate it to work with it,
you can't work with a class just like this,
at least not in that way here.
Now we do create the cart here in the shop,
here we have a cart, a cart instance where we could call add product
but here unfortunately we're not adding that product.
Now how can we solve that?
Well turns out there is a way we can actually make a syntax like this here work and that will help us
solve that,
let's have a look at that in the next lecture.