Now the output you'll get if you reload might not exactly be what you want because it actually yields
14 here instead of 0
but if you take a closer look at your code, that makes sense because current result is 0 here
but then we calculate a new current result.
So if I then use current result here, I of course take this current result and not the one I had up here.
The reason for that is simple,
your Javascript code gets executed from top to bottom,
actually your HTML file gets parsed from top to bottom by the browser
and if you then import some Javascript in there, that file gets evaluated and executed by the browser
and the code in there also gets executed from top to bottom and
that's the default Javascript behavior and hence of course if you do something in this line and then you
use it in the line thereafter, you get the result from this line and not the result from the first line.
It would be pretty bad if that would be the case because then you could never do anything in your code.
So to print zero here, we would either have to do this before we execute this line or store this initial
value in another variable
and that's actually where we could use a constant. Let's say we're writing a program here where we want
to initialize our current result with a default result value and I'm naming this constant here default
result,
you could pick any name you want.
Now I'm using the const keyword to indicate that the value I store in here will never change and I store
zero in here.
Now we can use the default result here to initialize the variable,
yes you can initialize a variable with the value of another variable or of another constant and
that's exactly what I'm doing here.
The result of that is if we now change current result, we can do that because that's a variable created
with let, we couldn't change default result,
so if I would try to do that here and I now save this, you will actually see zero here because our
script broke and you can see that in an even better way
if you go to the developer tools here in Chrome which I recommend that you use, you'll find those in the
view menu and then developer, developer tools or by using the shortcut you see there.
Now what are these developer tools?
I'll have a whole module after this module where we dive deeper into them and what you can do with them,
in general that's simply a tool built into the browser which you don't typically see or use if you're
using the browser as a normal user but as a developer, this is a special feature built into the
browser that helps us understand our code, look behind the scenes, have some insights in how our code
executes, trace and fix possible errors and also see error messages or info messages being output here.
So these are the developer tools, a crucial feature which do not just exist in Chrome, Firefox and Edge
also have developer tools built-in, Chrome just has very good ones and therefore that will be
the browser I use in this course but again, I'll have a whole module where we dive a bit deeper into
developer tools and what we can do with them
after this module. And in these tools if you go to the console here, so to console, you should see an error,
assignment constant variable.
That's a problem,
your browser complains about it because that's not allowed.
So that's not allowed but assigning to current result is allowed because that's a variable
but since I now store this default result which I then use to initialize current result, I can also refer
to this down there when I output my text or when I generate my text. We can refer to it here and here,
so I'm referring to default result in two places of my code,
I'm never changing it though because that wouldn't be allowed.
Now we introduced a constant and you might be wondering if we're not implicitly still changing the constant
with our code because I initialize current result with the value which is stored in my constant and
since I thereafter change current result, you could think that implicitly we also change the constant, right,
because we set those equal in this line
but it's important to understand that indeed we are not changing the constant here because here, we are
copying the value that's in a constant into this brand new variable.
So if we thereafter change the variable, we're changing the copy, the original constant and its value are
untouched
if we then change the variable, that's something important to keep in mind here or to understand. And
therefore now if I reload,
we see this result and we see the correct text representation of this calculation because we're now
using this correctly and we're building a text with our default value which never changes.
So this shows us constants and variables in action,
it shows us operators both used with numbers and also with text and we get something on the screen, not
too bad to get started with.