So the movies which we have in our array should be output on our page
and for that I'll add a brand new function here and you can of course name it however you want,
I'll name it render movies, like this and in render movies,
I will do something which is not the most ideal way of doing it but which is good enough for this demo.
I'll reach out to my movie list, so to this unordered list here in index.html with that ID
here with document get element by ID movie list and then there, I want to render all my movies into
this movie list.
Now the ideal approach would be that for every movie you add, you append one item to the already existing
list,
this is also what we did in an earlier module.
Now here to save some time and focus on objects which is of course the core of this module, I will actually
do it differently and I will reach out to movie list and set innerHTML to an empty string which
will clear it, so that if something was rendered into it, it's now completely deleted.
This is not ideal because now this means that whenever we add a movie, I clear the entire list and
re-render it from scratch which of course costs unnecessary performance
but again I'm doing it here to save some time,
you saw a different approach of appending one item after another in an earlier module. So here I am clearing
this,
I also want to make sure that we can see the movie list to start with because by default if we quickly
have a look at our styles here, we can see that movie list by default has a display style of none
and it only gets a display style of block if we add the visible CSS class to it.
So therefore here whenever we call render movies, I want to check if movies, so my array up there, if the
length which I can access with the dot notation here because length is a property of this array object,
if that is equal to zero which means there are no movies because if there are no movies, then I will
reach out to the movie list and class list and there call remove and remove the visible class if
it's on it, else I will reach out to movie list, to class list and add the visible class and this should then
show it. Now we can also return here after removing the visible class and therefore this innerHTML
clearance can also happen after this if check.
So now with that, we have this logic in place,
now let's make sure we actually output the movies here whenever we call random movies and we don't just
toggle the visibility of the list. So I clear the current content here by setting innerHTML to an
empty string,
now I want to go through all my movies and output them there.
For that we can use a for/of loop or of course also movies ForEach to work with this as well because
we learned about the ForEach method in the arrays section, so why not
and as you learned, you pass a function to ForEach which is then executed for every element in that array
and it will get the element as an input,
so our movie here, you can name it however you want,
I'll name it movie because it's in the end a movie.
I don't care about the other arguments
I could pass here because I don't need them and now we go through all movies here and with us going
through all movies, I want to create new elements, new DOM nodes for every movie of course.
So here we can create a movie element, movie el with document create element and that should be a list
item element,
so with the HTML tag of li and then here to that movie element, I want to set the text content equal
to movie.info.title because remember, our title is stored in that nested info object in each
movie,
so we have to access .info, that yields is a new object
and on that new object we got, we can access .title so you can chain,
that's how it's called, multiple property requests
so to say after each other and with that set here, of course l also want to append that movie to the movie
list.
So on movie lists, I will call append and add my movie element, still in the ForEach because that
should be done for every movie.
So with that, we just have to make sure we call the render movies when we add a new movie,
so here at the end instead of console logging it here, I will call render movies just like this.
So now whenever we add a new movie, it should be rendered.
So now if we reload here and we add Javascript - The Complete Guide, level 5 and I click add movie, you
see that's getting output down there
and if I add another element here, that's getting output there as well.
Now technically always everything gets cleared and re-rendered from scratch
and as I mentioned, that is not ideal but for this demo, it's absolutely OK.
So now we're outputting this here and we already use quite some nice object features,
now what we're not doing is we're not outputting the dynamic user chosen key-value combination here
but I want to output this here as well
so let's see how we can do that.