So let's start by making sure that we can not just get the coordinates for an address but also the address
for coordinates we might enter
so that we store both coordinates and the address
because I want to have both for then displaying this to the user when we have this shareable link. So in
location utility file here, we can add another function
either in front or below the other function, doesn't matter,
another async function which I'll also export which I'll name get address for or from coords,
so basically the opposite. Here
I expect to get some coordinates, an object with a latitude and longitude or a lat and lng key
and then we will use the same Google API to get the address because this Google API works in both directions.
We can also do a reverse look up and pass in coordinates and get back an address and that's exactly
what I want to do here.
So we can copy this link here actually
and then in here just set up a fetch request, again with a template literal so that we can conveniently
inject information into this string and we need to replace your API key here with the Google API key
constant we created and then the latitude here up to the comma, excluding the comma with something and
the longitude after the comma up to the key here.
Now for the latitude, I want to enter coords.lat, coords should be an object with a lat property
and coords.lng so that we forward this information into the string and set up a correct
URL.
Since we use async, we can again await this and store our response here and now I'll just copy this check
I'm performing down there because I need the same check here and that should be response and here I'll
just say failed to fetch address and therefore after these if checks, I know that this worked and we should
have an address.
Now how do we get the address?
If we have a look at this example response, we see it's an object, again with a results key which is an array
and the first element in the array has this formatted address field which is exactly what I need. So here,
we can get the address by accessing data.results, the first result, .formatted_address
and that's then what I will return here and simple use async await, this is in the end what is invisibly
created promise will resolve to.
So now we can call get address from coords in share place here when we locate the user. So here before
I call select place, I will get the address here by awaiting and for that to work, we need to add async
in front of locate user handler, so by awaiting the call to get address from coords which we need to
import from the location file so that down there, we can call get address from coords and forward the
coordinates object we are constructing here and I actually only want to hide my modal after that is
done as well. So now I got the address here as well and now I will forward the address here to select place,
also in our other method, in the find address handler, select place should here not only get the coordinates
but also the address which we have here as well, here the user entered it and I'm doing this so that
select place now accepts both arguments here and we can now set up a shareable link which will lead
us to that second HTML file in the end, where we display the address and the map with the coordinates.
So now here, let's work on select place. In select place, I don't just want to render the map but also
create this shareable link and output the shareable link here in this input so that when we click the
share place button, we do actually copy it into the clipboard.
So with that, let's go back to the SharePlace.js file and in there, let's get access to the share button,
that's the first step.
So here I need the share button and I can now get access to it with document and then this share button
does have an ID, share button so we can get access with document get element by ID share button here,
just like this.
Now actually, I want to set this up in the constructor though where we also get access to the other
buttons and so on but I will store it in a property, not in a constant, still here I want to add a listener,
an event listener, a click listener and we'll hook this up to a method in a second.
So for now we just get access to the share button here, we can then use this in select place because initially
this button should be disabled and it is because I set the disabled attribute here. So in SharePlace.js
now that we got an address, I will set this share button disabled to false to enable it, so to set
this disabled property to false. Now I want to get access to that share link input so to this input element
here next to the button
and this has an ID of share link so we can select it by this ID, by using document get element by
ID, share link and on this share link input element here, maybe name it element at the end,
I want to set the value to a link which I now want to construct.
I'll do this as a template literal so that we can build this in a more powerful way, in an easier way
which makes it easy to build a string with dynamic values
and there I want to start with the current server address and we can get this by accessing the location
object you learned about earlier in the course and there, the origin property,
this gives us our current domain,
so in our case here localhost:8080. Thereafter I want to add a slash
and then for example my-place and this can't be anything,
this should be the name of the subfolder so that in the end when we then later visit this link, we load
that index.html file in that sub folder, so my-place and then add a so-called query parameter
with a question mark,
so that's basically some extra data we can add in the URL which we then can read from that
URL in that other page we'll be loading later
and there I want to set an address key equal to
and now basically set this to the address I'm getting here
but again encoded to work in a URL which we can do dynamically with encodeURI
as you learned, URI
capital R and I, pass in the address here and then after this add an ampersand symbol to add another
optional query parameter to the URL which should be lat which I set equal to coordinates.lat
and then again &lng set equal to coordinates.lng.
So with that, I basically encode all that data into this URL which I construct here.
Now with that, let's save that and see it in action and I'm getting an error that I can't use await
outside of an async function,
so where are we using await?
Well my bad, of course locate user handler, that being marked as async doesn't help us because await
is not directly part of locate user handler, it's part of this anonymous function,
so this anonymous function needs to be marked as async. I think that's a good mistake to happen actually
because it makes it really clear that the direct function in which you want to use await needs to
be marked with async, not some other function around it,
the function in which you directly use it,
so this function here needs the async keyword for await to work in it.
So now with that if we save that, I get an error regarding the event listener, that makes sense,
let's comment it out for the moment here in the constructor of place finder and now with that if we save
that, if I get my location for example, you see now this URL is constructed here and we can click
share place which for the moment won't do anything because that's the next thing, I want to make sure
that when we click share place, we copy this link into the clipboard.