So now before we dive into the next module where
NOTE Confidence: 0.9216
we dive right into the language.
Let me dive a bit deeper into the history.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9219
Of JavaScript and where it's coming from and there.
Let's also have a look at that comparison between JavaScript.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9092
Java again. Now Java and JavaScript are 2 totally independent
programming languages.
NOTE Confidence: 0.938
That's really important, they have a totally different syntax different
principles.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9382
They have almost nothing in common besides the name I
would say,
NOTE Confidence: 0.9382
although JavaScript runs in the browser and.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9094
As learned all zinnober environments.
Java does not run in the browser.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9094
You can use it on the server side.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9135
To render HTML dynamically there and send it back to
users you can also use it in a non web
NOTE Confidence: 0.9135
development context.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9381
But it is not supported directly in the browser.
You can't use it for the same things as you
NOTE Confidence: 0.9381
can use JavaScript.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9143
You also as I mentioned have different principles,
Java for example, is strictly object oriented and strongly typed
NOTE Confidence: 0.9143
there.
You need to define which kind of data you're about
NOTE Confidence: 0.9143
to store in a data container.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9058
Where is JavaScript is really flexibel you don't have to
work with objects only there and will dive into object?
NOTE Confidence: 0.8446
Orientation and what that means for out the course no
worries.
NOTE Confidence: 0.8598
And it's also weakly typed as you learn.
NOTE Confidence: 0.8647
Now JavaScript was named JavaScript to Yeah,
Well, you sound cool. You could say Becausw Java was
NOTE Confidence: 0.8647
a big thing and.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9207
JavaScript kind of was inspired by it,
but it's totally different than in the end and well.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9051
People just wanted to. Have other people use JavaScript I
guess.
NOTE Confidence: 0.8998
Java does not run the browser answer mentioned,
though, that's really important to keep in mind,
NOTE Confidence: 0.9275
JavaScript does. And speaking about that differentiation between client side
and server side JavaScript clientside means in the browser server
NOTE Confidence: 0.9275
side with the help of node JS means.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9278
On a machine that is connected to the Internet,
which might be serving webpages,
NOTE Confidence: 0.9278
but which doesn't run code.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9145
Directly on the machines of the end users and the
client side part is really the origin of JavaScript.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9269
And as you learn different browser vendors so different companies
developing browsers provide their own JavaScript execution engines for example,
NOTE Confidence: 0.8784
DV8. Engin that's the name of the JavaScript engine Chrome
users.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9482
And the important thing there is that in the browser.
You are able to interact with the web page.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9273
From inside JavaScript you can manipulate the loaded web page.
You can also use certain browser features so called.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9112
APIs for example, to get the user location on the
server side.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9112
The idea was to well,
extract the engine out of the browser.
NOTE Confidence: 0.913
And allow you to run it outside of the browser.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9193
So that you can reuse your JavaScript knowledge,
but now use JavaScript for different tasks.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9006
And you can now run JavaScript anywhere with no chance
for example,
NOTE Confidence: 0.9006
in a server side and there,
you have special our features.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9066
Our APIs you can tap in for example,
to work with the file system or handle incoming HTTP
NOTE Confidence: 0.9066
requests.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9138
Now the syntax concepts, and core features are exactly the
same,
NOTE Confidence: 0.9138
though there for what you learn in this course.
NOTE Confidence: 0.8965
Where we primarily focus on the browser side since simply
also easier and more visual to use?
NOTE Confidence: 0.9081
Are the same would you learn in the browser applies
to node JS in our environments as well as you
NOTE Confidence: 0.9081
will also see?
NOTE Confidence: 0.8976
In the node JS section so that's why we start
with the browser side.
NOTE Confidence: 0.8976
It's JavaScript origene. There are no alternatives to JavaScript.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9372
Browser so you might not be interested in using JavaScript
on a server if you are interested in front end.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9156
Browser side web development, though you have to learn JavaScript
cause that is the only programming language,
NOTE Confidence: 0.9156
you can use there in the end.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9091
You can then transfer your knowledge becaus node JS uses
the same syntax so you easily learn node JS after
NOTE Confidence: 0.9091
learning JavaScript in general.
NOTE Confidence: 0.9257
Or in the browser. And it's more fun to learn
JavaScript if you see something on the page.