Now what if you don't remember the exact name of something and you still want to learn more about it?
Well let's say we don't know that it's called parseInt,
then googling this correctly would be that you type Javascript, to kind of narrow down what you're interested
in,
in this case the Javascript language and then convert string to number
and if we do that, then here automatically even Google gives us a hint that parseInt probably is helpful
but we also find more. If we scroll down here, we got parseInt already,
we also will find something on Stack Overflow which is the kind of official development forum where
you find a lot of discussions.
You can also ask questions on your own here
but many problems have already been solved and can be found here
and therefore you can find solutions here by just googling correctly.
Here you find one suggestion with this number thing which we haven't seen
but then here you also find parseInt again or this plus operator which already showed you in this
course as well.
So that's really helpful and this is what I mean with Googling correctly, first put Javascript so that
Google only shows you results that are kind of related to that and then try to describe the problem
you're having with only a couple of keywords. Don't write sentences here which you would speak
to another human but instead use keywords, important keywords that narrow down your issue and this
normally helps you find discussions where that problem has been discussed or it give you a link to MDN
or comparable sites right away.
So this is also how you should think about solving problems here and about finding help.