When you work with classes in Javascript, you have these properties and methods and fields which you
already learned about which are all instance properties thus far,
well turns out you also have something called static properties and methods.
Now let's have a look at what the difference between static properties and fields and methods and instance
field property and methods is. Now static properties and methods are defined with the static keyword
in front of them.
The difference to the instance properties is that the static properties and methods are only accessible
on the class itself, so you don't need to instantiate the class,
you don't need to use the new keyword to create an object based on that class
and we typically use this on helper classes or for some global configuration, etc. And instance properties
and so on are instead defined without the static keyword,
that's what we did thus far in this module
and they're only accessible on the instances based on that class.
So we use that for all the core reusable logic, for example in our code
thus far, we only work with instances,
we always use all these classes by using new because we need different product items which have the
same structure but hold different data, with static properties and static methods,
we have a class which is not instantiated and which therefore always works on the same data for example
but that's exactly what we can utilize here.
Here we could add a new class, maybe name it app because it holds our overall app, which is created like
a regular class,
nothing special there but in here, I add a new method, init where I now add the static keyword in front
of it and that's new.
Now we can move that code here for example into init, we can execute any code in there,
just be aware that if you would use this in here, you would always refer to the class itself not to an
object instance based on the class
and now you therefore also don't create a new app like that or at least you could do that
but to call init, you don't do it, instead you can just call app referring to the class itself like this,
.init like this
and this will execute this init method directly on the class itself.
Now again, we therefore have no app object we work with,
instead we directly operate on that class and hence this will work
but it's a different approach.
Now the advantage can be seen if we now solve our cart problem. Remember that on this cart here,
we got this add product method in the end,
this accepts a product and then should update the rendered cart.
Well what we can do now is for example on the shop which we initialize an app, we can store this reference
to the cart object in a property,
so this cart is equal to shopping cart.
So now this is a property of shop, with this cart
of course that means that here where I refer to cart, I also have to use this cart and the advantage of
this is that we can now go to our app class here and in init, we get access to that shop right and that
shop is in the end an object based on the shop class which holds this cart property, right?
So here we can also add a cart property by referring to that cart property on shop, like that.
Now if we save that and we reload,
this should still work.
Now why am I doing that though?
Because now here in app, I can also add another static method, add item or add product to cart,
expect my product here and now refer to this cart and call add product on that because this cart,
don't forget, refers to an instance based on our shopping cart
class and there we have that add product method and then call add product there and forward that product.
So we kind of use this app class and the static method as a proxy because and that's the advantage and
the whole idea of using these static methods, since we always operate on the class and not on instances,
we don't work on different objects which we would do if we would not use static and instead create different
apps in different places of the app
but instead the app I'm using here to init my app, this class is the same I can now call from inside
product item.
So here in add to cart, we can get rid of that instead just call app add product to cart, this product,
referring to the product stored in this product item.
So here I am utilizing static methods and the fact that we're not working on objects based on classes
but on the class itself to share some data, share the cart instance for example.
Now of course that's not the only way of solving this,
you would be able to find other approaches too but it's a nice case for static methods in this case.
Now important here I'm calling add product to cart on app and I'm forwarding this product, referring to
my product in product item. Now
here however, we'll have a problem. If I save the code like this and reload and click add to cart, we'll get
an error, cannot read property add product of undefined. So it can't find an add product method on cart
because here, I'm trying to store cart which I get from shop cart before calling render,
if you watch closely, you see that it's in render where I create the cart.
So this won't work in this order,
instead we have to swap that and first render and then we got access to the cart.
So now if we save that and we reload, it will still not work because I made a mistake earlier as I recognized,
here in shopping cart where I assign a new value,
that of course shouldn't be total output equal, it should be innerHTML equal because I want to
update the HTML content in there, not the value stored in total output.
And with that, if we reload,
now you see that changed to 1,
still not the real value because we haven't added the logic for that yet but at least we see a change
so that works and now we connect it to classes with the help of static methods.
Now one side note, it's optional but still I would say it's a good practice,
you can also add a static field here to the app class which is named cart
so that we make it clear that we have these static cart property.
We refer to it here with this cart and if you use this in a static method, it always refers to the
class itself, doesn't try to refer to an object based on the class, so it adds a static property implicitly
and accesses this static property and implicitly therefore
but still this makes it clear hat we expect to have that static property, not needed technically but
I think it improves readability and as a side effect, it also allows me to show you how a static method
or property would look like.
Of course you can also initialize this to some value if you need one,
here we don't need that and therefore the code is good like this.