That was it for functions here,
now you really are a function expert.
You know about its scope or the lexical environment as we called it in this module, you learned about
factory functions, you learned about pure impure functions, about side effects and you also learned about
recursion which is a powerful tool
every developer needs to know, not just Javascript developers and with all of that,
there is little more that you could need to know about functions, Javascript functions as you can probably
tell by now are a powerful tool, many things you can do with them.
Now don't worry, you don't always need to do everything with them, it's just good to be aware of the different
capabilities and different functionalities
and with that, you're well-prepared for any kind of application you could dive into or you might want
to write because you now know how functions behave, how they work internally and if you ever encounter
some tricky behavior of a function,
well you might want to recall what you learned here, for example regarding how they work with scopes
or regarding recursion where a function can call itself.