So it's time for the search logic then because adding movies works and I'll not work on making them deletable
here, not really the focus of this module but instead let's make sure that we can enter some term
here, something like that complete for example and then we can click search and we would find this
but if I had another movie which doesn't include complete in the name, I wouldn't find this.
So to achieve that, we need a new function here which I'll name search movie handler because it will
be connected to an event listener and this function here in the end, I want to read whatever the user
entered here and then also trigger the render movies function
but then I want to tell that function here that it should not render all movies but only filtered
movies,
so step-by-step. Let's first of all read the user input and if we have a look at the index.html file,
we can see that it's this input here with that ID
that's interesting to us,
that is where the user will enter the search term.
So here I can get my my filter term or however you want to name it with document get element by ID
with that ID and then .value here, just like that. Now that I know this, I want to call render
movies and forward that filter term.
Now of course render movies doesn't do anything with that yet but that will soon change, for the moment,
let's connect the search button here with add event listener, a click listener and then point at the
search movie handler here,
so at this function we just added. Now render movies now needs to accept that filter term but not always
because here, I don't forward it,
only when the search button is clicked and thankfully we learned how we can enable this or how we can
implement this, on render movies we can work with a default argument. So I can add an arguments here, maybe
named filter, however you want to name it and assign a default value, maybe an empty string.
That means that by default, this will be an empty string if we don't pass any more specific value,
then we can go to that part where we clear the innerHTML
and now I want to tweak the movies through which I go here.
That shouldn't always be all movies,
instead I want to have my filtered movies here.
So I'll add a new constant, filtered movies
and now that will either be all movies if filter is falsy,
if it's an empty string or any other falsy value or it will be my filtered movies if filter is string
other than an empty string.
So we can check filter,
so this parameter here, if it's not true-ish,
so if it's not truthy, if it's falsy, then if it's falsy I want to use all movies because then we
have an empty string or anything like that
and I want to use all movies because no filter was set in that case basically,
otherwise finishing this ternary expression here,
otherwise I want to use movies.filter and you learned about the filter method in the arrays and
iterables module. Filter takes a function which executes on every element in the array, so I can pass
it in as an argument to this arrow function in
this case, doesn't have to be an arrow function but it allows us to write a really short function here
and I don't care about any other arguments
this function would get, instead I just want to check if the movie I'm currently looking at,
if that movie which will be a string, if that includes and there is an includes function on strings,
if that includes a certain value
and here I want to check if it includes my filter term here.
Now let me reformat that and with that, we're filtering all movies for only movies where the movie includes
the filter term,
however of course looking at the entire movie does not make sense,
I should look at movie.info.title and check if the title of the movie includes the filter term,
that's what I want to check.
So if my movie,
if the title there in the info object, if that includes my filter, then I will add it to movies,
otherwise I will not,
if no filter is set, well then I always use all movies
and now we can use that filtered movies constant here to go through it
here with ForEach because that will now be the movies that respect my filter I might have set.
Now let's give it a try,
let's save it and reload and quickly add Javascript here,
level 5 maybe and then something else,
maybe
new courses ahead,
level 10 or any other key-value pair there
and now let's search.
if I search like that, nothing happens,
if I now enter Java here, you see only Javascript is shown, if I enter new here you see only new courses
ahead is shown,
if I search for level nothing is shown because that's not part of the title
and if I clear that, again everything is shown.
If I just search for s, new courses is shown because it's a lowercase s and Javascript only has an uppercase
s here,
if I search for a, both is shown because we have a lowercase a in both.
So that's how this,
of course basic but nonetheless, how this search works and how we can enable it with our Javascript knowledge
here and even bring some array magic to this example.