So let's make sure that the text that shows up on our tooltip can be set from outside.
And for that we will use an attribute.
Now attributes are not something that is exclusive to your web components or your custom elements.
Attributes exist on a lot of built in age HTML elements.
Take a link for example here the ref thing here.
That is an attribute and it allows you to configure this element so you link here in a declarative way
which means you don't have to write any code no javascript code to set the target of this link.
And we want to use the same approach for our own tooltip.
For example it would make sense that on our U.S. tooltip tag here we can use a text attribute or tooltip
text attribute or whatever you want to name it.
I will name it just text and here web components is a set of standards.
For example this could be the text I want to display when I hover over this U.S. tooltip element for
the second one.
I won't set a text attribute.
So here we maybe want to have a default value.
How do we now use that attribute from inside our tooltip.
Well it's actually pretty simple inside of our constructor.
We can initialize a new private variable and I will name it tooltip text.
Now there I will call get attribute and now entered the name of that tribute for which you want to extract
the value.
And in my case that is text because I chose text as the attribute name here.
So now we save whatever we stored as text we're asked to text attribute value we save Dad intuitive
tooltip text and we can now use that down there where we save where we set up some text to be displayed.
So here instead of this hard coded text I will set this tooltip text as a value now with that if we
save this we can go back and reload this page.
And now if you hover over it at we don't see anything there right.
Well the reason for Dad is that here we're initializing it in the constructor but as you learned the
custom element has been created at this point but it has not been mounted to the dorm yet.
This will only have happened inside of the connected callback.
So we should move this line into our connected callback so that we can safely access this dorm though
its attributes.
Because at this point of time it will have been rendered into the dorm.
And now if we save that and we reload this page we see web components as a set of standard now for the
second question mark.
We don't see anything because we have no default value there.
Now to make sure we have a solution for both cases I will actually go back into the constructor and
set the tool to text here to some dummy tool to text maybe something that makes a little bit more sense
than that.
And here I only want to overwrite it when we have that attribute for it is I'll add a check where I
see if this has attribute text.
So only if we have that attribute being set I will extract dead attribute and store its text in a tooltip
text.
Otherwise this will not be overwritten and we'll be using our dummy text.
So now we have the basic initialization which does not access to Dom in the constructor and then we
do access to Dom and overwrite the default value with a more specific value if we have the text attribute
being set in the connect that callback and now we can reload this page once again we see web components
as a set of standards forward a first tooltip for an a second we see our dummy tool to text.
Now this is how we can work with attributes.
Now there is a special thing when we then later change attribute values and you will also learn that
there is another way of setting something like this then through the attributes but that is something
we'll come back later for now we have dead.
Let me now show you how you can add some styling to this component because that obviously is missing.