Now before we move on to more exciting features about classes and how we can improve that code here,
let's first of all dive into another nice thing you can add to classes where you already learned about
when we talked about objects and that would be getters and setters, you can add them to classes as well
and the shopping cart here is a perfect scenario.
There, I am editing my items and I then want to update my but my output here in the end, right? Now we
could use getters and setters as an elegant solution for that,
we could add a getter, maybe name it total amount like this and we do this with the get keyword as you
learned in the objects module, then any name of your choice
and then like a method, like this method shorthand and in there. you have to return a value in the end.
Now the value I want to return here is the cart total and for that, we can use a technique we learned about
in the arrays module where we simply reduce our list of cart items to a single number.
Now since we in the end just store products and items here, every product has a price property so we
want to reduce that.
So here we can calculate a sum with this items reduce, items is an array so we can call reduce on it
and as you learned, reduce takes two arguments - a function
and here I use an anonymous arrow function and then an optional second argument which is our initial
value and there I'll start with zero.
Now that function which we pass in is a first argument itself also receives multiple arguments and
there are two important arguments which I want to accept here,
that's the previous value
and the current item,  you can name the parameters here however you want. Inside of the function,
I then want to return previous value, for the first run this will be zero,
thereafter it will be the value returned by reduce plus current item which will refer to an element in the
items array and therefore that's a product, .price because we'll have a price property on every
item and items. If the array is empty initially,
then this will automatically return the initial value which is zero.
So that's my reduction logic,
we can even shorten this now as you learned, remove the curly brace and the return statement,
remove the closing curly brace and also remove the semicolon here and then reformat that, remove
that extra comma
and now we have the reduce function with the arrow function here and the initial value.
Now it's the sum which I want to return here and here in my template literal, I therefore want to refer to
this total amount when we add a product
but actually I even want to change that logic and that's now totally optional,
I'm doing it so that I can also show you setters.
I'll add a setter and I'll name it cart items,
it will get a value and we create it with the set keyword and in here, I want to set this items equal to
value because I expect value to be an array of cart items,
so I override the existing array with a new one.
Now I also then want to run this logic here, so I'll move it out of add product and move it into the
setter so that when ever we set new cart items, I actually recalculate the total amount and update the
HTML code, so that this happens as part of the setter here.
Now in add product, I'll then just create a new constant, updated items which is a copy of this items using
that copy trick with the spread operator in a new array so that I have a real copy of that items array
and I then add that new product to that copied array and then set this cart
items, referring to the setter equal to updated items and this will trigger the setter, pass updated items
as a value to it and then therefore update the code like this.
Now we could have kept the old logic but this allows me to also show you as setters and getters in
classes which you can add just like that,
basically as you would have added them to normal objects. You can add them to the blueprints which will
be used to create objects like this
and then this logic will be added to the actual objects that are created when you instantiate this class
with the new keyword. Now with that if we reload here, you see this works, if I can now click Add to Cart,
this indeed updates with every click on the item,
also if I click on the carpet, then you see this makes much bigger jumps because the carpet is more
expensive.
Now a tiny adjustment I want to make at this point, I also want to call toFixed 2 here,
this is something we haven't really used before,
this will prevent this strange output
because of this floating point imprecision to which I'll come back in a separate module, we would
get output with a lot of decimal places,
this basically tells Javascript to always output a string,
convert this number to a string which only displays two decimal places,
that's what toFixed on total amount which is a number does.
That's just something I do add here to make sure that we always output this in the right way so to say.
So that's now the logic
added to the shopping cart and with that, the classes don't look that bad,
there is more we can do with them though.