So we got started with HttpRequests, with this XMLHttpRequest object. By the way you might be wondering
where the name is coming from,
in the parsed, actually quite some time ago, this was basically introduced so we could fetch XML data behind
the scenes.
Nowadays of course it's more common to use JSON data,
the name however still is the same. Now
there is more you can do with it, more you can configure and you can dive deeper into XMLHttpRequest
as you can actually dive deeper into almost all things you can do work with in Javascript. Attached
you therefore find some resources that do allow you to dive deeper
in case you're interested, now however I want to have a look at a more modern alternative which was added
to browsers a few years ago and which actually is not supported in all browsers, especially older browsers,
Internet Explorer
don't support that new API which you can use and that new API I'm talking about is the fetch API.
Now to use it, let me comment out all of that here inside of my promise construction function so to say,
let's keep the promise itself however,
so all the XMLHttpRequests logic in there is commented out and let's instead use the new API which
we have for sending HttpRequests.
It was invented to be more modern, to be less clunky with these strange event handlers there which is
really not modern Javascript at all,
that's why this new API was introduced and that new API is commonly called the fetch API.
Now it is called such because it all works around one key function, the fetch function and this is built
into browsers, it's exposed in Javascript just like that,
you don't have to call it as a method on any object or anything like that,
it's a globally available function in modern Javascript,
as I said not in old browsers though, more on browser support in the browser support module of
this course.
So how do you use fetch?
In its simplest form, fetch just takes a URL, so we can pass URL which should be a string to fetch,
then it will send a get request.
So if you just pass a URL to fetch, it will send a get request to that URL. Now fetch by default
is promise based,
so that's the first native promise API we see in this course.
We don't have to promisify ourselves,
it uses promises on its own.
That means we can actually remove our promise wrapper here,
we don't need to build our own promise, instead
we can just return the result of fetch which as I just said is a promise. So we can fetch URL and
then return the result which is a promise that helps us work with the response.
Now let's see how that works before we then fine tune it for the different kinds of requests and let's
get started with fetching posts where I call send HttpRequest and therefore, we try to send a request
to this URL which we should now fix by the way with the help of the fetch API.
Now if we try that and we reload and I click fetch posts, you'll see that I actually get an error, I get
this alert here.
Now this can be a bit deceiving, to see the actual problem,
let's temporarily remove try catch here in fetch posts so that we don't try this block and catch any
errors,
like that and let's try again.
Let's reload and click fetch posts and now we see, I get this strange error, list of posts is not ignorable.
OK, so what's going on here? What's failing?
Somehow we don't have list of posts, so somehow we don't get the response data when we called sendHttpRequest.
Now in send HttpRequest
however, in this function, I do return the result of fetch, sending a request to that URL.
Well let's check the network tab, there we see posts were indeed fetched,
so that seems to work,
so what's wrong then? What's happening?
Well the problem is or one difference is unlike our XMLHttpRequest approach here, fetch does not give
us the parsed response as we had it available here with xhr.response but instead, it gives us a streamed
response, which means basically that the response object we get here does not hold the body,
the response body in a way that would be ready to be used, instead what you would have to do and
we can do that here inside of the sendHttpRequest function, instead here, you get your response object
and there you have access to a response
JSON method and you can return the result of this because that actually yields a new promise as you
see. Now JSON,
when you call it on the response object which the fetch API gives you will parse the body of the response
and transform it from JSON to Javascript objects and arrays but it actually does not just parse that,
so it's not just a replacement for JSON.parse,
it also turns the streamed response body which you have in the response object into a snapshot
so to say with which you can work.
So long story short, you need to call response.JSON to convert your response body, the streamed
unparsed response body into a snapshot parsed body.
So now with that, the overall sendHttpRequest method will yield a promise which will eventually return
that parsed response data, response JSON is important for that. Besides response
JSON, you also have response text for example to return plain text,
so that will then just do the conversion from streamed to snapshot or response blob if you would be downloading
a file, that would give you access to the file.
Here however, we got JSON data so we need to return that.
So now with that, if we save that and we reload and I click fetch posts, now we render the posts again,
so now the other logic works
as before and just as before, we get the parsed data, the parsed response
but here important we need that extra step because it's not just JSON's data but also streamed data
which we need to turn into a snapshot
so to say and all of that is done by that JSON method on the response object.
Okay,
so we get that, we can get our posts,
now let's make sure we can also create a new post.