So it's time for our first if statement. We want to find out if after an attack, we won.
So here in the attack handler, we could add an if statement with the if keyword and check if the current monster
health, after we deducted the damage from it of course, if that is smaller or smaller or equal to zero
because I also want to check for equality because the monster is that not only if its health is below
zero but also if it's equal to zero. If that is the case, then we know that we won,
so in this case we could throw an alert when we say you won.
So this code here will only execute if this condition here is met and this condition is only met if the
current monster health is below zero or equal to zero.
So with that if we now reload this and we launch a couple of attacks against the monster's, span this button
until the health bar is below zero, we get this one.
Now please note, this message is output before the health bar updates simply due to the way Javascript
works here,
it blocks the UI update until we dismiss this dialog here
but the general logic works and if we dismiss it, we also see the health go down.
So this works and this is our first basic if check in action.
Now of course, it's a bit boring if we can attack the monster but the monster is not able to fight back.
So what we actually want here is to adjust the logic to let the monster fight back.
To do that, after we hit the monster, the monster should immediately lash back at us,
so it automatically hit us after we hit it.
Now for that, in vendor.js, we got the deal player damage function.
It works basically like a deal monster damage function,
it takes some damage, then calculates a random damage which is actually dealt, adjusts the player health
bar in the UI and returns the dealt damage.
So in app.js, I can take advantage of this, for that we just need to define what's the maximum damage
of the monster
and here I'll add a constant, monster attack value, again hardcoded into here and I will let the monster
hit me back with let's say a maximum damage of 14,
so more than we can hit it for
which means that right now, we will need a lot of luck in order to win because these are maximum damages
and the monster has an edge there.
Of course the game will evolve throughout this module and we'll also make the other buttons work which
will give us an edge again.
So let's take that monster attack value here to let the monster deal some damage to us
and for this, I will get my monster damage let's say or player damage depending on how you see it,
it's the damage dealt to the players, so maybe player damage makes more sense
and for that I will called deal player damage here, forward the monster attack value and then reduce the
currentPlayerHealth by that amount, again by simply deducting player damage with the minus equal operator.
Now here, we want to check if the player won,
so if the current monster health is smaller or equal than zero or if the monster won.
Now you might think that we simply add an else block, right? Because if we haven't won, if the monster health
is not below zero, then we lost
but that would actually be wrong,
keep in mind that the attack handler is executed for every click on the button,
so we run this check here for every button click and on most clicks, especially when the game just started,
neither party won.
So we don't want to let the player lose in the else case because if you do that, if we say you lost here,
you will see that if we reload here, right after the first attack, we get the you lost message which makes
sense because we run this check on every button click,
now after the first attack, we certainly didn't win so this condition is not met,
hence we make it into the else block and we lost,
so else is not right for this scenario,
instead I want to check else if, so if we haven't won, if maybe the monster won.
So here I'll check if the currentPlayerHealth is smaller or equal than zero.
Now of course you could argue about this logic because what I do at the moment is, I let the player hit
the monster and then the monster immediately hits back and only thereafter I check if the player won
which means the monster already dealt damage to us
and still, even if that damage took us below zero, we will have won if we also took the monster below
zero,
if we also reduced the monster's health below zero, which means the monster's damage basically is irrelevant
if we also took the monster's health below zero and of course you could argue about that.
Maybe you instead want to check if the player won here after the player dealt damage and therefore
don't give the monster a chance of dealing damage to us if we won or you just don't care, you always execute
both and then you give the player the advantage of checking the monster health first and therefore the
player wins even if the player's health also is below zero because the monster's health is below zero
after this attack.
So a lot of talking about how you look at this, from a technical perspective it's way easier,
we check if this condition is met,
so if the monster health is below zero.
If that is the case, we won,
if that's not the case, we check if maybe the monster won,
so if the current player's health is below zero and if neither of the two is the case, then nothing happens
in this if statement,
neither of these two code lines is executed, so neither the you won alert nor the you lost alert is shown
and instead we just finish the function execution and we're done and that will be the case for most
clicks, for most executions, especially at the start of the game.
So with that, if we now save this and we reload, let's attack and you see the monster is hitting us real
hard here,
we had a couple of weak hits and therefore we're probably going to lose,
so let's see what the end result is
and yes, we get the you lost message here
once our health dropped below zero, so the else if check is also working here. Now to fine tune this a
bit more,
we could of course say yes we really want to tweak this and we shouldn't be able to win if our health
is also below zero, instead it should be a draw
if both health values are below zero.
So here, we could say we won if the monster health is smaller or equal than zero
and, now with the and operator, the currentPlayerHealth actually is above zero,
so greater than zero, not greater or equal
because if it's equal we lost
but greater. So we can only win if our, the player's health, still is above zero
and the same for the monster, the monster only wins if our, the player's health, is below zero and the monster
health on the other hand is above zero
and that of course means that if both health values are below zero, it's a draw.
So we could add else alert you have a draw but of course, that again would be wrong because if we do
that, keep in mind attack handler executes for every click,
so this else case will basically execute whenever neither of the two conditions is met and that most
of the time will be the case.
So now again we have the same case as before, on the first click
we get that
you have a draw message because else again for this scenario, not always but for this scenario is wrong,
instead here I want to check else if the currentPlayerHealth is smaller than zero, smaller or equal
than zero
and the current monster health also is smaller or equal than zero, only in that case we have a draw. Now
to simulate that,
let's start with the max life of five where we have a realistic chance or a more realistic chance of
actually launching an attack that takes us both below zero and let's have a look at this.
If I now click attack,
yes
right away I have a draw,
you might have to test this a bit more often because since the damage is calculated randomly, you can certainly
have situations where you hit the monster for two and the monster hits you for six and therefore you lose
but after clicking this a couple of times, you should get that
you have a draw message here.
So with that, let me take it back to 100,
with that we now have logic that works correctly,
let's also check for a regular win or loss,
yes we lost here.
And with that, we got our basic if statement with if, else if and different logical operators as well
as the and operator to also combine multiple conditions,
so already quite a lot of the things you learned about in the past lectures are getting applied in this
first crucial element of our game.