We also have another nice feature in Javascript which we don't really need in this app but which we
will need in general from time to time in Javascript
and that's the spread operator in combination with objects.
Now we saw the spread operator in combination with arrays but we can also use it in combination with
objects and I will actually show this here in the console because there isn't really a great place to
apply it in this dummy project.
So let's say here we have an object, good old person and that person has a name, Max and maybe has some
hobbies which is an array where I have sports and cooking, close the array, close the object and we're
done,
so that's my person here.
Now if we want to copy that, for example into a new person, so another person here, then we can try it
like this but as you learned, objects are reference values
so if I now set person.age equal to 30 and I add this new property, another person will also have have it
because it points at the very same property in memory.
Now we can avoid this if we want to by using the spread operator. For that if I create yet another
constant, person2, however you want to name it, you can create a new object with curly braces and then
use the three dots just as you do it on arrays and then add that other object you want to spread into
this object.
What this does is it takes all key-value pairs of that object you pass after the spread operator and
merge these key-value pairs into this object.
So it creates a new object but copies over the values you have in the keys of the old object and not
only values but also the key names. If you do that and I set person.age to 31, you will see that person2
still has that age of 30 and didn't get that new value because now we created a copy.
Now beware,
just as with the arrays example earlier in the course, if you have other reference values inside of your
object, like the hobbies array, an array is an object and therefore is also a reference value,
then this will not be copied, instead
well it's of course kind of copied over into the new object but the object is not cloned, it's not copied,
it's still the same array object in memory.
So if I go to person.hobbies and I push a new hobby of coding, you will see that person2 also has
that on his hobbies if he expand this, here we also see coding now and that's just something which I
explained in the arrays section already.
This is normal, this is how reference values behave and the spread operator does not do a deep copy where
it goes through all level of nested reference values you might have in this object or array and then
copies it from scratch, instead it just copies the top level key-value pairs into a brand new object
and any nested reference values are kept,
the addresses there are kept, there are no hobbies created. If you would want to copy those as well, you
would have to do it manually by assigning a new hobbies array where you copy over the old array and that's
actually quite interesting to see so
let me show you how that would work.
We have person3 and again, I copy person let's say but I want to make sure that hobbies is actually overwritten
with a new array and we can not just use this technique if we want to overwrite another nested reference
value but whenever we want to overwrite a value. So let's say we also want to overwrite age, well then we
just add age here and set this to let's say 30 or 29
and what this will do is it will pull all key-value pairs from person, including age but since then you
again add age after this finished, the age that was pulled out of person will be overwritten with this
value and the same of course can be applied to hobbies. I set hobbies here to a new array and now we can
use a spread operator here in the array which you also learned and for example spread everything
we find in person.hobbies, so all the array elements in person.hobbies, into this new array and
therefore we now create a clone of that old array as well.
So now we create a brand new array here instead of copying the old array address and hence now we would
have a new object with a new array in there.
Now it's not a must do that you always do that if you have nested reference values, you don't always
need to copy everything,
it's just an option that you can do that if you then plan on changing hobbies for example on person
and you don't want that reflected on your copy persons, then you would have to use that approach, if you
don't plan on changing hobbies ever, then you of course don't need to create that deep copy because
ultimately, every operation costs a little bit of performance.
So if I now hit enter here and we have a look at person, we see there age is 31, hobbies is an array of
three items, person3 also has an array of three items but age is 29 because we overwrote it
here and if we then go to person and there, to hobbies and we pop off the last element, we see that
for person, now hobbies has two elements, for person3, we still have three elements in the array because
we did create a brand new array and copy over the old array values as well. So that can be a nice feature,
being able to use that spread operator on key-value pairs in objects as well,
perfect for creating copies and then as you see copies where you can still overwrite certain parts of
the things you copied.