Back in our project, there we could add a new class and I'll add it here above my other specialized classes
so to say which you can give any name you want and I'll name it component because in the end, this will
be a class I use to output different,
you could say, components, parts of my web page. Now such a component class will have a method which I'll
name createRootElement which receives three arguments - the tag of the element I want to create,
so I'll use that later to basically replace this line here, so I want to have the tag, I want to have
any CSS classes that should be added and any other attributes that might need to be added to that
element which is created here. Inside of createRootElement,
we can then create that root element here,
you can of course give that constant any name you want with documents create element and pass in that
tag,
then check if we have that CSS class constants set,
so if that is a truthy value, if CSS classes is a truthy value. If it is, then I'll go to the root
element and set the class name equal to CSS classes,
so I expect CSS classes to be a string of CSS classes that should be added,
else I'll do nothing so no need for an else block. After this if check,
I'll add another if check and see if attributes holds a truthy value so that's basically something
we can work with and also it's not just truthy
but also if it's an array with a length greater 0 because this should be an array and if both is true,
I'll go through my attributes here
with a for/of loop, you could of course also use a ForEach loop if you prefer that
and then on the root element, I will set an attribute with the set attribute method, where I expect to
have a couple of objects in this attributes array, where every object has a name property and also a
value property. To guarantee the structure, we can add a new class, an element attribute for example which
has a constructor where I get the attribute name and the attribute value
and then here I say this.name equal attribute name,
this.value equal attribute value, so we stored the data we got on the constructor in properties
of the class and then here, I essentially expect attributes to be an array full of objects created based
on that class so that we can set attributes on the root element. Well and then thereafter,
I also want to append that element to the DOM. For that
I need a place where we can add it
and for this I'll actually add a constructor to component, where I expect to get a render hook value
as a parameter and then store this in some property of component, so in a property for that component class
and this hook property holds the data passed into the constructor
and of course I'm just coming up with one possible way of implementing this,
you can definitely build this in a different way as well,
this is just one example,
let me really emphasize that.
So here once we created that root element, that HTML element with that given tag, I want to add it
to this hook, so to this element I got on the constructor and to be precise here I expect that hook should
not be the element itself but let's say the ID of that element, so maybe rename it to hook ID so
that down here, we can say document get element by ID for this hook ID, so for that ID we got here
in our constructor and then call append and append that root element here,
that's the idea here. Thereafter we can return this root element here.
So now we have this component,
how can we now use this? To inherit from this component class which I want to do on shopping cart, product
item and product list,
since these are all methods that render something, to inherit from that class, I go to for example the
shopping cart and there we now add a new keyword after the name of the class before we add the curly
braces that mark the class body and we write extends here.
That's the keyword, extends
and then we write the class from which we want to extend
and you can only extend from one class, so inheriting from multiple classes is not available in Javascript.
Some programming languages have it, most modern languages don't really have that, Javascript certainly
doesn't have it,
you can only inherit from one class.
Now what does this mean now?
It means that shopping cart now still creates normal objects
if we instantiate it but all these objects don't just have all the logic we defined in here but also
all the logic we defined in the base class,
so also the createRootElement method for example,
this is available in every object we create based on shopping cart.
The implication of that is that we can go to the render method now and instead of creating our cart element
like this, we can now refer to this createRootElement and my IDE even supports this here because this
here, when we call render in this class on an object created based on that class, this will refer to this
object and as I said, this object will hold everything or will have access to everything that's part
of the parent class as well, so createRootElement is accessible via this in the subclass. So I can
call createRootElement here, now as a tag I'll pass in section, as a class name I'll pass in cart and
therefore here we can get rid of this line and createRootElement of course returns an HTML element,
the element that was added to the DOM, so I'll still store this in cart el because I need it here and render
to define what exactly I want to do here. I can't move that code here into the base class because this
differs for every class, this here is specific to the cart, we don't need that on the shopping list. So
it's only that part where we create and append the element to the DOM
that can be outsourced and that is now part of a separate class.
The specific rendering for this cart item, that's still part of this cart class,
that's how this works.
So now with that, if we save that and we reload this page, we get an error,
now do you know why?
Well we get an error because we can't depend on null, so
we basically have a problem when it comes to appending the created element and that makes a lot of sense because
let's revisit createRootElement. There,
I need that hook ID to append my root element. Now hook
ID is set in the constructor of the component we inherit from and the question now of course is where
do we call that constructor?
When we call new cart here in the end, new shopping cart, we call the constructor of shopping cart.
So when does the constructor of this component we inherit from get called? Well when it comes to constructors,
there are a couple of rules,
if your subclass, so the class which extends another class, does not have a constructor,
the constructor of the parent class is automatically called.
The problem here just is
yes
this is getting called as I can prove if I just output something here, let's quickly add that and then
reload.
So this is getting called but of course render hook ID is not passed in because how would Javascript
know what to pass in there.
So it's getting called but without any values.
Now if you add a constructor, maybe below the getters and setters, to your subclass, so to the class which
is extending, then this constructor will be called and the parent class constructor will not be called,
so also not what I want. What I in the end want here is I want to call this constructor and from
there, call the parent constructor, so the constructor of the parent class which is the class we're extending
from and we can do this with another special keyword, the super keyword, execute it like a function and this
will call the constructor in the parent class and you want to do this in your own constructors if you're
a parent class also has a constructor that should be executed, which typically is the case if it has
a constructor.
Now one important note about super - when you add super to your constructor, make sure you're not relying
on any field in that super constructor method, that will become important later and also if you plan
on adding properties in your constructor with this something equals something else,
you have to do that after you called super and
you always have to call super, so the constructor of your parent class, of your base class first before
you start using this inside of your subclass constructor.
So now we can call super here and forward a value for that render hook ID,
so an ID which we find in the DOM. Now for that, here let me go down to shop where I also have a render
method and the ID where I want to add cart to for now is just app, right
because that's what I'm doing in shop here essentially, I get access to that render hook in my document
and then I append the cart element and so on.
So in the end here in shop, I no longer need cart element, so I can get rid of that line as well
and instead here to shopping cart, I want to forward app as a string, so that value of that ID here
which I want to use as a hook to render that item and then in shopping cart, in that class, I now expect
that render hook ID or however you want to call it as a value here on that constructor method and
then I simply forward that, so that value I'm getting here to the super, to the parent constructor so
that this constructor has access. And now as a side note, render here in my shopping cart
also no longer needs to return anything because I'm not interested in the cart element anymore, I don't
need it anywhere in the place where I call render.
So now with that if we save that and we reload, this looks a bit better but we get another error, cannot
set property innerHTML of undefined, this simply is an error here however because I'm returning this
root element in createRootElement, that's wrong, it's just root element, so that's simply an error I have
in my code. We're creating root element here and we're storing it in a constant, I should return that
constant, we're not storing it in any instance property here because we don't need to.
So with that fixed, if we now reload this, now that works and it behaves in the same way as before but now we're
taking advantage of this base class. Of course we're not there yet,
I now also want to adjust the other classes so that they extend from component as well.