To understand the shadow Dom let's understand how the normal dorm.
Also sometimes called the light dorm works for dad and your developer tools you can click on the elements
tab.
This is your dorm tree essentially.
You see that paragraph and then there you also see your custom component.
Now when you expand your custom component you also see that span that was added.
And when you hover over the question mark you see that this div gets added here too.
Now there is one important thing to note here.
The span with the question mark and that overlay div are all added to the normal to the light.
Dom here we are not using anything specially and we're not using the shadow dom.
So our custom component here in the end has a child which is this span with the question mark.
Now what would be nice is if in a normal in the light Dom we had our custom component and the span or
anything else like this overlay death which gets added is kind of hidden away behind debt and is not
added to the normal Dom because Dad would then mean that any styles we set up in a normal Dom would
not affect our nested custom component dom.
So basically are a custom component here should have its own DOM tree which is not mixed or which is
not kind of affected by the normal DOM tree.
And that would be the definition of the shadow Dom Our element should have its own Dom behind it.
Which kind of makes up what we see on the page but which is not directly connected to the real Dom which
is not affected by global styles and the other way around now we have a specification in the browser
that allows us to add such a functionality and we can unlock it in a very easy way in the constructor.
We simply call this attach shadow and there we pass a javascript object where we simply set the mode
to open and you can set it to closed and this simply defines whether you can access your shadow DOM
tree from outside this component or not.
Now closing is something you'll typically not do because even if it is closed there are ways to still
access it and it's simply not worth the effort.
After all you are already developer and if you don't want to access it from outside you simply don't
do it.
So we'll set it to open for all the rest of this course.
Now this element has its own shadow DOM tree attached to it.
We now just have to make sure that whenever we add new DOM elements with append child we don't append
them to our age shemale element which is still part of the light dom.
But to the shadow dom of that age html element and for dead when I call append child I will first of
all access the shadow root and that is now set since we set up a shadow Dom here in the constructor
so this will now access the shadow DOM tree and append to child to it which really this will not change
much but you will see does this will have a great impact.
And I do the same here where I append this tooltip container I access my shadow root and although of
course when I remove it I access my shadow root so I access the shadow Dom with that you can now save
that and if you now reload the page you will notice one important thing right away.
The text which was written between our opening and closing tax here so web components.
And here we go.
That text is gone now.
And the reason for it it can be seen when we expect our custom element here.
You see it now all of a sudden has a shadow root element which it didn't have before.
And there we see the shadow Dom.
Now conveniently we can see it here and developer tools.
But thanks to that shadow root this is now detached from the main Dom and we can prove that by hovering
over the question mark you see the orange border off the div is now gone even though we still have that
rule here we still have that styling rule.
But now with that shadow root being set up does this is gone now obviously as I just mentioned our text
between the opening and closing tag is also gone.
So we have to bring that back in to bring it back.
We'll use the other feature I mentioned templates.
Now what's up with templates.