So that's how we can go up and down the tree,
now what if I actually want to select the header based on a selection of the unordered list or even
of the list item?
Well if that's the case, li is already my last list item here because we have that here in our Javascript
code that we select this list item
and now when we want to reach out to the unordered list, that's of course easily doable by reaching out
to li parent element or parent node and I'll store the result in ul because that will be my unordered
list here as you can tell,
right.
So that's what I selected here with something you already knew
and I'm storing this reference to the DOM object which I in the end get here in my ul constant. Of course
that's the same as if I would have done query selector ul in this example here. In other examples
where you might have multiple unordered lists on the page, that might not be the same, you might be selecting
a totally different unordered list. Here in this example where we only have one, that would of course
be the same.
So we have the unordered list selected and now I want to get access to the header here.
Now the header is a sibling of the unordered list,
it's on the same level as unordered list.
It's not a parent or an ancestor
and it's also not a child or a descendant,
it's on the same level
and for that we can use the previous sibling or element sibling properties which are made available by
the browser. Now just as before with child nodes and so on, here previous sibling gives us the previous sibling
node
and in this case, that's actually a text node,
so that's this text node, this line break and excess whitespace we have in front of every item in the end.
Here if we have a look at the HTML code, in front of the unordered list, we have this excess whitespace
and this line break after header here,
so that's the nearest node we're selecting here with previous sibling.
Of course if I want to reach out to the header, I'm not interested in the nearest node, I'm not interested
in this text node which is basically between the header and the unordered list,
I want to get the nearest element node and I can do that with ul, let me clear that to make it easier
to read, ul previous elements sibling,
this gives us the nearest previous sibling element node, not any node but the nearest element node which
of course in this example here is the header and it also works in the other direction of course. If I
want to get the sibling after the unordered list, so the input here,
well then of course I can use my unordered list here and then we have next sibling to get the next sibling
node.
Again, that would be a text node because if we have a look here in our code maybe, after unordered list,
we have a line break, then some space,
so a couple of whitespaces here and then an input and therefore we have this text node. So if I'm
interested in the next sibling element node, then we would have to use next elements sibling
and this gives us access to the input which is the next element node in line here.
So this is how that works and how you can work with these different DOM traversal techniques,
this is always useful if you already selected some element in your document and you know the next operation
I want to do should be done to the next sibling or to the first child or something like this.
Using these traversal properties can simply be quicker, that always starting a new query with query selector
and so on and it's also not just faster for you as a developer, where you don't have to find a selection
criteria,
it's also faster for the browser because with query selector, if you use document query selector, it of
course has to go over all elements in your document and find matching ones,
that is still not super bad but it's certainly worse for performance than if you say ul next elements
sibling.
So if you have a possibility of reaching out to the element you want to select with this command, definitely
do it because this is then a quick and cheap way of getting access to that sibling element in this case.