So let's work on this
URL here or on this path
and here we now want to retrieve the data for a given ID
because the idea is that on the frontend, on my-place.js, we now no longer parse the coordinates and
the address from the URL params, instead on the query params,
we will of course find such a location key and that will hold the location ID which we want to look
up on our backend server.
So here, we get our locId by using query params get location,
that's the key name we use there
and then we want to send a fetch request here to http://localhost:3000 in this case,
/location,
that's the path we're setting up here on the backend,
so slash location and then here, I want to add this ID somehow to the URL. Now we could add
a query parameter but we actually can also add it as an extra path segment, we can add extra slash here
and then append locId.
Now we're sending a get request to this URL where the ID is actually part of the URL,
so this will be something like this URL and then some random ID thereafter. Now
then we'll get back some response
and just as before, we should return the parsed response, the JSON data, the parsed JSON data
and then we get the ultimate data in here in this second then block. It's then here where I want to create
my new loaded place with that extracted data and we'll have to see how we extract that as soon as
we know what we send back.
Let's now go back to the backend though, there we will get a URL which contains the ID as part
of the URL. Express.js is able to handle this, we can add an extra segment here to the path for which
we filter where we tell Express.js that we have a dynamic segment, so one which is not always the
same value but which changes. We do that by adding a colon here and then any identifier of your choice,
for example lid for location ID but again, you can name this however you want, the colon is important
though.
Now this tells Express that we filter for get requests to /location/something and now in
here, we can retrieve that location ID by going to request.params, there is a params object in
there, Express.js provides this to you and this will now have a lid key because I have lid up there,
if you chose a different identifier here, you have to extract the different one down there,
this will be the data which is part of the URL, this segment which is part of the URL. With that
we can now go to our location storage which will not be cleared as long as we don't restart the server
or we're running out of memory, to get our location by that ID. So in there, we have math random as ID
which is a number, what we get here will be a string because whatever you encode in the URL will be
a string, so we'll actually convert it to a number by adding a plus here and then we can find this here
in our locations array. So the location can be found by reaching out to location storage.locations and
then we can use the find method which exists on arrays in Node.js just as it does on the client side
and here we learned how that works,
this runs on every item in the array, so on every location
and I want to return true if we found the right location,
so I want to return true if loc.Id is equal to location ID, then I know I have the right location
and we store this here in this location
object. Now if location is falsy and this also works just as on the client side because this is
a default Javascript feature, this whole falsy, truthy if check thing, so we can check for falseness,
If that's the case then I actually want to send back a JSON response where I set my own status code,
status code with the status method of 404,
we can simply chain these two methods
and with that we first set a status code and then we can add some extra data where we maybe add
a message of not found.
So with that, we return an error response to the frontend and then we can do whatever we want with that
information there,
I just want to set this extra status code with the status method so that we have a chance to find out
whether we succeeded or not on the frontend
and I will return this
so that we execute no code after this
because after this if check,
I want to run the code which we run
if we found a location and in this case, I want to send the response with the JSON method.
We could add a status code here as well but 200 is the status code, the default status code anyways so
we don't have to do that
and here of course I want to provide my location data so we can set an address here by accessing location.address
because when we store a location here, we store an object which has the address field and
a coords field,
so we send back an address and then maybe coordinates where we refer to location.coords,
so to this coords field we're storing up there and now this is sent back to the client,
now let's restart our Node server here and on the client side, we now can also tweak this code a little
bit and to provide the coords to the loaded place, we can access data.coordinates because we will
send back a coordinates key here which holds an object with lat and lng which is just what we need,
so we access coordinates on the return data and data.address for the address.
Now we might get a status code which is 404 if we have no place,
so in this case here I want to check if response.status is equal to 404, in which case I know we
didn't find a location and in that case I want to throw a new error here where I say could not find
location and then add a catch block after the last
then block where I catch any errors like this one, where I simply show an alert with that error message
to the user.
Now with all of that, let's save that and first of all store a new place because I restarted the node
server, so our old place will be lost for now. Find that place
and now let's share that place,
let's copy the URL and enter this here and that looks pretty good to me and it's coming from a
server
and if we enter an invalid ID here, we get could not find a location.
So that is working as it should with our basic REST API here where we send requests to the backend and
we handle them there with different routes for the moment to then just store them in our temporary memory
storage here.