So which function could we write?
Well let's say we want to make sure that at some point of time in this module, we can click the plus
button and add whatever we entered here to our current result which initially is zero
and then if we type five here and click plus, we want to get five.
So the new result is then five, if I thereafter type 10 and I click plus, we would get 15,
right?
So that would be an idea to get started with
and for that, we need a function or we could add a function that does just that, that adds two numbers.
So for that we can define a function
and it's up to you where you do that,
you can actually do it kind of at the start of your script,
maybe below your variable definitions or you can actually also do it at the end of your script and Javascript
is smart enough to kind of read your entire file before it executes it and it will therefore find any
functions you use
so that it then automatically pulls these functions to the top so to say, so that if you define a function
down there but you then use it somewhere above its definition,
you can still execute that code without an error, something which by the way is not possible for variables
and constants you defined with let and const but I'll come back to this in a second. For now, let's just add a
function here let's say and let's name it add and you can pick any name you want here,
the idea for the name here just should be that it describes the action
this function will perform. So if its a function that adds two numbers, something like add or add numbers
makes sense instead of give me two numbers which describes what it wants to get as an input but not
what it does. You also don't want to have something like result as a name because what does this function
do,
it doesn't tell us anything,
it gives us some results,
sure but for which operation?
So here, add sounds like a fitting name, it makes it clear that this is a function which will do some
addition and then as I said, a function can but doesn't have to take parameters.
Now in Javascript and you'll see that throughout the course of course, there are functions which work
without any input,
let's say you have a function which kind of reads something from the HTML page.
This probably doesn't take any input because inside of the function, you have all the information you
need to kind of reach out to the HTML page and get some data from there.
On the other hand, a function which should add two numbers probably needs these two numbers which it
should add,
so we should provide two parameters here and you can give these parameters any name you want.
So I will go with num1 and num2 but you could go with a and b or with number1 and number2
or whatever you want. These parameters which you define here are then available in the so-called function
body which is the last missing piece on this function.
You add the function body by adding curly braces here, like this
and now important, after the function you don't have a semicolon.
Now you could add one but typically, you don't do that.
You add a semicolon after all these one-line expressions here
but after a statement as this is called, which includes such curly braces like this one does here,
you don't add a semicolon.
You can just keep this in mind, whenever you have some curly braces with some code, some executable code
in between, you don't have a semicolon after the curly braces. Whenever you have these short expressions
here, you have a semicolon at the end. So here, we have a function, keyword, name, parameters which are optional
and then the function body
and now in the function body, you can do all kinds of things,
for example we can define a constant in here as well, maybe name this result and just add num1 and num2
here. Now num1 and num2 are like variables, though they're never defined with the let or
const keyword but they're automatically defined by Javascript but they're only available inside of
this function body, not outside.
So if I would try to do something with num1 here after the function definition, this would not work
because num1 and num2 are variables only available inside of the function body.
Now I used them here to add them together because I expect this function to be called such that whatever
I get here on num1 and num2 are numbers and therefore, adding them works and I store the result in a new
constant.
Now the interesting thing here is that this constant is defined inside of the function, not at the top
level of our script
and that's something you can do in Javascript and that is actually quite normal.
You can have variables and constants here at the top level of your script,
this is also called in the global scope but you can also have them inside of your function
and it's actually important where you define that and I'll come back to that. For now, I want to calculate
a result which I only use inside of the function and therefore we can declare and define this variable
or this constant actually inside of that function.
Now inside of the function body, you see that my IDE automatically indents the code, which means it's
not totally on the left here but there is some empty space.
This is done for readability,
technically this is not required,
your code would run even if this would all be written in one line,
so if you would move that right next to the curly braces and have that all defined in one line but having
the functions split out across multiple lines and having this indentation, this empty space simply helps with
reading or understanding your function.
Now regarding the amount of empty space you have to the left, you can find a lot of discussions about
that on the Internet.
Now here, I indent it by four blanks so to say, so four whitespaces,
now you'll find discussions on the Internet whether you want to use four or two, whether you want to use
tabs or whitespace,
I'm a fan of whitespace and I'll typically use two also later when I do autoformat my document,
it's configured to use two whitespaces here instead of four as I have it right now.
You can go with whichever approach you want,
you then should just stick to it and be consistent and you can also configure your code styling, your code
formatting plugin for the IDE you're using to format your code according to your preferences.
Again my tool will later change this to two blanks here instead of four as I have it right now,
you can go for either of that, you just should write readable code in the end.
So this will now hold the result of num1 and num2 added together
and now what can we do with the result? Well we can for example output it with the alert function.
This is a function built into Javascript or built into the browser and provided to you in Javascript
executed in the browser.
So we don't need to define this function on our own to call it,
it's available,
it's one of the built-in functions
and there are a couple of built-in functions in Javascript,
it depends on whether you're running Javascript in the browser or outside of the browser
but here we're in the browser and there we have something like the alert function which is built
in, made available by the browser.
So alert then allows us to output a message and
We could say the result is and then this is a string of course, add result here
and of course you could have also used the back ticks notation with this dollar sign curly brace embedding
here. Now I do create a string here where I concatenate my result because alert actually wants
a message as a parameter and you can see this if you hover over alert in Visual Studio Code.
You see this is a function, again provided by Javascript or by the browser
and this wants a message parameter, you can ignore
the question mark for now,
that simply means that providing this message is optional
so you could throw an alert without a message which is kind of pointless though and message here is
a parameter which actually should be a string because you want to output some text typically.
So now I'm outputting this text here, this alert.
Now if I save this and we reload, nothing happens, we see no alert
and the reason for that is that we're not calling this function yet.
As I mentioned, you need to call a function in order for it to be executed.
Now how do you call a function?
Well you can just use the function name,
so in this case add and if you picked a different name, you have to pick a different name here and then
add parentheses like this.
So a bit like you defined it here but without the function keyword and without the body because this
defines what's inside of the function, how it works,
this now calls the function and here I add a semicolon again because here I don't have the curly braces,
I don't define the function here, I just execute this as a so-called expression,
so I just have this line of code which is executed.
This line of code is also executed but it's executed such that this code is registered and stored by
Javascript,
so it kind of is made aware of this function,
this line then executes and calls that function,
it runs that function.
Now this function to work correctly needs two parameters, also called arguments.
It needs a number one and a number two
and now here of course you don't provide num1 or num2, so you don't repeat these names,
these are just internal names for these automatically created variables
you can use inside of the function, instead here you now provide the concrete values that the function
should use for running,
so something like 1 and 2 if you want to add 1 and 2 together.
So now, num1 would be set to 1 and num2 would be set to 2 for this function execution
and as I said we can now run a function multiple times by executing it again with 5 and 5 for example.
Now we would execute the function two times - one with a value of 1 for num1 and the value of 2 for
num2
and then the second time we run it, we pass in a value of 5 for num1 and the value of 5 for num2.
And now if we save that and we reload this file, you see since this script runs right away, we get the
alert with the result is 3 because here I am calling this function with 1 and 2 and if I click
OK,
I right away get another alert because we're running this function twice and script execution is kind
of blocked by the alert which is why the second alert waits until we dismiss the first alert and then
in that second alert,
I see the result is 10 because I call this function with 5 and 5
and if I dismiss, then we see that page being rendered. So this is how we define a function and how
we call it in Javascript.
Now I will emphasize again that a function can have as many parameters as it needs if it needs to have
some,
you can have one parameter, two as we have it here,
three, five, four, as many as you want and a function can also do one other thing which we're not doing here,
it can return something.