Now that we had a look at an important feature, default arguments, which helps us with writing more flexible
functions,
let's have a look at another feature, not really related to our game here to be honest but related to
functions. So I'll add a brand new function here at the bottom of the file
since it is, as mentioned, not related to the game and the function here can again be created with one
of the three syntaxes you learned,
doesn't matter which one you use,
I'll go for the arrow
function and I'll name it sum up.
Now my idea here is that we can pass in as many arguments as we want and build a sum for those, so not
an array
but as many arguments as we want.
So here I want to have like a, b, c, d but I want to have an infinite amount of arguments here,
that's my idea and you can see where the problem lies,
I can't know when I'm writing this code with how many arguments this function will be called.
Well obviously, I will know if I'm the one calling it here
but let's say this is more dynamic,
it's done inside of a loop which is based on some user input.
So anything where we can't fully control how often that will be called.
So here I will call it myself in the code
but again let's assume I'm not the one calling it like this but instead, we wrote some code where this
is called dynamically with a different amount of arguments.
So we could be calling this with 1, 5, 10, -3, 6, 10 and so on
but I also want to be able to call it with an extra argument or with two extra arguments, something like
this.
So this should be flexible regarding the amount of arguments it gets.
Now you could think well since Javascript is forgiving and we can have more parameters than we need,
we can of course build this function with a lot of parameters in mind and hope that it never gets called
with more than that.
Well hope is never something you should rely on and in addition, you still might run into problems where
all unused parameters are undefined and if you then use this in some mathematical calculation, you will
probably get incorrect results or not a number as a result,
so this is not really a great solution.
Well another solution would be to simply force the user to pass in an array, right, something like this.
Numbers is an array,
now here we pass an array, here
I don't but I'll just comment this out for now
and now we can use a loop here, build a sum, start at zero, use a loop where we go through all the numbers
here,
the good old for/of loop you learned about and then simply add each number to the sum and in the
end, we simply return the sum here.
Now we have a sum up function and if we give that a try and we console log the result of calling that
function here, save that and reload and also avoid this syntax error and use a semicolon instead of
a comma, important. So save that and reload, we get 29 here, which is the sum of these numbers like
6, 16, 13, 19, 29.
So this works and of course, you could kind of implement it like this.
Now the thing is not in all Javascript programs you're going to write
you might be fine with a solution like this,
maybe you really want to allow that the function is called with multiple arguments, for whatever reason
that may be but you want to make sure that this is the case. In such a case,
you can call the so-called rest operator.
It looks like the spread operator which I showed to you in the behind the scenes module, you add three
dots but the place where you use that operator is different from the spread operator.
You might remember that spread operator was used when you created an object or when you created an array
and then you could use the three dots in there to take an existing object or an existing array and pull
out all the key-value pairs or all the elements of the array and add them to the new object or new array.
Now here we use the three dots in a different place,
we use it in a parameter list and there in such a function parameter list, it does something different.
Instead of pulling elements out of an array, here it takes all arguments
this function gets and that might be as many as you want
and it merges them into an array,
so it builds an array here inside of the function.
So now you can call the function without passing an array by having real different arguments but they're
getting merged into an array inside of the function, which you of course don't see when you just call the
function and then we can work with that array and in this case, return our sum.
So now we can also call this function like this,
so with these two lines of code I have here at the bottom. This will now work,
if we save and reload and we get 29 and 142 as sums because of that rest
operator which is really really useful therefore since it gives you more flexibility when you're writing
your functions. Now one important note about the rest operator, it always has to be the last argument
in your list,
for example if you expect another argument a here, well then a can never be passed in right
because this always consumes all arguments and merges them together in an array.
So if you would have arguments after an argument which uses the rest operator, you can never reach that
argument.
So here, we even get an error therefore, rest parameter must be last formal parameter for this exact reason
so this is not allowed.
You also can only have one parameter, one rest parameter I mean because for the same reason, this automatically
merges all arguments together
so there is no room for a second rest parameter.
What you can have though is parameters in front of this,
a for example and b and whatever you want because that simply means that the first two arguments in
this case, 1 for a and 5 for b will be assigned to these parameters and only all the other arguments
or parameters thereafter will be merged together.
So if we do that, now a and b will be excluded from the calculation and therefore if we run this, we get
different results than before, to be precise the same result as before, - 6 because 1 + five
is 6 because that's now not included in the calculation because it's not included in the numbers array.
So you really got a lot of flexibility here with the rest
operator.
Now a little side note, when not using an arrow function,
so when using a function keyword, so let's say we build a subtract up function and now I build it with the
function keyword, then you can also use the rest
operator there, nothing wrong with that, you can build it in the exact same way as you do with the arrow
function but here, you actually also have another way of building this.
So let me copy that code
but of course here now I subtract all the values,
so that's the difference between the two functions
and now let me call this, so subtract up and here I have 1, 10, 15, 20, something like this.
Well now of course it would fail because numbers here,
what we're looking for, will not be defined. Previously this was our rest argument, our automatically generated
array,
here it's missing.
So therefore now unsurprisingly if I reload, we'll get a little error here.
Now you can of course as I just explained use the rest parameter here just as you did it in the arrow
function
and if you do so, everything will be fine, we can reload and it works
but now and that's the blast from the past thing,
we can also use something different. In functions created with the function keyword,
you have a special variable available which you never define, which you don't accept as an argument but
which is just magically there
so to say and that's the arguments variable. Arguments as you see is already marked as a keyword because
it's built into Javascript, you can use it inside of functions but only inside of functions that use
the function keyword
and it gives you an array-like object, not a true array but array-like with all the arguments this function
got. So before the rest operator was introduced which happened with ES6,
this was the way of building a function like this one,
so this was then the automatically merged array.
So if I now save this, this runs again with -46 as a result,
so this is an alternative to using the rest operator.
That being said, using the rest parameter is recommended because this is always a bit strange to have
this magic arguments thing coming out of nowhere and it's much cleaner to define this rest parameter.
So whilst this does work, no matter if you're using the function keyword or not, you should always use
the rest operator,
so don't use that.
Just wanted to show it to you because you will find it in some Javascript snippets you might be looking
at and it was the only way of achieving this before this rest operator was introduced.