Let's start with our lost text.
It's easy to bring back because the template solution here has a tool for us to enable us to pass some
content between our opening and closing tax off the web component and this feature is called slots.
We can define a slot in the template which basically means hey you can insert the content which is between
the opening and closing tag off our element in that place.
You do that by simply adding a slot element opening and closing nothing in between like this inside
our our template if you do that with just dad additions.
If you now reload the page you'll see our text is back and now the question mark is correctly added
after it because essentially it's now taking this as a template and this template says Here is the place
for whatever you pass between the opening and closing tag and thereafter we have our own Dom our own
template whenever we want to have.
So this works now as before but now we're taking advantage of that slotting mechanism now slots also
can have a default value some default.
And this will kick in if you don't pass anything between the opening and closing tax.
So if I delete my text down there for the second usage of this custom component and I then go back to
the page and reload we see some default here because the text I PASSED BETWEEN MY slots tax then is
used as a default unless we overwrite it with our own text as we do up there.