So we can attack the monster normally, we can launch a strong attack,
we can heal,
we get various checks and they're also to see whether we won.
One thing we're not doing is we're not resetting the game after we won,
we're also not asking the user for an initial max health value,
right now we're hardcoding this to be 100,
I said that I want to let the user of the game, of this app, of this website
choose that value and we're also not doing is, we're not utilizing this bonus life.
Now let's maybe start with the bonus life. The idea behind the bonus life is that if we're low on health
and we would die, like now if I click attack and the monster hits us, we would very likely die,
then we actually don't die
but instead we consume this bonus life and we got time or an opportunity to come back.
OK,
so I didn't die,
now I should die,
I lost
and here
we shouldn't lose but instead consume the bonus life, freeze our health,
so don't reduce our health for this turn and thereafter, we have a chance to heal back up or if it was
close, maybe now launch an attack towards the monster that kills it
and therefore we have one chance to recover throughout the entire game
even if we then restart it later.
So this is the idea behind the bonus life,
where should this bonus life come in therefore? Well the and round function makes sense because this is
where we check whether we lost and here actually before we check this, we should check whether we have
a bonus life. So in here, we can add another if statement and check if the currentPlayerHealth is smaller
or equal than zero, which means we would beat that and now I also want to check if
we still have our bonus life. Now for that since it's exactly one which we can consume,
I'll add a new variable up there which I'll name hasBonusLife
and I give it this strange name because this will actually hold true initially.
So this is now a variable that just holds a boolean value,
true or false, not a truthy or falsy value but a real boolean and boolean variables are typically named
like this, where you kind of indicate what you're trying to control here,
so here, hasBonusLife, in other programs you might have something like isLoggedIn, to indicate whether
the user is logged in or not
which also makes sense to be true or false.
Of course we don't have that here but that would be another example.
So here bonus life, hasBonusLife is true
and therefore here I can check if we would be that and we have a bonus life,
so if this is true. Now we can just check this like that,
you could say equals true with triple or double equals sign
and that would not be wrong,
that would work
but as I also showed you on the falsy truthy slide, if you just reference a variable without a comparison
operator, Javascript will actually try to convert this to true or false and then take this in its condition
and here of course this conversion is really easy because there is nothing to convert,
this is a real boolean, it is true
so Javascript will check if this is true and this is true which means we would be that but we do have
a bonus life and in that case, I'll set the hasBonusLife variable to false because now we lost our
bonus life and I will call remove bonus life which is a function provided in vendor.js, which will
in the end just update the UI
and now I also want to make sure that our health is now not below zero.
So actually here at the beginning of the and round function, I'll log in the user's health before the monster
hits him,
so initial player life is here set equal to currentPlayerHealth, maybe also name this health therefore,
so initial player health is equal to currentPlayerHealth.
Thereafter the monster hit us and the currentPlayerHealth is reduced
but since we stored a copy here in initial player health, initial player health is not affected by
changes in currentPlayerHealth and therefore here, we can set back the currentPlayerHealth to the
initial player health, so we reset it to be health before the monster hit us,
that's what our bonus life does here.
Now let's just also inform the player about his luck and say you would be that
but the bonus life saved you
and of course also make sure we update the UI appropriately by using a function you find in vendor.js
and that's the set player health function which just updates the player health bar.
You simply pass it the health to which it should be set,
so here that's of course the initial player health to which we also reset our in-game health and with
that,
now let's save it, reload this game and now attack the monster a couple of times so that we would die
and now we would normally be that
but the bonus lives saved us
and indeed here we get a little bit of health left
so maybe let's try heal up and now we won.
You also see the bonus life was removed here.
So that's the bonus life, again with some if checks implemented, here
also with a variable which we don't compare to anything which again we could do but it's simply redundant
because if you don't add a comparison operator, Javascript will try to coerce this value to true or false
which here is simple because it is a real boolean and therefore we can use this in the condition
and hence, this works.