Now to react to a drop, we can add another event listener, still on the list because that's the area where
we drop and that's the drop event
we're listening to. Now in the drop event,
we can extract any data from the event object which we added here in drag start,
so data we passed here can now be extracted in the drop event, that is available.
So down here in drop, we can now get our project ID by going to event, data transfer, get data
and now your data identifier which is text/plain, that will retrieve this data.
Now here,
remember we are in one of the two lists and I want to make sure that if we're in the other list,
so if we really dragged the element into the other list, I do add it to that list.
If I dragged the element but let loose of it in the list it already was in, I of course don't want to
add it there because it already is in that list,
right.
So since this event listener here is added to list and runs inside of a method of project list, we have
to check if in the projects of that list the event listener runs on,
if there we find a project with this ID,
so we go through all projects and compare IDs.
Now if we find a project with that ID in the projects that are already assigned to that list, then
we know we dropped it in the list it already was part of
and then I don't want to do anything.
So in this case, we can simply return here which means we don't continue with this function execution,
which means the next line doesn't run and therefore we don't do anything.
Alternatively, you check the opposite here and move all your code into this if statement.
So now here I only continue if we're not having this project already,
so if we really dropped it in the other list, then I want to add it to this list where we dropped it and
I want to remove it from the list it came from.
Now it's actually not that simple because the projects I can interact with are only the projects where
the dragged project is not part of
and I only have the ID of the dragged project.
So we would have to find some solution, just as we did it earlier in the course already, with some function
we pass around between the two lists instances so that we now can call a function in the other list
and move our element or we do something else.
What if we then simply trigger a click on the finished button or on the activate button? That would do
the trick right
because that will move the element. It will run all the other click listening logic we already did
set up,
so that's what I'll do here.
I'll go to my document here and then get an element by ID and use that project ID because that is
assigned as an ID to the HTML elements
and now inside of that project which we selected, I want to get access to that button which I can
get with query selector button last of type
and then there, we can call click
and now effectively what I do is I go to the element which was dropped which isn't really moved as I
explained,
just looks like we move it.
So we go to that element which is getting dragged, in this case the finish the course element
and once I drop it, this button here is clicked for us with the help of this code,
this is what's happening here.
Of course I also want to remove the droppable styling here, so I'll copy that line and what you can
do here as well is you can call even prevent default,
it's not required but you can do it if there were some default behavior for dropping something here,
for example if you would be dropping some image somewhere else and the browser might then typically load
that image full screen, you could omit it here or prevent that here,
so you can add this, here we don't need it though
and therefore here we're actually done.
Now let's see if that works, if we save that and we reload, if I drag finish the course in finished projects,
you see the same thing happens as when I click a button here and we can drag items around just as we
should be able to do. So this is looking pretty good to me here,
this is drag and drop implemented here and working like a charm
as you can tell and therefore
we get that finished. Now before we close this module though,
let me also show you the drag end event which we don't need here but which you also can listen to.
Now as I mentioned, you can also listen to a drag end effect and you do that on the item where you also
listen to drag start,
so in this case on the project item. There, you can basically copy that line and of course we could also
therefore refactor that, item equals this here and then use item add event listener and then
here, also item add event listener and listen to drag end here to then do something when a drag ends.
Now we can console log the event here to see what's in there and save that
and with that if we reload and we now drag and drop, you see this is the event which gets emitted and in
there, we can get a couple of pieces of information,
for example the target was the element itself. By the way for the drop and drag enter and so on events,
so for all the events we added as listeners to the list itself, the target always would be the list, never
the element which is getting dragged because it's the list which triggers the event in the end, right?
Here
however, drag end is on the item and therefore the target is the item itself
and now here we can also pass around some data if we wanted to. In data transfer,
we also have the drop effect here.
We allowed that move effect and you see the drop effect now also is moved here.
Now that shows you that the drop succeeded because if a drop does not succeed,
for example if I let loose here, we still get the drag end event but there, you see data transfer drop
effect is none.
So you can always check the drop effect property in data transfer to find out whether a drop succeeded
or not
and now you could also run any logic you want in here to for example update the UI or move data around,
that would also be possible. And that's it,
this is drag and drop implemented with this example,
as I mentioned in the last lecture of this module, you'll find a complete guide, also with some other examples
and more details if you're interested
and with that, you learned a lot about events and specifically, also about drag and drop.