Now that is all nice but we also had the thing that I wanted to get this template out of the storm.
Now how does that work.
First of all let me say that having a template in our normal HMO file is of course fine as you see it
works.
But if we want to create a fully reusable web component it would be nice to define the template in the
javascript file too so that in the end we just have to dump this javascript file into any project any
web project and we can start using our own component.
And for this I'll go back to the tooltip jazz file and I will define a template in there which is really
easy instead of appending our template content so I can get rid of these two files here I will access
my shadow root.
And there we can set the inner h t Mal code enraged him L is a default property you can set on your
h him l elements on the built in ones too and there you can write any H Tim alt code you want.
So now we can grab this content we had in the template and removed a template thereafter and add this
here like this if you save that and you then reload this page you have the same as before the same behavior
as before but now you have your template as part of your javascript file.
Now I know that it can look strange to start writing h t mail instead of your javascript file.
Keep in mind that this in the end is just a normal string and it can look strange but it is a nice way
of creating a re usable age html element.
Now we can also use a next gen javascript feature called template laterals where we use back ticks instead
of single quotation marks.
So this is not a single quotation mark does a back tick opening and closing and this will still create
a string but now we can write a multi line string here so that we can form it does a nicer way we now
safeties.
You will see it still works as before.
So it's just a bit strange to get used to that in some ideas you get really great auto completion supportive
though mind doesn't pick it up here but still I will go with this approach because whilst it is strange
to look at we now have all the logic in the javascript file making this a really simple reusable web
component.
Now one important thing you might wonder how can I set the H Khumalo content here inside my constructor.
The reason is simple interface team L is just a property off our element here of our object and this
is just setting up some H similar code that will be rendered to to Dom once this element is mounted
to the DOM.
So unlike append child this does not try to access the DOM at this point it just prepares some content
for the DOM once it later is available and the browser will take care about rendering this when it is
able to.