So we see that the fetch API thus far is pretty easy to use and it uses promises by default
and actually it only works with promises,
so it looks a lot better than XMLHttpRequest.
Now one downside of it, of the fetch API could be that it doesn't support older browsers but as you
will learn in the browser support module, you might be able to work around that.
A bigger problem or a bigger annoyance at least can be seen when we have a look at error handling,
so let's see what happens there.
Again I'll break my get URL here by simply changing this to a URL which does not exist on the
server we're sending the request to and let's see what happens in that case. If I reload, click fetch
posts,
well at some point we get an error that we can't use the response data.
So of course we work with promises there,
so since this returns a promise, we could use try catch to wrap this all into our try catch block
and do our error handling or if we didn't use aync await, we could use the catch method in our promise
chain.
Now the problem with that just is just like with the XMLHttpRequest, that a request that technically
succeeded,
so where we don't have a technical issue but maybe just a 400 or 500 status code sent back by the server
will not trigger a traditional error.
So if I would to try to add some first error handling here in my sendHttpRequest function, then I could
add a catch method here in my promise chain which I return and keep in mind that this promise chain
itself also returns a promise,
that's how promises work. So here I could then catch any error we might be getting and we could handle
it here, store it in some internal log and then maybe just throw a new error object where I say something
went wrong or maybe we also provide more information than that.
The problem is, we'll never make it into this catch block for the error we currently have,
if I fetch posts again, you see this is coming from a different place,
we got no log coming from line 44, we got the line 56 here. So we don't make it into the catch block
and the reason is the same as with XMLHttpRequest, only technical issues like network connectivity
issues would lead us to go into that catch block,
instead we're here in the then block.
Good thing is just as with XMLHttpRequest, we can check the response status and find out if we have
an error here.
So if response status is greater or equal than 200 and response status is smaller than 300, then
we have a success case and then I want to return response
JSON, else I know we have an error, so else I can throw a new error here,
something went wrong
server side,
anything like that.
So if I save that and I now reload, if I fetch my posts, now we get that correct output but still we
have a problem here.
What if we want to look into the body of our response
because often for server side errors, the server might attach extra information to the response body.
So it's not just about the status code, even in the error case,
we get back a valid response with a response body and we might want to parse that response body to get
the data that the server might have added.
Now in the XMLHttpRequest world, that would have been easy, here in this else case
if we got an error, we could still access xhr.response,
that would be possible here in the XMLHttpRequest world.
Unfortunately that's not the case in the fetch API world. Remember, the body is streamed,
so at this point of time we have no direct access to the body,
we first of all need to call response.json in the error case as well.
So we always need to call that in order to get our data.
Now of course, you could think then I just add an extra step here,
return response.json
here
no matter if it's an error or not
and then I check my response status code in the next then block where I have access to the body data.
The problem just is here
we get the data but we don't have access to the response object anymore,
we only have access to that here.
So the place where we need the status code is a different place than where we get access to the body
and that's the problem we face here.
Essentially we need to write some wrapping code here to make all of that work.
We can say if we have an error, then I want to parse my body with JSON, that yields a new promise and
now we have a promise chain in a promise chain which is never such a great idea
but then here I have access to my error data and now here, I could throw my error and maybe utilize this
extra error data
we might be getting by the server. So let's now give that a try
if I reload and click fetch posts again and now you'll see a different problem,
now we throw the error basically in that nested promise chain, so the outer promise chain doesn't have
an error and hence we again think everything is fine and we try to list our posts and that of course
breaks.
So throwing the error here in the nested promise chain is also not an option,
we need to throw it outside of there but there, we don't have access to the error data
so how can we solve that.
Well we can move that back in there and simply return that inner promise chain so that it is basically
merged into the outer promise chain or now connected to the outer promise chain
and now with that, if I reload and I click fetch posts, now we have the proper error propagation and
we have access to the error data. So it's possible we can solve this but
of course that's not the most beautiful error handling code you ever saw.
It is what it is however with the fetch API and this is how you can use the fetch API and implement proper
error handling, with access to the response body at the same time.
Now with that if I go down here and I re-add try catch here,
let's see if that all works,
if we add this block again, reload, click fetch posts,
now I get something went wrong here as an error alert and we don't try to use the invalid data.
If I on the other hand fix this link again and then I reload, then fetching works again.
So that's the fetch API and how we can handle errors there.