Now that we know how to select elements both with the query methods, get element by ID but also with
the DOM traversing techniques and that we also learned how to evaluate and manipulate elements,
let's have a look at one specific way of manipulating elements and that is changing their style.
I already showed you how that works with the style property but turns out there are other ways of doing
that as well.
So of course you can use that style property with which we already worked, with that you directly target
the individual CSS styles applied to that element,
it's like using inline styles on the element in your HTML document.
So if you know a bit of CSS, you'll also know that this has the highest specificity, which means styles
assigned on the style property will overwrite any other styles that might be assigned to an element
by a class or anything like that. Now important here as you learned already, the style property names
are based on the CSS property names but they are adjusted, for example background color is written
like this and not as it is in CSS with a dash.
Now that's one way of setting styles but there are other ways and it's kind of obvious if you think
about it,
you of course can also manipulate the CSS classes that are added to an element.
So with the class name property, you can set the CSS classes that exist on an element to dynamically
change these classes, remove them or add new ones and that of course means that you adjust the styles
that are applied by these classes because you control the classes on an element. With class name, you
set and control all classes at once,
class name is a string and it's a string of all the classes that are added, so you can manipulate that
string to manipulate the classes. By the way, you of course
alternatively could also change the ID or some other attributes of an element if you are using
an ID selector or attribute selectors in your CSS code but CSS classes are of course the
most common way of spreading styles across multiple elements.
Now when it comes to CSS classes, you actually also have another way of editing classes on an element.
Class name takes one string, which is simply a string of all the classes that should be added and therefore
if you want to toggle a class there, you have to manage it manually, that you keep classes which you don't
want to remove and only remove the classes that you want to get rid of. To make that a bit easier,
all these element nodes also have another property,
the class list property which is in the end a Javascript object and not just a string like class name
but an object with a couple of built-in methods that make it easy for you to add, remove or toggle CSS
classes, so that it's easier for you to manage individual classes and not having to do this string
micromanagement that you have to do with class name.
It gives you finegrained control over the classes that are added and you can even use it in conjunction
with class name, though you should be careful that you don't overwrite each other and typically you use
either of the two.
So let's now dive into all these options to make it super clear what's happening there.
Back here on our page as I left it, we have the section with the unordered list and let's now say we want
to style this section. Now of course for that, we can simply get access to it with document query selector
section for example,
you could also assign an ID to it and use get element by ID but I'll just use that
and now with the section available, we can of course add some styles, for example with inline styles, with
the style property, we can add a background color but
of course you can add more than just the colors,
I'm just working with these since you can quickly see the impact.
So here, we can set the background color to green for example
and this looks beautiful, doesn't it?
So that's what you already know,
you can reach out to the style here and set it like this. On the elements tab
by the way, you'll see that this indeed added the style attribute and reflected your change back into
HTML here with the adjusted CSS styling even which you could add yourself in HTML,
so this is what Javascript does for you behind the scenes.
Now that's not too new,
that's what we did before,
let's now go back to our code into the HTML file and play with a bunch of CSS styles. For this, I'll
add a style block here in the HTML file,
of course we could also import some CSS file but I'm not writing that much CSS, so adding it here
is fine and I'll add a red bg class here,
so I'm writing some CSS here where the background color is set to red and the text color is set to
white.
I will also add a visible class here where I set display to block and an invisible class here where
I set display to none
and these are all just some CSS properties which I'm setting here.
So now we have three CSS classes to play around with.
Now let's say on section here, I'll add class
red bg, so this red background is always there. With that added here, if we save this and we reload, we
have this red background on this section, thanks to this class.
Now
no Javascript is involved in this step, this is just some regular CSS styling.
Now here in the app.js file, I'll select this section here with document query selector section like
this
and now of course, we can change the background color here for example to blue, again using some inline
styles and that's what I meant.
Now if we reload, this is blue because whilst the classes are still there and theoretically, the styles
but the class still get applied, due to the way CSS works inline styles have a higher priority and therefore
overwrite the class styles, the clashing class styles.
But that's not the main thing I wanted to show you here,
instead let's now actually go there and remove this red background class and for this, we can reach out
to class name, to this class name property on the element and set this to an empty string,
this will basically set this class attribute to exactly this string.
So if we save that and we reload, the blue background is gone because as you can tell here, nothing is
assigned to the class attribute because we reset it to an empty string.
Now that's convenient
if you really just want to clear everything or if you then maybe want to set it back up on some code
change, then you can also do that and now it will be there because we don't only set it in HTML,
we also now set it again here in Javascript.
And please also note, red bg is added here in HTML and now also here in Javascript and it's not
added twice or anything like that,
instead class is really set equal to your string here and now that can become a problem.
Let's say we want to keep the red background but we want to add another class.
Now right now, that means you have to set the string to the class you want to keep and your new class.
Now for that, let's add a button here,
maybe here and we say toggle visibility
and let's select this button here in app.js.
So here I'll select this button,
since it's the only button, we can again use query selector button here and now on this button, we can
do something we also saw before, we can call add event listener, add a click event and then here, an
anonymous function,
I'll use an arrow function, you can use whichever function type you want and there when we click it, I
went to set class them equal to red bg visible, which is one of the other CSS classes I defined here
and invisible
if we are in visible mode.
So I want to swap this visible mode depending on which mode we're currently in.
Now that's a bit complex to code here,
of course we could add extra variable which helps us manage the current visibility state.
If we only want to do it with the selected section, I have to check if section class name is equal to
red bg visible and that only works because I know I will at most have these two classes or I will exactly
have these two classes eventually,
if I had more classes that even change dynamically, that would be even harder to check here
but here I know if I have that, then I want to set the class name here to red bg invisible, otherwise
in the else case, I want to set it to red bg visible,
right ? So now with that logic which again only works that well in quotation marks because we don't have
more classes than these but even with that code, we already have quite a bit of code here
but now if I reload this, if I click the button here, you see this in the end after clicking it twice toggles
the visibility here as you can see on the right, dynamically changes the classes.
Now a problem with that approach is that we manually have to keep track of the classes we add, which
class is there and so on,
now that can be done in an easier way. Instead of using this, you can use this class list object I was
referring to.
So class list is another property you have on every element node and there you've got a couple of
nice methods, you've got a contains method to quickly check if a class is set.
So for example here you could then easily check if the visible classes is set and don't worry about
the entire string, you don't have to worry about other classes that might be set,
you can simply check if that is set.
You can also call add to add a new class or remove to remove a class, so that's all nice,
you can replace a class and you can also toggle a class
and here we can toggle the visible and the invisible class.
Now I just have to go to index.html and initially here, I'll add visible as well
and now class list will automatically check whether visible is set when we call toggle visible and we'll
remove it if it is and add it otherwise and the same for invisible
and the result of that is that if we now reload, this toggling works just as before but with less work
from our side.
Now of course here actually adding visible is totally irrelevant because invisible is the one that does
the main work here and that sets display to none, so we can actually even comment out this visible part
and only add invisible but I hope it becomes clear what the power of class list is,
it makes managing CSS classes much easier and that overall allows you to dynamically add or remove or
change classes, CSS classes on an element and therefore that in turn allows you to dynamically change
styles because while you sometimes might want to change inline styles, more often than not, you want
to add more complex styles to an element and instead of setting them all as inline styles in your Javascript
code which also is hard to find for other developers, you typically want to take your CSS code
and dynamically add or remove classes.
That also makes it easier to work in a team where you might have one colleague working on the CSS
styles and you working on the Javascript.
If you have to set styles in Javascript with inline styles, then you have to know CSS and you have
to align with your CSS colleague. If you use class list or class name but better class list for
more flexibility, then your CSS colleague can give you the CSS code and you can dynamically add
or remove classes from that code based on your logic, which simply makes working on that easier as well.