So that's basically it for all these special array methods.
Now there are two other special methods which are related to strings and they're also quite handy.
Let's say you have some data which you maybe read from some csv file which looks like this, New York;
10.99; 2000,
whatever value that might be but you have that value. You might want to transform this to an array where
you have three separate values instead of one single value like this, actually this of course shouldn't
be an array, it's just a string.
So instead of having a string with this combined data which to us humans is clearly recognizable as
three different pieces of data, you might want to split it into three real elements with which you can
work on the computer as well. For that, the transformed data can be created by running data.split.
Now that's a string method, not an array method because data is a string not an array.
Now split splits a string into an array of multiple segments and as an argument, you specify the separator
by which you split, that could be a whitespace, so blank, underscore, comma, any arbitrary character or of
course also a semicolon
and this will now split that string into three elements after every semicolon, it will pull out a new
element and split therefore returns an array with these elements into which this string was split.
You can also specify an optional second argument to limit the number of elements which is created
but here I don't want that,
I just want to split it like that and therefore here if we console log the transformed data like this
and we save that and we reload, we indeed have our array with these three data pieces.
Now of course if you would want to transform numbers to real numbers, you would have to do that as well
with parseInt by then diving into that transform data
and for example using the map method to transform some elements or targeting them by index and setting
that equal to plus transform data, one for example to replace it with a real number if you wanted to.
These are things you can do as you can tell
but the split method is the main thing I wanted to focus here as it allows you to split a string into
an array.
Now you also have the opposite kind of operation,
let's say you have the name fragments constant here and that has Max and Schwarz
so that could be a first and a last name
and you had this as an array because maybe you pulled this from two different inputs on the screen and
now you want to merge this together into one string which you can use in your user interface to greet
the user or anything like that.
Well then merging this into a string is very easy by using another special array method now because
name fragments now is an array, not a string
and there you have the join method.
Now join also takes a separator which you can use to join these things together.
Now let's first of all join without a separator to then see the difference and console log name.
So this should now join the elements of this array into one string and it will always generate a string,
even if you had numbers in here, it would still work but it would convert everything to a string.
So if we now save that and we reload, indeed we see Max Schwarz and you see by default it separates
the values by a comma. Now that might or might not be what you want, if you want some whitespace for example,
you simply add this as a separator here,
so as an argument to join and if you do that, now the elements of this array will be joined together
into a string with this as a separator between the individual words in the string in the end.
So now if we reload, we see Max, Schwarz like that.
So join and split also are very helpful for transforming strings to arrays and arrays to strings and
making sure that you got machine readable data and human readable names,
that's the idea here.