Let's have a look at the order. Here,
I'm defining my constant and my variable before I use it,
right?
I define current result right at the top of the script file and then here's the first time where I try
to use it because I try to assign a new value to it and then I also use it down there when I forward
it or when I pass the value that stored inside of it to output result.
Now our code would break if I would move that all the way to the bottom of the script,
so if I declare my variable here. Now if we reload this page, you see zero everywhere
and if you open the developer tools again,
in the console you'll see an error, cannot access current result before initialization.
Now this error message which the browser throws at us is pretty clear,
we're trying to use it here
and actually the error message even gives us the line number of where this error occurred,
it's this number you see here, eight.
So you see in line number eight and indeed that's the problematic number here,
we're getting an error because we're trying to assign something to the current result variable without
defining it first.
So in Javascript, when using the let or the const keyword which you should use, you need to declare
your variables and constants before you use them and declare is the part where you create the variable
with let or const.
Then as mentioned for the same name, you must only declare it once,
you can always reassign a value but with let and const, you only declare it once and you need to do
that declaration before you first try to read from it or assign a value to it.
You don't need to define it, so you don't need to initialize it with a value,
if I just set up current result like this, this would actually be valid, if I now tried to execute it,
you see this runs because I declared a variable before I then use it
and since I use it by initializing it with a value here anyways or by assigning a value here anyways,
I don't need to initialize and define it up there.
So doing this up here is totally optional, we don't really need to do that because I'm assigning a value
down there anyways
but you need to declare it with the let keyword.
Now for functions, that's actually a bit different.
I could grab this function and move it to the bottom of this file and if I do this, please keep in mind
that I do call it up here,
so technically before I define it. Still if I now reload this page, we get the same result as before and
if we have a look into the developer tools, you see no new error here.
The reason for that is that for functions, we have a special behavior in Javascript. What Javascript actually
does or what the browser actually does is that when it loads your script , it runs through it from top
to bottom, it parses the entire script and actually it doesn't execute it right away, instead it just reads
it from top to bottom and will take any functions it finds in there and automatically pull them to the
top and be aware of them
so to say. So it automatically registers all functions before it then really executes your script and
that's just the special behavior Javascript has there.
Therefore it's up to you whether you prefer to have your functions at the bottom of your script or towards
the beginning or is somewhere in between,
you just should try to find some consistent code style.
Now I personally like to have my functions towards the beginning of the file in most cases because I
think if you then read the file as a developer, you kind of see what's in there and if you then
later see that I call add, you recall that you did see that function definition above and you don't need
to scroll to the bottom of the file to find it
but there also are developers who prefer to have their function definitions at the bottom of the file
and ultimately, there is no wrong or right is up to you but you should find one approach and then kind
of stick to it for this program you're writing.
Of course, you can switch anytime in new applications you're creating or refactor your existing code
and move your functions to the bottom or to the top
if you kind of decide to go the opposite direction whilst in the project. Here again I'll have it towards
the beginning but this is up to you. You also reformat that which I did with the autoformatting functionality
I showed you in the first course module.