I already outlined it in the introduction video,
there are effectively three parts
that we'll have a look at in this course module.
The first part I want to have a look at is how you can write code efficiently
and with that, I don't really or don't necessarily mean that you can write code as quickly as possible
but I mean that you are able to really get a lot out of the tools you're working with,
that you know how to write code without too much copy pasting or manual work.
Now the next block we'll then have a look at is how you can find help because in programming, even if
you took many courses, even if you've been a developer for many years, you'll always encounter scenarios
or use cases where you're not sure how to solve something or where you know there was a feature in Javascript,
some built-in function that allows me to do that but I can't remember that function,
I don't recall how it worked in detail and that's totally normal.
When becoming a developer, the goal is not to learn all features and all the commands by heart,
that will be impossible not only because there are a lot of commands to learn but also because programming
languages evolve and new features are being added. So don't take this course or any other resource as a
I have to learn it by heart to resource, rather learn how a language generally works and how you have
to think about writing code and then also know where to find help and where to dive deeper if you need
a specific feature or a specific command and that's also something I'll explore with you in this module.
And the last block is that you need to be able to debug your code, you will encounter errors and therefore
it is important for you to be able to find and fix these errors.
So if we talk about writing code efficiently, what exactly does that mean?
It means that you should work in a productive environment, now
with that, I'm talking about the environment on your machine, not the environment you're working in.
Of course that should also be productive but that's something you'll have to figure out, where you work,
in which office and you might also not be able to control this if you for example are employed.
So I'm talking about the IDE, the editor and about configuring it such that you like working with it.
That also includes that you use the editor or the IDE to its fullest potential, that you're able to
auto format your code so that you don't manually have to indent things and so on,
that you use important shortcuts.
It also of course means that you take advantage of the auto completion,
the hints many editors and IDEs give you, Visual Studio Code
the IDE I recommend for this course certainly does so.
And of course it also means that you keep your eyes open for editor extensions and for the settings you
can tweak there to really adjust everything in the way you like to have it.
So let's have a look at that and let's explore some of the things I would recommend that you look into
and that you get started with.