I want to start with attaching data to DOM elements and why we might want to do that. Now in this project
we worked on, we do display a tooltip.
We got this tooltip component here
and right now what this does is when I click on more info, it adds a tooltip at the very bottom of the
page which of course is something we'll change with some dummy text in there and when we click on it,
it is deleted.
Now the dummy text is displayed because I am setting this here and the problem I have is that I don't
know which text should be displayed for which project.
Now we could be managing data like this in our Javascript code in an array of projects but here we actually
got to some HTML code which for example could be precreated on a server and sent to us on a client
like this
and therefore, we don't really have that tooltip data available in Javascript.
Now it's also not available in normal HTML tags because it shouldn't be rendered to the screen by
default,
instead what you can do is something I already prepared here for you,
we got this special attribute on these list items which represent these different projects,
data-extrainfo.
Now this is not a special attribute you have to attach extra tooltip info,
instead the data- attribute in general is a special attribute you can add to your own elements to
attach any kind of data to them,
so you could add data-id, data- whatever, data- whatever attribute or value you want to
append or you want to store on one of your DOM nodes
and the ID behind appending data or attaching data to DOM nodes simply is that you don't have to
manage it in Javascript. In cases like this one where we don't manage to project in Javascript,
we have a loose connection to the rendered DOM nodes,
we store the IDs of projects in Javascript but that is it,
we don't store any other project data there
and yes we could do that but sometimes you have scenarios where you want to store data in the DOM and
attach it to DOM elements so that when you work with that DOM element, you can read data from it.
Now for that, this extra data- attribute was created which you can safely use to attach any data
you want and you can add as many data attributes here as you wish.
Now the only question is, how can we read from that attribute?
And for that, you've got a special property you can read from.
So here in app.js
when I create a tooltip, here I got access to that tooltip element which I created,
now I also want access to that DOM node for which I'm creating a tooltip because on that DOM node, we'll
find this extra attribute.
Now here in the create method where we create a tooltip, we don't have access to this DOM node but I
am creating my tooltip on the other hand in my project item here which in the end is my Javascript representation
or connection I should say to that DOM node, it's not the DOM node itself, it's just an object which knows
about the ID of that DOM node and therefore we can select that DOM node and we can do this here
in show more info handler which is triggered when I click the more Info button and there before we
created a tooltip, I can reach out to the DOM node itself, so to the project element for example with document
get element by ID
and then this ID is a property of this project item which is the ID of that project here in my DOM,
so I can create by that.
This gives me access to this list item and on this list item, we got the special data attribute.
Now to read from this, we can reach out to project element and there, you've got a special dataset property
and that's important to keep in mind, these data- attributes are all merged together in a dataset
property.
Now let's console log that to get a feeling for what's inside there.
Now before we can try this out, one important note about this ID,
this refers to this property or at least it should
but due to the fact that show more info handler is attached to an event listener, we should actually
bind this here,
otherwise this will not refer to the same thing inside of show more info handler.
And with that if we save that and we then reload and click on more info, you'll see this is what's getting
printed, a DOM string map which in the end is a Javascript object where every attribute you added,
every data attribute you added is part of that and you see, the naming is automatically converted to
use camel case.
So I added extra-extra-info,
this becomes an extra info property in this DOM
string map object which I access on the dataset property of the selected node and that's just something
you have to know, you have to keep in mind
or I guess you can always console log it if you want to see what's in there,
this gives us access to this text which was added on the node.
Now if you would want to add your own content through Javascript, that's of course also possible. For
that,
you can reach out to the project element and then simply access dataset and dynamically add a new property
there,
for example some info. Set this to test here and what you'll see is that if you save that and you reload
and click on more info,
if you now inspect the DOM node here, you see besides data extra info,
we now have data some info added down there, so this then automatically gets added for you automatically
when you add a new property to dataset on your DOM node.
So this is how you can set data,
here however I want to read the data and I got my tooltip text here
simply by accessing project element dataset and then extra info was the name and then we can forward tooltip
text to the tooltip as a second argument to the constructor for example and then in the tooltip,
we just have to accept this,
so here we could add that text, get that text, then add it as a property, this text equal text and then
here in create where we set that text instead of using dummy, we can now use this.text.
And with that if we save that and we reload and click on more info and scroll to the bottom of the page,
we see this custom text which is part of the DOM node. The tooltip still is in the wrong position but
we at least extract the right text and this is all possible with the special data attribute and in Javascript,
with dataset which helps us access this data attribute value.