So what are these different features about?
Well let's start with symbols, though we'll later also have a look at iterators and generators, reflect
and the proxy API
but what are symbols? Symbols and that's really interesting and
good to know
are a primitive value.
I did mention that before in the course, we learned about strings, numbers, booleans there,
now symbols are also just yet another primitive value,
symbols are not objects, not reference values, they are primitive values.
You can use symbols as object property identifiers, as keys in objects
so to say, just like you can use numbers and strings. There are built-in symbols and you can also
build your own symbols and we'll see both in this module
and that's the unique feature or the special feature about symbols,
they guarantee uniqueness, every symbol you build is unique.
So you can use symbols to add a key, to add a property to an object where you know that this name won't
exist there yet because you just created the symbol,
it will be unique and you can't override an existing symbol of the same name there because every symbol
is standalone and unique and that's the biggest feature of symbols.
Now let's see how we use them and what this uniqueness actually means.
For this I get a very simple project which you find attached, just an empty HTML file where we import
app.js which is also empty
and then I just open this here, because I will not build a fancy user interface here,
as I mentioned all these features are less about end user interaction, they're more about code quality
and writing code that you could share with others which can have certain features that ensure that other
people work with your code correctly
and as I said let's start with symbols.
Let's create a new symbol, let's maybe name it uid for userId but you can name it however you
want and then you create a symbol by calling symbol. Important, not new symbol,
that would not work but just symbol, like a function basically.
So symbol then creates a new symbol.
If we now console log uid, let's see what we got there.
If we save that and we reload this page, we see
we got a symbol there,
right,
and that's not too exciting but that's in the end a symbol here.
Now you can pass an identifier to symbol, like uid, which is only for logging purposes, for identification
purposes for you as a developer,
now if I reload here, you see that's part of the symbol and we can identify this symbol by that ID.
This does not mean that this symbol now has an internal name, uid or anything like that, this is
really just an identification criteria for you as a developer.
Now how can we use such a symbol?
Well let's say we have a person object and we want to have an ID in there, abc or p1 or whatever
it is, I should add an equal sign here and we also want have a name in there, Max and an age, 30.
Now this is an object, how we created it multiple times throughout the course
and here I got an ID property which is just a regular property,
it's not a symbol, it's just a regular key name.
Now here we'll have to do some mental yoga,
let's imagine you're building a library where you expose certain objects with the users of your library,
just like the axios library which we used earlier exposes the axios object if you remember.
Now in the objects you expose, you might have certain keys, certain properties which you want to ensure
are not overridden by the users of your library.
So let's say we had some library, maybe some authentication library which creates user objects and in
the user object, you want to give the users of your library,
the developers using your library the full power to change the objects your library spits out but you
want to ensure that all the user objects your library generates always have some ID identifier which
can't be overridden.
Now if your library would generate objects like this, then of course, let's say this is coming from a
library,
if I'm the consumer of such a library, I could always change the ID here like that. This is one
scenario where symbols could come in handy.
Let's say this here is library land
and this here is app land
using the library.
So we're authoring this library and then someone else is using it
here with this code.
So this is exposed by our library, someone else is using it and we want to make sure that this should
not be possible.
Now that's where we could use a symbol, instead of adding an ID like this if we want to ensure that
only we,
so only the code in our library knows how to interact with that ID,
well then we could just add this symbol as a key and we don't do this by repeating the symbol name, this
would just add a regular key name to ID, instead we use this dynamic property ID syntax you learned
about in this course where you use square brackets here and then you could point at some variable
which holds the key name you want to use,
well in this case I point at this uid constant and we'll therefore use this symbol as an identifier
here now and then we could have p1 here.
Now this is a valid object but the thing is if we then use this object in our code, so we the developer
using the library use that object and we add or try to override the ID with this code, we can do that
but we won't interfere with this library internal ID here.
So if I console log my user object here, you will see that the symbol is untouched by this line here,
if I now reload here, you see there we still got this symbol identifier and since we know the symbol
in the library
but this code is hidden away from the users of our library, users got no way of accessing this property
here because they don't know this symbol
and if you would try to access something like symbol uid here,
so I create a new symbol on the fly and try to access this symbol on the user object, you'll see that
I get undefined for that because even though I use the same identifier here for the symbol, as I mentioned
this is really just for debugging purposes. This technically still is a new symbol, totally unrelated
to this symbol,
they are totally different objects.
You can also see this if you console log symbol uid and check if that is equal to symbol uid
and you'll see you get false as a response here as an output because these are not equal if I reload here.
So that's the idea behind symbols,
we do have unique identifiers which can't be accidentally overridden and only if we use that exact
same symbol again,
so inside of the library, if I then access this symbol again, I could change it.
So here I am of course using the exact same symbol I created here
and therefore not a copy of it or something like that but really the same symbol and hence I can change
it but if I don't expose this symbol as part of my library, users of the library have no way of using
it.
So now with that if I save that and I also console log user here and save that now, you will see that
now I change that symbol userId to p3 but I did that inside of the library,
it's not available outside of it.
Now of course you're not limited to using symbols inside of libraries,
this is just a common example or a use case where it might be particularly useful.
Also be aware that you don't need to add such an identifier,
this here also is a perfectly fine symbol, you don't have to add the identifier,
you just can add one so that you as a developer if you console log that or if you use the debugging
tools in the browser, that you can identify a symbol and you remember where in your code you set this
up, you technically don't have to add that.