Now besides different ways of sending HttpRequests, we also can send different data,
in theory at least, it always depends on the server and the URL you're sending this to, which kind
of data the server accepts, for example our dummy server here really only works with JSON data. When we
for example send the data to fake create a post,
then we have to add JSON data there,
it does not accept any other data but of course you might be working with different APIs in your
project and there, different data might be accepted as well.
Now you can send files, you can send binary data and add this as a body here, so you could add a pointer
at a file which a user picked in a file picker for example or another very popular data format,
you could add FormData
Now let's see what FormData is
and for that let's go to create post, here
I create my post object, add this to send HttpRequest and in there,
we basically convert this to JSON and add it to the request.
Now we can also add FormData instead.
Now again, this API does not support it but other APIs might and hence I want to show to you how that would
work. For that, here in create post,
let's say we can create FormData by creating a new constant, fd for FormData,
name is up to you, by calling new FormData.
That's a constructor function built into Javascript or built into the browser, provided in Javascript.
Now FormData builds a new object to which you can add key-value pairs,
so a bit like a Javascript object like this but internally or when it's sent over the wire, it will be
sent in a different way than JSON data,
it's not JSON format, it has a different format as you will see. Now to FormData,
you can append new entries with the append method and there, every entry has a key and a value,
so for example we could add a title and then pass on the title we're getting here as a value for this
key,
same is true for the body,
here we could pass in our content value and also our userId, append userId, userId,
now we would have prepared such a FormData object.
Now let's add fd here,
FormData
to this request, so let's pass in this as a third argument and inside of sendHttpRequest, we now have
to change the request a little bit,
I'll comment out the headers because I no longer want to tell the server that I'm sending JSON data
because I'm not and instead, set body not equal to the stringified data version but just to data
which should already be FormData and for FormData, the fetch API will automatically see that it's form
data and automatically send the right headers.
So if we set this and we reload, let's try it out. Let's create a new post with FormData and click add.
Now if we inspect the network tab, we see the API is quite forgiving,
it still reports a success because it really doesn't care about the data we send in the end because
it's a fake API
but if we scroll down in the headers, we see we add a different data,
it's indeed FormData and that's a special type of data which is added to the outgoing request. If we
have a look at the other headers, we see that there content type was automatically set to this value which
was automatically derived by the browser in the end.
Now the advantage of FormData is that for one, you might find it more structured to build your data
like this, b) a second great thing about it is that you can easily add files, if you append some file,
you can have any identifier you want here,
you could point at a file here, for example picked in a file input and then as a third argument, even
provide a file name like photo.png which the server can use.
So you can easily send a mixture of text, content text, key-value pairs and files to the server which
can be really convenient depending on what you build and a third advantage is
you can also use this to automatically parse a form and that's actually what I also want to show you
here.
Let's say we don't manually add title and body but instead we want to utilize the form fields which
we already have here.
Essentially what we want to do here is we want to replicate the default behavior
the browser would have if we wouldn't call prevent default upon a submission.
When we call that, we make sure the browser doesn't collect the FormData and send it to a server.
Now we still want to make sure that the browser doesn't collect and send
but we then manually want to collect it in the same way the browser would and for that, you just have
to pass a pointer to your form element, to FormData,
so to the constructor and form here really is just this pointer I select up there,
it points at the form element in the document and if we pass that to FormData, Javascript will try
to automatically collect all the data from the form.
Now for it to succeed though, you need to make sure that your inputs have a name attribute, title
and here, may be content or actually body because the API wants a field named body. The name attribute
is important
otherwise FormData is not able to identify these inputs and get the data out of there and store it
correctly in the FormData.
Now you can then still append extra data which might not be included in the form, like the userId
here and with all of that, let's give it a try.
Let's reload a new post, does this work and let's click add here and if we now inspect this outgoing request
and we scroll down, we see this was still populated but now automatically from the form.
Now again, it's important to realize that not all APIs support FormData,
if an API wants JSON data, you can't use this
no matter how convenient you find it to be but if you have an API, an API endpoint, so a specific URL
HTTP method combination that does support FormData you can use this approach and therefore form
data besides JSON is also an important data structure
you should be aware of when we're talking about sending data with HttpRequests from client side
Javascript to a server.