There is one special conditional expression which we haven't seen and used thus far and that's the so-called
ternary operator or the ternary expression. It's important to understand that if statements themselves
return no values,
right,
you just dump them into your code to then execute code conditionally,
it's not like a function or a calculation with some operators, an if statement doesn't return any value
which you could store somewhere.
Therefore this for example does not work,
you can't assign an if statement to a constant because this will not return anything, an
if statement won't return anything and this will actually be a syntax error therefore, this is
not allowed. But maybe you have code where you want to use a different value in let's say user name or
any other constant or variable and the concrete value you do want to save in that constant depends on some
condition. Actually that is something which we have in our code already, there here in attack monster,
we have max damage and log event and these are variables that hold conditional values, they either hold,
for max damage, attack value or strong attack value based on this condition and thereafter we use that
variable.
So in the end here, we have a variable where we store data that depends on some condition but I do so
by first setting up the variable and not assigning any value
and then we have an if condition which we don't try to store in any variable or constant because that wouldn't
work
as I mentioned
and then inside of the if condition, we assign values to max damage in this case and to log event as
well.
This is valid code and this works but this snippet here doesn't work
but it would be convenient to have some kind of if statement that would work like this where we kind
of return a value in it and then that returned value get stored in a variable, would save us some extra
lines of code.
Well there is a solution for that,
you can use the so-called ternary operator in such cases.
It allows you to have an inline if statement if you will, without the if keyword because that can't be
used inline but with the question mark and colon operators here and together, they make up that ternary
operator.
Now the logic here is simple,
you first put your condition which you want to check
and there you can have any condition, you could have an if statement, including multiple conditions combined
with and and or, then you have the question mark and thereafter you have the value you want to use if the
condition is true
and that's important,
you have a value here,
so something which could be stored in a constant.
You don't put more complex code here, not multiline code, not multiple expressions,
you can't use an if statement here or define a new variable here, instead here after the question mark,
you need some value that could be stored in a constant or a variable in any other place as well,
so which you could direct assign with the equal sign to a variable or constant, and then you have a
colon and then you have your else value and you need to specify this.
So omitting that else value is not allowed,
that would be a syntax error as well.
So here, we have the isLogin condition which probably is a boolean or as some truthy or falsy value
and if that is true, we store Max in user name,
if it's not true, I store null in user name.
This is a ternary operator in action and we can actually use that in our code as well,
we can change that code to not use this if statement and let me make it very clear that there is nothing
wrong with using an if statement like this,
in some cases using explicit if statements like this might also lead to more readable code than using ternary
operators but in some cases, you also can save some extra code by using ternary operators and
for example here we can comment out the if statement and set max damage here equal to and now I check if mode
is equal to mode attack and then if that's true, separated by a question mark, I assign the value to max
damage that should be used if mode is equal to mode attack,
so basically attack value here and otherwise, separated by a colon,
I use the else case,
so in this case strong attack value
and now we set that variable to either attack value or to strong attack value based on this condition,
so on this condition, if mode is equal to mode attack. Now of course, since i therefore never really assign a value
here, previously we did do it because we assigned values in the if statement,
now we initialize this variable with a value right away
thanks to this ternary expression, we can also switch this to be a constant because I never assign a
new value, we never use the equal sign
after max damage again in this function here and of course we can do the same for the log event.
We can also switch this to a constant and now assign a value based on this check here. So check whether
mode is equal to mode attack
and if that is the case, then we have a value of log event player attack,
otherwise we have a value of log event strong attack here and we can also structure this across multiple
lines, like this.
I did this with the auto formatting shortcut, as you see it's no problem, as always in Javascript you
can write your code along multiple lines here, Javascript then finds out where this ends with the
help of the semicolon here.
So with that, we remove that if statement and we saved some extra code
here, we are able to initialize these constants right away and therefore we are able to use constants
instead of variables
and as I mentioned, this is now not strictly better than using the if statement, absolutely do use the
if statement, especially if you had more complex conditions here and more complex values where you may
be also run some calculation first of all,
so where you then all of a sudden have very long lines of code, then you might actually prefer having
an if statement where this is more structured and readable. If you have relatively short conditions
and value assignments as we have it here however, then using the ternary expression is a fine alternative
that can save you some extra code. Well and with that we should see that if I reload here and I start
my game, that still works as before but now with the help of that ternary expression. It's also worth
noting that a ternary expression can also have nested conditions,
so here where a value is expected, you can have some other check and then have a nested ternary expression
where you then have the nested value and the nested alternative value here
but you should use that with caution because that can quickly lead to very hard to read code and using
a real if statement with else if blocks often is the better alternative to deeply nested ternary expressions.
Nonetheless it does work, it is supported and
it is something you can use, especially if you have short code, short conditions and it's not getting
unreadable.