So we're done with this module, was a large module with a lot of content about arrays, different ways
of creating and accessing arrays, different ways of manipulating arrays,
all these amazing array methods which help you transform arrays, sort them, add data, remove data,
splice which was a really convenient method to manipulate an array. You also learned about the spread
operator and array destructuring and we had a look at sets and maps which arguably are niche features
which you don't need every day but which every Javascript developer should know and you might encounter
situations and applications where you can actually improve your code, improve your performance, improve
your memory usage by using set, map or weak set and weak map even to improve your application.
So overall, a lot of key concepts covered here,
of course the array things, the array methods we had a look at and so on,
these are the most important things we worked with and these are the things we'll of course also as
always encounter throughout many modules in this course and which you will encounter throughout your
entire career as a Javascript developer because arrays are just such a crucial data structure and being
able to work with them, to manipulate them and so on is super important therefore.