So let's work on the output here of our log, of the calculation we did
so to say. Here, I in the end want to output the last calculation we did
and for that I want to output a string here and I'll create it with back ticks so that I can inject values
dynamically with this dollar sign curly brace syntax because what I want to output is current result
plus and then the new result.
Now the problem we have with that of course is that after this line, our current result already changed,
so I rather create this description here, maybe just name it
description or calc description or whatever you like
and grab the template literal as it's called and move it up here and then here, I refer to current result
before we change it because I run this line before this line and I want to add my number here. So I can
copy this code and add this here as well
and actually we of course don't need to parse this as an integer because I will need it as a text anyways,
we're building a text here after all, so I can also just use it like this.
Side note, when using this embedding syntax here in a template literal,
any values you pass in, even if they are numbers, will be converted to a string anyways,
so this implicitly calls to string anyways you could say, so this is automatically treated as a string
here.
And now I build my description here and output this as well and reformat the code to use these two blanks
here as indentation
and now we're building the description before we run the calculation.
And now if I save this and I reload and I enter five here, we see the description of the last calculation
we performed whenever we run a calculation. We don't see the full log because that would be way
more complex to build, a bit beyond what we can do right now
but we see the exact calculation that was just executed that led to this new result.
Now with that, there is however more we can change about this function because what we're doing here
is, we have a bit of code repetition.
Now in general, as a programmer, you want to avoid code repetition as good as you can, as much as you can
because if you repeat code, you write too much and that takes time and you want to save time
and in addition, if you ever need to change something about that piece of code, about that logic you wrote
there, chances are that you need to change it in a couple of different places. So therefore, you want to
avoid repeating yourselves, so that whenever you need to change that piece of code you wrote, you'll
only need to change it in one place, instead of 10 places or something like that.
So here for example, extracting that user input value,
let's say we renamed this user input constant here to usr input,
well then I have to change it in two places, usr input, usr input.
Of course that's not too bad but imagine that this would be a longer script, would be very annoying.
So it's better to then create a new constant, since I never plan on reassigning a value, which I could
name user number or better maybe, entered number and that could be this code snippet here.
So where I get the user input and parse it as an integer and now we can use entered number here because
that string interpolation or embedding syntax here doesn't care whether that's a string or a number,
it will convert it to a string anyways and we can use it here and
now the advantage of this is that whenever something changes here, like the name of this constant, we
only need to change it here and not in these two places.
So even though I added a new line of code now, we actually did something good because we're now more
flexible and we don't repeat ourselves.
Well of course, we repeat that name of the constant but that's something we can't change,
however we make sure we don't repeat the entire logic here
even though of course that's not too much logic here but you could have a more complex calculation and
you would therefore even save more repetition.
You could also take it one step further and add a brand new function, get user input for example.
Again I name this function like this because I want to describe what the function does
and this is a function which should actually give me the user input as a number, so we could also name
it get user input number or get user number input
if you want to be very clear but in the end, you want to give a clear idea of what this function does. Well
and in there, I want to return this logic here where I get that user input and parse it as an integer
so that here I can just call get user number input as a function.
So here I now call that manually instead of adding it to an event listener because whenever this function
runs, I want to run this function as well which I now use to outsource this logic,
that's especially great of course if you have more code here, multiple lines of logic for example that
you want to share,
you can then all put it into a function and call that function in any place in your code where you want
to execute it.
Right now that's only one place but that will soon change because we got more than one button here, so
let's work on the other buttons
now.