Now let's understand what happens here.
Of course we can't expect that this function returns an object right because we don't have any return
keyword in there.
It only returns an object because of that new keyword.
If we wouldn't have new here, if we just call a person like this, you will see that now if I repeat this,
I get an error,
cannot read property greet of undefined because we would be calling greet on person and person on the
other hand indeed is undefined because we just execute the person function,
this function returns nothing so it returns no value so no value is stored in this constant and on no
value, on undefined we can't call greet.
So calling person like this won't work because we effectively call it like a regular function,
the fact that it starts with a capital character is just a convention, not something that changes something
magically in Javascript.
Indeed it's the new keyword that matters
and you could use a lowercase p here like that and it would still work
and I would have to rename that constant here though
otherwise we have a name clash and it would just work. If I execute this again,
it works as before.
So the naming here really is just a convention which you should follow but which has no technical impact,
it's the new keyword that matters.
What the new keyword does behind the scenes
and that's effectively also what it does for classes
is it executes such a function, in there
it sets this equal to the object that's going to be created, so equal to an empty object initially if
you will, then it adds all these properties to this empty object and then it returns this
and this is this object.
This is effectively what's happening here you could say, this is what the new keyword does here behind
the scenes when you call a function with it, with new and that is a special scenario, a special feature
provided by Javascript using such a constructor function.
So now that we understand a bit how constructor functions work and that the new keyword matters,
let's understand how this function relates to this class then. In the end, this class here is just something
we call syntactical sugar for this constructor function because defining blueprints like this can be
a bit cumbersome,
it can be confusing
that you write
a normal function
and suddenly it doesn't behave like a normal function because you use new and especially if you're coming
from a different programming language, you might be used to having classes,
this is why classes were introduced to give us an easier way of writing these blueprint definitions.
Now behind the scenes, classes also do more than just set up such constructor functions,
they also help us with a concept called prototypes into which I'll dive in this module as well
but generally this class does just create something like that for us.
Now, the constructor function we have inside of a class effectively allows us to define this class
body, so all the instructions that should run when an object is created based on the blueprint inside
of a class
because in a constructor function like this, it's obvious that whenever we create a new object based
on it, all the code in that function executes,
so this is great for initializing it, for setting it up, for reaching out to some server or doing whatever
you want. In a class you have no such place,
well almost, you have that constructor function, this special method in there to be precise where everything
you place in it also executes when this object gets created,
so whatever goes into that constructor method here in your class is the same that would go into this
person constructor function.
Now your methods created like this actually are treated a bit differently,
that's something you should be aware of and I'll come back to how they're treated differently in a second
once we learn a bit more about another concept which is the concept of prototypes.
Now what's up with that?