So don't put important information into your frontend code.
Now let's move on to the next attack which is the most dangerous attack or the most dangerous attack
pattern you can expose in your client side Javascript code and I'm specifically talking about the client
side, so about the side which runs in the browser because the server side by default is way more secure
and when we talk about server side attack patterns, they are not specific to Javascript, whereas cross
site scripting and exposing security details is.
So for the server side, there is a different range of potential attacks,
one of them being CSRF attacks, others being SQL injection for example if you use a SQL database
and I'm not talking about them here because they're not primarily related to Javascript. In my Node.js
course which talks way more about server side code writing and so on,
I do talk about more security holes
you could expose on a server in general.
So back to the Javascript specific ones and there, to cross site scripting attacks, also shortened or
abbreviated with XSS.
This is an attack pattern where malicious Javascript code gets injected into your application and is
executed there.
Now I'll show you an example for this because it can sound abstract at first but this is really a dangerous
attack pattern,
you have to imagine if people are able to add code to your application which all users of your application
therefore execute, they are effectively executing code on the behalf of these users
and at the same time on the behalf of your application on the machines of those users and your code
can do anything the code you write could do as well,
so your code could send requests to certain domains which might allow access by your application with
the right CORS headers,
the code might read the local browser storage of the user and send that to some server of the malicious
user who injected the code and much more.
If you're able to inject Javascript code into another page so that it runs for every visitor of that
page, you're able to gather a lot of data about these visitors, potential security relevant data included
and you're also able to fake a lot of things and send a lot of requests, maybe to your own malicious
pages on the behalf of the application and only the behalf of the users visiting that application where you
injected your code into so that's really dangerous. You've got full behind the scenes control if you
inject code into another page. An example for that would be unchecked user generated content and I want
to show you that example so that you understand what the problem is. When we talk about cross site scripting
attacks, let's go back to our application here, to this share a place application and there let's generate
an address,
6th Avenue, find that place and then we have this shareable link here.
This is the link which does not use our backend code with a database but which encodes all information
into that URL, this attack pattern would also work with a backend database though
and I will come back to that in a second.
So here we have this link, we can visit this page and we see this page here,
so that's of course not too fancy,
how could this be insecure?
Now if we have a look at our code, there we have the my-place.js file and
this is the file responsible for displaying the page and this title here on this page once we visit
this link with the encoded information, specifically there we set the title text content to our address.
Now what if we would set, not the text content here which just sets the text node but in an HTML,
eother as a mistake or because we actually do expect address to be more than just a plain string which
it is in application but which it might not be in all applications and therefore since this might be
HTML code we want to output, we want to set innerHTML to not just render a text node but all the HTML
code which is inside of address.
If we do that and I save that and reload, we get the same output as before,
however if we inspect this in the developer tools, keep in mind we're setting the innerHTML code of the
h1 tag
and what we set there is the end what we send to address which is currently this part of the URL.
Now what if this part were actually a script
however? What if I prepared a URL which I want to share with other users which contains a script
as the address and not every user might carefully look at that
URL and therefore this might not be seen by all users who visit this page with whom I shared this
link.
So there, I could try to run an alert where I say hi there and hit enter,
now what you see is now this is injected here,
now we don't see a title here,
instead we see the script was indeed added here because I'm rendering this as innerHTML.
Now you also see it doesn't seem to execute though because actually modern browsers have a security
mechanism where they don't execute script tags which are output with the help of innerHTML because
of this exact scenario that you try or that someone tries to abuse a security hole in your application
and inject Javascript code which executes on your behalf, also keep in mind that normal visitors
off the page of course would probably not see that.
They might wonder why they don't see a title but they don't typically check the developer tools to see
what's in there,
so they might not see that.
Now still, this doesn't really seem to hurt us,
it's certainly unexpected but since the browser doesn't execute that script, we're fine, right?
Well turns out there's more than one way of executing script code, besides these script tags which indeed
are prevented by the browser to execute,
what if we added an image here with a source that does not exist and then add an onError handler where
we then instead execute our Javascript code,
this is a valid HTML element.
Now the source is not found, therefore onError should trigger and we can add this kind of event listener
to our elements,
we as a developer don't want to do that because it's not really a good way of writing code
but as an attacker it's great, we can add Javascript code that executes right on a HTML element.
If I now hit enter, indeed we should see hi there, in Chrome at least
and we see that here because this HTML code is injected here,
This image tag is injected here, the source is not found
so the onError handler executes and therefore this script, this alert executes. Now this alert of course
is just annoying but keep in mind I can share this link with anyone, I can post it in a Facebook group
for people to visit it
and of course an alert is not that dangerous, it's just annoying and unexpected
but here we could be doing other stuff too,
we could be doing anything which might be security relevant.
I could write a script in here and yes, we can write a longer script in here simply by separating our
lines of semicolons, where I access the local storage, read data from it or read data from the local cookies
and send that to my own malicious server for example. Visitors of the page will not see anything there,
they don't get an alert,
they don't get an error,
I could even if I'm really bad in addition render a h2 tag here with 6th Avenue and then people might
not see anything. If I now hit enter here,
you don't get an error,
okay I
didn't format this, probably I should fix that but other than that, the page works as it should
and here in the onError handler, in this script we can do whatever we want as an attacker. We can steal
confidential data from browser storage,
we can send requests on behalf of the user who visit this page with this link to any backend we want
and that is therefore really dangerous. Here,
this is a security hole we have in this application, we have this hole because here, we're outputting
innerHTML.
Now how can we fix that?
One solution to fix this XSS security hole we have here is to use text continents instead of
innerHTML.
If we do that and we visit this, you'll see now the code which previously was executed and rendered as
HTML is now output as text and therefore if we had any Javascript code in here, like for example our
alert again
where I say hi would not execute.
So now we automatically are not vulnerable to cross site scripting attack and if you never use
innerHTML anywhere in your code, you of course rule out a lot of potential attack patterns
but with that alone you're not totally safe yet.
For one, sometimes you might need innerHTML,
so then you need a way around potential malicious code and in addition, it's not just innerHTML.
If you're for some reason setting the onError handler of some HTML element dynamically to some user
generated content in some way,
Maybe you just want to have a user generated text which is output in here,
well still then whenever you inject any user generated code anywhere into the DOM, this could be
a potential issue so you always want to make sure you either inject it as only text with text content
or if you set some other attribute of an element to some user generated content and potentially Javascript
code could execute there, like with these onError
and so on handlers, then you want to sanitize user generated content before you output it.
So for example here, if if we really needed to use innerHTML, we want to sanitize the content before
we output it here.
Now sanitizing means that we strip away any Javascript syntax we might have in there, that starts with
simple script tags but should also include common keywords like alert and so on.
Now how can you work around the problem that you might need to inject user generated content somewhere
where Javascript could execute?
So you have no way of using a text content
node here for example and you still want to make sure that the user generated data you're getting here
is secure and doesn't contain any scripts that execute?
You can use packages like sanitize-html.
This is a package which basically helps you sanitize text and remove any unwanted tags in there so that
invalid code doesn't execute in there.
Now one import note can be found here in the description right away,
this sanitization actually should be done on the server if possible,
that simply means that if we were in our Node.js application here, we might want to store any user input
we get,
so in our case the address, before we put it into the database. So we sanitize it with this package for
example on the server-side before we store it so that the sanitized code is stored in a database because
that's also something I mentioned, this attack pattern does not only exist if you can inject it into the
URL, it also exists of course if you store something in the database because here, I could be entering
my malicious code, like this,
click find place and find place triggers our server to store this in a database,
then we have a problem.
So I want to make sure that whatever I send here is validated on this server before it's stored in a
database and you can do this with sanitize-html as well.
You can also use this in the browser but that is a bit too late,
it's not it's not too late from a security perspective but you still might have hacked or adjusted code
in your database which you also don't want,
it doesn't do any harm in there but it's not ideal,
if you ever forget to sanitize a browser, you then have an issue. So try to sanitize on the server not
on the browser.
Anyways if you wanted to sanitize then, well then you would just need to make sure you have this package
installed and you then can run the sanitize-html function,
pass your user generated content so that variable which holds the content the user has to sanitize-html
and then it will strip away things like that, it will ensure that this is not part of the output,
that instead you are able to render HTML but only secure HTML,
this is what sanitize-html does.
Now how do you use that package?
Well you can actually use the Node.js recommendation here, run this command here in your project so
I quit my dev server and run npm install sanitize-html with the --save flag
Now this will install it here as a dependency and in my-place.js, we can now import sanitize-html
from sanitize-html
and now here, whenever we want to output or inject some user generated content into an innerHTML tag
or into another place where Javascript could execute, we run sanitizeHtml address
in this case here.
And if I do that and then we restart the development server here, with this added and the file saved,
you will see that
now if I reload this page here, the alert is not thrown,
instead now I just have my header here
even though I still have my dangerous code in there but that was stripped away by sanitize-html. So
just to show this again, if I remove that and we reload it, we get the alert,
if we add it again and I save it, we don't get the alert.
So now we protect ourselves against cross site scripting attacks.
Again this is best done on the server before it's stored in a database
but in this example here, in this app where I don't have a server side, where it's all client side code,
where it's just data that's part of URL, then of course our only chance is to do that sanitization
in the browser and then we can do it like this
and we're now making sure that this specific cross site scripting attack hole is fixed.