So we have these different layers of performance optimization we could say, we have the startup time and
the runtime
and now let's have a look at the different things which affect performance there.
Now of course there are a lot of tiny factors which influence it but there are a couple of bigger categories
and potential improvements I'd like to think about when we have a look at these different layers. For
the startup time, an important factor is the size of our scripts,
so simply the question how big is our Javascript file
we're forcing the user to download before anything is able to happen on the page?
Remember when I said a couple of minutes ago that we have two parts when we think about startup time -
the time it takes to display something on the screen and the time it takes until the user is able to
do something with that screen,
well the script size can affect both.
If your script renders a lot of visual parts on the screen, then of course it affects how quickly the
user is able to see something on the screen but it most certainly will impact how quickly the user is
able to interact
because if your script is needed to add event listeners to a button and so on, then of course even if the button
is visible the user will not be able to do anything with it if your script hasn't finished downloading
yet and isn't available yet.
So therefore the script size, the size of the script file really plays an important role here,
the bigger it is the longer it takes users to download them and the longer it will take users to work
with your page and keep in mind that not every user is visiting your page from a great Internet connection.
Users might be using slow devices in slow network areas and therefore even a script file which is only
100kb big can take a couple of seconds to download and that could lead to a bad user experience.
Now besides the script size, it's also the amount of HTTP round trips and I covered this earlier
when we talked about Javascript modules and when we introduced webpack to bundle them into a single
or a few bundles
and the reason for a that is that
if we're working with a lot of script files and of course the same is true for a lot of CSS files
by the way, then the browser has to download all these files to make your page work and every
HttpRequest that needs to be sent to download something has a certain base cost it takes to set up that
request and send it, no matter how big the file is which you're downloading.
So the more HTTP round trips it takes to finally have the final state of your page, the longer
it will take until your page is ready to run and therefore
this is definitely a part you want to optimize and of course we already started optimizing both the
size and the number of HTTP round trips by adding webpack which does minify and optimize our code and which
also bundles our code together.
So now what about the runtime performance? There,
it's of course all about optimizing our code execution. If we're working in the browser environment,
that also includes one important aspect and that is DOM access,
so when we work with the DOM, when we add elements, when we remove elements, we want to avoid unnecessary
code execution, we want to write code which is efficient to execute and we definitely want to avoid unnecessary
DOM operations because if we unnecessarily for example re-render too many elements on the screen even
though maybe just one element needs to change, then we affect performance because it turns out working
with the DOM is really expensive
from a performance perspective because Javascript has to talk to the browser, the browser has to go through
the DOM and find the place you want to change, it then has to create a new element, it has to add the
element or remove one, whatever you're doing and that all are a lot of steps.
Now of course we're still talking about milliseconds here but they can really add up,
so being efficient here is super important as you will see in this module.
The other big factor are memory leaks, it's easy to introduce leaks and not all leaks are horrible, you
might not even recognize them
and I can tell you a lot of web pages out there do have tiny memory leaks but if you have bigger ones,
they can really add up and can lead to your page becoming slower or to actually even crash in the worst
case scenario. Now it's also interesting to think about different ways of solving one and the same problem
in Javascript,
so to find code alternatives with better performance. I will show an example for this throughout
this module. In the end here this is related to the first box here in the runtime performance part,
the code execution which we want to optimize. When you for example loop through an array, it turns out
you have a couple of different ways of doing so and they don't all have the same performance,
so that's also a thing you could think about and you could try to optimize. Related to that is another
approach which is called micro optimizations,
you can optimize certain parts of your code and actually looping through an array with a quicker alternative
would be one example for such a micro optimization, you can optimize parts of your code for specific use
cases. You could opt to use a certain data structure because it's a bit quicker than that other approach
you used before.
Now generally, you want to shy away from such micro optimizations though and I will come back to those
throughout the module and explain why you should be really careful when you try to optimize everything
but it is a thing which can matter in niche scenarios and very large applications,
the most important parts you want to care about are the first two boxes here in the runtime performance
part and of course all the boxes in the startup time performance part. And of course as mentioned, always
keep in mind that Javascript is just one part,
when we talk about optimizing our web page, it also includes things like writing efficient CSS and so
on
but that's simply not the focus of this course and Javascript typically is the most important thing to
optimize.
So with that we're almost done with the theory,
let's now find out how we can approach this whole performance optimization thing.