For this I prepared a little starting project which of course find attached to this video and you can
simply download that, run npm install in the extracted folder to set up all the dependencies I have here,
I don't have many dependencies, I only use webpack and then we have a very simple application here in
app.js, a Javascript application, frontend Javascript where I import some stuff and then have some
code to basically setup an event listener to a button and add a user to a list of users
when we click that button. I got util.js which holds the functions and importing into app.js
I'm using Node.js modules syntax here simply because that's a bit easier to test and doesn't require
a complex build workflow setup, on which I simply didn't want to focus on this video but I use webpack
to then bundle this all up and get a main.js file which is the file we then use.
Now what you can do is you can simply double click index.html,
I got no dev server in place here or anything like that, simply to not focus too much on the frontend
workflow
and if you did double click on that file, this is what you'll get,
you can enter some data and add a user and that is all we can do here.
So it's a relatively simple app but that is great for starting with testing because we can easily confirm
if our tests make sense,
if they do test something we would test manually as well.
So this is the application and now let's write some tests. Now for writing tests,
we need some tools to help us with creating these tests.
What do we need?
We typically need three kinds of tools -
we need a test runner which is simply a tool that executes our tests and summarizes the results and
gives us some output on the results, we can use something like mocha there,
that is a popular test runner.
We also have assertion libraries and there we define our tested logics, our expected outcomes,
so these assertion libraries give us tools to define expectations, to define comparisons, conditions we
want to check as part of our tests. There Chai is common or a popular assertion library, though what
we will use is a very popular library both for running tests and asserting and that is jest, jest
is relatively new
or at least it was rewritten not that long ago and it's a very popular library for writing tests because
it is both a test runner and an assertion library and it's really powerful and a lot of fun to work
with. For end-to-end,
we also sometimes need a headless browser, so basically a browser where we don't have to click manually
but where we can use the browser API,
the DOM and so on without a user interface necessarily because we'll analyze it in code anyways and
there we can use puppeteer which is a very popular solution for that.
We need that headless browser mostly for end-to-end testing whereas the test runner and the assertion library
are also needed for that but also then are the only things we need for unit and integration tests.
Now let's start with jest and with unit tests and you can simply google for Jest to find
jestjs.io,
the official web page of jestjs and there, I can only recommend trying that out, getting started, diving
into the official docs to learn way more but of course I'll also walk you through all the basics in my videos
here.
So we'll start installing Jest now and for that, let's switch over to our project and in there let's
run npm install --save dev just because jest will be a development dependency of our project
and it will be the tool we use for running our tests and for checking our outcomes or for writing some
conditions, some assertions as it's called. So this will now install and with it installed, we can write
our first test and I will write my test for functions defined in util.js.