So that was a lot of talking about selecting elements but of course it is an important part of working
with the DOM and I want to be sure that you really know how that works and which options you have there.
Now with that all selected though, let's add an event listener to the start add movie button because
that's what we all came here for,
we want to make sure that we can open that add movie modal and that should happen when we click that
button.
So here we can use good old add event listener which we didn't have a closer look at in this module
but we already saw this earlier in the course and I will have a closer look at events and how you can
handle them in a separate module because there's a lot you can say about events and it's just not the
focus of this module. Adding an event listener like this is something we saw before though, so we can
easily add a click event listener like that with this line here and now we want to add a function. We
could use an anonymous function here
but I will actually create a standalone function here, simply for readability so that this is clearly
readable and easy to see so that our code is also very understandable. For that,
you can define a function whichever way you want with the function keyword and the declaration approach,
with the expression approach where you stored a function in a constant or with the expression approach
where you use an arrow function.
That's the approach I will use here
but you don't have to follow that,
you can use either of the three ways of creating a function you learned.
So here, I will name this toggleMovieModal because that's what I want to do,
when this function gets called, I want to open the modal if it is open and I want to close it if it is
not open.
Alternatively of course, we add separate functions for opening and closing but I think we can combine
this quite nicely here in this app,
so let's do it like this. Then as I mentioned here, I add my arrow function, alternative would be to use
a regular function here or even a function declaration as I mentioned, let me move that up here and now
inside of that function, we can use the add movie modal constant, so this one which points at this div
which has that add modal ID and there in the index.html file, there on this add movie modal, we're
selecting this div,
right so there we have that modal class andin app.css, we see that if we add a visible class to these
same element where we have the modal class, we'll actually set display to block,
so we need to add or remove this visible class to show or hide the modal.
So here in toggleMovieModal, we can do that in two different ways -
we can set the class name property here but then we manually have to keep track of which classes we
have and we have to make sure we don't accidentally drop a class which should always be present, like
modal and card,
these classes should always be there
so we have to make sure we don't accidentally remove them by setting class name here to something else
which is not supported by CSS or which misses crucial classes and therefore the better approach actually
is to use the class list object which you learned about and there, the toggle method because this does
exactly what we want,
it checks whether a class is already on the element and if it is, it removes it
and otherwise it adds it and
we want to toggle the visible class.
So this will always keep all other classes on the element but add or remove this class based on its
current state,
so based on the question whether this class already is part of the element or not.
So this will actually hopefully show our modal,
we just have to connect it to the click listener by pointing at toggleMovieModal without parentheses
here of course because we don't want to execute it immediately, we just want to point at this function.
And with that if we now save this and we reload this page and we click this button, indeed this modal opens
up. Now currently we got no real way of closing it other than clicking this button again, clicking cancel
for example won't close it, clicking anywhere else won't close it
and I would also argue it's a bit hard to see. It would be nice if the background would darken, if we
had some black or grayish overlay over the background, also so that we can't click anything else whilst
we are interacting with that overlay.
So that will be the next task, it will be to select this backdrop because that will be exactly what we need
here if we check the CSS code, there if we search for backdrop, you see this in the end is this styling
here which sets the background to a transparent blackish color and positions this as a fixed overlay
behind the modal.
So our goal will be to also toggle the visible class on the backdrop when we show the modal. We could
therefore do it in this toggleMovieModal function but actually I want to create a new function because
we will need to reuse this backdrop, also in another place of this application later
so I don't want to tie it to this function.
Now this again is a great challenge for you, try it on your own first and in the next lecture, we'll implement
this together.