So that's arrays,
what about objects?
As I mentioned, objects are great for grouping data together and you create objects with curly braces
here and then you can have multiple key-value pairs separated by commas in them.
So let's create an object, let's say we don't just want to add the number which we added to our log but
a more detailed log information package if you will because the number alone of course doesn't tell
us much,
it would be interesting to log the result before we added the number,
the operation itself so that we can add items to the log not just here but on all these functions and
we can then just attach the information, whether that was an addition or a subtraction operation and therefore,
we need a more complex piece of data that we manage in the list.
This is a great scenario for objects because now we need to manage multiple pieces of data that are
kind of related and these pieces of data then in turn are managed as a list of these pieces of data
because we have multiple such actions.
So here, we could add a new constant let's say because I never plan on editing this which I'll name log
entry and this should hold such an object, which you as you learned create by adding opening and closing curly
braces.
Now of course we also use curly braces here for creating the function but that's different, here
we use that after the function keyword, after the name of the function and the list of parameters,
this is a pattern Javascript detects which tells it
these curly braces should now hold the function body. On the other hand here,
we have no function keyword and nothing like that.
Therefore this tells Javascript, since it's on the right side of the equal sign where you always define
the values for something, for a variable or for whatever you're working with,
this tells Javascript OK, you want to create an object.
Now you can create an object like this, an empty object but that's not too useful arguably.
Now what you can do instead of course is you can add key-value pairs, so pairs of identifiers and values
which you store in these identifiers.
Now often you will write object across multiple lines,
that's not required,
you can do it all in one line just for readability sake,
often you split it across multiple lines and then you can also of course indent to make it more readable
and here you could for example add a let's say operation key, the key names are totally up to you,
you could name this op or operation or whatever you want and then separated with a colon,
you add the value. Now values can be anything, can be strings, numbers, arrays or other objects,
you can also have objects in objects.
So here as an operation, I'll store a string which says add.
So this is kind of my identifier you could say that when we see that log entry later in the output, we
see OK,
that was the operation where we added two numbers.
Now of course I then also want to store these two numbers,
so I have my let's say number one or my previous results,
so the result before the operation, you can again use any key name you want here
and then again separated with a colon,
the value, here the value of course should be a number and it should be my initial result to be precise
because that is my result
before we perform this operation and we added the number. Now we also of course need the value which
we added, so we could name this number or operand,
so kind of the value we added to the previous result,
I'll name it number
and here again separated by colon, we now set a value to this identifier and here, that would be my entered
number because that is the number I added to the previous result
and maybe we also want to add the result after the operation here in our log entry.
So that could be the result or a new result or whatever you want to name it
and here I would simply use current result because we change current result here which means two lines
after that,
it's still that changed current result and therefore I want to add it here to my log entry.
Now it's the log entry which I push here on to the log entries array,
so that log entry object and then here, I want to log the entire array to my console. If we do this and
I reformat my code to use two blanks here, two whitespaces for indentation,
if we do that and I now reload, let me again enter any number here, click plus
and now you see here we have an array and this is just shortened in the developer tools, if I click
this arrow it's expanded, an array with index one, so with the first element at this index being an object
as you can see and if we expand this, we see the full object and we see in that object we have a number
key with the value of 66, the operation key with a value of add which is a string, here logged with double
quotes because that does not reflect the quotes we used necessarily, both are available interchangeably
in the developer tools here simply use double quotes. The previous result and which was zero and the
new result after the operation
and if I add another element here, I get a new array, if expand this we see that new element
and if I explained this we see our second operation where the number was 2 which is correct.
It was still an add operation, before we had a result of 66 and now we added 68.
So this is how we can create and use objects.
Now before we use that everywhere, let me show you how you can extract information from such an object because
it's also something you sometimes need to do.