So we're adding our log entries to the log entries array which is great,
now let's say for some reason, maybe in another part of your code or maybe here, you need some data from
your log entry.
You don't need the full object but you need the operation and here
let's just say we want to log it.
Of course, that's kind of redundant here because we know what operation we added here but it's just so
that I can show you how you can access data on objects and you do this with a notation which we already
saw. You use the name of the object, log entry here and then you use the dot notation, you add a dot here
and a dot tells Javascript that on the object in front of the dot,
so log entry here, you want to access one of the properties as it's also called,
so one of the data pieces that belongs to this object
and here you see my IDE already gives me this autocompletion,
you can also get this by pressing control and space and I can get access operation for example and by
outputting log entry.operation,
if I now reload this here and I add a five here, you see add gets printed here and that's just that data
piece I'm accessing here with this line of code.
So the dot notation allows you to access data in objects.
These key-value pairs here or the keys here are also named properties,
so you access a property here with the dot notation and then the name of the property or name of the
key, whatever you want to name it and of course that's also something we saw before.
It's also what we in the end he was down there when we call add event listener on our buttons. There,
we also use the dot notation and then the only interesting thing is that here, I'm not accessing a property
which contains some data I can read but that I actually access some function because you can also have
functions in objects but that's something we'll dive into in the objects module where we dive way deeper
into objects. For now, let's just think about them as groups of data, of key-value pairs where your values
can be strings, numbers, arrays, other objects and so on, where you can either hardcode data like I'm
doing it here or point at variables and then the value of that variable will be stored here as a value
for this key and that's it for now. Objects are really powerful and we'll see them many times throughout
this course, there's so much you can do with them,
for now let's just use it like this though and let's now also make sure that we actually are able to
add log entries, not just when we add two numbers but also when we subtract and so on.