So let's start building that modal component.
And for that I have a brand new project just an eight file with that basic HMO five skeleton no script
files nothing there I will now add my modal jazz file where I want to create that code for that modal
web component.
Now throughout this module always feel free to post a video and try something on your own.
If we're working on a certain feature where you feel like hey I can do that on my own.
Definitely pause and tried on your own.
Otherwise just code along and you will see many of the things we covered in the last lectures and modules
and this module should therefore also help with really understanding all these pieces and see how they
come together.
So in modal jazz I will start by creating a new component class with the class keyword and I will name
it modal and I will extend the H html element so not extend an existing H Tim l element like a div or
anything like that.
I'll start from scratch here now before I add any content here any logic I will also register this with
custom elements define all name and you see modal that will be my tag and I point at this modal class.
Now with that added I'll go to the index H Tim I'll file and there as before at these script import
to the modal jazz file and thereafter we can added here you see modal as our own H Tim Al tag in the
body off this template and later we'll also add some logic so that we have to click a button to show
it and hide it but that will all come later.
For now let's start adding some content to this modal and I'll start with the constructor where we always
have to call super first.
Now in a year I will set up this general template for this modal and for dad as you learned.
We want to create a shadow Dom.
Now as you also learned this is of course not a hard requirement.
We can create custom elements without the shadow Dom but the shadow Dom gives us many advantages and
therefore I definitely want to use is here.
So I will call this attach shadow and set the demoed to open as always.
And now we can use the shadow route to start setting our inner H Tim L so the template so to say the
H team L code office custom component that is hidden away from the light Dom.
Now I want to create a modal and this will actually consist of two major parts.
For one I will have a death with a C S as class of backdrop could also be an ideal backdrop if you prefer
that.
And this will be the part behind the modal which will grey out the rest of the page whilst a modal is
in the foreground and the other part D for is of course the modal itself and again here I'm using a
class of a modal.
Actually let's use the I.D. because we can be that specific here and selecting an idea is actually a
bit faster than selecting a class.
So from a CSX perspective it is a bit better.
And now let me also add style tags here so that we can style all the components or all the elements
we'll have in the modal and I will start with some rough styling and with the rough layout and later
we'll add more and more feature to that model like different slot areas and so on.
Something we haven't covered yet we'll learn it in this module.
So let's start building that model.
And first of all here I'll select the backdrop and I'll set a style for that backdrop.
Now the style for this backdrop will be that it has a position of fixed from the top of the page and
the way this is positioned in the index H2 mouthful fall directly in the body.
This will refer to the overall document to the overall page as a container.
So from the top I want to have a distance of zero from the left as well.
And then this backdrop should cover the entire page.
So I'll give it a width of one hundred percent and for the height this would not work unless we all
just sets the height of our body and D.H. Kim Il tak to 100 percent.
But here we can use 100 we H which stands for a viewport height and also is about the entire height
of our window basically.
Now I'll give it a background of RGA and then transparent black color maybe 75 percent opacity so 25
percent transparency here and with that we should have a backdrop in place now since we already import
this.
And we use our tag here.
We should be able to reload this page and indeed we now have a grey background and that is the modal
based background.
It's not obvious here but we can confirm this if we simply inspect indie developer tools.
It's this background this Dev.
Your dad is responsible for that.
If I uncheck the background it's gone.
So we see the modal background here.
That's great.
And if we had our content on this page and I will add something here please confirm your choice and
then we have a button which maybe says show details and confirm whatever you want.
For now reload.
This is hidden behind the modal or behind that backdrop.
So that is working.
Now just one tiny thing so that it's a little bit less ugly.
Let me again set some general styles here.
All set the box sizing of border box for all the elements.
That includes my custom elements by the way.
And for the body I was at a margin of zero.
And I'll set a fun family of sans serif here because I simply prefer that.
And now this looks a bit nicer.
I'll get rid of the margin actually.
Let's give this a margin of 2 REM instead so that we have a little bit of margin on the body.
Yeah.
Okay.
So this is the general styling the backdrop is in place.
Now let's also add the modal style itself in the next lecture.