So first things first,
if we reload, one problem we have is if I enter something here and I click cancel, the backdrop doesn't close.
If I enter something here and I click the backdrop, everything closes but my input is not cleared.
So there are a couple of things I want to change here, for one clearing that input. We got that clear
movie input function and we call that when the cancel add movie handler is called,
well in the end of course I also want to call this whenever we close the backdrop
of course, that also therefore calls this function if we close the other modal
but since that's the only other use case we have in this app, calling it like this will be okay.
So that should fix this error, that if we enter something here and we click the backdrop, the content
was still there,
this works. Now
however if we have another issue, if I click cancel, the backdrop doesn't close.
Now let's have a look at what happens when I click that cancel button, cancel add movie button here fires
the cancel add movie handler and in there, I close the movie modal, I clear the movie input.
Well in close movie modal, if I scroll up, I indeed don't toggle the backdrop,
so here I need to toggle the backdrop instead.
So now this should make sure that when I do click cancel here, we also clear the backdrop.
Now another issue we had was that if I do add movies here, let's say to and I click on one and I confirm
deletion,
now I delete it but I get an error and that does not close and previously, if we reload here, if we add two
items here, this one and then this one here,
right?
If I add two of them and I click on the first one and cancel and click on the second one and click
yes,
both are gone.
So this never closes and the deletion process also isn't correct. Now regarding the modal which doesn't
close when we confirm deletion, for that we can just go to our delete movie handler which is in the end
triggered when we really want to get rid of everything and there, we just have to call close movie deletion
modal, close movie deletion modal and therefore even though it would work in this order as well because
everything is parsed before this will be executed for the first time, I will move that up above that
so that I have a structure where I have the functions that I call above the functions where I need them,
therefore actually I will, even though it's not strictly required, also move toggle backdrop up a bit,
cut that and add toggle backdrop here at the top but that's not the main thing
but now we should close the movie deletion modal once we delete the movie but still we got some
error here in our logic as it seems, it seems like we're deleting the wrong item sometimes,
let me show you again. Now if we reload here and we add a movie, let's say a single movie and I click
on it and I confirm this, it works.
If I add two movies here, first one, second one and I click on the second one and click yes, this also
works. If I add two movies here,
like that
and then here like this and I click on the first one and delete it,
this now works.
Now let's see,
it seems to fail
if I have more movies
like this and we then click on one, cancel this and then delete the other one, now
this clearly does not behave in the way it should,
now what's the problem here?
The problem has something to do with the start delete movie handler, there
I set up these event listeners
and the problem is if we have a movie here,
it even occurs with only one movie and I cancel deletion and then I delete, here I get another error,
the error source is the same or the problem we have here is actually the same as the problem that causes
multiple items to be deleted.
Whenever I start the deletion process, we add an event listener for both buttons,
right? Now when I cancel, we of course execute this event listener or this function here and not the other
one.
If I then click on the same movie again or even on a different movie,
the problem is that we add new listeners to the cancel and confirm deletion buttons but the old listeners
are also still there,
You must not forget that the DOM object, these buttons,
the underlying DOM objects are never removed,
so the event listeners are of course never cleared.
So that means that if we then click confirm on that newly opened modal, all event listeners we executed
in the past will execute, even the ones for the other movie you might have clicked on before
and if we only have one movie and we open and close this confirm modal multiple times, like I can do
it here, then we basically add more and more listeners to the confirm button
and if I then click yes, I get as many error messages here complaining that you can't remove that element
anymore because it's gone already
as you opened this modal.
If I opened the modal five times, I get four error messages here because one time, clicking confirm succeeded
and deleted the item
but the other four event listeners which also were added go into the void,
they executed their function, try to delete the element but the element is gone, with multiple movies
I might have clicked on multiple movies and therefore, all these event listeners are registered
and then if I click yes on some movie, all event listeners execute. So what's the solution here?
Well we need to clear the existing event listeners
but the problem is there is a confirm deletion button and of course also for the other button, remove event listener
function
but this takes the event for which you want to remove a listener and then the function which you executed
on your event listener.
So in this case of the confirm deletion button, this delete movie handler function
but now here since I use bind, this actually returns a new function.
Now you might think no problem, I call bind here again but this will actually return a new function
object
and because as you know, two objects even if they hold the same content which here is not even guaranteed
because the movie ID might be different
but even if it would be the same content, objects and therefore also functions are different.
So this would look for an event listener with this function object which is not the same as this event
listener,
so this would not work for this delete movie handler function.
Now the good news is for cancel deletion,
so for this button, it will work because there I'm not using bind,
so here if I click and then point at close movie deletion modal, we use exactly the same function object
because we don't create a new one,
we point that this global object instead which is created once when the script runs at the beginning
and therefore this will work.
So for the cancel deletion button, we're good,
we clear an existing event listener before we add a new one.
Now for confirm deletion button, as I said this will not work and I can actually show this
to you if we save that and we give it a try and we add a new movie here, now click on this multiple times,
you'll see we still get the same error.
So that didn't work,
so let's comment it out. So for the confirm deletion button, we need a workaround and a workaround
we can use here even though it's a bit hacky for sure but it will work is to simply recreate that
deletion button because if we do that, we get rid of the old DOM object and with that, all existing event
listeners will be removed
if you hold no other references at this button which we don't, we only point at the button here inside
of this function,
so whenever this function execution is done, these constants will go into the void and therefore, garbage
collection can then kick in and actually get rid of these old event listeners.
So what does this mean?
It means that before I add event listeners here, I want to swap that deletion button so that I always
have a brand new button when that function executes again. To do this, I simply say confirm deletion
button and call replace with to replace this with a new node
and I want to replace it with confirm deletion button clone node true to make a deep clone
and with that we clone this confirm deletion button and replace the existing one with it.
So the DOM object is created with a clone
and therefore with a new object, which means all listeners can be deleted and a deep clone is required
here by the way
otherwise the text inside of the button will not be cloned.
So now this will replace that button, a bit hacky for sure
but at least now we have a way of practicing clone node and replace with and since it replaces the button,
this confirm deletion button reference which we have here of course will not work anymore,
that's the old button which we now removed from the DOM, hence I will actually change this to be a variable
and then simply repeat that selection process after I swap this so that I get access to the new button
thereafter
and here I get access so that I attach the listener to the right button.
With that if we go back and we reload this and we try Javascript The Complete Guide here, if we now
click on this a couple of times and cancel and then click yes,
this seems to work without issues.
Now let's also try multiple items here, multiple elements which we can add and click on the first one
cancel, click on the second one and now the first one indeed survived and this now should be a setup
that works and that works just fine no matter how often you click on something and what you do with
it
because now we're attaching this correctly with this little workaround here
but that simply is a nice way of practicing this again and it helps us solve the problem of having too
many event listeners here.
Now needless to say that Javascript of course also holds other ways of solving this but I found it nice
to also again play and work with replace with and clone node and other ways of solving this would actually
involve techniques and features of Javascript we haven't really learned about yet,
hence this approach,
we will however learn more about events and also about functions throughout the course so that we can
handle this entire deletion process or similar cases in a more elegant way in the future.
Nonetheless, this is this finished and working application here,
well almost, one thing is missing,
do you know which? Well it's a minor thing
but if I have no items anymore, I want to bring back this section here at the bottom.
So we have these update UI function where we do perform this check whether we want to show it or not,
so all we need to do is call update UI whenever we deleted a movie.
So here, I want to call update UI
and with that called, let's give it a try,
let's reload, try
Javascript The Complete Guide again, like this, open this, close it, click yes
and our text here is back and
if I add another item, it of course should be gone again,
yes that all works.
So now we're finished with this app.