So we got our hands dirty with TypeScript and we see why typescript might be helpful.
We also already learned about the first type typescript supports and that's the number type and how
we can assign this type to in this case a parameter.
Now before we dive into other types let me also make it clear how else you can work with types and types.
Here we are assigning a type.
We are actively tallying typescript hey this parameter is of type No.
Now actually in this snippet here types are all getting used in other places.
For example in this line here which type does result half we don't assign a type here right.
We have no colon after this.
Well turns out that we don't need to.
We can actually add one and make it clear that result will also hold a number.
Of course it will because we returned the addition of two numbers here but we don't have to do that.
We can do that but it's not necessary because typescript has a built in feature which is called Type
inference which means typescript is really doing its best.
And it is really smart about inferring types you're working with.
And in this case if I hover over result here in Visual Studio code I see that types inferred that dissolve
type number.
Now how did it do that.
Well it actually also inferred the return type of the add function if I hover over at here.
You see this is basically the type of this function.
You see the two parameter types here.
And then after to function as a whole you also see a colon.
And then here also the type.
No no.
That basically is what typescript inferred to be the return type of this function.
So typescript correctly infers that since we add a and b in here and return the result and a and b a
numbers we have a return type of type No.
Well and since we store the return value of the add function in result typescript all the infers that
result holds a number.
So type inference is really a key feature of typescript as well.
And it is a good practice to not unnecessarily reassign a type types who could infer anyways.
It's also not a bad mistake but it's simply not required typescript already knows which type we have
here inside out if y now where to assign another type.
For example string which types could also supports of course get an error because I'm actually storing
a number in constant which I'd find to hold a string so if I wanted to store a string in here then indeed
I now need to fix something about it my code I ever need to return a String here for example by wrapping
this into parentheses and calling to string here or instead of doing that of course we also could call
to string here.
So that is something we can do.
But here I will get rid of it and I will use this type inference because I'm fine with using a number
here.
No speaking of numbers which other types do we have.
We just saw the string right.
I assigned to type string here so string is another core type type score it supports and in general
it supports all the core types javascript knows as well numbers strings boolean as objects and so on.
So this is the string.
If we wanted to work the boolean like is done well then here types would infer that is done holds a
boolean actually it and for us here that it holds exactly false and I'll come back to these exact types
later but we can also accept any boolean here and if I would code turned us into a variable here where
we can assign a new value then type could all infers that this is a boolean and it would allow us to
assign true as a value as well just for a constant ID in third the concrete type false because constants
can't get new values so they're typescript knows that it's not even a boolean it's really just false
for a variable it is a boolean so boolean is strings numbers we have all these types makes sense I guess
whichever types do we have.
Well we also have function types and with that I don't mean the types of the parameters I really mean
the type of the function as a whole.
So a type that describes the entire function.
What do you mean by that.
Well if we hover over ad we see the function type.
This is how the function type in the end is inferred the function type includes both the parameters
as well as the return value and we can of course also set our own return value here by adding a colon
after the parameter list and then defining our return type.
And here again if I set this to type string that of course my current logic and a function is not correct
because this will return just the result of two numbers being added together which is a number.
So I would not meet my function type here.
So we might when I get rid of that and use type inference or change our logic.
So the function is made up of the parameter types and the return type.
Now when it comes to the return type you can all of course have functions that don't return anything.
For example print result let's say this is a function which takes a result and there I console log the
result like this.
Now if I use this function down there to print the well result I got here you see this will work.
But now of course this function doesn't return anything.
We can make clear that this function won't return anything by adding a return type of Y it here.
Now that's a type added by TypeScript and this basically means this function has no return statement.
We could also go with undefined here undefined is also valid type and typescript but as you see I'm
now getting an error.
Why.
Well technically a function that doesn't return anything returns undefined in javascript but in typescript
there is a slight differentiation between these cases.
If I set the return type of a function to undefined timescale I would expect that I have a return value
which simply is undefined.
If I don't intend on returning anything then technically still if I would use the return value I would
have undefined but then in typescript I should set this to wide to make my intention clear my intention
is to not even have a return statement.
And we do make this clear by setting this too wide here.
If I now would return undefined here I also could do that.
But the better practices to now not return anything.
Now Justice before however typescript infers that I don't return anything.
So we don't need to add to return type of wide here if we don't added then types could correctly and
first that the return type is wide and you'll always see one other important type here.
The any type you see that 4 result I didn't assign my own type.
Now of course typescript can't infer the type of result because we just find a function here.
It is as if we would create a variable a here.
How would typescript know what we plan on storing in there.
How does typescript know what we plan on receiving here.
It's not inferring the type by how we call the function later so it Condit for to type here in such
a case the type of default is any.
And of course we can also explicitly set to type to any here if we want to.
Now you should use any type carefully though.
It's kind of a last resort type you have in typescript.
This is basically the default for all values if you don't work with types at all and therefore you give
up all the advantages types offers because any well really works with any value so the advantage you
get by being explicit about your types and the advantage of being able to catch errors early that is
all lost if you work with the any type because of course with that typescript accepts any values.
If on the other hand I make it clear that I want a number here then I really only can pass a number
into print result and if it would pass and anything else a string a boolean whatever then it would fail.
So sometimes it's fine to use to any type but you should be careful about that here.
I will leave it like this for the moment.
Now before we move on let me also show you another way of working with types and how you can overwrite
type inference by typescript to give you an example let's say in the index each html file.
We actually have two input fields and input field with an idea of let's say num 1.
And then one with NUM 2.
And then we all have a button.
And when we click this button I want to trigger my add function here.
So now we got these two inputs and the button.
Now of course we need to get access to those inputs and the button in order to work with them and in
order to read values from there and add an event listener.
So at the very top of the file we could add a constant here num 1 input and use document get element
by D.
And use the idea.
Num 1 year to get access to this element in the DOM now num 1 simply is the idea I assigned here.
The Abbott input has the idea come to hence we can duplicate this to get the NUM to input by that idea
and also get access to the button element with document query selector button.
We only have one button on the page so we can selected with this query selector now with all that I
will actually comment out this code here at the bottom because we don't need it right now.
And instead I'll use the button element to add an event listener for the Click event and upon a click
I went to call ad and I want to use my two inputs here.
So we'll actually use an anonymous function here.
A little arrow function here simply and in there I will get to two concrete values the user entered
into these inputs and then call add with those values.
So num one here simply is num one input dot value and you already see I didn't get auto completion here
and I do get an error or here in my I.D. even though this should work right.
We are selecting input element here so I'm not sure where does this coming from we'll fix it later.
For now let's live with the error and let's also extract num 2 from num Q input.
Then we can calculate the result by calling add by passing in num 1 and 2 and then last but not least
we can call print result and pass in the result.
Now we have errors here but let's try running this code.
So I will compile apt Yes and of course we get errors here because we get the same error as my I'd already
detected but as I mentioned earlier the file D.J. S file is still generated.
So we do get this file here.
Hence if we go to the running application and I reload I got these two inputs and I can enter my two
values and click Add and it does something.
Now we are looking at an old bag again though the two values got concatenated instead of added.
Now this is not really what we wanted right and why do we get this.
I think we got rid of that when we introduced types.
So why do we have that error again.
Well keep in mind that types can help us but only if we really use them.
And here we clearly have an error.
So typescript doesn't really understand that we have a value property on num one input and if we take
a closer look at offer of course also doesn't know what's inside of value.
So num one effectively is of type any and we passed that into at and indeed add expects to numbers but
it turns out since num 1 is any typescript trusts us maybe that is a numbers.
So it doesn't complain here also because we already got an error here so types could kind of gives up
and allows us to pass and values which seem to be strings.
OK well maybe let's resolve this error first.
Why does typescript not understand that there is a value property on num when input we are selecting
elements in a dorm here and we know these will be input elements and of course they therefore have a
value property.
And indeed this part is not failing our code is working here.
So why does not understand that these are inputs.
Well how would it we only tell typescript that we select an element in the dorm by I.D. but this could
be any element you can have any idea on any element it could be a paragraph it could be a button it
could be a list item it doesn't have to be an input element and therefore if we have our Overgaard element
by I.D. we indeed see the typescript only infers that this is of type h him out element and that's of
course very unspecific it just means any h him Al element not specifically input element.
Now we of course know as a developer that we will get an input element here and by the way typescript
doesn't scan our index h t metal file to check what we're selecting there.
So we can't rely on type inference here.
Instead we can do something which is known as type costing we can override the inference made by typescript
we can tell typescript that this will be of a different type that you could think we'll do this by adding
a type here and here we could use the H HTML input element type you might not notice type it's one of
the built in types for working with the Dom and this basically says what I stored in here has to be
not any H Tim Al element but at h t male input element of course you see we get an error here and we
get an error here because just because we want to store as such an element here doesn't change the way
get element by idea works typescript still doesn't know what we get here.
So instead we'll use this typecasting thing I mentioned you do that by adding the ASCII word after it
a thing where TypeScript and first some type which you want to change and then you set the type you
want to use instead of the type typescript inferred.
So in this case h him l input element no this is pure typescript syntax this will all be lost once we
convert to javascript but this now overrides what typescript uses or infers here if we now hover over
num 1 input we see what's stored in there is a h t Mal input element and if we scroll down we see that
they for num 1 input we don't get this error anymore we now know OK yep this is now clearly a way lable
this property exists we get a new error which I'll come back later but this error is gone so this is
typecasting and action.
There also is another syntax you can use.
You can use angle brackets in front of the thing you want to cost instead of after it.
As we do it with ass and then use to type here both works.
This syntax is a bit more common now but both does the same thing in the end with Dad we're simply overriding
the type types called inferred and I'll leave both syntax is here to show you both of course in your
apps you should be consistent and typically use either of the two so now the errors down there are gone
but we've got a new error here and that error now makes sense.
It's important to understand that the value property owner input element always returns a string no
matter which type does input is off.
So even if you set this to type number here this doesn't change the type of value you get from the value
prop and it also does not change with the value the user entered.
If a user enters the number 10 into an input it's still a string it's wrapped in two quotes.
So to say value always gives you a string.
So when I'm 1 and I'm 2 are strings and therefore we are now calling add with two strings and that's
what typescript is not liking here.
If we would compile this file we would get errors where we clearly learn that type string is not allowed
here but that we want to type no instead.
So 2 changed as we now need to parse these strings two numbers so we can add a plus in front of both
value it retrieval easier to cost the string into a number.
Now that of course means that if anything which can't be cost is entered.
This will be converted into not a number but that's fine for now.
And with that we again see the power of typescript in action by being clear about the types we're working
with we can catch this nasty bug we introduced where we forgot to cost to values and where we hence
concatenated the two values instead of adding them mathematically.
So now with that if we safeties and we compiled is we can reload this page and now if I enter the two
numbers here we get additions in a mathematical sense instead of concatenate strings.
So this is how we work with types and some of the core types we can work with.
Now of course you can learn about all types in the official box here in the handbook but we will also
have a look at some of the core types and features for this module.
So let's continue.