So now that we have this big picture,
let's have a closer look at this HttpRequest thing.
How does this actually work?
Well we have our script, our client side, so the code that runs in the browser and we have our server,
the backend, the server side.
Now we can also name the client side as frontend because it's what the user sees, what the user works
with and that is detached from the backend. The backend,
so our server, could run on a totally different domain, a totally different server than our frontend.
So we might be serving the HTML page and the Javascript which is responsible for what the user
sees on
mypage.com
whereas the server side logic might be hosted on a totally different server, let's say on
mybackend.com.
Still, these two pieces or these two ends can communicate and the job on the client side is to get the
user input, validate it and then to send it off to the server because the job on the server side is to
store and retrieve it in a database typically and the database would run on yet another server,
it's important to understand this point that you don't directly connect your client side Javascript
code to a database for security reasons because you would expose your database credentials in the client
side code which you don't want to do but instead you talk to a web server and that web server might
then talk to a database server.
Of course using a database is totally optional
but of course often the server side will use one to persistently store data and then get it from the
database.
Now the communication between the client side and the server happens with the help of HttpRequests
and responses and these requests and responses have to be configured and set up in a certain way, following
a certain structure.
When you're sending a request to the server, it needs to know the address,
so it needs to know the URL made up of the domain and the path, the path is the part after the
domain,
so mypage.com/posts, mypage.com would be the domain, /posts would be the path.
In addition, each HttpRequest has a HTTP method that is assigned to it.
Now you have a couple of available HTTP methods, you have for example get, post, patch, put and delete.
These methods
describe what you want to do, though I will say it's totally up to the server to decide for which method
URL combination the server wants to do what,
so with the method you don't tell the server what to do,
the server just exposes different endpoints and for example might support a post request to /posts
whereas it maybe might not support a patch request to /posts but again, it's up to the people writing
the server side code to decide which HTTP method URL combinations are supported.
Typically of course you go for combinations that make sense logically because there the logic is
that get requests typically are there to get data, post requests are there to create data on the server
or create data on the server which might be stored in a database there, patch and put are there to
update data, patch in the sense of updating the existing data, put in the sense of overriding it and
delete as you can guess is there to delete data,
that's what you commonly use but again, it's the server side that decides which HTTP method URL
combinations are supported, on the client side,
you then can send requests to these combinations. If you use a combination that is not supported by the
server side, you'll simply get a HTTP error as a response.
Now other parts of a HttpRequest are potential headers, that is extra metadata which can be attached to
HttpRequests and some requests,
for example a post request, also hold a request body or extra data which is attached to a request.
As you can imagine, if we're getting a list of posts, there is no data we could attach,
we want a list of posts and we're done.
If you want to add a post, if you want to create a brand new post, that of course is different, then you
want to attach the data that is required for the post creation, like the title and the content to the
request you are sending,
so that's the idea here.
Now that data then can be sent in different formats and again, it's the server that tells you which formats
it expects or supports.
The most common format is JSON data, which I'll dive into in more details in a second but we also have
FormData which is supported in Javascript and which is fairly popular and you could also send binary
files or other formats
but again, it's up to the server to decide which data format is supported for which HTTP method URL
combination.
Now that is all the theory,
if that is all brand new to you, attached you find a couple of resources that allow you to dig deeper
into how the web works, into HttpRequests and HTTP methods.
I will now move on and now we'll have a look at how we can actually send HttpRequests to a server
from inside Javascript.