So we wrote this code here in the procedural style you could say.
Now let's create a new Javascript file,
oop.js where we will write basically the same logic but now using an object oriented style.
So for that in index.html, I'll swap the import for the oop.js file here.
Now how would this look like if we think about this in an object oriented way?
Now there are certainly different ways of approaching this but I would like to think about the different
entities, the different types of objects we could work with here.
We could say our form for example is one object,
it's one object which in the end will have two inputs which has this button and which will have a method
which is triggered when the button is fired.
The validation could be organized in its own object as well, in a helper object which holds validation
logic that we could reuse in different parts of the application
if we had multiple forms and the user we create in the end, we could create a blueprint for this
user as well, a class or constructor function which allows us to create user objects which has a built-in
greet method to show this greeting for example.
So here in the object oriented Javascript file, I will work with classes,
if you were working with an older version of Javascript, you could of course also work with constructor
functions instead. Classes in the end are just syntactic sugar with some extras and you'll learn all about
that of course in my complete guide in the object oriented and classes course section. So which classes
do we need here?
Well we have our form right,
so I'll a user input form class here and this should hold everything that is related to my form.
I also want to have another class and the order does not really matter here,
I'll just have the form at the bottom because it is the thing I will actually start with and it will
use all the other classes which I'm about to define,
so I want to define them first, though technically as I said, you could also organize this differently but
here, another class we'll need later is the user itself,
so not the input form but for the concrete user object we work with and then maybe also our validator
class here which holds our validation logic.
Now let's start with the user input form though, what could be in there?
Well I want to define my constructor function which allows us to do some initialization work whenever
we create an instance based on this class.
Now my goal is to create an instance based on this class when the app starts in the end.
So therefore here, I want to get access to the different inputs in the HTML file and to the form itself
so that we can add a listener.
So here I will add some properties to the instance created based on the class with the this keyword,
for example a form property and the name is up to you
and here I get access to get element by ID, user-input,
so here I store access to this user input form.
I also want to get access to the different input fields in the form,
so I have my usernameInput field, document get element by ID username and of course one for the password,
so passwordInput with document get element by ID password.
So basically what we stored in constants before, here
this constant, this constant and this constant is now getting stored in properties of this class or to
be precise, in properties of the concrete objects created based on this class. I also of course will
reach out to my form and add an event listener here for the submit event and when this is triggered,
I of course want to trigger a function.
Now we could work with an anonymous function here but since we're in the class and we want to write
object oriented code, it makes much more sense to create a method, so a function inside of an object, inside
of a class here.
So for that, I'll add the signupHandler method here which gets the event object and now I can point
at it here,
this signupHandler. This ensures that this function which is registered on this class and which therefore
is called a method is fired whenever the submit event occurs
and in here, we can now do stuff, we can call even prevent default but we can now also get the concrete
entered values and validate them
and so on.
Now one important word, if I want to get the let's say entered username here, then I of course can reach
out to this usernameInput,
so to this pointer at this input element in the HTML code we stored here and access .value
but this won't work,
why won't it work? Because the this keyword inside of this method will not refer to this class in this case
here,
why?
Because this method gets fired upon this event
and when you point at a function or a method based on an event that gets triggered,
so here on such a event listener, the this keyword will be bound to the event target,
that's a default behavior. To override this,
we have to call bind this here.
This ensures that the this keyword inside of signupHandler will point to the exact same thing
this would point to in the constructor and that will be the instance created based on the class.
So now this will work correctly and
we can therefore also get the entered password here with this passwordInput.value.
So now we get the two values,
now it would make sense to validate them
and here again thinking in an object oriented way, we could outsource this validation logic into a validator
class.
We don't have to do that,
we could write it inline here,
we could just copy over this logic here from procedural but that means that whenever we have some other
form in our application, we can only reuse our code by copying it again and copy and pasting is not something
we want to do too often because that is a bad programming style,
you're repeating yourself and you shouldn't do that.
So instead, I'll add something here in the validator class,
I'll add a static method validate, this means we can call it without instantiating this class and there,
I expect to get a value and then let's say a flag and a validator value if you want to,
so I'm writing a little bit of a more complex validator here.
What does this mean?
Well.
value should be the value I want to check,
so the entered username and enter password.
Flag should then allow us to identify which kind of validation we want to perform and then validator
value is basically optional allowing us to configure the validation.
Now for this to work, I'll add two new static properties here - required and I'm writing in all caps to make
it clear that this is basically a globally unique value you could say and min length here
and these are just identifiers which we can then use because my idea now is that I can check if in here
in the validate function, if the flag argument I'm getting, if this is equal to this required,
so if we're running some required validation and if it is, I want to return true or false, I want to return
true if the entered value is not empty and false if it is empty.
So I will return value trim length greater zero, if it's not an empty input, this will return true,
otherwise this will return false.
If the flag is let's say this min length, then I will return value trim length greater validator value,
so this extra argument with which we can configure validation.
Why am I doing it like this?
Well simply just to show that now we would have a reusable validate function because in the user input
form here, in the signupHandler, we can now use this.
We can now simply check if validator,
so this class I just worked in, .validate which we can call like this because it's a static method
hence we don't need to instantiate the class,
if this yields true for the entered username which is the value and validator.required as a flag.
So i want to validate this here with the required validator and check if it's not empty.
If this returns true, I'm fine,
if it does not return true indicated by this exclamation mark here,
I want to show an error but this is not the only validation of course,
I also want to check one other validation logic here, one other expression, if not validator validate for
the entered password, for the min length flag and a value of five as a minimum length, if this returns
not true or this first one returns not true, in any of these cases I want to make it into this if block
and here we can now show an alert and say invalid input, username or password is wrong,
password should be at least six characters. This is the alert
we could show here and then we want to return here to not continue with this method execution.
So the error message, the error handling still happens in this class here which makes sense because this
is the place where I do work with my concrete values
but the logic for checking the input is outsourced in a separate class.
Now this is not a must do but it ensures that we could now reuse this validator in other forms of this
application as well and we might of course have more complex validation logic in there than we currently
do. So now with this,
we know that after this if check, we have valid inputs and hence we could now create our new user.
So for this, let's go to this user class and work on this, here I want to define how a user should look
like and attach any logic to it which it should have,
so for example here let's add a constructor to define some values with which we create a user, specifically
the username and the user password let's say and then in here, we have this user name, set it equal
to uName and this password set it equal to upassword here,
this would allow us to create a new object with these two properties but I also want to add some logic,
I'll add a greet method here to this user object where I just say console log
Hi I am plus this username.
And with that, we can create a new user based on this class down there, our new user with new user, here
we need the new keyword to construct a new instance of the user class and we forward our entered user
name and our entered password here and thereafter we can not only log the new user but also call new
user.greet to execute that greet logic and with all that done, there's just one remaining thing now.
Thus far all the logic lives in the user input form but this is just a class, right,
we need to instantiate it to bring this code to life.
So below this here, we can call new user input form like this to create a new instance. We could store
it in a constant but if we don't work with this constant, we also don't have to do that,
so here I'm just creating a new instance and with that, this class here now comes to life,
we run this constructor, we set up this event listener and we're therefore good to go.
So now if we go back and we reload this page, if we submit an empty form, we should get an error and indeed
we do.
If I enter a valid password here but I have an empty username, it still gets this error and if I enter
a valid username here but my password is too short, we still get an error here.
If I enter a different password which is long enough, we do log our user object here and this greeting.
So this now works and it's essentially the same logic as before in the procedural style,
the difference is now that we think about our code as different objects working together and we split
our code logically into entities which can make it easier to reason about your code.
It can also help with reusing code
as I mentioned at the example of the validator because we can use this anywhere in the application, in
the procedural style, in the way we're doing it at the moment here, we would have to copy this around
to share it and again copy and pasting is bad because you need to change your logic in one place, you
then need to change it in 10 places or how often you're using it.
So that's the object oriented style,
let's explore the functional programming style now.