So let's add an event listener here and this method as you already learned works such that as a first
argument, you have a string with the event name
and that's now basically the same name as we had here on the property but without the on at the beginning.
So here we do have click and we als do have dbl click for double click or context menu for a right
click and you see I'm getting autocompletion here and you should be getting this as well if I open my
quotes here and here, I'm interested in a click.
Then the second argument is the function that should be executed when this click occurs and there I want
to point at my and for this, I'll bring back these two functions,
I'll point at my button click handler here.
Now again, you just point at it like this, don't execute it, just point at it like this
and with that, we set up an event listener.
Now if we reload and I click the button, we again get this alert
but now with the most elegant way of doing this
and now as I said, we can also remove this if we wanted to.
So here, let's say after with the set timeout, after two seconds,
second argument defines the duration,
I want to execute this function and in this function, I want to remove an event listener,
so basically after two seconds, this event listener should be removed
and now you do remove an event listener by specifying the event for what you want to remove an event
listener, click
and then as a second argument, the function which you registered as an event listen and here it's super
important that it's the exact same function object.
I'll dive into a couple of pitfalls you could face with remove event listener in a second.
This however should work and therefore now if you save that, you will see that if you reload and I click
this right away, it works
but if we wait for two seconds, now nothing happens because we now removed the event listener and that's
a super powerful feature of add event listener, that you can get rid of the event listeners,
so not only could you register more than one,
you can also remove them if you need to. Now as I mentioned, remove event listener also has a couple of
pitfalls which you can easily overlook or which you could not be aware of, especially if you're new to
Javascript because as I mentioned, you remove an event listener not with some ID which would be returned
by add event listener which you then could pass to remove event listener but by basically specifying
the exact same listening setup as you have here for add event listener,
so the same event name, same function. The event name, that's of course simple but the same function, that
can be tricky.
It works here but you could think that it also works if you pass an anonymous function here,
so here anonymous function console log clicked. Now we could grab this function here and also use it
here right.
It's the same function, it does the exact same thing, right?
However if I save this and I reload here, you'll see I can click this and I can click it forever,
so this never seems to be removed,
right,
the two seconds passed and it still is clickable.
The reason for that simply is that
this here looks similar to us humans but technically, it's not the same function object,
this creates a new function object and so does this.
So these are two totally different objects
and as you learned in the reference value lectures, if we would compare these two functions here with
let's say an equal sign, if this would be possible, then this simply would not work because these are
two totally different objects,
so this does not work.
Instead we have to make sure we store that function in a constant which then holds the address of this
function object and we can here, when we use this approach, only use that same address and therefore the
same function,
so now this works. A similar pitfall is if you bind this,
so if you bind this to bind the this keyword in a function or to pass in some arguments when this executes,
something we also did throughout this course,
now you might again think well this is similar,
no it isn't,
this is not similar, bind creates a new function object and therefore here we create a new function object
and here we create a new function object,
so this also will not work.
If you want to bind this or any arguments that should be passed in and then eventually remove this later,
you will have to store the bound function in a new constant like this
so that again we have the address of this function object stored in here and then use this here,
so that again we use the same function object. So this would work,
the other approach would not work.
So if we now reload this, you see I can click this initially but if you wait for two seconds now, nothing
happens.
So that's add event listener and remove event listener and some pitfalls you can face there which you
just have to be aware of so that you can work around them.