Now before we set up webpack or anything, let's start with linting
and if you're using Visual Studio Code, the easiest way of implementing it is to install a certain extension.
For that, you can go to view, extensions and in there, search for ESLint.
Now I already got that installed,
you can simply install it there and then you might need to reload your IDE,
your editor. Once this is done, ESLint should be installed.
Now once it is installed, you can go back to the explorer view here and then to use ESLint,
you can hit command shift and p on Mac or control shift and p on Windows and Linux to open up this
command menu, there you can type ESLint and then choose enable ESLint.
Now here, it's telling me that it already is enabled.
Now that doesn't seem to change much right,
I don't get any errors or warnings here. For the browser extension to work,
we need to also install the ESLint tool globally on our machine or in this project
and here I want to install it specifically in this project. For that,
quit that development server by pressing control c here and now in there, we need to make this project
manageable by npm, which means I want to be able to install specific packages that are exclusive to this
project,
so I don't want to install them globally but only inside of this project
and for that, we first of all need to create an npm configuration file to basically tell npm that this project
should be managed by npm and then also manage our different dependencies, the different packages we want
to use there. For that you need to have Node.js installed,
so visit
nodejs.org and if you didn't install it already, install the latest version of Node.js
here.
Simply download the installer, walk through the installer, works on Mac, Linux and Windows and once that
is done, potentially restart your system if you're facing any issues with the next steps and otherwise,
just execute npm init.
Here, in this project folder, I'm doing this with the help of the built-in terminal or command prompt
here in the IDE which you can open with view terminal.
This is your normal system terminal or command prompt but automatically navigated into this folder.
Now once you hit npm init, you're getting asked a couple of questions,
for example you need to define a package name and you can confirm the default here which you see in
parentheses by simply hitting enter,
you can also enter an alternative value and hit enter to confirm that.
I'm fine with the default here, also for the version, for description you don't have to enter anything but
you can, here I'll just enter Javascript The Complete Guide and hit enter, entry point doesn't matter
you can confirm this, test command,
you can leave that empty by hitting enter, git repository if you're asked you can confirm the default
or just ignore it, hit enter,  keywords, you can ignore that, hit enter with no keywords, author, you can put
in your name here or leave it blank, hit enter thereafter, confirm the default licence and in the end,
once all of this is okay,
simply hit enter again to confirm. With all of that done, you will have a package.json file which
you shouldn't delete. If you open that, you should see something like this, the settings you confirmed
basically. With that,
this project here can be managed with npm which means we can now install project specific packages with
npm and there, I want to start with linting again.