Let's try to implement it in another way.
For this I'll add a new function get men to and there.
I also want to get my numbers and I also will run this check here and throw an error if it's an invalid
input but now let's see if we can solve this differently.
I think our solution here is not that bad but still let's see if we could find a different solution.
Now what could be a different solution.
Well an alternative could be that we try to sort this array we're getting and if we sought it and we
know that we have the smallest item at the beginning then we could just return the first item in the
array.
We just have to sort it.
So we could return sorted numbers and data is simply the first item.
If we sorted in an ascending order so if we have the smallest item first and then the biggest item at
the end.
Now we just need a sorted numbers variable here.
And we now well need to do the actual sorting.
Now how can we sort an array now of course we could do it quickly by calling the sort function which
is built into javascript.
But actually let's write our own sorting algorithm which is all the something we can do.
Now how can we sort our numbers here.
Well we can again write a for loop here where we now actually start at index 0 and we keep on going
as long as I is smaller than numbers length and we then incremented and now inside of that loop we have
a never loop because I want to go through all items in my array but then for every item I want to go
through all other items in disarray and check if there is a smaller item than the one I'm currently
looking at.
And this will allow me to sort this so we can add a number loop here where we maybe use J instead of
I.
Because we can't reuse.
I hear you're already using that and I said this equal to I plus ones so that I started the next item
after the item we're looking at in his outer loop here and then we check if J is smaller the numbers
length because this hasn't changed we still don't want to exceed our array boundaries and we increment
J.
Now we just need to do something before we entered this inner loop we save outer element here and I
set this to numbers for the index eyes so the element I'm currently looking at in the outer loop and
in here we have inner element and as inner loop where we simply take numbers for J so that we have to
concrete elements we're comparing the one in the outer loop and the one in the inner loop and then we
need if check in here where we check if the outer element is greater than the inner element and if it
is greater then we know OK Indira we're going for Rousseau in disarray for example in the first iteration
where this would be the outer and this would be the inner element we know the outer element is bigger
than the inner element we need to swap positions we need to replace free with one and one with free
we need to swap these two so Soledad we ordered is in the ascending way here.
So we need to do a swap here by setting numbers for eyes so the index of the outer element equal to
the inner element so we swap these outer element with the inner element and of course that also means
that we have to set numbers JS so the inner elements position equal to the outer element.
This simply swaps the two elements in the array.
So this array for the first iteration would now swap free with one for example so that after this swap
we would have 1 3 and then 2 this would now be our current array for the first iteration.
Now we all need to update our outer and inner element of references because they're now wrong and now
we said outer element equal to numbers for eye and inner element equal to numbers for J.
Because since we swapped the elements here in their position in the array we now need to update these
variables again to be correct.
So that after the swap we as I just said had one free two but before these two lines outer element would
of course still be equal to three.
So to our first element an inner element would still be equal to 1.
Well now we need to update this after the swap so that they are after outer element is 1 and in her
element is free that's what we're doing here.
And by the way if Disney's confusing at any point you can simply add a console log statement here and
console log numbers ie numbers J.
And then outer and inner element to always keep track of what's where.
This however will be the logic we need to update the numbers we're getting and to make sure that we
actually have a sorted list.
So what I'll actually do now is I'll get rid of the sorted numbers array because I just used the numbers
array we got as a input here to sorted and hence here I will just return numbers.
And then the first element here.
So now we have a get mean algorithm which is of course longer if we compare to the first one where we
simply sort our list and then return the first element which has to be the smallest element since we
sought to do list in the ascending way with this logic here.
So let's see if that works.
If I try running this with get too.
So if this new algorithm.
Let's see if we still get one if I reload here I get one.
Now let's try this differently.
Let's say my algorithm and my array here is this one
and let's see if dad works.
We should get minus 10 now.
That looks good to me.
This is minus 10.
So what if I had just one element in their that also works and gives me that one element.
And what if I have an array that looks something like this well still works.
So it seems like this also does the trick now and it gives us the smallest number now which solution
is better than this one or this one.
Of course we have two different approaches here and that's quite common in programming.
Often you can find more than one solution for a given problem.
And now we need to compare solutions to find out which one is better.
But how should we compare these two solutions.