Where is this error coming from? What does this error even mean? Modules are a relatively new feature and
as you might imagine, since scripts can point at other scripts that should be imported,
we have to be strict regarding security,
we need to make sure that a script can't import a script from another page which might be malicious.
You might think why would I add such code to my own scripts.
Well if you're using third-party libraries, then such a library might be compromised and might try to
download files from other malicious files,
this is why we have a cross origin request policy which basically means cross origin, so cross domain
requests are not allowed,
you're only allowed to download scripts from the same domain
your page is running on.
Now the problem we're facing here is that we're serving this app with the file protocol.
Remember, what we always did thus far is we double clicked index.html in the Windows Explorer or
in the MAC finder and this opens it up in the browser but actually does not open it up as it would be
opened if it is served by a web server,
it just opens it with this file protocol, which simply just means it displays the content of the file
and is able to execute Javascript conveniently. Thus far, this wasn't a problem because a lot of features
worked just fine with the file protocol but web server dependent features, like using this cross origin
policy don't work there,
this policy requires the page to be served from a real web server in order to be validated and therefore
we now need to serve our app here,
our page through a web server and not through the file protocol.
Now that sounds difficult,
it sounds like we need to setup our own server, host it somewhere, maybe pay for it,
the good thing is you don't.
if you google for servejs, you should find this serve package here on npmjs.com,
we had a look at npmjs.com in the third-party library module and here, you get a basic web server
which you can install on your system and run on your system,
you don't need to deploy your page anywhere,
don't need to rent any servers, it spins up a little server on your machine, works on Windows and macOS
and this server will serve your application. Now to install it,
we need to install Node.js though, we haven't used Node.js in this course,
I will have a Node.js section later in the course but we also don't need to write any Node.js code
right now. We just need to install the Node.js runtime on our machine because this serve package requires
Node.js because that little server which it spins up is written in Node.js.
In addition, Node.js will also give us a tool which we can use to install this tool here, this serve
tool on our machine, so we get two benefits at the same time. So visit nodejs.org and download
the latest version of Node.js, at the point of time I'm recording this, it's 12 but it doesn't really
matter, simply pick the latest one.
It should automatically preselect your operating system,
it is available for all operating systems, if it doesn't, simply go to other downloads and manually pick
your system there.
So once you downloaded it and walked through the installer, it's a normal installer,
nothing fancy about that, you can run a special command to install this serve tool, not this command
but a slightly different one. For that,
open up your terminal or command prompt which you have on your system,
the path where you navigate to does not matter and run npm install -g which stands for global
serve. On Linux and Mac,
you might need to add as sudo in front of this to get the right permissions, on Windows
this is not required.
Hit enter thereafter and you might be prompted for a password,
if you are simply, enter it and now what this will do is it will install this serve tool globally, Node.js
ships with its own package management system which we'll have a close look at in the tooling module
and this manages packages on a per project basis but also on a global basis
and here we installed a global package which is now available on our entire machine.
So with that installed, back in our project you can open up a terminal which is navigated into this project,
so you can either navigate into your project with the cd command here or in Visual Studio Code,
if you go to view, you can also click on terminal here and this opens up a terminal, your default system
terminal or command prompt but built into Visual Studio Code and already navigated into your project
folder which is very convenient of course
and now here with serve installed, you can simply type serve and it will automatically search for the
index.html file and serve that through this dummy web server.
So now this gives you the address you have to enter in the browser to view your project,
in my case it's localhost:5000 and if I do enter this here, I load the same page as before
and we get some errors because we haven't fixed all errors but we're not getting this course error anymore
because now, we can use modules and this course setting which they managed for us behind the scenes.
You can ignore that favicon error here,
we don't have a favicon hence we can't load it,
we now just need to fix our modules and make sure we utilize this exported component.
Important note, you should keep this serve process running,
you can always quit it with control C or control D but if you quit it, you can't visit your page here
anymore,
so you will always need to restart it with the serve command whenever you want to continue working on
the project.
You can only visit this page here on this localhost:5000 address
as long as this process is running.