So we want to be able to show that modal and for Dad need a way to control the visibility of the backdrop
and the modal.
Now there are various ways of doing so.
In CSX we can set the opacity.
We can set the display property.
Anything like that.
What we will need in the end is some way to pass in the information whether it is should be visible
or not from outside.
So from our main document because one possible way would be to set let's say a open attribute even a
set this to true or as you also see it on some built in elements just open for example the built in
button element has a disabled attribute which you also add just like this so when open or opened maybe
is added let's say then we want to show the modal if it's not added We don't want to show it.
And now I'll add a script tag here and you could outsource this into a different file to of course where
I want to do something when this button is clicked and I want to add this opened attribute when we click
it.
So I will now get access to my confirmed button here maybe by using document queries selector and I
can selector select a button here because a no advantage of the shadow Dom we will just fetch this button
because the buttons in our model are part of the shadow Dom and therefore we are in no danger of accidentally
selecting these from outside.
So that's another advantage of the shadow Dom here.
When we select something in our main document we only select buttons in that main document.
And in this case we only have one button so I can use this query selector and then I'll add my event
listener here for the Click event and here I want to add the opened attribute to my you see modal element
for this all get access to my modal with document queries selector and now we can simply use U.S. modal
as a selector because this is a valid tag by which we can select it and then we could say modal set
attribute opened and now we need to assign a value here and I'll set this to an empty string now in
order to be able to see that effect we have to make sure that we're not showing the model by default
which we currently are and especially its backdrop is blocking us from clicking anything so to hide
it by default we got a couple of possible ways of solving this one way of making sure we can show and
hide this is to set the opacity to 0 by default which will hide this but then we'll face a problem actually
because now if I reload this it is hidden but we still can't click this because even though it's invisible
it's fully opaque it's still in front of us now we could changed a set index but we can also set the
pointer events here to non and this will not accept any clicks on the backdrop but let them through
instead we do the same on the modal and we just have to change this later when we show it.
So did we then really block clicks through it but here we want to allow them.
So now have a reload I can click this and if you watched you saw opened was added here on the right.
Let me show this again for reload this model here doesn't have to open attribute but if I click this
button watch it here on the right here it is there it opened.
So this is working and now in the next lecture we can work on doing something in our component.
When this opened attribute is added.