Now back in our little project, the monster killer project, let's simulate such a problem.
We do get some user input here actually, we get that entered value and I already do some validation here,
we check whether what the user entered can be used as a maximum life,
so if it's bigger than zero and if it is a number to begin with, after converting it to a number.
Now the kind of sad thing here, in quotes because it's actually good of course is that parseInt doesn't
throw an error
if the user enters something invalid. In other programming languages, that could be the case but Javascript
is really forgiving here
and if you enter something that can't be converted to an integer or to a number here, well then you don't
get an error, you don't get a system error that crashes your script but instead parseInt generates
this NAN value which we check for with isNan.
So this doesn't really produce an error but here to continue and show you try catch, I want to have
a real error
ANd the good thing is we can create and throw our own errors and whilst it might sound strange that
you want to do that in your code, you have to keep in mind that with Javascript, you can write very big
applications spanning across multiple files and indeed you might want to throw an error in some parts
of your application so that you can use these official error management tools to handle that error instead
of having to write a bunch of if statements in a couple of different places of your code.
So especially in bigger applications, it's quite common that you throw your own errors in some parts
of it
and here we will throw our own error so we can practice with try catch. In other situations which we'll
see later in the course,
for example when communicating to a server, you will automatically get an error
so Javascript or the browser will automatically throw an error if things go wrong, here for this user
input,
this kind of unfortunately isn't the case so we'll do it on our own.
So how can we do it on our own?
Well let's first of all move this logic here where we get that entered value into a function. So I'll cut
that
and then maybe here add a new function which I'll name getMaxLifeValues
and in here I get that
entered value and I try to pass it as an integer
and then here, I'll take that if check and put it in here to validate what the user entered
but then here I'll not set chosenMaxLife to 100
if this is not valid,
instead I will change this to be a constant which I'll name parsed value, something like this, we'll need
that in a second and then outside of that function here, I will add that chosenMaxLife variable which
I'll for now set equal to getMaxLifeValues. So I will call the function here and in that function,
I want to return the parsed value here in the end,
that's the idea
but in this if statement, if we have an invalid value, then I will not return 100 as a fallback value
which we of course could do
but in order to see how you handle errors, I will use another keyword in Javascript which is the throw
keyword which throws a new error and an error can be anything, you can throw a number as an error, a string
or an object
and here I'll throw an object with a message property,
that's kind of the convention, most errors are objects that have a message property where I say invalid
user input, not a number,
something like that.
So now we throw our own error here and the result of that is that if we go back to our application and
we open the developer tools here and I reload and I enter a valid value, then I got a different error,
cannot access chosenMaxLife before initialization.
Yes because here of course, in my if condition here, I should check parsed value, not chosenMaxLife,
since I changed it here we should change it here as well.
So that was not what I wanted to show you,
let's reload,
if I enter 100 hundred instead, this works as before
but if we now reload and I enter hi there which can't be converted to a number, we now get our own custom
error throw here.
You see this is just an error which is our object in the end with that message but it's marked
as red because this indeed is now really an error and it stops our script execution therefore.
So pressing these buttons doesn't do anything,
so we crashed our script. Again
you might want to do that on your own in more complex scripts, so that you can use the error handling
mechanism in different parts of it, here
I'm mostly doing it so that we can now practice with try catch because you will later also work with
other things, like network requests where Javascript itself will throw errors and therefore you need
to be prepared to handle such errors.
So how do we use try catch?