Now with named slots explored let's dig a bit deeper into slots and let's see how we could actually
get access to the content we pass in our slot in our code in a component.
And with that I don't mean get access in the sense of render it what we do here automatically by simply
using the slot.
But what if we would need to kind of read our list of data or list of H2 nodes that gets passed into
our slots.
Now for that let me first of all show you something else after setting up my inner aged email template
here so the next line after this statement basically I want to get access to all my slots and I'll stored
them in a constant.
And we can easily query for them on our schedule route with the query selector all method and then querying
for the slot element because this is a normal H2 Caltech by which we can query of course.
Now here we can access our slots.
This will basically be an array or a node list of H2 male elements and we have two slots.
The first one will be at index 0.
The second one at index 1.
Now let's say we want to have a look at our second slot.
So the one with index one and then we can add an event listener here and the event 2 which we can listen
is to slot change event and dad will be triggered whenever new content arrives.
Which will happen at least once when our shadow Dom basically is used to render our component into the
real Dom and we project the content we pass into our component into our slot.
This will be the first time this triggers but then also if we would updated programmatically from outside
and the content we pass in would change then slot change for this given slot would also trigger again
and then this function which then triggers we get an event object and in here most importantly we'll
be able to analyze the content that's inside of our slot.
So here I will actually console dir their presence and object in the console which we can inspect instead
of the HD female element console log with print and there I will print that slot.
We're listening to.
So now if I save this and I reload.
You see we now have a slot output here and that gets printed by this line.
So that means that the slot change event did indeed fire which it as I mentioned does when you rendered
this component to the screen because that is when the slot here will be replaced with the projected
content for the first time.
And if we now have a look in the slot here we can see a couple of interesting elements but some very
interesting data can be seen.
If we call the assigned nodes method on our slot.
So this is not a prop..
This is a method.
If we do that and we go back for a reload then we see an array of all the content that was projected
into our slot.
Now you might be wondering why we have four elements instead of just one paragraph tag.
Reason for Dad simply is that the whitespace in front of the paragraph tag and after the paragraph tag
all those treated as text in the end we have this paragraph tag we're interested in and if we would
optimize our code here and basically write this all in line which is harder to read but gets rid of
all the X's whitespace if we would do that here for our component in the HDL file then you would see
we only have the paragraph element in there and this is now the paragraph Dom node which gets projected
into our slot.
So this is also not part of the shadow Dom but still of the light Dom.
Just the content at which our slot points so to say now I do now restructure does again to make it easier
to read.
But now if a reload I get these four elements again but again it is the paragraph tag which we get in
the end here.
And if you ever need to get access to the content that is projected into your slot then this is how
you can do it.
You can use assigned nodes and as a little side note on the protected element you also find this assigned
slot property year which you can on the other end used to find out into which slot this was projected.
So this all is a maybe an interesting information depending on which kind of application you are writing.
So slot change combined with assigned notes can be very helpful if you for example also have an application
where the content in your slot might change at runtime too.
So not just this initial change which we have here but also a change on the later point of time maybe
because you loaded some data from the web and you want to change something in your modal when that is
done.
So this is just another thing I wanted to show you which can be helpful when you're working with slots.