So now did we covered a lot about slots.
Let's finish up this model by tweaking some of its styling again.
But most importantly and first of all by making these buttons work right now it can click cancel and
OK and nothing will happen.
Now I want to close the modal in both cases but I want to dispatch my own events to which I can listen
from outside my component.
So from inside my main application my main javascript logic which runs at my main document so that I
know whether the user has confirmed this modal or cancelled it because right now what I want to be able
to do in the end is that I add an event listener here to my modal object and keep in mind my modal object
is really just my own custom component and there it would be nice if we had like a confirmed listener
and confirm is not a built in event.
So right now it is will never trigger where I can do something so most of the time in my application
I would probably want to do something like create a payment request which I sent to some back and once
the user confirmed or where I also can do something.
If the user declines it.
So if the user cancels this then maybe I want to reset some state in my application.
Of course here I'll not focus on the application logic.
I want to focus on the component and how we add our own events there.
But I just want to give you some ideas of what you could do there in a real application.
So outside of your web component will focus on making these customer events work here now.
So confirm and cancel is to go for that.
Let's dive into our mobile again.
And there we have these buttons since these buttons are part of the shadow Dom.
We have to create listeners to these buttons inside of our shadow dom.
So for that I'll add a number of constants here in the constructor below my slots listeners I added
in the last lectures and then I'll have to cancel button and for this I'll give this button an idea
of cancel button maybe like this confirm button.
And now I can select by that I.D. All X is my shadow rude you stick very selector.
You could also use get element by idea of course and then select the cancel button idea here and then
I'll duplicate this to all to select my confirmed button here with the confirmed button idea.
So now that I have access to these two buttons I can register listeners here in my component.
So let's maybe start with the cancel button here and on the cancel button I want to hide the model and
I want to dispatch this custom cancel event to which I'm listening from outside therefore all first
of all add a new method here and I'll name it height I could turn this into a private method by adding
a leading underscore and always keep in mind it's not really private.
You can still call it from outside.
I just add this to show hey this should only be used from inside.
If you then don't follow that rule well you can do that.
But here I want to keep it as a public method because even though we're not doing it in our app you
could of course definitely imagine an application where you want to hide a model from outside.
So from your main application instead from inside of the component now how do we hide it.
Well in the end it's all about setting our open attributes to known or to remove it.
And we do that not with set attribute but with remove attribute there.
I want to remove my opened attribute we can add an extra check here to see if this has the attribute
opened before we then try to remove it of course
besides that I want to set this is open to falls of course to update this property as well.
And with that demoed it will already be closed because of that opened attribute which we use in our
CSX styles here.
So therefore we have that functionality to custom event is missing.
But I'll come back to that later.
So for now let's continue with the event listener on the cancel button in the constructor there we want
to listen to an ordinary click which of course is a built in event built into core javascript and the
browser and upon a click I want to trigger this height.
So does hide method.
And of course I'll bind the this keyword here to ensure that this inside of Hyde refers to the clause
and not to the button which is the event trigger now I'll duplicate this to also hook up my confirm
button there.
I also want to hide this modal.
Now we already see a problem here.
I definitely don't want to run the same logic two times.
So what I will do instead is I'll add a private method here which I'll name cancel and I'll add one
which I'll name confirm.
Now in both I will call this open and here we don't need to bind this because of recalling it like this
from inside the class.
The class itself is calling a method and therefore this in the called method will refer to the class
too.
So all the call Hi is here.
Sorry.
Here it should also be.
Height of course not open so it should be hide in both.
But now we can dispatch different custom events here so let's tweak that and go up and forward a cancel
button.
I will now actually call my private cancel method and for confirm my private confirm method.
And right now they will both just call hide but that will change soon.
So now with that we should already have a working model such dead when I click cancel it gets hidden
and if I open it again I can also hide it in close with.
OK.
And you can see I can reopen it even though I have extra check here in my main app in my index H2 file
where I check for whether it is not open yet which is open property and I can still reopen it after
closing it because I do update this is open property in my model as well.
So this is the first important step but the more important and more interesting step of course now is
to admit our own custom event.
Let's do that next.