So it would be really great if we could listen to our own event from outside our component and not just
from inside because that kind of defeats its purpose right.
Well the good thing is when you create such an event we can specify an object as a second argument where
we can add some information about how this event should behave.
And there we basically got free configurations.
Bubbles allows us to define whatever it is eventual bubble up or not.
This means if it should only be available on the element we dispatched it on or if it is not handled
there.
If it should go to the next element in the dorm tree.
So in our case for this button to cancel button if we don't add an event listener dear it would bubble
up and event listeners on the section would handle it.
And if we had no event listeners there it would bubble up and event listeners on this day would handle
it.
And if we have no listeners there would bubble up and so on.
So this doesn't sound too bad right.
If I set this to true let's see now theoretically we should be able to listen to it from other places
too and not just on event listeners on this button.
So maybe now our event listener on our accustomed component which the end wraps this button works.
So let's go back and reload and click cancel.
Still no output.
The reason for that is that there is another important argument and that is the composed arguments here
composed when set to true.
Now suddenly ensures that this will work.
If I now click cancel usually cancel here and the reason for that is that composed which by default
is false.
Just like bubbles composed means that if you set it to true then this event may leave the shadow dorm
in which it is if it is in one.
And here of course it is triggered inside of our shadow dorm.
If you set composed two falls then the event must not leave our shadow dorm tree.
So it will bubble up but only inside our shadowed on tree.
So we could add a listener to modal and handle it but not outside of our component.
So we need to set both to true bubbles and composed to handle our event outside of our component.
And now we can listen to it.
Now this is one way of doing that.
Of course there is a simpler way to I just show you this way because sometimes you need to take that
route.
But of course for record firm and we could have done that for cancel too.
We can all just refer to this which is our component.
So our own custom element in the end remember our modal extend stage Himmel element.
So this really refers to our own custom HD Himmel element in the end and therefore our custom element
itself also has to dispatch event method.
So here are a confirmed event can also be holding a new event here to confirm events.
So the name is confirm and you can pick any name you want but of course it should match the name we
are listening to outside and then here I will use this confirm event.
Now if I save this without any extra call on thick and I click OK we still get confirmed because now
we're triggering this event on our element itself.
So not inside the shadow Dom not on some nested element of the shadow Dom but on our custom element
itself and therefore listeners on our element will of course receive that event.
It will not bubble up there now though.
So if we would want to listen to it on the body in our main document this should not work.
But we also don't need to manage composed and so on because this is now simply not required.
So this is of course the shorter alternative and the one you would typically use.
But I found it important to mention how you can use bubbles and composed to also let events triggered
inside your shadow Dom on some nested element bubbles up through the shadow Dom and potentially even
leave it with composed.
So these are the custom events and how we can handle it.
And now we have the full flexibility we might need.
We're closing the model and in our main application which we typically would run or import in our main
document like this index H2 I'll follow there we can now also find out which button the user pressed
without having to kind of dig into our component and try to attach listeners to the buttons in the component
from outside.
Instead we use these convenient listeners on our custom element itself.