So last but not least, let's explore the functional programming style. For this,
I'll create a new file here, functional.js and of course import this here in the index.html file,
functional.
The idea behind functional programming now is that we organize our code around functions, so we
can still then reuse and share logic by simply sharing a function, by exporting it and importing it in
another file and so on.
So how could we split this application here into a functionally written application?
It can be hard to think about this if you're relatively new in programming.
My personal experience shows that object oriented programming is relatively easy to pick up because
it's close to the real world
so to say, we think in objects and that's how we think about the real world as well. The procedural style
also is not too hard because we execute code step-by-steps and therefore all we have to do is that we
have to think about what we want to do in our application step-by-step,
so what should happen when and then this code is basically writing itself. Now in the functional world,
it's a bit like in the object oriented world, we think about the different things that make up our application
but the things are now not objects but instead of different logical blocks, something like a validate
function, a function to get access to a DOM element, a function to extract user input, a function to create
a new user, a function to greet a user.
So basically we try to split our code into the different logical blocks we have here. So in functional.js,
how could we get started because maybe that helps us understand how it works?
It still starts with us getting access to the form right,
we need access to the form so that we can listen to the form submission. To get access here, we could
write a new function, connect form, name is up to you
and by the way you can write this function in any way you want, in this function declaration style here,
you could also write it as a function expression or of course, you could use an arrow function here if
you wanted to,
that all works, here
I'll just write it like this. So connect form, just like this without any parameters for now
and in there I want to get access to my form and I do so by calling document get element by ID user-input
and thereafter I will reach out to my form and add a submit event listener here and then,
then what? Then I want to point at a function that should execute when the form is submitted.
So maybe let's add a new function here, the signupHandler which gets this event object which calls event
prevent default,
it will also do more than that but this is something we definitely need to do
and then I point at it here.
This is something we could do but it's not the perfect way of setting this up.
Instead the idea or the core philosophy you really should embrace when writing functional code is that
your functions should be pure and all the data they work with is received as parameters, so that your
functions are as predictable and reusable as possible.
So for this connect form function, this means that we would probably get the form ID as a parameter
and also the form submit handler function as a parameter
and then here instead of pointing at user input here, we would point at form ID and here we would just
say form submit handler
and now this function has code which is totally reusable, which makes no assumptions about what's in
your HTML file,
it makes no assumption about this ID and about the name of the function that should handle the submission.
Instead we would call connect form here when our app is initialized,
so when this Javascript file is passed and executed for the first time
and here I would feed in the concrete values, so user input and a pointer at signupHandler.
Now of course in this simple app we don't gain much by this but now we really have a function which
is pretty focused, pretty straightforward, pretty easy to understand and which is also pretty reusable
because it's not tied to a specific form in the HTML code.
If we had multiple forms which we wanted to connect with submit handlers, we could reuse this function
and we could just call it with different arguments, that already is how you should think about code
when thinking in a functional programming style.
So now we connect this form, we point at the signupHandler when the form gets submitted. In the sign
up handler,
we now want to get our user input and we now also of course then want to validate it and create a new
user.
Now again we could copy our logic from procedural right,
we could copy this logic here for getting the user input for the moment and paste it in here and this
would work but we're not really thinking in a functional way.
What did I just say about functions?
Well they should be pure and should receive all the inputs they need as parameters
and here again I'm hardcoding IDs which are IDs for my HTML document into the function.
Now we could do this but is this good?
Well it's certainly not bad.
Now you might argue that hardcoding these IDs into the function is not something you want to do because
we got rid of it here but I would argue that the signupHandler is of course a very specific function
which indeed can be tied to the HTML file because it really is about this sign up form.
It's not a general function here, like connect form was which should work with any form,
this way you should only work with the signing up logic so that is fine but we're basically having some
code repetition here.
Why don't we create a new function here which we name get user input
and here I expect to get my input element ID
and in this function we then return document get element by ID to which I forward the input element ID
parameter and then I access .value here.
Now of course, this only works with the input elements but that's the idea behind this function,
so we could add an extra check which checks if this is an HTML input element
but here I just assume that it always will be one
and now we can rewrite this.
We can get rid of this line here and entered username
now simply is get user input for the username ID and we can get rid of this line and the entered password
now just is get user input for password
and again we have a reusable function here
and this is now leaner and more focused. So now we get the input,
of course we want to validate it. So unsurprisingly we create a new function for this, the validate
function
and here we could again follow the logic we set up into object oriented part.
We can expect a value, a flag and a validator value here and then basically copy over to logic from oop
because object oriented programming and functional program is not that far apart.
It's a bit more than just translating classes to functions
but the idea of organizing logic in methods and in classes is not that far away from the idea of organizing
logic and functions.
So unsurprisingly, we can copy the logic from the validate method here and add it in the validate function
here.
Now we just need to replace this required and this min length with just required and min length and add
some global constants here
and yes this is also possible,
not everything has to be inside of a function.
Here we want some global flags, some global identifiers and therefore we can define them just like this
in our script here.
So now we have that, we have our validate function and we can now use this validate function here in
the signupHandler.
So here we could now call validate and forward the entered username and so on and that again would
not be wrong but I want to create yet another new function, maybe here which I'll name create user and
this is a function that takes the username and the user password
and this should now run the validation
and that's just of course one way of doing it, not the only correct one, just one way of doing it.
So I want to run validation here and then if it succeeds, also create my user. So in here, I will now check
if not validate for username and the required flag,
so if this yields false or if validate for the user password and the min length flag and a min length of
five, if either of the two yields false,
we could throw an alert but this would be a side effect.
Now what's the side effect? A side effect basically is some logic you execute inside of a function which
does something outside of the function, which sends an HttpRequest, which changes something in
the DOM or like in this case, which shows an alert,
so these are typical side effects.
A pure function just receives parameters and then maybe returns something and for the same parameters,
it always returns the same thing. An impure function which has a side effect might also do that,
it might also return always the same thing but it also might manipulate something outside of the function,
so like I said in the DOM or send a HttpRequest. Now sometimes you can't avoid this but here,
I want to have create user as a pure function, so I will not throw my alert here,
instead I will throw a new error here with an error message of invalid input and I'll just copy the
error message from the oop file here.
So copy that string and throw this here as an error message on this Javascript error.
So here we're not showing an alert,
we're really throwing an error and that will automatically cancel the execution of the remaining function.
If this error gets not thrown,
so if we make it past this if check, if we do have valid inputs, then I will return a new object and that
is my user with a username which holds the username value and with a password which holds this user
password value.
So now create user is something we could call here in the signupHandler,
and we got our new user by calling create user and we forward the entered username and the entered password.
Now this could fail
however, this would throw an error if we have invalid inputs.
So here we can use try catch and again we could use try catch in the object oriented style and in the procedural
style as well,
don't get me wrong but now I think here is really clean to do it like this.
We use try catch and we try to create a new user but if this fails, I will now show my alert here and
yes this will now produce a side effect but we could even outsource this into a separate function, show
alert
but since I would do nothing else in there but call the alert function, I'll do it just in here.
And as I said, sometimes you can't avoid it,
it's okay to have functions that produce side effects,
you just want to keep most functions pure and side effect free,
here however I will output the error message in an alert.
If this succeeds however, I want to console log the new user
and of course also greet the new user and for that we could create a new function here,
the greet user function which gets a user object and just calls console log
Hi I am plus user username and again, this here would also technically be a side effect by the way because
we do something outside of the function.
So here I can then call greet user and forward the new user
and there are different ways of writing this,
these are just examples of course. If we now save this and we reload this page, if the form is empty and
I click submit,
I get this error. If I have a valid username but my password is too short,
I get an error. If my password is long enough but the username is empty,
I get an error and if both is valid and we click create user, we're showing Hi
I am Maximilian, the log is missing because I didn't enter it here,
so here of course I want to log my new user and then retry this, so reload,
enter the values here again
and now we get the same output as before.
So this now really is working
and now this is an example of functional programming.
The core idea of course being that we organize our code into functions where most functions are pure
and side effect free and therefore, highly reusable.