So that were the basics about cookies,
let's dive in a bit deeper,
let's say we want to store more,
so here when we store data, I don't just set uid but I also want to store some user data. With local
storage,
we created a user with a name, with an age in an object and then I would basically just, to transfer what
we did with local storage, add a user a key here and then use JSON.stringify on user or on the
person you created here to convert this to JSON which is a string and hopefully store it in the cookie.
Let's see whether that works.
Let's save that,
go back and reload, click store and click retrieve and indeed, this worked, our user data is encoded as
a string and stored in the cookie.
Now one thing you probably see there is not just that this works though but that we don't have such
a nice retrieval API as we had it with local storage. There to get an item,
we had the get item method. Now with cookies,
it's an all or nothing thing,
when I access document.cookie I got no get method or anything like that,
I just
do get all my key-value pairs separated with a comma. In the end what we get here is one long string
which is also why on document.cookie,
you can use all these string methods and hence for example, you could also split this on this semicolon
and if you would do that and you reload and retrieve, you see now at least you have the key-value pairs
split into separate items here in an array, though please be aware that there is an extra whitespace
in front of the user item because there was a whitespace in the cookie string before.
So how could you now retrieve a single item let's say? Well to get rid of the excess whitespace, you could
store your cookie data in a constant where we use document.cookie.split on the semicolon, then
on cookie data we can call map, a method which is available on every array and cookie data is an array
which requires a function which is executed on every item in the array and every item in the array is
just a string, there
I want to get rid of excess whitespace and I can do so by returning i.trim, trim is a method you
can call on strings to remove excess whitespace at the beginning or end and with that if I then console
log the result of this which we could store in a data constant, if we console log data here and save
that, you'll see that if we now reload here and click retrieve, we got an array without that extra whitespace.
Well and now if you would want to find a specific value, you just would have to get the value on the
right side of the equal sign, so for example for the user, you can access the second item in data because
it is the second item in our data array and then on that item, you can of course split that on the equal
sign and then you will have two items,
one is the key, the first element in the resulting array is the key, the second element in the resulting
array is the value.
So on the result of that split call which is that array with two elements, you can now access the second
element to get the value,
so this would be the user value here in this case.
So if I save that and reload and click retrieve, that's the user value.
So as I mentioned, a bit clunky, definitely not as nice to work with as local storage,
so what are the advantages of cookies then? The advantages of cookies are that you can set them to expire
and that you can also send them to a server with requests.
Now since we have no backend server we communicate with,
let's here focus on the expiration which is quite interesting.
Now it is very simple, if you don't set any expiration date on a cookie, it should expire when your session
expires,
so when you close the entire browser, though finally it's up to the browser when it wants to delete
the cookie.
Also keep in mind that just as with local storage, the user can always delete all cookies, either through
the dev tools and the application tab here or simply with browser preferences where you can also clear
cookies and you can clear cookies no matter if they have an expiration date or not
but back to that expiration date.
If we would want to say that our userId should not expire with the end of the session,
then we can add one of two flags, max age or expires. To add the max age flag, you add a semicolon after
your key-value pair and then whitespace max-age and set this equal to a maximum age. Now the maximum
age should be expressed in seconds,
so you could say this cookie should only be valid for 50 seconds or for 2 seconds.
If I do that and I save this, if I reload and I click store, if I go to the application you see under cookies,
this uid here has an expiration date.
If we expand that, we see,
if I double click in there, we can see the full date and that basically is in two seconds after
it was issued.
Therefore now already if I click retrieve, this should not work and I do indeed get an error because
my one cookie was removed and therefore when I try to call it split on the second cookie, this of course
failed because we only have one cookie by now,
it did expire after two seconds, hence if I reload and I click store and retrieve quickly, it works or
at least it doesn't fail, it doesn't work as before but I'll come back to that in a second.
So that's max-age,
the alternative to that is that you set expires to a value and expires
now takes a date.
Now that date needs to have a certain format and attached you find a link to MDN where you see examples,
where you also see that format for example,
so that would be an alternative. If you know it's not one minute or ten days or whatever it is, it is
a fixed date,
then you could use expires.
Now I'll go back to max-age and actually set this to let's say 360 seconds,
so to three minutes.
Now you might have noticed that we have a problem when we retrieve the data.
The problem is if I store data and I then retrieve it, here I print my userId
Now actually, it's now what I want to print,
I want to print the user, not the userId with this code.
Now why is this happening?
Well let's simply print
document.cookie here to get an idea.
So if I save this, reload, you don't need to store it again, it should still be stored but you can always
click stored to refresh it and if you then click retrieve, you see
this is how it was stored here.
Now why is it stored like this here?
Well of course because my cookie expired in the past, user did not expire and if we then set user again
to a value which it already had, it's not recreated, the old one is not deleted and the new one is added,
instead
it's just kept, it's not touched and your new cookie is added.
So since uid expired in the past but user did never expire,
user is still around and uid was readded but of course in the second position and that simply has
the implication that retrieving data just by index alone is not a good idea,
what you should do instead is you should search for the key name and you can do that on strings, for example
with includes where you can check for a given name. Attached you also find a link to MDN where
you find more patterns on how you can parse data and get data out of a cookie.
Please also note that max-age,
so this extra flag which I set and the same is true for all flags is not part of the cookie output
you get
so you don't have to worry about that when parsing your cookie at least and that's it for cookies.
Again, I did provide a couple of resources
you can use to dive deeper, for now
that's all I want to explore here though
and with that, let's move on to the last part, to IndexedDB