So let's now write an integration test and for integration testing, if we have a look at all our code,
which function could we use there?
Well we got, in the app.js file, we got add user which uses a lot of other functions which has a lot of
dependencies.
So testing this function would be an integration test
but this is a function that does neither take an input nor return an output,
instead it's a function that really added something, that DOM,
so this is something which you might want to test in an end-to-end testing scenario or in a user interface
test but an integration test would be kind of hard here, we would have to do a lot of manual DOM interaction
inside of our test which you can do but which you might not want to do.
Instead there is something else I can test and that is basically a part of that function you could say.
In the end what I'm doing in add user is I do select a couple of elements, then I do validate the input
and then I generate a text based on the input.
Now we could outsource this into a separate function and that is a part of writing modular code
that I mentioned earlier,
you are forced to write modular code which also makes your code easier to manage and reuse though.
So in util.js, I can export a new function and let's name it check and generate or whatever you want
to do.
Now check and generate will get a name and an age as an input and then I will go to my app.js file
and I will grab that validation code and move it into check and generate to validate input for
and now that's important, for the name here and then there, for the age
like this
and then if we make it past this if block, I will return a call to generate text where I pass a name and age
because that is what I then return here,
I return the checked text.
So in app.js where I'm using this, output text in the end just the result of my call to check and generate,
I don't need validate input here anymore, I don't generate text anymore, I'll just import check and generate,
this new function, I'll import that in app.js and down there, output text is the result of check and generate and
I can move that up here and here I can now simply check if not output text, so if we did return let's
say false here, we return false if validation fails,
so if this is returned and therefore if this is not true-ish, if it is false for example, then it will
return an add user too and it will not continue creating that element.
So now this is the tweak add user function and this gives us the check and generate function which is
great to use in an integration test.
So let's write the test for it and I want to test if my validity works correctly and I then get the
expected text back, so I should generate a valid text output, something like this and then here in this
function, I will test my check and generate function which I therefore have to import and I can simply
create my text with check and generate and I pass Max and 29 here and I would expect this
text to be equal to Max 29 years old.
So my expectation actually is the same as in this unit test but it's not a simple unit test because the
function we're testing has more to it. We could fail because validation fails or because generate text
fails, however generate text is kind of ruled out because we have a separate unit test for this and this
is also how you want to write your test by the way. You want to ensure that you drill down like to the
smallest possible level and write unit tests for all your units, so write a test for generate text would
also be worth writing one for validate input and then your integration tests really just rely on the
units being tested and ensure that the units also work together well, so this is then the idea behind
an integration test.
So here I have this test and if I now save this, it actually fails. Now I get an error that validate input
is not defined here and that's true because I do export validate input,
I don't need to do that anymore,
I should instead create it or define it as a constant,
the same is true for generate text so that I can use these functions directly in the util.js file
and then at the bottom, I should also export generate text and assign the generate text constant here
and also export validate input maybe and assign that constant, so that I could use it in other files too
and now you see my tests passed, both tests passed.
Now the idea about the integration test is that if I do change something in my check and generate function,
for example here I use my validate input function incorrectly, so the result of that is used incorrectly,
now it fails
and now this is a great example of why I have an integration test.
I could have a separate test in validate input and validate input does work correctly,
I can tell you that but my error is directly here in check and generate, I'm using the result of validate
input incorrectly by not checking for it being false but for it being true
and this means if my name is valid, then I actually return false which is of course the wrong logic in
check and generate.
So even though my units work correctly, the combination of the units fails because I have an error here
and this again shows you the power of tests and why integration tests makes sense too and unit tests alone
could not be enough because all units could be working, if you are combining them incorrectly,
you still have a problem,
so now it's working again though.