When comparing values in Javascript, there is a strange behavior you might notice if you start comparing
objects and arrays to each other
because these don't work like numbers or strings do. Consider this example - you have an object which has
a name property which holds Max as a value and you have another object which has the same value.
Now these are not the same object,
we're not talking about one variable here which I want to compare to itself,
that would be redundant but instead let's say these are two different variables with two different objects
but of course the objects themselves regarding the values that are stored in there are kind of equal to
us humans. Now
still, if you compare these, no matter if with the triple or the double equal operator, you will find out
that the value is not true as you might have expected but instead that it's false.
Now why is that?
Because objects and arrays and for arrays, it's indeed the same, if you had two arrays with the same values,
they would not yield true if you compare them with the equal sign operators. For objects and arrays,
you have to understand that they're kind of special in Javascript.
Now I'll dive deeper into what exactly is special there
later in the course where we have a closer look at the technical details of Javascript and some of the
core things you also have to be aware of,
for now let's just keep in mind that these two types of data, objects and arrays, are special. Now we can
again check this by opening the console in the developer tools,
here again in the calculator but that does not matter and in there, let's create two constants or variables,
doesn't matter, person1 which is an object with name Max,
so with a name property that holds a string and then person2 which basically now holds the same data.
Now if you now compare person1 to person2 with the equality operator, again it doesn't matter if you use
two or three equals signs here, you see you get false as a value here, so this generates a boolean of the value
false here
not true, even though to us humans, this looks exactly the same.
Now it has something to do with how that is stored behind the scenes in memory
but again we'll dive into the details of that a bit later,
for now just keep in mind that two objects stored in different variables will never be the same.
It's different if you have an object stored in a variable or constant and then you create a new constant
or variable, let's say a person3 which you set equal to person1,
then you will see the person3 is indeed equal to person1 but if you have another constant or variable
where you assigned a brand new object which you created like this and then assigned like this, then this
will never be equal to an equal looking but differently created object in another constant or variable.
So that's just something to keep in mind,
again why this is the way it is is something we'll have a detailed look later.
It's also the same for arrays as I mentioned
if you have your hobbies array here and it includes sports and cooking, like this and then you have more
hobbies and that has exactly the same values written in exactly the same way, then here
also you will find out that hobbies in this case is never equal to more hobbies no matter how many
equal signs you use, just as it was the case with objects, now
also because arrays behind the scenes are objects as you learned earlier.
So again why this is the case will be covered later, for now
just keep it in mind,
equality comparisons won't work like this for object and arrays. You would have to compare individual
values,
so for example person1.name equal to person2.name
since you then get access to the string that's stored in there,
this again would work so this is a comparison you can make but the overall object or array, that can't
be compared.