So let's move on to IndexedDB and for that, I'll rename app.js to cookies
and create a new app.js file in which we'll now work.
Copy all the code from cookies though but get rid of the cookies specific code and the functions,
I just want to have the listeners and the functions here
and now let's work with IndexedDB.
Now IndexedDB is the most complex storage and therefore just as before, you find an attached resource
that allows you to dive way deeper, here
I just want to explore the basic functionality. Now the basic functionality is that you work with an
in-browser database and for that you can leave that development server running,
you can also use the file protocol for IndexedDB though,
here I'll do it with the server.
So the first step with IndexedDB is that you create a database or open a connection to an existing
one.
For that, we can call IndexedDB which exists on window and which we therefore can just access like
this and there, call open.
Now to open, you pass the name of your database, the name is totally up to you
but of course it shouldn't exist yet as a database,
for example storage dummy. Second argument can be passed, can be the version of the database, you can use
that to keep track of different versions, update a database, change it and so on,
not something we'll explore here, so we can just set the version one.
Now when this runs for the first time and the database doesn't exist yet, it will create it
otherwise it will just open a connection,
so that's the first step.
Now this is not promise based or anything like that unfortunately,
so we can't call then and get the database connection object as an argument,
that's unfortunately not how it works.
Instead this open method here returns a so-called request, a db request as I'll call it.
Now on db request, you can add two event handlers, two event listeners, either with add event listener or for
best cross browser support, with onSuccess which should point at a function and then also additionally
onError which should point at a function. Now in both functions, you get access to an event object and
now you can interact with that. Now in onError, I'll just console log error and not worry too much about
it right now, of course in your application where you really depend on IndexedDB, you should provide some
fallback logic but here it's fine like this, in onSuccess
however, I want to continue. There, we get access to the database to which we connected or which was just
created through that event object, event.target.result is a field you can access here, a property
you can access and that will hold access to the database that was created.
Now we can configure that database,
remember this fires when this open request succeeded
so now we can configure that once this happened.
Now I mentioned that IndexedDB would work with tables and records like databases you know from servers,
now actually the terminology is a bit different,
it's object stores which you work with, a bit like tables, you can have multiple object stores and each
object store can store multiple objects I guess but it's a bit like tables and records in the
end.
Now with the database you get access to, you can use it to create an object store by calling create object
store like this.
Now this is a function that takes a couple of parameters,
first one is the name of the object store,
for example products.
Let's say we're building an app where we want to store some products here on the client side, though
keep in mind what I said earlier,
business critical or security relevant information as well as data that has to be shared with other clients
should not be stored here,
so it's really just data which can get lost and which we just need to enhance the user experience,
so let's say we're storing a couple of products. Now.
every object store needs one key, one property that exists on every stored object by which this object
can be identified.
You configure this in a second argument you pass to create object store, there you pass in a configuration
object which has to have a key path property, where you set up that single key which every item has
by which it can be identified,
let's say for a product, that's an ID field, it's up to you,
it just has to be a field which later exists
once you start adding data. This returns access to the object store, so we can store access to that object
store in a new constant,
now we can initialize this object store. We might want to add some initial data here and of course that
now really depends on your application, whether that's the case or not,
so that we can see something,
I will do it here.
We can use the object store object for that and there, we'll have a transaction property on which we have
an onComplete listener. This points at a function where we also get an event object which we don't need
here though in which we now can execute code. Now onComplete will trigger once the object store creation
finished in the end,
so it's now in here where we can interact with the database and this object store. Now to store new data,
we reach out to the database because you could store it in any object store and there, you also have a
transaction method though now which you execute like such, so you execute a transaction method, which
takes two arguments.
The first argument is the name of your object store,
so the name we set up here, in my case products. So I'll point at products here,
second argument is the mode under which you want to access this store and that could be read or like
in my case, read
write,
I want to be able to write as well. Now this should open up a connection to that object store, on the resulting
object,
you can now call object store as a method and pass in that name again.
You need to call that object store method because you could pass in multiple object store names to the transaction
and then this would allow you to select a single object store and this will now give you direct access
to that object store
we're trying to establish a connection to.
You can store that object store access here in a constant, products store for example
and now we can work with that.
Here we can use product store to call add and add a new item
and now that item should be a Javascript object which needs to have that key here,
so in my case it needs to have an ID property, could be p1 for product one and then it can have
any fields you want,
for example a title for the product, a first product, maybe a price which can be a number, maybe a tax array
where we have expensive and luxury as tax for example.
Any object can be added,
you just need to have your key path here,
you need to respect that in the object
and with that, this should be added.
That was a lot of talking.
Now let's save that and let's reload this page and we get an error. Now this error tells us that the
database is not running a version change transaction.
Now the thing is we defined this onSuccess callback here,
this onSuccess function which would fire when the database is successfully created.
It turns out that we actually interact with the database,
you need a different handler which is onUpgradeNeeded,
so if we save this now with this changed and we reload, this error goes away.
Let's now visit the application tab and there under IndexedDB,
you should find that storage dummy database.
Now it says zero objects stores though, so you might want to delete that and then simply reload and it should
then create it in the correct way with the products object store and there if we expand this, we can see
our key but we also see the value which was stored for that key which is this Javascript object and
therefore
this is more structured data stored in there without the need to encode it with JSON or anything like
that
and of course you can store multiple such objects with ease here, all identified through their key. So that
was a lot of work and it already shows that this is more complex to work with but also more powerful
therefore,
now let's say we want to store something when we click the store button.