Now of course we might be interested in sending back some HTML data,
right,
that would be
great.
Now of course we can do that, here when we write our response,
we can use HTML, for example we can write Hello there like this and have our HTML tags there.
Now if we do so, there are two things - one, we must now quit the server and restart it because we change
the file,
the ongoing process of course still is based on the old file when we executed the process.
So when we changed the file, we have to quit the server and restarted during development and of course
also after you deployed your server, if you change something in code and you want that code to have an
effect, you upload it onto your server and restart the server,
so onto your cloud machine and restart that server that runs there.
Now with that, that is done but now you'll notice something else, if we reload
you see Hello there
there actually is displayed correctly
but if we open the developer tools and go to the network tab and you reload the page so that you see your
request there and you access this, you will notice that under headers here, if you have a look at the
response headers, so the headers that were part of the response sent back by the server, we say nothing
about the kind of data that this actually is.
Now the browser here actually renders this correctly as HTML in the DOM but this is not something we
should take for granted,
This is a smart guess by the browser here because it sees that our content seems to contain some HTML
content, not all browsers necessarily do that.
Instead it is a good practice and really important to set an extra header, so to add extra metadata to
the response header when sending back the response that explains to the browser which kind of data is
attached because this then tells the browser what to do with that data
and we're not relying on these smart guesses.
Now we worked with headers before but there, we worked with headers on the requests we sent from client
site Javascript to a backend, so we set headers on the outgoing requests, something like the content type
of the data we attach there.
Now we need to do the same but the other way around, we need to set headers not in the client side Javascript
but in the server side Javascript and we can do that, on the response object,
we got a set header method.
This takes two arguments where the first argument is the header identifier and the second argument is
the value for that header and there for example, we can set the content type.
We worked with that before on client side Javascript,
it also is a header we can set on the server side though and set this to text/html.
This is the standardised identifier for saying hey we got HTML text data attached to the outgoing
response,
so it's a text, it's a string but it is HTML which is in the text. An alternative by the way
would be text/plain
and let me do that first to show you the difference. With text/plain we're saying this is normal text,
don't parse it as HTML. If we do that and we restart the server and we reload this page, you see
now the tags here are output as text because the browser is not guessing, because we're telling it that
the data we're getting here is of text/plain and therefore the browser is not guessing whether it should
render it, instead it knows I should not render it as HTML because you were telling me it's plain text
and therefore it displays it just as a text node. We can of course now change this to HTML, restart the
server and now reload and we're back to what we had before but now in a cleaner way because now we explicitly
set this response header and tell the browser hey this is HTML content, please render it as such and
all browsers will then do that.
So this is actually how we should send back our HTML code here.