And I can prove this to you of course. If we comment this out again here,
all of that and we comment back in that class here and we now add another class up there, AgedPerson,
I don't know, something like that and in there
I add this printAge method where I just console log this age and now I here extend the AgedPerson
and I change nothing else,
if I now go back to my code or to my page I mean and reload this, well I get an error regarding the
constructor, the base class constructor not being called,
if we added our own constructor, we need to do that as you learned,
so let's add this here in the person class and now you see I get basically the same output as before
and when I output my person prototype here, you indeed see that is my AgedPerson,
the only difference to the output before is that indeed I still have that constructor property.
Now I'll show you why that is the case in a second.
Now what can be confusing here is that here you actually see the greet method though,
so the prototype seems to be AgedPerson but where is our printAge method then?
Well actually if you expand the prototype of the prototype, so the fallback object of the fallback object
of your person so to say, there you will find printAge.
Now the reason for this double prototype structure, which class with extends creates here which clearly
differs from what we get with our constructor function and just person prototype will be explained a
little bit later in this module,
it has to do with how Javascript adds methods to our objects,
it does this a bit differently with classes than it does that with a constructor function here
but again I'll come back to that. For the moment,
we can still keep in mind that in the end extends, when we use classes and we use the extends keyword,
still works with prototypes to make functionality available on all classes that extend the same base
class but other than that,
what happened is that the prototype of our person object was set to this object here so to say,
to an object based on this class here and this also explains why you have to call super. In the end
what this does is it creates an object based on this class and then sets it as a prototype to the object
built based on this class,
that's also what we did manually here,
right?
If I comment this back in and comment this here out again, then what I do here is I create a concrete
object and set it as a prototype for person so that when I create an object based on that, I have it
available and that's the same thing here, in the constructor of the object, of the person object
so to say, I have to create an AgedPerson object first
so that this can be set as a prototype for the to be created object
that's based on person thereafter.
So it's the same, just with of course some syntactic sugar which is easier to understand than this code
down there but this in the end what happens behind the scenes.
Now what's strange here or what can be strange is that if I now reload, this was my old output when I
used the class with extends, we see that now the prototype is back to an object which has proto and print
age but not the constructor method.
Well that happens because what I do here when I assign a new prototype is I replace the old default
object which is assigned as a prototype with a new object.
A better approach therefore typically is to not replace it but instead, reach out to a prototype and dynamically
add a new property or method by adding a dot and then the name of your property
and then here this can of course be a function, so I can now copy that here, add the function keyword and
then add it like this. And the result of that will be that if we now save this and now I reload, you'll
see here I also now have an object which still has this constructor method. By the way in case you're
wondering, this method here refers to this constructor function.
So you could create more objects of that type by saying const p2 equal to p__proto
constructor like that and add the new keyword.
If you do this here, you will get a new person object as you can see if you reload
but of course that's a very complex way of doing that, here
it can be useful in the apps where you somehow don't have access to the constructor function anymore.
Here we do and therefore this instead of just new person of course makes no sense but it can make sense
if you don't have direct access to the original constructor function anymore.
So that's what the constructor method points to,
more importantly, this is how you typically want to edit the prototype so that you don't override the
default one and hence you keep the constructor method
but instead you just add what you want to add.