So as I said, I now want to focus on the more info button. For this, in connect more info button,
we first of all have to get access to the button and we can use similar logic as here in connect switch
button,
copy that line to get the project item element itself with the help of its ID and then get the more info
button here with project item element query selector
and now in there, I want to get to the first button with button first of type because the first button
we have in there is the more info button. Now for the moment,
I don't know how to get any text which I want to display there
and I also don't want to render any element, instead for now I just want to log something to the console
which of course could do with console log but I will use a new class for that, the tooltip class which
then does this logging in its constructor for the moment but we're not there yet.
For now, we need to add an event listener to the button of course, a click event listener,
this should trigger another method here,
show more info handler could be a fitting name, so point at show, at this show more info handler here
on this click listener
and now here I want to create that tooltip.
So I want to in the end build my tooltip here with new tooltip and then let's say call a show method to show
it
and for now again, this will just log something to the console.
So in the tooltip class, we can simply add a show method here and there, console log the tooltip and
for the moment, that will be it.
If I now save that and I reload and I click on more info, we're outputting the tooltip over there on
the right in the console.
Now let's actually finish this up by getting a little bit more fancy than that,
the tooltip is just showing something in the console at the moment,
now why don't we make sure it renders some element, even if it's then in the wrong place but render
some element let's say at the bottom of this page,
something like that.
For that, we can create a new element here in the show method, tooltip element, something like that with
document create element
and here we can just use a div, then assign a class here which I prepared in advance, which can be card
so that it has a nicer look
and then just append it with document body append tooltip element like this.
If we now save that,
give it a try, click on more info, if you scroll to the bottom of the page, you will see some boxes getting
added there.
Pretty hard to see but if you click often enough, there are enough boxes added. Now to see them a bit better,
let's add some text there, text content dummy because for now I have no better text and with that if I
reload, we see that's getting added and now I just want to make sure that we can also dispose of such
a tooltip by clicking on it
and for that we need to add an event listener here,
so tooltip add event listener.
It's not a button but we can also listen to clicks on any other element,
so here to that div we add a click listener and then on the tooltip, we can add a remove method or maybe
name that detach and name this one here attach
so that's a bit more generic but that's up to you
and then here, add event listener click, this.detach and here in detach, we now want to remove that
tooltip element, to have access to it, I'll store it in an instance property. This element is equal to
tooltip element,
so now as long as we make sure that this refers to the correct thing in detach which we can do by using
bind this or as an alternative to also show this, by using this other syntax here for creating a method,
this field methods syntax where you learned in the last section that this then actually is added in
a bit more of an inefficient way because this function is now recreated for every instance of tooltip
but for this app, this should be fine and also to show this alternative.
The advantage of this approach when using an arrow function is that this will always refer to the class
automatically,
so here we can then therefore call this element and refer to the element we're storing down there
with this line here and called remove here or if we need to support older browsers, use this
element, parent element remove child, this.element. This would work in older browsers as well but
I'll go with a shorter modern syntax
and now we should be able to click on a tooltip and get rid of it.
Now since I rename this to attach and I don't name it show anymore, we have to change this here to attach
and now if we go back and reload this one more time, click on more info here for example, scroll to the
bottom,
click on it,
it's getting deleted,
also of course if we added multiple tooltips. So this works and now we can interact with this a bit
at least and we're outputting something.
Now I'm still not fully done though,
I want to improve this code a little bit more, though for this simple app of course you wouldn't need
to do that but for one I want to make sure that if we click on this button, that should show the tooltip,
so when show more info handler, when that function executes, I want to check whether we have an active
tooltip so that I can't open more than one tooltip for a given project and to manage this, I'll add a
new property to project item instances, has active tooltip, which initially is false because initially
there is no active tooltip but here when we executed this code, I'll set this to true, so I'll set has
active tooltip to true
and then here at the beginning, I'll check if this has active tooltip is true and if it is, I will return
so that I don't execute this code in that case and we therefore don't open another new tooltip.
Now I just need to make sure that when we close a tooltip,
so when we detach here,
so when this event listener triggers here, I let my project item class know about that so that I can
set has active tooltip to false again so that we are able to open a new one thereafter. To make sure
that this works, I'll add a new method here, close tooltip and of course we could do this in detach as
well but soon, I want to remove these two from this class and move them into a base class,
that's why I'm creating this in a more generic way.
So here in close tooltip to which I'll now bind this here, close tooltip,
therefore this will now use this trick with the arrow function assigned to the field here,
this detach method can now be converted to a normal method because here I will now want to call this
detach and therefore this inside of detach will now refer to the correct thing because I'm calling
this now in an arrow function but here besides doing that, I also want to call a method which I also receive
here
through the constructor let's say, we could name it close notifier function and then set this close notifier
handler equal to close notifier function or just name it close notifier here because I'm not
binding this to an event so I'm fine with naming it like this and then here in close tooltip besides
detaching it,
I'll call this close notifier as a function and now I just need to make sure that this function is passed
in to the tooltip constructor,
so in project item where I create a tooltip, there I want to pass in a function that sets has active
tooltip to false
and for this we can add a new method or use a quick anonymous function here where I just said this has
active tooltip to false if this executes. So I'll just do this because it's such a simple function.
So with that we shouldn't be able to open the tooltip more than once,
let's give it a try,
let's reload, click on more info, new tooltip was added.
If I click this again for the same element, I don't add more tooltips,
if I click another button for a different element, we can add it,
if I close these tooltips, I can reopen them though. So that seems to work correctly,
yes looks good
and with all of that, the remaining thing which I want to do is I want to add a base class so that we
have detach and attach and a base class and could reuse that for other elements which we want to add
to the DOM or remove from there dynamically as well.