Enough about numbers,
let's have a look at strings.
Now for one, I want to point your attention to something which you already know actually, strings of course
can be created in three different ways -
double quotes, single quotes and back ticks, back ticks create a string with that template
literal notation where you can dynamically inject dynamic values like this
and on any string no matter how it was created, you also get a couple of properties and methods,
for example the length property to find out how many characters the string has but then also many useful
methods, for example to uppercase to transform a string to be all upper case characters,
of course the same exists for to lowercase and various other methods for combining strings, for extracting
substrings, for checking if a string for example starts with a certain sequence, like in this case and
so on.
A great place to learn about all available methods is of course MDN, there if you search for
MDN string you'll find this article and on the left, you find all the methods on this prototype which
is in the end attached to each string you're creating and there, you can find out which methods exist
and what you can do with them and how they are supported in different browsers.
Now this can be really useful to work with strings, to remove excess whitespace for example with the trim
method, to convert it to all uppercase as you just saw or to do many other interesting things with it.
Now that's strings and that's the uninteresting part because the more interesting part is actually what
you can do with template literals, there
we only scratched the surface yet.