So let's have a look behind the scenes now, at how our Javascript code is executed and how all these
things are working together.
So we wrote our Javascript code, something like that, probably a bit more elaborate and complex but we
got the Javascript code as we wrote it all the time.
Now we can split the question at how this is executed into two parts -
one is what does the browser do with that code,
how does that actually result in something being shown on our screen?
And the second part which we'll also have a look at of course in this module is what the browser does
internally with our code, with whatever it did with that, so that it manages the execution flow of our
code, that things are executed in the right order and that our program works the way it should.
These are two different questions as you will see throughout this module and here we'll start with what
the browser does with this piece of code. So we wrote this code, we import it in our HTML file and
therefore the browser reads the HTML file,
that's what browsers do,
detects the script import and then and that's already something you can memorize or keep in mind, whenever
the browser hits a script
imported in HTML or written as an inline script in HTML,
it will execute it. So the browser comes in and executes our script,
now what does execute the script mean? And for that,
please keep in mind that the exact details of course depend on the browser and the engine used.
The Javascript code you write always is the same but what the browser does with that code in detail,
that differs
and if you really want to dive super deep into that, attached you find a couple of links where you can
dive way deeper into the different engines and how they work under the hood, though you absolutely don't
need to go through that to learn and use Javascript,
it's just a bonus if you're interested in that.
So we're talking about the browser executing the Javascript code,
what does this mean?
Well throughout this course, you heard me talk about the browser parsing and executing our code.
Now I'll summarize this in one step, with parsing, I basically mean that the browser reads this Javascript
code, loads it so to say and then execution is the actual process where something happens, where our code
has an effect
and for that part, browsers have a Javascript engine,
every major browser has a Javascript engine,
the engine of Google's browser Chrome for example is named v8, for Firefox it's called Spider
Monkey
and these engines do that parsing and execution and they typically consist of two parts - an interpreter
and a compiler and the compiler typically is a just-in-time compiler
and I'll come back to what that means in a second. Now again, the exact details depend on the browser
you're using but that's generally how that works. For v8,
so for Chrome's browser for example, this is exactly how it works.
So we then parse our script which basically means we load it and we then start execution and that is
done by the interpreter.
The interpreter basically loads our script, reads it,
it then kind of translates it to byte code which is a bit easier to execute you could say and then it
goes ahead and starts running our script
but what's the job of the compiler then?
What is a compiler?
Well the interpreter starts executing our script but it does so line-by-line in an optimized way, which
means the script execution works but is far from being as fast as possible. To have the best possible
performance,
you don't just want to interpret the code and basically execute it like this but instead you want to
compile it to machine code and hand it off to your machine, to your operating system if you will
because that will always be faster and that translation of your interpreted Javascript code to machine
code is exactly what the compiler does.
So the interpreter does not just start executing your script, it also hands off the byte code to the
compiler, so this loaded script in the end, it hands this off to the compiler.
Now the compiler is also built into the browser, so it's part of the Javascript engine the browser
ships with, in case of the v8 engine which works in Google Chrome browser,
the name of the compiler is turbo fan but that's just a side note, doesn't really matter.
So the compiler, whilst the interpreter already started execution of your script, now compiles the script
to machine code.
Now needless to say that for very short scripts, the interpreter might already be done but even then,
this compilation step happens,
so this happens side-by-side with the interpreter executing your script.
Now once this compilation machine code is done, which typically is also relatively fast,
this machine code is handed off to your computer which then may execute it or which then will execute it
and that's then the fast possible way of executing the script.
Now the Javascript engine, the browser, applies a couple of optimization techniques to speed up that execution
and compilation time,
so for example code that didn't change between the last execution and the current execution is not necessarily
recompiled but instead the already compiled code is taken again.
So if an existing script or a part of the script executes again, it's not necessarily recompiled but instead
maybe the already compiled code can be taken which of course is way faster than if you go through that
interpreter, then the compiler and so on process again.
So there are a couple of optimization techniques applied
and again the attached links allow you to dive deeper if that's what you're deeply interested in. Now
it's also important to note that the browser also gives you a couple of features, so-called APIs
which are built in, which you can tap into from your Javascript code.
Things like working with the loaded HTML code or for example, what we'll also cover later in the course,
a couple of other built-in APIs, for example for getting the user's location.
These browser APIs are part of the browser,
for example written in C++ but again that depends on the browser you're using and the browser gives
you communication bridges
if you want to call it like this which you can call from Javascript. So it gives you Javascript functions
or objects which are just available in your Javascript code, which you can simply call in your Javascript
code
and when that code then gets interpreted and compiled, the browser knows where to find these functions
or objects, it knows where to find these APIs and it basically includes that call to that native
API or to that feature which is built in the browser into the interpreted or compiled code and therefore
the finished compiled code which runs on a machine
of course also has access to these browser APIs because that's access or that wish for access, whatever
you want to call it, is basically included in that compiled machine code.
That's the big picture of how this works and how the browser handles your Javascript code.
I can't emphasize enough that of course the exact steps or the exact names differ based on which browser
you use and therefore definitely check out yet the attached material if you want to dive super deeply into
that.
This is the big picture though which I find important to know if you're working with Javascript, it never
hurts to have a rough idea of what's happening there
but in my opinion it's also enough to know this.
Now again that's just a big picture of how the browser handles your code though, it does not really answer
the question what the browser does when your code executes,
so for example how are your variables stored,
how does function execution work,
how is the order guaranteed and so on. That's therefore the next step
we'll have a look at.