Speaking of scrolling, we can not just find out by how far the user scrolled on the entire page or inside
of a box but we can also actively scroll the user somewhere and a good example would be when I add buy
groceries to finish projects. It gets added there
but of course it gets added at the bottom and therefore I can only see a part of it.
Now maybe we want to scroll in this box where we add an element to, to make that element visible and
we can do that,
you can actively control scrolling through Javascript.
Now let me show you how it works here in the developer tools.
Let's select this section here and in there, to be precise,
let's select the unordered list.
If we now expand the styles, you see that there I kept the height and I make sure that we can scroll
to see the content which doesn't fit in the unordered list, so that unordered list is scrollable.
Now with it selected, let's go to the console and use $0 again to interact with that unordered
list
and now there, you got a couple of methods you can call, for example scrollTo. scrollTo takes two coordinates -
x and y, where you can define how much you want to scroll to the left or right and how much you want
to scroll to the top or bottom.
Now here we can't scroll left to right so there's nothing we can set there,
if you set this to 100 on x for example, it wouldn't have any effect but we can scroll on the
y-axis.
Now if I set zero here, then I tell Javascript that I don't want to scroll at all,
not that helpful. If I set it to 50 however, then this might be better because now I tell Javascript
that I want to scroll down to 50 pixels. If I hit enter now, you see indeed this changed right, it scrolled
there.
Let me show this again,
let's repeat that same command, boom,
it scrolled. If you set it to a very high value,
well then it just goes as far down as possible.
Now you can also not just scroll to absolute values,
you can also
scroll relatively with scrollBy. With scrollBy I tell Javascript by how many pixels I want to scroll
down.
So if I enter 50 here,
I'll have the same effect as before actually
but you'll see a difference
now if I am at 50 and I repeat this command, now I scroll down 50 pixels more.
If we would do the same with scrollTo, scroll to 50 here, you will see I scroll to 50 pixels and if
I repeat that and I am at that position, nothing changes.
So you can control whether you want to scroll to a specific position or by some amount of pixels and
combined with the fact that you can get the coordinates of any element on the screen, you could of course
then also use this to tell Javascript to scroll to a specific element by getting the coordinates of
that element and then scrolling to it. If you want to make a specific element visible with scrolling
though, there is an even easier way.
You can also go to that element, for example the project item which we added here with the help of this
add project method in the project list class and make sure that this element, when we move it, gets scrolled
into view and to make sure that this happens, we can go to this place where I move the element here and
then on that element which you want to bring into view, there you can call scroll into view as a method
and this will do just what the names suggests.
So if you now save that then reload, you will see that if I add buy groceries to this finished projects
box, it gets scrolled into view automatically and of course the same if I add something to active projects.
So this can be useful to make sure that it scrolls into view.
Now of course what you might notice is that scrolling here always means jumping, it immediately is
there, we have no animation. Well you can
in some browsers at least, Chrome and Firefox support it, you can set up how scrolling should be performed.
By passing in an object
here to scroll into view where you can set the behavior to smooth, the default is auto which just jumps
there but with smooth, you'll get a tiny animation.
So if you set this to smooth here for example and you reload and then you add groceries here to finish
projects, watch the bottom box, you'll see it scrolled there with a nice animation and that might be nicer
than just jumping there.
Again, it's not supported in all browsers, specifically Internet Explorer and Safari
don't support this feature but you can still add it to your code and on these browsers, it will just
not have any effect, on the browsers that do support it though, you get this enhanced behavior.
You also have this configuration available by the way
if we select the unordered list again on scrollTo and scrollBy, there you can pass in the coordinate
pair or alternatively pass in an object where you set top and left, top
by how much you want to scroll from the top and left how much you want to scroll from the left, so I'll
ignore left here because I don't want a scroll from the left but I'll set top to 50 and then here you
can also add the behavior and set this to smooth
and now here you'll also get that animation,
same is available for scrollBy as I mentioned, like this.
So this is how you can scroll and how you can control scrolling from inside Javascript, a feature which
of course also can be helpful to make sure users see the content you want them to see.