Now the last thing we saw on the previous definition slide is that Javascript runs on a host environment,
so that means a Javascript engine can be part or can be executed in different environments.
The most well known environment is the browser,
modern browsers have Javascript engines built in and they're therefore capable of executing Javascript
code but you also can run Javascript in other environments,
for example on the server side, so right on a computer without having a browser in between, so not inside
of a browser but simply execute code like this on your machine.
Now Javascript was invented to run in the browser, to make web sites more dynamic, to be able to change
things on a web site without loading a new page you could say because Javascript is able to closely
work together with the loaded HTML code, with CSS,
you can also use Javascript to send background HTTP requests, so to send some behind the scenes requests
and fetch data without reloading the page and much more and it will do all of that throughout the course.
Now there also are certain things Javascript can't do when it runs in the browser environment though,
for example it can't access your local file system for security reasons because otherwise every web
page you visit would be able to read your file system, maybe delete files on your computer and so on which
would be horrible of course
and in general it is running in a sandbox
you can say, it's not able to interact with your operating system and so on, the browser gives you certain
things you can do in this environment and doesn't allow other things.
Now as I said, the browser is only one environment though, the one for which Javascript was invented
but not the only one we're restricted to right now,
instead the Javascript engine Google developed, v8 is the name of the engine, was extracted by some people
to run Javascript anywhere because the idea was if we have the engine in the browser, why don't
we take it out of the browser and then make it available as a standalone tool which you can use to execute
Javascript anywhere else directly on your machine
and this tool is in the end called Node.js.
Now in this course, I'll have a separate module about Node.js where I show you how that works and
how it uses the same Javascript syntax you learned throughout the course but which new features it
brings to the table. For the majority of course however, we'll focus on the browser side because this is
the side where you absolutely need Javascript
and it's also the site where you're able to see more because you have a web page where things change
and so on.
Now back to Node.js though for a second, Node.js can be executed on any machine and therefore it's
also often used to build web back-ends, to build web servers, server side
Javascript is also something you often hear as a description for that.
Now you might know about server side languages like PHP or also Java and other languages as well,
well Javascript with Node.js can also be used to run it on the back-end of a web page,
so on the server and not on the client in the browser of your users. Now Node.js also has certain things
it can do and can't do, since it runs directly on a machine, in Node.js
you're able to access the local file system, so you are able to write files and so on because unlike browser
side Javascript, Node.js code has to be executed actively by you,
it's not like you visit a web page and then this starts happening,
instead it can only access the file system on the machine where it executes
which for example is the server where it runs, not your machine and it's also able to interact with the
operating system and so on.
However on the other hand since it doesn't have direct access to the loaded web page, it can't manipulate
HTML or CSS like browser side.
Javascript is able to do, so we basically have even inverse access capabilities here and these are the
different environments where Javascript is able to run.
Now in this course, we'll focus on the browser side because the Javascript syntax you learned will be the
same, no matter in which environment you run Javascript code
but in the browser, we simply have more visual feedback and can see what happens.
Nonetheless as I said, we have the separate Node.js module later in the course
where I'll also dive into the different things we can do in Node.js and how that works.