Now sending back data is one thing,
typically you also want to be able to receive data.
Now for that we need to send back different HTML code,
we need to send back HTML code which includes something that allows the user to send us a request.
Now with that I'm not talking about a script where we used the fetch API, we could do that but would be
a lot of code we have to write here,
we can instead start simple and sent back a form.
You might remember that a form had this default behavior that when a button was pressed, we actually
had the browser default of a request being sent to the server that served the page and we had to prevent
this with Javascript.
Now here, I don't want to prevent it,
I want to have this default behavior so that the request is sent to the server because that's simply
another way of building web applications. Instead of having client side Javascript do more of the work,
we could take the more traditional approach with less client side Javascript because we maybe don't
need it here, we don't want to validate the user input here on the client side and instead we let the
browser do its default thing and send the request to the server so that on the server we then validate
the input and so on, both is possible and of course both can also be connected as you will see later. So
here we could render a simple form with an input of type text, like this and with a button in there
and make sure you get these opening and closing tags right. Now in this button here, we could have a send
text and the type of the button, and that's important, should be of type submit.
So now here I have a form element,
then we have an input element,
then we have a button and then we have the closing form tag of course. If we save that and we reload,
now you see that here.
Now if we enter something here and we hit send, you see the page reloads right, you'll see that here in
the network tab, tis flickers because the page reloads and you briefly see a second request,
that's the outgoing request before the page reloads.
Now the outgoing request by default is a get request, on form we can set a method attribute and set
this to post to send a post request instead
and we can set an action attribute and point at slash
nothing to tell the browser to which URL to send this HttpRequest and then to encode the data of
the form properly, we should add a name attribute to the input and for example give this the user name
identifier,
this is totally up to you though. With that the browser is able to parse that form,
have a look at all inputs that have a name and basically create a data object behind the scenes where
it stores the data entered here under a user name key and then sends a post request with that data object
to this URL, that's what the browser now does and that's a default browser behavior, has nothing
to do with Node.js, has nothing to do with Javascript in general. We could just prevent this with client
side Javascript where we listen to the form submission and prevent the default but I don't want to do
that here, I want to use that default behavior instead.
So now we'll send this request to the server, if I now reload here and I enter something here and I hit
send,
well we get the same behavior as before but actually we will get a request here,
we just have to parse it now
and for that here, let's work with that request object which we haven't used thus far.
Parsing the body of an incoming requests can be a bit tricky or strange at first but we'll later learn
how we can do it in an easier way.
We first of all start by creating a variable, body and that should be an array actually because the body
is received as chunks of data for efficiency reasons and we have to basically store all these chunks
and then convert them to text thereafter.
So here we get our chunks of data,
now we need to extract the data from the request body actually. Now before we do that, let's see what's in
the request.
We could log the entire request object but this will be a huge object,
so instead I want to start by logging the method which is one property we can read and the URL and
then we at least see which requests reach this listener here, for which methods and which URLs.
If we now save that and we restart this and we reload here without sending that, we already see some
output here, get and /?, the question mark was added earlier to my URL when I hit
send here before configuring the form,
if I remove that and hit enter here, we see just get/. So we see by default when we visit the page,
the browser sends a get request to ourdomain.com/,
that's what we get here.
The rest of URL simply is omitted here, on the URL property
we just get the path on our server here.
Now if I entered something here however, for example Anna and I hit send, you see now we also got a post request
to slash nothing which makes sense because that is what we configured here in the end.
So this is now some data we can get there but of course we want to get the body and to parse that, we
need to add a listener on request which we do with the on method, not with add event listener but with
on, there is an add listener method but that's not the right one here, we just want on.
Now that's a difference to the browser because we're not working with a browser side API here and of
course generally, every API can implement this the way it wants.
Node.js typically works with on or with once if we only want to listen once instead of with add event
listener
but that's just something we have to get used to.
So with on, we set up a listener here and I want to set up a listener
first of all to the data event here.
This is one event Node.js knows, just as the browser knows click on a button for example, Node.js knows
the data event on the request and here we need to provide a second argument which is a function that
should execute when this event occurs. There, we will get our chunk of data, will be passed in by Node.js
and we can then add this to our array by pushing it into it. It's a normal Javascript array with the
normal Javascript methods. By the way, on Node.js, you also have all these special methods like filter,
map and so on you learned about in the arrays module,
this is supported in Node.js as well.
So now on every data piece we read in, so every data piece that's coming in on the request, we add it
to this body array.
Now we're interested in the point of time when we're done receiving data and for that we can add another
listener to the end event.
This will be fired when we're done reading in the request, so when it has been fully parsed, there we
also have a function that should execute in this case
and now we know the body array will be fully occupied now with our chunks of data,
we will have all the chunks of data we got in this array.
Now we just need to convert this body from an array of data chunks into some string data we can work
with and for that, we can set b ody equal to buffer which is a global object available in Node.js,
.concat body, so body before we stored it here is an array of chunks, to string.
This is the end just one way of converting this array of encoded chunks into a normal string and store
that back in the body variable here,
this is also why I use the variable here and not a constant.
And once this is done, we know what's inside of the body,
so let's console log body here then and see what is inside there.
So if we now quit that server again and restart it and we reload here and send Anna to the server, we
now see this is what was extracted,
user name equals Anna. Well now we could parse this to do with it whatever we want, since it's such a string
we could for example get a user name by using body, split it on the equal sign and then take the second
element of the resulting array which is the concrete user name, so the thing after the equal sign and
then work with it.
So now we could send back a response and now it's important to send it back in the right place,
currently what we're actually doing is we're sending back the response before we finished parsing the
incoming request because this here is asynchronous code,
This listener here triggers multiple times potentially, this listener also triggers at some point of
time in the future when we're done parsing this in.
So these functions here which we registered on these listeners don't execute right when this line executes,
they execute when this event happens and that's the same as in the browser,
the function you register on a click event only fires and runs when the click happens, not when Javascript
parses the add event listener line.
So therefore right now what actually happens is this line and this line is executed and then these lines
are executed and only thereafter sometime in the future, these functions will execute.
Of course I only want to send back the response once I'm done parsing the data, so we should move this
code actually in here, into this request on end listener
so that we don't send a response before we're done parsing this.
So now if we save that and we reload this, we'll see no difference
but this is technically cleaner and it is not just cleaner but absolutely required if we want to take
that user name into account in the response you sent back.
For example if I add a h1 tag here where I want to say hi user name, then we should convert it to a template
literal with back ticks so that I can conveniently inject data here and then we can say hi user name
here.
Now of course to make sure that this also works before we submitted our form here, I will actually
change user name to let here , cut this code and set this to a default of unknown user and then check
if body is a thing, so if this is truthy and set user name equal to our split body or only if that's
the case so that we have a fallback user name here in case we haven't set one yet
and if we save that and restart our server, you need to hit enter here, just reloading will not
work, you need to hit enter here in the URL to send a new get request
otherwise you just reload these parsed post request.
So let's hit enter here and you should see hi
unknown user but as soon as you enter something here and click send, this will reload and show your data
here.
So this is then how you can parse incoming data and how you can send back a response
but obviously this is quite cumbersome which is why we also have an easier or a better solution for that
and which is why we have a framework for Node.js,
just as we have frameworks and libraries for client side Javascript code as well.