So now with splice, we already entered the world of special methods
we can use on arrays.
Now there are many methods we can use on arrays and for that,
I'll also comment out this code block and I always just do that so that console here doesn't get
too crowded and we can always focus on the most recent code we're writing and I'll add a brand new array
here. I'll name it test result but the name is totally up to you and in there, I'll have a couple of numbers,
integers and floating point numbers,
so numbers without decimal places and with decimal places, also some negative numbers,
yes something like that, really doesn't matter, just a bunch of numbers.
Now we saw splice which is a really versatile method for adding and removing and inserting and even
swapping if you use it correctly elements.
Now another method you but you can use which has a similar name but does something totally different
is slice,
so not splice but slice.
You can use slice like that and that should be test results of course
and if you save that and then reload this page, you see basically an array as I entered it.
The interesting thing slice does here though is it returns a brand new array and therefore this actually
is also a nice way of copying an array, you remember? Arrays are in the end objects and therefore reference
values.
So if you compare an array to an array that looks totally equal to us humans, it will return false if
it's not exactly the same object.
Also if we store an array, store the results in another variable, so if I store test results in the stored
results constant here, then you of course see that if you output the stored results here and the test
results, these will be equal
even if you then added the test results and you push a new value in there.
So if you add this value here to test results, you'll see that stored results are also affected if I
reload.
So you see, this new value 5.91 is part of both arrays.
That happens because arrays are reference values and they affirm what we store here is just a pointer
at this place in memory, just the address of the array.
So if we then change the array, well that still points at the same address
so it
points at the same changed array.
That's something where slice can help us because it returns a brand new array based on the old array.
So if I call slice here and I store the result of that slice call in stored results, I store a copy
of that array in stored results,
so a brand new array is created and stored in memory based on that
old array, it has a brand new address which is in the end stored here and therefore
now if we added test results here, this will not affect stored results because that stores its own
brand new copy.
So here if we save that and reload, in test results we see 5.91, in stored results which is this first
array,
we don't see it, there we don't have that sixth value. So that's one use case of slice for copying arrays
but actually slice is also really nice for selecting ranges of an array. You can select a single element
of an array with the index based access here, 0, 1, 2 and so on
but what if you want to select two elements at the same time?
So you want to select a part of your array, not the entire array but a part. Well slice helps you with
that, you can use it like this and it will give you the full array but you can also specify a start and
an end number and these are indexes of the array,
start is included and is not. So if I specify 0, 2 here, I tell slice to give me a new array which is
based on the existing array, starts add the first element, index 0 and then goes all the way up to the
element with index 2 which is the third element here but does not include that. So slice here with this
configuration should give us this part of the array, 1 and 5.3.
Well let's have a look at that.
If I now reload this, indeed we have 1 and 5.3 in that first array which is my stored results
array. So slice can be used for selecting ranges,
of course you can start at any index but of course the index where you end should then typically be
higher than that index, though even if that's not the case, you'll see that it works but it's now just
an empty array because there is nothing between the element with index three and the element with
the index two, it doesn't select in the reverse direction. Though what you can use are negative indexes
but then both have to be negative. So you can start at the third last element,
this has negative index 1 because there is no negative 0,
so in the negative indexes the first element from the end has index 1, negative index 2, negative index
3 and then going up to 2, you might think you select this part but this is actually not supported,
this is not how it works but you can for example go to -1 and this will then select from the third
last element all the way up to the last element
so these two should be selected.
Now if we save that and we reload, indeed that's what we get here,
these two elements were selected. You can also just specify a single index here, negative or not, doesn't
matter and not specify a second argument and this will then start at this index,
so in this case at the element with index 2 which is of course this element and then select everything
up from this element all the way to the end,
so this would select this here for example, this configuration would select this. Hence if I save that
and I reload,
exactly
that's what we get,
starting at 1.5 all the way up to 10 which is the end here.