For some features, you can't use feature detection,
you can't use fallback codes you can't use polyfills and you can't ignore them,
typically that's the case for core Javascript syntax features like let, const, async await, arrow functions,
all of that. These are features you as a developer might want to use because they allow you to write
cleaner code, work around certain issues you have with older Javascript code and so on,
so you want to use this modern code but you also need to support browsers that might not support these
Javascript syntax features.
Let's take let or const as an example here, if we search for it on caniuse, we see const has decent
browser support, even Internet Explorer partially supports it but older versions of Internet Explorer
don't for example and that might be an issue if you need to target these top 0.3% of users.
If you search for arrow functions here, you see there it's even a bit worse,
Internet Explorer for example doesn't support this at all,
not even in version
11.
Now what do you do if you still want to write modern code with all these features and you still want
to support
let's say Internet Explorer in this example
or these older FIrefox or Chrome versions,
what can you do in that case?
You can't use a polyfill because it's a core language feature
and if the let keyword is not recognized there is no way of making it work, unlike promises and fetch,
these are not functions you call after all,
instead const really is just a keyword that tells the engine what the code after it is all about, that
it creates a variable that does not change and in the example of const for example and therefore this
is a functionality that can't be rebuilt with other tools,
it's just missing the const keyword, it's not recognized and therefore browsers that don't know it, that
use a Javascript engine that doesn't know it
I should say will just crash when they detect this keyword.
Now to still make that code work or to still ship, so deploy code that does work,
you can use transpilation.
The idea behind transpilation is that you transpile, transform your code, your modern code into older
code and this of course is not done manually because if it would be done manually, you could just write
older code right from the start,
instead you have tools for that, most prominently Babel is a tool that does that for you,
it can even be integrated into your webpack workflow so that that all happens in one step.
This allows you to write modern code, use cutting Edge Javascript language features and still ship, so
deploy, cross browser code that for example still uses var instead of const and let or that uses normal
functions instead of arrow functions.
So how would that look like?
Well for that, we need to quit our development server and now install that transpiler,
you do that with npm install --save-dev and now let's see which transpiler we need.
For that, you can just google for Babel and you should find babeljs.io,
now actually let's search for Babel loader, this is the webpack integration and go to that GitHub repository
we find there, on babeljs.io however, you can learn more about the Babel project and all its
rich configuration options and so on,
so definitely also check this out. Now here on Babel loader, you learned how you can install it and
you will actually need to install Babel loader, @babel/core, @babel/preset-env, and webpack
we don't need that, we already got this in our project setup but we need the other three packages, so
you can just copy that and add this here after --save-dev, by the way --save-dev
is just a longer form of just -d here.
So now hit enter and this will now install these three packages into your project and we can then tweak
the webpack configuration to use them. In the end what we got here is Babel loader, which is the integration
into webpack which basically does the connection of webpack and the Babel tool,
we got Babel core which is that Babel tool,
so the tool that actually knows how to translate modern code to older code and Babel preset env is a
preset that controls which features are compiled in which way,
so actually this is the package with the concrete translation rules
you could say. So now we have these three packages,
now how can we use them?
Well just as explained here, you have to add this entry here to your webpack configuration, so let's copy
that actually and then go to webpack.config.js and there let's say above the plugins, though
the exact position does not matter,
you paste this in and add a comma after it.
This adds a module entry which basically gives instructions to webpack how to transform your different
modules and a module in webpack world is just a file,
so it basically tells webpage what to do with the files
it's managing, then you can add a rules entry here and that takes multiple rules because you can control
different kinds of files with different so-called loaders.
A rule is a Javascript object where you have a test property, there
you define how the file you want to translate should be identified.
This is a regular expression, you learned about these briefly in the strings and numbers section of this
course
and here we're basically saying any file ending with .js or mjs, so with an extension of js or
mjs, should be treated or should be handled by this rule, other files ending with a different extension
of which we have none
but if we had them would be ignored. Now we also want to exclude any files that are in those
modules or power components which is another package manager which we don't have here,
so we can actually remove that, will be ignored so that we don't start transpiling code which is part
of third-party packages,
these should be ready to use out of the box and then we have the concrete action that should be taken
with the use key here.
It's again an object where we configure the loader that should be applied, so that Babel loader should
take care about such Javascript files and that as an option, it should use that preset-env ruleset.
This is now what we're doing here and we also should do that by copying that in the webpack config
profile.
Arguably there it's even more important because this is the code we ultimately want to ship to our users.
So here under testing, we might test this in modern browsers anyways, though you should still compile it
there so that you have the same experience as the users who use your actual code
but it's the users who get your production ready code that actually needs that code that works in older
browsers as well.
So now that's a first step,
now we're not entirely done though,
we need to configure which browsers we want to support because that's the cool thing about
@babel/preset-env,
I said it's a set of rules that controls which features are translated to which older code, for example
that let and const are translated to var.
Now of course the exact translation you want depends on which browsers you're targeting,
this is where we come back to our market analysis because keep in mind if you revisit this compat table
that the different features modern Javascript offers have different browser support,
for example const and let have quite decent browser support
so we might not even need to compile them if all we want to target is Internet Explorer 11 and higher
and these partial features which are missing are not a problem to us. On the other hand, there might be
other features which are also important to us which are not supported in the browser
we want to target and therefore they should be compiled.
So we want to tell Babel and this preset-env package for which browser is the compilation should
be fine tuned and thankfully, Babel works exactly like that,
it wants this information and then it really gives you code that is fine tuned to the browsers you want
to support.
Now how do we pass that information to Babel
however? We can do that with the package.json,
there simply add a new entry, let's say here which you name browser list, like this. The value it holds
is also a string with double quotes and now in here, you can specify a browser list configuration string,
browser list is a separate package and tool that is used under the hood by @babel/preset-env and attached,
you find a detailed description of which options you can set there.
You can do stuff like set > 2% which means you want to output code that works in browsers
that have a market share of greater than 2% and of course every time you build, this is checked
and this under the hood taps into a source which is always kept up-to-date so that you build code that
works in browsers with greater than 2% market share.
Now with that, that should be browsers list by the way with an s after browser,
now with that we can run npm run build prod or just build to get the unoptimized output
and now in scripts here we see an app.js file with our code and yet now the interesting thing is of
course this is the webpack world
so it has all this webpack extra code but what we can see if we scroll down a bit is for example here,
we see const button equals document query selector.
This is our code and webpack then does some stuff with it
but this is our code and you'll see for example const was kept here.
Now if I change this to let's say we want to support browsers with a market share greater than 0.2 which
of course includes way older and smaller browsers and I now rebuild this, let's check the output again.
If we now go down there, we see we get a var in there.
So now our code really was translated to code that would work in older browsers as well
and this all happens magically with the help of webpack Babel loader and the browsers list and again,
attached you find the link to the documentation of which options you can set there because you can not
just target market shares, you can also be specific about different browser versions, so you could say
Chrome version 58,
Internet Explorer version 11 or higher and so on, so you can also set stuff like that.
You can also combine multiple queries or multiple instructions, for example you can add not dead here,
this means only browsers that still have official support,
for example Internet Explorer 10 at the point of time recording this would be considered dead because
it's not receiving any official support anymore,
Internet Explorer 11 is at least receiving some support still.
So these are some things you can set up there and this will influence how your code is transpiled and
how you can make your modern code which does use constant arrow functions also work in older browsers
because const and let is translated to var and an arrow function for example is translated into a normal
function.
Now one problem we still might have in this example here for example is that we still use then, so we
still use promises and now we have code that works in older browsers from a Javascript syntax perspective
but it still might not really work there because whilst we transpiled core syntax features like
let and const, other features like promises might still not be working in these older browsers. So we might
want to combine this approach with a polyfill and as it turns out, this is also rather simple.