Now it is important to understand that the prototype chain does not end after reaching out to that prototype
of that person object.
If we try to call a method like printAge which is not part of the person object itself because we
don't set it up in the constructor function and we didn't add it to the person thereafter either,
well then we go back to the fallback object which is the prototype, right?
So it's this prototype here which indeed has the printAge method.
If we called something else, for example if I tried to console log p.toString, the question is will
this now still work.
It worked earlier because we could fall back to an object, a base object which had the toString method,
the question is, is that still the case now
that we kind of edited
the prototype here?
Well let's see.
Let's save it and reload
and yes it still works,
we get no error. Now it still works because the prototype chain doesn't end at this default prototype.
If we have a look at our prototype, it's this function or this object excuse me which has the printAge
method and the constructor method but which itself also has a prototype.
As I mentioned, every object has a prototype, not just the object we build based on a constructor function
but also the fallback object of our object,
so the prototype of our object. That prototype, that fallback object has its own fallback object, its own
prototype and we can reach out to it with the special __proto__
property here.
If we expand it here, we see an object which has that toString method, the question just is where is this
object coming from? This in the end is the base object
you always have access to. The default prototype every object gets, thanks to it being assigned as a default
to be assigned prototype on every constructor function can be found on the global object class or to
be precise, object constructor function.
If I console log object like this, this is globally available in Javascript,
this is a constructor function that's built into Javascript so to say. If I console log that, maybe at
the bottom and get rid of that p2 log,
if I console log that, you'll see that this is in the end
something like that.
Let's try console dir here if we can look into it, well yes we can
but in there you'll find a bunch of interesting things but toString is not part of it,
instead this has its own prototype but again, no toString in there. In its prototype,
we find toString somewhere though
but that's actually not the reason why we have access to toString here on our person, instead object
here is a constructor function with a bunch of built-in properties or methods you can call. In the class
based world,
we would call these properties and methods which you can call without instantiating an object based
on that constructor function static properties and static methods. So everything you see here in the
end are just static methods and static properties of that object constructor function
and indeed when you go to your class and you add a static property,
this simply means that a property is added directly here to your constructor function object, so it is
as if you go to person which is a function but which therefore also is an object and you add describe
to it and say that this is a function where you want to describe what this function does for example,
creating persons.
Now this is a property of the person object,
it's not a property that will be added to objects created based on the constructor function.
There we only add what's inside the constructor function,
this does not tweak the function body or anything like that,
instead it interacts with that function object which is created
and even though it's not that common, of course you can add properties and methods to that object as
well.
Again, this has no impact on what executes the function body,
it's just something you can interact with on the function object itself.
So if I add describe like this,
indeed if we build a new person and we console log the entire person object down there, like that, you
will see that if I reload here, our person has no describe method.
My function which I log up there however has a describe method,
so it's really added on the function object itself and object here, this globally available constructor
function, has a bunch of such predefined static methods and properties
but the important thing is that object itself is not the fallback object, the fallback prototype
all other objects can come back to in the end. If it would be, then we should be able to for example call
length and get a value of one on any object of our choice,
so I should be able to reach out to p.length and print a length of exactly one because a length
property does not exist on person, so it should go to its fallback value,
this prototype,
there it also won't exist and therefore it should go to the fallback value of this object
and if that were object, so this global object here, then this should print one but as you will see instead
if I reload here, it prints undefined because as I mentioned, this global object constructor function
is not the fallback object of everything, instead
and that can be confusing at first,
the fallback value of all objects is object.prototype, again because of this property naming it can
be confusing but keep in mind that this prototype property exists on everything which is a constructor
function and object is just such a constructor function in the end. It defines what will be assigned
as a prototype to any object that is created based on this constructor function.
Therefore, any object created based on person receives the default prototype with the printAge function
added. Every object created based on this object constructor function,
this built-in object constructor function receives its default prototype and it's this default prototype
if we have a look at it that indeed has the toString method and a couple of other methods.
So this is just configuring which default fallback is assigned to objects that are created based on
the object constructor and there it's just important to know that this fallback object here for the
person constructor function,
this default prototype you get here or any object you create on your own with the object literal notation
for example by default always uses this global object constructor. So any object created with the object
literal notation or the object created by Javascript automatically is a default prototype here will
be based on this object constructor function and will therefore use this prototype as its fallback value,
so every object by default uses this as its fallback value including the default prototype object you
get for your own constructor functions,
this is how that is connected.
Now in case you're wondering, this prototype itself then has no other prototype, you will not find any
__proto method here,
just a getter and a setter
but this won't do anything,
it will basically just capture any interactions because if you try to get the prototype of that base
prototype of everything, you will see that if I now reload this, it just prints null.
So that's where the prototype chain ends, it ends at object.prototype.