Now to add an item, we in the end need to repeat this process here.
So I'll copy that code here,
move it into my event listener,
the database in the object stores will be initialized when this code is executed and therefore
now here, I again establish a connection to the product object store and I add a new product,
so here a second product for let's say a higher price with the same tax.
That should almost work,
one problem we'll have is the database.
This is a variable we define here in this function,
so it's scoped to this function, to make it available outside of there, we can define the globally
let db and then just assign a value here to it so that this is available in the whole script
and therefore now here, we can access it as well,
we could check if db is set or if it's not set, so that you don't try to work with it if it doesn't
exist yet,
this is an extra check we could add here. And with that if we save that and reload and you click store,
you'll see nothing changes. Now
our problem here is that we set db in
onUpgradeNeeded,
this however doesn't always run. If we have a database where the version number did not change, this will
not rerun, this essentially just runs
if the version changes, onUpgradeNeeded will run whenever the database is created for the first time
or when the version number changes thereafter.
Now of course we could just change the version number here and this function would run again but then
we would try to recreate this object store which already exists,
so you should not use this version number to kind of try to make your other code work,
you should use it if you really change the internal structure of the database, so that's not what we
want to do here.
Instead what we need to do here is copy that code and add an onSuccess handler here
which will run whenever this is opened or created and then get rid of all the non-database assigning
code here so that all we do is this,
now we got some code here which will run whenever the script reruns, whenever the database connection
is opened and will give us access to the database,
so then the database variable will be set and we're able to work with it.
So now if we save that, go to the application tab here, reload and click store,
you might need to click that refresh button but then you'll see your new data here.
Now that's how you can store data, for retrieving
we can go to the retrieve button function here and there you need access to the object store, so we
can reuse this code
and of course you could also put this in some helper function therefore and on that store object here,
you can now call a get function and enter the key name of the item you want to retrieve, for example
p2.
Now this will not give you the item like this, instead it gives you a request object where you again
can add an onError and onSuccess handler,
this is just how this API works.
Now here in this function, we also don't get the item as an argument unfortunately, it is what it is,
instead we can now get the retrieved item on the request object which was returned by get here and there,
we'll have a result property which should be the item that was retrieved.
So with that if we save this, reload, go to the console and click retrieve,
indeed I did retrieve the item with key p2. So some aspects which can be confusing for sure,
it is the API IndexedDB offers, though because it's a bit clunky with all these handler assignments
here,
there actually are third-party libraries,
most importantly idb.js which is linked on this lecture
so you'll find a link attached that make working with IndexedDB much easier,
that promisify all these features and so on. So a link to that is attached,
in addition you also attached find a link to an MDN document which dives way deeper into this base API
and explores what else you can do there besides this basic storage and retrieval.