So we wrote to our first line of code and we're setting a variable here and this variable of course
doesn't do anything yet.
Now let's do something simple,
let's for the moment not care about what the user enters here but let's make sure that we actually right
away have a simple mathematical operation where we output the result down here in the result part of
this screen and therefore, I want to set current result to a new value and that new value will later
be the user input
but since we don't really fetch this yet, I'll use a dummy value here, let's say 10
but you can use any number you want and add this to the current result, so let's say current result plus
10 and then store this value back in current result.
So here a couple of things are happening,
I am again referring to the current result variable here on the left side of the equal sign and on the
right side
and if we start on the right side, I'm using the current value stored in current result and I'm adding
a value to it, in this case 10,
I'm adding by using this plus operator.
Now operators are something we haven't heard about yet,
what are operators? Operators are syntax features or a syntax feature in Javascript that allows us to
manipulate values
you could say and there are the typical mathematical operators you're used to - plus, minus,
then the asterisk operator, the asterisk character here to multiply two numbers and the slash to divide
two numbers.
There also is a modulus operator, the percentage sign which divides two numbers but doesn't return the
result of the division
but the remainder,
so the part that remains if clean division without a decimal value as a result isn't possible and there
also is the exponentiation operator which allows you to use exponentiation on a number.
Now these are the mathematical operators which you typically also know from math,
there also are other operators in Javascript, like the assignment operator which we already use to assign
a value to a variable, the equal sign. So here in this line of code, we're using two operators, the plus
operator to combine two numbers
and now this combination, this operator yields the result of this mathematical operation and we then
assign this result we're getting here with the equal sign to the value on the left or to the variable
on the left.
So here, current result gets overwritten with the result of this operation
and now we use current result on both sides of the equal sign
but the right side will execute first,
that's something you can just keep in mind
and therefore
we'll use the old result 0 here, add 10 and therefore we now have 10 as a total result
and then we overwrite current result with it.
So we only overwrite it after we're done with this calculation, so that we don't try to overwrite it with
a value we depend on or anything like that.
So now current result, after this line was executed, will store of value of 10. Now to output this, we can
use one of the things I'm providing here in vendor and we'll learn what exactly that is in just a second,
for now we'll use this output result thing by simply writing output result here and then adding parentheses,
opening and closing and in there, you can pass in current result, just like this, also add a comma and
thereafter two single quotes with nothing in between.
Again, I'll come back to what this is and what this does
in just a second. If you do that and you now reload your page, you should now see result 10 down there and
that's just a result of our code which executed here.
We're calculating this result, storing it here
and then what this thing here which we're getting from the vendor file,
well what this does is actually it just takes whatever we pass in here and outputs this in this part
of the HTML page and throughout the course, it will become clearer how this works, for the moment you can just
take it for granted. So we had a first basic look at a variable, at an operation and then at this thing
here which we don't really understand,
let me come back to that operation. Here
we use two operators but as I mentioned, there are a couple of operators available, actually more than
the ones I just showed
but even with those which I did show, all these basic mathematical operators, you can do a bunch of things
and you're not limited to two operators per line or to one,
you can also add the asterisk here, the multiplication operator and multiply this by three and Javascript
by default follows normal mathematical rules where it will now first execute 10 times 3 and then
add this to current result.
You could change that order however by adding parentheses, just like you do it in math. If I add parentheses
around that,
now Javascript will first add ten to current result and then multiply the result of this with three
and of course we can then also divide this by two and subtract one or whatever you want,
you can have any mathematical equation here, any mathematical operation here as long as it should be
where you can use parentheses to group the different mathematical calculations together if you need
to do that.
So now if I would run this for example, I got a result of 14 because we have 0 plus 10 times 3 divided
by 2 is 15 minus 1 is 14,
so that makes sense. Now with that out of the way, let's think a bit more about the that values we're
actually working with. I added a number here but numbers are not the only values you can use in Javascript
and actually in all other modern programming languages.