So by now we actually had a look at a lot of different operators which we need in different situations
in our code - arithmetic operators for calculations with numbers or in the case of the plus operator,
also with strings and also the assignment operator and these shorthands for incrementing or decrementing
numbers or for quickly assigning the result of a calculation with the plus or minus and so on operator.
So these are things we had to look at
and in addition, we also had a look at these boolean or logical operators which we used to derive true
or false.
So roughly you can say where these arithmetic operators - plus, minus, the asterisks, the multiplication
operator and so on, where those operators helped us with numbers and in the case of the plus, also with
strings which we could concatenate, these logical operators produce true or false
which we then in turn typically use in conditions.
Now with that, we have a solid list of operators but then we also have these and and or operators and
these actually also are operators.
Now as you already see, not all operators produce the same result,
some operators produce boolean values, true or false,
other operators produce numbers or strings.
Now there's more where we dive into
but one thing that already is important to understand is the concept of operator precedence and for
that attached you find a link to this web page on MDN which talks about operator precedence. In the end,
this is a fancy term for saying how are operators handled,
so in which order are they executed if you will
and the good thing is when we talk about plus and minus and times and the division operator, the normal
mathematical rules apply.
So for example if you have something like 3 + 2 * 5, the 2 * 5 is evaluated
and executed first and then 3 is added to the result of that,
so normal math and you can override that just as you do it in math by using brackets, parentheses.
There, you can change how that is passed and that is all built into Javascript and it works just as you
would expect it to be.
But of course with the and and the or operator, the question also is which operator takes precedence
there?
And this article has a table if you scroll down a bit which lists the precedence of operators and you
can simply reach that table from top to bottom with the topmost operator taking the highest precedence
and therefore unsurprisingly, that would be the parentheses. With parentheses, you could basically override
the normal rules just as we did it with the mathematical equation I showed you a second ago.
Now in this table, you'll find many operators which we haven't seen yet.
Now of course, needless to say that I'll dive into all the important operators throughout the course but you
will already recognize some of them,
for example if you scroll down further, you find the typeof, you'll find the exponentiation operator, multiplication,
division,
remainder, addition, subtraction
and there you can see that multiplication and division have a higher precedence than addition and subtraction
which is just what we saw in that equation I showed you a second ago and if we scroll down further, we
see that the boolean operators have a lower precedence. The impact of that is that if you for example
check if three plus two is smaller than nine minus two, then you will actually get true because Javascript
will first evaluate this and this and then compare the results because the addition and subtraction
operators which I'm using here have a higher precedence then these comparison operators,
therefore these calculations are executed first before the comparison is made. Again,
that is basically what our common sense would tell us
and it's good that Javascript behaves the way. It would be strange if the result of this would actually
be is two smaller than nine and then we have three plus true minus two,
that doesn't even make sense, right?
So we would expect that this is evaluated and this is evaluated and then the results are compared
and thankfully that's exactly what's happening in Javascript
but of course the question for example is if you have five equal five and you also want to check if
three is smaller than six or if 10 is bigger than 20,
well in which order is that executed? Does Javascript check this and then check the result of this comparison
or does it check
is this true and this true or this true?
That of course matters because if we change this a little bit and we say is 10 greater than 5, so this
is true
but here we check if three is greater than six, then the result of this first comparison, if this would
be executed first would be false because yes this is true
but this here, this comparison is false.
So if the and operator where both has to be true to return true, this would actually return false.
Now as you can already see here in my IDE, we will get true as a result , o this already indicates that
this is evaluated first and then this
and if either one of these two blocks returns true, the overall condition will return true and that's in
case what's happening here.
Instead if it would be the case that this is evaluated and then this would have to be true, then it would
also work like this but not for example if we check if that is not equal.
Then if we say this has to be true and this has to be true, we would have a problem because this first
part wouldn't be true.
So what I'm saying here basically is that and has a higher precedence than or and indeed that is what
we see here in the table,
the logical and has a higher precedence than or which means that first Javascript connects these two
pieces and evaluates them and then this operator kicks in and considers the second condition as well,
which means that if this is true, we overwrite the fact that this yields false.
So you can always check this table if you're not sure about some order but actually in most cases as
I mentioned, it's just what you would expect to happen,
so definitely don't learn this by heart,
there also are operators in here which are quite niche which you will never use to be honest,
so don't learn this by heart, just take it as a reference if some behavior is unclear to you.
In general, common sense is what's happening in Javascript or what's getting applied there
and the one thing where you might not have an intuition is maybe that and and or thing, well there and
takes precedence over or which means first this is evaluated and then it's compared to this and there,
the or operator simply means if one of the two is true, the overall statement returns true, the overall
expression returns true
and therefore this overall returns true because this is true and therefore thanks to the or operator,
this doesn't matter, the fact that this is false but still important to know, this was grouped together
because and takes higher precedence.
So instead of grouping together this, this was grouped together.