Now last but not least, in Visual Studio Code, under view,
you also got these different modes here.
I showed you the extensions view which allows you browse extensions,
explorer is that view you see here which is the view you typically work in the most,
it allows you to see your files here on the left.
Search can also be very helpful though, search allows you to search through all your files and you can
change how it searches
for example if it searches in a case sensitive way here and there, I could search for write to log and
if I do that,
it shows me that it found this write to log thing in five places all in app.js
and if I click on there, it highlights it here,
it also highlights all the results here in the scroll bar on the right.
So this can also be very helpful.
Now under view, you also have the scm view,
now that helps you with source control,
so when you're using Git, then you see what you've changed since your last commit
and you can inspect what you changed here and commit that and so on.
So if you want to have a graphical user interface for source control, you can use this and debug is a
mode
I'll come back to later in this module once we dive into debugging our code.
This can be really helpful with understanding our code, how it executes and can help us find and fix
errors.
So that's Visual Studio Code and working with the IDE and I hope it gave you a general idea of what
you can configure there, what you might want to think about and what you might want to explore to work
with your code effectively.