Now to focus on that, we do something which is called mocking,
we mock features which means we replace features
we don't want a test with some dummy implementations and how could this look here?
Well in utiltest.js, we got load title and we want to test if that successfully transforms our title
to be all uppercase, to be this text.
Now to test this, what we need to do is we need to replace fetch data with a mock.
Now jest gives us a great way of preventing us from using that fetch data method.
We can create a new folder called __mocks, all lowercase, __ next
to the files that contain our raw source code,
so in this case in our root folder.
Now here, we can add a http.js file, so the same file name as the file that has the
function we want to replace and now in http.js, we can now do some magic to set up some functions
that will replace our real functions when running the tests. For that,
I'll copy my code from http.js, I'll get rid of axios though because I'll not use that here, I'll
still export fetch data though
but in fetch data, I'll simply return a promise which I instantly resolve with promise resolve to an
object that has a title property with the text I want to test which I'll now convert to all lowercase
though, so delectus aut autem
and now that I'm exporting this here,
something interesting will happen. In http.js, I added a console log statement to fetch data to
see when we're hitting this API and when we're not.
If I now run npm test,
we are hitting the API as you can see here, we have that console log statement from the HTTP file
in there.
Now we can go to utiltest.js and in there, we want to add jest mock at the beginning and mock the
http.js file like this,
you can omit .js though. Now if I run npm test,
you see it also took close to a second because it had to do some magic behind the scenes but you don't see
that console log statement because what now happens is when this test gets executed, when this testing
file gets executed, jest goes ahead and replaces the HTTP file with our mocked file,
so all the functions that are export that here are then replacing the functions we are normally exporting
in the real HTTP file for our tests only. So for the tests only, we use our mocked functions here,
so this dummy fetch data which gives us back an object that allow us the other functions to work fine but
which does not hit the API because we don't want to test the API response and we don't want to test
the access get method, so we can rely on the API returning as an object that has a title property and
we can rely on the access get method giving us an object and a response which has a data property, so
we don't need to test that. We want to test whether our code in the util.js file correctly extracts
the title and transforms it and that is the case
otherwise this test would not have succeeded for our mocked implementation of fetch data where we return
an object with a title that is all lowercase,
so not what we test for lowercase this text and therefore since our test succeeds, we know that our transformation
here does work.
So this is how we can test async code or how we can replace code, how we can replace functionalities
if we don't want to
in this case hit the API, the same would be the case for let's say code that accesses the filesystem, you
don't want to do that,
instead you want to mock such functionalities. You can by the way also mock global packages, like axios
itself. Instead of mocking our fetch data function, you could create an axios.js file here and there,
we could export our own get function here
which we of course have to define
because remember in my https file, I am using the get method of the axios object.
So here I want to export a get method and that would be a function that takes a URL as an argument
but we don't care about that URL here, what we want to do here is we can return an object which
in this case, since this is faking the response from axios,
so we want to fake whatever get gives us back and that should be a response object which at least has
a data key because we're extracting that,
so here in the axios mock, we want to have a data object which should in turn be an object with the title
we want to test,
so that lowercase title we defined here.
So basically we're now mocking a functionality which is one level above the last functionality, where
we mocked our own function,
now we're using we're mocking the function, this raw function so this function depends on.
So now in the axios.js mock file I'm returning an object which has a data key which has an object as
a value, which has a title key which is the lowercase version of our text and with that being mocked, we
can go to our utiltest.js
file, we can comment out this mocking of our HTTP implementation, so we'll now not use this HTTP file
we created a second ago, Jest.js will automatically use mocks of global node modules though, so axios.js
this module should be used automatically, we don't have to instruct jest to do that and now we
can simply run npm test and here
it fails because what I return here is not a promise and this already proves that this mocked file is
being used, otherwise it would not have failed. I'm returning an object there and therefore calling then
fails, I of course have to return a promise here by using promise resolve,
so a promise that eventually yields this object and once I do that and therefore my mocked get method
provides a promise as the real axios implementation does, once I do that, it passes again. We see fetching
data here because we are now using my original fetch data implementation but the get method we're using
here is not the real one, it's our mocked one,
so this one here.
Now this is how you can mock certain functionalities to test async code or code in general which might
depend on third-party packages.
Now there are other strategies as well,
you'll also find the term spies or stops when you went deeper into testing and you can definitely also
check out these alternative approaches to learn about alternative strategies for working with async
code and third-party libraries. Attached to this lecture, you also find additional resources that allow
you to dive deeper into these topics and into jest in general and learn more about testing and build
up on the knowledge you gain here.