When speaking about manipulating elements, it's also important to understand the difference between attributes
and properties because it's easy to confuse these two things or to not even be aware of these two different
things because often, indeed attributes are mapped to properties and some live synchronization is set
up and I'll show what l mean in a second but that's not always the case,
for example here we have an input element with an ID, with a CSS class and with a value
and it's interesting because there we have three different kinds of attributes which behave in different
ways when it comes to the DOM object that is created and how the properties of that object are initialized.
So these are all attributes here placed in the HTML codes,
so what you write in the HTML code is named an attribute, what you add on the HTML tag, that's an
attribute of that tag. What the browser does with these attributes is it creates such a DOM object based
on the tag name, input
in that case and preconfigures it and preconfigures some of its properties based on these attributes
because the important thing is that the attribute is the thing in your HTML code, in your HTML text in
the end. The property is a value stored in the object that's created based on your HTML code
so to say, right? Objects in Javascript have properties, no matter if there are some DOM objects or
not.
So of course for DOM objects, we also have properties and these simply reflect the configuration and
setup and positioning and so on of that rendered DOM node, of the DOM object
and the idea of attributes is that you, if you're writing HTML code, can provide a certain default
configuration to this to be created DOM object.
So that's what you do with attributes and how they are translated to properties
and here for example, we see that if we get access to this input element and store it in a constant, let's
say we name it input, then we can read the ID from it but also the class name and the value and the
properties as I mentioned are automatically added on the created DOM objects.
Now here, it's important to understand that not every attribute has a one-to-onemapping in properties
though,
input ID has it, there we have an ID attribute and an ID property
and if we change the value of the attribute, the property updates,
if we change the value of the property, the attribute will update,
so we have some live synchronization going on here.
Input class name is different,
there we also have live synchronization,
so if we change the property, the attribute will change,
if we change the attribute, the property will change but the names are not equal so we don't really have
a one-to-one mapping. Class on the input,
so on the HTML tag is translated to a class name property here on the DOM object and
of course the browser does this automatically, it's just important to know that not always the attribute name
is equal to the property name and for value, we have yet another different behavior.
There we have a one-to-one mapping,
it's called value as an attribute and value as a property but we have no real life synchronisation going
on,
only one way because what you have here is actually that if you change the input value, this will not
be reflected back to the attribute, only if you change the attribute, the value properties value will change
again and that makes sense because you have to keep in mind that for example this input element is there
to hold some user input
and if you would always reflect this back to the attribute, then that would mean that if you ever want
to reset the input to its initial value which the developer writing the HTML code at some point of time
stored in that value attribute, that this would not be possible if we always reflected the latest user
input in the value attribute because then we could never reset it because we lost the original value
we wanted to assign there.
So that's why when the user types there, the users input is stored on the value property but not reflected
back into the HTML code.
So let's see that in practice here
and for that, I'll add an input element here actually with a value of default text here and after saving
this, we can reload,
of course the color here is gone by the way.
So here we have that input element with the default text
and again of course, we can store a reference to it by using for example query selector and here then
just the inputs tag selector like this and we can of course console.dir input here to get access to
it.
We find a lot of properties which we already know but if we scroll down to v, we will also find one which
is not available on all elements and that's the value property which in this case holds default text.
Now if I go to the input here and in this elements tab here, we change default text by adding an exclamation
mark for example, if
we go back to the console, you'll see that if I reselect this, so const input2 document query
selector input and I now console.dir input2, you will see that if we scroll down to the value at
the bottom here, we have this exclamation mark in there as well.
So if I change the attribute that is reflected in the DOM object,
so that is reflected.
Now if I go ahead and we reset input to .value equal to some other input the user might have entered
and I hit enter,
you see this this reflected in the user interface,
right? This is set as a value here,
so that's great
but if we now inspect this again, we see there the value is still the default text we had in the attribute
before,
so there this is not reflected back.
Now as I explained before, for CSS classes and ID for example, that's different.
If I select my h1 tag here with get element by ID main title and I then set the ID equal to new
ID for example, I don't lose my reference here by the way because here we set up this connection and
thereafter, this is mapped to the address in memory,
so the address in memory is stored here,
so if I change that ID, this doesn't clear that connection, just the same command would of course
not work again because in elements we now see this has a new ID and this is now also reflected here
in the HTML code,
so there it is reflected back into the attribute. The same would be true for class name by the
way. Now important, if you do want to change an attribute, then you also have a method for that, you have
a set attribute method.
So on the input for example, we could call set attribute and this takes two arguments, two parameters
and the first one is the name of the attribute,
so here we could set value, should be a string
and the second is the value you want to assign to that attribute,
so here some other default text and if you do that and you hit enter,
this does not update UI because actually, changing this value here will not overwrite any existing changes
that might have been made so that you don't accidentally get rid of the user input but you do clear
that value here, you do indeed change that attribute here
but since we have no live sync,
indeed if I go to the value that's stored in there, I still have the other value which was set and not
the new attribute value here. So value indeed of course is one of the more complex properties you can
work with due to the way how it updates under which circumstances but generally of course, it's pretty
straightforward regarding how this value attribute and property behaves, it behaves such that you don't
accidentally clear user input and that your changes you made to value aren't easily dismissed but
that you can still have that attribute around and either assign a new value or of course if you would
want to reset the input, you could always just set value equal to input.getAttribute to get the
value stored in the attribute, reach out to the value attribute and since this doesn't reflect the current
input but instead whatever you set here or originally in the HTML code, you can run this code here
to reset the content in there to that starting code.
That's what I meant with that resetting and why this is kept around.
So this is how you can work with attributes and properties with set attribute and get attribute
and dot notation to interact with properties like this
and this is therefore how we can evaluate values stored in DOM objects and also change them if we
need to.