Now to come to an end.
Let's actually leave this code file and talk a bit briefly about the compiler.
Thus far I always compiled a file by typing TSC and then the file name.
Now that's a bit cumbersome.
No actually we can't enter watch mode by adding dash w thereafter.
Now it compiles but it keeps on watching that file and whenever I change something in there it re compiles
it automatically.
Now that's better but I'll quit this book control C because it might still not be everything we want.
Sometimes you also have multiple times good files and a project and you want to compile them all simultaneously.
For example we have other tests and in there I console log Halo which doesn't really use any type good
features but which still might be a typescript file I want to compile as well.
For now I have to type T is C. apt T S and TSC our daughter t s if I want to compile both.
And that's cumbersome.
Well we can turn this into a typescript managed project by running TSC dash dash in it.
What this does is it creates a two year conflict of Chase and file ad which will have a look in a second.
But even without looking at the file we now can do something different.
We can run just TSC without any file name.
We point at and although TSC dash w both is possible when we run either of the two what now happens.
All types could files get compiled.
Now you see I now get an error here and it will come back to why we get this in a second.
We didn't get it before it.
Now we get it again and we'll come back to that.
But it will compile all files and it can prove that by deleting the two JavaScript files and running
it again.
Now you see it created the two files.
So now we can compile all types good files simultaneously and we can also watch all of them.
Samuel heinously with Dash W.
But why am I getting an error now.
Object is possibly not.
We didn't get that before.
Well because the T is confit Jason File allows us to configure the compiler now and the default configuration
which was generated here is a different one than what we had for the TSC command without that file before.
Now you see there are loads of options in there.
Most of them are commented out and you find short descriptions here on the right in my understanding
types of course here and you'll meet I walk through all of that and way more detail here for example
you can control to which target you're compiling and if you set this for example to iOS 6 classes will
not be converted to non class code which works on older browsers but you will end up with iOS 6 javascript
code which therefore only works in browsers that support iOS 6.
So that's how you can control which javascript code is produced but you also have a number of setting
here the strict setting and this controls how strict the typescript compiler is.
And that's what's responsible for this error in the end before the compiler was not that strict.
Now it effectively turned on all these options here which checks different things in our code for example.
It checks whether something could potentially be null and could lead to unexpected errors in an app.
Yes we have such a case when I get access to my button here and all the to the inputs what I get here
could be now.
Now here I use typecasting so I make it clear to typescript that this will not be now but an HD female
input element.
Here however I rely on inference now typescript infers that since I use the button tax selector.
This is a H.M. button element or with a union type here.
It could also be not because if I have no button in my HDL file I can select one.
So this could be now and before typescript didn't care about this with the strict mode here.
It now does.
Now we can even turn this on or simply not use this general strict rule but only turn on the D strictness
checks we want.
But here I will leave it on and show you how to work around this issue.
It's very simple.
We could even add a if check and check.
If not button elements.
If this is false see and if that's the case we do something or we only add an event listener if it's
true.
So that's one thing we could add if check or if we know with certainty that the button will exist.
We can add exclamation mark thereafter which is also a typescript feature not a vanilla javascript feature
which tells typescript this will never be null ignored the null case and now our error would be gone.
So it's another type of good feature which can be useful especially if you've got the strict options
turned on.
And now there is more.
You can configure here and going through all of that it would really bloat this module and be too much
for this introductory module.
If you want to learn more about TypeScript and about this file my type of course or of course the official
docs are the place to go.