So what's up with data structures for this I'll add and you file data dash structures.
J.S. and in there I want to get started with data structures.
Let's import them and for a data structures it's important to understand that data structure is anything
that stores stayed up.
So string like this is a data structure but of course a fairly trivial one where we can't do much with
and which is also already built into javascript an array is a more interesting data structure also already
built into javascript but very important.
And of course one we use a lot the same for an object or maps or sets.
These would all be Data Structures data structures built into javascript.
Now maybe let's start with the array and let's say we have an array of ages 30 29 54 something like
this with this array we can of course do things we can sum it up as we did before here with the sum
up algorithm or we can find the minimum value something like this.
Now it's important to understand that certain operations with data structures also have certain time
complexities.
For example if I push a new age onto disarray what would be the time complexity of this action.
Now of course push is not an algorithm not a function we created on our own but still it is a function
that does something.
And if you want to learn what it does you can check out MDA and or other resources that explains such
built in functions like this one.
Well it's important to understand how push works when you push something you have an array like this
one here and then push adds a new element in this array and it adds it at the end.
So here where I added this blank space dad is where push inserts an item.
Now it's all important to understand and you'll learn this dead in an array.
The elements are ordered and every element has an index that identifies the element.
So here we have an index of 0.
Here we have an index of 1.
And here we have an index of 2 right now when we push here we of course create a new index for that
newly added item the index free in this case.
So what happens when we push we add a new item at the end and this item gets a new index.
Does this affect the other items.
No not at all.
So adding item at the end of an array with push has actually a constant time complexity.
0 1 because the other items are not affected we add one item we don't affect the other items we have
a constant time complexity note that changes if we use on shift on shift adds the item at the beginning
of an array so if we take a closer look at this and I copy that here then we see that what.
On shift will do is dead it adds the item here at the beginning.
The problem with that is that means all items effectively have to be moved.
You could say they get a new index.
So here it is new item receives an index of zero the item which previously had zero 30 had zero now
receives a new index one the item which previously had the index one which was the item twenty nine
receives a new index 2 and so on.
So here for on shift all existing elements are touched.
So this actually has a linear time complexity o n for every new item we add we have to touch and move
all existing items we have to reassign indexes so that is of course way worse than pushing.
It's also something I mentioned earlier in the course already in the arrays section so I'm shifting
sometimes of course is what you want to do and then you should do it but you should be aware that it's
way more expensive from a performance perspective than pushing an item to the end of the list.
What's all the important to know and to understand is that of course it also costs you something it
takes some time to find an element.
For example if I want to get my age and let's say I am 30 then of course if I know that my age is stored
in position 1 or year after underreporting actually at position 2 I can get it by its index index 1
here index 1 gives me 30 so if I know did I want my age and my age is the second item India raise so
it has a mix of 1 then I can access it like this.
And this actually accesses it at constant time complexity 0 1.
Why is this constant.
Because every item has a index.
So JavaScript can immediately go to that place in memory and give me that item.
It doesn't need to look at all the other items now of course this changes if we work with a different
data structure.
So here's a new example let's say we actually have an array name popularity
and what's in there is a bunch of objects.
So we have objects which is a no data structure in an array and there we have an I.D. or user name whatever
you want to call it like let's say Max and we have a number of usages let's say five times and then
here we have the user name menu and that's getting used six times.
And of course you could have more and more items.
So effectively we have identifiers and then we have values for these identifiers and now we want to
get the usages of menus.
So we want to get the number of times the name man who gets used.
So menu usages could then be named popularity where we use the built in fine method which executes a
function on every element in the array.
Looking at that person or whatever we want to name it and we have to return true if it's the item we're
interested in and fault if it's not.
So here I look for manuals I check of person user name is equal to menu.
If that's the case we return true.
We stopped searching for more and then this object will be returned by find.
So what I get back is an object which has is used just queue and this gives me the use such as off the
name menu.
So what I'm doing here is I'm looking for the item with a user name of menu and then I get the use just
for this item.
That's what I do with this line here.
Now in the best case manuals the first item here.
So we execute does function which we pass to find exactly once because we find manual right away for
the very first item we're looking at.
So we have executed this function once we get to use it as and we basically in the best case have constant
time complexity right.
The very first item was the one we were looking for but that's of course not always the case.
The worst case is that we have linear time complexity o n because manuals the last item and the average
case of course is somewhere in between but for a large number of items this in the end all the ends
up to be linear time complexity you could say so on average we'll have to walk through all the items
or close to all the items to find what we get because the elements are randomly distributed let's say
we don't know at which position manuals and data for we have linear time complexity because find executes
this function on all items in the array.
Now this is a scenario where another data structure might be a better choice instead of using an array
like this why don't we use an object or a map.
Let's rebuild this in this better way we have our name map let's say and we can use a normal javascript
object for this and now the keys here are the user names and the values for the keys are to use the
chips like this.
And now when we want to get men use usages and I'll just name it man you use just two to not clash with
this name.
Then we can simply reach out to the name map and access the key.
Man you'll like this.
And then this gives us the usages for man you know this is way better because this will be constant
time complexity
0 1 because the way javascript stores objects internally they are just key value pairs and for a given
key JavaScript can instantly give us back the value that's stored for the key so it doesn't have to
go through all the key value pairs.
Just as an array can instantly give you the value for a specific index an object can instantly give
you the value for a specific key.
So if we have a scenario like this using an object might be better than using an array of objects as
we have it here because we go from linear time complexity in the worst case or in the average case to
constant time complexity.
Now if we had a key which is not a string but let's say some other object or anything like this then
of course we could use a real map and you learn about that in the data structure section early and of
course we can create a new map like this and then simply add our items to this real map which is capable
of using anything as a key not just strings or numbers but also our object ends on.
So a real map is already built into javascript and if you had a scenario where you need uniqueness you
could use a set so you will have these different built in data structures and for different operations
stay off for different performance or different time complexities.
You should be aware of that so that you can use the right data structure for the task you are trying
to solve.
Now just as before here I also got an article I can strongly recommend about built in data structures
and also other data structures you could build on your own where you also see time complexities for
different operations some comments and then also some examples for these data structures and how to
use them with certain operations not important.
This article does not just include built in data structures like the array.
It also shows you how to build brand new data structures with the built in ones.
So building up on the built in ones of course.
Dad can be better suited for certain operations or certain tasks.
This is a bit more advanced and I will say right away that in many scenarios you will not need these
custom built data structures but for a highly sophisticated or advanced applications you might need
to build your own data structures which just an optimized for certain tasks to be faster than what you
got built in.
But that's a next step.
After you master the basics.
For now it is important to understand different time complexities of different operations and that therefore
it is important to think about what you plan on doing and coming up with the right or with the best
solution for the task at hand.
To have a well performing solution.