So now that we learned a lot about closures and scope and so on,
let's have a look at recursion which is a quite interesting pattern, a quite interesting way of using functions,
which is not exclusive to Javascript but which you can use in any programming language.
Let's start with a simple recursion.
Let's say we want to create a function,
power of which should calculate the power of something
and this function should get two arguments - the value and then the power which we want to use, so that
we for example can run power of two and three and what we would get is the result of two times two times
two,
right,
which would be eight,
that's two at the power of three.
So this is what this function should do.
Now a first implementation could simply start with a result of one and then use a for loop where
we go through all iterations that we need, so i smaller n and increment i
and then in here, we change result to be equal to result times x or shortcut, like this and then in the
end, we return the result.
Now this calculates the power of x because what it does is it goes through this loop n times,
so in this case here three times and every time, it takes the result where we start at one because we're
doing a multiplication, starting at zero would be a bad idea,
we would always get zero,
so we start at one and then for the first iteration, i is zero
but we don't really care about i, we just care about x..
So in the end we take the old result which is 1 and multiply this with x which is 2 for this call here
because the value for x is two.
Then we go through this loop a second time,
i is now one but n was three
so we still go through that and our result is two from the first iteration,
x is also still two
so now we have two times two, we got four and now we go through that a third and last time because i is two
now, n is still three
so we go through that, result was 4, x still is 2, new result is 8.
We don't go through this loop a fourth time because i now is three and so is n and hence the result gets
returned.
So if i save that and i reload, i get eight down there,
that works as it should.
Now we could implement it like this but with the concept of recursion, we can actually write this in
a shorter way.
So let me copy that and comment it out and let's try again.
So here is another try of writing that power of function, this time with recursion. The idea behind a
recursion or a recursive function is that the function calls itself. So we return x times and now we
reference the same function here with a value for x but now with n - 1,
so what's the idea here?
Well when we call this function, we return x which is two times the same function call but with n
minus one,
so n is three here, we call the function again with a value of two for n because it's n - 1.
So if this function then runs again, we get x two but n now also is two for this function call and it's that same
function.
So now again we have 2 times and now again, we call that same function again, this time again with n -
1,
so n was 2, minus 1 is n equal to 1.
Again this function runs again, calls itself again here and so on
so obviously this would lead to an infinite loop
so we also need to specify some exit condition with an if statement where I check if n is equal to 1,
then i want to return x actually,
so then i want to return just x, i don't want to call myself again, otherwise and we don't need an else
statement because if we return here, this won't execute anyways, we run this code.
So if i save that, we again get a, we get no error or anything like that, we get the expected result.
Still, it might not be super clear what's happening here.
So to make that clearer, let's actually use the dev tools, dive into app.js and let's set a breakpoint
here,
let's set a breakpoint inside the power of function here.
Now if i reload, this pauses and now let's expand this section down here and let's have a look
at the call stack, we see in the call stack,
there is one power of call because we just got started,
the value for x is two, the value for n is three.
So if we continue, we skip this if check because n is three
so we don't make it into there and we're now in this line
and now here, we call this function again.
So now let's step into that function call.
Now you see on the call stack, we have two power of calls, the first one with which we started
and the second one and the difference can be seen here,
n here it's three,
here it is, for the one we're currently in, it's two.
So the same function executes again
but of course it's a different execution, we got two ongoing executions. The first one is paused
so to say because it waits for the result of the second execution,
so now let's see what the second execution does.
N is two so we still skip this if check and we call ourselves again,
so let's step into that function call and now
n is one for that third function call, we got three times the same function called on the call stack
now. Now n is one so now we will actually make it into this if check,
so if we step into there, we actually return and on the call stack, you will see that if i advance,
we now get rid of one of the function calls, instead
now this function call for the second one,
so the third one which was triggered by the second one, returned a value, it returned a value which we
now use in that second call.
So now if we continue, we're back in the first function call where we started everything
and if we now continue, we're done
and the overall result of this function called will be 8.
So this is the idea of recursion, we call ourselves and why is this now better than a loop?
Well simply because it's shorter. As you will also see in the next lecture,
it's not just shorter,
it can also help us with other problems
but here already we can save some space because we can even write this in a shorter way.
This is the more understandable way, the shortest possible way would be to return a ternary expression
where we check n equal one and if that is the case, we return x which we do here as well,
otherwise we perform this operation.
So now we got one line where we previously needed a for loop,
that's the power of recursion,
it can save us code and it can do more than that as you'll see in the next lecture.