Now to conclude this module, let's have a look at regular expressions. Regular expressions help us work
with strings,
consider this example - you're having an input and there, you get some user input and that should
be an email address,
something like test@test.com,
this is what you get from an input you might have on your page.
Now of course, users can enter anything in there and by accident, they might enter something which is
not a valid email address,
let's say for some reason the @ symbol was forgotten.
Now you want to verify whether what the user provided to you in your code, when you work with that value,
whether that is an email address or not.
Now a trivial test you can make or you can perform is you can use a string method for that, the includes
method and check if that string includes an @ symbol and we would get false here and hence you would
know that the user input we got is not a valid email address but a valid e-mail address is not just
determined by the existence of an @ symbol,
instead we also want to have a domain ending at the end, dot something.
So of course we can also check whether it includes a dot
but that would also mean that something like tests.t@test would be treated a valid email address
because it includes a dot even though it's in the wrong place and that's where regular expressions can
help you.
Regular expressions don't just exist in Javascript, they exist in most programming languages and they
help you search for patterns in strings.
Now you create a regular expression in Javascript in one of two ways, you can create it with the new regex
constructor and then to this constructor, you pass a string which describes the pattern you want to look
for and there is a rich regular expression language and syntax you can use here or you use a literal
notation for creating that regex object, just like you can use square brackets to create an array
object, you use two forward slashes like this and then in between these slashes, you define your pattern and a
simple email validation pattern could look something like this, the carry symbol here, then
\S+@\S, capital S,
that's important in both places, \.\S+$. Now this looks super weird
right now but let's just accept it as it is and make sure you don't mistype.
Now with that, you can use this and as I said, it is an object and call a method on this object
and there we could call the test method and to the test method, you can pass a string where you want
to validate if it meets this pattern and there we could pass in user input, we would get false. On the
other hand, if I test a valid email address, let's say here I test test@test.com, I get true.
Now the reason for that is that this in the end describes a regular expression which says we accept
any kind of word at the beginning,
this symbol means we start from the left
so we have to start with any kind of word, like test,
then somewhere in the overall string I want to have an @ symbol, thereafter again, any kind of word,
so this test here for example, then a dot which we have here and then again, any kind of word with which
we end this string.
This is what this expression means in the end and this string here for example fits into this pattern.
Now of course, there is a rich regular expression syntax you can learn and it's almost like a programming
language on itself.
In the next lecture, I'll provide a brief introduction into this syntax but by no means a complete overview
of all the things you can do there,
however linked to the next lecture, you'll also find an external resource, a little bit of a more detailed
introduction I prepared in the past which you can have a look at and also some MDN documentation
to learn more and I will also show you how you can find out which pattern is best for your use case.