Now let me also make clear what output result really does here,
this does something which is called call a function, which I'll dive into later so we can ignore this
for now,
in the end it triggers some code which I defined here in vendor.js and this code uses two pieces
of information which I kind of forward to it.
Again we'll figure out the details of what this is and how we use it later because we'll write our
own functions then but in the end, I push this data to this thing in vendor.
What this does is it takes these two pieces of information it gets and writes them into my HTML
code
you could say because ultimately what that code does, without diving into the details which we'll also
cover later in the course because it's a bit more advanced, what this code does is it targets two places,
two pieces of our HTML code,
these two lines essentially and overwrites the data which is hardcoded in there with a dynamically derived
data
with the data you are forwarding here,
so with your result and with this empty string, that's what's happening here.