So we potentially at least improved our startup time,
now let's have a look at runtime performance and for that, I'll go to the performance tab here, enable
CPU throttling, clear all previous snapshots and I'll take a new snapshot
when I delete a product, then stop that.
Now you see, here is the interesting part so let's zoom in there,
you see ongoing network requests, that were the extra chunks that were downloaded,
let's close that.
Now let's have a look at the main thread down there because that's the more interesting part.
Now what you see is here I got my click on a button and you see we have a little warning here that this
took around 80 milliseconds which isn't great,
we have the function call and then we have another function call here where other functions are getting
executed based on the extra bundles we added.
Now here whilst we don't see the function names unfortunately here in this tab, we see it's from
line 10 in the shop.js and this is delete product function which makes sense because that
is what should be triggered if we clicked the delete button and then after our extra chunks were downloaded,
more code was getting executed here from our extra chunk files.
Now to be honest, here this time it took for the handler,
we probably won't be able to do much about it because the function call here which is getting executed,
which takes some time really isn't taking that long because of any of our code,
you see all the code which is executing here and executing here runs fairly fast.
I mean for example this entire script here takes like 42 milliseconds which should be okay but actually
in our script we still have an issue or a couple of things we can improve.
For that I'll even turn off throttling because I can show it nonetheless. Again hit escape here and in
the bottom tab here, click on rendering and turn on paint flashing,
this will allow us to see which problem we have on this page, you can now close that. If you now reload, you
see everything flashes green and whenever something is re-rendered, it flashes green.
Now the interesting thing is if I delete let's say the last item, the t shirt here,
so if I click on delete here, you see everything here flashes green,
that's what we saw earlier already.
If we expand the unordered list here and we watch the list items on the right,
whenever I delete an item, everything here is updated, the entire unordered list and all the list items
and I'll turn off the flashing because it's a bit annoying
but you see the problem here, the whole list is being re-rendered
whenever we delete an item even if it's the last item and there is no reason for that to happen. It makes
more sense when we add a new item because when we do add a new item, we actually add it at the beginning
of the list so of course Javascript has to shift all items to the back or the browser has to shift all
items to the back here but why is it re-rendering the entire list when we delete an item, even if it's
the last one?
Well we could see the answer if we have a look at the rendering.js file here in the optimized folder.
In rendering.js, we see render products which is the function responsible for displaying the products
on the screen, when it executes it always clears all existing DOM elements in the product list element
which is in the end that unordered list element here with the product list ID and then it creates
all these new DOM nodes and adds them for every product we have,
so for five products initially, if we had 100 products it does it for 100 products.
Now this is really not a great code here,
this is not what we want to do, re-rendering everything for every change can be horrible,
imagine you have a list with 100 items and you delete everything on the screen and re-render it all
for every tiny change,
well if your users have a bit slower devices, they will probably feel that and see that and it's not
a great user experience because accessing the DOM in general is quite performance intensive and such
errors like this one can quickly add up.
So we should improve the render products function here to not re-render everything
whenever we change something and therefore to improve this, I will actually add a new function here, update
products which should be a little bit more careful when we add or remove an item. We will still
need render products to render the entire list when we initially render all products here in init products
but I certainly don't want to call render products when we added or removed an item. So I'll leave render
products as it is but in update products,
I want to add code which we can use when we added or removed an item.
So therefore here I expect to get the product data which was added or removed as a first argument,
let's say we also need the product ID in case we're deleting so that we directly get that, I want to get
that delete product function because if we add a new product, I will still need to render a button which
points at this function and I want to get one last argument which tells me if we're calling update products
because we're adding a new one or because we're deleting one because then I can use an if check to find
out if we're adding and if we do, I essentially want to create a new product again and append it, otherwise
I want to remove it. So let's start with removing maybe in the else case here, I want to get access to my
product element here or product el to stay in line with the naming in other parts of this script
by using document get element by ID prodId because when we render a product in the future, I want
to add the ID attribute on the rendered DOM node and point at the ID of the product which was added.
So here in render products, my new list element which is my new product item here
should actually get the ID property set to product.id,
so to the ID of the product we're-rendering, so that every DOM element has the ID attribute which
is the ID of the product,
we can then use this to get a hold of that element when we want to delete it.
And then we can call product element remove or for better browser support of course as you've learned,
reach out to the parent element and there, call remove child on product el. Both works, I'll use the
shorter, more modern approach here which doesn't work in all browsers though.
So this is now the deletion part,
now I want to call update products when we do delete.
So in product management, in delete product, I don't want to call a render products in the end but instead
update products.
So from rendering, I'll import update products and down there, I call update products with a pointer at
the product
I want to update, the ID of that product, a pointer at the delete product function,
so this function itself and the value for is add which here would be false.
Now the problem is the product which is affected I don't have access to it here and this code here in general
also isn't optimal yet. Now we can optimize this code later, for now I'll add a variable, deleted product
and here in this loop where I go over all my products, I'll check if the product I'm looking at does
not have the ID of the deleted one which means I want to keep it which is why I add it to updated products
which I then set as my new products array,
so else if the IDs do match, I know this is the product which was deleted,
so I'll set deleted product equal to prod in that case. And then down there, deleted product is what I
want to forward here,
prodId which is the argument I get here is the ID I want to forward, here
I point at the function itself for this argument which the delete part of the update products function
won't even use though and important, for is adding, we set false because we're not adding, we're deleting.
So now when the delete product function executes, update products should actually execute and that should
now update our list of products in a way that doesn't cost the entire list to re-render,
well let's test this.
Let's reload and expand unordered list here,
now you see the IDs are being added here,
I'm using dates as IDs here and now watch the list items on the right
when I delete the magic broomstick. You see, the list items here didn't flash, only the unordered list
because the unordered list of course was affected, one of its child items was removed but the other
list items which weren't removed weren't re-rendered, they weren't touched and therefore this is far more
efficient than what we had before.
Now definitely, use this now as a chance to pause and try coming up with an approach of implementing adding
in a way that doesn't affect everything or doesn't re-render everything, of course in the next lecture,
we'll also do it together.