[Autogenerated] So in this short clip,
let's just have a quick recap on what CloudWatch is and how we can use it.
Now.
CloudWatch is a service that monitors are a W s resource is as well
as our applications that were running on A W s.
And it does this in real time.
Now it allows us to collect and then track certain metrics that
are important to us in order to gain that operational excellence
and building off of this we can.
Then create alarms based on those collected metrics
to alert us whenever we need it.
So, for instance, if we see some high CPU usage in an auto scaling group,
we might want to create an alarm that takes an action.
And we will dive into that a little bit deeper here in the upcoming clips.
The next thing it allows us to do is visualized resource utilization.
So we can see how much of a specific resource is being used.
Next, we have the ability to measure application performance.
So we can see how well our applications are performing within our services.
And then finally we have the ability to maintain operational health.
So we're going to be able to leverage CloudWatch to
keep our systems healthy and running, which is always a good thing.
Now let's go ahead.
We're going to wrap up here and in the next clip will start discussing the key CloudWatch concepts.