[Autogenerated] welcome back,
since we have a good understanding of some of the key
concepts of CloudWatch and what CloudWatch does,
let's go ahead and dive in on getting hands on experience within the service.
Now,
some of the demos that you're going to see here and hopefully take part
in our we're going to explore the different name,
spaces and metrics that error offered by CloudWatch.
We're going to create a dashboard with specific metrics that we deem important.
And then we'll go ahead and set up a CloudWatch alarm to
send out a notification to a made up admin.
And in this case, it will be me.
So without further ado,
let's go ahead and wrap up here and let's begin diving into interacting with Amazon CloudWatch.