[Autogenerated] All right, let's pick back up where we left off.
In the previous clip, we created an association IDE,
and set up our inventory for our managed instance.
And we see this instantiate right here.
Now, the next thing I want to show you is a run command.
So run commands Allow us to execute and automation document,
which will take a look at here shortly and we can target instances that we
want to run these on remotely slow click on run command.
And this takes us to our command document selection screen.
There's a lot of documents provided by a W S.
But if you create your own,
you can actually go ahead and filter by owner and see Hey,
I want the ones owned by me now.
What I'm going to do is actually go ahead and filter to Linux platform.
This will knock out the windows ones or at least the windows specific ones.
And I want to go ahead and I'm gonna find runtime
sell script so I'll select this.
You can see we can provide a version and under here there is default
version of latest version or the actual version number.
This allows some flexibility in your execution.
You'll see there's a description provided to us.
So this is running a shell script or specifying commands that
we want to run on our target server and at the bottom here we
have our command parameters.
So this is where we actually create our shell script or command to run.
Now I'll go ahead and I'm going to run a simple touch command to create a file.
So let me do that here.
And all we're doing here is I'm creating a file.
And then I'm echoing a simple it worked statement into it.
We can specify a working directory if we wanted to,
will leave the default, and then we have an execution time out.
The default is one hour, so if our command hasn't completed within an hour,
it would time out.
But you can also go up to 48 hours as seen here.
I'll leave the default for now,
and the next selection that we have is our targets.
Now you'll notice this is similar to when we created our inventory collection.
In the previous clip.
We can specify by tags we can choose manually or we can choose a resource group.
Now I cover resource groups in my other course on Pluralsight,
and it's called Managing A W s Operations.
So if you wanna learn more about those, I recommend you take that course.
But for now, we'll choose manually.
I'll go ahead and select all which is really just one,
and then we have our other parameters.
So we can type a comment about what we're doing and we can specify a time out
for the command in seconds will leave the default here.
The next thing that we can do is specify a rate control,
so we can specify a concurrency.
So we want this to execute on up to 50 targets at a time,
or we can do a percentage, and then we have an error threshold.
So how many errors are we allowing,
or how many failures are we allowing and still consider this successful?
I'll leave it at zero, and the next thing we have here is output options.
So it's going to write all of these command outputs to an S3 bucket,
and I'll choose a bucket here from the list.
I'll choose my old Pluralsight CloudTrail bucket
that we used in our previous demos.
We can give it a prefix.
So maybe I want to type in S S m.
And then we can also output this to CloudWatch.
So if we wanted to push these logs to a log group and then maybe
trigger or collect off of that we can do that as well.
We have SMS notifications.
So we can send a notification to a topic based on certain events.
So maybe we want to notify that were completed with this execution.
And then finally, it shows you the equivalent A W s CLI command.
So this is a pretty handy part that you won't be tested over.
But it's awesome to have this because then you can build off of this and
make your own without having to leverage the console.
Now, before I click on run down here,
I just want to show you the instance and verify
that that file does not exist yet.
So I'm SSH it in.
And if we go to opt here, you'll see we don't have that testing file.
So now if I go back to the console, I click on run,
we'll see this is in progress and I'll pause really quickly.
And then when it's done, I'll resume now.
It was done pretty quickly because it's a simple
command we can CR status here at the top,
our targets in the middle,
and then we can look at our description and our parameters.
So now if I go back to my instance and I ls that directory again,
we see our file.
So this executed that shell command on our instantiate
Oatley without having the log in.
And if I cat that file, you can see Hey, it worked.
So that's awesome.
We've now executed a shell command remotely without having to log in to do it.
Now this is just a single example of what you can do with run command.
And in the next clip, I'll run through how we can manage patching,
which leverages these run command documents to automate,
are patching procedures.
So let's go ahead and take a break. And in the next clip will start looking at ST manager and Patch manager