[Autogenerated] Okay,
so we just got done viewing how we can update our CloudFormation
stacks with both direct updates and change sets.
Now, this time we wanna look at configuration Drifts.
So to do this I want to find drifts and you can see we have not checked.
So that's our current status.
So if I go ahead, detect stack drift, this will run in the background.
And while this is running,
I'll show you what I did now in the instantiation group.
The original one here I actually added an additional rule to
allow ICMP traffic from anywhere on the net.
And now, after I refreshed this page here,
you can see Hey,
our stack has drifted and it shows the resource drift
statuses that are available we can see,
three of our four current resource is are in sync.
But hey are instantiation group which is the one we looked at here,
has been modified and is not current.
So if I select this and I've you drift details you can see Hey,
we added a rule to our security group for ingress traffic.
It shows us what kind of change it was the expected as well as the
current value and what's neat is down here at the bottom.
It shows the expected template format,
and then it shows the actual template format so you
can see the differences here.
This is where we added that new rule.
So we've went ahead and detected our drift status.
But how do we actually go about and remediated?
Well, unfortunately, as of now,
A W s only allows us to actually detect the drift,
not automate the fixes.
So in this case, let's go to security groups.
I want to get rid of these two rules here.
I'll save.
It will go back to our stack and let me detect our
drift again for that resource.
And there we go.
It's now in sync.
So Ah,
good thing to do here might be to create a lambda or some
type of automation that can do this for you.
So that's going to do it for detecting drift within a W s CloudFormation stacks.
We'll go ahead and end here and in the next clip will dive into stack sets as well as nested stacks