[Autogenerated] all right,
So now that we have an understanding of CloudWatch metrics,
we're going to take a look at dashboards now.
Dashboards are not going to be tested over,
but there's something useful for you when you're
implementing your architectures within AWS.
Now, CloudWatch dashboards, which we can see here on the left,
are just customizable.
Home page is, if you will, that allow us to specify what resource is.
We want to view on a single pane of glass,
so let's go ahead and create a dashboard.
Let me select create.
I'll give it a name.
We'll click on Create here and there we go.
We've now started the process.
Now what this does is it brings us to a widget selection screen, as you can see.
Currently, there are five different options,
and each of these is going to display differently now,
for this will use stacked area.
I'll click on configure, and this brings us to the screen we saw before.
It's our ad metric graft screen, so let's go ahead and do the exact same thing.
Will go to E.
C.
Two per instance,
and I'll go down and I'll find our instance IDE and I'll select CPU utilization.
And there you go.
It's populated our graph.
And if you notice it's a stacked area Grafana supposed to a line
graph like it was before and if we wanted to,
we can change that by coming up here.
We'll leave it as is for now.
And then the next thing we want to do is we want to give it a name.
Now, this is something descriptive.
So we can quickly identify what we're actually measuring.
So let me give this a name.
I'll go ahead and save this and then I'll click on
create widget And there we go.
We have now created a widget on our dashboard.
Now, one more important thing here is we want to save the dashboard,
so make sure you save it whenever you make any changes.
Otherwise, they're going to get wiped out.
So that's how easy it is to create your very own dashboard.
Now, before we wrap up, I just want to show you two things.
The first is under the main CloudWatch screen.
This is considered a dashboard Now A W s provides this by default
and you can see we have an alarm's section.
We have crossed service dashboard.
So we can have aggregated metrics within our account,
and then we can have a default dashboard down at the bottom.
Now, one last thing if you go to a service.
So let's just go to Ec2.
Since that's what we've been using and I load this easy to console.
Let me locate my instance.
You can see we have a monitoring tab built in.
So if I click on this,
this brings us to a dashboard provided to us by a W s CloudWatch.
You can see we're measuring data for the last hour.
Or I should say we're presenting data measured within the
last hour and you can see all of the different key metrics
that error offered to us.
Now.
Another thing to notice is we can actually enable detailed
monitoring if we wanted to from this tab.
Now, just remember, that incurs extra cost.
Now, I'm not going to do that here.
We're actually going to go ahead and wrap up and then move on to CloudWatch alarms