[Autogenerated] Okay, let's dive into actions and change.
Now, the first thing that I want to talk about is our maintenance Windows.
Now, I'm not going to create one.
But this is where we create our maintenance window for
our patch manager if we want one, and then we have change calendar,
which is a new service.
So you're not going to be tested over it anytime soon.
We'll go ahead and look at it, though from an overview.
And if you read, you'll see,
it allows us to control our changes specifically when
they happen on a calendar date.
Now, the big piece I want to touch on here is automation.
Now, automation, as you can tell, is fleet wide automation for common tasks.
So let's just go ahead and demo What that means when I execute,
it shows what's owned by us and Amazon, or even shared.
We have our categories on the left and then our
automation documents here on the right.
Now these documents are shared resource documents within S S M.
They all utilize run commands in the background.
The difference is these are usually doing more than one step.
So, for instance,
if I choose instantiate Let's create a managed Linux instantiate.
I scroll down we can see that we have our document details.
I'll use the default versioning and then we can
specify our execution that we want.
I'll do a simple we specify the A M D that we want.
So let me copy this in here.
And this is just the latest Amazon Linux two OS am I IDE.
We'll leave the default BBC.
We'll use the default role name that's going to be created.
Our security group, which is fine we can specify our instance.
Type.
We have to specify a keep your name so we'll use the
same as I used for my other one.
We're allowing remote access from anywhere,
which is fine because I'll delete this.
We specify an automation role we want this to use,
which you can see is optional.
This will just use my permissions and we can specify a
default sub net that we want to use.
I'll leave this at default.
I'll click on execute and what I'll do.
I'm gonna pause here and then I'll resume after this
is completed and we'll take a look.
Okay,
so it's completed now and we see it's successful so let me go
to Easy to let me refresh And there we go.
There's our new instance we just executed that
automation for So if I click on it,
we see our I am role that we went ahead and used.
We see our security group that was created in our AM I IDE
that we used now an interesting fact here.
So what this actually did in the background is it created a
CloudFormation stack managed by a W s in the background to create
our resource is and then it went ahead and deleted that stack
after the resource is were created.
So that's kind of the workings in the back end.
And we'll talk about CloudFormation here in the next module.
We'll go ahead and in this clip here and in the next clip,
I'll go ahead and install the S S M agent on a server that
will use to mimic an on Prem server.
So I'll use easy to,
but I'll remove the default installation and then manually install it and configure it