[Autogenerated] welcome to Module two of the gaining operational
excellence within a W s Pluralsight course.
In this second module,
we're going to look at leveraging CloudTrail to secure our AWS accounts.
Now, before we dive in, there are a few module objectives we want to cover.
So the first is we want to be able to create a W s CloudTrail trails for audits.
And then the next thing is,
we want to protect our CloudTrail trails via validation and encryption.
And then finally,
we want to learn how CloudTrail is best use within
organizations and advanced architectures.
So those are the key module objectives for the upcoming module. Now let's go ahead and dig into CloudTrail.