[Autogenerated] All right, Welcome back.
Now we just got done Demo ing a scheduled expression CloudWatch event.
And in this one, we're going to create an event based rule.
So let's go.
To create rule again will select our event source and our
trigger is going to be an event pattern.
So if you notice it's going to essentially trigger on an event
pattern that CloudWatch receives now specifically,
these error CloudTrail events and we'll discuss CloudTrail later on.
But for now,
the concept is that it's capturing an API call within our A W s account.
So we can select our service and you can see there are
several services available to us.
Almost all of them are available.
But for this, let's select E.
C.
Two.
So we're looking for an easy to event we can.
Do all events or we can specify any event type now for this,
we'll go ahead and choose instantiate change.
We'll specify a state.
But if we wanted to we can do any state and let's say we wanna
go ahead and trigger when we're receiving a terminated instant
state as well as a stopping event.
So whenever any of these instantiate notifications are received,
this event should trigger now.
We could specify, in instance, IDE,
but we'll leave it at any instance because we want to say,
Hey, I want to know when any instance is getting terminated.
And then on the bottom here, you can see we have an event pattern preview,
so this is similar to what our event will look like.
Now we'll add our target again, just like before.
I'll go ahead and do a land of function, and I'll select that same function.
I'll configure details.
I'll give it a name again.
I'll give it a description.
I'll enable it, and then I'll create it.
So now this does not invoke like a rate based expression does.
This only invokes when an event is captured.
So let's go ahead and demo this.
Now let me navigate to E.
C.
Two.
I'll find my instance that I was playing with earlier and stress testing.
So let me go to running instances.
I'll go ahead and terminate this instance here,
and then you can see it's shutting down.
So that's our first instant state change that we notice.
So let me go to my lambda.
I want to view my logs and you can see, this is our most recent indication time,
and this was from our previous demo.
But here at the bottom, we've had another indication,
and it just happened right now.
So what I did is I made a prints statement that prints
the JSON event that we received,
and you can see it's an instance state change notification like we specified.
It gives us a time and account a region and most importantly,
in the detail block.
We have our instance IDE in the state that it's in.
So it's terminated.
So now when I go back to Ec2, we see it's in a terminated state.
So hopefully that kickstart some ideas on how you can utilize
CloudWatch events with event based triggers to perform specific
actions for your own use cases.
These event based triggers really allow you to do an enormous
amount of tasks in an automated fashion,
so be sure to check them out and play around with
them whenever you get some time. For now, we'll go ahead and wrap up here and move on