[Autogenerated] Okay.
Welcome back.
Now let's just take a look at a W s Ops works when you
come to the original screen here,
The landing page for the service we can have three different selections.
We can Look at our stacks, which will look at in a minute.
We can immediately jump to chef automate or we can jump to puppet enterprise and
you can see the differences here listed below the pictures.
So I'll go to stacks and you'll notice on the left is a
similar menu to what we just saw.
Now we're under stacks,
and you can either register existing instances or you can
add your first stack and start fresh.
So let's go ahead.
I'm gonna add my first stack.
We'll go ahead and do a sample one,
but notice you can specify your version if you wanted to,
I'll do it on Linux Ops works creates an I am role
for this particular operation.
And then it ran through setting up our sample.
Steck.
So let's look at it.
You can see we're looking at our stack that we just created.
We have a new app server layer.
We have our apps themselves, and then the number of instances that we have.
So from here,
we can treat our stack as a logical unit or resource and we can
run commands or change settings as a hole.
So this allows us to automate deployments for all of our instances that
belong to our application and do it using chef or puppet so we don't
have to repeat manually what we're doing now.
If I go to layers, we'll see we have our note app server layer that we looked at.
Let's look at settings so we can specify some settings.
We can Look at our recipes and these error custom chef recipes
that we want to deploy to this entire layer.
So any instances belonging to this layer will have this
Node.js demo cookbook deployed via this recipes setting
we can specify network security tags.
All the normal compute based resource is.
So I'm going to go back to stack.
I'm in my samples stack here.
Let's click on run Command.
You can see we have different command apps tions that we
want to use we can update cookbooks, execute a recipes we can set up,
configure or upgrade the OS.
You'll see.
Hey, I wanna upgrade to this version of Amazon Linux.
All allow a reboot.
And then if I needed to,
you can pass in customs Chef JSON for this to run on now,
we don't have any instances running right now in this stack.
So this is not going to do anything.
I just wanted you to be familiar with how you can use this
run command on your deployments in order to automate your
configuration management.
Now, that's gonna do it for this overview of a W s ops works.
If you leverage chef or puppet in your enterprise,
this managed service might be your best bet to get things up and running quickly and efficiently, so be sure to check it out.