[Autogenerated] way to go.
You have now completed the fourth module in this course before we wrap
up and end lets us go ahead and have a quick review.
We learned how we can use aws CloudFormation to
automate our infrastructure deployments.
We looked at the different stacks that they offer,
like stack sets and nested stacks.
And we gained an understanding of what infrastructure as
code is and its many different use cases.
We actually gained hands on experience with
different stacks within CloudFormation.
So we deployed that stack set and then we ended it by
seeing how we can leverage AWS ops works to automate our
configuration management tasks.
We can leverage this a ws managed service to have it handled the burden of
the load for standing up the infrastructure needed for a chef or puppet
set up that's going to do it for this module.
We'll wrap up here and then in the next clip,
I'm just going to do a quick course overview. So we can recap everything that we've learned throughout this course