[Autogenerated] Okay.
Congratulations.
You've made it through the first module.
Now, before we move on, let's just have a quick wrap up review.
So we started off by seeing how CloudWatch monitors are A W s
resource is and our applications in our accounts,
we covered the six key concepts for CloudWatch.
And with that, can you actually name those six key concepts?
We created alarms based on selected metrics for our use case.
So what we did, if you recall,
is we created an alarm that sent me a notification.
Once R E C two instantiate reached 50% CPU utilization.
We used CloudWatch events to trigger actions,
and we use both scheduled expressions and event based.
And then we finished up with pushing custom logs to Amazon CloudWatch.
So we de mode what it would be like to push logs to CloudWatch from an
on premise server that's going to do it for this module on configuring
and using CloudWatch for advanced workloads. Let's cut here and then I'll see you in the next module