[Autogenerated] first things first, let's go ahead and give a review on what a.
W s.
CloudTrail is now.
CloudTrail is an a W s service offered to us that allows us to enable
governance compliance and operational and risk auditing of R A.
W s accounts.
And it does this by recording events performed by users roles in A W S services.
Now,
these events that are being recorded include any
actionable event from the console, the CLI and any sdk or API call.
So essentially any interaction with our AWS account is
going to be recorded in CloudTrail.
And the beauty of this is it's enabled in our accounts by default.
So you do not have to do anything to have CloudTrail be
working immediately upon account creation.
Now we'll talk about customizing CloudTrail and creating our
own trails outside of the default one.
But it's important to know that it's enabled by default with
really no customization around it and to tie back to earlier
clips in the first module.
When we de mode are CloudWatch event often invent based trigger.
This is the service that it was using behind the scenes to trigger our rule.
That's a CloudTrail event.
And then, lastly, it allows us to gain visibility,
to view, search, download, archive,
analyze and respond to many different monitored activities that
error happening within all of our accounts.
So it allows us to drill down and see exactly who's
doing what at what particular time.
It's essentially an audit trail,
and that's very critical for you to know for any of the solution.
Architect exams.
Any time they mentioned auditing, it almost always is relating to CloudTrail.
So just keep that in mind now.
One last tidbit here is trails are regional,
but they can be created in all regions at the same time.
And I'll show you what this means here later on in the upcoming clips.
Now let's talk about CloudTrail configuration.
Now CloudTrail is made up of three primary configuration options.
Now the first one is management events.
So any particular event that happens in our account
relating to management and these error,
anything relating to dealing with resource is or managing resource is in a W s,
and then we have our data events.
So these error specific to data handling within our
accounts so you can think S3, for example.
But not the buckets themselves, but rather the objects in the buckets.
And then, finally,
we have the ability to store our log files in S3 for a long
period of time and then encrypt those files to protect the
sensitive data that those log files contain.
Now we'll cover all of these in the next upcoming clips,
but I wanted to get them out in front of you so you can be familiar
with them when we start seeing them in the console.
Now, before we wrap up,
I just want to cover our demo overview that we're
going to see in the upcoming clips.
Now the first thing we're going to do is we're going to view
our default trail and event this Torri within our CloudTrail
service for our AWS account.
And then after that,
we're going to go ahead and create our very own trail with
customize settings specific to what we need.
So let's go ahead.
We'll wrap up here and in the next upcoming clips will start demo ing and getting hands on experience with CloudTrail