[Autogenerated] awesome.
You have now completed the second module in this gaining
operational excellence within a W S course before we officially
in this and move on to the next module.
Let's just have a quick recap on what we learned.
We learned that CloudTrail helps us enable
governance compliance and risk auditing.
And we explored how it does that within our own A.
W s accounts.
We learned that CloudTrail is actually turned on by
default in all AWS accounts upon creation.
But we also learned that there are some limitations to that default trail.
We went ahead and got some practice on creating our very own
trails to customize our options to our liking.
We learned that we need to utilize organizational
trails for centralized logging.
So the master account or one other central account that you might choose,
like a security based account,
can store all of those CloudTrail logs in their very own buckets.
So then you have an aggregated view of your logs,
and that would be from all sub accounts.
So it allows for a lot of customization.
And then finally,
we learned that we want to always enable S3 log delivery and log
validation within our CloudTrail in our accounts.
This will ensure that we have long term storage as well as protection against
anyone trying to manipulate the data within those log files. So let's end here, and I'll see you in the next module.