[Autogenerated] Okay, now you know what spring integration is about,
and it's time we start working with it in practice.
In this module, we're going to start working on the demo application.
It's going to be a Web application where people can
register for the Globomantics Tech conference.
We're going to start with a plain and simple spring boot web application.
I'm first quickly going to show it to you and explain its architecture.
Er,
then we're going to introduce bring integration into this application
to decouple the web player from the surface layer.
You will learn how to use spring integration in the spring project,
and I'll show you different ways to configure spring
integration components using XML configuration,
Jaffa annotations and the spring Integration Domain specific language.
Spring integration provides a number of different message
general implementations that correspond to different
enterprise integration patterns.
We will take a look at what those are and organize them
so that you have a clear overview.
Offspring integration message generals.
You will have a strong foundational knowledge of spring integration, and in the next modules we're going to build on top of that