[Autogenerated] since everything in spring integration is
about messages and message channels,
it's very important to understand the different message colonel implementations
that spring integration provides Let's organize them and get a good overview
off the available message channel implementations.
There are six main message colonel implementations we're going to look at.
There are actually a few other ones,
but these six are the most common and most important ones.
The other one's error really specialized
implementations for less common use cases,
so they are not so interesting.
For now, let's start with what all the message channels have in common.
They all implement interface message channel.
This interface is very simple.
The only methods It defines our to send methods,
one that takes a message and another one that takes
a message and a time out value.
The first distinction that we can make to divide the message channels
into two types is the way that messages are received.
Direct Channel,
Executed channel and published subscribed channel are all subscribe.
Double channels que channel around the View Channel and
Priority Channel are possible channels.
The distinction between subscribe double channels and possible channels
corresponds to to enterprise integration patterns.
These event driven consumer pattern and the polling consumer pattern.
The difference will become more clear if you look at the interfaces.
Subscribe double channel and possible channel,
which both extent interface message channel interface
subscribe double channel AD DS methods to subscribe and
unsubscribe message handlers to a channel.
This is how the event driven consumer pattern works.
To receive messages from a subscribe double channel,
you subscribe a message Chandler that will be called by the messaging
system whenever a message is sent to the channel.
Receiving messages from a possible channel works differently.
Interface.
Possible channel AD DS to receive methods to receive a
message from a possible channel.
You call one of these methods,
which blocks until the message is available or a time out occurs.
This is the polling consumer pattern.
Another way to describe the difference is pushing versus pulling messages.
A subscribe double channel.
Push his messages to the receiver by calling the receiver,
and the message is available versus a possible channel where
the receiver has to pull messages from the channel by
calling a blocking receive method.
Finally,
a difference between these two types of channels is that possible channels
may buffer messages while subscribe double channels do not.
We'll get back to that when we take a closer look at the possible channels. But let's first look at the subscribe A ball channels in more detail.