[Autogenerated] Okay, so let's look at subscribe double channels first.
Subscribe double channels implement the event driven consumer pattern.
They work by pushing messages to receivers, and they don't buffer messages.
The three subscribe double channel implementations can
be further divided into two types.
The difference between these two types is in the way they
dispatch messages to their subscribed message.
Handlers.
Direct Channel and Executed Channel are both unique casting message channels.
While published, Subscribed Channel is a broadcasting message general,
Just like with subscribe double channels and possible channels.
This distinction corresponds to to enterprise integration patterns point
to Point Channel and published Subscribed channel,
Direct channel and Executed channel.
Both delivered the messages that are sent to them to
exactly one subscribed message hander.
This is what makes them point to point Channels
published subscribed channel broadcasts,
messages that are sent to it to all its subscribed message
handlers that makes it correspond to the published subscribed
channel Enterprise integration pattern.
Note that it is possible to subscribe multiple message
handlers to a direct channel or executed channel.
But when a message is sent to either off these channel types,
it will be delivered to only one of the handlers.
Which handler gets the message?
Depends on how you configure the channel.
Finally, I can explain to you what exactly a direct channel is.
It's the simplest possible point to point channel implementation
that's based on the event driven consumer pattern.
The implementation off its sent method is very simple.
The only thing it does is immediately called one of its subscribers.
In the same threat that the scent method was called,
Run the first version of the demo application again make a
registration and pay attention to the logging.
There, you can see the direct channel in action.
In the logging, you see that the registration service comes first,
logging that it has received the message and saved the registration.
After that,
you see the registration controller log in that it has sent a message.
It happens this way because when the controller calls sent on the channel,
the direct channel immediately calls the service
activator to receive the message.
Send and receive all happen on the same threat as
you can also see in the logging.
When the service returns to controller gets to write its log message,
telling you that the message was sent executed channel
is very similar to direct channel.
The difference is that it doesn't call one of its message
Chandler's directly in the same threat, but that it does this by running a task.
And an executable is executed Can, for example,
be a threat pool that you can have multiple threats,
handling messages concurrently and without blocking the sender's threat.
We will get back to publish subscribe messaging later in the course, so we'll save published subscribed channel for when we get there.