[Autogenerated] We now have a nice demo application that can process
registration messages by saving a registration in the database,
sending a confirmation email to the at and and notifying the billing system.
These old works fine as long as nothing goes wrong.
In the real world, however, things do sometimes go wrong.
So our software has to be prepared to deal with errors and unexpected
situations in this module will investigate different error a
scenarios and see how the application reacts.
For example, what happens?
Even error occurs when we are inserting a record in the database or if
the mail server or the building system are unavailable.
Well, look at how we can deal with these situations in different ways.
First,
we will look at how we can have revenue in Q reroute messages
that cannot be processed to with that letter.
Q.
Finally,
we will use spring integrations error handling mechanisms to
get more fine grained control over errors that happened in the
components of our integration flow.
While we're doing this,
you will also learn more about how spring
integration uses threats and transactions.
Let's start by checking out different ways things might go wrong in our demo application