[Autogenerated] all right to get started,
you first needs and background information.
We will set the scene by taking a closer look at what
integration means in this context and by introducing you to
the enterprise integration patterns.
The enterprise integration patterns focus on a synchronous messaging,
so we will also take a look at what exactly that is and why it's useful.
Then I'll give you a first look at spring integration,
and I'll explain what enterprise integration patterns have to do with it.
Many companies have many different software systems and
applications to run their business.
The systems often have to be connected to work with each other on
also to systems outside of the company itself.
Connecting these different systems is what we mean by integration.
Integrating systems is not always easy,
because the systems may have vastly different
interfaces and use different data formats.
Some of the ways in which systems can be connected
together include web services, messaging systems,
exchanging files, fire,
FTP share database is email and even custom
application level networking protocols.
Integration is about connecting systems using these mechanisms and also
about translating data between different formats.
As a software developer, you have undoubtedly heard off design patterns.
Design patterns are general reusable solutions to
common software design problems.
In 2000 and three,
Gregor Hope on Bobby Wolf published a book with the
title Enterprise Integration Patterns,
which describes 65 design patterns that specifically
have to do with integration problems.
Although 2000 and three years long ago in the fast
changing world of software development,
most off the book is still very much relevant in today's
world of micro services and cloud computing that didn't
exist yet when the book was written.
Since spring integration is based on the enterprise integration patterns,
We will look into the main concepts off enterprise
integration patterns in this course.
If you want to know more about enterprise integration patterns,
then you can find detailed information about the book and the patterns on the
books website www dot enterprise integration patterns dot com.
You can, of course, also by the book.
The book focuses on using a synchronous messaging as a
solution for integrating systems.
Let's take a quick look at what that is and how it
differs from other ways to connect systems.
One very common way to let software components communicate
with each other is through web services,
especially RESTful web services over HTTP.
With JSON.
As the common data format are frequently used,
web services work in a synchronous way.
The client sends a request to the server and then waits until the
server has processed it and sends back a response.
However, communication does not always need to be synchronous.
In many cases, it can be Asian.
Chrome is instead, when using an asynchronous messaging system,
the center sends a message and immediately continues processing,
not waiting for a response.
The messaging system will make sure that the message is delivered
to the receiver at some point in the future.
If the response is needed,
a message might be sent back to the original center in the same way.
It's the same as a difference between talking to someone on the
phone and sending someone a text message.
Talking on the phone is synchronous you say something and then wait
for the other person to respond to what you said.
Sending a text messages asynchronous.
You send the message and continue doing other things.
At some point in the future, the other person will read your message,
a synchronous messaging as a number of advantages over
synchronous request response processing.
For example,
the center of a message doesn't have to wait until
receiver sends back a response, which makes systems more responsive.
Messages can be buffered.
For example, in a cube.
This makes it possible for the system to continue working if the receiver is
temporarily unavailable when the receiver is back up again,
it continues to process messages that are waiting for it in the Cube.
This makes systems able to DLL with temporary failures without losing data.
A.
QUE also helps to prevent the receiver being overwhelmed with
requests because the receiver can get messages from the Q and
process them at a rate that is independent off how fast the center
is putting messages onto the cube.
Imagine an online shop, for example, when a customer places an order,
the website needs to inform the warehouse that these ordered
items need to be shipped to the customer.
Suppose that the communication between the website and the warehouse
would happen via a synchronous web service call.
If there is a problem so that the warehouse is temporarily unavailable,
then the customer wouldn't be able to place the order that would be annoying.
It would work better if the communication between the website and the
warehouse woodwork fire a synchronous messaging.
The website sends a message to the warehouse using a messaging system and
immediately informs the customer that their order has been placed.
The messaging system might temporarily store the message
in a Q and deliver it to the warehouse whenever the
warehouses available to process it.
So what exactly is spring integration?
And what does it have to do with enterprise integration
patterns and a synchronous messaging?
Spring Integration is an implementation off the enterprise
integration patterns based on the spring framework,
which enables you to use these enterprise integration
patterns in your own spring based applications.
Since it's part of the spring framework family of projects,
the way you use it in your applications will be familiar.
If you know the spring framework, you will use spring beans,
dependency,
injection aspect oriented programming and other features off the
spring framework to make your application modular,
maintainable and testable,
it will make it easy to connect your business larger components with each
other and with external systems through a synchronous messaging without
the need to write a lot of plumbing code.
Before we dive into the details off working with spring integration,
we will take a closer look at the main concepts and terminology off enterprise integration patterns.