[Autogenerated] in the error scenarios where the email
server or the building services down,
you might have noticed that the registration is still saved in the database,
even though the message is given back to rabid MQ.
This happens because currently,
the transaction boundary for the database transaction is
only around the registration service.
Remember that we had a transactional annotation on the service.
The transaction starts when the register method is called and
commits when the register method returns.
So when an error occurs while sending email or calling the
building service after the registration service,
the database transaction has already committed.
What if we want the database transaction to be committed only
whenever a message has been handled completely,
without errors through the whole flow and rolled back?
Whenever an error occurs anywhere in the flow,
it's possible to make the API inbound channel of
after participate in the transaction,
and since this is the entry point off the flow,
it puts the transaction boundaries around the whole flow.
To make this work,
we have to set two attributes on the AM Cube and Bound channel adapter.
We have to add channel transacted is true and transaction manager
is transaction manager note that the name transaction manager
refers to the default platform transaction manager Bean that
spring Boot has initialized, and that's also used by spring data J P.
A, which he used to access to database.
What happens now when we run this is that these am kubectl
analyze app to will start a transaction,
and when the registration services called it will
participate in the existing transaction,
the transaction now finishes with the commit or roll back after the whole flow.
This means that when the male outbound channel adapter or the HTTP outbound
channel adapter for the building services throws an exception,
the database transaction will be rolled back so that we don't
get records in the database for messages that have not been
completely handled successfully.
A side note.
Transactions in spring are normally threat local.
So this all works because in the whole flow,
we are only using channels that execute and receivers
in the same threat as the center.
As I mentioned in the previous clip,
when I explained where exceptions go that are thrown by a receiver
making the API channel adaptor started transaction was,
however, just the first step.
There are still some problems we have to solve when
an exception occurs in the flow.
The message is still being negatively acknowledged to rabbit MQ
and put back on the queue so that the back and starts trying to
process the message again continually.
In the next clip, we'll see how we can deal with that problem.
Another problem is that not all of the components in the
integration flow participate in the transaction.
The mail server and the building services are not
transactional systems when an error occurs.
While calling the billing system, the email has already been sent,
and that can't easily be undone.
We now have a particularly undesirable situation.
When I run the demo application without the billing
service and enter registration, then the message will continually be retried,
but that each try and email is being sent.
After just a few seconds.
It will have spent these at and with hundreds of confirmation emails. We'll definitely have to do something about that