[Autogenerated] since bring integration is based on
the enterprise integration patterns,
you will have to understand the basic concepts off the enterprise integration
patterns in order to understand and use spring integration.
Let's take a look at the most important concepts and patterns.
The enterprise integration patterns are all about a synchronous messaging,
so the first thing to understand is what exactly a message is.
A message is a unit of data that is transmitted from a center to
one or more receivers via a messaging system.
In the view off enterprise integration patterns,
a message consists off two parts.
The payload and headers.
The payload is these actual content off the message?
This can be any kind of data,
and the meaning of the payload is application specific.
The hand is off.
A message contained metadata,
which can be anything that the messaging system needs
to deliver the message to receiver.
For example, a unique IDE timestamp correlation IDE and return address.
If you know how HTTP works, then this model of a message will look familiar.
And HTTP request a response also consists off headers with metadata
and optionally a body that contains application specific data to get
messages from a center to receiver.
They are transported over a message channel.
A message general is the pipe,
so to speak that gets the message from the center to the receiver.
Note that the enterprise integration patterns are abstract
ideas and not prescriptions about specific implementations
off these ideas in software.
A Message general is these abstract idea off something that
carries messages from a center to receiver.
There are many different ways to implement message generals.
Queues are an example, but a message general is not always a cube.
There are two main types of message channels which are point to
point channels and published subscribe channels.
A point to Point Channel is a message channel that connects
exactly one center with exactly one receiver.
One possible implementation off point to point channels accused Remember
the online shop example that I mentioned earlier there?
A point to Point general in the form of a message queue was
used to have the website send messages to the warehouse to
process orders from customers.
In the next module,
we will get started working with spring integration by first
using point to point message channels.
The other main type of message, General is to publish.
Subscribe General, a published subscribed channel,
is used to broadcast messages from one center to multiple receivers.
One common scenario where you would want to use a published subscribed
channel is to broadcast event notifications to parts off your software
that are interested in particular types of events.
After we've looked at point to point messaging,
we will look at how we can use published subscribe messaging
in our demo application for this course.
When you work with the messaging system,
senders and receivers of messages need to connect to it in some
way to be able to send and receive messages.
A message endpoint is the part of the code off a sender and a
receiver that connects to the messaging system.
This is a very general idea,
and there are more patents that described more specific types off
message endpoints such as general adapters,
gateways and service activators.
I realized that this might sound a bit vague if you're completely new to this,
but don't worry.
It will all become more clear once we start working with
message and points during this course,
and we encounter different kinds of endpoints.
The important thing to remember for now is that the term message
endpoint refers to some piece of code that connects to the messaging
system for sending or receiving messages.
As we will see,
spring integration provides you with many different message and
points in the form off channel adapters and gateways to connect
to many different types of systems.
From message brokers to database is email services, web services and much more.
Another main enterprise integration patterns concept is message transformation.
Different systems often produce and consume data in different formats.
For example, a center might produce messages and JSON format.
While the receiver expects XML,
you'll need a message translator between them to
convert messages from JSON to XML.
Other kinds of message transformers work on the headers
rather than the payload of a message,
or enriched the content of a message with data comment from another source,
such as a database.
The Enterprise Integration Patterns book describes several
specific types off message transformation patterns.
The final concept, I'll mention here is message routing.
There might be situations where the receiver off a message that got
sent to a message colonel is not always fixed.
You might want to decide, for example,
based on a specific header value in the message.
Which receivers should process the message?
A message.
Router is a component in the messaging system that makes such decisions.
The messaging system might even decide to drop a message
altogether on not delivered to any receiver.
A component that makes such decisions is a message filter.
Just like message.
Transformation is really a category off more specific patterns.
There are also more specific message routing patterns.
These are the basics of enterprise integration patterns.
I've introduced you to the main concepts and categories of patterns,
messages, channels, endpoints, transformation and routing off course.
There's a lot more to enterprise integration veterans.
The book has more than 700 pages far too much
information to summarize in a few minutes,
but you now know what it's about, and you'll learn more as we encounter new concepts during this course.