[Autogenerated] when someone registers for the Globomantics that conference.
We want them to receive a confirmation email when
their registration has been saved.
So let's add a listener to the registration event
channel that sends a confirmation email.
You will learn a few new things here, creating a chain off message.
Chandler's using a header and richer and using an
outbound general adapter for sending email.
Let's continue with the code where we left off.
To be able to use the spring integration Outbound channel adapter for email
will first have to add some dependencies to our project.
Support for integrating with different types of systems is
organized in separate libraries in spring integration,
so that you can choose to include exactly those libraries
that you need for your application.
We had already included Spring Integration Am code ping to connect to Rev.
Enum.
Q.
And now we'll add spring integration Male to connect to a mail server.
The Spring Integration Male library also expects us to include
an implementation off the Java male API.
In our project, let's use Jakarta adult male version OneDrive 64-bit,
which is the current version off the reference implementation of
Java mill under Eclipses Jakarta e project,
which is a successor to Oracle's Java E.
Now let's get back to the Spring Integration XML
configuration file and add the necessary components.
First,
we'll add the name Space Declaration for spring Integration
male so that we can use the components that is library
provides in our configuration file.
Our goal is to add an outbound channel adapter that listens to the
registration event channel and that takes a registration event message and
turns it into an email that's sent to the attorney.
Spring integration Male has an outbound channel adapter that we can use
by adding an inter email outbound channel adaptor element to the
configuration on this outbound channel adapter.
You can set a number of attributes we can set the channel attribute
to connected to the registration even general.
There are also attributes to tell it which mail server to send email to.
For now, let's set these attributes to local host Port 30 25 username,
Globomantics and password Globomantics URL.
We'll come back to these shootings later,
just adding the outbound channel that after like this is not enough.
It's going to receive registration event objects from
the registration event channel,
but the general adapter doesn't know by itself how to create an
email out over registration event object.
So we'll have to add some components between the channel
and the outbound channel adapter to transform registration
event messages into emails.
Let's add a transformer that listens to the registration event Cannell and
that transforms registration event objects into emails.
We'll pass the output off the transformer to the album channel adapter,
just like the service activator.
That transformer has a ref,
and method attributes that point to a method in the spring
Bean that dusty actual transformation.
I've added a class confirmation mail transformer
with a method named to mail text,
which takes a registration event object and returns a string containing
the body of the email that we want to send before we continue with
connecting the output off the transformer to the outbound channel that
after let's talk about message handler, change with what you've learned so far.
What you would probably do to connect the transformer to the
outbound channel adaptor is defined another channel.
That's the output for the transformer and the input for
the channel adapter that would work.
But you can imagine that if you have a more complicated
application with lots of components.
You would also have to define lots of channels to connect all these components.
To avoid having to define so many channels.
You can define a chain a chain groups message Chandler's
together that will be called in sequence just as.
If you would have defined direct channels between the message
Chandler's Let's Put the Transformer and the outbound channel
adaptor together in a chain, we'll add an inch chain element.
Let's give it an ID Confirmation email chain.
We'll move the transformer and the channel adapter into the chain.
Instead of having the handlers in the chain listen to a channel directly.
We'll make the chain listen to the Registration event channel.
We can remove the input channel and channel attributes from
the transformer and the channel adapter.
The chain will pass messages it receives to the first handler and pass the
output off each handler automatically to the next one.
So in this case,
it will send registration event messages to the transformer and the
output off the transformer to the channel adapter.
Using a chain is useful if you have a sequence off message Chandler's that
are related and always have to run in the same order.
It helps you to organize your configuration file and not have to
explicitly defined channels to connect up all the handlers.
There's one thing that's still missing here.
The transformer creates the body off the email from a registration event object.
But we also have to tell the channel adaptor the email address to send
the email to and the subject line off the email.
The outbound channel adapter can get this information from the
headers off the messages that it receives.
We'll add another component to the chain,
a header and richer spring integration.
Male has a header and richer component that we can use to set message
handers that these outbound channel adaptor understands.
Real set three message headers.
First the from header with the email address of the center of the email,
then the to header.
We want to get the value for this header from the registration event object.
We'll use the expression attribute to get this in this expression.
The keyword payload refers to the payload off the message we're working with,
which is in this case, a registration event object.
So payload to .NET and email gets S3 email address off the
attendee that we want to send the email to.
Finally, the subject header sets the subject line for the email.
Now we're ready.
We have a published subscribed channel with so far a single receiver,
which is the confirmation email chain.
The chain contains three message handlers that set the hands of the message,
transformed the payload into text and send the email to run this,
you'll need to have a mail server.
If you have a meal server that you can use,
then you can, of course, at the host port.
Username and password on the outbound channel adapter to use that meal server.
If you don't have a meal server,
then you can run green meal in a docker container.
Greenmail is a very small and simple mail server
that's meant for testing purposes, which is perfect for us.
Here.
You can start it with a command like this.
It will you support 30 25 for outgoing mail using
SMTP and Port 31 43 for I'm app.
With greenmail running,
you can now run the front and then the back end off the demo application
and under a registration after the registration is saved.
A registration event message is sent to the registration event
channel on a confirmation email will be sent.
If you want.
You can configure an email client to receive the email from greenmail
by pointing it to local host Port 31 43 using IMAP.
Another way to read the email that's being delivered in
Green Mail is by using the curl command.
With the following command,
we can check how many messages there are in the in box.
The output also tells you the IDE off the 1st 100 email.
You can read an email with the following command,
where the number after UI IDE is the idea of the email
that you want to read off course.
The point off published subscribe messaging is that multiple receivers
received the messages sent to about the subscribed channel. Let's add another listener to the channel.