[Autogenerated] Let's take a few minutes to understand what you should
already know to get the most out of this course and what other courses you
might want to follow before and after this course.
These courses meant for Java developers who are already
familiar with the spring framework.
If you haven't used to spring framework before,
or if you are brand new to programming in Java,
then I recommend that you follow other Java and spring framework.
Fundamental scores is first.
You should be familiar with the core concepts of the spring framework,
such as inversion off control and dependency,
injection spring beans and configuring them using XML and annotations some
other spring projects that will use besides spring integration,
our Spring web, MVC, spring data, JPA A and spring boot.
It will help if you haven't least basic knowledge about these spring projects.
There are many excellent courses about Java and spring available on Pluralsight.
Just search for them in the Pluralsight up or on the website,
and you'll find them.
This course is meant to be your first course about spring
integration and enterprise integration patterns.
It will be the first in a series.
Off course is organized in the spring integration learning path.
At the moment I'm creating this course.
Other authors and I are busy creating these learning path.
So more courses that will go deeper into specific spring integration topics
will be available soon on Pluralsight or they already are.
Depending on when you're viewing this, these will be great to follow after this getting started course.