[Autogenerated] we've now completely decoupled the front
end and back and using rather than queue.
As a consequence of this,
we no longer have to have both the front and on the back and running.
To be able to enter and process at and registrations there is another advantage.
2D Isha's well, we can now also skill the front and then back and independently.
For example,
we can have multiple instances off the back and running to process
registrations as the last demo in this model,
let's see how we can have one instance off the front and
running and two instances off the back end.
Let's take a look at the next example project in the back and application.
We're using an embedded in memory H two database.
This means that the database is running inside the back and
application itself and doesn't store registrations on disk,
but only in memory.
When we stop the back and application,
the database and all the data it contains disappear.
Now we want to be able to run multiple instances off the back and application,
and we want them to use the same database,
so we're going to change the database configuration off the back end
to make it work with an H two database running in a separate process
to make it easy to run the database.
Separately,
I've created a small and simple Docker image and
made it available on Docker hop.
There seems to be no official Docker image for the H two database,
so I've made one myself with the following command.
You can start H two in a docker container.
The H two console will be available on local host Port 80 82.
Now there are two things we have to do in the back and application
first Editor Spring Bootstrap Application Properties to make it
access the age to database running in Docker instead of creating an
embedded in memory database.
Second is to remove the scheme adult SQL and data dot SQL files from the source.
Main Resource is directory because we don't want the back
and application to try and create a schema and insert data
every time when it starts up,
we do have to make sure to run the SQL commands in these two files once on
the H two database running in Docker so that the schema axis and the data
is inserted Let's now in one terminal windows.
Start up the front and application using maven minus B l web
Spring boot run and then starts to instances off the back and
application using maven minus PLC services.
Spring boot Ron in two other terminal windows, both off these instances.
Off the back and application will connect to Rebel
MQ and listen to the same cube.
Since the Q does point to point messaging whenever the
front and sends a message to Rick, you rabble,
MQ is going to deliver it to only one of the
instances off the back and application.
Enter some registrations in the web application.
Look at the logging off both instances off the back end,
you will see that sometimes number one processes the registration,
and sometimes number two used the H two console on local
host sport 80 82 to see that both instances are saving
registrations in the same database.
As you can see,
it's now easy to run multiple instances off the back and application to process registrations