Hi.
My name is Danny Jessee, and I would like to welcome you to this course,
Securing Data and Secrets on AWS.
You can reach me on Twitter @dannyjessee. If you're watching this course,
you've probably worked with AWS for a while,
perhaps even in a role focused specifically on cloud security.
Maybe you're getting ready to take the AWS Certified Security Specialty exam.
If so,
I'm here to prepare you to answer the types of questions that may be
asked from the data protection domain of the exam.
And if you aren't currently preparing to take the exam, that's okay too.
We're going to cover best practices for encryption, key
management, and securing information on AWS with an emphasis on
how security engineers use these tools and services in their
day‑to‑day work to protect sensitive data.
So without further ado, let's get started by talking about encryption.
Now I'm sure you already know a thing or two about encryption. In short,
when we have data that we want to secure so that the only people who can see
it are the ones we explicitly allow, we need to encrypt that data.
Encryption uses keys and algorithms to encode usable,
readable data into a form that is neither, making it useless to anyone
who doesn't have access to the key to unlock it.
This is obviously of the utmost importance in a cloud
environment when data isn't living on physical servers
under our control in our data center.
And even if it was,
you would still want to encrypt your data to keep it from falling into the
wrong hands or being intercepted across the network.
The good news is that AWS has designed its tools and services from the
ground up to leverage encryption. And you may be working in an environment
where there are security compliance rules that dictate that you must use a
certain encryption algorithm or provide your own security keys or even
store your keys in a physical tamperproof hardware module, things like
that. Of course, AWS can support all of this too,
and we'll discuss these various options as we go through this module.
But before we go too far,
I want to draw an important distinction that might come up on the exam.
That's the difference between encryption in transit and encryption at rest.
When you see encryption in transit, think in transit over the
network, so using SSL and TLS. To be fully secure,
we are going to want to encrypt the data we're sending up to AWS.
So in the context of S3,
we can enforce this by using a bucket policy that forces secure transport.
And that policy is literally this simple, deny access when any S3
action takes place and AWS secure transport is false.
So now if someone tries to put data in S3 over a non‑secure
connection, so using HTTP instead of an HTTPS endpoint,
that action will be denied.
That's how to enforce encryption in transit.
Everything else we are going to discuss in this module involves
encryption at rest or how we support encrypting data once it's
already in the cloud, whether it's physically stored in S3 or on an EBS volume or in a Redshift cluster, things like that