The AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store,
which you'll sometimes see referred to as the SSM Parameter Store
(and SSM stands for Simple Systems Manager,
that's an old name for the AWS Systems Manager,
but the acronym still lives on),
offers a centralized place to store and manage your secrets.
So instead of hardcoding your parameter value,
your application will call Parameter Store to get that value instead.
And it's important to note that Parameter Store is just one
small offering within AWS Systems Manager,
which handles all sorts of things beyond the scope of this
course but also includes things like inventory,
compliance, patch management, and many other things.
But we're going to focus on Parameter Store in this course.
It's free, and you can store up to 10,000 secrets per region,
each one up to 4 KB in size within its standard tier.
There is also an advanced tier that scales up to
100,000 secrets up to 8 KB each.
But there is a per‑parameter cost associated with that.
Access to Parameter Store is controlled through IAM.
So it's important that you configure the proper IAM roles
within your account for EC2 or Lambda, for instance,
depending on where your application is running so that you
will be able to access these parameters.
Parameter Store allows you to store secrets as
plaintext strings or lists of strings,
and these are good for secrets that you don't want to store in your
code but maybe aren't too sensitive in nature.
But for more sensitive secrets,
so maybe for something like a privileged account password or something
that requires an additional layer of protection,
we can use something called a SecureString parameter.
And SecureString parameters are actually encrypted using keys managed in KMS,
which you'll recall we talked about in the last module,
so you can actually use a key policy, in addition to IAM roles,
to further restrict access to the secret.
In other words,
I might have an IAM policy that allows me access to Parameter Store.
But if I don't have access via the key policy to the KMS
key used to encrypt that parameter, I won't be able to decrypt it,
and this is useful if perhaps you have a compliance requirement
that dictates your secrets need to be encrypted,
in addition to having restricted access.
Now let's see Parameter Store in action.
In this demo,
we will store our connection string secret in the AWS
Systems Manager Parameter Store.
First, we'll store it as a String parameter,
and then we'll use a KMS key to encrypt it and store
it as a SecureString parameter.
So I'll start by going to SSM, and here I'll choose Systems Manager,
and under Application Management, I'll select Parameter Store.
And to create my parameter, I'll click Create parameter.
And this is a very simple interface here.
So I enter a name for my parameter.
And remember that these names are meant to be in a hierarchy,
so like a URL or a folder structure.
So, for instance, I might have a dev path and test and production paths,
things like that.
But for this example, I'll just enter /dev/dbconnectionstring.
Now I could enter a description here, and you see,
I have the choice between standard, which is the free tier,
and advanced, so if I needed more than 10,000 parameters or up to 8 KB in size.
But keep in mind, there is a cost for these,
so I'm going to leave this as standard.
For this example, I'm going to leave this as String.
We'll see how SecureStrings work in just a second here.
And I'll come down here for the value and paste in my
connection string example from my code.
I'll click Create parameter, and that's it.
So here's my parameter, but let's go into the command line interface,
or CLI, and see how we can retrieve this value.
So I'm doing this from a PowerShell window with the CLI here.
But you could perform similar operations with the
AWS SDK in your Java code or .NET, Ruby,
Go, Python, really,
just about any language is supported to do this from your application.
So the command line operation is aws ssm get‑parameter
with the name of our parameter here.
And now you see here's the type and the value and the version.
So keep in mind, these parameters are versioned as well.
So now, instead of hardcoding this value in my application,
I've stored it in Parameter Store and can update and
maintain it separately from my code.
But it still isn't encrypted.
So what if I had a requirement to encrypt all of my parameters?
Well, that's what the SecureString parameter type is for.
So let's hop back over to the console,
and we will create a SecureString parameter to hold this value.
Now you might think that you could just drill in here and click
Edit and be able to change the parameter type.
But as you can see, I'm not able to change it here.
So we'll need to create a new parameter instead.
So I'll come back here, and I'll click Create parameter again.
And this time I'll call my parameter /dev/dbconnectionstringsecure,
and this time I'll make it a SecureString parameter.
So when I choose this,
now you see it's prompting me to choose the source for the KMS
key that will be used to encrypt this value.
So I can choose my account or another account.
But within my account here, you see the default AWS key for SSM.
And if I click this, you'll also see the keys we created in the last module.
So I'll just go ahead and choose mycmk and paste in my
value here and click Create parameter.
So here are both of my parameters now.
And now I'll go back into the CLI,
and this time I'll call ssm get‑parameter again and change
the name to cbconnectionstringsecure.
And you'll see the value here.
But, wait, this isn't the value I entered.
But that's because this value is encrypted.
So how do I get the decrypted value?
Well, assuming I have access to the KMS key that was used to encrypt the value,
which in this case I do,
I can call this same command but add a ‑‑with‑decryption switch here,
and here you'll see the decrypted value.
But you see how this can add a layer of security because not only did I
need the IAM permissions to access Parameter Store,
but in this case I also needed access to the KMS key in
order to decrypt the string value. So that is Parameter Store.