In this demo,
we will enable Amazon Macie in our account, view the information it
collects as it analyzes the S3 buckets in our account, and configure
a data discovery job that uses a regular expression to match a
custom text pattern when scanning objects stored in S3. Here we are
in the S3 console,
and I just want to quickly show you that I've
created a couple of new S3 buckets.
One is called myawscoursepublicwritablebucket,
which, as the name implies,
has public access and is writable. So that would
obviously be a problem in the real world.
And the second one is called awscoursefakepiibucket.
And inside that bucket, I've uploaded some files that contained fake PII,
including data in a FakeEmployeeID field.
And I'll show you how we can configure something like an
employee ID number as a custom identifier when we create the
job that tells Macie to scan this bucket.
But keep in mind that Macie will always be scanning for other PII such
as Social Security numbers and credit card numbers. And keep in mind
that having publicly‑writable S3 buckets or even objects containing PII
in S3 wouldn't necessarily mean that something was being done
maliciously, but it's definitely something you would want to know about
as soon as possible.
So what I'm going to do first is enable Macie in my account, and that will
examine the configurations of all the S3 buckets in my account and start
assessing my overall security at the bucket level.
So to get started, I'll go here to Macie,
and then I'll come over here and click Get started.
And you see here on this screen,
Macie is telling me I will be giving it permission to discover,
classify, and protect my data,
as well as to generate alerts about potential security issues.
So I'll click Enable Macie,
and you'll see that doing that takes me to a page that gives me a quick,
high‑level assessment of all the S3 buckets in my account.
So you see, it's giving me a count of my publicly‑accessible buckets,
my unencrypted buckets, and my shared buckets.
Now you may have noticed earlier that I have four S3 buckets in
my account, but it's only showing three here,
and that's because we're filtered to the Northern Virginia US East‑1 region.
As you'll recall,
that fourth bucket was used for replication to the US West‑1 region.
So this is useful just to get a snapshot of my overall
security posture within S3, but keep in mind,
this has not yet actually scanned any of the data in the objects I have in S3.
In order to do that, I'll need to configure what's called a job.
But before we do that,
I want to create a custom data identifier for my employee ID numbers
because maybe to my organization that's considered sensitive
information, but I don't want to have an S3.
So here, under Settings,
I'll go to Custom data identifiers, and I'll click Create. And here,
I'll give my data identifier a name and a description.
So I'll say Employee ID, and then I have to specify the regular expression.
So let's say my Employees IDs always start with the letters EID,
then a dash, and then five numeric digits.
So here I can say EID‑. and then \d to represent a numeric digit, then a
in curly braces will signify five of those digits.
And if you want to learn more about regular
expressions and how to construct them,
because you can definitely get much more advanced than this,
I encourage you to search Pluralsight's library because there are some
great courses that cover regular expressions in a lot more detail, but
this is good enough for our purposes. And over here, you see you can test
your regular expression, so I can enter EID‑12345 and see that it does
match my regular expression.
But if I take away the fifth digit here, now it doesn't. And it's
worth showing that adding an extra digit on the end would still match
my regular expression as I have it now, but this is certainly good
enough for demonstration purposes,
so I'll go ahead and scroll down here, and here you see that I can also
add keywords to match or even words to ignore to determine whether or not
a match is something I actually care about.
So maybe I'm only concerned about employee IDs if they appear in the same
paragraph as the word payroll or action or something like that,
in which case I could put those keywords here and specify a maximum
distance to still count this as a match with my identifier.
So I'll click Submit, and that will go ahead and create my identifier.
And now that I've done that, I can go ahead and create my job.
So I'll come over here to Jobs and click this link
to select buckets to evaluate,
and I'll go ahead and choose my fakepiibucket and click Create job.
So I'll say Next here, and here I can specify whether I want to run
this job on a schedule so that could be daily,
weekly, or monthly or if I just want to run this job one time.
So I'll choose One‑time job for this demo and leave the
sampling depth at 100% to make sure it scans all the items in
the bucket and not just a subset of them.
And I'll include my Employee ID identifier,
so I want to know if that identifier with all the parameters I specified
earlier appears in any objects in this S3 bucket, and click Next.
Now I'll give my job a name, and then on this summary screen,
I'll click Submit, and now that job is running.
And even for a small bucket, it might take a while to complete,
so I'll come back later and refresh the screen.
So here we go.
The job is now complete.
And if I go up here under Show results and click Show findings, here we see
we have a couple of high‑severity findings, and you can see in one case the
Finding type is Financial, and for my Employee ID document, there are
multiple findings. So I can click the finding here, and over on the right
you'll see more information.
So in this file, for instance, i't found eight credit card numbers.
And if I come back over here and click my other file,
you see Macie found 17 Credit card numbers, 28 Addresses,
32 Names, and if I scroll up a little bit under Custom data identifiers,
we see it found 236 matches for Employees ids.
So now we've enabled Macie in our account and seen how we can
configure custom data identifiers and jobs.
But I still have to drill in here through the console to see the findings. So let's talk about how we could automate this process a little more.