So there's one simple thing you can do to increase the
security of items stored in your S3 buckets,
and that's to turn on default encryption for the bucket.
And I'll show you in the upcoming demo,
it's one little radio button to set the default encryption at
rest for new items uploaded to the bucket,
and you can enable or disable this at any time.
Now it won't retroactively encrypt any data that's already in the bucket,
but it will automatically encrypt anything you upload to the
bucket from that point forward after you enable it.
And you can do this default encryption with either an AWS S3 managed key,
which is referred to as SSE for server‑side encryption,
S3, or a key you manage yourself within the AWS Key Management Service,
or SSE‑KMS, which we'll talk about later in this module.
Beyond these two encryption options that you get with
default encryption SSE‑S3 and SSE‑KMS,
there are a couple of other ways you could encrypt data at rest in S3.
One is to use server‑side encryption with customer‑provided keys or SSE‑C,
and the other is client‑side encryption.
And there's an important distinction here between SSE‑KMS and SSE‑C.
With SSE‑C, you, the customer, are still managing the key yourself,
but completely outside of AWS.
So this is useful if you already have keys that you're using outside of AWS.
Or maybe there are compliance requirements that prevent
you from storing your keys in AWS.
When you use SSE‑C,
you have to provide your key in the request header every time you upload or
download an object because that key isn't stored in AWS at all.
But AWS still needs the key in order to encrypt or decrypt the data on its end.
And this is important.
Keep in mind that AWS is still doing the encryption and
decryption operations with your key.
It just isn't storing the key anywhere.
With client‑side encryption,
and you'll notice it doesn't have an SSE acronym because the
encryption doesn't happen server side.
Instead,
you manage your own keys and encrypt the data
yourself before you upload it into S3.
Similarly,
this means that you also decrypt the data yourself
after you download it from S3.
With client‑side encryption, AWS never knows anything about the key
or the encryption algorithm you choose because you are performing
your own encryption and decryption.
So there may be some instances where security policy dictates
that you do client‑side encryption so that AWS can't see your key at all or something like that.