Obviously, S3 isn't the only place we can store data in AWS,
and S3 is a little unique because you can enable default encryption or change
the encryption of an individual object anytime you'd like.
But that isn't how most AWS services handle encryption.
In this demo, we'll see the different S3 encryption options in action,
but we'll also see that most other AWS services require you to
enable encryption at the time a resource is created.
This goes for EBS volumes andy EFS file systems,
as well as DynamoDB tables and Redshift clusters.
I'll hop onto the AWS console now to show you what I mean.
Here we are in the console.
I'll start by going to S3,
and you'll see I don't have any S3 buckets created yet.
So I'll go ahead and create one.
I'll give it the name myawssecuritycoursebucket and then
scroll down to click Create Bucket.
Now that I've created the bucket, I get this message.
And I could click this link up top,
but let me show you where you can always go to set this property.
I'll click the bucket name, and up here I will click Properties.
And if I scroll down here,
you'll see that default encryption is currently disabled.
So to change that, I'll click the box here,
and you'll see the options for default encryption are none,
which is the current selection.
Or I can choose AES‑256 or AWS‑KMS.
So you see, these are the SSE‑ S3 and SSE‑KMS options we talked about earlier.
So I can choose SSE‑S3.
Or if I choose SSE‑KMS, you'll see I have the option of selecting a key.
We'll create some keys later on in this module.
But for now, you see the only option is the default AWS S3 key,
or I could enter the ARN of another key.
But for this demo, I'm just going to select SSE‑S3 and click Save.
And you see now it says AES‑256 is the default encryption for this bucket.
Now if I go back to my bucket,
I want to add a new item and show you a little quirk of the S3 console UI.
I'm going to go into my bucket here and click Upload,
and then I'm just going to browse to a random file here.
And if I click Next, I'm going to see the permissions for the object,
and Next will show me the storage class for the object.
But the final screen will show me the encryption for this object,
and here you'll see that it says no for encryption.
And although this is telling us we haven't chosen to apply
any encryption specifically to this object,
it does not show us that, in fact,
the default encryption setting will apply to this file.
So I'll click Upload here and select my file,
and you'll see under Properties that yes,
in fact, this file does have AES‑256 encryption applied to it.
So that's default encryption.
And we can turn on and off default encryption at the bucket level or
change the key we use to encrypt or any other options related to
encryption at any time whenever we need to.
So that's S3.
And now I'll quickly show you some encryption options for other AWS services.
So if I go to EC2, I can show you the create experience for a new EBS volume.
So if I come down here and I click Create Volume,
here on the first screen, you'll see a checkbox for encryption.
And if I check that box and hit the dropdown,
you'll see the default option here is the aws/ebs key,
which is an AWS managed key.
When you create your own keys, as we will do later in this module,
you'll see those keys appear as options here as well.
Also note some important information here regarding the
encryption status of new EBS volumes based on encrypted
versus unencrypted snapshots.
What this is basically saying is if you're creating a new
EBS volume from an existing snapshot,
it will inherit the encryption status of that snapshot.
If you're creating a new volume, you can decide whether or not to encrypt it.
But you have to make this decision at the time you create the volume.
You can only change it down the road by creating a new snapshot and
then creating a new volume based on that snapshot.
And now I'll show you the create experience for a new EFS file system.
So If I go to EFS and then click Create file system,
I can go to the next step here and scroll down.
And you'll see again, I have the option to enable encryption of data at rest.
And there is an important note you see here,
encryption of data at rest can only be enabled during file system creation.
But encryption of data in transit is configured when
mounting the file system from an EC2 instance.
So keep in mind that there is not just encryption at rest,
but also encryption in transit here with EFS with data going across
the network to be stored on the network file system.
And again, if I check the box here, just like with EBS,
I can choose which KMS master key to use.
And if I had my own keys, they would appear in this list here.
Or I can enter the ARN of a key to use from another account.
Now a couple of other services we'll look at quickly here,
starting with DynamoDB.
When I go to create a new DynamoDB table,
you'll see the settings include encryption at rest enabled by default.
If I uncheck this quickly,
you'll see I can also choose encryption with KMS using a
customer‑managed CMK or an AWS‑managed CMK.
So I don't have any customer‑managed keys here yet,
but I can choose to use the AWS Managed DynamoDB key here.
And as a final example, we'll take a look at Redshift.
So when I create a new Redshift cluster,
if I scroll down here and turn off the default configuration,
I can scroll down to Database configurations. And here you'll
see similar options, so use an AWS KMS key,
which could be the default AWS‑managed Redshift key or a CMK you manage
from this account or from another account. And you'll see also here a
hardware security module or HSM option,
which I'll discuss more at the end of this module.
So that's a quick tour around several AWS services
and how they manage encryption.
But the point I want to drive home is that with the exception of S3,
you generally have to configure encryption at rest at
the time you're creating the resource.
So whether that's an EBS volume, an EFS file system,
DynamoDB table, Redshift cluster, etc.
Now during the course of this demo, we saw KMS come up several times, so let's talk a little bit more about KMS.