And with that, we've made it to the end of this course.
So let's quickly recap what we've learned.
We started with a discussion about encryption.
We learned about encryption in transit,
encryption at rest, envelope encryption, and how encryption is deeply
integrated with almost every service in AWS. We learned about keys
and saw the AWS Key Management Service, or KMS,
where we created customer master keys, or CMKs,
which can be used to encrypt and decrypt data in AWS. We learned how to
securely store sensitive parameters and secrets in AWS,
either in Parameter Store or AWS Secrets Manager.
We then learned about replicating data across AWS regions,
whether via cross‑region replication, or CRR, in S3,
or copying snapshots from EBS and RDS,
as well as how we can use this process to enable encryption on a
resource that was not initially created with it.
And finally, we wrapped up with an overview of Amazon Macie and saw how
it uses machine learning to classify and protect data stored in S3.
Thank you so much for watching this course.
I hope you found it valuable.
And if you're planning to take the AWS Certified Security ‑
Specialty exam, I wish you the very best.
Please feel free to ask questions or leave any feedback you
may have on the discussion board for this course, or reach
out to me on Twitter @dannyjessee.
And be sure to check out the other courses in
Pluralsight's ever‑growing catalog of AWS content. Thanks again, and have a great day.