So let's talk a little more about KMS in depth, starting with key rotation.
Key rotation is what happens when we update a key's backing material,
and AWS saves the old key material so you will always be able to decrypt
information that was previously encrypted with an old backing key.
Now for the standard AWS managed keys, and these are,
of course, the default keys you see for each service in each region,
the key material is automatically rotated every three years.
You can't change or disable this,
and this rotation happens in a way that is completely transparent to you,
and when a key is automatically rotated,
you don't actually need to update any references to keys in your application,
because it's only the keys backing material that has changed,
not its ID or alias.
For a customer‑managed CMK with AWS‑generated key material,
the key material can optionally be rotated automatically every year,
but you must enable this yourself.
So notice this is every one year, and not every three years,
like the AWS‑managed keys.
But for a customer‑managed CMK with imported key material,
there is no automatic rotation option at all,
you must manually rotate the key material yourself,
which involves creating a new CMK,
importing the new material, and updating the existing
key's alias to point to this new CMK.
I'll talk about the process for doing this in the demo.
Now there is one advantage to importing your own key material,
which is that you have total control over the key rotation
schedule when you have AWS‑generated key material.
So that's both for the AWS‑managed and customer‑managed
CMKs with AWS‑generated key material.
The three and one year rotation schedules for these
are fixed and cannot be changed, but with imported key material,
you could rotate it every six months, or every month, or
whatever is required in your environment.
Let's hop over to the KMS console and I'll show you what I'm talking about.
In this demo, I'll show you how to create new customer master keys.
I'll create a CMK with AWS‑generated key material, then I'll create
another key and discuss how to import your own key material.
Now here we are in the console.
I'll go to kms, and you see I don't have any keys yet,
so I'll go over here and click Create key. By default, keys you
create in KMS are what are called symmetric keys.
These keys never leave AWS unencrypted, which is obviously a best practice.
Now you could choose asymmetric here,
but I'll leave this as symmetric, and then show you the advanced options here,
which is where I choose between KMS for the key material origin,
which is AWS‑managed key material, or external,
which means I would import my own key material.
You see CloudHSM is also an option here,
and we'll discuss that a little bit later on in
this module, but for this example, I'll choose KMS and click Next.
Now here's where I give the key and alias,
so I'll call this mycmk, and I won't worry about any tags for now.
Now here on the next screen is where we set up the elements of the key
policy, which we'll discuss more in a bit, but here we can choose key
administrators, so the users and roles who can administer the key, and
I'll choose my awscourse account for now, and we'll grant that account
permissions to delete the key as well; and this permission is an
important one, because deleting a key is usually not a good idea, and in fact,
if you do attempt to delete a key, you can't just delete it right away.
AWS will force you to choose a waiting period between
seven and 30 days before the key is actually deleted, and
there's good reason for this.
If you delete a key and let's say there's an EBS volume out there or
something else that's using that key for encryption,
you're going to need to copy the data off of that
volume while it's still attached, or you won't have access to it anymore,
and I'll click Next, and now we can choose the users and roles who have
permission to actually use this key to encrypt and decrypt data.
So again,
I'll choose my awscourse account, and you'll see here, I could actually
add another AWS account here for cross account access.
Now I'll click Next, and here's the default key policy.
We won't go through this right now, we'll talk through it
in more detail later in this module, and now quickly here,
I'll just show you how we could create a CMK with imported key material.
So we'll click Create key again, we'll choose symmetric, and this
time under Advanced options. we'll choose external for our key
material origin, and before I proceed,
I have to acknowledge that I understand the security availability
and durability implications associated with this.
So I'll click Next, and again I have to give my key an alias,
so I'll call this one myimportedmaterialkey, and click Next.
I'll choose the same key administrator and key usage permissions, and so
here is our key policy, and now when I click Finish,
you'll see that I'm being prompted to download a wrapping key and import token.
So the actual process here is beyond the scope of the exam.
But what you would do here is click download,
and once you've saved this file,
you basically have 24 hours to use the wrapping key to encrypt your
own key material, and you could use something like OpenSSL to do this
encryption, but then you come back here and you upload the file
containing your wrapped key material,
as well as the import token from the file you originally downloaded.
Then you click upload key material, and now you have a CMK
with imported key material, and keep in mind that if you
wanted to rotate this key,
you would create a new CMK, import your new key material using the same process,
and then update the alias to point to this new CMK, and that's how we create new customer master keys in KMS.