I want to wrap up our discussion of KMS by looking at key
policies and grants in a little more detail.
It's important for the exam that you be able to look at the JSON
document for a key policy and be able to read it,
interpret it, and understand exactly what it is doing.
When we created our CMK earlier in this module,
we got to select which users and roles were key administrators,
as well as the users, roles,
and AWS accounts that have access to use the key for encryption and decryption.
And all of these selections were reflected in the default
key policy that was created for the key.
So let's look at this key policy a little more in depth,
and then we'll look at a few other key policies and walk through how
they are structured and exactly what they're doing.
So here again is the default key policy.
And as you can see, it's a JSON document that consists of an array of statements.
And to make these a little easier to go through,
I've broken them down into separate tabs that we'll
look at in this text editor together.
And when we decipher these policies, we want to look at three things,
the effect, the action, and the resource.
So this first one here says Enable IAM User Permissions.
And what it's doing is allowing, so that's the effect,
the action of all operations within KMS,
so that's the asterisk there, on all resources,
so again you see the asterisk.
And this applies to the root account within our AWS
account with this number here.
So this statement gives the root account full access to this key,
which is important because no matter what else we do with permissions here,
we will always have the ability to use our root account to get access to this
key and then use IAM policies to grant access to other users,
roles, and accounts to be able to also access this key.
And although it looks like this statement is only
allowing access to the root account,
it does also mean that other IAM users and roles in the account might have
access to the CMK even though they don't show up directly here.
Now this next statement is granting administrative
access to our AWS course account, and you see again the effect of allow,
the action of this list of administrative operations within KMS,
so things like create, update, revoke, disable,
and the asterisk here again denoting all resources.
The next statement is for the key usage permissions where
again we just chose the AWS course account.
But here again, the effect is allow.
The list of actions this time are just the actions of actually
using the key to encrypt and decrypt data and,
importantly, to generate data keys as well.
And as you'll remember,
generating data keys here is the basis of envelope
encryption like we discussed earlier.
And again, this applies to all resources.
Now here's how instead of a user being specified as a principal,
we can actually give these permissions to any user
with the IAM role awscourserole.
So this could apply to any user who has this role.
And IAM best practice is always to use roles whenever possible.
So this is a good example of doing that.
And in this example, we're allowing access to a user,
a role, and another AWS account.
Now we have this statement allowing attachment of persistent resources.
So what we mean by that is the ability to create and revoke grants,
which allow you to programmatically allow access to
your CMK to other principles.
So in this case again, the effect is allow,
the list of actions this time is creating,
listing,
and revoking grants on all resources with the condition that the
grant is for an AWS resource that uses grants.
So notice this condition here.
It's pretty straightforward to read and understand what this is saying,
but just know that you can always attach conditions to these policies.
Just like we used a condition in the S3 bucket policy
to enforce encryption in transit,
we can always use conditions in conjunction with our policies.
So grants are especially useful when you need to
grant temporary access to a CMK,
and this is usually done programmatically in code.
You can just call CreateGrant, specify the CMK,
the principal to which you are granting access and the
allowed operation or set of operations.
And when you're done, you can call RevokeGrant, and the access goes away.
And finally, when it comes to allowing access to AWS services,
we can actually be even more granular than what we've seen so far using
what's called a KMS via service condition to evaluate requests coming
via a specific AWS service or services.
So here you see an example where the effect is deny,
so notice we can allow or deny access in a policy document.
And in this case, we are denying access to my AWS course user,
but only when the request attempts to use my CMK to perform an
encrypt operation via the EC2 service and,
even more specifically, only in the us‑east‑1 region.
So hopefully these examples have gotten you a little more
comfortable reading and interpreting key policies.
Remember to always look for the effect, the action, and the resource.
Then determine if there any conditions tied to the statement that use via
service to restrict access to a specific service and region.
You'll need to do this on the exam,
and the JSON can look a little complicated at first.
But if you break it down,
I'm confident that you'll be able to answer any questions about key policies and grants with ease.