Process, process, process, don't leave home without it.
If you haven't guessed it yet, I'm a process guy.
Remember from the first module, I mentioned I work for an aerospace company,
well jets do not take off unless you follow a process.
I hope on your next flight when the jet takes off,
you remember my course and thank the people that followed a good process.
Okay, now here are a couple definitions.
I keep using the word process, but let's make sure we all know what it is.
A process is a series of actions or steps taken in
order to achieve a particular end.
You will have several processes that are required to run your team.
Now let's extend that definition to a business process.
These are designed to add value for the customer and
should not include unnecessary activities.
So what is the outcome of a good process?
Let's see.
The outcomes of a well designed business process is increased effectiveness,
that's value for the customer, and increased efficiency,
less use of resources, money, time, et cetera.
So keep this in mind when you are designing and using your processes.
You want the results of those processes to increase effectiveness and increase the efficiencies.