In this section I have outlined several processes that I believe you
will likely need to jump start your team's activities.
Maybe you only need some of these and maybe you need
others that are not listed herein.
No worries, do what you have to do.
I have given you a template approach in the previous
section on how to manage your processes.
Okay, let's see what they are.
Okay here are 10 key processes to jumpstart your team.
Don't forget about the other four I mentioned at the beginning of this
module that relate to the four other module topics.
Okay the first is work intake, requirements analysis,
estimation, design and architecture, construction,
user acceptance testing, promotion to production,
application maintenance, operational support,
and lastly project management.
I have shown this process underneath for supporting all of the others
since many times you will want a project structured to own and manage
the activities shown in the other boxes.
Now each of these could easily be a complete class or course in their own right.
And in fact, three are.
Requirements analysis, estimation, and project management.
I have three Pluralsight courses on each of those three topics,
and I'll talk about those a little bit later as well. Okay, let's get started.