The first step in meeting or even exceeding your customer's
expectations is to know those expectations.
So here's a collection of techniques and strategies you can use
to determine your customer's expectations.
Every single customer interaction is an opportunity to manage expectations,
every single one.
Don't ever forget it, ever.
Whether it is a meeting, email, phone call,
et cetera, listen to your customer,
seek to understand and appreciate their thoughts and comments,
and then discuss further to try and ensure you have the same
expectations for the work that you're doing for them.
Also, you need to take the time to educate,
inform,
and even train your customers about what you do and how you do it so they have
an appreciation of what you need to do to get the job done.
The number one important take away from this entire
module is this statement in front of you.
So I will say it again,
every single customer interaction is an opportunity to manage expectations.
So don't miss those opportunities that are so important to help you in your job. Okay now let's look at some strategies.