In this section we will discuss your work intake process.
I like to see it as a funnel in a way,
at the top of the funnel all work intake may be a bit fuzzy.
Is it a user request, some requirements,
maybe it's a ticket, it's an operational issues,
is it a project.
And as it moves down the funnel it'll become more understood and actionable.
Okay, let's jump in.
The work intake process is the activity of collecting,
organizing, tracking and prioritizing work for your team,
also known as, AKA, your portfolio of work.
At any time you need to be able to show and share this
information with your team so they can easily see
everything on your collective plates, both your in work,
you know, what you're working on, and backlog activities,
what's in your backlog, what you may work on in the future.
You need to be able to show and share with your manager so he and she can
see what is on your plate and the status of each item.
And lastly,
you need to be able to show and share the portion of the portfolio
that belongs or is owned by each of your customers.
You typically only show those items that the customer
has provided to you to each customer.
Work intake, the management of work as it comes in,
is extremely important because it'll drive all the
activities that you should do, when you should do them,
who you do them for,
and you need to be able to provide crystal clear transparency
and clarity to all potential stakeholders,
your manager, your employees, your team,
and your customers.
If you do not have a handle, that is a process,
to manage your work intake, I suggest to you,
strongly, that you will not be successful.
You will not deliver priority items and your team will be in
chaos and feel insecure about what they work on,
and if it has any value to the business.
Remember,
people like to work on things that have value and that they can contribute.
But let me also say, the work may come into your team,
may in fact be a bit chaotic.
That's normal in business.
So what you'll want to do is get ahead of this and manage it.
So requests can come in in many methods, certainly there's verbal.
Face to face encounter,
such as in a meeting or even in a hallway discussion or your boss just
coming into your office saying hey I need you to do this.
Another way is the phone, it's just another form of verbal,
but for completeness I have added it here.
Both of these examples are unstructured,
soft, and typically poorly understood forms of telling you what to work on.
So return to your desk or computer,
write down what you think you understand the work to mean,
send an email back to the requestor for validation before you begin any work.
The English language, or any language, is packed full of ambiguities.
Another way you might get requests is email.
This is a very common way to receive a request.
It is written, which is a great start, may have attachments,
which is good, screenshots,
images or other artifacts which can really help you
better understand the requirement.
But emails are notoriously poor for tracking and
managing anything but your junk mail.
Tickets, even a better way, I like this.
The data collected in a ticket is very structured and you can
easily decide on the structure yourself,
and it's automatically tracked.
There are many ticketing systems out there and if you don't use one,
please consider using one as a way to manage and track
your work requests that come in.
And lastly, it may be some sort of request form,
which is fine,
like a project request form or requirement request form or some other form of,
well, form.
It may be electronic form as well, and hopefully it is.
So that's another way to handle work as it comes in.
Okay, now that that's happened, the process begins.
So let's take a look at it.
Organizing work intake.
Work gets started for a variety of reasons,
but good intentions are usually not enough to justify each activity.
In spite of defining or enforcing intake criteria,
work continues to be launched,
which should never have been approved in the first place.
So you must manage and organize all work requests and a
manage process starts with tracking, more on that later.
Why?
You need 100% visibility of all potential work.
This is very important.
If your manager thinks you're not doing very much, is that good?
If you manager thinks you're doing a ton of stuff and you have a huge backlog,
that's great, you might get more people.
You might be able to hire more, you might get more tools.
That's good.
Next, you need to know where your work is coming from, what are your sources.
Next, you need to know the status of your work.
At any time someone should be able to say, what's the status of this project?
What's the status of this bug?
What's the status of this activity?
At all times, so you can respond to your customer,
you can respond to your coworkers and you can respond to your manager as well.
So you need a transparent portfolio.
I use the term portfolio as the collection of all your work intake activities.
You need to easily convey your portfolio to management or,
in fact, senior management.
Okay, there are many benefits,
your development team will have complete access to all this information,
which is great, you can look at the portfolio to help you make decisions,
make options, start projects, stop projects or activities.
And visibility for all, I keep stressing that,
this is very, very important so that everyone can see the entire work intake,
all the activities, either in work or backlogged.
And lastly,
just the whole benefit of having everything in one spot
is then you can do backlog management.
You can look at all your items,
you can groom those items and see what you need to work on,
what should wait, et cetera.
All potential work and work in progress gets logged and tracked.
Let me say it again, all work, no exceptions,
don't let anything slip by,
get everything in that portfolio so that your management and customers can have
the full benefit to all the activities you're working on.
And this is very important for your team to feel
good about what they're working on, to reduce chaos,
for the customers to believe that what you have is what you're
working on and you really do have a backlog,
you're not just saying to them, hey I'm busy,
don't give me anything else.
No,
you can show them and you can demonstrate to them that
you have 28 items in the backlog, help me prioritize these,
help me go to management with the higher board developers,
help me make this happen for you.
Very, very important.
Of all these sections, in this particular area here,
the 10 sections I'm going to talk about,
this one I think is number 1.
So what information should you track in your portfolio?
You need to track and prioritize and release or authorize your work and
you're going to use your portfolio as a way to do that.
So here is a sample portfolio schema or template,
in other words here are the columns or fields you should have.
Now please feel free to add, subtract, or change anything that works for you,
but here's just a starter, because you're going to need to meet once a week,
maybe twice a week, to look at your portfolio,
to review, scrub, groom, all your work intake,
to make sure what you're doing is on track,
maybe there are blockers,
maybe there are things you have to do or activities
in order to move things forward.
Okay, let's get started.
An ID, I like to have some sort of unique ID for a reference,
sometimes they're auto generated by the system you may use,
and again, you may use a spreadsheet, you may use SharePoint,
you may use Jera, millions of tracking tools out there,
find one, use it.
Who's the leader of this or the owner, the name of the item,
some sort of short description so you know what the heck the item is.
LOE, level of effort, come up with what you think is the right criteria,
maybe small is less than 24 hours, maybe medium is 24 to 48,
maybe large is over 48 and extra large is over 100.
Or maybe you can use more of an Agile scrum where you
have different kinds of chunks of work, just small,
medium, large, and big or something like that.
Whatever works, but be consistent.
What's the start date?
When should this thing begin?
What's the due date?
When does the customer request it to be complete?
And if it has started, what's the percent complete?
Then you'll want to have next week's deliverables,
so another little column, might be a little wider if you will,
in other words, once this task or activity has been worked forward,
you'll want to know what's going to be delivered in the next week.
Alright, then you'll want to have another column for a blocker or issues,
in other words, this item is stuck.
What's the blocker,
what's the thing blocking it from moving forward or the issue,
that's also very, very important.
And there may be more than one, and then you'll want to talk about that,
remove the blocker so it can move forward.
And then there's risk.
What could happen downstream if you don't do this or you're working on it?
Maybe itemize the risk or risks that could affect this item.
And then what's the team priority for this?
In other words,
how I like to do this is as a manager I'd like to put
down my priorities for the team, in other words,
I might pick the top 3 that are important to me,
so people know when they come up for air or are free,
they choose one of these first before choosing maybe the other priorities.
Sponsor or contact,
really who is the person that gave you this task or the
customer area or a sponsor or things like that,
maybe their phone number and email so we know who
to go back to and ask questions.
And then status, just what's the status.
And you can come up with anything you want,
it could be backlog, active, you know, on hold,
come up with a variety of status types if you'd like.
Now this is just a short list and you could have a lot more columns as well,
make sure they're meaningful to you and your team,
capture the right information, all very important.
And this could be the start of all the work you're going to do in your team.
Now let's summarize the work intake process.
You want to collect,
organize and track all work intake items so as they come in
from any of those sources we talked about,
you immediately log them.
For each item, fill out as many of the columns of data as you can,
and we talked about that with the portfolio schema,
and again,
change the columns of information any way you want to reflect
an accurate representation of your world.
You'll want to meet regularly to scrub your portfolio,
I'd say at least once a week, maybe even twice.
And what I mean by scrub is to review line by line each item and
discuss it's status whether it is still in the backlog,
not being worked yet, or it's been released for work,
and again, maybe twice a week,
figure out what your cadence is and what works for you and your team.
And lastly, provide total visibility to your manager,
to your team, and to your customer, so anyone can easily click,
if you will, and see what it is you're working on.
Maybe it is a list structure in SharePoint,
a spreadsheet, a ticketing system,
use anything that will allow concurrent usage and easy access.
Okay, so how do you know what to do for an item or an activity in your portfolio?
You will need to do some thinking,
I guess or requirements analysis before you can,
in my opinion, do anything at all. So let's talk about requirements analysis next.