Now let's talk about communicating with your customer with quality.
Okay the first, consistently communicate.
Communication is key to managing customer's expectations,
providing clear and efficient ways for customers to communicate with your
business helps to continually reinforce expectations.
Examples of communication are status emails,
presentations, meetings, even hallway interactions and phone calls.
Next, open communication.
Okay, you know,
your customer is looking to you to help them find solutions to
their business goals or operational issues.
You need to be well versed and able to speak to those
possibilities or options quickly by openly discussing possible
solutions to a problem with the customer.
By presenting alternative solutions, each with pros and cons,
you can enable your customer to understand the complexity of a
particular problem and they may feel more involved and
committed to the solution of choice.
Additionally, by rendering a clear picture of possible results,
your customers won't have unrealistic expectations of how
simple or difficult the resolution will be.
For example, there are two ways to go here,
we can build your own single sign on class library or buy
one off the shelf and configure it.
Here are the cost differences, the pros and the cons,
and some long term effects of support.
Then recommend which one may be the best for the customer,
not you, based on the business requirements you know he or she has.
This gives the customer their choice to pick and at the
same time they know the pros and cons,
which helps set and manage their expectations.
Next is transparency.
Now transparency is absolutely critical to managing customer
expectations effectively and will effect a client's ability
to trust you and your team.
You want your customer to be confident in you and your team at all times.
Transparency will result in positive experiences with your customers,
enhancing trust.
So be clear, that is to be transparent and able to be easily comprehended,
and if I may, no BS.
For example,
do not discuss a bunch of technical jargon to confuse your customer about
how hard something is so you can delay your due date.
Instead,
tell them that the skill level in one area of your team is not sufficient.
You have to learn more than what we realize,
maybe even pulling in a consulting company to get up to speed,
and because of that we have to delay delivery by 5 days.
So on the plus side,
we now have additional knowledge and this may help shorten
our schedule in other areas based on how that you're going
to be smarter and learn more, maybe partnering with the consulting company.
Be honest from the get go.
Though it may sound counterintuitive,
I always tell potential new clients or current clients,
in our initial conversations that there are no guarantees.
As with most things in life there are too many factors at
play to make any grandiose promises,
especially in today's very complex technical and business world.
There may be some things that you can predict estimates and schedules for,
and others may just be too fuzzy to do so.
Although it may feel uncomfortable for you,
I think that saying this clearly and in no uncertain terms positions the
customer to understand the process behind your work.
For example, you could share how to manage your work intake,
work requests come in from the business analyst,
it's reviewed, estimated, and placed in a backlog.
Then by working with the customer you review the items,
the customer chooses their priorities, and you begin work.
In this way the customer clearly sees that the work
according to a process and plan and the customer can have
some amount of control over the process.
This example actually embodies honesty, transparency, and open communication.
Now what do all these attributes have in common?
Well trust.
Trust is your secret weapon to not be a better manager and service provider,
but a great leader as well.
Trust leads to long lasting business relationships,
which enables a healthy working environment and successful careers for everyone.
This talk about consistency in writing,
you can better manage customer expectations by following up in a timely fashion.
You do not want your customer to wonder about whether you
understood their need or request or requirement.
You need to always close the loop so that they know you
understood and are taking actions.
You should do this, more often than not, by using written communications.
Of course there will be times you may have a phone call or a hallway discussion,
but I suggest to you strongly to follow up even those
encounters with a quick email as well.
The written word helps ensure what was said, it makes history.
Talks about what actions are required, what has transpired,
and other important and pertinent data.
It also provides an audit trail of discussions for later reference.
We're all busy and we all forget things.
We can go back and look at written communication to
follow that thread and that trail.
The customer really likes and appreciates that.
For example, if it is a bug fix,
be sure to follow up with an email stating the bug is fixed,
it will be in the next release, et cetera.
This makes the customer comfortable and prepared.
If you have a status meeting you follow up with meeting notes,
and email them out to all the attendees.
If you are planning future projects, you provide information about each project,
budgets, et cetera.
Next is meetings.
I know, most of you may think meetings are just a waste of time,
and how knows, maybe some are.
So it is your job to make the most of a meeting with your customers.
Have an agenda, again, that is written, have an outcome in mind,
which is written so when it is over you have the information or data you
need to keep the projects or activities moving forward.
Again, this is an opportunity to get a read on their expectations as well.
For example, review open activities or tasks,
ask your customer if there are any issues with each of them,
review the due dates, get a read for each item.
At the end of the meeting ask if there's anything else you can do for them.
If their expectations are what you think,
then great, if they are not, then you must manage those mismatched expectations.
For example,
you are expecting task 12 to be done by Friday and based on
the other new requirements you gave me,
that needs to slip or the other task needs to slip,
which one is the most important?
Negotiate, come to an agreement and document it in writing.
Now that you're both in sync on these expectations that's good,
hence you must write meeting minutes, email them out,
documenting all the agreements, notes and status items.
This keeps everyone's expectations on track.
If you do not write meeting notes then it is all from memory and guess what?
We all know the customer will only remember that you
must do everything by yesterday,
so we must write meeting minutes to make sure we're
on the same page and in sync.
Next emails, so use emails to keep in regular contact with your customers.
Not only emails, you want face to face meetings and such as well.
Some emails may be more formal with status reports, others can be simple.
For example, hey just a note, we are on track with the new release for Friday,
we only have one issue at this time, we may need to reach out to you for help.
What did this just say?
This says to your customer the following,
you are working on their stuff, things seem to be going well,
there may be one issue.
So that gives them a subtle clue that there could be a problem.
So you're setting their expectation so it won't be a surprise.
And lastly, you might reach out to them if you need their help,
that's very important.
It makes them feel inclusive and supportive.
Now reports.
Probably not everyone's favorite task during the week,
but reports show a clear delineation of work that was
done over a course of a week or a month.
Remember reports don't have to be very long,
or in a format that clogs up all your time when you email.
A simple email detailing tasks completed for the week shows your clients
what they're paying for and thus keeps them happy.
Hopefully by following these steps you'll be on the road to an
even better relationship with your clients.
By following this process you'll most likely achieve
better results in your work as well.
Next, let's talk about marketing.
You want to subtly market what you and your team does.
This is very important to set expectations for the client as well.
So you'll want to market your team and what they can
do for your customer or business.
And what I mean by that is when you're speaking or writing during emails,
meetings, reports, et cetera,
adding a few items that market and promote the
things you and your team do is great.
Don't overdo it and brag about things certainly.
Here's an example,
the team completed release 23 on Thursday as planned and I
want to thank my team for staying late.
Your customer will appreciate how hard your team is working
to get something done and you have also shown your
appreciation to your team as well.
Another example may be in a status report where you
mention other services you perform.
This may result in more work, growing your team,
and expanding opportunities for your team's technical growth and your management growth as well.