Walk arounds.
So what's a walk around?
They're an impromptu and unplanned quick visit or chat with an employee,
team member or other person.
It should only be a couple of minutes, maybe 3 to 5 minutes.
This is not a meeting and is a very informal and casual encounter.
What I am calling the walk around is also known as
management by walking or even wandering around,
MBWA,
and these refer to a style of business management which involves you
the manager walking around in an unstructured manner,
through the work places, at random,
checking with employees about the status of their work,
et cetera.
Now the purpose is to get and stay connected with your
team at a more natural and human level.
In order to do this you need to walk around and talk to your team,
ask questions, and be there to help when needed.
Now the benefits are huge, you get grass roots,
real time feedback from a person, usually in the comfort of their office.
You might even discover any issues early in order to
avoid bigger problems downstream.
Also you can get a pulse or a feeling of the health of a team member and
what I mean by health is how they feel about their job,
their assignments, their workload, or even personal items.
Lastly, it helps build a personal rapport with each person.
As I mentioned, they are impromptu, that is unplanned.
Now they are planned in my mind as a manager,
for example I'm going to go get some coffee from the kitchen and on the
way back I am planning to stop at someone's office.
I don't know which one,
but I want to drop in on maybe one or two if that makes sense.
That's the extent of my planning.
If there are two people talking intently I will not stop.
I will use my judgment to be nonintrusive and respectful of their time.
I don't want to bug anybody.
But just to pop the head in and say - hey how was your weekend?
You know, are you working on that particular project?
Yeah, sounds good.
You know, there's a chit chat here and there, that's really, really good.
So throughout the day I might try to drop in on all of my folks,
at least for a couple minutes and see how they're doing.
In fact, they may even drop in to my office and we chat.
Here's a little more on walk arounds.
Now I have focused on the walk around for you to directly
interact informally with each of your team members,
but this could apply to anyone in your professional sphere if interactions.
I would like you to include your management,
maybe each day or two drop into her or his office and just say hi,
hey I'll get that report to you, but how was your weekend?
Or I heard you just got back from vacation, how was it?
Something like that.
That stimulates a little brief conversation and a connection,
some a little bit around personal activities and some around work activities.
Also, your customers,
if it is possible to physically drop in and say hi without a formal meeting,
that would be great.
Maybe something like - hey Joe, how are you?
Is this system working okay for you?
Oh, great, I'm glad that it is.
Did you just get back from seeing your family in Hawaii?
Also,
there are what I call remote drop ins because people may
not be physically near or around you, and you could do a causal phone call,
maybe even Skype or some web conferencing tools to quickly just touch base,
not in a formal setting, not on a meeting,
just hey, how are you?
Just thought I'd give you a quick call, and again,
it might be 3 to 5 minutes and you move on.
Of course,
you can tailor the walk around so it best fits you and your environment. Alright, now let's talk about emails.