So how are you going to do requirements analysis?
Whether it's a simple 2 hour job or a large project,
well you need an approach, that is a process.
So whether you're Agile, Scrum, waterfall or something in between,
good quality requirements will also be required as
part of your job or your team's job.
Let's look further.
Requirements analysis, in systems engineering and software engineering,
requirements analysis encompasses those tasks that go into
determining the needs or conditions to meet for a new or
updated product or service.
They take into account various stakeholders,
they do some analysis, documenting, validating,
and managing software or system requirements.
Sometimes this is also called functional specifications.
Here's a note,
I typically see in so many IT organizations that they hire only
software engineers and leave the determination of the
requirements also to the software engineers.
Now this can be a major flaw to me.
Developers typically do not like to write requirements,
so they either don't get written or maybe get written poorly.
So please be sure your team is staffed with professional business analysts,
or BAs as they're called, to augment your team.
Also many BAs are suited for project management activities,
which is coming in another section of this module.
Now let's talk for a moment about why requirements analysis is so important.
Do you know what a major cause of failed software is?
Well it's poor definition of requirements,
that's one of the major causes of failed software and after
all my years in the software business, I truly believe this.
Now Agile, waterfall or blend, well the same issue applies,
creating quality requirements is still essential.
When the activity of defining requirements is
either skipped or poorly performed,
the resulting application software is likely not to
meet your customer's requirements.
Now that is what I think about Scrum, for example, and Agile methodology.
Because you build things incrementally in relatively shortly sprints,
you can make course corrections.
This process, in my opinion,
greatly improves your chances of a successful product,
but remember quality requirements are still necessary,
either in sprint forms or prior to sprints or something like that,
you still need good requirements in order to build out software.
Next, define and follow your process,
successful software development is often hindered by the poor
state of the process of requirements analysis.
Most organizations do not have any rigor or process to gather requirements,
resulting in vague and imprecise requirements.
So define your process.
Create templates to be easily reused, keep your artifacts,
that is requirements that you've written before,
easily accessible by the developers and the customers alike.
Now requirements should be documented, actionable,
testable, traceable, and tied to the business as well,
and related to identified business needs or opportunities,
and defined to a level of detail,
sufficient for system design and architecture to take place.
And that's another section coming up later.
Alright now let's look at some tools for requirements analysis.
Here's a really good quote, "we don't need an accurate document,
we need a shared understanding, " by Jeff Patton.
This really resonated with me, so it is the process of gathering requirements,
the meetings, the analysis, the research,
talking to people, workflow diagrams, documents,
mockups, prototypes, et cetera,
that will enable a common understanding of the intended outcome.
Yes, I certainly prefer an accurate document,
of course,
but not at the expense of losing a common
understanding between software engineers,
business analysts,
project managers and most importantly the customers and the users.
Okay, have I piqued your interest in requirements gathering?
Let's see where you can learn more about requirements gathering.
As I mentioned earlier,
each section in this module could in fact be a complete course.
Well I would like to recommend to you another one of my Pluralsight
courses titled Best Practices for Requirements Gathering,
which would be a nice adjunct or companion course for this course. Okay, let's go estimate some work.