The point of talking about informal emails is to contrast the
difference between them and the formal ones.
I will talk about the formal ones in the next section,
but mostly what I want to say here is when and why you
should use or not use informal emails.
Okay,
basically an informal email is usually be two people who know each
other pretty darn well and usually in a casual,
friendly or family setting.
So when to use, rarely and only with well known coworkers and maybe your manager,
but never customers and I would recommend never
informal emails with senior management.
Now this will all depend on your company's culture, of course.
I mostly come from the corporate world and the consulting world.
So I rarely use informal or causal emails with any
of my professional relationships.
Also, I would suggest using them only for friends and family.
So why use them?
They're often used to request information,
maybe congratulate people, give advice and ask questions.
There are a lot of similarities between an informal
email and just plain conversation.
You may use slang or abbreviations and your grammar may suffer as well.
And well, who cares, it's an informal email.
But again,
I would strongly suggest only formal emails in the
workplace and use your judgment.
Now there is a risk of someone forwarding your email
to a customer or senior manager, possibly with good intentions,
but that may not be a good reflection on you,
possibly based on how you wrote it and what you said.
It could be the context of what you said,
it could be used all lowercase lettering,
your grammar could be poor, it could be just an informal email,
but somehow got forwarded to the wrong person professionally.
So pay special attention to that.
So basically this slide, therefore,
is a heads up on paying attention to when you might want to use informal emails.
Personally,
I go formal all the way in the professional environment and I would suggest you do too.