Aligning IT team goals to business goals.
So how do we align the work we do with the business?
Now every company organization is likely to be different in the approach
or capability and granularity in determining alignment.
In fact there may not be any at all.
If there is none, it'll be your job to create one.
If there is an existing one,
it'll be your job to learn that process and possibly evolve
and improve that process to ensure that the work you do is in
fact aligned to the business.
Now let's run through a complete example.
Now let's talk about goals from fuzzy to measurable.
When it comes to getting or extracting business goals,
sometimes it can be challenging.
Sometimes they are what I call very fuzzy.
What you are looking for are goals that are more measurable.
For example, your customer might way I want to increase revenue.
Well, okay what does that really mean?
And by how much?
Or maybe I want to avoid costs.
Well, which costs and where are they and how much?
Or I want to improve customer satisfaction.
Well that sounds great, how do I go about doing that?
How do you connect those dots?
I call these fuzzy goals.
Okay, next might be more what I call measurable goals.
Maybe increase product revenue by 25%,
so now I know that the revenue is tied to the product by 25%,
that gives me a better handle on where to maybe put my IT resources,
or reduce non-selling inventory by 25%, oh I could run some reports,
figure out what's not selling and reduce that
inventory from the bottom up by 25%.
Or maybe I could rewrite the user interface to be more user friendly,
that might improve customer satisfaction.
So when you do get fuzzy goals,
spend more time with the business to better understand just
what they mean by increasing revenue, for example.
So you may need some extra time to talk with the customers,
maybe you have a business analyst on your team or maybe on their team,
to further explore the business goals, decompose them,
deconstruct them to be more specific so you can better
apply those resources to make a difference.
Now let's continue with the example.
Now that you are a new manager,
you first need to align your work with the business.
Let the team continue their development activities they have in their cue,
but you will need to first get out of the weeds and
get a handle on the business.
So to determine IT activities takes business analysis effort and time,
either supplied by one or more subject matter experts in the business units
and/or business analysts on the IT side of the organization.
Your company may or may not have articulated and written any business goals.
Your company may do things via what I call chit chat.
Your company may have well written and structured goals.
So whatever you company has, one or the other or both, here's what I recommend.
First work with your manager to understand the
broader business goals of the company, business not IT.
This will give your team a bigger picture of where the company is
going and what the company wants to accomplish.
Next,
work with your manager to understand how your work and
projects align with the business goals.
This will give you and your team a sense of value and purpose,
key elements to support inspiration and motivation.
Next identify who are your customers that would
benefit from the work you will do.
This will give you an understanding of your project's stakeholders.
Remember,
stakeholders are those people that have a vested
interest in the success of the project.
Usually they are the recipients of the project's outcomes,
but also maybe the IT infrastructure team and the financial team who
will want to know the budgets or cost savings,
for example.
And go out and meet and talk with them, begin developing relationships.
These relationships will make or break your success.
Lastly, document everything.
Write it all down since we will need it later on, of course.
And if our company has some existing artifacts,
write down their location, file share, URL,
et cetera, so you know where that stuff is. Okay, now let's check out an example of how you would go about doing this.