Step 4, integrate lists and prioritize.
We all know that budgets are always limited so you will have to prioritize.
So as a team exercise itemize all the training needed and go
over each item making down its priority.
There should be a group discussion with you breaking the ties.
I just kept it simple by using high, medium,
and low as priority indicators,
but you could use a different criteria if you'd like.
You might also consider delivery dates of projects to the
customers since that can drive priority,
certainly.
Sometimes the skills that your team will personally
select may fall to lower priorities, be sure you explain why this is.
In other words, the priority is the business over personal ambitions.
But try and champion more budget if you can to support their needs.
Now let's sort with the higher priorities going to the top.
Okay, so this is a little nicer.
We can see what is the most important on top.
We have the highs up front, then the mediums, and now the lows.
Now let's develop a plan and implement.
Step 5, develop a plan and implement.
So first we want to secure approvals and then secure budget.
You won't have much training if you don't have any budget.
Next we want to find the sources, where are we going to get that training from?
So some examples might be external companies,
like Pluralsight, educational institutions,
maybe some internal experts that work in your company,
self-study,
and then you need to go out and schedule that training and maybe
even some trainings more just in time where maybe you learn the
training in classroom or internet-based and then you follow up by
mentoring in just in time where you actually apply what you've
learned directly on a project.
I find this really important and really effective as well.
Okay, so now let's take a look at a sample plan.
Step 5: training skills implementation plan.
So let's lay out a very simple plan.
We added three new columns to the previous chart.
The first is budget, that is how much we think we need for that training.
The next is source, that is where we're going to get the training from.
And lastly, the last column is when we need to be trained by,
the date, and if we are not sure of any of these we just put TBD,
please don't leave blank.
Okay now let's see the final step.
Step 6 I call inspect, adapt, and repeat.
So you want to review your plan as needed,
maybe review quarterly or under special new business circumstances,
update by following the steps we already covered,
adjust the budget and plan as necessary.
Now in the next section let's take a look at some easy and
effective training ideas to augment the traditional training we have just talked about.