You might be asking yourself,
well how can performance reviews have anything to do
with building your team's capabilities?
Well I think quite a bit.
It's all interrelated.
Now let's see how.
Okay so just what is a performance review?
It is the process of examining and evaluating the performance of an individual.
Well, that might sound a bit like, well so what,
I've had them before,
maybe you think they're a waste of time or other such comments,
especially if you're not a manager.
We've all been there.
But as a manger, in your new role, they are an important part of your job.
If HR, Human Resources, does not make you do them, you must do them anyway.
They're very important to the support and the growth of your
team and the success of your team as well.
Let's see how performance reviews build team capabilities.
First to identify and correct existing problems, issues or concerns.
And another way of stating that ala Agile,
it is to inspect and adapt,
and then chart an improved path that you and your team
member will find the best way to correct existing problems
or issues or concerns as well.
Next, to encourage improved future performance,
possibly based on mentoring or coaching by you or
identifying additional training needs.
Therefore the performance review can make the need for training more
urgent and important by relating it clearly to the performance
outcomes and future career goals as well.
Next, team performance is enhanced.
Since now you have conducted all of your reviews and now you have a complete
picture of your team's strengths and weaknesses and areas of improvement and
from the point of view of your organization as a whole.
A consolidated view of your overall training
requirements is now in front of you.
Now you can adjust your training plan, as we discussed before,
and modify according to the needs of the outcomes of the reviews.
So what a great time to revisit the six steps we have just covered,
to determine or re-determine your team's skills needs.
Building your team's capabilities through reviews has
other worthwhile benefits as well.
Here are a few.
Provides recognition.
Performance reviews provide employees with recognition for their work efforts.
The power of social recognition as an incentive has long been understood.
Next, shows that the employer cares and of course you care as well.
If nothing else,
the existence of a review program indicates to an employee that
the organization is genuinely interested and cares in their
individual performance and development.
This alone can have a positive influence on the individual's sense of worth,
commitment, and belonging.
Targets needs,
performance reviews can target a specific area of
weakness or area of improvement, that sounds a little better,
that needs evaluation and remediation.
It can also serve as a valuable tool for establishing goals that
will lead to promotions and career advancement.
Using a performance review to uncover training needs allows the company and
yourself to focus efforts on better areas of improvement.
Also charting progress,
performance reviews can be used to chart the progress of
an individual and your team as a whole.
Comparing performance reviews from one benchmark period to
another will provide both the company and the employee with
measurable marks of improvement, lack of improvement,
regression, in the job performance areas.
This data is valuable for maybe salary increases or demotions,
promotions, and maybe even terminations.
All of these elements can be tied to the progress
reflected in the performance review data,
so it's good to see the history, review by review,
to look at the progress of the employee to see how
they're progressing or maybe falling back,
in what areas, and how to help them along.
Employees, your team members,
will greatly appreciate your help and your mentoring to build
their skills for themselves personally, for the team,
and for the company.
Next, building relationships.
Performance reviews give the employer and yourself and the employee
the opportunity to sit down and discuss performance.
In these busy times where everyone is taking care of business,
periodic reviews between you and the employee allow them
to form or strengthen a relationship.
Developing this rapport opens as line of communication for
the employee to use in making future suggestions for the
company or applying for promotions.
Of course,
this is not the only time and way to build relationships with your team.
You'll be building relationships, of course,
every single day with everything you do.
This is just another more formal way to enhance and build a
relationship with each of your people.
Next, I think it motivates employees.
Performance reviews often serve as motivational tools,
the company may offer a bonus or other perk to employees who are able to
improve their performance reviews from one period to the next.
It is important to offer improvement opportunities such as training seminars,
mentorships or classes to employees desiring to
improve their performance reviews.
Now let's look at the review process itself.
Here are some guidelines on how to conduct performance reviews.
First, always follow company standards and policy.
Above all, you must follow the policy at all times.
Based on the size and maturity of companies,
I have seen some that are extremely formal with
processes and procedures for reviews,
and other companies that actually have absolutely nothing.
So find out from your management how your review process works
and communicate this process to your team.
Whether it is your company's, your own, or a blend of both,
you must follow the process.
Formal versus informal.
If you have a formal process and forms, et cetera, that still may not be enough.
I have seen some forms from human resources that are just so high
level they don't apply to the technical teams at all.
If formal, find out what latitude and flexibility you have and if informal,
in other words, if you're doing your own thing,
then come up with your own review template.
More on that later.
Because consistent, never miss a review.
We do ours on the employees on their anniversary date of
maybe you do the whole team at once.
Follow your company's standards and if you have none I like the
anniversary date the best so it is not so overwhelming on you
having to do all of them at one time,
you can kind of spread it out over the year.
Follow a defined process.
First if your company has one, you follow that,
and if they don't have one, come up with your own process.
Next, document everything, the process, standards,
procedures, the review forms, the review results,
and any notes you take during review must be captured and kept.
Generally the reviews are a very positive experience with everyone,
but in some cases there may be some legal issues and you
better document and save everything.
Okay, let's look at the review itself.
Alright here's a little bit about the review itself.
Develop a performance review template.
If your company or HR does not have one, you must have one of your own.
I put a sample of one in the demos.
zip file for this module.
Please check it out.
Very basic, very simple, just use it as a starting point,
change anything you'd like to change if you need to.
Next,
your review template is based on roles and responsibilities
that we built earlier in this course.
And for each skill and duty described we rate the person for each.
We want to provide positive feedback,
everyone does do good work at least some of the time,
identify it,
provide your appreciation for it and how it has
helped the team and the customer.
Also, you're going to provide areas of improvement.
That is the nice way to talk about areas they don't do very well.
Sometimes it might just be the lack of training or experience,
and in that case you can provide the coaching or training they need.
If it is more along the lines of attitude and motivation or even carelessness,
don't be shy,
talk about it and see if you can't arrive at a plan to correct
and improve poor or inadequate performance.
Solicit the employee's feedback, always get their feedback about you, yes, you.
Sometimes it may be your style, your approach,
or maybe even your inexperience, remember you're a new manager,
that is affecting their performance.
Come to a meeting of the minds and put together a plan for both of you.
And next, what I call 360 feedback.
It is where I get inputs on the employee's performance from coworkers,
customers, or other important people that have work with them.
I don't see and work with my employees every single day
and every minute so I really need their inputs for a full
360 view of their performance.
I do keep the inputs anonymous at all times, that's very important.
They come up with an aggregate performance review based on their inputs.
Alright now let's do a little bit on motivating your employees and how it relates to this section.