Design and architecture.
Based on our work intake process, we have identified some work to do.
We have done some requirements analysis and now we have
our business or functional requirements.
Then we developed some estimates.
So now let's go to the next step where it's time to
think about design and architecture.
So now that the requirements are defined and we have
some idea of the high level estimate,
we will likely move on to designing your solutions,
sometimes also known as the technical specifications.
Okay, system design is the process of defining the architecture,
components, modules, interfaces,
and data for a system to satisfy specified requirements,
in accordance with your architectural roadmap and
standards that I'll talk about later.
Now typically the customer is usually interested in the functional specs,
you know, the business specs,
the use cases and things like that as discussed earlier,
unless or not at all in the technical specifications.
Now let's see why design and architecture is important for you.
Why is system design and architecture important?
In fact, extremely important.
So if everyone just went out for a long one,
in other words,
every application would be designed and architected
differently by each developer,
now that is not necessarily bad if the business requirements are driving it,
but it is bad, not good,
if each and every developer decided on their own how
to do everything their own way.
You cannot run a business or maintain applications efficiently if
you do not have a design and architecture process.
For example, maybe one developer uses MVVM,
one MVC, one Angular 1, another one Angular 2,
through a design and architecture process,
those decision will be vetted and jointly determined for the best interest
of the applications and the solutions for the customer.
Alright, best practices.
What's a best practice?
It's a method or technique that has been generally accepted as superior
to any alternatives because it produces practical,
expected, efficient,
and repeatable results that are better than those achieved by other means,
and that relates to your own organization in your department.
As an example, maybe one developer uses stored procs,
another Entity Framework, and other dynamic SQL.
Through a design and an architecture process,
those decision will be vetted and jointly determined to be the best solution.
Design patterns,
a design pattern is a reusable form of a solution to a design problem.
For example, at my company we had a data layer,
a complete data layer that we use on about 90% of all our apps,
it was a standard, reusable and extendable layer of software.
Hence the developer could move from project to project very easily,
and by the way, we had tons of prebuilt design patterns,
not just for data access.
Standards, the most simple case, for example,
we have programming standards say for C# and SQL.
This helps, again,
when a developer moves from one project to another
or application to application,
it just makes it easier for them to jump right in and go forward.
Common tools, for me fewer the better.
I firmly believe you'll want the fewest tools that maximize your productivity,
again, barring special business driven circumstances.
Fewer tools mean fewer licenses, therefore saving money,
may mean less training, may mean a more streamline set of best practices,
design patterns and standards.
Next, legal and regulatory.
Based on the industry you are in,
you may have a plethora of legal or regulatory items you must be compliant with.
For example, some apps must comply with ADA,
American with Disabilities Act, regarding user interfaces.
I also recommend you have documented your best practices,
documented your design patterns,
documented your standards and common tools and architectures so
that everyone can understand that this suite of items is a
continuously evolving set of decisions and architectural patterns
that structure your software tools, enable scalability,
enable improved performance, enhance maintainability,
increase usability, all resulting in superior quality systems.
Okay,
all of this is for delivering the best functionality to
meeting the needs of your customer.
Now let's take a look at an architectural roadmap.
You need a design and architecture technology roadmap.
This roadmap is the guidance, the recommendations,
and the predetermined approaches on how and when to use what technology.
Design and architecture process, what is that?
You need a process by which you can continually review
and evolve and improve your roadmap.
Here at my company we have quarterly meetings to review or we have just
in time meetings based on the needs of the customer,
project, or architect.
Technology selection,
you need a process to maintain the technologies within your roadmap as well.
And lastly, for this module, check out the demo.
zip file to see a sample of a roadmap,
in there you'll see our technology roadmap,
our design and architecture process,
and an entire technology selection process as well.
Alright now it's time to move on to construction. Actually, let's go build some software.