Now let's break down an SLA.
SLAs typically contain the following attributes,
a description of the service being provided.
For example, maintenance of areas such as network connectivity,
maintaining an application software, or writing ad hoc reports,
et cetera.
Next, reliability.
When the service is available,
percentage up time and the limits outages can be expected to stay within,
for example.
Responsiveness.
The punctuality of services to be performed in response to
requests and scheduled service dates.
Procedure for reporting problems, who can be contacted,
how many problems will be reported, procedure for escalation,
and what other steps are taken to resolve the problem efficiently.
Monitoring and reporting service level, who will monitor performance,
what data will be collected and how often as well as how much access
the customer is given to the performance statistics.
For example,
I may report in a weekly status that we closed 5 bugs and have 7 in the backlog.
Next, consequences for not meeting service obligations.
These may include credit or reimbursement of hours or budgets to customers.
Sometimes in our company if we have a bug,
well we fix it and don't charge the customer,
that's part of the consequences of not meeting our service obligation.
Escape clauses or constraints.
Circumstances under which the level of service promised does not apply.
As an example, holidays and weekends may have different constraints.
You are all welcome to add or subtract any attributes that would make
better sense to your service and product offerings,
but you at least get the idea of what an SLA is trying to do.
Okay let's see specific examples of each attribute
pertaining to software engineering.
Okay in this example, you the new manager,
is responsible for a team of five software engineers
supporting the sales business domain.
You have been noticing a mismatch between what you thought you were
delivering to your customers and what the customers really wanted.
Hence, their expectations are different from yours and what you are to deliver,
so you think the SLA may be the way to go.
Okay, so you fire up MS Word, drop in the attributes from the last slide,
and start typing.
You want to start getting your thoughts together.
Okay, first your service description,
provide all application development and support for
the sales application portfolio, that's a great high level mission statement.
And some detail examples may mean that I support the prospects system,
I support the Salesforce interface, and I support the ERP interface.
Those are the key three things that you support.
Now for this example in the following slides it will give
you examples of the SLA attributes.
I'm going to provide you a relatively light weight
set of descriptions and examples.
You will more than likely provide more comprehensive
descriptions and be more thorough.
The next attribute is business alignment,
so I would write my group participates in quarterly planning to ensure
our work and projects are aligned with the business.
Basically I, as the manager,
will follow the guidelines of activities that I have outlined in
the module when aligning IT to the business.
So some example details, would be I have some active projects,
A and B are aligned to ITG-1.
1.
1 and also adding 100 new courses to the on-line catalog.
So I just took some of the material from the aligning IT to the business module.
And you may have several other examples certainly in this one category.
And again, I'm taking the light weight approach just for an example.
The next SLA attribute is reliability.
Each system is tested thoroughly before being released to the customer,
well, of course.
Example details would be we perform unit testing,
we do use case testing in 4 environment,
dev, QA, stage, and production, and follow a rigorous release management process.
So again,
here's how we ensure that reliability happens and the
steps that we take to ensure it.
Therefore, this is how the reliability section is written for your SLA.
The next attribute is responsiveness.
We follow an issue management process and will respond
to posted issues within 2 hours.
Some detail examples,
we use a web-based issue tracking system that routes issues to our
support center for disposition and remediation. So we lay out the attribute and what we do about it.