Hello, I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the overview module in the course
Practical Team Management for Software Engineers.
But first, a story.
Okay, that's me wearing black.
I was about 2 years out of graduate school and just loved to write software.
I worked for a major aerospace company, heads down and cranking out code.
Life was grand.
Then after almost 1 year exactly after I started with the company,
my boss's, boss's boss said, got a sec and can you come into my office?
Well, uh sure.
I wonder what he wants.
Let's find out.
Hey,
I think you've been doing a nice job and I would
like you to manage a team for me, maybe about 5 to 8 developers,
and I would need you to work with the customers,
figure out document requirements, determine your software development lifecycle,
standards, manage work tasks, you know, et cetera.
Come up with all the team management stuff you think you need.
Oh, by the way, you start tomorrow.
I was 26, I didn't know squat about the things I needed to manage my new team.
Well, here's what I was feeling.
Sometime between leaving his office and heading back to
my cubicle panic started to set in.
What just happened?
Well I got promoted, that's good, and more money too,
but do I even want to do the job?
Well I was not asked, I was actually told.
Okay in a very nice way, of course.
But do I want to be a manager?
Can I lead people?
Can I set the right direction?
What tools and processes do I need to do the job?
Can I do the job?
Will I still be able to write some software?
Will I miss doing that?
To be honest with you, I was overwhelmed.
I had never done anything remotely like that, just wrote software.
If you find yourself in a situation similar to this, then this class is for you.
Okay, so I began to think about my next steps.
Let's see what they are.
So I thought for a while and concluded that I needed two key critical skill groups of expertise to even remotely succeed in my new role.