User acceptance testing.
Now you've done your software development and construction and
you've done unit testing and all sorts of testing scenarios and
you think you're basically done,
well you're not done done until the user accepts what you've
provided and we call that user acceptance testing.
Now let's talk about this for a few moments.
Here's the basic definition of user acceptance testing or also known as UAT.
It's the last phase of the software testing process.
During UAT,
actual software users test the software to make sure it
can handle the required task in real world scenarios
according to the specifications.
Now programmer testing is much different than user acceptance testing,
I think very different.
So sometimes we code things,
but not fully understand what it means or its value because we're
just kind of building from the functional specs and sometimes we
don't have that full appreciation of what value should really be on
the screen at that point in time.
And it's only experienced subject matter experts that
can really see and discern that, especially on very large and complex systems.
We really need to partner with the users,
with our customers and doing a joint development and test activity.
So I really need to partner with our team and with our
customers and users to do user acceptance testing.
So we must rely on our users for the final
acceptance of any software we deliver.
Now here's a simple UAT process.
So first you want to develop a UAT test plan.
So you need to write up a test plan,
that is how are you going to approach the UAT testing activity,
these will be the steps you'll want to perform.
Now typically you'll identify acceptance criteria,
which are those items that if they work correctly the customer will say,
hey all done, looks great.
Now an example of acceptance criteria, maybe that they can define an order,
allocate the items in the order, and release the order for fulfillment,
something like that, that's a very simple one,
of course.
You want to identify the key sign off user because,
you know, not every user has the influence or position in the company to do this.
So be sure you identify that key user, or maybe users,
that'll do the sign offs and say, hey this looks good,
let's move it to production.
Next you want to develop the UAT test cases and identify those.
Since you've already probably created use cases or user
stories when you did the requirements,
well these can be so easily repurposed to be the actual test cases themselves.
If you were thoughtful in writing the user stories in the user's own words,
then it's very easy for a user to read those,
follow those, and then apply it to the UAT process.
Also you want to define the UAT environment and the data
appropriate for doing the testing, so it's really important.
What you have to do, of course,
is to simulate that future production environment and try to
perform the most realistic environment for testing.
Now sometimes I like to set up a UAT that in fact becomes
the production environment at some point,
then later I still need to build a new UAT since you will always
need UAT testing prior to going to production.
Next, document the requirements tied to this version or release.
You may be making several releases or versions as you
perform UAT testing and for each release,
document and make clear what new features or bug fixes or other items
are now in this release so that the users who are doing the testing
clearly know what has been delivered.
Lastly, you want to get that 'ok' to promote to production.
So that key sign off user I just mentioned above,
well he or she will be the one that'll say okay promote to production,
not you,
you don't have the authority or power and shouldn't to promote to production.
Now that release may not be perfect, which is okay,
but close enough so as to be viable and usable to get work done.
Again, that's up to the sign off user to determine that and approve that.
Now this seems to work more in an internally facing application,
where it's in terms of the company and maybe the user can sign off and say,
hey, that's good enough, I know there's a couple of tweaks we've got to make,
I'll get those in the next release,
but at least that can still be productive in this current release,
again that's up to the identified key user for the UAT testing process.
Okay, now let's look a little deeper at a UAT test plan.
So here's a quick primer on a UAT test plan.
And of course, the most important things is the goal,
what is the goal of the test plan?
Okay, so for example the goal for say project x may be the following,
test all features of the system to ensure that the system functions as
documented in the functional and technical specification.
Okay sounds pretty straightforward and you probably
wouldn't expect anything other than that.
Okay,
now what might be some of the references we want to
have as part of the test plan?
Okay the first would be, well what are the functional specifications,
do we have usage summaries, use case specification,
maybe a technical specification, maybe data model specifications,
or other specifications, maybe even security and things like that.
All these should be artifacts and referred to in the test plan.
Okay, features to be tested.
So let's use, as an example, a university enrollment system.
When you list out the features to test, these can be,
I think, very high level at first.
They are basically describing what you want to test and not necessarily how.
The how will come in the next slide.
So for example, a high level feature would be pre-enrollment.
Here you would list all the things like data that must be set up
in order to perform an enrollment of a student.
What must be available, in other words, pre-enrollment, for this to really work.
So pre-enrollment setups actually can be quite lengthy and complex,
so be aware of that.
Next, enrollment itself.
A student is going to enroll,
so you may want to identify some of the enrollment steps,
the things that need to be done.
Post-enrollment,
so these are all the features that you can do after a student is enrolled,
such as maybe a student can drop a class.
A student cannot drop a class in pre-enrollment or during enrollment,
but only after being enrolled, things like that.
So if you have written good quality requirements,
then this step is really easy since you can repurpose the material for UAT.
So I want to reemphasize what I said earlier in this course
about producing quality specifications.
It's great for reuse and you can refer to all these
specs as part of the test plan as well.
Okay, now let's look at a simple example.
Now as part of our test plan, we're going to identify many test cases,
so here's a simple test case example.
So I'm going to give it a name, ENRL, short for enrollment, Test Case 2.
14.
So easy naming convention for the test cases so we can
refer to them throughout the UAT process.
And what is in that?
I'll write something like user directs system to create a new fee waiver,
for example, users enters the Program Department,
Authorizing Identity, Expiration Date and Waiver Amount.
So it's saying to the user what needs to be done.
Next would be the screens that are going to be used to do that,
that will guide the user in doing the UAT.
We want you to use the Student Search screen,
the Student Master screen, the Student Profile screen and the Fee Waivers screen.
Next, document test steps and expected results.
In other words, there are going to be pre-conditions,
so these are the to-do's prior to testing that we mentioned earlier.
And then we're going to have the post conditions,
in other words, these are the expected results.
So perform the pre-conditions, then follow the test case,
go through, and then do the post conditions.
So this is kind of a simple template of a particular instance of a test case.
So your test plan will be a collection also of a variety of test
cases that are part or a portion of your test plan.
Now the point of this slide is not to make you an expert in any
of these testing types I'm about to show you,
but give you a general awareness that you can decide later if
any of these may work for you in the future.
So the following are the types of testing that you can may choose to perform.
The first, requirements coverage,
this will be the foundation for testing all aspects of the system and will be
used to make sure that this system is performing as it should.
Another type is called white box testing and this testing will
be implemented at all levels of testing,
unit testing, integration testing, system testing,
to verify that all paths of the code are working
correctly according to the requirements.
Can you make it through all the appropriate paths and test everything out?
Black box testing,
now this concentrates on what data are entered and what data are emitted.
Since black box testing is not based in an knowledge
of any internal designer code,
tests will be based on requirements and functionality.
So there will be tests that call for reviewing database
activity afterwards to ensure the inserts,
update and deletes are performed.
So in other words, given a certain set of data that might go into a system,
what is the expected outcome that would be inside the database or outputted,
for example, without the necessary knowledge of what goes on on the inside.
Input and output domain coverage,
and this testing ensures that when data is entered,
it is validated, saved and transformed into the correct form,
like invoices or credit memos, enrollment schedule,
and things like that.
Data outside of the specified input range should be tested to check
the robustness of the program and boundary cases should be tested
top and bottom of a specified range, for example,
to make sure the highest and lowest allowable inputs produce the proper result.
Now this type of testing will be done throughout the testing lifecycle,
but will become increasingly important as the system is
developed and greater sample data is available.
Another one may be data flow coverage and this testing follows data as it
flows through the system and to its designated form of output,
maybe invoices or reports, payments, things like that.
And this is also performed throughout the testing lifecycle.
Another one is what I call ad hoc testing or I even call it monkey testing.
The purpose of this testing is to try to create any
unforeseen errors at any level of testing,
from entering erroneous data to test scenarios that will
be incompatible with the functionality.
And this type of testing can flush out any weird or strange
occurrences with data or logic validation.
Smoke testing is kind of an initial testing effort to determine if
a new software version is even performing well enough to be
accepted for testing in the first place.
Why waste the time and effort of your UAT team if
the darn thing won't even load.
So, for example, if the new software doesn't allow valid logins,
or the menu items do not take the user to the correct pages,
or maybe even you have some words misspelled,
the software may not be in a condition to warrant
further testing in its current state.
So this is also performed throughout the entire testing lifecycle to ensure
that each version of the software is not dead on arrival.
Development testing includes the writing and exaction of unit tests.
So this is testing that's just focused simply on the software
engineers themselves and it helps them test in an automated way
business logic and to ensure code coverage.
Integration testing,
usually one of the most complex of all the testing scenarios here,
because it's testing all the combined parts of an application to
determine if they function together correctly.
But what if you have, you know,
a half dozen APIs and 14 different databases and data
flowing and all those kinds of things,
it can make integration testing very challenging because
you're going to also have pre-conditions in order to do the
integration testing in the first place.
And lastly, regression testing.
So basically this is when you finish testing in an area of an application,
you may then test other areas not expected to have been affected to
ensure that no new errors have been introduced.
Now this is pretty tough,
regression testing is very time consuming and rarely performed,
but should as much as possible.
So you go over and fix an area, an area say A,
and you go ahead and do the testing for A,
but you realize you have B, C, and D, should you test those again?
Most people say hey I don't have time,
but regression testing would make it all the way through again,
A, B, C, and D and make sure it all works.
Very important, but time consuming and costly.
So if the user acceptance testing is now a success
and the identified user says okay,
I'm going to give the okay to promote to production, let's go check out promote to production.