Now that we've promoted the last release into production,
we'll likely have some application maintenance,
and let's explore and define application maintenance in this section.
Application maintenance is the activity consisting of planned
minor fixes and enhancements into an application that is in
production for user organizations.
For purposes of this course it excludes hot fixes,
user ID management and authorization.
I will discuss these in operational support section since I look at these
items as op support and not application maintenance.
You may not agree with all my definitions in this module,
but I need to set up some definitions, put some scope around it,
so you know what I'm talking about in the context.
You may use different definitions and different terms in
your environment and that is okay.
Project versus hot fix versus application maintenance.
So for context, I would like to divide up the world as follows,
for larger, chunkier backlog items I like to call them a project.
In one company I was helping it was 80 hours or more was considered a project.
So anything over that was identified as a project and
the work followed a different process.
It had a project manager, et cetera.
I will talk about this later in this module in the project management section.
For a production problem, or what I call a hot fix,
I see this as more of a production ops or operational issue.
I also include user ID management and feature authorization in ops as well.
And I will talk about operations in a later section of this module too.
Lastly, application maintenance,
such as new requirements that fall under the project threshold,
and bugs, but they are bugs that can be lived with or tolerated,
they're not quick fixes, got to have it right now.
Okay,
of course you can design your world any way you want as long as you design it,
document it, and train everyone and it is not just chaos.
Okay, as a reminder,
all normal work comes into the work intake process that we already
discussed in the first section of this module,
except for hot fixe and production failures.
Okay let's dig deeper into application maintenance.
Here is a real simple process for application maintenance,
it can be certainly improved and elaborated upon.
Your application maintenance backlog, that is all of your potential work items,
and again we are not considering projects or hot fixes for
this section on application maintenance.
A backlog item might remain in your backlog for months or
even years if the priority warrants it.
We actually want to groom the backlog,
that is in this phase we want to describe the
process of view with your customer, typically reviewing the items,
their priority, timing, need, estimates,
et cetera.
You might consider performing the grooming process once a week,
determine the right cadence for you and your customer.
The outcome of the grooming is that you have identified work items to be worked.
They are basically released for work into your team.
Therefore, next you want to assign the work,
that is select your resources, the people on your team to work that item.
You may pick more than one person to work on an item if you want to, of course.
Then you work the work.
Then the work gets, well, worked.
Next, determine a release.
A release is like a bucket, that is,
what are all the work items that you are targeting for in the next release.
There may be just one, there may be a half a dozen,
it depends what works for you.
Then you're going to create a build that includes all of the
work items determined for this release.
And then of course,
you're going to promote to production and we've
already discussed that process earlier.
So now let's talk about actually doing the work and how
you might manage your daily work tasks.
Here is a quick simple technique known as Kanban, originally from Japan.
So Kanban is a Japanese term for visual signal or card.
Toyota line workers use a Kanban, that is an actual card,
to signal steps in their manufacturing process.
The system's highly visible nature allowed teams to communicate more
easily on what work needed to be done and when.
It also standardized cues and refined processes,
which helped to reduce waste and maximize value.
So this technique can be used as well for software development.
So a simple Kanban board, if you will, may have a list of to do items,
which would be the backlog items, doing,
the things you're actually doing in work,
or items that are done, that are complete.
So you can be really creative as well and you can have different categories.
Maybe you have one for re-do, in other words it was done and a defect was found,
so it's in the re-do pile, if you will, or maybe the feature is moved into UAT,
User Acceptance Testing, or maybe a feature is moved into production,
it's actually completed into production.
So let's see a real simple example in the next slide.
Here's a sample Kanban board,
just to give you a general idea of what they're all about.
First we may have a little grid pattern like this and we're going to have a
column for the to do items and a column for the doing items,
the things in work, and a column for the done items.
And we could use cards like you see at the left there,
here are all the things we need to do, these are our backlog items.
And then as they get released and then we start working on them,
they'll be moved over, the card might just be picked up,
it could be a post it note or something like that,
there are a lot of Kanban board tools in the industry today,
check them out online.
And the last column, of course, is the done column.
So we can all easily see what is it we have to do,
what are we working on,
and what's done and you can do a simple standup every
morning and discuss it with the team.
Now a particular card might look something like this, it might say task 3.
2, this is the 12 month scheduling feature,
so that's the feature that's being worked on.
In the lower left corner of the card Joe and Mary are working on it,
and in the right corner it's identified as having maybe 32 hours of effort.
You can design your card any way you want to so the team can
quickly understand what it is all about.
Now let's look at another example.
So here's another sample.
Of course we have the grid, we have the to do items,
we have the doing items and I added a re-do column and then a done.
So if something was done and was found to be a defect,
I would move the card back to the re-do column.
So we have all our to do items, our doing items, our re-do and our done.
Now you could add even more columns to represent UAT or promote to production,
as examples.
Be creative with not only your columns, but the information on the card as well.
Just be sure it is very simple,
easy to read and easy to understand by your team and even easy
to read and understand by your manager or your customer so they
can easily see what you're doing.
Very transparent,
very powerful and I would suggest a stand up every morning to
review with the team where you're at and what you're doing and
everyone knows their assignments for the day,
and things will move very smoothly forward. Now let's move to the next section on operational support.