Yes, you need to write status reports and you may need to write several per week.
Now maybe your team will author some of those for you,
but you'll still need to review and send out yourself.
So to whom do you send your status reports?
Well for me there are three main types of status report recipients.
Now they are across to your customer, up to your manager,
and down to your team as follows.
So first your customers,
now the lack of a status report is usually interpreted by a customer as either,
hmm something's wrong or you don't know what is going on.
You do not what that impression of you.
In fact, your consistent status reports,
following the 5 C's, will support a positive,
professional perception of you and your team by your customers.
So consistent statusing your customers is important, never miss one.
So whatever the cadence is, for example,
every week on Wednesday or maybe every week on Friday
or maybe the first of the month, figure out what that cadence is,
get the bio from the customer to make sure they're okay with that,
and then never miss a one.
What you want, this will sound silly,
but you want is for your customer to see the status report come in and
then just delete it because they know it's regular,
they know it's consistent, they know it's professional and they trust you.
Alright, you want to also status your management.
Be consistent.
I suggest copying your management also on your other status reports
that are going through customers or stakeholders.
He will also see the progress and quality of your work
as well as your customer's will too.
And you also want, of course, status your team.
Now statusing your team may be on the informal side as well,
quick little emails or whatever,
but on the formal side it might be company policy that comes down,
HR related things that come down,
here's the schedule for the performance reviews and things like that.
So you'll want to follow the formal structure because this is a formal and
professional email that you'll want to send to your team.
Alright, let's talk a little bit more about the structure of a status report.
Whenever you are writing a status report,
always answer at least one key question.
In other words, where is the project or activity now?
Because that is what your customer or management will be looking for.
Just where are we right now, where are we going, what are the issues?
Okay so to answer that, we must look at both the past,
the present,
and the future because any status report is built
with the following three categories.
Okay, what's been done or progressed?
You're looking at the past, what has been achieved to this point?
What is left to do or what are the plans, what's in the future?
What are our goals or objectives and plans yet to do?
And then are there any issues or problems?
What challenges have been encountered?
Items that are stuck or can't be finished sometimes are known as blockers.
Problems to issues often need help from someone else or other organizations.
Those should be noted in the status report as well.
Okay I call progress, plans, and problems, Michael's 3 P's.
That's the basis for the simplest and most common status report
on which all variations I think are based on.
You could also look at these three sections a little differently,
what's done, what's to do, open issues.
It's the same.
So you can always add additional categories to progress, plans and problems.
And in software development you could just list
things like proposed feature ideas, ala scrum,
additional backlog ideas, you could add an area for customer feedback,
you can add an area for logistics, for example,
we're going to be out of town one week and we're changing the meeting locations,
so you can add other categories,
but the three core categories you should always include in the status report,
progress, plans, and problems.
Okay, so what do you think about this module so far?
Do you have what it takes to be an effective communicator? Let's see.