Now for my closing thoughts about the wisdom of
listening and the importance of people.
To this point I have been discussing several formal
and informal communication topics.
This is pretty much you communicating to others.
But please remember that you need to do more listening than talking.
And boy that's actually pretty hard.
Good listeners are rare.
I have to constantly remind myself to slow down and listen to others.
Even after all these years of communicating,
I personally still need to improve in this area.
In fact,
I used to have a little post-it note behind where people
would sit in my office so that while I was talking to them
it reminded me to listen as well.
That helped me remind me to stop talking and listen more.
So give it a try.
Listening effectively takes practice.
"Wisdom is the reward you get for a lifetime of
listening when you would rather have talked.
" - Mark Twain.
It's a great quote.
The point of this slide is that if you can be patient and listen to others,
there are several rewards, people will respect you,
appreciate you, and be more loyal to you,
and as a bonus you will have learned so much more about
them and the topic they're talking about.
Okay now let's see what business is all about.
Do you have any ideas?
What this all comes down to is that business is about people,
it always has been and always will be.
Too often businesses fall short,
not because the leaders don't understand the business,
they usually do quite well,
but because they don't understand what the people who work for them
need in order to bring their best effort to work.
This is your challenge, it will not be easy.
But now that you are aware of it, you can make a difference, and I know you can.
Okay, let's summarize this module.
So here's a recap of the module.
Now first we talked about some informal communication methods,
such as stand ups, those are the real quick,
yep you're standing up,
maybe 3 or 4 or 5 people in a conference room or a corner somewhere,
just doing hey here's what I did yesterday,
here's what I plan to do today and the issues and around you go.
There are also the walk arounds, this is where you got up and walked around,
maybe you went to the kitchen or went somewhere and you
stopped and you poked your head into an office,
try not to bother anybody, a quick hello,
good morning, how's it going, what'd you do last weekend,
how's this project going, things like that.
Real quick, real informal, nothing big issue wise or anything like that,
just a hello, I recognize you're there, I recognize you're working hard,
how are you doing?
And of course, informal emails, which are fine,
but again the point of this communication module is on the
formal emails compared to the informal emails.
So use informal emails sparingly please.
And just plain daily interactions, what are all the things you do,
your behaviors, the way you hold your body,
the way you talk to people, your voice,
your mannerisms and how you get around and get along with everyone,
that's important, people are watching.
Formal.
Okay we had several ways to communicate with formal and that is presentations,
you've going to have to be able to develop and deliver quality presentations,
have your outcome in mind,
so you can put together the slides just in the way
you need to get what you want.
Know who your audience is going to be so you can deliver the best presentation.
Next would be meetings, lots of different kinds of meetings.
So meet with your customers, you meet with your managers,
you meet with your team or maybe individually,
you'll do performance reviews, you might meet with suppliers,
consultants, lots of different meeting forums,
each must have an agenda,
you will lead those meetings and you'll come up with
action items and things like that.
Then you're going to have your follow up email that'll talk
about everything that happened in the meeting,
notes, action items and things like that.
That's very, very important.
We talked about formal emails.
And that the TO: is who you want it to go to from the sense of I
want them to read it and give me feedback.
The CC: are more informational only.
The Subject is important because we want it to be clear and concise,
easy to read,
easy to understand and also a little compelling so they'll click and open it.
And we had a template for the body,
and I suggested to you that you use that template for every
single formal email and then just tweak it or add or subtract
some things from that to make it your own.
Next, status reporting.
I know that's a tough one, most people hate writing status reports,
but it is extremely important, especially to your customers that you do that,
so they see a consistent message from you and that you're on the ball.
You're going to talk about progress, what you did,
plans, what you're going to do, and any problems or issues,
so everything is transparent and your customer knows exactly what's going on.
Of course we also talked about listening and that's a tough one, as I mentioned.
Try to listen.
You know, next time you're in a meeting,
especially one on one, see how long you can go within talking.
That's not easy.
Practice better listening skills.
And lastly, read my lips, "it's all about the people,
" people are what makes the world go round,
makes the professional environment what it is,
and it is extremely rewarding to have that relationship with people.
Build that relationship, trust them, get them to trust you as well.
Alright,
now in the next module we're going to discuss the key and critical processes you
need to have in place to run a smooth and productive team. See you there.