So, here are the key skill groups of practical team management.
Aligning IT activities to the business.
Everything you do should make a difference to the business.
Managing customer expectations,
make sure what your team is doing is in alignment to what
your customers think you are doing.
Building team skills and capabilities.
A good manager and leader is always improving their
team skills and capabilities.
Acquiring the right talent.
Team building is not just about building a team from the inside but
also from the outside through good hiring practices.
Managing through effective communication.
To excel at being a manager you will need good maybe even
excellent written and communication skills.
Lastly, promoting productivity through team processes.
In this module we covered just how you're going to make that software. Alright, now let's do a summary of each of these modules.