There is a demand for IT manager and team leaders in the market today.
So with that growing demand,
employment of computer and information systems managers is
projected to grow 15% between now and 2024.
That is much faster than the average of all occupations.
Demand for computer and information systems managers will grow as firms
increasingly expand their business to digital platforms.
The median annual wage for computer and information
systems managers was about $130, 000 last year,
in 2015, that's pretty good.
Companies that have realized that respected,
well trained manager boost morale, and improve morale boosts retention,
well there you go, that's a cost savings as well.
Now let's explore the value of a good manager to a company.
I would like to end my overview with this thought provoking question,
what's the value of a good manager?
To you as a software engineer, you might say little or no value.
I have heard the chat at the water cooler about management.
Now what is the value of good management to a company?
Well I say priceless.
If my key managers left me,
I think my company would be greatly impacted and
would take me awhile to recover.
A great manager has enormous value, I've seen it, lived it, and breathed it.
Think about your own career for a moment,
this is anecdotal, but I think people take jobs because they like the company,
but people leave the company because of the manager they work for.
So don't be one of those managers and shoot from the hip,
start with a set of processes and tools in this course to get
your jump started quickly and on your way to becoming the most
successful manager you can be.
What more can I say? Let's get started.