In this video we're going to configure the code light idea that we just installed to work on our windows
system with C++.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to start code like.
So I'm just going to double click on the icon and the first time that you run code like you'll probably
get a little setup wizard pop up and here it is.
You may also get a window that says you want to update to the latest version which you can certainly
do.
I'm going to cancel for this video.
And here's the setup wizard.
Now it's important that you run through this setup wizard.
If this does not show up for the first time you can always find it appear you can still like help and
then you can run the setup wizard here.
But in this case it does show up.
So I'm going to go through this and only have to do this one time.
I'm going to select next.
Now here the way that code works is it uses a lot of plugins to support ph C C plus plus and so forth.
We only care about C++ in this case.
So what we want to do is we want to clear these plugins so you can see all the checkmarks are gone and
then we want to toggle the C++ plugins only someone to select that until only the C++ ones show up.
OK so that's what we need to do.
Just make sure that not all of them are set up just some of them you can use that toggle to do it or
select next.
Now we want to set up the compiler.
Now remember if you've already installed the Mingy w compiler then you could just click scan if you
haven't go back to the video and install it.
I wouldn't install it from this option because it installs an older version of the GW compiler.
So I'm going to scan and it should find it.
There it is.
So I want to select it and press next.
Now here you can customize the colors to whatever you like.
This dark moniker chi theme is kind of nice on the vision it's not so hard in your eyes but for the
video.
I'm going to use the classic eclipse look that way I think it shows up a little better on video so I
select next will leave these defaults as is and will press finish.
OK now at this point you want to save and exit.
It's going to ask you this every time you make a change and it gets pretty annoying.
So I'm just going to say remember my answer and don't ask me again and every time I make a change I
want to save and exit soft save and exit.
OK so it saves it and it opens it up again and now the settings that I set were applied.
And again I'll cancel the new download here.
So let me make this full screen here.
And as I mentioned before if that setup wizard does not show up you can started here.
Run the setup wizard.
OK so now what we want to do is we want to create a new workspace and once we create the new workspace
We'll run.
I have a couple of settings to do and then once that's done it will be all set.
So let's create a new workspace.
A workspace is basically an area where you can have different C++ projects in.
So the first thing we want to do is create a new workspace I'll select that.
You can also say file new workspace.
OK so I'll do it right here and it's going to ask me for the name of the workspace so I'll just say
see workspace.
You can do this whatever you like if you want to have a workspace rather the section one exercises section
2 Section 3 or whatever you like whatever makes sense for you.
I'm going to put it in my documents folder and I want to create the workspace under a separate directory.
That just helps me organize my files.
I'll select OK.
Good now you can see here on the left pane of my workspace view I've got a workspace now the workspace
in and of itself.
Is it real useful.
I need to create a project within the workspace so I can right click on workspace and say new project.
So I'll do that and select new project.
At this point we've got some options.
We're going to select the console option and then simple execrable G plus plus that's basically the
C++ compiler.
It's called C++ because it's from a canoe.
So I'll select that next.
And then you give your project a name.
This could be again any name you like.
Avoid spaces just to be safe.
Just simple name so I'll say test one let's say.
And again I want to create a project under in a separate directory or press.
Next here you can choose the compiler has probably already chosen it for you if you've got multiple
compilers.
You can set individual compilers on a per project level but we're using the GW compiler and we're using
the good debugger.
The build system will be default and select to finish.
So it's gone off and created a new project you could see it here on the left side it's called Test 1.
And as I explode these you can see that there's my main file.
That's the program that it's created for me by fault the dots BPP extension means that it's a C++ file.
I'm going to double click on that and you can see my fondest.
Pretty small here because I just installed this let me increase my font.
You may not have to do this on your end but it's going to show up better on video if I do it.
Someone to go to settings colors and fonts and not just set it to 16.
It should be nice ply can go that way it's much easier for you to see.
Now what we want to do is we want to delete all this.
This is actually C-code not C++ code.
So let's delete all of that and let's write a real simple test from scratch.
So the first thing we'll do is we'll include IO stream.
This allows us to do input and output.
And we'll talk much more about what these include directives mean in a future video.
In this example just type along and make sure that the environment is working.
So you want to say pound include and IO stream in angle brackets.
Then we want to say int space main.
This is our main function to Prendes and we'll create a couple of Curley's curly braces then in here
we're going to say is s t d colon colon.
Seek out the insertion operator which is two less than signs followed by a low testing or anything you
like.
And then a semi-colon at the end and then finally return 0.
That's it.
That's a simple test.
Again will be a separate video where I go over the anatomy of a C++ program and we'll go over all this
in detail.
So in this case again we're including IO stream.
We've got our main function and we're printing hello testing to the screen where we're turning zero
which means programs successful.
I'm going to save this and I'm not going to do this on the videos but you can certainly do this at home
if you come up to view and you can toggle the minimal view.
When you do that you'll get some icons up here you can use these icons to build and say for example
that's a safe right there.
I'm not going to do that because I don't want as much screen real estate as possible on the videos so
I'll just toggle that off.
OK.
So I'm going to file say.
And at this point we're ready to run the program but we need to make a couple of changes just because
we want to use modern C++.
So what we can do is we can click on the project test one in this example and all right click and then
at the bottom you'll see settings.
So select settings and you can see right down here at the bottom where global settings.
I want to select that and where it says C++ compiler options.
You can click right in there and then you'll see these three little dots here and the buttons are useless
and other menus you can select that.
And we want to make sure that a couple of things are set.
We want to be sure that C plus plus 14 is checked.
That means we're using the latest version of the standard which is modern C++.
We also want to be sure that the w h l l all warnings is checked.
OK.
So that's it for now.
That will be fine.
We will select OK
and we'll apply and.
Okay perfect.
Now I also want to click on the workspace itself and right click on that and come down to workspace
settings and select that.
And when you come to code completion you want to be sure that C++ 14 standard is enabled code completion
is something that the ID does as you type is trying to figure out what you want to do and help you out
so you don't have to do a lot of typing.
And in this case we want to tell it to use the foreignness C++ 14 standard so when it's trying to figure
things out.
So I select OK.
Now at this point we should be ready to try this out.
Someone expand this little window down here at the bottom and I'm going to come up to it says build
and then we'll select clean project then we'll go back to build and just say run at this point it's
going to say what do you want to do.
Do you just want to run it or you want to build it and run it.
In this case I want to build it and run and not talk more about the workflow that's used for cleaning
and compiling and so forth a little bit later on in the course.
So in this case I want to say build and execute and it will compile and run the program.
If there are no errors it'll run and you'll get a window pop up with the output.
Hello testing in there.
If there are errors let me show you what they might look like.
Just in case you do see them.
Suppose I forget that semi-colon at the end there and I'm going to say build run build and execute and
you can see this red down here that says error.
I expected a semi-colon before the return.
You also get a read error here and it says again semi-colon expected So basically you just put the semi-colon
in there save it and then go back up to build and run build and execute.
You can click on here for it to remember to always build and execute or just execute again.
Don't do that yet.
We'll do that as the course progresses and I'll show you the different workflows we can use.
Build and execute.
There we go.
Now if at this point you get a error that says that some DLF can't be found then what you want to do
is you want to go back to the project right click and go down to settings.
And remember you only have to do this if you get some kind of runtime error that says some C-p PDL file
was not found and go to global settings and then would you want to do is you want to go to the linker
options and just select write on there and click that little button and down here at the bottom what
you want to do is you just want to add a couple of lines you can say Dasch static dash lib GCC and then
press center and that Dasch static dash lib.
S t d.
C plus plus.
OK so what will happen here is now the linker is going to statically link the files and not have to
use dynamically linked libraries or DL else.
Again you only have to do this if you if you get that error if you don't get the error you can do it
also and it's not going to hurt but still like to OK apply and let's do a build rebuild.
Let's do a clean first.
Whenever you change any kind of settings you want to clean the project which really just cleans everything
up and gives you a starting place.
So will clean the project and then we'll just say run build and execute.
In this case it's going to statically link it which is just as good and hello testing.
We're all set at this point.
We've got a grid install it's configured and we're ready to use code like to start learning C++.