Now that we've downloaded and installed the command line tools and the C++ compiler will now install
the code light ID code light as an integrated development environment that's cross-platform open source.
It runs on Mac OS 10 Linux and Windows in this video we're going to install it on Mac OS 10.
So open up your favorite browser and go to code light dot org.
That's Cod LITV dot org and you'll see a web page similar to this.
You want to find the download link.
You can see one here at the top bar menu and there's also this big blue button which is the one I'm
going to click on select that.
And you take you to a page where you can contribute to the developers if you wish or you could just
go straight to the downloads and I'll do that.
So I said I tried here not now.
Take me to the download.
Now here we've got some options that we can install for Windows for Mac for Linux and so forth.
We're interested in Mac in this example.
So the third one down says code like 11.0 app bundle for OS 10 that's the one I want and I'm going to
select the direct link to begin the download.
The file is not very large but the download quite slow from the site.
I'll post a video of the download occurs once the download is complete.
You can see that it's downloaded a compressed archive file.
So what I'll do is open that
and I'll double click on it to compress it.
There is my code Light App which I just drag to my Applications folder.
That's it.
Code lights now on our system in the next video will run code like and configure it to use C++ compilers
on Mac OS 10.