This video will run and configure code light on Mac OS 10 and we've already installed the compiler tools
and we've installed code like.
So let's run code like will come up to Spotlight search and type code light and double click on the
icon
will allow it to run.
Now the first time that code light runs a couple of things will happen.
You get the small code like windows show up and then you get a setup wizard we just leave that window
smallest will make it larger in a minute it's not really going to get in our way right now.
What's important is that we run this set up wizard if the setup wizard does not start come up to code
lights menu and go up to help and then run the setup wizard and run it manually.
OK.
But here in this case it did pop up.
So let's select next
code like uses a bunch of plugins to allow support for HP and know it and other technologies.
We don't really want all that.
We only want the C++ plug.
The rest are just going to clutter up our interface.
So what we can do here is we can press clear and then just toggle the C++ plugins that way.
Only some of these will show up which is exactly what we want.
We just want to concentrate on C++.
So like next.
Now we can scan our computer for any installed compilers we can press this button here and you can see
it's found GCC clang and across GCC we're going to use gcc.
They're really the same but we'll use gcc here and press next.
Now the customisation of the theme is really up to you.
This is your personal preference the moniker dark theme is real nice and easy on the eyes but it doesn't
show up too well on video so I'm going to select the classic eclipse theme and select next will keep
these defaults and press finish.
Now what we can do here is we can say Save and Exit you want to be sure that you save so we can save
the changes we've made
and we can run code light again.
OK so this time I want to make this window nice and big
and we've got a couple of options that we still need to contribute.
But before we do that we need to create a workspace.
You can create a workspace by clicking this button here or by coming up to file new workspace.
Either place works fine.
A workplace is just an area where we can have our C++ projects so we can have multiple projects in a
workspace.
So I'm going to select a new workspace and the workspace name could be anything you like.
I'm going to say the workspace don't use any spaces here just keep it all together and I want to create
the workspace under a separate directory so I can keep my files organized.
Select OK and you can see that it's created the workspace over here on the left pane.
Now we need to create a C++ project so you can right click on that and select new project or you can
select the workspace and then come up to file new project.
Either way now we've got some options.
We're going to create a console project and simple executable plus plus right here and that's the compiler
we're going to use and we'll select next the project name again don't use any spaces here just create
your name the name for your project whatever you'd like.
Again I'm going to create a separate directory for each project and I'll select next as far as the compiler
would want to use the gcc compiler but the debugger we don't want to use the new debugger we want to
use the l l DB debugger.
That's the apple divider.
So let's finish and you can see over here on the left that we've created a project called Test 1 and
it's just short directory and it's got a file there called main C.
Now before we run that file there's a couple of things that we need to set up.
First click on the project.
In this case test one right click and then come down to settings and select that then done here to toward
the bottom where you see global settings come up to compiler options and select the right side and then
you'll see this little button right here with the three dots select.
And what we want to do here is we want to check a couple of options when we scroll all the way up and
I want to like enable all compiler warnings wall and I want to enable C plus plus 14 features.
That's the latest standard that's modern C++.
Want to make sure that that's enabled.
And this guy doesn't come on but you can see that it is there.
Sometimes it doesn't check on.
You can see that the command line is correct.
So just click OK I'll apply and click OK.
Perfect.
Now go to the workspace select it right click on it and come down to workspace settings and you'll see
we have environment and code completion slide code completion.
And check the Enable C++ 14 standard.
The integrated development environments.
Use code completion they try to figure out what you're typing and what you want to do and where you
want to go and really help you out with suggestions.
In this case we're simply telling code like to use the C++ 14 standard for those suggestions click OK
and that's it for the set up.
Now let's modify this C++ file and run it.
That's double click on that and that's font is really small so I'm going to do is I'm going to make
it a little larger so it shows up better on the video.
Most likely you won't have to touch it at all.
But I'm just going to come to settings colors and fonts and I'll set the font to let's say 18
I'll apply that and that should be much more readable.
OK so now let's modify this file.
This is actually C-code Nazi posts plus code.
So let's get rid of all this and we'll type a simple C plus plus program that will test our installation
during this course.
Will go in detail through the anatomy of a C++ program and everything I'll be typing here will be explained.
But for now just follow along type along to make sure we've got a clean install.
So the first thing you want to do is win a type pounde include and we want to put IO stream in angle
brackets and press Enter then int space main left and right person then we want to open up a left Kerley
and you can see that the IEEE has closed it for me.
And then what I want to do here is I just want to say as T.G. to call in side by side no spaces and
then seek out the insertion operator which is to signs again together with no spaces and anything you
want to type here as far as hello testing we want to type of string inside double quotes and a semi-colon
at the end and then next line will be returned 0.
That's it.
That's the entire program.
When we run this program what we want to do is we want to display hello testing to the console.
That's all it's going to do.
I'll save this
under File at this point on your end you may want to do.
You toggle minimal view and that will display.
We do that again that will display some buttons and things up here which you might find useful.
I'm not going to do that because it clutters up the screen and I don't want any distractions when I'm
teaching the class to toggle that away.
And what I'll do is rather than click on the buttons I'll be really explicit as to click on build run
build clean and so forth.
That way you can see exactly what's going on.
Once you get familiar with the ID you can use those buttons.
That's it.
So I've saved it.
Now I want to run this first thing I want to do is I want to go to build and clean the project when
we clean a project we're basically just wiping out everything that's been done in the past except the
source code.
So the project is in a state that's ready to go so I'm going to clean it and then I'm going to come
back up to build and I'm going to say run now it's going to give me an option that says Would you like
to build the active project before executing it.
Of course I do because I haven't built yet in this case so I'm going to select build and execute and
that will compile the program and open up a window and there's the output right there.
Hello testing.
So this terminal window is running the program that I just wrote.
That's it.
It's as simple as that.
Some things could go wrong though.
Suppose that you forgot this semi-colon here and I'll say it and then I'll do the same I'll do run build
and execute and you can see if I move this window just slightly up you can see that I've got a compiler
error and this is what compiler errors look like.
You see the read text here and it says error expected a semi-colon after an expression.
Also you'll see that little red arrow right here telling you just something wrong here.
And basically what you need to do is put a semi-colon there just type the program really carefully exactly
like I did and you won't have any problems.
But you know you could have things missing like this.
Quote The first quote is missing.
This time I have three less than signs.
There's all kinds of little things that could go wrong with the program but if you'd just be very careful
type it in save it and come back up to build and run build and execute and you can click on there if
you like that we don't have to keep doing it all the time.
And there's a run.
That's it.
We're all set on Mac.
We've installed the command line tools we've installed code like we've configured code light and we're
good to go.
Now let's start learning C++.