This video we'll go over the steps necessary to write build and execute C++ programs from the command
line on a Mac.
All we really need is a terminal session and an editor.
Now as far as the editor is concerned there are a bunch of editors out there some of them are free some
of them are paid editors.
The one I'm going to use in this example is called Atom A T O M and you can download it from the Internet
and it's absolutely free.
And it's a fine text editor.
Now before I do that I'm going to create a folder on my desktop and I'm going to call it CVP projects.
And within that folder I'm going to create another folder called Project 1
and this is where we're going to store our source files.
Ok so now what we need is we need an editor and we need a terminal window so let's create both of them
first let's create the terminal session.
So get a spotlight search and type terminal and press enter.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to move this terminal over here on the right so that it's right
doc just perfectly and I'm going to run the Adam editor Now again you can run any editor you like.
And there's the Adam editor and all closed down so these tabs here so that we're here from scratch.
Perfect.
And again I'm going to just dump this over here on the left side.
OK so now what we want to do is we want to create a file in that folder that we just created.
So let's go to a file new file and it's going to be a C++ file so I'm going to save this right now so
that Adam knows it it's a C++ file missing file save as
and I want to put this on my desk top
in my CGP projects project one folder and I want to name the file name that C.P
That said I'll save it.
And now we can start typing our C++ program.
It's really straightforward that simple hello world program is what we're going to write so we're going
to say pound include and you could see that we've saved it as a dot file Adam knows and it's C++.
So it's going to allow us to you know it's going to help us out with the code highlighting and syntax
highlighting some of the include IO stream.
Then I'm going to have my main I'll say and main open close friends and open Cur-Lee which it completes
forming.
Now here all I'm going to say is SCD.
Colon's seek out it followed by the insertion operator which did to less than signs together and I'll
just say any string.
I'll just say hello Mac command line and I'll terminate that string and then I'll put a new line at
the end so the cursor goes to the next line when we do the output.
So that's the end DL It will return 0.
That's it.
That's the program will save it.
Now we need to go over to our terminal to compile and run it.
When you open up the terminal it defaults in your home directory so you can see if you type D that prints
the working directory which is users followed by your user name.
That's not where I want to be.
I want to be in the desktop folder that we created so we can use a CD command to change directory and
I'll just type desktop and you can press tab to autocomplete.
Sonam in the desktop directory that I want to go to my CPV projects directory and finally to my project
one directory.
That's where I'm at now if I want to know what's in there.
Just type LS which gives you a file listing and you can see there's maned not see Peepy that's this
file we just created in the editor what we want to do now is we want to compile this file.
So what we want to do is when to type G plus plus that's the name of the compiler that will execute
the compiler.
Then we want to provide the compiler the same switches that we did in the ID so will say dash capital
W o l.
So it turns on all warnings.
Do we want to write dash s t d equals C++ 14.
That'll tell us.
Tell it to use modern C plus plus the 14 standard.
Now we tell it what files you want to compile.
In this case I only have one main dot CTP.
If you have more than one you would just list them all separated by spaces.
But here we've got main Dotsie peepee.
That's it that's all you need to do.
You press enter.
We get no error messages.
No news is good news.
Would do an ls again and you can see that now we've got a new file created called a dot out.
That's the default executor files name when you don't provide a name in order to run this.
You just type a dot slash aid out out when I press Enter we should see.
Hello Matt.
Command line.
That's exactly what we see.
That's this statement right here executing.
It's as simple as that.
Now if you don't like 8. out you want to provide your own file name you can come up in what I'm doing
here as I'm pressing the up arrow and the down arrow you can see it's going through what I've typed.
So you want to go back to the statement where you ran the compiler and just type a dash lowercase O
and whatever name you want.
Your executor put a B in the press center.
Now if we do a directory listing you can see that main is there if you want to run main dot slash main
and that's it.
We've created a file a C++ program.
We compiled it and we ran it using only the command line.
No IDs and as I mentioned there's a whole bunch of editors out there that you can use add them brackets
text Wrangler text mate sublime and there's a bunch much more you can just do a search on on Google
and you can come up with a bunch of examples of text editors.
OK so let's talk about compiler errors now.
I'm going to clear the screen here and I can do that in the terminal by just type clear and let's get
rid of that semi-colon at the end here.
Now if I run the compiler again you can see I've got a clean compile that makes no sense because I created
an error here by removing the semi-colon while the issue is that I never saved this file.
When you work with the IDs the IDs sync everything up.
So they realize that your source code has changed so they're going to compile the latest version of
it.
Here these two are two separate programs and not saying.
You're the person that has to sync them together by making sure you save it.
So in this case I'm going to come here and do file save or command s.
Now when I come back here and compile again I'll see the error which says I'm missing a semi-colon so
I'll add that semi-colon.
If I put a semi-colon in here at the end of IO stream which I should not have.
I'll save it and then I'll go compile it again.
You can see this an extra token at the end of the line.
It's complaining about it so I can go back here.
Command us again to save.
And I can recompile this time I'll get a clean compile and I can run my main.
That's it.
It's as simple as that.
If you don't have the resources to run an ID or you do like the idea or you feel the idea is confusing
you and not really allow you to focus on the C++.
This is a great alternative.
Pretty easy pretty fast.
Go be a business real quick.