It this video will go over the steps necessary to create build and run a C++ program on Ubuntu Linux
using only a text editor and the command line.
So in this video we won't be using any integrated development environment.
First of all I've created a folder on my desktop called C-p projects and in that folder I've created
another folder called Project 1.
This is where we're going to store our C++ program.
In this case it's just going to be a man a real simple test.
So I'd like to close this up and the first thing we need to do is we need some sort of editor to type
in our program now on Linux.
We've got it.
I could just come to search my computer and type g at it and we can use that text editor which is a
fine text editor it's real simple.
It's comes with your installation.
There are many other text editors and programmer text editors that you can use like brackets Adam and
many others but this one is already here so you may as well use it and it works just fine.
I've gone ahead and gone to Edit Preferences and I just turned on line numbers and you can set all kinds
of different settings that you like.
I made the font also a little bigger so you could see it.
So it may look a little different when you start yours.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to write this C++ program.
So let's do include
IO streams just like we've done before.
I'll leave a space a little say into main two parentheses.
The open curly and are close to Curly while I'm at it.
And now we'll just say we could just press tab will say as t d to Colon's C out the insertion operator
which is to less than signs bright together with no spaces.
Now I'll say hello who buntu command line will close the string.
We'll put another insertion operator and let's put a new line at the end that we have our cursor will
go to the next line when we do the output and that's e and d l followed by a semi-colon and then we
return 0.
Just like we always do.
That's it.
That's our C++ program.
Now it's important that we save this with the DOT extension and not a t xt the extension the C++ compiler
does not like to seek extensions and you're going to get all kinds of weird errors.
OK so let's do that let's go to File Save As we'll find where we want to say that we want to save toward
desktop projects.
Project 1 that's where we would like to save it and I'll give it to name as main Dotsie Peepy.
Now you'll notice a couple of things when I named the file C.P the editor's smart realizes that this
is not a regular text file to see post-box text file.
So I'll save it and notice what happened here.
Notice the color coding it knows C++.
Again it's not an integrated development environment so it doesn't have a lot of hooks to the compiler
and so forth but you can see that now it's really helping me because I can see that my string is terminated.
For example if I get rid of that guy then that's black and it shouldn't be black it should be a magenta
color.
So again I'm going to press control as to save that file.
Now we'd like to compile and run it.
So in order to do that we need to open up a terminal so I come up back up here and say terminal and
that will open up a terminal which I'll pull down just right by here so we can run them together.
Now one of the things that you'll notice is that if you do a PWT which prints your working directory
I'm in home.
Frank I don't want to be at home Frank I want to be in this directory right up here that you can see
desktop C-p project's Project 1.
So I need to change into that directory and could use a CD command to change directories.
So I want to go to my desktop and you can press tab for completion auto completion and press enter.
Then I want to press that I want to type CD see projects and then finally Project 1 and you can do this
all in one line if you like.
I just did it in three steps.
So now I'm in the correct directory if I want to know what's in that directory or I could just type
LS which gives me a list of the directory.
And you could see that my main file is there.
That's the one that I want to compile.
So let me make this thing a little bit wider so you can see what I'm typing here.
So the first thing I want to do is I want to execute the compiler so I want to say G plus plus that
calls the compiler.
That's the new C++ compiler and I want to set some options.
These are the same options that we would set with the ID here we're just going to set them as switches
right at the command line.
So when I say capital W A L L that turns on all warnings then I want to say dash s t d equals C plus
plus 14 that's going to use the for the 2014 C post-Bush standard which is the latest one that's out
there.
Now we supply what do you want to compile.
I want to compile the main but c file main Dotsie P.P..
That's it.
So it's going to execute the compiler turn on all warnings.
Use the latest standard and compile that one file made C.P Precentor.
I got back no messages which is good as they say no news is good news.
If you have errors it'll tell you if you don't it will be nice and quiet.
At this point I'll do it again to see what's in our directory.
You can see that it's created a file called a dot out.
That's the common normal file executable file that's created.
What you don't say hey create Mainer create some other name to run it.
You just type dot slash dot out and there you go it says hello to command line exactly what we typed
up here in our program.
If you don't want the 8. out and you want your own executive will then you could type that in and show
you how to do that.
What I'm doing now is I'm pressing the up arrow and the down arrow.
You can go through what you've typed in that what you want to type it all in again.
So you want to go back to the statement where you compiled just type a dash lowercase O and the name
of the file that you want to create.
So in this case this is the same man that will be my executive will Precentor.
I'll do ls again.
Now you can see that there's a main file right there and I can outrun man and I get the same output.
OK.
Simple as that it really is very straightforward.
Now what are the things that you have to keep in mind.
Since this is not an idea you've got two things going on here separately right.
You've got your editors here and your command line tool here.
They're not really sync together.
You're the one that's sinking them together.
So if I remove the semi-colon from my text editor and I compile again I expect an error right.
I didn't get an error.
The reason I didn't get the air was because I never saved the file.
You have to be sure to save the file and then compile the ID sort of handle that magically behind the
scenes they realize that you've made a change so it's going to compile the latest changes you made.
This is different since sort out in sync.
So you want to be sure that you can come up here and save file save or control S..
Now I've saved it now a compile.
Now I see the error.
So you could see the errors it's expecting a semi-colon would check and replace.
If I get rid of this quote mark and control some saving again.
Now I run over to get a different error.
Something about a terminating quote character is missing so I can put that back in control S and save
and compile again and we can run main.
One more time.
That's it.
So that's it.
It's pretty straightforward.
These are the steps necessary when you have a plain text editor and the command line.
If you cannot install an ID for some reason maybe you've got minimal hardware requirements you just
don't like IDS or you find them too confusing.
Don't let that stop you from learning C plus plus you could still use a simple text editor like this
and a command line tool and you could see the command.
You could see the command right there.
It's really really straightforward.
If you've got multiple C++ files which we will later on in the course you just type them all in here.
File one that C.P. file to the DPP and so forth.
It will compile everything linked everything and run it for you.
It many times you are if you're a consultant and you're working out there you'll show up at a place
and there's no idea you you're working as a consultant.
All you need is an editor and a command line in your business.
OK so that wraps up this video.