When I take a course I always like to know what will be covered in that course so I know what to expect.
In this video I'd like to go over the curriculum for this course.
The curriculum has been developed in such a way that students with little to no programming background
can get started programming quickly in C++.
C++ is a very complex language.
Probably one of the most complex programming languages use today.
That doesn't mean that learning the basics should be impossible to grasp.
In fact all programming languages provide the same general constructs that we use to build programs.
This is a beginning modern C++ course.
There are many many topics in C++ that are at an intermediate or advanced level.
I won't be covering those topics in this course.
My goal in this course is to teach the basics of C++ so that you can write C++ programs that solve problems.
More importantly this course lays the foundation necessary to go forward and learn more advanced C++
concepts.
This foundation will also allow you to read C++ code written by other programmers C++ frameworks are
used everywhere.
For example if you want to program games in C++ using the Unreal Engine then you'll have the background
necessary to use their frameworks.
If you want to use the popular C++ Boost libraries you'll be able to use them and understand many of
their a prize.
OK so let's talk about the curriculum and what you can expect in this course.
We'll begin our C++ training by going over the code like IDS interface and writing a C++ program using
code like as we do this will understand how to compile build and run a C++ program.
Also talk a bit about some areas you may encounter.
I know what you're thinking.
Geez she's already talking about errors already.
I haven't even started learning to program yet and he's talking about errors.
Is this going to be that difficult.
Don't worry.
The sooner we talk about errors kinds of errors why they happen and how to fix them.
The sooner errors will become normal and expected.
I've seen students get turned off from programming because they get errors.
Expect the errors fix them and move on.
Then we'll talk about the structure of a basic C++ program.
I'll explain LB include name spaces comments.
The main function see in and see out.
These are the elements that nearly every C++ program will have.
Then we'll talk about variables and concepts and how to use them.
You can't write a C++ program that does much of anything unless it has variables and constants.
We'll go over how to declare them use them Name them and much more.
We'll also discuss C++.
Basic types which allow you to use integers floating point numbers characters and more.
Now that we know of variables are will group a bunch of variables together into collection of variables
called an array.
Now we'll be storing and using multiple variables like a bunch of test scores or temperatures for the
last 7 days.
These collections are called arrays and vectors and will learn how to create them and use them.
Also learn how to use multi dimensional structures so we can model things like grids boards and spreadsheets.
Then we'll learn about strings and C++ strings or collections of characters like my named Frank which
is f r a and k strings are used extensively in C++ and we go over the basics in this section in the
following section will learn how to write program statements.
These statements are made up of expressions will also go over some of the C++ operators like plus minus
multiply divide and so forth.
At the end of this section you'll be able to write C++ statements that tell the computer what to do
in order.
Now we get to the real powerful stuff control flow.
It's nice to be able to write a bunch of statements one after the other but to really have power we
need to be able to make decisions and repeat things more than once.
This is control flow.
This will open up the world of programming and give you so much power in the next section we'll learn
how to write functions a function let's as group a bunch of statements into a single construct.
It helps us organize our code and think more abstractly.
Following functions We'll talk about C++ pointers and references.
You may have heard horror stories about C++ pointers don't worry I'll walk you through how and why do
you use them and you'll see the incredible power they give you over your hardware.
Finally now that we know the basics of procedural programming and C++ will dive into object oriented
programming or O P O P is awesome and lets you model your program in terms of real world objects.
C++ is after all an object oriented language and that's how we want to use it.
Once we understand the basics of AP we'll learn about operator overloading which allows us to define
how the built in C++ operators can be defined so that they work with our own classes so they feel like
are part of the standard language.
Then you'll learn about inheritance and the power that it provides.
Imagine reusing existing code by inheriting what you need from it and just modifying the parts that
you need to solve your problem.
We'll wrap up our with polymorphism.
Polymorphism allows your program to determine its behavior at runtime and really let you think in general
so you don't have to be concerned about details.
The last several sections of the Course are slightly more advanced but they're so important that I wanted
to include them in this course.
The first is smart pointers.
We'll talk a lot about C++ pointers since every C++ programmer really needs to understand raw pointers
but C++ also provides smart pointers which make memory management much simpler and make your program
safer to use.
Then we'll talk about the C++ standard template library C++ provides a standard C++ template library
with a rich set of containers iterators and algorithms that are ready to use.
Why reinvent the wheel when you can use the wheels you have Aguayo over the basic FCL elements so that
you can put them together and solve complex problems.
Will finish off the course by talking about input and output to files in Exception handling exception
handling allows you to deal with exceptional conditions that might occur in your program.
What if a file doesn't exist or you try an operation and it fails.
It's important to understand how to write your code so that it's aware that something has gone wrong
so you can recover from it.
Wow that's a lot of material.
Some of these topics can be covered by an entire course dedicated just to them but don't worry we aren't
going to get into every possible option or explain every construct from a theoretical computer science
perspective.
This course is practical and it's about learning beginning C++ so that you can further explore this
amazing programming language and use it in real world applications in the next videos.
I briefly discuss the challenge exercises and the quizzes that are included in the course sections.