This video.
All right.
Our very first program.
So what we want to do is we want to create a project so again I'm in this section for workspace and
I'm going to right click on there and say new new project I'm going to select my default template again
and it's going to call this first program.
And I select next and finish.
Now I noticed that project 1 is the active project so I want to be sure that first program is the active
project so I can just double click on it and I can open up that C++ file.
That's it.
So this is a source code for the first program.
Now what I want to do is I want to be racists and I want you to really just type it in that way you
get used to typing these things in at the beginning and that's probably the best way to do it.
Just to follow along.
So let me tell you what this program is about.
This program is going to ask the user to enter their favorite number a number between 1 and 100 and
then it's going to display.
Wow that's amazing.
That's my favorite number two.
That's it.
OK.
So let's start first thing we need to do is we need to do pound include of IO stream.
Now as I type I going to press.
Oh then when I press S.
You could see that the code completion is helping me out is trying to figure out what I want and it's
giving me a guess as to what I want and I want those dreams.
I'm just going to select it and close it.
There is no semi-colon here on this statement.
These pounde directives and will talk more about what these preprocessor directives are.
In Section 5.
But they don't take semi-colons at the end.
So I'm going to press enter in that we want to create our main function.
Remember the main function is the main entry point.
This is the place where execution begins.
So we're going to say int main left Purab right Pirenne and then we're going to put a left curly and
the ID will terminate that left curly with the right Curly.
We'll talk more about style as we go.
But some programmers like to line up their braces like this.
Others like to line them up like that.
Right now it doesn't matter.
Just line them up like this.
All right.
So what do we need to do we need to prompt the user to enter their favorite number.
So how do I do that.
I do that with a C statement.
So I'm going to say s t d to Colon's then C out and we'll do the insertion operator which inserts something
into that stream remember C out is typically tied to your consul your terminal.
So the user can type things in and we're going to display enter your favorite number between let's say
100 and I'll just put a colon there.
Now you'll notice that you've got a quote mark and then a terminating quote mark.
This is called a string.
This is called the string literal.
This will be displayed exactly as is.
Now this is a statement.
So all statements and the semi-colon remember main returns an integer and that integer is zero.
If everything is good so I'm going to return 0.
Right so if I run this program now it's all of it's going to say is enter your favorite number between
1 to 100 that say it's not going to grab the number from anywhere.
It's not going to display anything else.
We need to somehow read what the user types in on the keyboard.
So just like C out writes to the console C in reads from the console.
So we're going to do here is we're going to say as t d c m and now we're going to use the extraction
operator because we're able to extract information and it's the same as the insertion operator except
going the other way.
But now what we're saying is we want to grab whatever the user types in and we want to store it somewhere.
Where do we store that.
Well this is where variables come in.
And what do a lot of talking about variables in section 6.
I'll talk about how do you declare them how you initialize them the rules for naming them and so forth
but declaring variables is very strict for so let's do that here.
What we do is we tell the compiler remember the compiler is really dumb it's not guessing.
It does exactly what we tell it to do.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to tell it that I want a variable name and that name is called
favorite number.
That's where I want you to store what the user typed in.
And you also have to tell it what kind of data that is.
Is it a string is it some big huge structure.
No in this case it's just a whole number and integer.
So we're going to say int space favorite underscore number semi-colon.
That's it.
That's a variable declaration.
You've just told the compiler that this variable name right here favorite number is an integer.
Now I can read information into that so I can say as T.T. to Colon's.
And again yesterday We'll explain later on.
It's a namespace but we definitely need it here as TDC in into favorite number.
Now again I'm going to type f a V and the code completion we'll try to figure out what I want.
So it's going to use favorite number record Precentor semi-colon on the end.
So notice what we've done so far we've included IO stream.
Why did we include IO stream because we need the input output libraries.
We can't do IO without it.
So we're including it now the compiler understands about input and output it understands C out and C
in they are defined in here great.
So I'm out putting end to your favorite number between 1 and 100.
Now the user is going to type something at the keyboard and whatever they type we're going to store
it into favorite number.
This guy right there right now we just need to say see out and I can say something like amazing
That's my favorite number two.
Here we can do and line.
So we flush the buffers and print out to the next line.
That's it.
So let's go through this again one more time.
We've got a main function.
This is the entry point.
This is where execution begins.
All C++ programs must have a main function.
All C++ programs must only have exactly one main function.
So when the program begins to execute this is where it starts.
Here I've defined a variable called favorite number and it's an integer.
It can only hold whole numbers.
I'm outputting to the console and to your favorite number between 1 and 100 the user is not going to
put something into the console number and I'm going to read it and store it into that location into
that variable into that box then I'm going to say seek out.
Amazing That's my favorite number two and I'm just going to print and line at the end of flesh out the
buffers and move the cursor over to the next line.
Finally I return 0.
Everything's good.
Now next thing to do is to build this program.
Programs are not going to run by itself.
We need to compile it.
We need to link it and then we need to execute it.
That whole process of compiling and linking is called building.
Now you'll notice that when you right click on that source file right here made CPV you see it says
compile.
Now if I press that it's going to compile our program and you can see here zero errors zero warnings.
We'll talk about what happens if you get errors and warnings a little bit later.
Also notice that we're using the C++ 14 standard which is what we want to use.
That's what we did when we set up that default template if you recall what we need to do next is to
build the project by compiling and linking.
That's going to create the eaks file on Windows or the executive files on the Linux and Mac and we'll
do that in the next video.