This video what talk about compiler errors and why they can happen.
Programming languages have very specific rules about how to write code so that the compiler can translate
that code to machine code.
These rules involve both structure and meaning.
For example C++ says that all variable declarations must end with a semi-colon.
If we don't add the semi-colon at the end or we put it in the middle instead then we have a syntax error.
The compiler is complaining that the structure is not correct.
In the first example we didn't terminate the string error with a trailing quote character in the second
example we left out the semi-colon at the end of the return 0 statement.
Both of these are syntax errors or something wrong with the structure of the code.
Now these syntax errors are pretty easy to fix and the compiler errors usually give us pretty good information
about what's going on.
Semantic errors are a little different in this case the syntax or structure is correct but the meaning
of the code doesn't make sense to the compiler.
Suppose we want to add two variables A and B.
If the variables are both integers then Miss makes perfect sense.
But what happens if one of the variables is a person and the other variable is an integer.
Does it make sense to add a person and an integer.
Probably not in this case the compiler generates an error.
What do we think of compiler errors.
We really think about both of these classes of errors.
Remember compilers are very very picky.
Why.
Because their job is to translate your code that you wrote into machine code that functions as you said.
If the compiler has any problem understanding the meaning of your code then it won't guess it will generate
an error.
Let's head over to code like and see some of these errors.
So Dhami code like and I created a project called compiler errors and I created it right from our template.
So it's just a simple hello world program it's just printing out Hello world.
Now what we want to do is introduce it some compiler errors into this program so you can see what they're
like.
Now let's do some.
First let's do some syntax errors.
Simple stuff like.
OK we forgot this quote right here and I can save and compile and you'll see that I'll get an error
that says missing terminating character and if you click on here it takes you here.
Now in this case we've got another error.
This is expected.
Primary expression before return.
This happens sometimes the compiler gets confused.
It sees that first error and that is trying to figure out what's going on and it goes to the next line
and it says I don't know where I'm at and it creates an error.
Many times when you fix that first error many of the subsequent errors go away.
So let's put that quote back in.
We'll save and let's recompile.
Now we've got a clean compile so that would be my my advice when you're first learning.
Start out at the beginning get that first syntax error fixed recompile and very likely a whole bunch
of others just went away.
OK so that's an example of a syntax error.
The compiler is expecting a string and it knows it's got a rule that says all strings have to have a
quote character.
A bunch of characters and then a quote character a dn to terminate it.
It didn't see that it didn't like that and there's the syntax error.
Really easy to fix.
Other times you may have things that are misspelled.
So for example let's say I spelt and L here raw I put an extra L in there.
Now when I compile it saying error and L L is not a member of the standard namespace so it knows that
C is and L is but and L-L is not.
So in this case this error message kind of leads you to the place where the problem is just.
Oh of course I have a typo so you can fix that as well.
Another example of a compiler error syntax error is forgetting the semi-colon here let's say that the
returns 0.
All statements have to end with a semi-colon so we just forgot it.
That violates one of the rules that the compiler knows about and it doesn't like it.
So what we'll do here again will compile and you could see it says error.
Expecting a semi-colon before that.
So there's the curly and it's expecting a semi-colon.
Sure is because of that.
OK now suppose we just say return semi-colon.
Now this is problematic because we've told the compiler in our code that main returns an integer.
But here we're just returning when not returning an integer.
So let's see what it says.
Let's compile and it says error return statement with no value in function returning integer.
Pretty good statement right.
It's telling you I've got a function.
You told me it's returning an integer but you're not returning any value now.
So I can return 0.
OK.
So let me show you an example of a semantic error something like this.
This is perfectly valid.
I can return an integer I can return a string I can return a lot of things.
The problem is that doesn't make sense to the compiler because you've told it here that you're returning
an integer but now you're returning a string.
So let's run that and see what you get.
Here you go error.
Invalid conversion from a character star which is a string to an integer so the compiler is trying to
figure out how do I convert that Joe to an integer IDE or no I don't have.
I have no idea.
I'll just throw the air.
And that's up to you now to fix it.
So in this case again I'll fix it to return 0.
Now let's do another one let's get rid of that first Curly.
This is a real interesting compiler and I'll compile it and then we'll talk about it.
Let's compile and you can see that I've got three errors from that.
What's happening is the compiler is totally lost here.
The policy.
Int main.
And then it's expecting a Kerley and it's processing more and more stuff kind of hoping to see that
left Karlee eventually and it's not seeing it so it's seeing other things and it's throwing errors it's
saying I don't know what's going on before the SCD.
I've got an unexpected unqualified something before return.
I'm lost.
OK.
So when you see these kinds of errors I mean this is a tiny little program and I've got three compiler
errors.
Sometimes you'll compile something you know 20 40 errors and many times when you fix that first one
most of them will go away.
So in this case all it's missing is that that curly so I'll compile and we should have a clean compiler.
Now we do sometimes add extra Curley's at the end which again is illegal.
So I'll compile
and there it is an error.
I'm expecting something before that token doesn't know what you're doing.
So we'll get rid of that.
OK so let's do one more semantic air.
Let's say that we've got hello world in here and I want to apprentice around it and I'm going to divide
it by 125 and I put a print this year on that.
Just simple math.
OK.
That's pretty weird.
I've got something here divided by something here that's valid.
I can divide two things.
The division operator which is that Slash is a binary operator works on two things right.
So four divided by two is two eight divided by two is four and so forth.
But in this case the syntax is correct but the compiler is going to say I have no idea what you want
me to do here.
You're telling me to divide hello world by 125.
I don't even know what that means.
So let's compile that and the error is something like Error invalid operands.
So the division operator the slash operator has got invalid operands is two operands right.
One is a string.
The other one is an integer and it's say I don't know what to do here.
So these are some simple examples of compiler errors.
Don't be afraid of the compiler errors.
You're going to get them.
Don't let them frustrate you if you have any that you can't figure out.
Please post to the forums and I'll be glad to help you out.
It's just something that we have to learn to work with because we're going to get compiler errors.
We all make mistakes.
Sometimes we're prototyping with trying new things and forgetting getting errors sometimes are just
silly mistakes and they're hard to find sometimes.
Sometimes you'll be looking at your own code.
I can tell you this this little error here with the the and double L.
This is a good error message that you got.
But if you're looking at this code and you've been coding for a few hours I don't think you'll see those
too.
Most likely they look like one L..
So you know this is the kind of thing that programming is about one of the important things is getting
rid of all these compiler errors.
Once we get rid of the compiler errors then we can test our code and we could look for logic errors
and so forth.
OK so that wraps up this video in the next video.
We'll talk a little bit about compiler warnings.
They're a little different from yours because they're not true errors but they're telling you something
that you should look out for.