In this video we'll talk about linker errors and why they can happen.
Linker errors occur when the linker is trying to put all the pieces of a program together to create
an executive will and one or more pieces are missing.
Typically this can happen with an object file or libraries can't be found by the linker.
Fixing linker errors can be tricky.
Sometimes it's just a matter of getting the paths correct so that the linker knows where the missing
pieces are.
Let's head over to code light and we'll force a program to have a linker errors.
You can see what the error message looks like.
So I mean code light and I've created a project called linker error based on the template that we use
so all I've got is a main C.P. file that says Hello world.
Now we're going to force a linker error here.
This is not something you want to do normally but I'm going to do it to show you what the error looks
like.
So what I'm going to say is I'm going to say extern and C but let's just say X and I'll explain all
this to you in just a second.
And then in the body of the main I want to try to use that X right there.
It's just an integer and let's say I want to print it out.
I just want to print out x.
Simple as that.
I'm going to save this.
Now you see if I compiled this program you'll see what happens and what a reichlich compile I get a
clean compile there's nothing wrong with the program.
But when I try to build and run it
you could see the linker error.
This is classic linker error undefined reference to something in this case it just happens to be X..
Also you'll notice that the linker returned one here L.D. returns one which is the next status.
So something was wrong with the link.
Obviously the compile was fine because we got no compiler errors that we do that again there's the compiler
no errors no warnings.
So let me explain to you what's going on here.
Let me grab my stylus here real quick.
And what's going on here is I've got my main CVP file here and it's going to be compiled to make oh
let's say or made object in here we have a reference to an X..
You can see it right there.
You could see it right there.
So in here I've got a reference to an X which I'm going to use.
Now we also have our IO stream libraries.
So the linker needs to grab those libraries and I'll just type IO stream here.
You know what I'm talking about.
The linker needs to put these two together to create my main you see or in this case I believe it would
be linker error.
But you know what I mean.
So the compile is fine we've created our object file this library exists.
The problem is that I've told the compiler here that this X is not in me it's somewhere else.
It's defined by somebody else.
Well obviously it is defined by someone else because that kind of forced the issue here.
So now the linker needs to resolve that X and saying OK where do I get that value to print.
Because that's what you asked me to do right here right.
I wanted to print the value of x where where is X but can't find it.
That's the linker error.
That's exactly what's going on.
And let me build this again so you can see the error message one more time.
And it's build it run it
and there's the error message it's saying undefined reference to X..
You can see Zackery what's going on.
Can't find x.
Now this is not a compiler error.
This is a linker air that's really important.
Understand linker errors are tricky to fix.
A lot of times the files that you need to link are missing they're in the wrong places.
You don't have to worry about that using code lightning in this course we're going to basically do everything
ourselves.
But if you're using libraries from third parties this is the kind of thing we'll talk about in a more
intermediate or advanced course.
But I just wanted to show your linker errors in case you do come up with one posted in the forum and
we'll work through it together.