It this video.
Talk about run time errors and why they can happen.
As the name suggests runtime errors or errors that happen when the program is executing these types
of errors can be difficult to predict when we're writing our program.
These areas include divide by zero errors.
File not found errors out of memory errors and many many more.
Some runtime errors can cause your program to crash.
We use exception handling to help us know when runtime errors happen so we can try to recover from them.
We'll see examples of runtime errors later in this course when we work with files will also work with
exception handling toward the end of the course.