This video we're briefly go over using C++ name spaces C++ name spaces can be a little confusing when
you first see them as our C++ programs become more and more complex.
Our programs become a combination of our own code the C++ standard libraries and their code and libraries
from third party developers and their code.
So as you can imagine sooner or later we're going to run into this situation where Company X named something
the same as Company Y when we use that name in our program the C++ compiler doesn't know which one to
use.
So we have something called the naming conflict.
For example suppose another library that we're using has defined a name called out.
Well that's a big problem right because now C++ doesn't know which C out to use.
C++ allows developers to use name spaces as containers to group their code entities into a namespace
scope.
That means that I could create a namespace called Frank and I could define C out within that namespace.
Now if a programmer wanted to use my version of C out all they had to do is say Frank double colon C
out that's it.
If they wanted to use the one in the standard library they would just say standard double call and see
out.
It's as simple as that.
Name spaces are used to reduce the possibility of naming conflicts.
The double colon operator is called the scope resolution operator.
It's used to resolve which name we want to use.
However many programmers find it tedious to type as t d colon colon all the time when using C in C out
and buy in and so forth.
So C++ provides a few mechanisms to help in that regard.
In this sample code you can see that we're explicitly telling the compiler to use see in C out and N
line from the C++ standard namespace using as Tedi followed by the scope resolution operator.
This is how we've written code to this point.
Now let's take a look at another way we can do this without so much typing.
In this case we can use the using namespace directive followed by the name of the namespace we wish
to use.
In this case the standard namespace.
Notice that I no longer have to use as c d followed by the scope resolution operator.
When I refer to C and C and line the compiler now knows which one to use based on the using namespace
directive.
This is pretty easy to use and it's the way I'll do it in this course from this point forward since
it reduces code clutter and it's better from a teacher's perspective.
However this may not be the best solution for large programs using namespace standard.
Not only brings in C in C out and line it brings in a bunch of other names that are defined in that
namespace.
So the possibility exists that you may still have a naming conflict.
C++ provides another variant of the using namespace directive.
Let's take a look at that.
In this case we have a qualified using namespace variant in which we tell the compiler exactly the names
I want to use from a specific namespace.
In this case you can see am using Threet using directives each qualified for a specific name in a specific
namespace.
The advantage of this approach is that we can still use C in C out and line in our code without the
namespace in scope resolution operator.
And we're not getting any other names from the C plus for standard namespace for the examples in this
course.
You can use the namespace standard directive from the previous slide with no problem but keep in mind
that it may not be the best practice in larger programs.
That wraps up namespace in the next video.
We'll take a quick look at basic IO with C in and see out.