In this video we'll look at basic input output using See in and see out see out C in C air and see logger
defined in the C plus plus standard to use them you must include IO stream.
C++ uses a stream abstraction to handle IO and devices like the console and keyboard out is an output
stream that defaults to the console or the screen.
See air and see log or Also output streams that default to standard error and standard log respectively.
And finally Sienna's an input stream that defaults to the keyboard.
The insertion operator is used without put streams and the extraction operator is used with input streams.
Let's look at how we can you see out and the insertion operator the insertion operator inserts the value
of the operand to its right.
In this case the variable data into the output stream since C out is by default the console the value
of data will be displayed on the screen.
Since we're using stream abstraction we can change multiple insertions in the same statement.
This makes basic IO very very easy to do.
It's important to understand that the insertion operator does not automatically add line breaks to move
to the next line on the console.
You must do this explicitly either by using the line manipulator or by including a newline character
the slash and you see in the last example if you use the on line stream manipulator It will also flush
the stream.
This is important to know since if the stream is buffered it may not get written to the console until
it's flushed.
We'll talk more about this when we talk about file streams since it's more applicable there.
Let's see how the extraction operator works with CN the extraction operator extracts information from
the CNN stream which defaults to the keyboard and stores the information into the variable to the right
of the extraction operator.
The way in which the information is interpreted is based on the type of the variable.
So in this case if data is an integer then an integer representation will be read from the keyboard.
If data is a double then a real number will be read and stored.
If data is a string a sequence of characters will be read and stored.
Extraction operators can also be changed in the second example two variables data one and data two will
be assigned values read from the keyboard based on their type the characters entered using the keyboard
will only be processed when the enter key is pressed.
See in extraction uses whitespace that is spaces tabs.
New lines as terminating the value being extracted.
That's important to understand so if you put spaces between the things that you type in the spaces will
be ignored.
It's possible that the extraction operator could fail.
For example suppose you want to read an integer and the user enters my name Frank in this case the operation
fails and the data will have an undetermined value c and extraction is very easy and useful.
However we'll later learn about other methods we can use with CN that give us more control over the
data that's being input.
Finally we can use the same operators to insert and extract data from file streams.
This is pretty cool since the syntax is already familiar and the behavior is very similar.
We'll work with files later in this course.
Now let's head over to the code line idea and go over some examples in life code.
Ok so now I'm back in the code like ID and I've got a section 5 workspace within the workspace I've
created a basic IO project and this is the main file for that project.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to do some basic IO using C and in C out and I'll show you
some of the nuances so that you really understand what's going on here.
First of all remember four we've got to include IO stream and on line 6 I'm using namespace standards
just to make the code a little bit easier to read.
Best practice would be to actually include standard scope resolution operator C out and so forth as
we talked about in the last lecture.
So first thing we'll talk about is the statement on line 10 right here.
C out insertion operator a string Hello world.
We've got another insertion operator and then we've got the end line manipulator.
What this does is it prints hello world to the console and that advances the cursor to the next line.
OK I'm going to run this and I want to run it by pressing control F5 which is the same as run here.
So when we build and run you could see it prints out to the screen hello world and then it goes to the
next line and this time elapsed message prints out after that.
OK.
Pretty straightforward.
If I leave out the end line and I'll do that really quickly and I'll run it again.
You could see that it prints out Hello world.
It does not advance to the next line and then everything just prints out right after that.
OK so that's pretty straightforward.
Let's take a look at a couple of other examples.
Look at this example here and what uncomment this out.
First I'm displaying hello and then I'm displaying world and them the and line at the end.
Notice that there is no end line after the first hello.
So you would expect that these two should run together with no spaces so we should see Hello world all
bunched together.
So let's try that and you can see that that's exactly what happens.
You can see Hello here followed by world with no spaces.
It does advance to the end to the next line because we have that line manipulator here.
OK.
So let's do a few more.
And as you can see by default right here when we use the insertion operator with a string in this case
hello.
It does not advance to the next line until unless we do it specifically and explicitly.
So that's what line does.
So here for more output statements the first one just says out Hello world just like we've done before
and advances line the next one change the insertion operators.
So you could see that I'm putting hello on the output stream then I'm putting world on the output stream
you can see there's a space right before that W there and then I'm printing a new mine.
So getting the same effect as the previous one.
Same here I could say hello world but here in this case you can see that I'm using a slash and a backslash
in this character right here is a newline character.
So what happens is you can embed that newline character in the string and it will advance to the next
line.
So it's similar to lime.
It doesn't flush the buffer but it still advances to the next line.
And then the last line you can see you can see that just a couple things going on here.
You can see that I've got a new line here.
New line here and a new line here.
So you expect this to print out hello and then go to the new line
and then print out here.
Then go to that in advance of the next line and print out there and then advance to the next line here.
So that's what we expect we expect the first three statements.
On lines 15 through 17 to pre-done exactly the same day in that December effect.
And the last one would be a little bit different.
So let's try this out and we'll compile and run here.
And you can see Hello World Hello World Hello world.
Exactly the same and then we have Hello out there.
One word per line.
And remember even though that this is all in one string that are all here we still have the slot machines
in there which That's how they work you embed them inside those strings.
OK so now let's do a little bit with variables.
We'll talk a lot about variables in the next section but I'm going to declare three variables right
here and I'll explain that to you real quick.
They're really easy in this case I'm declaring three variables.
Number one number two and them three.
Those are the names.
Number one is an integer and number two is an integer and then number three is a double.
That's a floating point number like 2.5 or eight hundred point seven.
A real number will use them two and them three or a little bit later but right now we're only going
to use someone someone to comment this line.
Uncomment this line and you can see what's happening here.
I'm saying I'm prompting the user enter an integer.
Then I'm reading an integer using the extraction operator I'm extracting an integer from the input stream
and I'm storing it in.
No one can see it's going right in here.
And then I'm simply going to output you entered whatever they typed in.
So let me explain how this works.
Here's your keyboard and remember CNN is by default tied to your keyboard.
We can redirect it as we wish but by default it's the keyboard.
Now what happens is characters are read from your keyboard and they're not read directly by CNN they're
stored in a buffer.
This is done to make the program more efficient.
So if I type in 123 on the keyboard then what happens is the numbers are read from the buffer the characters
in this case are read from the buffer and the compiler knows that number one is an integer.
So it's going to read those characters and it's only going to process what makes sense to be an integer.
So in this case it's going to read to one and say yeah it's going to read the two.
Yep going to read the three.
Yup.
Now we're done.
So we've got 123.
So 123 gets stored into number one and that will print out here.
OK.
Now you need to press enter.
When you do this on the keyboard and also whitespace is ignored.
So if I type in like 10 whites you know 10 spaces or tabs or anything that's considered whitespace and
then I type in 123 then I type in a whole bunch more whitespace it'll all be ignored.
OK so let's take a look at that in action and I'll just clear this real quick and let's run this and
it's going to say enter an integer.
So I'm going to type in 123.
Press Enter member have to press enter and it says you entered 123 just what we'd expect.
Run it one more time and this time I'm going to type in a bunch of spaces and pressing the spacebar
and pressing tab then I'll press 123 and I'll type in some more spaces.
Now when I press enter you can see you still entered 123.
All that beginning whitespace is ignored and everything after the three is considered not an integer.
So this is where if you read from C in again it's going to start right after that three OK.
So that gives you an idea of what's going on there.
And let me comment that out again and we'll keep going through some more examples.
In this case we're going to read two numbers.
We're going to say enter a first integer and we're going to read that into number one and to a second
integer and we're going to read that into number two.
And then we're just simply going to say you entered number one and number two remember in this case
here number one and number two right here.
Will be replaced by whatever values the user typed in.
OK so let's do this let's run this one and you'll see it's exactly what you would expect.
And that's the obsession of commented these guys out that me and comment them and let's try that again.
So enter a first integer.
So we want to type in 100 and I'm going to press enter enter a second integer 200 press enter again
you entered 100 and 200 again.
Just what we expected.
Now let me show you something that you might not expect.
Let me run this one more time.
And then when I enter 100 followed by a space followed by 200 and press enter you can see my output
statement work that says you entered 100 and 200 but the output looks a little different right.
Well you can see what's happening.
I ventured to integers.
So what happens is when I read those integers from the standard input right via the extraction operator
is going to grab both of them.
It's not going to wait because it's got both of them in there already.
So again it's not going away for me to press Enter 2 times because it's got him in there.
Let me show you what that looks like.
So you can better understand.
All right.
So let's say that we're here and we just ran this program and we entered 100 followed by a space and
I'll just use that character for a space followed by 200.
And so right here it's waiting for me what I did was I entered 100 spaced 200 and I pressed enter the
extraction operator realizes that no one is an integer so it's going to try to read an integer from
the stream here seem to start right here and it's going to say I've got a 1 0 1 0.
Boom I hit a white space.
That must mean that my integers done.
So it's going to take 100 and store it right into number one.
Now it's going to output end to another integer and is going to try to read that second integer from
the input stream.
Well it's already in there right so it's going to start right here and it's going to say to 0 0.
Hit the end.
That's 200.
It's not going to wait for me to press enter because there's already data in that buffer.
So in this case the 200 it's put into number two and this will produce 100 and 200.
So your output will be correct.
But the way that the prompts are displayed is a little different because it's got data in that buffer
already.
Same thing with I mean run this one more time and I'll show you a little bit of a different example.
Same thing with space.
One hundred space tab 200 or 200.
You can see you entered 100 and 200 is just ignoring all that space but it's got those two values in
that stream.
It's just going to process the stream doesn't wait for you to press enter twice.
OK.
So a comment goes out and
we can chain the extraction operator just like we had we can change the assertion operator.
So in this case you could see that we've got the C in followed by an extraction operator right there
followed by another extraction operator.
So what I'm doing here is the output statement for the users a little different it just says Enter two
integers separated with a space.
So let's say ancho 100 a space and then 200.
Now this guy's going to read two integers from the input stream and it will assign 100 here and 200
here.
OK let's do that.
And you could see right here into two integers separated with a space remember I could put leading spaces
too if I want but in this case I'll just say 100 spaced 200 and it says here you entered 100 and 200.
This is actually a really handy way to get information from the user when you want them to you know
enter more than one number you know entered three numbers separated by spaces that's really easy for
them to do.
Rather than say enter Number 1 enter Number 2 Enter number three and so forth.
OK.
So that's another option you've got.
OK so I'll come this out and now we'll process some doubles.
In this case if you remember me scroll up just a little bit if you remember number three was a double
right so it's a floating point number a real number.
And what I'll do here is I'll just uncomment this out and the prompt to the user is enter a double right
here and you're going to read the double into number three from the input stream.
Again here's the input stream.
Suppose I typed in twelve point five.
That's a real number.
It realizes that it needs to read a real number from the input stream because number three was defined
up top as a double.
So it's going to come here to read of one it's going to get the two it's going to see the decimal point
that's valid in a real number and it's going to read the 5 then it's done.
And twelve point five will be assigned here and it will be displayed down here.
OK.
So let's run that
into my double press.
Twelve point five and enter and it says right there you enter twelve point five just like we expected.
OK so let's do this last one and I'll show you what could go wrong here.
There's always something that could go wrong right.
So the uncomment that.
And look at this example here.
This one is saying enter an integer and you're going to read the integer into number one and then it's
saying to redouble and you're going to read the double And number three.
OK.
Now if we run this and I type in let's say 10 and 12.
Space twelve point five.
That's not a problem at all right because it's going to read the integer and it's going to say 1 0.
I see a space.
I'm done.
The ten goes into number one then it's going to read a double here num three is going to say one two
decimal point five twelve point five.
Perfect it's going to go in here.
The integer is 10.
The double is twelve point five and that will work just fine.
Then we run that just so you can see that.
And then we'll do one more example a couple more examples where you can see some of the issues here.
So there's my integer that say it's 10 and the double is twelve point five and you can see the integer
is 10 and a double is twelve point five.
OK.
But what happens if I enter something like let's say ten point five
something like that.
Think about this logically you're probably guessing what's going to happen.
It's going to read an integer.
So it's going to see that the one in the 0 and it's going to say Yep that's an integer when it sees
the decimal point.
It knows it can't be an integer anymore.
So it's just going to take the 10 and store it here.
Then you're going to say well read me a double.
What's going to start at the decimal point and he's going to read point five point five is a double
right.
So it's going to store point five here sir output is going to be 10 and 0.5.
Maybe not what you expected but you can see the behavior makes perfect sense you're telling it what
to do.
You typed in ten point five tens and integer and point five is a double and I can read those.
So let's try that with ten point five and we'll see what that looks like.
So let's enter the integer ten point five.
Now remember there's going to be THAT point five left in the buffer.
So it's not going to ask me it's going to ask me to enter the double but it's not going to wait for
me to press enter because it's already got data in the buffer so I press enter.
And you can see and try a double right it's not waiting for me here.
The manager is 10 and the double is 0.5.
Now the last example is that's run this one more time and we'll do something really weird here we'll
just type Frank.
Now that's really what I want because you've just told it that you're going to read an integer in a
double and you just gave it a string of characters here.
So if I press enter you can see what's going on here.
The integer is 0 and the double is some undefined crazy small number here.
OK well what happens is when it tried to read the integer it got the F and Frank in its lost.
So the input failed and it goes into a failed state.
From that point on everything that's happening is unreliable.
You can see that the integer got zero got basically initialized to zero there.
But everything else after that point is completely unreliable.
You've got to be really careful now in real world programs.
We're not really using cn to read characters we're using strings we're reading them with strings and
then we're trying to convert those strings to numbers or whatever else we really need.
But they're really really handy and easy to use and that's what we're going to do for the vast majority
of this course.
We're going to use C-n and seek out so that we can read numbers and we can output numbers or strings
or whatever we like.
So that finishes off this video.
This is basic I O using CNN.
You can see it's pretty straightforward.
Don't worry about mistakes right now as we're working through these programs.
If it says enter an integer enter the integer says enter a string enter the string.
Don't worry about error handling that comes later.