This video will learn about C++ as size of operator and about the sea limits and see float include files.
C++ has an operator called size of that returns the number of bytes used to represent any type size
of can also be used to determine the size of compound types like arrays structures and objects.
Learn about compound types in a future section in order to determine the size of a specific type.
We provide the name of the type inside the parentheses for example size of it size of double.
This will tell us the size of that type in bytes on the specific machine and compiler that you're running
the program on.
You can also determine the size of variables using their names.
In this case you can use the same syntax or you can omit the parentheses since they're optional for
variables the size of operator gets its information from two C++ include files C limits and C float
see limits provides information about interval types and see float about floating point types.
These include files also provide a bunch of handy defined constants that we can use to determine the
precision of our primitive types for example.
And Max tells us the maximum value we can store in an int on this specific machine.
There are many others and you can see some in the examples in this slide.
Let's head over to the code ID and we'll see what some of these values are in my machine.
I'm into code like ID and I've written some code that uses the size of operator.
Let me walk you through it.
First thing I see is that we're including IO stream and we're also including C limits.
Everything I'm using here will use C limits.
You can get the same information in C float.
I'll leave that as an exercise for you if you like.
First thing we'll do is output size of information for types.
So in this case I would output char followed by size of char in bytes.
Size of int size of unsigned int short long and long long.
Now when I run this I get information about how big or how much storage is necessary to represent a
character an integer and so forth on my specific machine using this specific compiler.
OK now the rest of the code is commented out and again.
Uncomment that as we go through.
So what I'll do is and I've created a project here called size of operator project and you can run this
code on your machine and see what your values look like.
So I build and run and you could see the size of information that's come up.
A character is one byte in integers 4 bytes an unsigned integers also 4 bytes.
That makes sense because the only difference between an int and an unsigned int is that signed bit and
how much precision you can store in a short integer is two bytes along integers 4 bytes long long integers
8 bytes and there you go.
Now I'm running a 32 bit compiler on a 64 bit operating system.
If you're running a 64 bit compiler these numbers will likely be different.
All right so that takes care of the basic size of for the integral types.
Let's look at some of the floating point types.
So in this case you can see that I want the size of the float size of a double and the size of the long
double.
OK so what we can do is we can build and run and you could see now that a float on this particular machine
again is 4 bytes.
A double is 8 bytes and a long double is 12 bytes.
That's the amount of storage that it takes to represent these specific types on this machine.
Ok so now the C limits file contains some pretty nice defined constants and let's use some of them can
see what it's like.
In this case I want minimum values so I want to know what's the minimum value that I can store in a
character.
What's the minimum value that I can store to an integer in a short integer in a long integer and in
a long long integer and you could see that defines are right here and those will default to some integer.
So let's let's run this now.
Again I'll build and run and you can see that the minimum value I can store in a character's negative
1:28 that makes sense because a character is one byte be it an integer you can see the number there
in a short negative 3 to seven six eight long and the long long.
Your numbers may look different on your machine depending on a lot of factors.
All right.
Now we can do the maximum of values and it's exactly the same except we're doing char Max Max instead
of char Minutemen.
I'll run this again in a press control at 5 to run an hour maximum values are for characters 127 for
short three to seven six seven and for long long so you can see that's a pretty big number.
All right so that's the use of see limits and size of with types.
We can also use size of with variable names and I'll show you an example here where what we have here
is here we've got an integer called H.
And we're suddenly 21 to it.
We're not going to use the 21 at all.
All we're interested in is the size of that variable.
So rather than size of int here we're saying size of age.
This is one syntactic variant.
We can also just say size of age without the parentheses.
So I'm doing that for an integer called age.
I'm doing the same for a double called wage.
So obviously we would expect the double to be much bigger.
But again what I'm doing in here is I'm using the variable name instead of type here as well.
All right so let's run this one more time.
And what we've got now at the bottom here is that the size of using variable names.
So age is four bytes and if you recall here we know that age is an integer right.
And integer up top is four bytes.
If you recall that statement at the top.
So age is 4 bytes.
The other syntax variant gives exactly the same result and wages a double which is 8 bytes and you can
see our doubles.
Here is 8 bytes.
You may be wondering why in the world would I ever use this stuff.
Well it's important to understand what the size and precision of your types are on your system.
Later on when we deal with arrays and other data structures sometimes it's nice to be able to understand
how big something is how big each section of it is.
This is one of the big differences between C++ and other languages like Java and Python with those languages.
You're really far removed from the machine so you're programming at a much higher level C++ we're at
a lower level so we've got to deal with this kind of thing.