This video we'll look at the syntax for multi dimensional arrays and C++ will focus on two dimensional
arrays but you can use as many dimensions as are supported by your system.
While there's no real limit to the number of dimensions you can have for a raise.
Be aware that some compilers do place limits on this bill the limits are quite high and you're unlikely
to reach them.
The syntax for declaring multi dimensional arrays just involves adding another set of square brackets
with the new dimension inside them.
In this example you can see we're declaring a two dimensional array named movie rating.
This survey has three rows and four columns which means that the total size of the array is 12 integers.
We have not initialized this survey so we should assume that the array elements contain garbage data
until initialized.
Let's see how we might model real world data using this to the array.
Suppose we want to collect movie ratings.
We have movie reviewers and each reviews a series of movies with an integer rating from zero to five.
We have three reviewers and each has to review the same four movies.
We could choose to model this data by having one array of movie ratings for each reviewer so we could
declare three arrays of four integers each and solve our problem like that.
Another option is to use a two dimensional array.
The first dimension or row in our grid is the reviewer and there would be four columns in the grid one
for each movie.
This is similar to the layout of a spreadsheet in the figure the reviewer is the first index or row
of our re-enabled in red and the movie is the second index or column of our array labeled in green.
Now its pretty easy to go to a specific row and column and get or set that movie rating for that specific
reviewer and that specific movie accessing the specific movie rating is easy.
I can ask the user to enter a movie rating as integer and story and movie ratings are one step two.
Suppose these are inchers five this update that specific element in the array.
I can also display that element to the console using the same syntax.
Initialising multi dimensional arrays uses the same initializer syntax that we saw with one dimensional
the race in this case we provide in the initialiser list the rows of columns you could do this in a
single line but it's much more readable if you split it across lines as I've done here.
You can see the initializers providing three rows of four integers each which is exactly how we declared
the array while one and two dimensional arrays are by far the most commonly used arrays in programming.
Extending the syntax to three dimensions and more is just as you would expect.
Don't forget that the same characteristics holds for multidimensional arrays as for single dimensional
arrays.
We'll see well two dimensional arrays again when we talk about iteration in C++.
So that's a look at C++ arrays.
If you see them at existing code you'll understand how they work what they look like and their syntax.
Remember at the beginning of the section I mentioned that we rarely use C++ arrays in modern C++.
Instead we use vectors that take a quick look at C plus plus vectors.