Welcome back I hope you enjoyed working with vector's and learn more about how to use them.
You can find my solution in the section 7 workspace challenge solution project.
Let's go through my solution to this challenge one line at a time.
I've inserted the challenge directives in my solution is comments so it's easier to follow along.
So where do we start.
First thing we need to do is we need to include the vector library.
If you didn't do that you probably got some syntax errors about vector not found and probably got a
lot of errors.
Also we can use the namespace standard.
We don't have to do this but it makes the code a lot less cluttered and it's easier to display.
For teaching purposes that way if you didn't include namespace standard you might have gotten errors
and you probably did something like standard scope resolution operator vector.
So let's do the first directivity it is declared two empty vectors of integers named vector 1 and vector
2 respectively on line 42 and 43.
That's exactly what I'm doing.
You could see vector 1 is a vector of integers and vector 2 is a vector of integers.
There is no constructor here with the size.
There is no initialization list so these are going to be empty vectors.
The second directive on 945 says add 10 and 20 to vector 1 dynamically using pushback.
That's what I'm doing on lines 47 and 48 effect to 1 DUP push back 10 vector one push back 20.
These two elements will be added to the back of the vector and the storage will be allocated automatically
for them.
This is where we can see that defectors can grow on line 50.
We want to display the elements at Vector 1 using the method and we also want to display the size of
the vector using the size method so you could see that between lines 52 and 55.
That's what I'm doing here on line 53.
I'm simply saying give me the element at Vector ones 0 and then give me the element at 1 so that will
display 10 and 20 because that's what's in there.
And then I'm going to say vector one contains vector dot size will return two because there are currently
two elements in the vector 1 so it should display a vector one contains two elements.
OK so so far pretty easy.
Let me scroll up just a little bit.
An on line 57 we're doing the same thing with the 100 and 200 but to vector 2.
So I'm adding 100 and 200 dynamically using pushback on vector to vector to empty.
So after this vector too should have 100 and 200 and the size of two.
What we're doing on line 64 through 67 is the same thing we did with the vector one except we're doing
it with vector to where displaying the results this should display 100 200 and back to 2 contains two
elements.
OK let me scroll up a little bit more now on line 69.
The directive says declare an empty two dimensional vector called vector to D and does that little bit
there that says Remember that a 2D vector is a factor of vectors.
So this is how we would declare this vector to D.
That's my object is a vector of integer vectors or a vector a vector of integers.
However you want to pronounce it so you get the idea there.
So it's a vector that can hold other factors.
Therefore you have the two dimensionality unlined 74 and 75.
What we're doing is we're adding an entire vector to the vector to d with pushback.
We can do that right because it's a vector of vectors could certainly add a vector to it.
And that's what's happening on line 77 and 78 on line 77.
I'm adding vector 1 to vector to d using pushback which means that remember vector to d at this point
was empty.
So storage will be allocated vector one will be put in there doing the same with vector too.
So at this point we'll have a two dimensional vector that contains two vectors.
So online Adey were displaying the elements in vector to d using the method.
So you can see here I'm displaying the element at 0 0 and then the element is 0 1 and then the element
1 0 and the element is 1 1.
So this should display 10 20 and 100 200.
So this is the interesting part.
Now I've asked you to change vector ones first element write the element at index 0 to a thousand and
then display the vector again.
What did you expect some of you might have thought that that first element would have changed right
because after all we did put vector 1 into the to the vector and you might be surprised that it didn't.
And we'll talk about that in a second.
But here we're displaying vector one just to see if it actually did change.
So let's run this and will walk through the output.
Someone to build and run and you could see at the beginning we're saying OK vector one right we pushed
a 10 and 20.
So that was fine.
And that vector 1 contains the two elements.
That's what we expect vector to.
We inserted the 100 and the 200 and vector 2 now contains two elements vector 2 d contains vector one
and vector 2 within it.
Right.
Again it's a two D vector.
So the first one was 10 20.
The second one was 100 200.
Pretty cool.
But now at this point what we did was this is where we're at right now.
We just changed vector ones first element to 1000 and then we printed out that 2D vector again.
But you can see the 2d vector.
There's no thousand.
Here where the 10 is that's where you would expect it.
Right.
There isn't the reason for that is that when you add elements to vector you actually make a copy of
what you're inserting.
So that tells you a little bit about what's going on a little bit later on in the course what we'll
do is we'll have vectors of references or vectors of pointers.
And those are a little bit different because here we can actually change what it's pointing to and it
will be reflected in the vector.
But when you are using integers and floats and doubles remember we're making copies of what we're putting
into the vector.
All right so that completes this solution.
I hope you enjoyed the challenge and I'll see you in the next video.