In this video we'll go over C++ is arithmetic operators.
These are exactly the ones you expect the plus symbol means addition the minus symbol means subtraction.
The asterisk is multiplication.
The forward slashes division and the percent symbol is the modulo operator or the remainder of division.
You may not be familiar with this operator but that's ok we'll cover toward the end of the video.
The plus minus multiplication and division operators are overloaded.
What that means is they'll work with different types.
So we can add two integers we can add two floats we can add two doubles by simply using the plus symbol.
The same is true for subtraction multiplication division.
The modular operator only works with integers.
And again I'll show you an example of that a little bit.
So let's try a few examples here and the code down here you can see that I've declared two integers.
Number one and number two and I've assigned 200 and 100 to them respectively.
Again these are integers you could do this with doubles or floats or anything you'd like but I'm just
going to use integers here.
You can see that this first line is first output statement right here.
Let's walk through that really quickly so we're clear as to what's going on here.
Remember we've got expressions here.
So number one is an expression.
Number two is an expression and that addition expression is evaluated to the sum of number one and number
two.
So in this case number one is two hundred So this will be replaced with 200.
No.
2 is 100.
And this will be replaced with 100 and then number one post them 2 will be added together.
That's why the plus is there and this will give us 300 OK.
Now these guys are inside quotes so their string literals and all will be printed out as is.
So what we expect here is 200 plus 100 equals 300.
And of course we've got the new line or the line at the end.
All right.
So let's run this and see if we get what we expect.
And exactly that's what happens.
200 plus 100 equals 300.
OK so let me comment that line out and what we could do is rather than do that calculation right in
line right here we could simply do the calculation and assign it to a variable.
In this case let's create a variable called result and will initialize it to zero and all we're saying
is add no one and number two that will give us 300 and assign that result to the result variable.
OK so we're going to add 200 plus 100.
That gives us 300 and we're storing 300 into result and then rather than do the calculation here as
we did we're just going to print that result.
It's as easy as that.
So when I run this now I should have the same exact output 200 plus 100 equals 300.
So now let me comment out some of these and we'll walk through these real quick and I'll do it right
up to their.
So this next one here on line 29.
I'm simply subtracting number one minus number two.
Storing the difference in result and then I'm outputting result.
So here we would expect 200 minus 100 we'd expect 100 on 9:32 that were multiplying the two.
This is different from algebra.
Did you have to have that multiplication symbol that asterisk you can't just say someone to or something
like that you would do in algebra you just put the two things together you can't use a dot like you
could in algebra as well it's got to be the multiplication operator which is the asterisk.
So we're going to multiply number one and number two that it is 20000 which we store in result and we're
displaying that.
And then the third one would be.
Result is number 1 divided by number two that's on my 35.
And we're going to store that quotient in two result.
There we would expect 200 divided by 100 gives us two.
OK so let's run.
We've got right here and see what our results are.
So we've got 200 plus 100 like we did before 300 200 minus 100 is 100 200 times 100 is 20000 and 200
divided by a hundred is two.
OK.
So this is exactly like you would expect is really really simple math works just like you expect it
to.
Now something you may not expect is this result right here on thirty.
I'm going to uncomment this.
And in this case what I'm doing is I'm dividing number two by Number one day remember.
Number two is 100.
And number one is 200.
So what's happening here is I'm dividing 100 divided by 200.
You would expect 0.5.
That's not what you get.
We're doing integer division.
OK.
So there are no digits after the decimal point we're working with whole numbers only.
So in this case what happens is 100 gets divided by 200.
And the result if this if these were doubles would be 0.5.
But we're working with integers so this piece is just chopped right off.
So we end up with a 0.
OK.
So let's run this
and you can see here 100 divided by 200 is 0.
You've got to be really careful when you're doing division with whole numbers or integers because this
is the behavior if you need to 0.5.
You want to be really really precise then you need to use doubles not integers.
And I'll show you an example using doubles in the second.
Now let's look at the modulo operator or the remainder of operator in this case right here.
I'm saying number one mod number two again what's number one.
It's 200.
What's up to 100.
So 200 divided by.
Let me write that out real clear.
So it's not confusing at all.
So we're going to say 200
divided by 100.
The result of this is to wear the remainder of 0.
That's the modulo operator.
It's only interested in the remainder so in this case it'll print out a zero.
The next line I'll uncomment that out in a second.
With the next slide we're going to say right here number one.
We clear that draw that line a little nicer than here we're saying number one mod number two.
So we're saying 10 maade 3.
Remember this only works with integers.
So the result here of the division will be three with a remainder of 1.
Number three times three is nine and you get the 1 remainder.
That's the result of the modulo operator.
It's a pretty handy operator.
So let me clear this and I'll uncomment these few lines of code right here.
And we'll run this
and let's take a look at the result.
So here we go 200 maade 100 is zero right.
That's the remainder because we get to with the remainder of zero.
And in this case 10 MMOG 3 is one because we get to three with the remainder of 1 when we divide by
3.
This can be a really really handy operator to use.
And in the challenge exercise you're going to have to use a tool to solve the problem.
Couple more things just like you can with up with any programming language and doing any kind of math
we can add and divide and subtract and we can do everything in line.
It's important to understand that the precedence or the order in which this stuff happens is the same
precedence you probably learned in grade school here in the U.S. we learned Pember the US that was the
acronym we use which meant parentheses first then exponents then multiplication and division and then
addition and subtraction.
You may have learned something else if you're from a different country but that's what we learned here.
So what this means is that multiplication and division happened before dition and subtraction right.
So in this case what's going to happen is no one is going to be multiplied by 10 and then we're going
to add them to that result.
Right.
If you want something else if you want to add the 10 and the number two first then you need to use parentheses
around there like that.
It's as simple as that.
And it's again it's something that we're all used to by now.
Let me clear this and then I'll do this last example with the division comment.
These two lines out.
So in this case I'm outputting 5 divided by 10.
Remember this is using integer division so 5 divided by 10 is zero not 0.5.
In this case five point zero divided by ten point zero is zero point five because we're using doubles
here in a couple of videos from now we're going to do a video where we're mixing types will be multiplying
and dividing integers and doubles all together on the same expression.
In that case we can use cast's to tell the compiler hey you know what I really want this to be a double
instead of an integer even though it looks like an integer there.
So we'll get to that in a minute and let me run this thing one more time and you could see the last
two results right down here.
Five divided by 10 is zero and five point zero divided by ten point zero is 0.5.
OK so now let's solve a real problem.
Let's convert euros to us dollars.
And I've created a project in the section 8 workspace called euros.
This project that I worked on right here is called arithmetic operators so you can refer to that if
you like but I've created a project called euros and that's when we'll get to next.
OK so I've opened up the main C-p file in the Euros project.
Right now there's really not much in here I'm just printing a newline at the end to separate that little
time message that is displayed at the end.
And there's no real code here.
We're going to write the code from scratch.
So we want to do is we want to convert euros to us dollar so obviously we need some sort of conversion
factor.
I just went on Google now and I saw that you have 1.1 nine dollars per euro.
OK so one euro is 1.1 nine dollars so we need to use that value somewhere.
Now that's going to be a constant So let's define that is a constant we can do it right here.
We could say Konst we want it to be a double right because it's not an inchers 1.1 9 and we'll give
it a name we'll call it US dollars per euro currency you are able will initialize that to 1.1 9.
And don't forget the semi-colon.
So now we've declared that constant US dollars per euro to be 1.1 9.
It's not going to change even accidentally.
Now what do we need to do.
What we need to output a message to the user will say seek out will say welcome to the EU are two USD
converter or something like that and we'll put it in line at the end.
We need to ask the user to enter the value in euros right.
And that's the whole idea.
So seek out will say enter the value
in euros and we'll do something like that.
We won't put a new line there because we want to use or to type something and right next to it.
What do we do next.
Well we need to do a few things we need remember most of these programs are input processing and then
output we need input we need to read in from in the number of euros that they want to convert.
Right.
So we need to have something like in into euros.
So we need to define that variable right here.
Right.
So let's do that right in here.
We'll say double we'll call it euros that's a good name and we'll initialize it to zero point zero.
That way we know we've got to zero value in there.
We know we're going to convert this to dollars right.
So we may as well create our dollars variable as well.
So we can say double and we can call it dollars.
And again zero point zero.
Perfect Now we're red in the Euros.
We need to convert the Euros to dollars.
How do we do that.
We just use a real simple multiplication.
We can say that the number of dollars is equal to again the number of euros times the constant we have
dollars per euro and now all we need is that final output statement let me scroll up just a little bit
and we'll say something like see out and we'll say the Euros whatever whatever they entered
is equivalent to we'll actually say euros that will be nice.
They can read it better.
Is that enough to put another insertion operator here.
Type in dollars whatever they whatever the conversion was and then we'll just type the string.
So nice and readable that will put a new line at the end within line.
And that should be it.
Let's run this as if we have any errors.
We'll test it to make sure we don't have any errors and we'll debug it if we do have any errors.
All right.
So I'm going to save in a minute press and trial at five to run.
There is no compiler error so that's great.
So enter the value in euros.
Well let's type in one euro right.
If we type in one euro we expect back 1.1 nine dollars that would be a real simple and good test case.
One we get one euro is equivalent to 1.1 nine dollars.
Good.
Let's try another one.
It's run.
How about 120 three point five euros.
We get back one forty six point nine six five dollars.
Don't worry about the precision and the dollars and cents will we'll learn how to format output a little
bit later.
That's it.
That's the program really really simple.
You can see what we're doing here is where you were using the things that we've learned right.
We're using RCN we're using our sea out we've got a constant defined right here.
We've got some variables that we need here and we're initializing them to zero and we're doing our calculation
here using one of the earth Medich operators the multiplication symbol.
I encourage you to write one of these programs on your own right.
I don't know a something to something converter Fahrenheit to Celsius kilometers to Miles yards two
inches meters to centimeters.
Right.
One of these programs just like that that will give you a good practice.