In this video we'll learn about mixed type expressions.
This is when you have an expression where the operands are of different types.
For example a plus b where as an integer and B is a double C++ is very consistent with its application
of an operator to operands the operands must be of the same type as we'll see in the next few slides.
It's very important to understand the rules that C++ uses to ensure that the types are the same since
the results of the calculation could be different depending on which operand type is changed.
C++ will try to convert one of the operands so it matches the other.
In many cases this happens automatically and we'll talk about how that works in the next slide if an
automatic conversion or coersion is not possible then a compiler error will occur.
We saw an example of this in the assignment operator video when we tried to assign a string to an integer
in order to understand how these conversions happen.
We need to understand higher versus lower types.
The idea is simple the lower types are those types that can hold smaller values and the higher types
can hold large values.
So a long double is a higher type than a long and a Long is of higher type than an int.
The idea is that we can typically convert from a lower type to a larger type automatically since the
lower types value will fit into the higher types value.
But the opposite may not be true.
Short and character types are always converted to integers.
So let's look at the terminology a type conversion is also called a coersion.
Since we're chorusing one type to another.
Sometimes this happens automatically and sometimes we do it ourselves in code.
Promotion is when we convert a lower type to a higher type.
An example would be when we add an integer and a double.
In this case we promote the integer to a double and then do the calculation.
Demotion is when we convert a higher type to a lower type.
Suppose we want to store twelve point five into an integer variable.
It won't fit.
So a demotion happens and the decimal part of twelve point five is truncated and we're left just with
the integer 12.
Let's see a few examples in the first example.
We have two different types and an operator you can think of the operator is the multiplication operator
but it applies to any operator in order to perform the multiplication.
The compiler will convert the lower type to the higher type and then perform the multiplication.
You can see in the example where we multiply the integer 2 and the double 5.2.
In this case we can promote the lower type which is the integer 2 to the double two point zero and then
perform the multiplication in the second example.
We're assigning a value from a higher type to a lower type.
In this case the compiler demotes the higher type to the lower type potentially losing information.
Many compilers will warn you about the possible loss of precision but not all do.
In this example we have Gnome as an integer and we assign a double one hundred point to one hundred
point two will be demoted to the integer 100 and 100 will be assigned to them.
As mentioned previously the C++ compiler will try to do automatic coersion when it can.
However as programmers we can explicitly tell the compiler to cast to a specific type if we wish.
Let's see how.
So let's talk about how we can tell the compiler to coerce or cast one type to another.
Let's walk through this example.
You can see we have two integer variables.
Think of total amount as a running sum of several numbers and we want to know the average of those numbers.
So we need to know how many numbers there are in this case.
This is represented by the integer total number which is a the average in this case would be total amount
divided by total number which is twelve point five.
But since both of these variables are integers the compiler will do integer division and the result
will be 12.
That's not what we want we could change the type of total amount to double.
But we're modeling a running total of integers so an integer type is more appropriate.
The solution is for us to tell the compiler to cast or perform a coersion of total amount from integer
to double.
The syntax is to use static underscore cast followed by the type we want to convert to in angle brackets
and then the variable name in parentheses.
Now one of the operands is a double so the compiler will automatically convert the total number to a
double and do double division which is exactly what we want.
Now we get twelve point five which is the result we wanted.
Let's head over to code line and write a program that asks the user for three integers and computes
their average.
OK so now I'm in the cold light idea I mean the Section 8 workspace in the mixed expressions project.
So let's write a program here that asks the user to enter three integers.
We calculate the sum of those integers and then we calculate the average of the integers.
All right.
Then it then will just display the three integers that were entered.
The sum of the integers and the average that we calculate it.
All right so let's get started.
We have an empty Main here and I'll scroll this up so we have a little bit more room to work.
And we know we need a total wreck.
We need to sum up those three numbers.
But we also need to store those three numbers.
So let's create those variables first.
We'll create a total variable.
And again the names you use can be anything you like and will zero that out and we'll create three variables
for the numbers that we're going to enter.
We'll call them number 1 and I could do this and do each one on each line but what I'm going to do is
I'm going to do them all in one line.
Some to say number one.
And I'm going to say number two.
And finally I'll say them three this initialises all three of them to zero.
If you don't do it this way or rather if you do it this way and you don't put those initializers there
then some three will be zero and no one in them two will be undefined.
So if you do it this way be certain that each one of them gets its own initialiser.
So that's it.
We've got our three numbers we've got our total.
And we also need a count right.
We're going to have three numbers.
We may as well define that integer as a contest and we'll call it count.
And again we'll initialize that three.
That way we know we're not going to make any silly mistakes.
Great.
So let's prompt the user will say see out and I'll just say Enter three integers separated by spaces.
That way they could just type them in on one line.
Would have to do three prompts
and we'll just leave it at that.
Don't forget the semi-colon at the end.
We don't need an end line here.
Now we're going to read all three integers so what do you see in.
We'll use the extraction operator.
No one would just chain them together.
Two and them three.
All right so now we've got all three of our integers.
We need to total them up.
Now we need to some of them all up so we've got our total variable.
So we'll just say total is number one plus two plus number three.
All right so now we've got that now obviously we could have total be a double but it really makes sense
for it to be integers because we're adding up integers so the total should be in the.
So now let's calculate the average We need a variable to hold that.
So that will be a double and we'll just call it average and it's initialized to zero point zero.
That way we know we've got a known value in there.
Great.
So let's do the calculation now average.
And I'm just using some blank lines here just to separate them.
Normally you wouldn't write all these blank lines but I just want to write them so you can really see
what's going on.
So I'll say average is the total divided by count.
That's it.
And now we've got our output statements will say that just say something like the three numbers were
and will display all three numbers will say no one will put a comma here forcing them to put another
comma.
And finally number three followed by the line next day we'll say the same
the sum of the numbers is.
And obviously that is our total variable.
So we'll split total here and again we'll follow it by and then line and then finally average is my
last output statement and I would just say the average
of the numbers is and again average.
OK so so far so good in line.
That's it.
Let's compile this and see if we've got any compiler errors that we have to fix.
OK.
No compiler errors it runs.
So let's run this into three integers separated by spaces.
How about 10 30 and 20 right.
That's 40 50 60 60 divided by three is going to give me 20.
So I expect that to be the average Precentor the output says the three numbers were 10 30 20 That's
correct.
The sum of the numbers is 60.
That's correct.
The average of the numbers is 20.
That's also correct.
OK.
One more test case we'll say 10 20 15.
In this case we've got 45.
The average is 15.
Good.
We're done.
No we're not.
Program has a pretty big problem in it.
And we saw that in the slides.
Suppose that I run it again with a different test case something like 10 20 20.
In this case it's 50 divided by three which is sixteen point six six seven.
Instead I'm getting 16 because I'm doing integer division.
This is why testing your program is so important.
We're talking about testing as we go through the course but testing your program is important in testing
involves knowing what the result is before you run your program.
Right.
So in this case have some test cases ready maybe 000 something that is divisible evenly by three.
Another test case it isn't divisible by three and so forth.
OK.
So how do we fix this.
Well what we can do is we can cast that guy or this guy either one to a double and we'll use a static
cast.
So we'll say static underscore cast then in the angle brackets we put in the type that we want to cast
to in this case I want to cast it to a double or convert it to a double and then we put total inside
parentheses.
That's it.
Now what's going to happen is the compiler will convert totals would double the compiler will say oh
I want to do have got to double in an integer here so I'll convert the integer which would double as
well and do double division which is what we want.
So let's run this again and let's use that same test case 10 20 20.
And now we've got the correct average here.
OK.
Now before I finish this video off in older C-code instead of seeing this cast the static cast here
you might have seen something that looked like this
something like that.
Then total
divided by count or something like that.
OK.
This is the old C-style cast.
The static cast is what we want to be using in modern C++.
It's a little bit more restrictive than this kind of cast this kind of cast just assumes that whatever
totallers is going to be converted to a double The static cast double checks to make sure that it can
be converted to a double.
So you don't want to do this I'll just write.
Here is the comment old style just so if you've seen it you'll know it's all about.
OK so that's it.
That's the example.
Pretty straightforward way to finding some variables.
We're getting some input.
We're doing some calculations and then we're checking that calculation to be sure it's correct.
In this case I've got integer integer division.
I've got to make one of those double Otherwise I'm not going to get the right result.
OK.
That's it for this video.