In this video we'll learn about the C plus plus if statement the statement is the most basic of the
C plus plus selection statements and his syntax couldn't be any simpler.
We start with the keyword and this is followed with the control expression in parentheses the control
expression must evaluate to a boolean true false value.
If the value of the expression is true then the statement is executed.
Otherwise the statement is skipped.
Note that the statement is indented.
Indented our code in the main function but the station is a very important element of style that we
need to start getting used to right away by indenting the statement it makes it easier for someone reading
the code to see that the statement is part of the if statement.
Remember indentation style is just for us human programmers to help us see the structure of the code.
The compiler doesn't care where you place the statement so you can see how simple the statement is.
But see conceptually what's going on in the if statement.
Suppose we have this code.
If Nahm is greater than 10 incremented by one the expression numb greater than 10 will be evaluated
to True or false if it's true then none will be incremented.
If it's false no increment will take place.
The flowchart on the right shows visually what the flow of control looks like.
Let's see some simple examples of if statements
in the first statement were checking if selection is equal to the character A.
If it is then we execute the output statement.
If it is false we skip the output statement in the second example we're checking if number is greater
than 10 if it is we execute the PUT statement in the last example.
We're using the and logical operator in the control expression.
In this case we check to see if health is less than 100 and player healed is true.
If both these expressions are true then the entire control expression is true.
And we set the player's health to 100.
Otherwise we skip the statement.
But if you want to execute more than one statement if the condition is true well that's were block statements
come in a block statement is a sequence of statements inside a block which is made up of opening and
closing curly brackets.
Notice the code on the left.
The two statements in the body of the if statement are inside curly braces.
If numb is greater than 10 then the block statement is executed which means that the increment and the
output statements are both executed.
The diagram on the right shows a visual representation of the control flow let's talk a little more
about blocks.
We've actually already seen a block statement.
Remember the main function we've been using in all our programs so far it has an open curly at the beginning
and a close curly at the end.
This is a block statement and we had sequences of statements in the block statement block statements
introduce a new level of scope.
We'll talk about scope as we go through examples in this course.
But just like we declared variables in the main block we can declare variables in any block even in
a block that's inside an if statement variables that we declare in a block are only visible to statements
that are also in the same block.
This lets us modularize our code so we have better control of who sees what which makes writing and
debugging our code easier.
Let's head over to the idea and we'll see some if statements in action.
OK so I mean the code like Id I'm in the section 9 workspace in the if statement project.
And what I want to do here is I want to create a simple program that will create four different if statements.
Let me show you what we'll do.
Let's say we've got a number line here and there's a minimum of 10 and the max is 100.
Let's say here what I want to do is I want to ask to use an integer and I want to be able to check that
the integer is greater than or equal to 10.
So that will be one of the statements I want to make sure that the integer The entered is less than
or equal to 100.
That would be the second one.
The third if statement I want to write is I want to be sure that that integer they enter is within that
bounds.
So between 10 and 100 including 10 and 100 that will be the third one.
And then the fourth statement will right as well.
Check that boundary condition.
So we want to know whether it's actually equal to 10 or equal to 100.
So those are the four statements we're right and we'll we'll talk a little bit about if statements as
we go.
So first thing I want to do is I want to create some variables I need an integer I'll just call it numb
and all initialize it to zero.
This is where I'm going to read the integer from the user into then I need to model those boundaries
so I'll use constants for that.
I'll just say min and max will set me into 10 and we'll set max to 100.
OK so that represents those boundaries.
So the first thing I'll do is I'll ask the user to enter a number between minimax
OK.
Simple as that.
And let me put a little Pullan here so they can see what they're doing and then what we're do is we'll
read that into.
No that's the only input we're going to be able to get in this program just a simple integer we'll get
it from the user and try a number between min and max.
Let's test that make sure we didn't make any mistakes.
Enter number between 10 and 100.
Exactly.
And I'm entering 10 I'm doing nothing right now with it and I need to get rid of that little extra space
that I had there.
OK so now let's write our first if statement will be number one here.
So I'm simply going to say if the number that the user entered is greater than or equal to 10 which
in this case is min then all I really want to say is as my output statement I'm going to say nothing
else is greater than men.
That's it.
All right.
So let's test that out.
So when I am going to type something greater than 10 now I want to type in 20 that if statement should
fire and I get 20 is greater than 10.
Perfect.
Now if I type something in that is not greater than 10 let's say five I should see no output which is
exactly what happens because that statement will be skipped.
Now suppose that I want to display something else I want to execute more than just that one statement.
This is where you need a block.
So I'll create a Cur-Lee here and I'll put a Cur-Lee down here below the if that establishes a block.
Notice that I'm indenting I'm not writing on my code or flush on the left.
If you indent it's much easier to see the structure of the code.
And as you in debt further and further and you mess things one within the other the structure of the
code really jumps out at you and it's very easy to follow.
So in this case I want to do a statement right up here since we're going to write four if statements
I'm going to say this to a slash and to give me a new line at the beginning and I'm just going to put
some dashes and then must say if statement 1 Put some more dashes here and you'll see why I'm doing
that in a little bit.
OK.
So if we run that now we should see both of those lines display.
So I'll enter something greater than 10.
I put in there 30 and those are both my lines my if statement one line as well as the 30 is greater
than 10.
So again really simple anytime you want to execute more than one line of code or more than one statement
you need to wrap them up in a block.
Now suppose that I also want to display how far away that is from men.
And what's the difference between the number that I entered and men.
Well I could just subtract right.
It's pretty simple.
So we could create an integer here and I'll just call it.
Mean create a little space here.
OK I'll call I have an integer and I just call it for the difference and I'll initialize that to the
number the user typed in minus the mean right because I know it's greater than men so that's going to
be positive.
And then I'll just say see out the number you entered is and use diff here the difference amount and
I know it's greater and greater than men.
That's it.
Now it's really important to understand a couple of things here.
One is this variable.
I'm declaring that variable diff inside the block.
You can see the block right here.
There's one Cur-Lee there's the other curly.
So what that means is that that variable div is only available to the statements after I've declared
it inside the block basically So it's only this block that's it.
Nothing else can see that variable.
This is a good thing if that gets a really scary value in there and it's really out of whack.
Well then the only place it could have changed that is this block so I know exactly where to look.
OK.
So let me clear a little bit of that and what I'll do now is let's run this and see if this is correct.
So I'm going to enter a number between 10 and 20 and 100 and say I want to enter 50.
I know that that is greater than 10 and I know that it's 40 away from 10.
So that's what I'm expecting.
And there's my IF statement 150 is greater than 10 and 50 is 40 greater than 10.
Perfect.
If I again type something and like five I'll get no output which is perfect.
That's exactly where I want to be.
So that takes care of that first statement.
Now that's right.
The second IF statement this one we're going to check to see if the number is less than or equal to
Max.
Right so it's the same idea I'm just going to say if the number is less than or equal to the max That's
the upper bound.
Then I want to display this out statement me just copy and paste that
and I'll just change this to a so my IF statement 2.
And over here I want to say that my name is less than in this case.
I should be less than or equal to that I should fix that appear because I know that it's greater than
or equal to.
Since that's what I'm doing in my condition
fix that quick trigger that should do it.
In this case it's less than or equal to max
OK and that's the difference here as well.
Now here if I say if I just do something like diff
is equal to max minus numb which is the calculation I want to do.
But when I compiled this you're going to get an error is going to say diff was not declared in this
scope because this is gone now if was declared in this block that block is finished.
The diff isn't even visible anymore.
So I need to create another if diff So if I just say and if and I'll just initialize it to max minus.
Similar to what I did above.
This creates a new copy of that integer div that's only visible to this block here.
Now sure I could have just created that diff way appear like I did with and it would be visible to everybody
but it's wanted to show you how the scope rules work.
OK so there's my def number to say see out the number you entered is gif amount.
In this case less than
max
and I'll finish that off.
OK.
So let's run this testis out.
All right.
So let's type a number like 80.
We we expect both those if statements to fire right because 80 is greater than 10 and it's also less
than 100 less than or equal to 100.
So there we go both if statements fire 80 is greater than or equal to 10.
80 is 70 greater than 10 that are here we're saying 80 is less than or equal to 100 and it's 20 less
than 100.
So both those if statements fire.
But let's test this with other numbers here.
So let's say I type in 150.
In this case only if statement 1 fires because 150 is greater than or equal to 10.
But it's not less than or equal to 100.
OK.
Same thing if I type in let's say five on the if statement two fires now.
OK so hopefully that makes sense.
So now the third statement we want to write is the one that's right here it's going to check to make
sure that is within the bounds.
OK.
So in this case what we'll say is we'll say if the number the user entered is greater than or equal
to the men and the number the user entered is less than or equal to the max.
Remember you've got to do this here with numb you've got to write that word and you can't just say less
and we go to Max you've got to say numb Let's go to Max again I'll have my block statement here.
Notice that when I type that beginning curly coat light finishes it off with the curly and let's copy
this guy right here and we'll say that this is if statement 3.
And in this case would just say something Vecsey out number
is in range let's say.
OK so we know that it's within that range.
There's no difference here to take care of we could draw differences.
But let's just do that.
What's interesting here is that statement 3 will only execute when statements want to execute right
because we're in range we're greater than 10 in less than 100.
So let's write that down as well.
We'll say see
this means statements 1 and 2 must also be true or must also display in this case that just say display
hopefully that makes sense because you can see what's going on here.
If I entered a number that's in range somewhere in here then obviously this is going to be true and
this is going to be true.
So we'll have all three of those statements displaying a case that will run this and test it one number
in the middle and put in 50 notice all three if statements fire.
Which is exactly what we'd expect if we type in a number that's greater than 100 on the if statement
one fires.
And if we enter a number that's less than 10 only if statement 2 fires.
OK so now the last one we'll do is watch a check to see if it's right on those boundary conditions.
So we'll say if the number the user entered is equal to the men or the number the user entered is equal
to the max.
Notice how you have to have that or in there.
And would not work because it's never going to be equal to both.
So in this case we just care if it's equal to one or the other in which case we'll output statement
for
change at to for real quick and I'll leave this code available for you guys to play with afterward and
mess around with all you like.
And then what will say is see out Gnome is right on the boundary.
And what's need about this one is that if this one fires in all four statements supposed to be fiery.
So again I'll say
that all for display.
It will give this a quick test.
OK so let's do one of the boundary conditions 10.
There you go.
All four if statements fire because 10 obviously were in the range were on the boundary were greater
than one side and were less than the other so we're good here.
And again if I just type a five on the second IF statement fires so you can see some of the logic.
Now what's important to understand here let me just clear the screen real quick.
What's important to understand here is a couple of things.
One is these are independent if statements.
There are no elses in here.
We'll talk about Elsa's in the next video.
So this statement will execute so that condition is checked if this condition is true.
We execute this code.
Then we come here and we check this condition.
So we're basically checking the condition for all four of those if statements.
OK.
So hopefully that gives you some insight into if statements.
They're pretty straightforward.
Remember this condition we have in here could be anything we could use relational operators like we're
doing here.
We can use equality operators like we're doing down here.
We're comparing nomine men.
We could use logical operators like we doing right here and we can use all kinds of combinations of
these things as well.
OK.
So that finishes up off this video in the next video what we'll do is we'll talk about the if else statement.