In this video we'll see how we can nest if statements within other statements.
Many times the logic we need to use in order to solve problems is more complex than just an if else
decision.
Many times we need several layers of logic since and if or if else statement is a statement then we
can use it in C++ anywhere a statement is legal.
So in this case we can replace the statement part of the if statement with an entire IF statement if
we want.
That's exactly what this example shows.
Notice the indentation.
It becomes even more important now.
In this case we can test multiple complex conditions easily.
So we evaluate expression one.
And if it's false we skip everything.
But if it's true then we test expression too.
And if it's true we execute statement 1.
If it's false we execute statement to we can continue by including if or if else statement says we need.
Notice that we have two ifs and only ONE ELSE.
In computer science this is called the dangling else problem.
And every programming language has to decide how to handle it.
The problem is which if does that else belong to him in C++ and else belongs to the closest.
If of course we can use block statements to achieve any logic we want.
Let's see another example.
In this example we check if score is greater than 90 if it is not.
Then we skip down to the bottom up statement and we display Sorry no way.
If the score is greater than 90 then we check the nested IF statement condition and check if scores
greater than 95.
If it is then we display an A plus.
If it's not we display an AA in this slide we can see a flow chart that visually shows the flow of control
for the logic in this example.
Notice the first condition is checked.
Score greater than 90.
That's the expression in the first diamond on the left.
If true then we test the condition in the nested IF statement which is on the true branch.
Of course we can also use block statements as required to execute multiple statements.
In this example we're checking of Frank scores not equal to Bill's score.
If this fails that means that the scores are equal.
So we go to the else statement and display looks like a tie.
If their scores are not equal then we checked the condition the nested IF statement.
And if Frank scores greater than Bill score we display Frank wins.
Otherwise we display bill wins.
And these examples the nested IF has been in the true section of the if else statement we can have negative
statements in the L section as well.
Let's go to the idea and see some examples of nested if statements OK what I want to do next is I want
to open up the grades project within the section 9 workspace again.
In this case the main is empty.
And I'm just going to get rid of this piece right here just to print out a new line at the end.
OK so what we're going to do here is this program is going to ask the user for the score on an exam
between 0 and 100.
And we're going to tell them the letter grade similar to what we did in the slides but we want to validate
to make sure that what they entered is actually between 0 and 100.
And if it isn't we're going to tell them Sorry you need to know the number you entered is out of range.
Also once we determine the users.
Once we determine the student's grade we'll tell them your grade is your letter grade A B C D F and
if they get an F we'll tell them sorry you have to repeat the class OK.
So let's start here.
First off we need a couple of variables let's just use one called score.
That's what we're going to ask the user for and we'll say see our let's do the input output part really
quickly I would just say enter your score on the exam.
And I suppose you were at a 100 here so they know what the range is
and we'll grab the and put in to score.
OK so now we've got what we want.
We also would like to have a variable called letter grade and what we're going to do is we're going
to assign a b c d or f into that variable.
We can simply use a character variable that will be fine.
I was going to say char letter grade and we'll just initialize it to zero.
OK so now first thing we need to do is we need to validate that score.
We need to make sure that the score is between 0 and 100.
So we'll use a simple IF statement here.
So we'll see if the score is greater than or equal to zero and the score is less than or equal to 100.
I'll use a block here.
We need to do the true part right.
This is where we need to calculate their grade.
But if it's not then right here we want to say else and I'll do another block statement.
And in this case what we want to say is sorry
we'll say sorry and we'll tell them that the number they entered
is not in range.
Something Real Simple when we learn about looping in a couple of videos from now we'll be able to ask
them to enter it again.
But in this case this will be fine.
And let's test this.
A lot of times when we test our code you see there's nothing in here right now.
So we just do something like this and we expect to see that output in the positive case right in the
true case.
We're going to write code and actually calculate the grade but it's good to test as you go.
Don't write all your code all at once and then try to test it all at the end just test as you go and
you'll be much better off.
So let's try this let's run this get an error here.
Sorry no it's not no score.
There we go.
So there we go.
Enter your score on the exam.
Let's enter something valid like 70.
We should get the x's displayed.
There they are.
So we're good here.
And let's run it one more time and type in 120.
Sorry 120 is not in range.
And let's try something like negative 1 Sorry negative 1 is not in range cool.
So our logic seems to be right now what we need to do is write the logic in this piece right here that's
actually calculating there.
Great.
All right.
So what we can do here is we can write the if else if else if type code.
When I learned this stuff a long time ago that was called an if else ladder.
I haven't heard that term in a long time but it makes kind of sense because it does look like a ladder.
So what we'll do here is we'll say we'll use that same grading scale 98 76 he will say if the score
is greater than 90 and I'm not going to use blocks here just to save some some space on the screen we'll
save the letter grade and we'll assign an A to it and I notice that's a character.
So so those are single quotes not double quotes.
So we've got that and will say else if score is greater than 80 we'll say that her grade is a B again
single quotes don't forget the semi-colon.
Else if you get the idea we're just walking right down that ladder.
If it's greater than 70 then the letter grade in this case is a C
couple more else if the score is greater than 60
then the letter grade is a D.
And finally there's our catch all else in which case there are letter grade is an F.
OK let's try that out run this and we'll test it with a few numbers.
And I said greater than 90 I probably should have said greater than or equal to 90.
But it's all good.
So we'll say 91.
That's definitely anay.
We never printed out.
So that's two that this is why we test track C out.
Your grade is and we'll just display letter grade here.
Put it in line at the end.
OK now remember when I put this here fix that reader will see this it will execute no matter what.
So this if statement will execute one of those letters will be signed and then be displayed here.
Try that again.
So in this case we've got a 91.
That should be anay.
Your grade is an A.
The 81 should be a B.
It is still about a 50 which is definitely an F..
And here we go OK.
Obviously you would test this a little better.
But for the sake of time I'm not going to do that.
The last thing we want to do is right here we want to tell them.
Did they pass or did they fail.
Well the only way you can fail in this example is if your better grade is an F and so there's no sense
in checking the score again.
We've already got the letter grade.
So I'm simply going to say if the letter grade is equal to an F doubled member double equal sign on
a single equal sign.
If that's the case C out
sorry you must repeat this class
ok.
Otherwise you passed
Gretz that's a passing grade or whatever you want to enter in here.
All right so that should do it.
Let's go through this real quick one more time.
We've got their score here.
We're prompting for the score and we're reading it in.
If the score is within range we do the calculation.
If it's not within range we're down here and we're out right away sorry the score is out of range.
We clean that up a little bit.
If the score is within range then we're going to use this if else latter.
And if it's greater than 90 it's an a greater than 80 to be we're going to walk all the way down.
You know what let me put equal signs here because it's it's bugging me
that it matches the slides that I gave you.
OK.
So that's a little better.
So now if it's greater than 90 you get the day and all the way through the AM who we're here.
Your grade is your letter grade.
And then we check to see if an F is just an F you must repeat the class.
OK let's run this now with a couple of test cases.
Suppose you got you are 90 now and should be DNA because we had the greater than or equal to your grade
as in a kind of Gratz.
If your grade is fifty nine your grade is an F..
Sorry you must repeat this class OK.
So there you go.
That's a simple example of using the if else if and the if else statements together on the next example
we're going to open up the shipping project in the section 9 workspace.
So we're in the shipping project of the section 9 workspace and I've gone ahead and started this little
example just so we save a little time.
And what we're doing here is we're doing we're using a shipping cost calculator.
We're going to ask the user for the package dimension in inches and the package is dimensions would
be length width and height and they all integers.
The dimension must be 10 inches or less for each dimension.
Otherwise we can't ship it.
The base costs for shipping is two dollars and fifty cents.
And if the package volume is greater than 100 cubic inches there's a 10 percent surcharge if the package
volume is greater than 500 cubic inches there's a 25 percent surcharge.
Okay.
So I started this already and I've got some variable set up and let me talk about them really quickly
we've got obviously we need the length the width and height that's what the user is going to enter.
And we've got the base costs which is a double $2 and 50 Cent so I've initialized that then we've got
a couple of other constants here.
One the Tier 1 threshold that's the volume.
So again if you exceed 100 cubic inches that kicks in and we've got to Tier 2 threshold to be 500 cubic
inches so I've defined those as constants the maximum dimension for any length is 10 inches.
And I've got the Tier 1 surcharge at 10 percent and the Tier 2 surcharge at 25 percent.
So that's pretty much it.
I've got all these constants and variables declared so that I can use them.
All right.
I also have another integer here called the package volume which obviously we need to calculate.
So this is where we're at.
Hello.
Welcome to the package cost calculator.
Enter the length width and height of the package separated by spaces.
And we've just read the length the width and the height into these variables.
Now we need to do our logic for the calculation of the package.
First thing we should do is let's make sure that the package is valid right.
Otherwise there's nothing to do.
So what we can do here is we can say if the length of the package is greater than the maximum dimensions
write the max dimension length which is 10 for everything or the width is greater than the max dimension
or the height is greater than max dimension.
Right if any one of those is greater than the maximum allowed dimension for any one side we really have
nothing to do.
Done.
So in this case what we want to do here is we want to say see out sorry package rejected or something
like that.
Dimensions exceeded
okay or some some message that tells them what's going on.
OK.
So that takes care of that.
Now here's the else part.
Right.
And we may as well put this in a block because we never know when you're going to add code to this or
put a Curlee here and a Cur-Lee here.
Now I can add code in there easily.
So that's my my if part this is when the package has been rejected the else part is now where we're
going to do all our calculations.
So again I'm going to do see out and do a quick test to make sure that we're compiling and everything
looks good.
So we want to run this and I'm running the old project that double click on shipping and it's Try that
and to the length width OK.
So let's say I'm exceeding right so much say 12 8 and 12 5 and 3 so the 12 should be over.
Sorry package rejected dimension exceeded.
That's good.
We could do test cases for all three of them right.
I'm not going to just to save a little time and in this case six seven and eight that's valid.
And we print out the three x's and we're ready to do our calculation.
OK.
So I mean get rid of that statement that I just did and that hello world on here at the bottom.
Right so now in here what we need to do is our calculations.
So we need to know what the package cost is right so we need to have a double in here we can do that
right inside the block because the only time we're going to use it is if we're going to do some calculation.
So in this case I could just say package cost and I can just initialize that to zero.
And how about the package volume again I could have defined that in here as well but it's already defined
outside the package volume is the length time the width times tonight.
OK so now we've got our package volume here is being calculated as the product of those three dimensions.
And we may as well say that the package cost is the base cost right right now we could start with that.
It's always going to be $2 or 50 cents plus perhaps some surcharge.
Okay so that's where we're at.
So far so good.
Now we need to do these checks for the package volume exceeding those thresholds.
What we want to do for us is we want to check the the Tier 2 threshold because it's the highest.
So what we want to do here is we want to see if the package volume is greater than the Tier 2 threshold.
If that's the case then the package cost
plus equals we're incrementing by the package cost times the Tier 2 surcharge.
Remember we're incrementing the left hand side by the right hand side and we could put a debug statement
in here.
Again it's very common to do that just saying adding Tier 2 surcharge you get rid of these when we ship
the code but it's nice to have them in here soon I'll teach you how to use a debugger which makes this
even easier.
OK so if this is not the case then we can say else if the package volume exceeds the Tier 1 threshold
and if that's the case we can basically just copy this and paste it in here.
In this case the package cost is the plus equals package cost times the Tier 1 surcharge and we can
just change that statement right here to do that.
OK.
So we're really done what we need to do now is say seek out the volume we'll give the user some information.
The volume of your package
is and will display the volume package volume.
We have an end line here and then we'll just tell them how much it's going to cost and that's really
what they want.
Your package will cost you put a dollar sign here.
And I believe it was package cost.
There it is
to ship
and that should do it.
Clean up some of this white space and we'll run this and then we'll do one more little thing before
we go and see Tier 1 surcharge.
I spelled it wrong.
She need an underscore right there.
And that that way you can see some of these errors.
Perfect.
So let's say five five and five I'm adding a tier 1 surcharge because the volume is greater than 100
You can see are 125.
So the package will cost 275 to ship.
Let's make it a little bit bigger the package that say it's 8 by 8 by 8.
In this case I'm adding a tier 2 surcharge.
The vault the package volume was 512 and it's going to cost three dollars and twelve cents to ship.
Okay.
Now you know this is 3.1 to 5 displays.
I'll show you how to set that up a little bit later in the course.
But for now just for how to do it really quickly.
If you come up to the includes And you include I O my net that's the input output manipulators.
And then right before you start printing the dollar amounts we're actually anywhere you can put this
anywhere you could just say see out fixed followed by set precision to 2 decimals after the Packers
this is
that just prints dollars nicely.
So if we run this again let's try that again.
We'll do 8 7 and 9.
You could see it printed up nicely three dollars and twelve cents.
And again I'll talk about those manipulators a little bit later on it just helps us look at our code
a little nicer.
All right.
So there you go.
There's some magic for shipping this package we've got an if statement.
We've got an else out if else if statement and hopefully this logic makes sense again.
Build these programs one step at a time testing as you go.