In this video we'll learn about the C++ for loop and a few of its variations.
The for loop consists of the four key word followed by three expressions in parentheses.
Each of these expressions is separated by semi-colon the semi-colons are required but the expressions
are all optional.
We'll see more about this later.
In its simplest form the for loop has initialization expression followed by a conditional expression
that evaluates to a boolean and then an increment expression.
First the initialization expression is executed exactly once before any iteration occurs.
Then the condition is checked if it's true.
The body of the loop is executed then the iteration expression is executed and we check the condition
again and repeat.
When the condition evaluates to false the loop is terminated and we continue processing the statements
and follow the loop.
As you can see in this examples the for loop can execute one statement or many statements by using a
block statement.
Let's see a simple for loop that counts from 1 to 5.
Let's walk through this for live one step at a time.
Notice that in order to count we need some sort of variable.
It's common to use the variable named I as the loop variable that's incremented or decremented in a
loop.
In this case we declare it to be an integer and initialize it to zero.
Now we enter the loop.
The first thing that happens is the initialization.
In this case we assign one to I.
Now we check the condition.
Since one is less than or equal to 5.
We execute the body of the loop which is the output statement and we display 1.
Then we execute the increment expression which increments by one note.
That plus plus and plus plus mean the same thing here.
Since the increment happens on it's own and it's not in another expression.
So now as to we check the condition again and it evaluates to true.
So we execute the body of the loop again and display 2.
Then we increment it again and keep iterating after we display 5 items.
I will be 5 and then we incremented to 6.
At this point the condition fails and the loop terminates C++ for loops are very efficient and in their
basic form.
Very easy to read or modify.
Let's see another way to declare the Luby variable.
We can declare and initialized the looping variable.
I in this case write in the initialization statement.
This is very commonly done and has some advantages.
Here you can see we're doing it using two styles.
The first uses initialization style and the second uses assignment style.
I will be using initialization style in this course.
The looping variable eyes only visible inside the for loop.
Once the loop has finished I'm no longer visible and you'll get a compiler error if you try to use it.
This is a great feature since you know that I'm totally under your control within the loop and won't
have any strange values coming into the loop or exiting the loop.
Let's see another exam in this example.
We're looping from 1 to 10.
The body of the loop test to see if the remainder of II is 0.
So it's testing to see if I's an even number.
If it is that display XY.
So this loop displays all the even numbers between 1 and 10 inclusive.
Let's see how we can use a for loop with an array.
In this example we're using a for loop to display the elements of an array.
Here we've declared scores as an array of integers and we've initialized it to one hundred ninety and
eighty seven.
Since array indexes begin at 0 and go to size minus one we must be sure to stay within those bounds
or our program could likely crash.
So we declare an initialized to zero and our loop condition is less than 3 and we increment by 1 at
each iteration.
So we loop for equal to zero 1 and 2.
Which is exactly what we want.
The body of the loop simply displays the array element at index.
This will display one hundred ninety and eighty seven as we wanted.
Be very careful when you work with loops in arrays.
The condition should either be less than the size of the array or less than or equal to the size minus
one hot tip.
Always use one or the other and stick to it.
Don't start flipping between them because eventually you're going to make a mistake.
I always use less than the size of the array and I've been doing it that way my entire career.
This helps prevent what are called off by one errors which basically mean that we went overbalancing
your program could crash or corrupt data C++ has an operator called the comma operator that isn't used
very often in C++ but sometimes you see it used in loops to initialize loop variables.
The comma operator allows you to separate expressions with the comma in both expressions will execute.
Note that the associativity is right to left and the result of the comma operator is the leftmost expression.
In this case we're just using it to initialize two variables and then to increment those two variables.
In this example we want to start at 1 and j to start at 5 and we want to loop while it is less than
or equal to 5.
The output statement in the body of the loop displays I times J the product.
Then the increment also uses a comma operator to increment both i and j.
So in this case I goes from 1 to 5 and J from 5 to 9 and at every iteration we display the product of
i and j walk through this example slowly yourself and you'll see that it's pretty straightforward.
The syntax looks a bit odd though since there's so much going on the basic for loop with all three expressions
is concise.
Easy to read or modify in the examples I showed we used integers.
But you can use doubles with four loops as well.
Also I counted up in these examples.
You of course can count down but since the expressions are all optional it's possible to have all sorts
of variations.
You could even have a for loop with just a semi-colons in the parentheses.
This is by definition an endless loop.
Best practice in Protip.
Don't write for loops with missing expressions and complicated expressions with comma operators.
The example I showed is simple and understandable but if you find that you're omitting expressions then
consider using one of C plus plus other loops.
Great.
Let's head over to the idea we'll see some examples of the for loop in life code.
I mean the code like ID and I'm in the section 9 workspace in the for loop project.
What I want to do here is I want to write a few different for loops to write a bunch of them that behave
differently some will count up some will cut down to get a feel for how these four loops work and I'll
write them and I'll comment them out along the way.
That way they'll be in the source file so you can play with them later.
So let's do a simple one first.
Let's just say something like.
For it I will start at 1.
That's the initialization expression right there and then we want to loop while I say is less than or
equal to 10 and at each iteration what we want to do is increment by one.
Now in this case I can say plus plus I or I plus plus it means exactly the same thing as case and simply
output.
I
will Kate.
Simple as that.
Let's run this you can see we're going from 1 to 10.
Obviously when I hit 11 this condition right here fails and I stop the loop and then I just hit this
and line over here right before the return.
OK.
So real simple example and I'll just copy and paste this so that you can see a variant of it and I'll
comment that out here.
Now suppose I want to go from I to 10 by two.
I don't have to increment by one.
I can imprint by whatever I want so I can hear in the increments expression I could just say I plus
equals two equals I posters were going to do the same exact thing except when we increment we're going
to increment by two.
So let's run this one.
And there you go.
1 3 5 7 9 exactly what I expect because I'm starting at 1 and then eventually it's going to hit 11 and
it'll fail.
OK.
So hopefully that makes sense.
Let's count down on the next one.
Let me comment that out and let's do this now let's say for ant.
And again I is a real common variable name to use with looping i j k you'll see those all over the place
and C plus plus could.
So let's say I want to initialize to 10 in this case and I want to loop while I is greater than or equal
to zero let's just say greater than zero.
And in this case I want to decrement every time.
So again I'm starting with eyes 10.
And as long as I is greater than zero or I'm positive I want to execute the statement which I'm going
to write right now and again I'm just going to output I.
And then I want to decorate it.
So this should count down now.
So let's try that out.
And they go 10 9 8 7 6 all the way down to 1.
If I write in something like this and say blastoff then we expect that to execute after the loop is
done see that.
So that works out perfectly.
There's a blast off.
And one quick thing.
Some compilers not all compilers but some compilers will give you a warning when you indent wrong.
OK so in this case if I indented C out this blastoff statement over here that's not correct.
Right because I don't have Curley's.
So this for loop really only executes that one statement.
But when I see this code visually My eyes are telling me that those two statements are in the for loop
but they're not.
If I try to compile this notice it works but I get a warning.
The warning says Warning this for Clause does not guard.
That's not real helpful I know but notice the morning message is misleading indentation.
That's a great warning a lot of compilers don't do that.
So what it's telling you is that something's not right with the indentation.
You may think it's doing one thing but it really isn't.
So once you unindexed that indent it properly now you'll have a clean compile with no errors and no
warnings.
That's a really nice feature of the GCC compilers.
OK so let me come get that piece out again and let's write another version of a for loop.
In this case why don't we count from 10 to 100 by 10.
So again for the initialization statement.
I will initialize it to 10 members that only happens exactly one time right before the loop begins.
And I want to loop while I's less than or equal to 100.
And in each iteration I want to say I plus equals 10.
So when increment by 10 each time and I'm going to put in a block statement here just because I'm going
to use a few of their statements a bit.
But right now let's just print.
OK so again we're going from 10 to 100 inclusive by 10 so we expect this to print out 10 20 30 40 all
the way to 100.
Let's try that out.
And that's the result from 10 to 100 by 10 exactly what we expect.
Now suppose I only wanted to print out those numbers that are between 10 and 100 by 10 and also divisible
by 15 without a remainder.
OK.
So what we can do here is we can put an if statement here we can say if that specific I am looking at
mod 15 is equal to zero.
Right so if that is divisible by 15 then I want to display it.
So at this point.
Out of those 10 20 30 40 50 and so forth we really only expect 30 60 and 90 to match this criteria.
Those are the only ones that are divisible by zero.
By 15 I'm sorry.
So let's run this.
And there they are 30 60 90 you are the only ones in that set that are divisible by 15.
Now let's take a look at that comma operator I talked about the syntax for this is again that's not
bad it just gets kind of long and convoluted.
So let's try that out.
Let's say for now in this case in the initialization statement I want to initialize more than one variable
so I can put them all in here separated by commas not semi-colons commas.
So I say it.
And I want to initialize I to 1.
Now I put a comma in there and j to 5.
That's my initialization I'm setting I to 1 and j to 5.
Now comes my loop condition.
I want to loop while I is less centered 5 and now is the increment expression.
So where I say what I want to do it each iteration where I want to increment I.
And I want to increment J so I can put the comma operator there.
Any comment J.
So you could see the purpose of this operator within this for loop is just to make everything concise
because it makes sense here right.
I mean I want to initialize I and J before I loop and I want to increment them both at each iteration.
So rather than spread this logic all over the body of this loop you can just put it right in the head
or like that and it really conveys exactly what you want at this point.
I can just have a simple output statement that say we want to add I and J to generations are meant to
display.
I want to display that plus symbol.
I want to display J.
I want to display the equal sign.
That's a literal.
And this is display I Plus J will end up with a new line.
So let's run that and you see we have one plus five is six now.
It's I encourage you to walk through this example.
Mean grab your pen kind of like I'm doing right now and say OK this is I this is J.
Right now I've initialized them right.
One in five now I start the loop is I less than or equal to 5.
Well I's one so sure it's less was five I execute the body of the loop which says display I.
OK.
One then the plus then the J and the equal sign and then there's some then we do the increment which
means now eyes to JS 6 and just walk through the loop this way this way you really get an understanding
of what's going on.
Remember what happens we do the initialization one time then we check the condition that we execute
the body.
If it's true and then we do the increment.
So that's the order that this is all happening in.
OK.
So let me close this up and let's say that we wanted to use that use that conditional operator inside
the loop.
Just like I showed you in the conditional operator video there's a handy way to do it here.
So suppose I want to print out the numbers 1 to 100 in a little bit of a table format so they look nice
there's 10 across so 10 rows of 10 columns each.
How could I do that.
Well I could use something like for this or I mean that for an eye.
We can start at 1 and we want to loop while I
can try that again let's loop starting at it.
I said to one and I want to loop while I is the center equal to 100.
And in each iteration I want to increment I.
OK.
So that's what I want to do.
I'm going to put a block statement here so I can read a little bit more code.
Now I want to output I know I don't want to put an end line here I just want to output the itself in
what I want to do is every tenth I want to output a newline.
Otherwise I just want to output a space to move them across the row.
So let's do that with the modulus operator and say if I mod 10 so if it's the 10 item equals zero would
you want to do here.
Well in this case I just simply want to say seek out give me a line
and if it is not the tenth item I simply want to output a single space.
OK that's it.
So let's run this and see what we get.
You could see we're going 9:59 11 to 20 21 through 30 and again walk through this and you'll see exactly
what's going on.
It should be pretty clear here.
I'm printing out the I and I'm checking for every 10th item and I get every 10th I want to print a new
line.
Otherwise I just put a space if I wanted to print this as five across.
I can just change that guy right there from a 10 to a 5 and now I've got 20 rows of five.
OK.
So that takes care of that one.
Now suppose I wanted to write this same logic using the conditional operator Well let's see let's get
rid of this stuff here and what we can say right now here with the conditional operator is we could
say that's output that.
And then that's output.
Let's check the condition right.
Same condition we had before.
I mod 10 equals zero.
And if that is true we just display in the line we'll use the escape character.
Otherwise just a space.
And if we run this we should get exactly the same behavior we had before which we do.
Now remember since we're outputting we can chain output we can actually just get rid of all of this
stuff and just make it on one line we can do that.
We can up with the followed by either a space or a new line.
So this can be just written as a single line and we get the same behavior as before okay.
The last example I want to go over is using a vector and then we come at that out in the slides should
you how to do it with an array how to loop through an array and I'll show you how to use a vector.
And then the next video will use the range based for loop which makes using vectors really really simple.
But in this case let's create a vector.
You know I just get myself a little room here and I'll just call the vector Nom's and it's going to
be a vector of integers.
Let's just call it Nom's and let's initialize it to I don't know let's say 10 20 30 40 and 50.
So we've initialized it to those five numbers.
Now remember we're using a vector.
So we have to include vector.
So I'm going to come back up to the top and pounde include vector Otherwise we'll get a compiler.
So I'll come back down.
So there's my vector and let's say I want to loop through that vector and just display each item in
the vector.
Pretty easy I could say for it I want to initialize to zero member vectors started at zero.
Just like arrays now I can say while I is less than Nom's dot size will use the size method that is
in the vector class and that tells me how many items are in the vector and I want to increment by one
each time.
And I just simply want to say see out Nom's.
So I when I run this I expect to get 10 through 50.
We're going to get a warning and I'll show you how to fix that warning in a second.
And it's actually a good morning.
There you go tend to 50 is the output.
That's what you expected.
We're printing out all of those elements.
The warning says Warning comparison between signed an unsigned integer expressions.
OK.
What's going on here is that this numskulls size expression read here is returning an unsigned integer.
That makes sense right because you can't have vectors that are negatively sized.
So that's returning an unsigned integer and your return.
You're comparing it to a signed integer.
So you can just simply type unsigned here instead of signed and it actually makes more sense.
I've been using signed integers all along but a lot of times when you're looping especially when you're
looping through all the positive numbers it makes sense to use unsigned integers here so I'll save that
will compile and run.
And now we've got down here as you can see no errors no warnings and only compile.
So that pretty much covers the basics of for loops.
I will leave all these examples in the source code so you can play with them and change them around
as you like so you can learn from them.
The best way to really learn this is just to make up little examples and print out every fifth element
and see if they're divisible by 7 or something like that and just really get a feel for the way that
loops and walk through these examples one step at a time that really really is helpful.