This video we'll look at the last looping construct in C++.
It's called the do while loop the do while loop begins with the do keyword followed by block statement
then the while keyword followed by the loop control expression in parentheses.
Notice that you need a semi-colon at the end of the do while statement in a do while loop you execute
the body of a loop while the conditional expression is true.
Pretty straightforward.
Note that the condition is checked at the end of each iteration that makes the do while loop.
A post test loop.
It also means that you're guaranteed that the loop body will execute at least once.
This comes in very handy in many cases.
You don't have to force our way into the loop like we had to do with the While loop.
Let's see an example of using the do while loop for input validation.
In this example we execute the body of a loop.
Then test the condition.
So we asked the user for a number between 1 and 5 and assign it to the variable number.
Then we test to see if number is out of range.
If it is then we loop again.
If it is in range then the loop terminates.
You can see how much cleaner the logic is in this case.
Also let me talk for a minute about the variable number.
Notice how we declared it outside the loop body.
Since number is used in the while loops condition expression at the bottom A cannot be declared within
the body of the loop.
If you do so you'll get a compiler error.
In this example we're declaring selection as a character type.
It's outside the loop because we're using it in the loop condition at the bottom.
So let's look at the loop.
I always start reading loops at their conditional expression.
In this case we know we're looping while the selection is a lowercase or in our case Y.
If the selection is any other character the loop terminates.
Now let's see what's going on in the loop body.
We see we have two doubles width and height declared and initialized to zero and we asked the user for
these values and read them in from the keyboard.
Then we're calculating the product of the within the height and initializing another double named area.
With that result we display the area to the user and then we ask if they want to calculate another.
Note that we have executed that first iteration of the loop unconditionally.
That means we always execute this loop at least once.
This makes sense in this case since I want to be able to calculate the area.
Now we ask the user if they want to calculate another and we read their response into the selection
variable.
Then we test this variable in the loop condition.
If they entered a lowercase or an upper case why we perform another iteration of the loop and calculate
another area.
If they enter anything else the loop terminates and we display thinks the choice between a while loop
and a do while loop isn't always crystal clear.
However if you know that you must perform at least one iteration of the loop then you should consider
the do while loop as your first alternative.
Let's head over to the IDM We'll see how we can use a do loop to do a real simple menu system.
OK so I mean the ID and let me share an example of the application we're going to build.
Run it now and you could see it's a simple menu driven application there's the menu press 1 2 3 or Q.
If you press 1 you do this if you press to do that.
If you press 3 you do something else.
Obviously the selections could do any kind of behavior depending on your application.
So in this case I enter a selection.
I press number one and it says you chose 1 doing this.
If I press 2 it says you chose to doing that.
Press 3 you chose 3 doing something else.
Obviously if I press a lower case Q or an upper case Q to quit anything else should give me an illegal
entry.
So let's say I pressed 4.
It says here unknown option try again.
Say I pressed P again.
Unknown option.
Try again.
The only valid choices will be 1 2 3 and lowercase are uppercase Q.
So now if I type q the program terminates and says good bye.
OK so that's what we're going to build.
And in the section challenge at the end of the segment you're going to be using this kind of logic to
build a more complex application.
All right so let's start where do we start.
Well we know we need to display a menu at least one time right.
Because the user has to select Q or X or whatever we choose is the exit criteria.
So that's a good choice for a do while loop.
So basically what we're doing the do part which is display the menu while they haven't quit makes sense
so that's what we're going to build.
Now obviously we need a character variable and I'll just call it selection and whatever the user types
in will be stored into that Kerak variable.
Now let's do the do logic here.
We've got a do loop and we want to do the body of the loop.
While a condition is true now what is that condition.
Well we want a loop as long as they haven't typed a lower or an upper case Q So we can see something
like.
While selection is not equal to a lower case Q and selection is not equal to an upper case Q.
OK if you were thinking or here that would not be right and you would test your coding you'll see that
it doesn't work right.
So let's just write a real simple test here before you bother with anything else.
Let's just say in selection no menu no prompting No we're just going to grab a bunch of characters here
and see what happens.
So let's run that OK let's type in a loop.
Q We stop.
Cool that's what we want.
Ms try that again.
A one way loop to loop a three loop for we loop again.
The only time we should stop is when we get an old case or an uppercase Q we stop.
So our logic is correct here.
Right now what we can do is we can actually prompt the user and with the menu we can say see out and
let's just use a newline at the beginning so it gives us a new line every time we do a dash of characters
here and we'll do that and then we'll give them the menu options so you can press one.
And if you press one of Will do this.
Obviously this would be you know at a record or delete a record or do something in a real application
so that would be that.
And I'm just going to copy this and paste it to save a little time here.
So number one.
Number two would be do that number three.
Or option they would be do something else.
And then finally and we can say q or X or whatever letter you like.
To quit
perfect and we'll give them one more little prompt here that says it will put a new line in Frejus to
separate will say enter your selection
Colan no end line here so that looks nicer for them and then we put the selection right into selection
right.
So let's run this and we should see a menu show up and there you go.
Do this do that do something else or quit.
So if we press one we stay in the loop and we display the menu again.
Same thing with two.
Same thing with three four gives us the same issue because we haven't checked for anything that's illegal
right.
5 P whatever.
Now whenever I type Q I stop.
So what I need to do now is decide what the user has typed in and what to do.
OK how do I do that.
Well it's a lot of choices here.
We've got liberals here we got one the two the three these are character riddles so we could certainly
use a switch statement really really easily.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to use an if else if later here.
Again I encourage you to do this with an if.
With a switch statement with all kinds of logic that we can play around with it.
So let's do this.
I say if the selection that the user entered is the character want to remember this is a character so
we need the single quotes.
So if the user entered the one we simply want to say something like see out let's see you chose one
which was do this or let's just say doing this can put an end line at the end else and we don't need
block statements here we could certainly use them and makes it easier to modify our code.
But I wanted to try to keep as much on the screen as I can so else if the selection is a two then what
we want to do here and again I'll just copy and paste this to save a little bit of typing time.
Then you spell that correctly.
That's better you chose to which was doing that
else.
I remember your indentation make it make sure the indentation is correct because it adds to the readability
big time.
So if the selection is equal to three then in this case copying that again
you chose three which was doing something else and then so now what where are we at.
Well let's worry about the unknown option as the bottom else of this condition.
So if nothing else matches then we're going to say oh sorry try again.
But in this case if you really think about this one two three and Q are all valid.
Right.
So let's deal with Q Ossett else if selection is equal to AQ or not is that here we need more whereas
in the wild we need a demand or selection is equal to or lower case.
Q Then in this case really all we want to say is goodbye because Luke's going to fail we're going to
be out of here in a minute.
OK.
So that takes care of that case.
So what's left this else to here.
So what happened.
Well it's not a one.
It's not a 2 it's not a 3 it's not a Q It's got to be something that I don't know and I really don't
care it's something that's illegal.
So in this case we're just say out let's say something like a known option.
You spell that right and maybe try again.
We could do something like that.
Let me clear the space up and let's walk through this and make sure we're not missing anything.
We've got our selection variable declared that's important.
We're in the do.
We're going to execute this code immediately right.
This is unconditional the first time in we're in.
So we're displaying the menu and we're reading the selection of the user if the user selects one we
print we output you chose one doing this and that's it we're out of this if else if latter we test down
here and we loop while the selection is not lowercase or uppercase Q We come back up.
We display the menu again if they typed three.
We execute this code right here and we keep looping.
If they type.
Q What do we do we simply say goodbye.
And then this condition fires at the end it will fail and we're out of the loop.
If none of these are true we just say unknown option.
I don't know.
You've entered.
OK so let's try this and again I'm in the section 9 workspace and the do wild project.
So let's build and run
and we've got a clean compile and a run.
So let's try this.
Press 1 do this.
You chose one doing this exactly what we want to.
You chose two doing that three you chose three doing something else.
Let's say we press for unknown option try again.
But notice how we don't get out of the loop.
We don't want to get out of the loop right.
We want to ask them to do to enter Q If they want to get out.
So at this point we can press an uppercase Q And there it is goodbye and the program is finished ok
really really common use case is this idea of menu driven programs you want to display that menu the
first time ask the user for this election and basically use an if else if latter here or switch statement
would work here.
Try rewriting this program using a switch statement you'll see it's pretty easy to do as well.
Same same logic really.
OK.
So that's pretty much it in the challenge exercise at the end of the section we're actually going to
do stuff when the user presses one we're going to use a vector and you would be adding things to the
vector and displaying the vector elements and so forth depending on what they choose.
OK so that's the end of this video.
I encourage you like I said to walk through this and tweak it and change it and change his tune or and
see why it doesn't work.
Understand that that's really really important that's a very common mistake.
All right I'll see you in the next video.