Hello welcome back.
I hope you enjoyed the challenge and I hope it was successful in this video.
I'd like to go over that challenge and give you one solution to it.
So I'm in the section 9 workspace the challenge solution project.
In your case you're going to have this solution already but we'll work through it together here.
So let's say where are we.
Well we need some sort of data structure.
We need a list.
We need a collection that the user type integers and we can store it into right.
So in this case we're going to use a vector It's the only one we know right now and it's a really easy
and logical one to use.
So in order to use a vector we need to include vector.
I'll do that right now.
And obviously we need to declare a vector that's going to hold the numbers and we also need to declare
character.
That's where we're going to store whatever they typed on the keyboard.
So let's declare those two variables.
Right now we could call this vector whatever we like.
I'll just call it vector member it's a vector of integers and I'll call it numbers could call it data
you can call it whatever you like and I'm initializing it to empty.
And then I've got a character which I call selection and I'll also initialize that empty.
What we're gonna do is we're going to read the user's choice into that variable.
Ok so where are we now.
Remember what we're going to do is we're going to display the menu to the user.
We're going to ask them for choice depending on what they choose we'll do something or other and then
at the end of this do we want to keep looping while they haven't pressed Q Right either uppercase lowercase.
So let's write that logic first.
Let's start with baby steps.
Here's the DO loop and then we want to do while the selection is not equal to.
Remember in this case they can type in an upper case or lowercase Q Right.
So while it's not equal to a lowercase Q And again those are characters I make sure they're single quotes
not double quotes and the selection is not equal to an upper case Q.
There's a semi-colon here at the end of this while loop right there.
Do while loop.
That should take care of our logic now.
What we want to do in here is we want to display that menu right right away and that's the first thing
we want to do unconditionally.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy and paste my menu code right here which is just a bunch
of output statements.
And we're reading the selections so we can test this right now.
We're going to display print the number at number and all the menu choices that you saw in the demo
and then we're going to ask them tend toward choice and we're going to read that choice into selection
which is that character variable right here.
So what do I expect here.
Well I expect that if the user types lower or upper case Q The programable and if they type anything
else we should display the menu again and again and again asking for and to another choice.
All right.
So let's try that will build and run.
And there's the menu numbers out of numbers display number and so forth.
So let's say we enter P we get the menu again uppercase the same thing a 1 3 5 It doesn't matter anything.
Now what we're really interested in is we want the program to quit.
When I pressed both Q's upper and lower someone to press lowercase Q program stops perfect I'm going
to test this again with an uppercase Q program stops again.
Perfect.
Make sure you test both of them because a lot of times I've seen typos like this and of the tests with
the lowercase Q And it quits correctly.
But then the uppercase doesn't work.
So make sure that you test everything really well.
Now this is where we're at right here.
We know the user has selected something right.
So what do we need here.
But we need some selection logic.
We need to say well if you picked P I want to do some stuff.
If you pick a I want to do something else we have a choice.
We could use a switch statement really easily because these are going to be character literals.
This is a character so I could do a switch off of selection and they say case p p has case a case M
and M M but I mean uppercase lowercase and that'll be fine.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to use an if else if latter because it's usually what you'll see out
there and this kind of example over the case statement.
OK so let's try that first thing.
Let's deal with the print.
So we've got the selection here.
So here I want to say if the selection is equal to let's say an uppercase P or the selection is equal
to a lowercase P and I'm going to do a block statement here because I'm going to write some extra code
here so that's where we're at.
If the user types of P whether it's upper or lower case we're going to execute this code right here.
Well what does this code say print all the numbers in the list.
What's my list numbers right here.
What's the best way to do that range based for loop no question.
Really really easy is one thing we need to take care of though.
If that list is empty we need to tell the user list is empty.
We can do that now or we can do it or else statement.
I'm going to do it right now.
Someone to say member indent right here.
Want to say if numbers is the vector dot size is the method that returns the size.
If that returns is zero what's going on.
The list is empty right so I'm just going to say seek out and again indent under the if C out.
The two square brackets with nothing in it and then I'll just say the list is empty
and line and that's the if part.
Now what about the else part the else part is going to have a few more statements and this is soon to
say.
Else and then again a block statement here.
I could have said if numbers that size is not equal to zero and then put this code appear and then the
L sort of in the empty part both ways are absolutely perfectly logical and they're both correct.
So but in this case right now I'm here.
So when am I in here.
I'm in here when the size is not equal to zero.
In other words there is stuff in that vector.
So what I want to do now is printed out.
I want to pretend I don't.
A nice way with those brackets.
I'm just going to say C out and I'm going to print out that left bracket followed by space no and line
because I want to print the numbers right next to it and then I want to close it off with and bracket.
Now what I want to do here in the middle is print out those numbers one after the other with a space
between them.
How do I do that.
What's the best way to do that.
A range based for loop.
So let's do that for auto.
I'll call the variable name and the collection is numbers
and what do I do for each one of those.
Display it.
See out number.
Followed by a space
that should do it.
OK now right here.
I definitely want to do an end line that will take me to the next line.
Now let me clean this up so we can see the structure a little better and get rid of this space as well.
So look what's going on here we entered a selection the selection is piece of the user wants to print
out all those elements.
We know that there is either nothing in the list in which case we do this.
Otherwise we print out all the numbers in the list.
Right now the list is empty the first time I do this because I haven't been able to add anything right
so will run it and when I select P It should say list is empty.
There it is.
The list is empty.
Then I get the menu again that's important.
I'm going to quit.
Now let's test this with a list.
It's not empty what we'll do is we'll just come right up here and just put some stuff in there.
One two three four.
The list is definitely not empty now so we're run this and we expect to get one two three four right
in the brackets perfect.
So it looks like our print is done quit and we'll move on to the next one.
Now we're here it wasn't pee it's assumed that it wasn't right.
So what we'll do is we'll create the else if latter here.
So I say else if the selection is an upper case or the selection is a lowercase k then we want to worry
about adding something to the list.
Right so I've got my block statement here.
So what do I do here.
Well I need to ask the user to enter a number and then add it to my vector.
So I need a variable it let's call it nothing to add.
That's what we're going to read the number into We'll initialize it to zero.
It will say will output to the user.
Enter an integer.
To add to the list.
Something like that and what we'll do is we'll read it into number two and so now we've got the number
that we want to add.
What do we want to add it to the vector numbers.
How do you do that.
Numbers don't push back.
Right we're going to push it to the back of the vector and we're going to push no to add just like that.
And then we're going to tell the user we've added their number.
So I'll just say something the C out need to add let's say just simple added and we'll put an end line
here that looks pretty good.
We can test that out as well.
What I'll do is I'll come up here and I'll initialize that vector again to empty we'll get rid of that
test right there.
So there we go the vectors empty again we run this.
And let's add We'll press a Antron interest to add to the list.
Perfect we'll type in an integer 10.
We're reading that into Lumb to add now and pushing it to the back of the vector.
It says here 10 added.
Now if we print the numbers again with the p option we should see a list with attendant awesome.
That's exactly what we have.
Let's add a 20 and we'll print it again.
Now we've got a 10 and a 20.
Exactly what we expected.
OK.
Well Press Q to quit.
So we're working our way down these these options here.
The next one would be m to display the mean.
So let's do that again we'll see else we're that's that.
Else if.
Else ladder else if the selection is equal to a capital M character or the selection is equal to the
lowercase and character in this case I want a block statement and then here's where we're going to calculate
the mean.
Just like we did before.
In some of the other examples that we've done how do you calculate the mean.
Well we need a running total right.
We add them all up and we divide by the size of how many elements are there.
But we need to be careful of one thing.
We have to be sure that the vector is not empty right.
So we'll do this test again.
We'll say if numbers
dot size is equal to zero will simply say See out and we could do this in a block statement but I'll
just use a single statement.
Was it unable to calculate I mean no data or something like that.
And we'll finish it off with an end line.
Now we've got our L statement in a block who's in need.
We need to do more than one thing here.
So now the only time we're ever going to be in here is if there is data right.
There's stuff in the vector or integers in there.
So what do we do we need to calculate.
Adam all up.
So let's create a variable called Total and it's an integer.
And now what do we do we loop.
So we loop through that vector again and we total up all the numbers.
So let's use another range based for that.
That's perfect for the situation that say numb and the collection again is numbers.
And what do we do with each iteration.
We just say total equals total plus that number perfect.
Now we're out of that loop.
Don't indent here.
We're going here because we don't have a block statement there and now we just simply say see out the
mean.
Clean that up.
The mean is and what we can do here is we can actually do the calculation right in mine.
We could just say total divided by numbers that size which is the amount of data in that vector and
line
OK.
Now that's almost correct but it's not quite correct there's a little error here.
And if you remember what it is we've got an integer total being divided by an integer size so we're
going to do integer division here.
So this is where a good test case comes in handy.
Let's run this and let's type in let's add a one and we'll add a to it's print or list 1 and 2.
That's take to mean we expect 1.5.
We get a 1.
That's because we're doing integer division instead of double division.
So we quit here.
We need to provide a static cast here of one of these two guys that would just do this.
So we'll stay static underscore cast to a double and of total that's it.
We'll run this again.
It's or number one.
Let's add another number to print them out make sure we have the one of the two in there.
Yes we do.
Let's take the mean now we expect 1.5.
Now we've got 1.5.
OK so the two pieces left are smallest and largest and this video is getting a little long.
Someone to stop this here and I'll join you in the next video where we'll do the last few pieces.