In this video we'll go over some examples of using C-style strings.
First thing you'll notice is I'm including C string.
I need to include that header file for the C-style string functions.
And I'm also including CC type.
That's because I'm going to use some of the character based functions in this example.
Ok so I'm using namespace standard and I have declared for C-style string variables which are really
just arrays of characters on lines 9 through 12.
First name last name full name and temp and I've made them to be pretty big 20 20 50 and 50 that should
allow us to put stuff in there without exceeding the bounds.
OK so the first thing we'll do is notice here.
First name is uninitialized.
There are actually all uninitialized.
Let's display first name.
This is a real problem because we've never initialized that array.
So it's very likely we're going to get garbage.
So let's run this.
And by the way I'm in the section 10 workspace in the C style strings project.
So let me run this and there you can see the garbage right up here and see it right in there.
What display's is.
Who knows right.
Whatever characters happen to be in those locations you might get lucky and the null character might
be in the first location and which has nothing will print but more often than not you'll get garbage
like this.
And this is a real common sense.
And whether you displaying to the console or inside a window in Microsoft Windows or X window and you
see something that displays look down on a button or appear on a titlebar is something that's a classic
symptom of uninitialized string.
Let me comment that out.
And we don't want uninitialized streams.
Now obviously we'd want to initialize these guys just like that or to a string if we want.
So let me just go ahead and initialize all of them which is really the best practice
camps and other all initialize.
So the first thing we'll do is uncomment these lines here.
And this is nothing we haven't seen before.
Pretty straightforward.
Enter your first name and we're using the extraction operator to get our first name into that variable
first name which is the array.
So whatever I type in I'm going to use my name in these examples Frank will be stored into first name
and will be f r a and k and then the character will automatically be put in there for us.
Same thing with last name.
OK so again nothing we haven't seen before.
Now here let's talk about these two lines.
In this case that we grab my marker real quick in this case we're saying hello first name.
Now this will be replaced with a value of first name what's the value of first name.
At this point I have Frank in there and remember this is 20 big here.
But in this case as you say I've got them all character.
So how do we determine the value of first name.
Well we start here do we see a no no.
We move over to we see a no no.
And we keep going until we see that no at that point that's what's returned.
So this will display Frank.
That's really what's going on when we're displaying these C-style variables.
So I was going to say Hello Frank.
Your first name has and then we see this function right here.
As to our land or the string length function a function is nothing more than a request for somebody
else to do something for you.
All right.
Functions really soon I think in the next section.
So in this case I'm calling the Charland function I'm passing in that array of characters Frank.
So what's it going to do.
It's going to do the same thing.
We just did here.
Right.
Let me clean this up a little bit and we'll walk through this again.
So in this case how does the string length determine the length of that name.
Well you start here.
Is that a no no.
That's one.
Is that a no.
No that's two.
How about this guy.
No that's 3 the n.
No.
OK.
That's five.
Now we see the No.
The length is five.
That's what's being returned here.
Now as Harlin doesn't return an integer it doesn't really return an unsigned integer.
It returns a type called size t and i haven't talked about that yet but I'm going to now size he really
is an unsigned integer it could be an unsigned long.
You really don't know what it is based on your system.
That's the whole point.
We really should be using size t because regardless of what system you're on this will work.
You can be sure it will be unsigned.
Right because it doesn't make sense to have negative sizes for strings or negative sizes from the for
loop variables and things like that typically.
So from this point forward I'm going to start using size t where appropriate rather than an unsigned
it's the more correct way of doing it.
OK.
So that will return 5 so this will display.
Hello Frank.
Your first name is has five characters and your last name.
Same idea.
It'll print out my last name here and my last name has 11 characters.
So it should display 11 characters.
OK so let's run this example.
My first name is Frank and also put in my last name Metropolis and it says Hello Frank.
Your first name has five characters and your last name Mitropoulos has 11 characters exactly what we
expect.
Now everything I'm talking about in this video is totally dependent on that guy right there.
If for whatever reason those null characters are that no character is not there you can imagine how
we're going to keep counting until we hit one which weight may be you know a thousand characters down
the line in memory.
Typically you don't have to worry about it when you use these functions as Arlen's seen as to your cap.
Mike we'll see it here.
They handle that for you.
But if you're working with strings on your own and you're processing characters and movie characters
around you've got to be aware that you need to null terminate your strings otherwise you're going to
run into problems.
All right.
Let me clear this up real quick and let's do another example down here.
Uncomment this piece of code and we'll talk about that real quick.
So what do we have now.
Well we have Frank the first name right.
So first name is Frank.
I just typed it in and I'll type it in again in the next example.
What we're doing here is we're copying using the string copy function.
We're copying first name to full name.
This is the way it works it's going from this right argument to the left and not the other way around.
This is confusing sometimes for students.
So I'm copying first name into full name.
So again here was first name and it had Frank in it and over here is full name again this is first name
and this is form an how does it copy Well one character Time is going to copy the f the r the A D and
the K and it's going to keep copying until it hits that no character at that point it copies them all
character and it stops.
So at this point fullname will have Frank followed by the null character the TR cat function is the
concatenate function.
In this case what I'm doing is I'm adding space.
You can see the space right there and double quotes.
I'm adding the space to full name.
So now it's putting a space here right in there and then it's putting the null character.
So at this point that's going to be Frank followed by a space.
I'll just use that underscore to denote the space that I'm doing another string cat.
And what I'm doing now is I'm concatenating again this goes this way I'm concatenating the last name
to a full name.
So I'm putting in my last name here and it will also put in the null character DN and then I'm just
displaying.
So notice what we're doing here what we're doing is we're basically building up full name from first
name and last name using as TR cat or string cat Let's run this and what I'll do here is I'll say again
my first name is Frank and my last name is Metropolis.
Hello Frank.
Oh that's the same in that it says here your full name is Frank metropolis.
Notice how it is concatenated the frank the space in the metropolis to one.
So full name now contains that string.
Ok so let's do another example I'm going to comment all of this out so we're fresh every time.
And in this example here this is an example that shows you one of the behaviors of the sea in extraction
operator here.
What I'm doing here is I'm prompting the user me this case for my full name and I'm going to enter the
full name.
I'm going to display the full name.
OK.
So let me run that and I'm just going to say my full name is Frank Mitropoulos But now when I try to
display my full name notice I only get Frank.
That's the normal behavior for that extraction operator.
It's read again.
F R A N K space.
That's a white space so it stops.
That's it.
Sometimes you want to be able to read the entire name right.
The whole line.
So this is what we're doing these next few lines here.
In this case again I'm prompting and to your full name but now I'm using Sian's getline function.
This is.
This works again with C-style strings.
So in this case I'm providing the name of that C-style string of that array name here is full name and
a limit.
This is how many characters maximum you're going to read some saying cnt getline.
So this will stop either at 50 you've reached the max or when the user presses enter.
So in this case it's going to read the whole name right.
So let me run that again and I'll say Frank Metropolis again and press enter you can see the full name.
Now is the first name and the last name.
So it's reading the entire line.
Now let me do a couple of more examples as to a comparison example here.
In this case remember fullname will have my full name in it.
Frank Metropolis and what I'm doing that I'm copying that to temp temp if you recall or scroll up real
quick.
Temp is another array of characters.
Pretty big nice 50 size so my name will definitely fit in there.
And when I say big size my name will fit in there.
That's one of the things you always have to worry about when you're working with C-style Strange's you've
always got to be sure that you've got enough storage if you don't have enough storage going to have
a problem because you're going to run over the balance and probably clobber some other memory location
with something.
OK so again let's assume that I've typed in my name and now I'm going to copy my name to temp that I
want to compare those two.
They should be the same.
Right because I just copied it to another variable name where we can use the string compare function.
We pass in the two strings that we want to compare and this case temp and full name.
And if we get back to zero that means that they're the same if we don't get back to zero.
That means they're not the same.
So in this example I expect to get back to zero.
So let me run this real quick and I'll type in my full name.
They are the same Frank Mitropoulos and Frank Mitropoulos are the same because it's the same string.
So I did get back to zero.
OK so now let's modify that string and then we'll compare it again.
So we'll do this tumbles we'll use a for loop and uncomment this code out real quick.
And you notice what we're doing we're going from equals zero.
And notice I'm using size t here instead of into or unsigned This is the better way to do it the more
correct way to do it.
So I'm going from I zero.
While I is less than the string length of the full name against string length is going to return however
many characters are in there.
I want to be sure I'm going less than that because remember we're going from zero to the size minus
1 and I'm incrementing by 1 each time.
Then I'm using one of the character functions I'm saying full names some I.
That's the specific character right.
So it's going to be F R A and K and so forth that's an alpha character a letter.
Then I'm going to convert that letter to uppercase and put it right back where it was.
So now my name will be all capitalized.
OK.
So let's run that and I'll type in my name with mixed upper or lower case you can see here that it compared
them and they're the same.
And now my name is all uppercase because I use the two upper function.
So now let's compare those two.
Now obviously they're not the same right because I just made one a little bit different.
So let's do this let's comment.
All of this out and walk through it.
And so what's going on here I'm comparing temp and full name.
They're not the same anymore.
Right.
Full name is now all uppercase and temp is not someone to compare them and it's going to say are they
the same or are they different now.
I expect this to be different because this will not be equal to zero.
So what how does this work with the zero.
Well if the two strings are the same and that's character by character lexically the string compare
function will return to zero.
Otherwise it will return a negative number or a positive number depending on which to which of the strings
is larger.
Right.
So in this case I'm comparing them temp and fullname and then fullname attempt so you could see the
result.
So let's run this.
So again I'll use my name and press enter.
So as you can see the two strings are now different.
And destry compare function will return zero if the two strings are the same.
You can see here that we're comparing two different strings that returns less than zero if the first
string lexically comes before the second string or return greater than zero.
If the first string lexically comes after the second string.
Ok so that completes this video.
This gives you a little bit of insight as to how to use C-style strings and their functions.
What we'll do next is we'll talk about C++ strings.