Hello welcome to the section 10 challenge in this challenge what I'm asking you to do is to create a
substitution cipher program.
This is really straightforward but it will give you some experience using the C++ string class.
Now there's an easy way to do this in an easy way to do this.
I'm not going to tell you what the easy way to do this is because I want you to learn and try to figure
it out on your own.
Let me talk about the challenge.
A simple very old method of sending messages is the substitution cypher.
I remember using this as a kid with some of my friends we used to have something called a secret decoder
ring.
And the idea is you have a message and then you look at every character in that message and you replace
it with the character on the ring.
So for example every time you see a lowercase A gets replaced with a capital X or the time you see a
lower case b gets replaced with a capital Z and so forth.
So it's called the substitution cypher it's really a straightforward cipher.
It's not a very secure cipher at all but it's a fun cipher to do.
So here's the idea I want you to write a program that asks the user to enter a secret message that will
be a string and then I want you to encrypt that message using the substitution cypher and display the
encrypted message.
Then take that encrypted message and decrypt it back to the original message.
OK.
You can use two strings for your substitution.
You can have one string for the alphabet.
And let me write this here for you.
That way you maybe understand a little bit better.
So let's say you have one string which is the alphabet and this string contains all the characters that
you want to substitute.
So for example let's say we've got a B C and so forth and capital a capital B capital C..
Ok then I've got another string called the key and you can name these Anything you like.
And the idea here is that for every character up in the alphabet string you're going to have a character
in the key strain that will substitute it.
So if I want to substitute that lowercase a for an X it'll be here and let's say that the B gets Z and
C gets a Q And then this upper case a gets a lowercase let's say z a lowercase Q and A lowercase D.
Does it really matter what you replace them with.
So now the idea is really straightforward.
Whenever you see the secret message this is the secret message is a b c you look in the alphabet you'll
look for that little AA.
You find it you find it in position 0.
Then you go to the key the position 0 and whatever is there you replace it you do the same thing with
lowercase b.
It's going to be replaced with a Z and you do the same thing with the lowercase c to replace it with
a Q Obviously you just keep going down the string whatever you find to replace.
So that would be my original message.
This is now my encrypted message.
How would I decrypt the message.
Do the same thing just the other way around.
You look in the key for an x.
I find it at position zero so I go to position C Roman alphabet and I grab that little AA.
Again I look for the Z it's in position 1 there's my be in position one and then my key is going to
be in position three or sorry position to and gives me my c.
So there you go.
Really really straightforward to do make the cipher stronger if you wish.
This is a really weak cipher.
Right now it's on the substituting the letters.
And let me scroll down here just a little bit to show you when I'm giving you to start with.
You can see what I'm giving you to start with I'm giving you an alphabet which is a string of all the
lower case and upper case letters.
I kept these in order just to make it easier to debug.
And then you've got the key.
Those are the substitution.
So for every one of these letters there is an equivalent letter here that we're going to substitute.
So for example whenever we see a lowercase a in our message we're going to substitute it with a capital
X..
Whenever I see a capital Z I'm going to substitute it with a lowercase r that's for encryption and then
for decryption you just read the encrypted string and you go the other way around.
So if you see a capital x in your encrypted string you replace it with a lowercase a to decrypt it.
That's it really straightforward.
As I said I'm only using letters here.
I'm not dealing with numbers or spaces you can be as creative as you want with that.
There's a lot of ways to make this a lot stronger and just have fun doing it.
Remember I'm writing this right here on line 28.
Remember the less code you write the less code you have to test reuse existing functionality in the
libraries.
Use the code that's in the string class.
Don't try to create all this on your own.
Remember the kiss principle.
Keep this as simple as you can reuse as much as you can and that makes your program very likely a lot
more correct than it will be if you try to do everything on your own.
Remember those those library functions and methods that we've used they've been tested and they've been
debugged for years and years so they're pretty solid so reused us so that may give you a sample run
so that you can see what to expect.
So I'm going to run this and you can see here.
Enter your secret message and I'll say I'll meet you at Lili's house
at 10am.
Now Precentor.
And it says encrypting message.
And here's the encrypted message you can see it's replacing characters.
It's pretty obvious what's going on here right.
You can see the Capitol in isle is being replaced with a lowercase J.
The apostrophe is not being replaced at all because I'm only dealing with letters the L lowercase L
is being replaced with the D a capital D.
You can see here you can see it going across it.
That's your encrypted message then.
I'm taking that encrypted message and decrypting it just doing the opposite.
I just did and I got back the same message I started with.
OK so you can see it's pretty easy.
So my secret message will be this is
my secret message.
There's the encrypted message.
OK you can see the third character here is an AI which is being replaced by a capital J and you can
see the eye again right here and the is and there's the Capitol J again.
OK so have fun.
Like I said and make us stronger.
That's what I like to do learn and play around with ideas that you may have to make the stronger it's
a lot of fun to try.
OK so when you're done I'll see you over in this solution and I'll show you my solution.