In this video we'll learn about function overloading in C++.
We can have functions with different parameter lists that have the same name.
For example I may have many ways to display information to the screen depending on what I want to display.
So rather than having many functions with different names such as display char display and display double
and so forth we can have a single name display and then implement a version of the function for each
type of parameter.
Then we just let the compiler figure out which function to use based on the function call arguments
and the defined function parameters.
It sounds more complicated than it is and we'll see an example in the next slide that I'll show you
just how simple it is.
This is a great use of abstraction since as a developer.
All I need to think is display and pass in whatever information I need.
I don't have to keep track of dozens of different function names in software engineering.
We have a principle called polymorphism which means many forms for the same concept.
This is an example of polymorphism.
Let's see what overloaded functions look like.
In this example we have two functions that are both called add numbers.
The first function expects to integers and the second function expects to doubles.
I'm only showing the function prototypes in this slide but we actually have to implement both functions.
I'll do that in the next line.
Notice that in main.
I'm calling both functions but I don't have to think about different names.
I just want to add two numbers.
If I call add numbers with two integers then the int into version of the function is called If I call
add numbers with two doubles then the double double version of the function is called In this light
I'm providing the function definitions for the add numbers functions that we prototyped in the previous
slide.
It's important to understand that we must implement all of the overloaded versions.
Notice that the code for these two functions is nearly identical except for the types.
C++ has a feature called function templates that allow us to just write one generic version of the add
numbers function and it will take care of providing the correct version when called function templates
are a little bit more advanced topic and we'll discuss it when we talk about the standard template library.
Let's take a look at another example.
In this example only show the function prototypes but remember that you'd have to implement all of these.
I have five functions named display.
The parameter lists for these functions must be different so the compiler can tell them apart.
Once these functions are implemented I can call display and pass in my data.
The compiler will check the type of the argument in the function and match it to one of the available
overloaded display functions.
If it can't match it or if it can't convert the argument to one that matches then we get a compiler
error.
There is one restriction to function overloading the return type is not considered when the compiler
is trying to determine which function to call.
So here we have two overloaded functions both called Get value and both expect no parameters.
The only difference is that one returns an integer and the other a double.
This will produce a compiler error since the only difference is the return type.
Consider the output statement at the bottom of the slide.
Which function would the compiler call it could call either and that's the problem.
It won't guess so to produce a compiler error overloading functions is used extensively in Object-Oriented
Design and we'll see it again when we design our own C++ Object-Oriented classes.
I mean the code like ID in the section 11 workspace and M&amp;A function overloading project here it just
want to go through some examples of overloading of function.
Remember overloading a function simply means using the same name for various forms of that same function.
In this case it's print and what I want to do is don't want to overload print to work with different
types so you can see some of the function prototypes here.
In this case I've got an inch version of print so if I pass in an integer to print it will use this
version of the function one that expects a double one that expects a C++ string object one that expects
to see plus String objects and the last one expects a vector of string objects.
OK remember we have to implement each one of these and that's what I'm doing here.
I'm just saying printing and printing double so that we know which one is being called.
So in the case of print it is simply says printing integer and it displays the number for double it's
doing the same thing string and so forth.
OK and then for the vector version it's just iterating through the vector and pretty up all the strings
in the vector.
So let's see how this works.
In this first case I'm simply calling print in a passing in 100 not 100 as an integer.
So I expect that this integer version of print is the one that's going to be called and it'll say printing
it.
OK so let's give that a try.
Printing it 100 exactly what we expected.
In this version I'm passing in a character now.
Characters are always promoted to integers.
So in this case it's going to call the same function that expects an integer but it's not going to print
out the character.
It's going to print out 65 which is the ASCII code for a member it's using integers here.
So let's run that.
And there you see it says printing integer and it's Partita 65.
In this case I'll come in both of these out in this case we're going to use the doubled version which
is this version right up here print expecting a double and is just going to say printing double and
display the number that was passed in.
So in the first example I'm passing in 120 3.5.
No problem.
One twenty three point five is a double so they should match perfectly.
However in the second example that f right there makes this a fluke not a double.
So in this case I'm passing a float to the function but there is no overloaded function that expects
a float.
So what the compiler does is it will promote the float to a double it'll match that function and call
it.
So both these statements will use that same function.
Let's run that.
And you can see here one twenty three point five.
And in this case one twenty three point three.
OK so what about C-style strings.
Let me uncomment that out.
Remember we've got a version of print right here that expects a string object and it simply prints out
that string object.
However I'm not passing in a string object here and passing in a C-style string an array of characters
that does not match that function prototype.
But the C++ compiler knows how to convert a C-style string write an array of characters to a C++ string
object.
So we'll use that conversion and it'll pass in the literal.
Make it an object and then we're going to display the object.
So if we run it you'll see you'll see a printing string C style string.
Ok exactly what we expect.
Once you understand how the conversions work it all makes a lot of sense in this next example.
I'm declaring right here s to be a string object.
This is not a C A C style string.
This is a C++ style string object and I'm passing it into print that's going to match exactly and print
out C++ string.
All right in misprints statement here we're passing in a C-style string and a string object both.
Now we've got a version of a print function that expects to string objects.
Well no problem right.
We'll convert the first argument to a string object and then pass the second one as well.
So in this case when I run it you'll see that that same printing to strings method is called with a
C-style string and a C++ string.
Ok pretty cool.
And then the last one is this vector here I'm creating a vector called Three Stooges which is a vector
of string objects and we've got Larry Moe and Curly in there and I'm calling the print function in passing
and three stooges.
So it's going to match this one right here that expects a vector of strings.
And I'm just going to iterate through there and print out the three stooges names of the three strings
in that particular vector.
OK so I'll run it and there you go.
Pretty vector of strings there.
Moe and Curly.
So you could see how nice it is to be able to overload functions the nice part about it isn't so much
all the code that I've written that's that's not that great.
The nice part about it is once the code is written I can just think print.
So if I'm solving an application I'm printing Print Print Print and printing everywhere I'm not doing.
You know I don't have to do print int and print string and so forth I'm just thinking in print which
is what abstraction is all about.
Now there's some couple of things you need to worry about when you're overloading functions.
Be careful when you overload functions and you use default arguments.
Ok I'll show you why.
Here's an example of the print with the integer version.
I could certainly default this to 100 let's say.
So if I don't supply the argument to the print function it's going to default to 100.
And let's test that out we'll do it right up here.
OK so at this point now we should get 100 here and then 100 on the next line as well right.
So let's run that and you can see there's the hundred.
That's the default argument right there that makes sense.
But what about if we didn't do that and we did it down here in the print double.
Let's say that we wanted default.
This went to 125 point five.
Now when I call print here it will default to one twenty five point five because it's up here right
there that's when it's going to match rank.
So there's the 125 point five in the double version it's called again.
Makes sense where you run into trouble is when you do both see you do something like that.
Now you really are in trouble because the compiler can't figure out which one to use.
Again look at the print call right here.
It says print but it doesn't supply any type information.
So now the compiler can choose either one because they both match and it's not going to choose either
and he may give you a compiler error.
And when I write it say something about an ambiguous call right here error or call of overloaded print
is ambiguous.
So whenever you use overloaded functions with default arguments you've got to be a little careful.
So get rid of that and I'll set those back up to the way they were.
OK so that covers overloaded functions we're going to see overloaded functions a lot when we talk about
object orientation and when we create our own classes we want to have different ways to initialize our
classes.
You saw that with the Vector class in the String class all the different ways that we can create those
objects.
Well that's all based on overloading functions.