OK so now that we understand the basics of C++ pointers Let's talk about what are the main use cases
for pointers that is dynamic memory allocation.
When we're developing software we often have no idea how much storage we're going to need to model our
data.
For example if I'm modeling the students in my class how many students do I allocate storage for if
I'm using an array to model the students then I need to know exactly how many students I have since
when to allocate an array it's fixed in size.
I know what you're thinking hey didn't you tell us earlier that we should be using vectors instead of
arrays.
Yes I did.
And that's still true.
However it's important to understand how to allocate memory dynamically not just for a race but for
other data including objects.
Also how do you think vectors work behind the scenes.
They use techniques to allocate and deallocate memory from the heap.
So we really need to understand how that works in this video.
Go for the basics of allocating memory dynamically from the heap all memory that's allocated dynamically
via a pointer comes from the heap or the Freestore.
As I said we'll use dynamic memory allocation again later in this course in the context of object oriented
objects.
So how do you allocate storage at runtime.
Let's see we use the new keyword to allocate storage at runtime.
In this example we declare int pointer as a pointer to an integer rather than assigning the address
of some integer variable as we've done previously why don't we create an integer at runtime that's on
the heap and store that variables addressed in pointer.
That's pretty cool.
You can see how easy it is in pointer equals new int.
That's it that's all it takes.
This allocates storage for an integer on the heap and stores its address into pointer.
Now we can use the pointer to access the integer the first output statement displays the value of int
pointer.
This is the address of the newly created integer.
If we want to get to that integer we need to dereference the pointer.
But notice what gets displayed.
A really large integer value.
That's because the integer that was allocated hasn't been initialized yet and it contains garbage data.
So in order to assign a value to that integer on the heap we dereference the pointer to get to the integer
and then store 100 in and in this case.
Now when we display the value of the integer we get back 100.
That's pretty cool.
A couple of things to understand.
When you allocate storage in this manner the storage is on the heap the allocated storage contains garbage
data until you initialize it the allocated storage does not have a name.
The only way to get to that storage is via the pointer.
If you lose the pointer because it goes out of scope or you reassign it then you lost your only way
to get to that storage and you have a memory leak.
I'll talk more about that later.
Finally when you're done using the storage then you must deallocate the storage so that it's again available
to the rest of the program.
Let's see how Here you see that we again have declared it pointer is a pointer to an int.
Then we assign new int to it pointer.
This statement allocates storage for an integer on the heap and stores the address of that image or
in int pointer just like before we can use the pointer as we wish.
And then when we're done we need to release or deallocate the storage that we allocated for that integer.
We can do that easily using the delete key word followed by the name of the pointer.
Make sure that the address in the pointer is an address of stories that was allocated using new we just
saw an example of allocating a single integer dynamically.
You can do the same with double strings vectors and so forth.
But in this I will do something a little more useful than allocating a single integer.
How about we allocate an entire array of integers on the heap at runtime in the sample code.
We declare a pointer to an integer called array pointer and an integer named size.
We asked the user how big they want the array to be.
This could be the number of scores on an exam or the number of temperatures to read and so forth.
Then we use the new operator with square brackets this time and the number of elements to allocate inside
the brackets.
This will attempt to allocate that many integers on the heap contiguously in memory.
If the storage is successfully created then the address of the first integer is stored in array pointer.
That's pretty easy.
Of course when we're done with the memory we need to release Sidor deallocate it.
Let's see the syntax for that.
Here's the same code example but the last statement deletes the entire array that we allocated dynamically.
Notice the square brackets between the lead and the name of the pointer.
These brackets must be empty do not include anything inside the brackets.
OK let's go to the idea and create some storage dynamically OK so I mean the ID I'm in the section 12
workspace in the dynamic memory project.
What I want to do in this little example is allocate a single element on the heap.
In this case will do an integer and point to it from a pointer.
OK.
We're going to use the new keyword to do that.
And then after that we'll allocate storage for an array like we did with the slides.
All right so let's do this first.
We need a pointer to a pointer to an integer and you know what before we do that.
Let's talk about exactly what's going on here.
If you remember when we talked about our memory model earlier we've got our memory model here where
we've got our code is down here that we had our global variables and then we had our stack right here
in our stack is where the function calls happened and this is push pops we're pushing and popping activation
records on here just like before.
Well we also have a part of memory called the heap.
It's also called the Freestore all dynamic allocation happens here.
We can't really do dynamic allocation on the stack.
It's already doing dynamic allocation.
When we push and pop activation records but we can't really decide at runtime how big those things are
going to be.
We can't to a point but not really the heap is a free for all.
We've got a whole bunch of memory out there and we can request that we you know we get a thousand integers
2000 integers you know 15 objects as much as we want but we need to take care of that heap and we need
to release the storage when we're done.
So that's the kind of thing we'll do here.
Now what I want to do is I want to create an integer pointer that's going to be in main.
So it's going to be on the stack and I want to allocate an integer on the heap so I want to allocate
an integer dynamically on the heap and I want to point to it from that point to OK that's what I want
to do first then what I want to do is I want to allocate an array of doubles let's say in this case
on the heap again.
And how big is it going to be.
I don't know I'm going to ask the user how many doubles they need and then what we'll have is we'll
have a pointer to doubles in this case.
That's going to point to their OK.
So that's what we're going to do.
Let's start here.
Let's do the integer First we need a pointer to it.
So we're going to have an integer and we'll initialize it to load pointer.
That's our best practice.
So what we've done is we've got a variable member it's a variable called pointer that points to an integer
so it's going to hold addresses of integers.
Right now it's pointing nowhere.
If we want to allocate this dynamically at run time from the heap we just say it.
Pointer equals new.
And then followed by the type that I want to allocate in this case ant.
Now what's going to happen is that storage for an integer is going to be allocated on the heap and its
address will be stored in the pointer.
So we can just use something like display in pointer and that will display the memory location where
that integer is on the heap.
Remember that's the address that stored in pointer.
So let's run that.
And you can see that Hex address right there that's where that integer lives on the heap and our pointer
is not pointing to it.
It's important to understand that that integer that we just created on the heap has no name.
There is no way to get to it except through this point.
So if I lose the pointer I've got something called a memory leak which I'll talk a little bit about
later.
So at this point we can use this integer however we like and when we're done we need to delete it.
So the syntax for that is simply the keyword delete followed by the name of the pointer which in this
case is into pointer.
That frees up the storage OK.
So pretty easy.
Now what we'll do is clean up a little bit this white space here.
Now what we'll do is we'll create a whole contiguous block of memory on the heap can and will do doubles
this time.
So there's two things here we don't know the size so we have to ask the user how many doubles do you
need.
And we also need a pointer to that area.
So we declare both of those right now.
The size will declare it as a size type and we'll just call it size will initialize it to 0 and the
pointer will be a pointer to doubles and the name of the pointer.
Let's just say 10 pointer.
So it'll be temperatures and again will initialize it to No.
So we're good to go here.
So let's ask the user.
So will I see user will see how many taps and how many temperatures do they need.
And we'll read that into size.
So now we know how many temperatures to allocate.
So if they typed in 50 100 200 10000 whatever they typed in that's how much storage we're going to allocate.
So what do we do.
We use the pointer we're going to say 10 pointer equals new.
What am I allocating.
Well Medicaid doubles in this case.
And how many size.
This is where you put the size in the square brackets.
That's going to allocate that chunk of memory happens to be an array in this case because it's contiguous
doubles in memory and store the address of the first one into 10 pointer so at this point we can say
seek out.
Let's just say 10 pointer see what's in there.
Obviously it's an address of that first double right.
And let's run that real quick.
See what we get.
So how many attempts will say 100 temperatures and you can see right there that's the area in the heap
that contains the address of the first of those 100 doubles.
Pretty easy know when we're done what do we do we always need to free up the space that we've allocated
so we can say delete in this case we allocated an array right there.
You've got the square brackets in the new call so here you get put the square brackets in the delete
nothing inside the square brackets.
And then the name of the pointer which was temperature pointer that's it.
That's the entire program.
And you could see what's happening at this point right.
What we did was we had an I'm not going to draw the whole stack again but we had that 10 pointer right
here that was on the stack.
We allocated 100 doubles on the heat 10 pointers pointing to the first one OK.
That's really what's happening.
This is on the heap and in this case 10 pointer was on the stack because it's local to main right here
notice what happens if we lose this point or I mean if we do something really silly like I don't know
10 pointer
because no pointer right and we do that before we did this which just happened where we just no doubt
this pointer.
So this is gone.
We just lost our only way to get to that storage.
And that's called the memory leak.
What did the delete call does is it frees up this storage again your pointer is still pointing to it
and that's important because if you try to use that pointer again after you've deleted the storage you
could have really really unpredictable results.
But in this case you don't want to lose your pointer to the dynamically allocated memory because then
it's basically orphaned out there and that's the memory leak.
OK now let's see what happens if our call fails our call to allocate the size here.
Now I'll do something that you should never do when I'm going to create an endless loop here.
I'm just going to say while true allocate that so this is going to not.
How many temperatures you want to allocate.
I want to type something by 10000.
And then what I'll do is I'll just keep looping allocating and creating memory leaks all over the place.
Eventually we're going to run out of memory in the heap.
So eventually this will fail and I should get an exception.
So let's see what that looks like.
How many times let's say a lot.
I remember it's going to be in an infinite loop doing this over and over and over.
And there you go.
That was pretty fast.
You can see terminate called after throwing an instance of standard bad Alik.
So basically what happened was the call to new fail.
There was no more memory available.
And this is the exception that's thrown well talk about exception handling a little bit later in the
class.
But what you want to do is you want to catch that exception you don't want your program to just stop
like that when it catch the exception.
And if you can deal with it somehow maybe you've got you know memory and caches and temporary stuff
that you can free up to free up some memory and then you can allocate this memory again trying to con
you again.
So this is again I'm going to delete that.
That's not a good idea.
But that's basically it in the next video we'll talk about the relationship between arrays which is
really what's going on here and a pointer and you can see that really almost the same thing here in
this case and how we can actually use that array.
That's on the heap from our code.
So I'll be right back.