So at this point you may be wondering how we can allocate an entire array of integers and store address
into a pointer to an image.
That's a good question and it's critical that you understand the relationship between arrays and pointers
and C++.
Remember that the value of an array name is the location or the address of the first element of the
array and the value of a pointer is an address.
So if a pointer points to the same type of data as the array elements then the pointer in the array
name are the same as far as C++ is concerned.
The only difference is that the array name is not a variable so you can't change it.
But otherwise all the calculations done to access array elements can be done with the array name or
the pointer name.
In this example we have scores as an array of three integers.
If you display scores then the value of the array name is the address of the first element of the array.
What if I dereference scores.
Wait a minute score's is an array.
How can I dereference that sure score's is the address of the first array element.
So if I go to that address which is what dereferencing is I get the integer.
So the output statement for dereferencing score's displays 100 the first array element.
Now if I declare a score pointer is a pointer to an integer and I initialize it discourse.
Notice that the value of score pointer is the same as scores.
So when I dereference score pointer we get the same results.
The value of the element at that location which is 100 in this case I know this can be a bit confusing.
And when we head over to the idea I'll try it out visually so you can see exactly what's happening.
So if we can pretty much use an array name and appointer name interchangeably that means we should be
able to use arrays subscripting on a pointer right.
And that's absolutely correct if score pointer points to the first element of the score's array as it
does in this example.
Then when we display score pointer Sub-Zero we get 100 score points or so of one is ninety five score
points or Step two is 89.
That's weird right.
Well not really if you understand the C++ doesn't really have two arrays and that arrays are just the
address of the first element in a chunk of memory.
Then this makes sense.
So does that mean that we can add the offset to the pointer variable then we can make a point to any
array element.
And again yes it does.
Let me show you how we're using the same example here.
Notice that we display score pointer.
We get back in address if we add one to score pointer then you can see that the value of score pointer
has increased by four not by 1.
Why.
Because we're not adding one to the pointer value we're adding the size of one integer to the pointer
value the pointer doesn't hold integers and holds addresses of integers.
So when we add one we're adding the address of the next integer which is 4 bytes away.
If we add two we increment score pointer by 8 which is two integers away.
This is the basis of pointer arithmetic which we'll talk about in the next video.
Once we have scored pointer pointed to the image that we want we can simply dereference the pointer
to get to the integer.
Let me show you how that works.
Here's the same example except that I'm dereferencing the expression.
Notice that how we follow the pointer and display the integer that we point to in this case we're moving
along the array using the pointer.
That's pretty cool.
Let's see this altogether so it makes more sense.
This table shows the equivalence between arrays and pointers.
Notice that we can access array elements using array subscript or pointers subscript notation using
either the name of the array or the name of the pointer.
You can also see we can use array offset or pointer offset notation.
Also using the array name where the pointer name.
Take your time with this and that can be confusing but when it clicks you'll be able to easily understand
more advanced memory allocation principles.
Let's head over to the idea.
What over some of the examples in his video.
OK so I'm in the IDM in the section 12 workspace in the arrays and pointers project.
I've gone ahead and written some code that uses array subscript notation pointers subscript notation
pointer offset notation and array offset notation just so that we can walk through this he can really
understand the equivalence of pointers and arrays and C++.
So let's get started here.
First of all I've created a score scores array of integers right here and I initialize it to 195 in
89 and that's it over here in this little box over here so this is 100.
This is 95 and this is 89 and it scores.
And let's assume that this is at location 1000.
So what that means is that this integer 100 is at location 1000.
This integer 95 is that location 1004 assuming that we've got 4 byte integers which I do on my machine
and this 89 is at location 1 0 0 0 0 8 in memory.
OK we know they contiguous because it's an array perfect so when we display scores here the name of
an array is the address of the first element in the array.
So in this case it's a thousand.
So we expect this to print a thousand Obviously when I run this on my machine I'm going to get a different
value but that's OK.
Now I've created another variable right here called Score pointer.
So don't put this guy I'm going to put him right here score pointer and score pointer we're assigning
to score points or scores scores is the array name which is the address of the first element in the
array.
So score pointer was have 1000 in it right now.
And there's my pointer.
There's no need to put the ampersand here and percent score since the score the name of the array already
is an address.
So now we print out the value of score points while it's a thousand.
So these two values will print the same because they are the same the name of the array and we just
store the name of the array which is the address in two score points.
So now let's do array subscript notation.
This is what we've been doing all along scores is an array so scores Sub-Zero.
Now look look at what the compiler is doing here.
The computer saying scores Sub-Zero is really 1000 right.
That's what scores is plus 1 0 integers away.
So that's going to be a thousand.
So it's going to grab whatever is that location of 0 0 0 0 0 and display it which is in this case 100
What about score someone.
So in the case of score someone it's going to have scores again which is a thousand and it's going to
go one away from that and it's not going to be a thousand One it's going to be one integer away from
it because it knows it's horse is an array of integers.
So in this case it's going to be a thousand four so it's going to go to 1000 for it sees the 95 and
displays that then the same thing with score Sabtu would display the 89 K that's using a raise subscript
notation.
Now take a look at pointer's subscript notation is exactly the same.
The only difference is that I replaced scores with score pointer right.
Therefore we've got pointer and subscript.
So again score pointer Sub-Zero what is score pointer a thousand.
In this case right it's right here plus 0 away.
So it's going to go to location 1000 and grab what's there which is going to be 100 the one we use subscript
notation we're basically grabbing what's at that address.
Same thing with score points.
So one it's going to go to 1000 plus one integer away which is a thousand four.
And there's the 95.
And here's the 89 OK.
So hopefully that makes sense.
Now here we've got pointer offset notation.
We don't have any square brackets so we're using the offset.
Now let's start right here.
What happens if I dereference score pointer follow the pointer to where it's pointing score points is
a thousand I'm going to dereference it which means I'm going to go to that location here.
And what do I do.
I display 100.
Now what about this line right here let's go with that one carefully.
When it's say score pointer plus 1.
Now notice the parentheses and then dereference.
So what happens first.
What's in the parentheses.
What's score pointer 1 0 0 0 0.
And it hasn't changed.
Plus 1 What.
Plus one whatever score pointer is pointing to integer in this case.
So 1004 I'm dereferencing 1004 which means I'm going to 1004 for getting what's there.
That's the 95.
Same thing here I'm going to 1000 eight and getting what's there which is the 89 so there's pointer
offset.
And then the last one is a re offset.
Notice here I'm using scores.
Well what does an array name.
Well an array name is the address of the first element in the array.
Right.
So the reference scores is the same as saying scores of 0 here.
So in this case score's is a thousand Sigma to 1000 and grab what's there.
Display 100.
Here we've got scores plus one dereferenced right what scores the name of the array is the value of
the address of that first element right there a thousand plus for right them dereferencing that again.
You can see it's exactly like what we did with pointer offset.
So we've got 95 and 89.
So the output from this program is going to be exactly the same array subscript pointer subscript pointer
offset an array offset their equivalent as far as C++ is concerned.
Now why is this important.
This is important too because when we allocate arrays dynamically on the heap we can we have to be able
to walk them right use them display them change them do whatever we like with them.
Well we have a pointer to them and that's what we got back when we used that storage that pointer to
that array.
It's going to be a pointer so we could use pointer subscript notation if we want.
We could use pointer offset notation if we want.
Right.
Either one we can use and we'll be able to get to that array and the array elements really really easily.
All right so let me run this and we'll be sure that we get the correct values and you can see here this
is the important piece the value of scores is that Hex address right there and the value of score pointer
is the same hex address.
Makes sense right because we assign scores to score appointer and scores is the address of that first
element in that array 100.
Then we go through array subscript notation we print out one hundred ninety five eighty nine you can
see pointer subscript pointer offset an array offset it's all exactly the same thing.
Take your time understand this walk through it.
Play around with it you know change a few things if you like.
It's really important once you understand the equivalence of arrays and pointers in C++ it really opens
up the world of power.