Now that we know about references and how to use them let's look at L values and our values L values
and our values are something you don't worry about too much when you're first learning C++ but as you
learn more advanced features of the language they become very important.
It's important that the fundamentals make sense now so that when we move on to topics like C++ elevons
R-value references and move semantics there'll be much clearer.
So in this video we do a basic introduction to L values our values and l value references.
So let's start with an l value an l value is an object that occupies a location in memory and is addressable.
So in these examples X and name are L values.
They have names and they are addressable.
We know that there are addressable since we can use them on the left hand side of an assignment statement.
So what's not a null value in these examples 100 is not an l value because it's not addressable.
It's a literal.
In fact the compiler generates a compiler error for the one hundred equals x statement saying that 100
is not an assignable value.
Similarly in the assignment statement 1000 plus 20 equals x 1000 plus 20 produces a temporary variable
with the value 1020 but that variable is not addressable so we can't use it as an l value in the last
assignment statement.
Frank equals name.
Moe Frank is not an l value since it's not addressable.
So these examples are of non L values.
They're in fact called our values.
Let's talk a bit about our values.
We can define our values by exclusion.
So anything that's not an l value is in our value.
Usually our values are on the right hand side of an assignment expression.
Our values can also be temporary values that the C++ compiler creates.
We saw some examples of our values in the previous slide and see a few more here in the first statement.
One hundred is an R-value in the second statement X plus 200 will produce a temporary variable and that
variable is an r value since it's not addressable the string literal Frank is also an r value.
And Max 20:30 is an r value because it returns a result that's a temporary and not addressable.
Our values can be assigned to L values explicitly.
So L values can appear both on the left and right sides of an assignment statement.
In this example we see the first assignment statement is using the R-value 100 on the right hand side
of the assignment statement.
And this will be assigned to the l value Y in the second example the temporary R value with the sum
X plus Y will be assigned to the l value x.
Now let's look at references from the perspective of L values and our values.
The references we've used so far have all been l value references.
That means that we're referring to L values in the first reference declaration we're declaring ref 1
as a reference to x.
Notice that X is an l value.
This makes sense since we are an alias for X and we can use ref 1 to the left hand side of an assignment
statement since it refers to an l value.
But what happens when we declare ref to is a reference to 100.
Well 100 is an r value.
So this isn't allowed and the compiler will generate an error.
The same applies when we pass parameters by reference to functions.
In this case we define a function square that expects an integer by reference.
We have an integer initialized to 10 and then we call square and pass in.
This is fine because N is a reference to an l value and knowm is an l value.
However if we pass in the literal five to the function we get a compiler error because 5 is not an l
value it's an r value and we must reference L values.
Don't worry if this is a bit confusing now as we learn more about C++ semantics it will make more sense
but it's important going forward.
When we talk about move semantics.