In this video we'll learn about using access modifiers to determine what will be hidden in the class
and what parts of the program have access to this information.
C++ has three basic class member access modifiers.
These are public private and protected class members that are public or accessible everywhere private
class members are only accessible by other members of the same class or by friends of the class.
We'll talk about friends later in this section.
Finally protected members are used with inheritance which we'll talk about later in the course.
Using the class member access modifiers is super simple in the body of the class you specify the access
modifier followed by a colon then everything you declare from that point forward will have that access
modifier applied to it.
In this example we're using the public access modifier and anything we declare.
After this will be public until we see a different access modifier.
In this example we're using the private modifier by default.
Everything in a class will be private if no access modifier specified protected works exactly the same
way as private.
For now you can think of protected in private as being pretty much the same.
The different comes in when we use inheritance.
Of course we commonly use public private and protected all at the same time to tell the compiler what
class members should not be available outside the class and what class members should be part of the
public interface of the class.
This is how C++ implements information hiding.
In this example the player's name health and XP are all private.
This means that they're only accessible from the other members of this class.
And from friends of the class that talk and is dead methods are publicly accessible.
So what happens if we try to access a private class member.
Simple you get a compiler error.
Here's some examples.
First we create a player object named Frank.
If we try to access the player object's name instance variable then we get a compiler error because
name is private and it's not accessible from outside the class.
The same is true for health.
Why would we want to make some class members private and others public.
The idea is that you want to control access to certain data and methods by making them private.
For example you want to prevent users from directly setting Franke's health to a thousand as in this
example.
Maybe the maximum health for the player is 100.
In order to control this you would create a public method in the class that sets this health property
and in the code for that method it makes sure to max out the Health at 100.
Since that method is a class member it would have access to the private health property in the second
example we create a pointer named enemy to a player object.
If we try to directly access the XP property we get a compiler because it's private.
However we can call the talk method with no error since it's public.
Let's see another example in this example we have an account class and the name of the account and the
balance of the account are private.
These properties cannot be accessed directly from outside the class.
We also provide public withdraw and deposit methods that can be called from outside the class.
Since these methods are member methods they have access to the balance and can update its value based
on whatever business logic we have for the class.
Here are a few examples that use the account object frank account is an account object.
If we try to access the object's Balance property directly will get a compiler error because balance
is private.
However we can use the deposit method and provide the amount to deposit it since deposit is public.
The idea is that the deposit method would somehow verify that the $10 million and I want a deposit are
indeed available before incrementing balance.
If I try to directly access the name of the account I also get a compiler error for the same reason
the account name is private the same behavior applies whether we access an object using the dot operator
or via a pointer using the operator in the case of Mary's account trying to access the balance or name
directly results in a compiler error.
But using the deposit method is fine since it's public.
You can see how powerful this is.
For example if we have an object whose balance is 20 million dollars and we know that that must have
been an error then the only place where that error could have happened in this example is in the deposit
method.
There's no way that any other part of the program could have changed that value since the value is private.
This makes testing and debugging code much much easier.
Ok so I'm in the IDM in the section 13 workspace in the access modifiers project and in this project
we've got our player class that we've been using.
And you'll notice some in a couple of changes to it.
I made the attributes all private.
So the name the health and the expwy are all private.
And I made the two methods talked in is dead.
Public.
OK.
So I want to show you the compiler errors you get when you try to access those private data members.
So in this case I want to create a player object a frank and if I try to set Frank's name so I could
say Frank name equals anything.
In this case I'll just say Frank.
And we'll try to compile a build and run with control of five.
You see the error I'm getting.
And you can see it here in the box as well as his players name as private within this context.
Same thing we're seeing here.
So you're trying to access a private attribute which is name from outside of the class.
This is exactly the same area you'll get if you try to use health or XP and it's not just a matter of
trying to set that variable it's trying to use that variable as well.
So if I tried to do something like seek out Frank health you know do it in line here and we'll compile
this as well.
We'll see.
I get two errors now.
Same idea.
I don't have access to health.
It's not just a matter of not allowing you to set it.
It's not allowing you to access it.
OK.
Now these I'm going to comment those two out for a moment and let's initialize the name here just to
play or just so we have something to see when we call the talk method.
OK so now what I can do is I can say Frank got talk and I can pass in the string Hello there.
Now if I try to build and run I says player says hello there.
OK.
So we know it works in this case because we're accessing a public accessible method right here talk.
Same thing with his dad we can't call his dad because we haven't implemented it yet but we did implement
talk right here.
OK.
So that's really all there is to it.
If you get these errors that are saying you don't have access to something that's exactly why now why
do we do this.
It's really good programming practice to hide certain parts of your classes declarations.
The idea is you want to control that variable via some sort of public method.
So they've got to go through the public method and then the public method makes sure that the health
is within some reasonable range.
And as I mentioned in the slides if we're doing this and we put some value of health that's 20000 or
something like that that's really really out of whack.
If health is public then anything could have changed that property.
But if health is private then I know that the changes that were wrong happened somewhere in here right
somewhere in the public interface.
My methods made that mistake and I can find and fix that error much much easier.