In this video we'll learn a little bit more about the Konst qualifier in the context of class methods.
We've already learned that we can create Konst variables which can't be changed.
And we've also seen how we can pass references and pointers into functions as Konst and they can be
modified while in the function well and this video will learn how to create Konst objects and see what
happens when we pass constant objects to methods that don't expect to Konst using Konst correctly in
parameters as well as method declarations is the basis for Konst correctness in a program.
In this example we're creating a concept object named villain.
Now once villain is created we can't change any of attachable.
So that's the whole idea with it being Konst.
So what happens if we call member methods on a Konst object.
Let's look at calling a setter method that changes the object.
Obviously this can't be allowed since the object is declared as contest.
And in fact this produces a compiler error.
The compiler complains that you're passing a concert object as this to a method that could change it.
But what about the output statement.
In this case I'm not modifying the Konst object.
I'm simply getting a copy of its name for display.
While this won't compile either.
In fact you get the same error that you get when you called Set name.
So what's up.
Well the compiler assumes that the get named function could potentially change the object so it gives
an error but we need a solution to this problem since we would like to call the getter methods and other
methods that are public that don't modify the object.
Here's another example.
Again we define the villain object and its a constant so it can't change.
Now we have a display player named function that expects a reference to a contest object.
Again we get a compiler error here the problem is that when we call P-doc get name in the displayed
player name function this pointer isn't expecting a cost object.
So get name could potentially change the object.
The compiler is being very careful not to allow a concert object to lose its constants.
So what's the solution.
The solution is actually very simple.
We need to tell the compiler that specific methods will not modify the object and all we have to do
is put the Konst modifier before the semi-colon and the method prototype.
That's it.
Now the compiler will not only allow this method to be called on const objects.
It will also produce a compiler error if you try to modify any of the object attributes in the method
the idea of class methods having conc qualifiers is part of what's referred to as Konst correctness
Konst correct this can get pretty complicated.
But this video serves to give you a basic idea of what it is and how important it is.
Now you can see that the call to get name works just fine.
But the call to set name is still not allowed to set name is not a Konst function remember since you're
telling the compiler that get name is a Konst member function.
Then if you write code in the body of get name that modifies the object you'll get a compiler that's
conc correctness in action.
Let's go to the idea and see this example in code.
Ok so I'm in the IDM in the section 13 workspace in the concert in classes project and this is basically
the player class again you can see we've got our private attributes some public methods and so forth.
And this is the real method that we're interested in in this example right here.
It's a simple getter that returns the name.
So you could see get name is the name of the method it returns name which is a string.
Simple as that.
That's the one we're going to have to fix so that we achieve Conn's correctness with this program.
So let me go down to and you can see I've got constructor copy constructor all the normal stuff.
I'm going to come at this function because we're going to use that one in a minute but this is what
I've got so far.
I've created a villain object that is a player type and it's constant.
I've also created a hero which is a player type Pierro is not constant.
So what does this mean.
This means that I cannot change any of villain's attributes.
So here's a real simple way to tell that this actually works.
If I take that Expwy attribute that's private and just make it public for a minute and then I come down
here again and I'm just going to say something really simple like villain.
XP is a thousand.
It should let me do that right because XP is public but it won't because villaine is constant so if
I try to compile this i'll an right here is this assignment of member player XP in a read only object.
Makes a lot of sense.
That's actually a really good compiler error.
It's telling you that that object villain is read only you can't change any of it right.
That's what that construct does.
So let me undo what I just did here and I'll make XP private again.
OK.
So let's do a couple of things.
Now let's come down again to our main here and I'll remove that line right here.
So we're back to where we started we've got the villain and we've got the hero now.
Obviously I should never be allowed to change villain.
Right so doing something like villain does set name to no super villain.
That should never be allowed because if you look at the set named Melville right up here it is actually
changing that name attribute.
So if you try to compile this you would expect an error and you do get an error and the error message
is saying passing Consta player and that's what this is right here villaine as this argument discards
qualifier.
So what it's telling you is that you're passing this in as a constant.
But the class is not expecting a constant and it's going to be able to change it.
Now you'd get the same error if you called the get named function.
So let's try that on villaine.
You may not.
This one may not seem so obvious as to why but let's say we did something like that.
Just put that in an output statement.
So we'll say something to see out area or something like that.
I'll come at this one out because we know that once that one should never work right ever not even once
we're Konst correct that that should never be allowed.
But now we're here.
So I'm saying villaine give me your name.
That should work.
You really think about it right because it's not changing the object it's simply returning that string
and display it but it won't work.
It's going to give you an error and the error is again same error passing Konst player as this argument
discards qualifier.
So what's going on.
Well that get name method could change the object right.
There's no reason I couldn't write some code in the get method right here that change one of those attributes
and the compiler can't guarantee that at this point so it's going to throw the error.
The fix will come up in a little bit but now what if I did something like this when if I did the same
output statement.
But I did it with hero instead of villain.
Let's compile that.
How are you going to get a clean run right.
That makes sense because hero is not Konst so the compiler doesn't really care if you change hero in
that method or not.
OK so what would make all these concert correct them a little bit.
So there you can see some of the issues here.
Now suppose that I'm going to comment all this out and then I'll uncommented it a little bit.
But now suppose we have this function right here and this is not a member function it's just a regular
function it's called display player name and it expects P which is a reference to a concert player object.
Right.
And all we're doing is getting up that player objects name or displaying it.
So let's call that method.
So we'll call display player name it will pass in villaine And what would expect it is to print up villaine
right.
So let's compile that we get an error Error passing Konst player this argument discards qualifiers like
the problems right here right there.
And OK you know we can sort of understand that air.
But now let's try this with Hero
and we'll just replace Villiam with hero here and I'll comment this line out.
So we're definitely sure what's causing any errors if we get any.
So look what's happening here.
Hero is not a construct.
Someone to pass hero into Display player as a contest that means this function can't change it.
Right.
That's the problem.
When I call up get name as far as P-doc get name is concerned that's a contest.
It can't change it.
Right.
But there's no way to guarantee that.
So this is going to give me the same error as before.
There's the air again.
So what's the fix.
Well the fix is pretty simple the fix is we come up here to our class and we come to that method get
name and we want to tell the compiler Hey compiler I guarantee and you double check for me that this
method get name is not modifying the object at all.
You do that with the conc qualifier right there you put a cons right after the parameter list.
If you've just got a prototype you just put it like right before the prototype right in there before
the semicolon.
That's it.
Now you've just told the compiler I guarantee that I'm not changing that object in this method.
So now the compiler is happy and all of this stuff will work now.
Right.
Let's uncomment all these out and uncomment this guy out as well because that should work as well.
And that's it.
So now we run this we should get a clean run villain hero villain hero just what we expect.
Obviously this will never work.
That should never work because it's we don't want to set anything and Villette which that should never
be allowed.
So I'll just leave that comment out.
And then the other thing that's important I understand is once you define a method here as Konst you
can't mess around with those attributes in here I can't say XP equals 100 right because now it's you're
just violating what you just said you were going to do is no longer Kotz So if I compile and when you
get an error right there on that line.
Right.
You're changing something in a read only object.
So this is conc correctness it can get pretty complicated when you're passing things all over the place
as Konst to non-contest here and so forth.
But the rule of thumb is all your getters should be Cotts basically any method that you have in your
class that doesn't modify the object should be Konst.
OK so that's it for the Konst correctness.