In this section of the Course will learn about overloading operators in C++.
C++ allows the programmer to overload most operators to work with user defined classes.
This is intended to make code more readable and ridable by allowing the use of familiar operators in
a familiar manner.
But with our own classes and objects First we'll look at exactly what operator overloading is and some
of the basic rules that C++ enforces.
We'll start with the assignment operator the assignment operator is a very important operator and C++.
It defines the semantics of what happens when you assign one object to another.
C++ provides a default way of doing object assignment much as it did with the copy constructor that
we learned about in the last section.
However many times we want to be in control of what happens during an object assignment and we can overload
the assignment operator to do exactly that.
For example when we use raw pointers in our classes we must provide our own version of the assignment
operator.
Additionally we can override the assignment operator to handle both copy and move semantics as we did
with the copy and move constructors in the last section.
We'll learn how to do that in this section.
We'll also see how we can overload other operators as both member functions and as global functions
in a way we want to choose one over the other.
We'll finish up this section by overloading the stream insertion and extraction operators so that we
can easily use our objects with C++ streams just like we've been doing with the built in types.
So let's get started with operator overloading.