In this video will overload the movie assignment operator for my string class.
Remember the copy assignment operator that we just overloaded in the previous video works with l value
references.
The move operator that will overloading this video works with our value references.
Again think temporary unnamed objects.
You don't have to provide a move assignment operator and if you don't C++ we'll use the copy constructor
by default.
But as we said when we talked about the move constructor move semantics can be much more efficient.
And it's not a lot of extra work to provide a move constructor and a move assignment operator.
First let's see when the move assignment operator will be used in the code snippet in this slide you
can see that we create a string object as one that's basically just an empty string.
Now we assigned to my string object with the string Frank to it.
Notice that to my string object initialized to Frank must be constructed and once it's constructed it
has no name.
It's a temporary object.
So it's an r value that means that when we assign it to S1 the move assignment operator will be called.
Since we're providing an r value reference let's see how to do this syntactically Lolitas the move assignment
operator declaration is very similar to copy assignment but there are a few differences.
First we use the double ampersand operator in the parameter list to tell the compiler that the right
side object is an r value.
So the right side value will be a r value reference.
Second the right hand side object reference can't be Konst Since will be modifying that object when
we move the data.
So the declaration for the my string class returns a string object by reference and expects an r value
reference to a String object.
You can see that in the two assignment statements on this slide the move assignment operator will be
called because the right hand side of the assignment statements are our values.
So let's look at the code for the move assignment operator for this example as you would expect the
code is very similar to the copy assignment.
With the exception that we're not deep copying from the right hand side object.
Instead we're simply stealing the pointer and the nulling out the right hand side pointer.
Again you can see from this code how much more efficient This is compared to copy assignment.
Let's walk through this one step at a time.
First we check for self assignment just before and if we're self assigning then we returned the left
hand side object and we're done.
Since there was nothing to do otherwise we again deallocate the storage pointed to by the left side
object.
Since we'll be overwriting this and we don't want a memory leak.
Now the left hand side object is ready.
So let's move the pointer over.
First we steal the pointer from the right side object and assign it to the left side object.
This is simply a copy of a pointer variable.
We're not doing a deep copy here.
Then we know that the pointer on the right side object this step is critical.
Finally we returned the left side object.
Now let's head over to the ID and compare the assignment operator to the copy assignment operator in
life code.
Ok so I'm back in the ID I'm in the section 14 workspace in the my dash move dash assignment project.
Now what I'd like to do in this project is add a move assignment operator to are my string class.
This can be really useful when we're assigning R-value references.
So let me give you an example of how this would work.
Here we've created an object A and it's using an overloaded constructor that's expecting that character
pointer and we're just constructing a simple object.
A That's got that string attribute pointing to hello on the heap.
Now at this point we want to use a sign that remember already exists.
Now this would be assignment not initialization.
And what I want to do is construct another my midstream object off of the initialization string.
At this point that temporary object has no name.
So it's an R-value.
If we don't provide any move semantics then it's going to use a copy constructor or a copy assignment
operator to do what it needs to do.
And if I run this right now remember I don't have any move constructors.
Sorry I don't have any move assignment operator implemented.
So if I run this at this point you'll see that it's using copy assignment using copy assignment.
Now we really could use move assignment here since we got this R-value references and that's what we'll
do.
So let's go over conceptually what's going on here again at this point we've created that object and
it's on the stack.
It's got as TR attribute which is a pointer.
And once this object has been constructed that pointers point it to the string hello which is on the
heap.
And again remember it's got that null terminator at the end.
So this is the situation once we instantiate a.
Now what we want to do is we want to assign to a the object that we created right here.
So let's create that object that object creates created exactly the same way as we created run it using
the overloaded constructor.
But it doesn't have a name.
It's an unnamed temporary object.
So I'm just going to leave it right over here like this without a name.
It's got an AS TR attribute and it's pointing to Ola which is on the heap.
So that's the situation like right now.
Now what we want to do is we want to assign this guy over to this guy but we really don't want to do
the overhead of copying because we don't need to this temporary object will be destroyed soon.
So let's just use move assignment so that we can steal that pointer and not have to make any copies
of anything or copy anything over.
OK.
So let's do that.
How does this work.
What are the semantics.
Well the first thing we need to do is deallocate the space here.
Right.
We need to call the lead for this guy because we're not going to use that.
That's the whole point I want to assign to it.
So we're going to get rid of that.
And what that's going to do it's going to leave us in this situation.
Where we're no longer pointing to that area and then what we want to do is we want to steal the pointer.
So I want to make this point here point to all the and then once that's done what I want to do is not
delete this I don't want to delete this information here right.
I don't want to deallocate that because I'm using it now over here.
All I want to do is just KNOW out that pointer.
So that's what I'll do.
I'll just know this pointer out.
So this guy is now.
No.
You'll notice a is now with a stream attribute and is not pointing to the correct string in the heap
which is what I want.
This guy has been called out so when it gets destroyed by the destructor it won't delete anything out
there on the heap because it's not pointing to anything on the heap.
So once this gets destroyed we're right back to here which is exactly where we want to be.
And the same is true with the statement right here is your will create a temporary object.
There is the s t r and it's going to be pointing to your
right now when we assign over we'll do the same thing.
We want to deallocate that storage right here.
So we want to get rid of this.
We want to move the pointer right.
We just want to seal this pointer let it point over here and then what we want to do is set this point
to right here to no right so we just move the data and simply by just pointing to it from a different
place.
This will be destroyed.
And that's the effect that we want.
Okay perfect.
So now let's write some code for this and you'll see it's actually a little bit simpler even than the
copy assignment.
First things first.
Let's go to the header file and you'll notice that I've already implemented a move constructor.
I just wanted to be complete there so the move constructor has been implemented and it's about as dead
simple as you can get.
I mean what the move constructor looks like.
It's right here.
Remember this is a constructor.
Now this is not an assignment so this is actually creating a new object based on an r value reference.
So you can see right here on line 35.
I'm stealing the pointer right.
I'm taking the source object's pointer and moving it right twist here and then I'm nullifying the source
subject point.
So that's it.
We just store the pointer that other object will eventually be destroyed.
Let's write the assignment operator.
So let's go back to our header file and we'll do it right here and we'll do something like my string
reference because it's the same idea here.
We're overloading operator equal.
We don't want to be Konst here because we do need to modify that right hand sides.
String attribute to knock it out.
So it's simply going to be my string to ampersands here because we wanted our value reference right
hand side.
That's it.
And we'll call this guy move the sun.
All right.
So now let's go implement that methods will go to my string BPP file and right underneath the copy assignment
right here.
I'll just put it right here on the move assignment and you can see I've already set some breakpoints
just to save a little time.
So let's implement this here.
So what do we do.
We're going to return to my string reference and it's part of the my string class we're overloading
operator equal.
And we're expecting my string r value reference.
OK that's it.
So first thing we do is as usual let's just put a string out Ansted at c out and we'll just say something
like using move assignment.
That way we know that we're actually in here and we'll put an end line here.
Perfect.
Now let's check for self assignment.
I'll scroll up just a little bit here.
We'll check for self assignment.
So we're going to say if the current object right the address of this object is equal to the address
of the right hand side object if that's the case I've got self assignment.
So all I want to do is just return this in the case that we're not doing self assignment.
Remember the conceptual drawing I just drew.
So what do we want to do.
We want to delete see you from the current object we want to steal the pointer.
So we want to assign the right hand sides pointer to the left hand side pointer and we want to nullify
the right side pointer.
This was really really important if you forget to do this step then there's going to be problems because
what's going to happen is when that temporary object gets destroyed it's going to take this data with
it.
So you want to be sure that this is pointing to nowhere.
So right hand side string equals null pointer that's it.
We return this.
Now we'll step through this in a second but let's run it first.
And now you can see the difference in the run using move assignment using assignment.
That's exactly what we want.
And then we've got two destructors being called for no pointers.
Right.
Which is again exactly what we want.
All right so let me put a breakpoint here.
And let's walk through this using the debugger some and go back to my main here and I'll start the debugger
over here.
All right.
So this is where we're at right now we're about to call the overloaded constructor to create the A That's
pretty standard stuff.
Now here we are we don't have a null pointer so we're simply going to allocate space for the string
and copy it over and we're done.
So now a is hello you can see the address of that string attribute right here.
Now what we need to do here is first construct that temporary object and then call the overloaded assignment
operator right with an r value reference.
That's exactly what this is this is an unnamed object.
So let's walk through this.
So first we're going to create the object using the overloaded constructor right here.
So we'll walk through that.
Allocate the space.
Copy it over.
It's done.
Now notice that the move assignment operator gets called right away.
That's exactly what you expect because we have an r value reference here which is a temporary unnamed
object.
So we display using move assignment.
We check for self assignment which we don't have.
We delete this as TR.
Right.
Remember this is this object right here.
So we're going to delete that and deallocate it we're going to steal the pointer and then we're going
to nullify that other point too.
Now the temporary OBD-II is being destructed right here.
And we do have a null pointer now because we know that you can see it zero right there.
So this will print out calling destructor for a null pointer will delete the area and that's it.
Now if we refresh or see that a now is all.
So we did exactly what we said we were going to do here it's the same idea first we're going to construct
a temporary object based on that string.
So let's do that.
Here we are we're in the overloaded constructor and that's going to create a temporary object with Bonjour
in it.
Then we call the move assignment again because we have an r value reference.
And what we're going to do here is we're just going to steal that Bullen's your pointer first.
We delete what we're pointing to right.
So all eyes gone then we steal the bones your pointer.
We set that temporary objects pointer to NULL.
We return the object and then we're going to destroy that temporary object again the one that we just
stole the pointer from We'll delete it.
We're back and you can see now that A is on your will unwind now and it will destroy a.
There you go.
And you can see over here that we've got to move assignments three destructors to destroy and just null
pointers temp objects and then the final one destroying the actual object that we created.
That's it.
So you can see it's pretty straightforward and we'll see that in the main driver here.
I've got a lot more code and if you recall that code running from before.
So I'll run this code again in the main Now that I've commented it.
And if we remember when we ran it before it was use the copy constructor and copy assignment.
Well in this case when we run it we're going to see a lot more moves semantics going on so I scroll
up here and you can see that we've got move assignment move assignment move assignments move assignments
move constructors.
So this version is much much more efficient.
And if you again walk through it check out the statements use the debugger if you like and really understand
what's going on.
But it's very very straightforward.
In the case of our values we really want those move assignments and move constructors just to make our
code so much more efficient.