Hello everyone welcome back.
In this video we'll go over the challenge solution to this is the solution for the overloaded operators
using nonmember functions.
So I mean the section 14 workspace and the challenge Dasch solution to project.
And you can see my header file now from the private modifier down it's exactly the same thing that's
changed is that I've declared prototypes for my overloaded operator functions and they are all friend
functions.
Now we don't have to do that.
We can certainly not have front functions and work through getters and setters and so forth but but
for the purposes of this video I'm making everything of friends who have got access to everything that's
private in this class which is really just that string pointer right here.
Now as you can see when we have something like operator minus in this case we're overloading the Yairi
operator.
There is exactly one item in the parameter list and when we have something that's binary We've got two
parameters and parameter list.
So it's a little bit different from using member methods and that's about it.
Now what we do is we basically have to implement these functions and you'll see it's very very straightforward.
Same idea as with the member method.
So let's go to the implementation file here and we'll start with the equality operator.
Now we don't have remembered in all of these cases we no longer have a this pointer.
There's no object dot operator method because there are non member functions so we don't have that this
pointer but we do have another object.
And in this case we have left hand side and right hand side and all we want to do is compare the left
hand side string with the right hand side string and you can see that we're doing that right here in
this string compare function.
We're comparing the left hand side straight to the right hand side straight.
And if we get back to zero do the same and that's what we're returning.
So we're turning to fault's here same exact idea does not equal operator is exactly the same thing except
negating the result right here with the bang for the less than and greater then overloaded operators
you can see that the code is almost exactly like it was in the member method version except that I don't
have this on the left side I've got an L.A. chess or a left hand side object.
OK so let's take a look at make lower case in this case.
In this case this is a urinary function so I've just got one argument right here.
And what I'm doing is something I did before I create an area in memory to copy that string into what
I'm going to do is make it lowercase.
And that's what I'm going to do here I've allocated enough space for that object string's length plus
one.
Then I copy that object string character my character into buff and then I simply loop through buff
and make each character is lowercase equivalent.
When I'm done with that I construct the object that I'm going to return right here in a constructor
based on buff.
Return it.
And don't forget to delete the buffer as we always do so we don't leak memory.
The concatenation operator same idea I've got the left hand side and the right hand side.
So obviously you're going to have left hand side plus right hand side.
So we need to allocate another character buffer here.
That's the length of both those strings added together plus one.
So you can see here we have left hand string.
Here we have Right-Hand string we copy the left hand string over and then we concatenate the right hand
string onto that.
We create the new object here based on that new string that's concatenated now.
And we return it.
And of course we delete the buffer as well.
That's it really straight forward.
Now they get really really simple to implement because we've got to R plus equal right or concatenate
in a sign where we can implement that based on our concatenation because Plus equal simply means left
hand side equals left hand side plus right hand side.
So we can express that directly which leads to very very readable code here.
The repeat operator or the star operator overloading.
Same idea I remember repeating something just means adding it over and over so will take advantage that
we've already overloaded that concatenation operator right here and 9:44 we're using it right there.
So given and we're just simply going a loop that many times and say temp equals 10 plus left hand side
do it again and again and again and we're just basically tacking on that string to itself over and over
and over when we're done we return temp our star equal operator or repeat and assign operator works
the same in this case it's a binary operator it expects an object and then the star and then an integer
is how many times you're going to repeat it.
So we'll do the same thing or take advantage of the fact that we've already overloaded the repeat operator
or the store operator in this case will simply say left hand side equals the left hand side star and
that we'll call this.
It will take care of it and then we return left hand side so we can keep assigning and the last to the
left or the pre-increment and post-increment operators which just make the strings uppercase.
So the semantics for the increment are simply just increment that string is really straightforward.
The stream belongs to RBJ right.
This is a unitary operator will only have one object here in RBJ has an s tr pointer that points to
a character or a rank on the heap.
So what we're doing is just looping through that character array one item at a time one character at
a time and we're setting the item of that object string to the uppercase equivalent of it.
And then we just simply return the object when we're done.
So you can see we're actually modifying RBJ here which is exactly what you would expect with a pre-increment.
So the post-increment is very similar.
We need to keep a copy of the original object so we're doing that right here.
We're creating a copy temp based on an object which is the one that's being incremented then I'm doing
a pre-increment of object which takes care of making all the characters uppercase and then returning
the old object.
So you can see that this line right here actually modifies the current object and this line right here
returns a copy of the original object which is exactly what the semantics are of post-increment.
I wrote a comment here as I mentioned before make sure you call pre-increment and not post-increment
if you call post-increment this method here will be called over and over recursively and you'll never
be able to break out of it.
So that's it.
If we run this we should have exactly the same output as we had before.
Let's try it.
A string to repeat and we'll do the same string I enter before dash three zeros and a dash and I believe
I said five.
Last time I'll do that again.
And there we go.
We've got our 5 000 strain's we've got 60 of these now and the rest of the code is exactly the same
as it was.
All right.
So congratulations I hope you did well on this challenge.
You can say now that you're no longer C++ beginner programmers that's for sure.
Yeah you've learned a lot about the way C++ works behind the scenes operator overloading the constructors.
The move assignments the regular copy assignments.
So you've learned a lot.
The next step is to learn about inheritance and polymorphic functions and that's where we're going to
go.
And I should mention one last thing is when you look at these test cases that I created these aren't
really test cases they're just little pieces of code that exercise some of those methods that we wrote
and functions that we wrote.
When you do testing you really want to do proper testing using unit testing using some frameworks such
as a unit test plus plus or something like that.
So keep that in mind.
We're doing this just to keep it simple and not have to learn other frameworks in order to learn this
framework.
So I'll see you in the inheritance section.