In this section we'll learn about one of the most useful features of object oriented programming languages
inheritance conceptually inheritance is easy to understand.
However inheritance in C++ can be very complex.
We'll keep it simple in this section so that the basics of inheritance and C++ are clear and you can
have the foundation to study more advanced concepts in more advanced courses.
First we'll look at what inheritance is and why it's so useful.
Think re-usability and then we'll discuss some of the terminology and notations used when talking about
inheritance.
Aggregation is also a re-usability mechanism and we'll see the difference between inheritance and aggregation.
Since many times we can use aggregation instead of inheritance to achieve what we want and avoid unnecessary
complexity.
Then we'll get into the syntax of inheritance in C++ or learn how to derive one class from an existing
class and discuss the three types of inheritance provided by C++.
You may recall when we talked about the public and private class access modifiers in Section 13 I mentioned
that there was a third type of access modifier named protected.
Well protected is used in the context of inheritance and we will see how it can be useful in that context
in this section.
Then we'll look at constructors and destructors and see how they work when we've got inheritance hierarchies
with inheritance.
We can create new classes that modify the behavior of their parent classes so we'll see how that works
and how it can be useful.
Finally we'll talk about what class hierarchies are and we'll do a short introduction to multiple inheritance.
Once we understand the basics of inheritance in this section the next section will really open up the
power of C++.
When we talk about polymorphism when it's used with inheritance and polymorphic methods.
So let's head to the next video and see what inheritance is all about.