In this video we'll look at how we can use both inheritance and composition to reuse existing code and
our projects.
We've already seen what public inheritance is and how it can help us create class hierarchies that provide
general and specialized functionality.
Public inheritance creates an is a relationship between the derived and base classes and with inheritance
we automatically inherit all of our base classes attributes and operations and we can see examples like
an employee is a person a checking account is an account.
A circle is a shape.
However sometimes we want to reuse existing classes but the relationship really doesn't apply.
For example suppose that all persons have an account.
I can't really say that a person is an account or an account is a person.
Since that doesn't make sense.
Instead we can use composition to model this relationship.
Composition creates a has a relationship between classes.
For example a person has an account.
A player has a special attack.
A circle has a location.
You get the idea using a combination of inheritance and composition.
We can express complex relationships between classes and leverage code reuse.
But see an example in this example we have the person hierarchy we saw earlier.
Note the inheritance relationships are modeled with the triangle pointing to the base class of the relationship.
As we mentioned in the last slide it wouldn't make sense to introduce another inheritance relationship
between person and account since it is a relationship just doesn't apply.
So we use composition instead.
Notice the association between person and account.
It's modeled as a solid line.
No inheritance triangled this time.
UML provides several different types of notations to model associated classes that don't have an inheritance
relationship.
These are aggregation Association and composition.
You can learn more about these in an object oriented design course but will use the term composition
to simply mean a has a relationship and we won't be concerned about whether the account object can logically
exist without being associated with the person object.
So what we're describing here is that a person has an account.
That's exactly what we want.
So does a student also have an account.
Yes because a student is a person.
What about a faculty member.
Yes because a faculty member is a person.
Notice that we create the association at the most general class in the hierarchy where it applies.
Since it will also apply to its derived classes we've actually been using composition all along when
we model class data members we're using composition.
Many times the instance variables are primitive types so we don't include them in class diagrams.
But the concept is the same.
So when do you choose inheritance over composition.
Many times it's easy to decide if the is a relationship doesn't make sense.
Then don't use public inheritance.
Other times it's not so clear a rule of thumb when using inheritance is to step back look at your design
and be sure that the inheritance is appropriate.
If you can model the relationship with composition then you should consider doing that first since inheritance
adds more complexity to your design.
In this case an inheritance relationship between student and account simply doesn't make sense.
So we use composition
Here's how the class person might be declared using composition.
Notice that it's pretty much what we've been doing so far in this course.
Composition is a common design pattern for reuse and you'll see it used much more frequently than inheritance
but we can use both inheritance and composition together to create powerful frameworks that allow us
to reuse existing code.
Ok so in the next video we'll see what the syntax of inheritance looks like in C++.