Hello everyone.
Welcome to the section 15 challenge.
That's the inheritance challenge.
This is a very challenging challenge.
You're no longer beginning C++ programmers.
That's for sure.
This challenge involves extending a class hierarchy by adding a few more classes and I'll talk about
them in just a second.
And it also involves understanding someone else's code which is you know something that happens in real
life or actually more often than not you're modifying someone else's code.
We don't write our own code from scratch very often out there.
So this is part of the challenge before you attempt this challenge.
Watch the video previous to this video where I go over the classes that are in this project I go over
the account class and the savings account classes in detail.
If you haven't done that I encourage you to do so now and then come back and give the challenge a shot.
So let me go over the challenge and tell you what's involved.
First of all I'm in the section 15 workspace in the challenge project.
This is your starting point.
This has an account class and a savings account class that's derived from the account class.
Everything's working.
The tests are there the utility functions there and so forth.
So you're provided with these two classes as I mentioned here your provider of the Account class and
the savings account class.
The Savings Account class is an account so we're using Puplick inheritance.
So in this case we have an account that has a name and a balance and then the savings account is an
account and it adds an interest rate.
And as I mentioned watch the previous video and you'll get a good understanding of exactly how the deposit
method works and the withdraw methods work and so forth.
Also I created some account helper functions in the utile header and CBP files that make it easier to
display deposit to them withdraw funds from a vector of accounts and savings accounts.
And that's what I'm using in the main driver just to make it a little easier.
Otherwise your main gets really really convoluted and you're always checking for was this a successful
deposit or was this a successful withdrawal.
And the code just gets really nasty to follow.
So what's this challenge about.
Let me just scroll up just a little bit.
And so this challenges we're going to add two classes to this hierarchy.
The first class you see right here it's a checking account class and we want to add that to the inheritance
hierarchy.
So we want this to be a derived class of either account or savings account.
You decide a checking account has a name and a balance and it has a fee of a dollar 50 per withdrawal
transaction.
So every time we do a withdrawal we're going to assess a dollar fifty flat fee the trust account is
the other account.
I want you to add to the hierarchy.
And again you decide whether it belongs under account or under savings or under checking account.
And for that matter is the checking account under a trust account.
So you figure out what the hierarchy is it's pretty straightforward.
I think once you sit down and think about it.
So a trust account has a name a balance and an interest rate but the trust account deposit works just
like the savings account deposit.
Except when we've got deposits that are five thousand dollars or more we'll get a $50 bonus by the bank
the trust account withdrawal is also different.
It only allows three withdrawals per year and each of these must be less than 20 percent of the account
balance.
You don't have to keep track of calendar time.
As I mentioned here.
So just make it fail on the fourth attempt to withdraw.
Sorry a change that should be withdrawn.
Fixed that in the spec.
So the fourth withdrawal will fail.
So what are some hints.
Well reuse existing functionality.
That's the whole idea behind inheritance right.
It's all about reusability.
So don't reinvent the wheel don't duplicate code reuse as much as you can.
Think about what the base class will be for each of these new classes that we're going to add.
Also I've created those helper functions in the account Udal file.
You may want to add the trustee account and checking current versions to them.
I would recommend that you do that.
That just makes it much easier to use these things in the main but you don't have to.
You can just test these in the main it's up to you as always have fun.
You're no longer beginner C++ programmers that's for sure.
Once we delve into the world of inheritance this is no longer beginning C++ is more intermediate C++
So congratulations that you made it this far in the course and the last thing is if you want more practice
with operator overloading you can overload the plus equal in the minus equals so that they do deposit
and withdrawal which can be handy.
OK so that's it.
I'll be back in the next video with my solution but give this a shot.
And as I said Don't get frustrated with this.
This is not an easy challenge.
There's a lot going on here.
And just take it one step at a time do one class at a time implement one method at a time test as you
go.
And before you know it you've got a great solution.
All right.
So good luck and I'll see you on the next video.