In this video we'll learn about the virtual keyword virtual functions and how to declare them in your
own class hierarchies.
When we derive a class from a base class we can redefine the base classes functions behaviors in the
derived class.
This creates a specialized version of the function specific to the derived class.
If we don't use the virtual keyword with these functions then they're statically bound at compile time.
As we've already seen overridden functions are bound dynamically.
We do this by declaring the function to be virtual.
So virtual functions are overridden functions and they allow us to think abstractly by treating all
objects in the hierarchy as objects of the base class.
Let's see the syntax for declaring a function as virtual.
First we declare the function we want to override in our derived classes as virtual in the base class.
You can see in the code snippet that were in the account base class and we declared the withdraw method
as virtual by preceding the function's prototype with the virtual keyword.
This makes withdraw a virtual function which means it can be overridden in derived classes and it will
be bound dynamically at runtime when we use a base class pointer or reference.
Once we declare a function is virtual then that function is virtual all the way down the class hierarchy.
From this point forward here we can see an example of overriding the withdraw function in the derived
class checking the derived withdraw function will be implicitly virtual.
So we don't have to use the virtual keyword again but it's best practice to do so.
It's important to understand that in order to override a base class is function the function's signature
and return type must match exactly.
If you don't match it exactly the compiler will treat it as a redefinition and statically bind it.
That's it.
It's pretty simple and provides so much power.
Remember virtual functions are dynamically bound only when we call them via a base class pointer or
reference.
Otherwise they're statically bound.
So let's head over to the idea.
Make that simple account class hierarchy dynamically polymorphic with virtual functions.
It's so easy to do.
OK so I mean the IDM in Section 16 workspace and I in the virtual functions project.
All right.
So here we've got the simple account hierarchy you can see we've got an account class a checking account
a savings account and a trust account and there are all accounts and right now we've all we've only
got the withdraw method and it's been redefined in every single class and all we're doing is just displaying
an account withdraw and checking withdraw.
You've seen this one before.
This just tells you which one is being called so that we can better follow it.
So there are my four classes and right now it's you can see there's no virtual keywords in here at all.
So this is not going to use dynamic binding.
Here are pointers again.
P one P2P 3P for each one pointing to a different each one pointing to a different type of account.
And we're just simply calling the withdrawal method for each one and then we're cleaning up our pointers.
Now since we don't have dynamic polymorphism when we run this we expect all four of these methods to
be bound to the account class is withdraw.
So let's run that and be sure that that's our starting point.
And that's exactly what we see here.
Those are the withdrawal methods executing right here where executing a count withdraw for all four
of them because we're using static binding.
All right so now let's make this polymorphic.
What do we do.
So we go to a base class and we look at the functions that we want our derived classes to be able to
override.
And those are the ones that we want to make virtual.
There's only one example here.
But typically you would have several in a base class.
In this case this is the one withdraw.
So all you need to do is put virtual in front.
That's it.
That's a virtual function now.
Whenever I come at any derived object via a base class pointer or a base class reference it will be
dynamically bound.
That's as simple as that is pretty powerful.
Now I don't have to put the virtual keyword down here but it's best practice to do so because many times
users will be looking at this function.
At this class here and it's nice for them to see that it is indeed virtual.
So let's do this virtual here.
Just copy that will do it here and we'll do it one more time right here.
So now every one of these classes has overridden that withdrawal method.
All right that's it.
That's all we really have to do.
If we run this now we'll get our polymorphic behavior which is exactly what we want.
See that in account withdraw and savings withdraw and checking withdraw interest withdraw.
This is awesome.
I mean one simple keyword you get a lot of bang for your buck here.
There's a lot going on.
Now you'll notice a few things.
We're getting some warnings here and we're getting four warnings and they're all about destructors whenever
you have a virtual function you need to have virtual destructors.
And that's what we're going to talk about in the next video so you can see how simple this was to do
and the power that it gives you in the next video will address these warnings and we'll talk about virtual
destructors.