In this video we'll learn about the C++ 11 override specifier.
We know that we can override base class virtual functions in our derived classes.
We also know that we must provide the exact function signature in the derived class including the return
type.
But what if we don't.
What if we inadvertently make a small change to the function signature by mistake.
If this happens then the function we intended to override doesn't get overridden at all.
Instead it gets redefined and we know that redefined functions are statically bound not dynamically
bound.
This type of error is really hard to find some times since the function's signatures may look very very
similar and it may not be easy to spot the difference.
C++ 11 addresses this issue by providing the override specifier.
You can add the specifier to the method you're writing in your derived class and the C++ compiler will
ensure that you're indeed overriding and not redefining.
This is a simple addition to the language but a very useful one.
Let's see what it looks like in code.
Here we have two simple classes in a class hierarchy.
The base class has a virtual function named say hello.
It returns nothing expects nothing and is a Konst function in the derived class.
I wanted to override dysfunction but when I wrote the function prototype I forgot the concept at the
end of the prototype.
Since the function signatures are not exactly the same the C++ compiler considers this function redefinition
and not overriding it will compile just fine since this is perfectly legal.
Let's see the difference between the methods.
Here it might be easier to see that the function signatures are indeed different.
So the say hello function of the derived class will be statically bound not dynamically bound as we
expected.
This will cause unexpected behavior when we use a base class pointer.
Here we have two pointers to a base class object P1 and P2 p one is pointing to a base object and P2
is pointing to a derived object.
When I call say hello via one this will be bound dynamically and it will call Bass's say hello.
However when I call say hello via pointer to.
I expected to display hello on a derived class object because I expected dynamic binding but I messed
up when I created the function by not matching the signature Exactly so the function call is statically
bound to base.
Say hello.
We can easily prevent this error by using the C++ 11 override specifier
notice the say hello function of the derived class we can place the override specifier after the function
prototype.
This tells the compiler that you intend to override this function and it should make sure that you do
so in this case the compiler will produce an error and you can add that Konst to fix the problem.
Let's head over to the idea.
See this example in life code.
I mean the idea I'm in the Section 16 workspace in the using override project.
You can see here that I've got a simple base class and all it has inside is a virtual function right
here called Say hello.
And notice that this is a Konst function and all it says is Hello I'm a base class object.
Now I've got a derived class here that's derived publicly from the base class.
And what I meant to do here was to override this say hello function right here but I messed up and I
forgot that Cotts right there.
So should have had a Konst there but it doesn't.
So now as far as the compiler is concerned this function right here my derived class is redefining the
base class function not overriding it.
So it's going to statically bind it rather than dynamically bind it.
OK so let's take a look at the main and we'll walk through this.
You can see exactly what's going to happen.
OK so here's P1 and P One is a pointer to a base object and instantiating a base object and point a
right to it.
So now when I call say hello via that P1 pointer.
Obviously this is going to do dynamic binding and it's going to bind it to my base class and that's
what I'm pointing to.
So this will call base say hello.
In this example this is a little different than what we've seen here have.
P2 is a pointer to a derived object and instantiating a Derived object.
So in this case what's going to happen is this is not a base class pointer.
This is just a regular old pointer to an object.
So in this case it's going to be statically bound.
And we're going to call derived say hello.
This is the problematic one right here.
P 3 The problem here is since we did not override Instead we redefined.
This will not be bound dynamically to be bound statically.
So as far as the compiler is concerned I've got a base pointer right here.
So it's going to bind it to base say hello but I really wanted it to bind to derive say hello.
Right so let's run this.
And then what we'll do is we'll fix this with the override keyword.
So let me run this.
And here's our output.
And you could see our main enemy scroll up just a little bit right here.
She could see here P1 points to a base and it's looking at a base so high a base class object.
In the case of P2 we're statically binding because we were pointing to a derived object and that's exactly
what we have.
So to say hello I'm a derived class object.
Here's the problematic one on 09:30 P3 is pointing to a base object and it's currently pointing to the
derived right.
Here is where the problem is because I redefined that function was going to be statically bound rather
than dynamically bound.
So it's called base say hello and you could see right there.
Hi I'm a base class opti.
That's not what I wanted.
I wanted it to say hello I'm a derived class object because I wanted to use dynamic polymorphism.
So how do we fix this.
Well the fix is easy or we just come up here and put Konst in there but we can also use the override
keyword in C++ 11 which is really handy.
You really should do this every time that you're going to override a function or a derived class.
Simply put the override word in there.
Right.
You can put the override specifier right at the end of the function prototype.
So now when you compile let me just build this real quick.
Now you get an error and the error says virtual void derive say hello marked as override but it does
not override that gives you a really good clue as to that you're not overriding anything here.
So you can come in here and say OK I got it.
There's my Konst you can put your concert in there now and then when you run.
You can see that now let me scroll up just a little bit.
Now you can see that third statement this says hello I'm a derived class object.
That's what we want.
So now we've got our polymorphic behavior so real handy really easy to do.
Use it all the time and it'll save you a lot of grief with debugging.