Welcome to the Section 16 challenge this challenge is all about polymorphism.
I'm in the Section 16 workspace and there's going to be a couple of projects here.
First we've got the challenge project this is the base source code that I'm providing for you.
Then we'll break this habit to a few parts and several different videos so that we can take this step
by step.
So right now we're in the challenged project and I in the description text file which describes this
challenge.
So what's the idea.
I think you know what you're going to have to do right.
You've got the solution that we had for last sections challenge where we have the account class and
it's all working great.
Well now we need to modify that so that it's polymorphic so that we're using dynamic polymorphism so
we can use base class pointers and get this all working using dynamic polymorphism.
That's going to be pretty cool but it's going to be some work.
So let's see where we're at.
We've got a source code that I provided and your challenge is as follows.
Remember the source code right now has no virtual functions in it.
Therefore it's all being bound statically.
That's what we want to change.
So here's the challenge part one of the challenges.
Modify the account class so that it's now abstract.
How do you do that.
Pure virtual functions.
We want two of them and they're right here giving them to you right there.
Deposit withdrawal will now be pure virtual functions.
Remember we can implement these into account class if it makes sense in this class it does make sense.
So you may want to consider implementing a simple deposit in a simple withdrawal in the account class.
Even if you implement these in the account class the account class will still be abstract because it's
got those pure virtual functions and that's going to take some work because you've got to revamp your
class hierarchies you've got to think about what you're doing.
Remember once you put virtual functions in there like we are here don't forget about the virtual destructor.
So there's a lot of little things that you'll have to do along the way.
Great.
Now to create the printable class interface similar to what we did in the class.
The idea is that all accounts are going to be printable.
So I've given you the class right here.
I haven't implemented this guy.
You guys can do that.
And obviously the account class can be derived from a principle so now it's principle and all those
concrete account objects can implement that guy right there and they should be printable which is pretty
cool.
One little hint here you'll notice this destructor right here.
Obviously we need virtual destructors we can use equal default tells the compiler to generate a simple
destructor for me.
So this is really same as you writing that kind of code but you don't have to do it at all just say
equal default let the compiler do it for you then the last part of the challenge is to modify the functions
in that account that Udal file that I gave you.
Remember that one had to display deposit and withdraw for an account and it had displaying a positive
withdraw for a checking account and it just had a lot of code in there.
What we want is we just want one version of each.
So we want one display function one deposit function one withdraw function that will work with any kind
of account.
And you'll notice what's going on here.
There's our base class player and that's why this is going to work.
So in this case when we create these vectors in our main We're going to create a vector of base class
pointers and that's what we're going to pass into these these functions here.
Finally test your code both with base class pointers as well as local objects.
I've given you a main driver that gets you started but I'd suggest that you just take it one step at
a time.
It's really the best way to do it.
What I would suggest that you do for the very first thing is take that account class and make it abstract.
Add those virtual functions to it and start from there and then work your way down the class hierarchy
and see what you have to override what you don't have to override and so forth.
That's it.
Have fun.
This is a very very challenging exercise.
There's a lot going on here.
So again take it one step at a time.
Don't think that you'll be able to do this in 15 minutes.
This will take some time and some thought because there's a lot going on a lot of little pieces to this.
All right.
So give it a shot.
I'm sure you can do it.
Take your time.
Think about everything you learned in the class and put it all together in this challenge.
I'll see you in the next video where we'll do part one of the solution.
Part one is taking that account class and making it abstract.