So what are smart pointers well smart pointers are objects in fact smart pointers are implemented as
C++ template classes which we can instantiate smart pointers can only point to heap allocated memory
and they automatically called the Leite when that's no longer needed.
Also very importantly smart pointers adhere to RAII principles as previously mentioned C++ has several
types of smart pointers unique pointer shared pointer weak pointer and auto pointer auto pointer has
been deprecated.
So you shouldn't use this going forward and we won't discuss it in this section.
So now let's see how we can create a smart pointer.
First we need to include the memory header file since it defines a smart pointer classes and functions
will use.
As previously mentioned smart pointers are implemented as class templates.
Very similar to the way that the vector class is implemented and we create them using a template parameter
much as we did with vectors.
Smart pointers are basically wrapper classes that contain and manage a raw pointer.
The actual implementation of smart pointers is compiler dependent and it's beyond the scope of this
section.
Once we create a smart pointer we can use the smart pointer much in the same way as we use raw pointer.
The smart pointer classes provide overloaded dereference and member selection operators as well as methods
to get the raw pointer and more.
However you can't do pointer arithmetic on smart pointers like you can with raw pointers.
Finally we can have custom Do leaders with smart pointers where we can explicitly defined the exact
behavior we want when the pointer is about to be destroyed.
Now let's see the syntax for declaring a smart pointer.
Here's an example of how you might create a smart pointer variable.
Of course you would replace smart pointer with one of the C++ smart pointer types like unique pointer
shared pointer or weak pointer.
In this case the smart pointer PGR will manage an object of type some class that's been allocated on
the heap.
Once we create a smart pointer object we can use the dereference operator the member selection operator
or any of the other smart pointer member methods.
Notice that we don't have to explicitly delete the pointer when we're done with it.
In this example when the pointer goes out of scope the smart pointers destructor is called automatically
and it takes care of deallocating any heap storage that was used.
That's pretty cool.
You can see how powerful smart pointers are they can prevent memory leaks.
Make your code easier to read and write and maintain with less errors.
Now let's talk about a common idiom or design pattern used in C++ programming.
It's called RAII or are a lie and it stands for Resource Acquisition is initialization a complicated
acronym for a pretty simple concept.
First RAII objects are allocated on the stack.
The resource acquisition part is pretty straightforward.
It means that RAII objects will acquire some sort of resource that could be opening a file allocating
memory acquiring a lock and so forth.
The initialization part is also straightforward.
This means that the resources acquired an object initialization time.
So in other words it happens in the object's constructor.
Now at some point we need to relinquish that resource that we acquired and that happens in the destructor.
Here we can close the file deallocate any allocated memory release locks and so forth.
Smart pointers are examples of RAII classes since this is the idiom they follow with regard to memory
resources.
A simple concept but a very powerful concept.
So let's start our exploration of the C++ smart pointers with the unique pointer in the next video.