Let's start by exploring C++ 11 smart pointers with the unique POINAR the unique pointer is a simple
smart pointer that's very efficient and it can be a drop in replacement in many cases for your typical
point to use case where you allocate storage use it and then free it in the same block.
A unique pointer declaration uses a template parameter which is the type of the object that the smart
pointer will manage on the heap.
So this allows us to declare a unique pointer objects that point to any type we need as the name dates
unique pointers are unique.
So you can't have multiple unique pointers pointing to the same object on the heap.
This implies a strong ownership relationship between the pointer and what it points to unique pointers
can't be copied or signed.
So their copy constructor and copy assignment operators are not available.
If you try to copy or assign them you'll get an error but unique pointers can be moved.
So they're great for placing a standard template library containers such as vectors.
And since the ownership is unique you're guaranteed that when the pointer goes out of scope the object
that it points to will automatically be cleaned up from the heap.
That's pretty powerful stuff.
So let's see one way we can create a unique pointer here you can see that we're declaring P1 to be a
unique pointer to an int.
We're also initializing it to point to a new ant that we create on the heap and that integer has been
initialized to 100.
Now P one owns that object on the heap when one goes out of scope the INT on the heap will be deallocated.
You don't need to call delete with the smart pointer.
Now as far as using the pointer The syntax is pretty much like using a raw pointer.
You can see that if we dereference P. one we get the integer that it points to.
In this case.
One hundred and we display it.
We can also modify the integer re-appointed to in a similar manner.
There's another better way to initialize a unique pointer and I'll show you that in a little bit.
It's also possible to create a raw pointer variable and then initialize unique pointer variable using
that raw pointer.
I'm not going to describe that since it's not good practice to do since you're referring to an object
on the heap from a smart pointer and from a raw pointer not something you typically want the unique
pointer has many methods.
But here are some useful ones.
In this case we again have a unique pointer p one that points to the integer 100 on the heap.
The get method returns a pointer to the managed object.
You don't often need to use this method but it can be useful when you're working with libraries that
use raw pointers.
The reset method sets the pointer to NULL pointer in the memory it points to will be released.
Also notice that we can check if a pointer is initialized using a simple IF statement as in if P1 in
this example the if block won't execute since we just reset the pointer to NULL pointer we can also
compare unique pointers using relational operators.
Of course unique pointers as well as other smart pointer types allow us to point to user defined types.
In this example we're creating a unique pointer that will point to an account object and we initialize
it to point to the Larry account.
Notice the syntax is as you would expect.
We use a count as the template argument in the unique pointer declaration.
What this says is that the unique pointer P1 will manage an account object on the heap and we're creating
that account object in the initializer list.
Now we can use this pointer as we would use a raw pointer.
We can dereference to get the account object as well as access the account object member methods via
the member selection or error operator and again when P one goes out of scope.
The heat storage associated with the account object is deallocated as we said unique pointers can't
be copied or assigned.
In this example we create a vector that will contain unique pointers to integers and we also create
a pointer which is a unique pointer to an int and it points to the image on the heap which has been
initialized to 100.
We can't simply push back that unique pointer to the vector because that implies a copy of the object.
And since any pointers can't be copied this will give you a compiler error.
However we can use move semantics to move the pointer.
In this case PCR gives up ownership of the pointer and it's moved to the vector.
The vector now owns the pointer and Peter will be set to NULL pointer when the vector goes out of scope.
It will deallocate all its elements in the integer on the heap will be deallocated correctly.
Now let's see another better way to initialize unique pointers since C++ 14.
We can use the make unique function.
This function returns a unique pointer of the specified type and it allows us to pass initialization
values into the constructor for the managed object.
So in the first example we declare P1 as a unique pointer to an integer and use make unique to initialize
the pointer and create the managed object all in one step.
Notice that in this case we're not using the new keyword in the second example.
P2 is a unique pointer to an account object.
And again we use make unique and provide the template argument account as well as the initialization
values which will be used by the account constructor.
Again in this case we don't use the new keyword.
The last example works the same way except we're using the auto keyword.
Let the compiler deduce the type of P3 based on what makes unique returns.
In this case you need a pointer to a player object.
The auto keyword can be very useful here since it makes the code more readable and more readable.
Now let's head over to the ID and go through some examples of using unique pointers in life code.
Ok so I'm back in the IDM and the Section 17 workspace in the unique pointer's project.
Now there's a lot of stuff going on here but it started out slow.
You can see that in the source tree.
Here we have our account hierarchy including our printable interface so this is the one that's using
dynamic polymorphism with that abstract base class account.
I'm going to use that in a minute using unique pointers in a vector.
But before we get there.
Let's just play around with a real simple class called test that I wrote right here.
It starts on 9:12 you can see that I get a class test and it's got an integer as an instance variable.
It's got a couple of constructors one just initializes data to zero.
That's the no args constructor and the other constructor just initializes data to whatever is passed
in.
I've got to get data a method that returns that data and a destructor that just says Hi I'm a destructor
real simple so let's create a test object just to be sure that this works OK.
So let's create a test object called T-1 will initialize it to a thousand and when we run this because
it's on the stack we should get the constructor and a destructor being called.
And you can see that's exactly what's happening here.
Test constructor with the thousand tested structure with a thousand perfect.
Now let's do it with a pointer and what we'll do is we'll just modify this slightly we'll say Prince
T-1 is a new test and will still use the thousand.
Now obviously if I don't delete it I'm going to leak memory secrecy.
That's exactly what happened here right.
My test constructor was called but the destructor was never called.
So as we've already learned what we have to do is we have to say delete T-1 And now when we run we'll
have both the constructor and the destructor called in we're not going to leave any memory.
That's exactly what we want.
This is using raw pointers what we want to do now is use different kinds of smart pointers in the next
couple of videos.
In this video we're using a unique pointer so I'm going to comment this code out and we'll do the same
thing using a unique pointer.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to declare the unique pointer.
So we're going to say Studd unique pointer and now we need a template parameter.
This is the type of class that we want to reference.
In this case it's test.
Later on we're going to use a count but it can really be any class you want and we want a call pointer
let's call it T-1 And now we'll use the new way of creating it will say new test and give it the constructor
parameter.
All right so what's that going to do.
Let's walk through this one.
We're creating a variable called T-1 which is a unique pointer to a test object and we're instantiating
that test object right here and initializing it to 100.
So in this case we've got that unique pointer pointing to this heap object right here.
Notice there's no delete T-1 necessary.
What's going to happen here is the constructor will be called and then the destructor will be called
automatically like we've seen.
So let's run that.
And you could see right here.
Test constructor for 100 test destructor for 100.
We never called Delete.
We did call on you because that's the style that we used to run that one.
So now let's use the make unique function.
Do the same thing so we'll say again stood.
And again we're going to point to a test object to call this T-2 and it will simply say equals stood.
Make unique and the first thing we want to do is we want to pass in the template argument which is test
followed by whatever constructor or data we want to pass it.
So let's say this is a thousand and this syntax might look a little odd but it really is pretty straightforward.
Again I'm creating a unique pointer to a test.
It's called T-2 and I'm using the make unique function to do it while the make unique function can make
any kind of unique pointer.
So we have to tell it what kind of unique pointer we want and that's what we're doing right here.
Once we do that the piece here inside the Perrin's we're here the thousand that is the argument that
you want to pass into the constructor.
That's going to call this constructor right here on line 17.
So now what we'll have is we'll have to.
You need pointers both on the stack.
Both will be constructed and when they're in they go out of scope the heap memory that they point to
will be destroyed automatically so we don't have to call delete and let's run that.
And you can see here test constructor for 100 for a thousand.
And then we're destroying both of them.
So that's pretty cool.
We really had nothing to do in this case right here on 9:28 with the make unique function we didn't
even have to use the new keyword at all and that's one of the things that you'll hear about modern C
post-flood.
You don't have to use new you don't have to use delete you just use smart pointers and they handle it
all.
And for the most part that's true but there are some cases where you still have to use it.
OK so that's that's a good example right here.
Now let's do another example.
Suppose that I want to create another unique pointer and we'll call this one T-3 and it will also be
to a test.
Let's just call it T-3.
Just like that and it's initialized.
Remember this is an object so it's going to call a constructor for the unique pointer just not pointing
anywhere now.
So now what do we do.
Can we say T-3 equals t one.
Well I can't do that because I am not allowed to assign unique pointers and you can see the error right
here use of the deleted function.
It's a long winded error basically telling you that that operator error you kind of see it over here.
The error message is kind of telling you that that operator equal has been deleted.
You don't have access to it.
Same thing if you tried to copy construct it won't let you because you you're not allowed to copy or
assign unique pointers.
You can move them.
So what we can do is we can say stood move to one and what that's going to do it's going to move the
ownership of that test object on the heap from 2083.
So now T-3 will be referring to it owning it and T-1 will have a null pointer in it.
So we can run this and you can see everything works exactly the same.
And we can actually test right here we could say if not T-1.
So if T1 is not pointing anywhere in other words if T1 is a null pointer then we could just simply say
See out and do something like T-1 is null pointer.
So the way that this is possible or X will end that line here.
And we should see that display helps me put that present back in and there you go you can see the output
right there is one is no pointer.
That's exactly what we expect right.
Because when you move the ownership from T1 to T-3 T-3 now owns that object.
The one is now.
It can't own the object because we're not sharing ownership.
Now let's create some unique pointers to accounts and the way we can do that is really really straightforward
again and either me at this or.
So it does not keep displaying and what we could say is we could say that we want a unique pointer to
an account.
I remember this is a base class pointer now which is what we want because we want dynamic polymorphism.
And what do we want to call it let's call it a one and we'll use make unique.
So now what are we pointing to we can't say a count because it counts as an abstract base class.
So we have to have one of those types of account one of our concrete classes.
So in this case that said we want to point to a checking account
in now what are the constructor parameters for a checking account where we can semo.
And let's say $5000.
And that should do it at this point we can use that object however we want but we have to get to the
object.
So if I want to display that object I could simply say dereference a one member.
A One is a pointer.
So if I dereference a want I get that checking account object and it's going to call our overloaded
insertion operator that we've defined.
So let's see if it does let's get rid of that extra Pirenne right here.
And let's give this a run.
And there you go checking account.
Moe $5000.
Pretty cool.
Of course we can use the object in any which way we want.
We could say a one and we could say deposit another $5000 and let's display the object again.
So you can see we're using dereferencing and we're using the arrow operator here as well to access the
actual object that we're pointing to.
So now we can build and run and you could see that mow has 5000 and 10000.
All right.
Pretty cool.
Now let's do a couple of more.
Let's create a vector and what we can do here is we can create a vector in that vector is going to be
a vector of unique pointers and those unique pointers will point to account objects.
OK so again it's a vector of unique pointers and those unique pointers are going to be referencing account
objects.
And we could just call this accounts simple as that.
And then what we can do is we can create some account objects right.
But in this case we're going to create them on the heap because we've got pointers to them and we're
going to create a savings or checking and a trust and I'll copy that code over just to save a little
typing time.
OK so I copied it over and you can see what I'm doing.
I'm adding checking account James with the thousand balance to the accounts vector and I'm doing that
using the push back method and I'm also using make unique because remember this is a vector of unique
pointers.
So I'm adding James Billiam Bobby a checking a savings and a trust account.
So that's pretty easy no.
We need to do is loop through that vector and display those account objects right.
So let's do that.
We'll say for then we can we can use a arranged base for loop here and I can say for auto.
And let's just call that a CC in accounts which is my collection.
And at this point we really need to do is just say stood out.
Right.
Dereferenced A.S.C. which is my account and display a new line.
Now this won't compile when I try to compile this.
I want to get an error right here and the problem is this is doing copy right where copying each of
those unique pointers that's in the account vector.
But we can't we're not allowed to copy unique pointers so we have to do this by reference and it's even
better if we do it by Consta reference.
So now we can run our program and you'll see that we're displaying James Billie and Bobbi's accounts.
OK.
And notice that we didn't do a single delete here right.
Memory is being cleared up automatically for us if we really wanted to see those destructors called
we can go into our account classes and just change that destructor from the default destructor to actually
just put some code in there that says hey I'm being destructed or something like that but they are being
called and that's pretty cool.
In the next video what we'll do is we'll learn about shared pointers.