Welcome back to the challenge one solution for Section 17.
What I'll do now is I'll write these three functions and we'll do it together and we'll explain it as
we go.
The first one is the make function that's the one that creates that unique pointer.
And the way we do that is we use make unique.
Now obviously we need to return it.
So we'll say return still make unique.
And what are we making.
Well we're making a vector and the syntax is going to look kind of weird here but we'll just have to
deal with it because that's just the way it is and it's not that hard once you break things up together
as I said.
So we're returning a unique pointer to a vector right.
And that vector is of stood shared pointers
to test objects and we'll have three greater than size here to close that up.
And then what we need to do is we need to call the constructor for that vector.
That's it.
That's all we really need to do here.
Now we'll clean this up in a second and we'll make this even better than it is here.
But that's one liner that's all it's doing.
We have to make that unique pointer remember down here on line 89.
We've got a constructed unique pointer right but it's not pointing anywhere yet.
That's what we're doing here and now we're actually creating that vector.
All right so now there's the Phil. How do we do the fill.
Well the fill expects that vector.
So it's pretty straightforward.
I just need to read that integer from the usery for each iteration.
Right so we need a temporary variable here let's just call that tap.
That's what we're going to read into and now we're going to loop How many times are we going to loop
or a loop number times however many numbers the user wants to enter.
So we'll say four ant equals one will start at 1 and we'll go I left center equal to numb and increment
each time.
So that's my loop.
We're going to use a for loop here because we know exactly how many times we need to loop we need to
loop number times.
So what do we do here.
Let's prompt the users will say stood out and we'll ask to use to enter data point and we'll just give
them a little number here so that's easier for them to understand which one they're putting in.
And we'll just surround that in brackets like that.
That's it.
And then what we do is we're read from CN into temp.
So we're going to do that three times five times ten times however many times they want.
Now what we can do is we can create our shared pointer.
We know the data that's going to be in the test object right.
That's this guy right here Templi just read it so we can do this in a couple of different ways.
Let's do it two ways.
The suit in two steps and then we'll do it one step.
So what we need to do is we need to have a variable here and it's going to be a shared pointer to a
temp object.
So my template parameters temp.
And what do we call this.
This is called PCR.
This variable name could be anything.
And we're going to use to make shared again test.
And what are we going to construct it with.
Well we're going to construct it with data or temp whatever the user entered.
Now that we've got that pointer remember we have a vector of shared pointers we just created the shared
pointer.
So all we need to do now is just say Veck dot push back and we're going to push back the pointer.
That's it we're done.
So that's exactly what's going on here.
And we're going to loop that many times create each key for each iteration create that shared pointer
instantiate that that test object and that's it.
Now rather than do it in two steps like this let's just do it in one step because it's much more efficient
to use move semantics.
So let's just say vector push back and write in here we'll just say stood make shared right so that's
going to call that's going to create that R-value and the R-value ref will be moved over.
So test and temp.
All right.
So again one simple statement.
And now the last thing we need to do is display this vector.
So I've already got the header information here with the two outs.
And what do we do here.
Well let's just use a real simple range based for loop.
So we'll say for conc auto We use a ref Mukalla pointer and we're going to iterate through that vector
and for each iteration all I want to do is just say stood out and we want to print the pointer's data
right so we need to do reference that pointer and get its data.
Something like that.
And then an end line.
And that should do it.
Let's compile this.
And there's a run how many points do you want to enter.
Let's say I want to enter 10 data points and there'll be that say two four six eight 10 12 14 16 18
and the last one is 20 there we go we are displaying our vector data and then you can see that our data
is being cleaned up automatically Our Test objects are being destroyed.
Pretty cool.
And you can see that there wasn't a lot of code to write at all.
Now let's clean this up just a little bit here.
Remember we can allow the compiler to do smart types for us so we can really clean this up a little
bit since the compiler knows exactly what we're returning right here.
We can simply replace this whole piece right here to auto just say auto right here let the compiler
figure out what the type of that return value is and it knows it based on this and we can also change
it up here in the function prototype.
Get rid of all that and just replace that with auto.
So we can replace this entire return type right here with auto.
And now we build again we get the same compile we get the same run.
So let's put three data items in here and we'll say five six and seven.
There we go we're displaying our data vector 5 6 7 and we're destroying those objects.
Pretty simple.
No news no deletes.
Not worrying about who needs to delete what.
And that's it.
That's the solution to this challenge.
I hope yours was close.
If you had issues with the pointers and figuring out how they work don't worry just keep at it.
It's just a matter of practice and understanding.
Conceptually what's going on and what's pointing to what dereferencing what to get what.
And it's just a little process that takes time to learn.