In this section of the Course will learn about exception handling and C++ exception handling is definitely
not a beginner topic but I want it to cover the basics so that you can understand exception handling
and be able to move on to more advanced features in Exception handling as you learn more C++.
We'll talk about what an exception is as well as how we can handle exceptions and C++ then we'll look
at a simple program that has a divide by zero error.
And with that exception handling to it so that we can handle that error once we understand the basics
of exception handling will create a function that throws an exception when something goes wrong within
it and we'll see how to throw an exception from that function and also learn how to catch the exception
outside the function and deal with it.
Obviously when something goes wrong in a program the normal flow of control of that program cannot continue
as if nothing has happened.
So it's very important to understand how exception handling affects the flow of control of your program.
Specifically we'll learn about stack unwinding what it is and how C++ uses it.
Then we'll create our own exception classes so that we have complete control over the exception types
that we throw and handle.
Finally we'll look at the standard exception class hierarchy provided by C++ and we'll look at the types
of exceptions that are already defined in C++.
Let me finish off this section overview with a few thoughts.
Writing exception safe code in C++ is extremely difficult and it's beyond the scope of this course.
In this section I want to introduce you to the basic concepts the syntax and the behavior of C++ exception
handling.
There are several schools of thought when using C++ exception handling.
One is that it should only be used for extremely exceptional conditions conditions that would prevent
your program from continuing.
Another is that it should never be used and then somewhere in the middle is a school of thought that
it should always be used even for not so exceptional situations.
And then of course there's all sorts of opinion in between all of these.
I've worked with C++ code where each of these scenarios was used and they all have advantages and disadvantages.
It really all comes down to how you define what an exception is.
This section of the Course will present a few C++ exception handling best practices but it's very difficult
to establish these best practices in C++ because when and how to use C++ exception handling is such
a hotly debated topic.
OK so let's see what exception handling is all about.