In this video we'll see how to format boolean types to output streams.
Note that we're using C out in these examples but any output stream will work including file output
streams which we'll learn about later in this section.
By default a boolean value is displayed as a 1 if the value is true or is zero.
The value is false but sometimes we'd like to display the strings.
True or false.
And I really don't want to write if else logic all over our code every time we need to do that.
Instead we can tell our output stream to display boolean values as 0 1 or as true false whichever we
want first.
Let's see an example of the default behavior for boolean values.
First we display the value of the expression 10 equals 10.
Since this is true a 1 will be displayed then we display the value of the expression 10 equals 20 which
is false.
And as you see a zero is displayed.
Now let's use a stream manipulator to switch this to true false mode in the first statement.
We're setting the output stream C out to Boutelle alpha mode.
This means that all further output to see out will display.
True or false as strings and you can see the output from the same program now displays true and false.
It's important to understand that with Boolean formatting once we set it with bool alpha or noble alpha
then all further boolean values will be displayed that way we can toggle back and forth as appropriate
as shown in this slide.
We can also set the format for boolean types using the set f method.
In this case we have a bunch of flags that can be used to set and reset formatting directives.
In this example we can pass stood IRS bull alpha or Stewart iOS noble alpha to the C or object to change
its formatting.
Finally we also have a method named reset.
AOS flags that expects the flag to reset.
In this case we can pass in studio as bool Alpha and it will reset the stream to whatever the default
is for that flag.
In this case it will go back to displaying booleans as zeros and ones although you sometimes see this
type of code in production.
It's more common to see the manipulator version and that's what I focus on in this section.
So let's head over to the IDM will do a couple of examples using bool Alpha and noble Alpha.
OK so you mean the ID.
I mean the section 19 workspace in the manip underscore Bouley in project and in this project.
I've got a bunch of simple test cases here that just display certain values just pointed out or see
out.
In this case those values are boolean values and we're going to manipulate them using the noble Alpha
and bhool Alpha manipulators.
So here's the default what we're doing here we're going to use this same test case throughout.
You can see what we've got here we've got word is 9:39.
That's either true or false.
Obviously this is true so this will always display true and 10 equals 20 will never be true so that
will always display false.
In this case we're using an expression but we can certainly use a variable.
Anything that evaluates to a true false value.
So by default this will display true which is a 1.
And this will display false which is zero.
So by default that is the way that we display boolean values as we saw in the slides.
So why don't we run this program.
And then we'll start modifying it just a little bit so we can start displaying the actual string true
false.
So let me run this and you can see right here.
I'll move this over here so you can see what's going on.
Noble Alpha is the default.
I didn't set it but it was just the default you can see I've sent nothing here.
All I'm doing is those to see out statements and I'm getting a one here and I'm getting zero here exactly
what I expect.
OK so now let's make a few changes here so you can see what I'm doing here on line 14.
I'm inserting stood Alpha onto Seow.
It's a manipulator.
This will switch the the default formatting in this case now to true false.
Now it's important to understand it will show you on lines 19 and 20.
That this is true.
Once we set that everything else whenever you need to display a boolean value.
This is the setting that'll stick there so if we need to go back to 0 1 we have to do that manually.
All right so what we expect here now is to actually display the word true in the word false so let's
give this a run.
And who you go you can see the original two statements 1 0 but now we're seeing true false.
Ok so here all we're doing is showing that once we set it it's set.
Right.
So here it's set to true false and we just displayed two statements to see out.
Now we've got another two and we expect those to be true false as well.
There you go.
True False True False.
It's going to keep doing this until you change it.
And that's what we're going to do here on this lines 23 to 25 I'm using stood no bull Alfonso this is
toggling back to the default of 0 1 and at this point we should be getting 0 1.
So I should get again 1 0.
TRUE FALSE true false.
And then 1 0 again and that's exactly what I'm getting 1 0.
And then 1 0 here.
OK.
So that's pretty straightforward.
And believe it or not what you're seeing here holds for every one of the manipulators that we're going
to see.
So it's the same kind of behavior not the part of once you said it it's set some of them just work for
one insertion but we'll talk about those.
But I'm talking about the syntax and the general flow here.
It's pretty much the same for all of them.
So let me comment out these lines 28 to 30 and in this case I'm doing the same thing except I'm not
using the manipulator I'm using the set f method.
So you can see him saying stood out.
Dot set f set f is the method and it expects a stood iOS bhool Alpha.
Now that looks maybe kind of intimidating and nasty it's not so bad.
Stood is the namespace iOS is a class and bhool Alpha is a flag that's defined in that class.
OK so C++ is doing exactly what it is expected to do.
If you just type bool Alpha it won't know where to find it so you have to say it's stood namespace I
Os class bool Alpha flag.
If you're using namespace standard then you don't need to put stood here or here or anywhere here that
you see it lighting up right.
You could just use iOS Alpha.
OK so in this case again I'm sending it back to true false but I'm doing it with this method now.
So you should see those last two statements display the words true false and there they are right.
Here you can see there is true and here is false and then the last one is used to reset certain flags.
All of these flags that we're going to use have default values so when we talk about left and right
justification and you know the way we display numbers or the way we display booleans as in this case
they have default ways of doing it.
We know the default for booleans is the number is 0 or 1 right.
So there is a manipulator here called reset U.S. flags and again it's understood namespace reset Iowas
flags and then you pass into it whatever flag you want to reset and it will reset that.
Not to Alpha but reset it to the default behavior for displaying booleans which in this case will be
numbers right 0 1.
So when we run this we expect that to be reset to the default.
And what's nice about this is suppose you've got a modifier that has there aren't any like this.
But suppose you had 8 different values right.
One of them is obviously the default.
You don't have to worry about which one it to set.
You could just basically call this with the flag you want and reset it to the appropriate behavior.
So let's run this in now we expect that those last two statements to print out one in zero.
And there you go so that's it.
The basics of everything else we're going to do with most with the manipulators are here.
We can use them in line we can use them with functions and what we'll do next is we'll talk about integer
output so we'll be right back to do that.