Welcome back to the section 19 challenge to solution.
Hope you had fun doing that challenge.
It was pretty nice.
And you got a lot of different ways that you can tweak and extended to make it your own.
So I'm in the section 19 workspace in the challenge underscore to underscore solution project.
And I wrote some functions to solve this.
But first I just want to go through the logic in the main So you could see that it's really dead simple
and the functions that I wrote make it even simpler.
So let's just start here at the top and we'll walk through this.
I've got an input file stream called infile that's what I'm going to use to read the responses file.
I've got a string for the answer key and I've got a string for the student name and the student responses
and I'm going to read it.
Each iteration of the file read.
Ok then I've got a running sum and a total number of students that we're going to use to calculate the
average score.
OK.
Pretty simple.
So let me scroll up just a little bit here and here is my program pretty much opening the input file
right here responses to x T.
Notice again that the dot dot slash should because I mean code like if you were in another Id probably
have to do the same thing or just use responses that text it's totally up to the ID.
If we can't open that file we display problem up the file and we're out of here just like before and
then the very first thing I'm going to do right here I'm reading that first line in the file right.
Or the first string in the file which is the answer key.
That's it I'm reading it from file and storing get an answer key.
So that will be that A B C D string.
Then I'm going to print the header which just displays student and score with a bunch of dashes underneath
it.
So that's a function that I'm using to print the header and then I've got the logic of my loop right
here so I'm saying while read from infile the name and the response pair if anything.
And those two are strings that I declared up top I just showed them to you a minute ago.
If anything all goes wrong here.
Hit and file.
If we have a bad read We've got bad data.
This will fail and I'm out of here.
But if we don't now we've got name and response contain the strings for for example Frank and Frank's
response.
We increment the total number of students because we need to do that to calculate the average and then
I'm going to call a function called process response.
I'm going to pass into it the response and the answer key and it's going to return an integer with the
score.
So it'll return 0 1 2 3 4 5.
In this case because that's we can get them all wrong or you can get them all right or everything in
between that's it I add the score to my running some of scores.
And then I call print student I'm going to call that each time.
So I'm going to print the student's name.
So right here I'll say Frank and Frank got a five minute loop and I do it again.
OK.
So I'm going to clear this screen real quick.
Then at the very end I just calculate the average.
To be sure that I don't do a division by zero error.
So if the total number of students is not equal to zero I'm going to do the division and I'm doing the
static cast that you guys have seen before here psych's I need to make one of these double and at the
end I get the footer and in order to print the FOTR it doesn't know what the average score is.
So I'm sending it to it.
I close the file and I'm done.
OK so you can see the logic is really straightforward right.
You can see here I'm opening the file making sure it's open.
I'm closing the file down here.
I'm reading from the file right here and the rest.
And here as well and the rest is just the processing that I need to solve this specific problem.
OK so now let's take a look at these methods.
Scroll up a little bit and let's start with the printhead method.
Pretty straightforward right.
Just a bunch of print statements to see out and what I'm doing here is I'm displaying the student and
displaying the score and I'm using the set w manipulator here on and left to mine them up nicely.
I could have used constants for 15 and 5 and 20 but I chose not to with such a simple little program.
And then I'm using Cetaphil to display a little dashed line.
That's it.
I set Phil back to space just in case somebody else needs it.
I don't want to have them display dashes.
The footer is passed in the average score and it just displays the footer really really straightforward
again.
Now I probably should have used the set precision and set fixed one here but I'm using it here.
So it's it's persistent but good practice is to put it in here as well right about here.
That way if someone changed it and then this function got called you'll set it the way you want it.
And then the last one is the print student where I pass in the student's name and the students score
and I just display them just like we've done before.
So these are just these handy little functions.
And the reason we're using these functions is so we don't clutter up our main and this is just a lot
of code a lot of noise really because it's just all about I mean all I'm doing here is displaying student
displaying score.
But you've got all this other stuff around with the manipulators I need to set which set I need to do
left and I need to write precisions.
And it just really clutters up the logic in the main.
So you really want to extract that out of modularize it out into a function get it out of the way and
out of sight out of mind it's abstraction.
I just call footer and whenever I need it and pass it an average I just call print Hetter and that's
it real simple.
And then the last thing is that function that actually calculates the number right.
So that's a process response right here.
So we're passing in the student's response which was a string that could be like ABC x x or whatever
it is.
And the answer key which in this case was a b c d and we're setting the score to zero we're assuming
they haven't gotten anything right and all we're doing is we're looping one character at a time through
that answer key and we're comparing the answer key to the response of the student at I if they're the
same.
We're bumping up the score.
We're doing that throughout.
So we're going to check this guy with this guy.
And then this guy with this guy and so forth.
When we're done we turn the score.
So that's it.
That's the solution or that's one solution you may have your own solution.
If it's you think it's cool.
Post it on the forum and if we run this that's what we get just what we expect students.
Frank Larry Moe Curly Michael and their scores.
And then the average score 3.6.
And the nice thing about this solution I think is this right here.
I mean I'm looking at the code right here which is really doing most of the work while this first one
is well which is reading the key.
So this this piece of code right here this is really what's doing it all in when you read it it's really
really easy to read and reading the answer key and printing the header while I'm grabbing those pairs
I'm processing the response.
I'm printing each student and then I'm calculating the average and pretty in the footer.
So looking at this it's really easy to understand and to debug it and that's it.
That's the challenge.
I hope you have fun with it I hope you extended it.
And there's another challenge coming up right after this one.