This video or write some code that will allow us to create some files and create some files a couple
of different ways first will create a real simple find just write a string to it and then what we'll
do is we'll read a couple of copy file utilities just like we did in the slides.
OK so I mean the section 19 workspace in the right file project and I've got nothing going on here except
these includes them including IO stream stream and string.
Let's get started.
First thing we need to do is create an O.F. stream object so we'll call it stood O F stream and we'll
call it out file.
It's it's going to be an output file and we'll initialize it to slash again I'm in code like.
That's why I'm doing this.
And I'll name the file output text.
OK.
Now we'll check to see that it was open correctly.
So if not out file then what we're going to say is just get out of here write some error.
So will provide an error saying error creating file because it is an output file it will return something
other than zero you get rid of that extra quote right here and we'll return one.
That's it.
So if we get now to this line 13 with our file has been created in this case remember if the file does
not exist it's going to be created.
Right now it does not exist so it will be created if it does exist.
It will be truncated.
OK so we'll lose whatever was in there before.
So let's create a string variable we'll just call it line and we'll ask the user we can call it the
variable name anything we want.
Unless the user to enter something to write to the file
and we'll simply read it from We'll use getline to read it because we want to read more than just one
word.
So we'll say Get line from CNH into line.
Remember again we're using string objects here we're not using C-style strings.
That's it.
So what do we do now we say file and we insert that line into that file and we'll give it a new line
as well.
Number and line will flush out the buffer and then we're done here we'll just close the file
that's it pretty easy.
Now if we run this let's do that
into something direct to the file I'm going to say Hello there file I'll press enter programs done I'll
exit this.
Now there is nothing that shows up here by default some of the ids will show that file when it's created
code like doesn't.
So what you can do is you can select the project right click and say open containing folder that will
open it up and explore or in Finder for on a Mac and I just drag that over here and you can see that's
right here we just created the file name remember the mean drags down just a little bit file name was
output DXi there's output that text here right here.
And you can see the contents of it right over here.
Hello there file OK.
Now let me move this out of the way and let's run this again and if we run it again I'll just say my
name is Frank and Precentor.
And now if we look at the file again I'll drag this back over.
You can see that what was there before was erased because we're opening the file and truncation mode
so it gets rid of whatever was there.
That's the default.
Now if we want to add something to the file we can simply open it in a pen Moat's we can put up another
flag here just say we'll say stood IO s of Penda mode or AP and we run this again now we say this should
be another line.
So we'll take a look at the file now and you can see my name is Frank.
And now I put this should be another line as you can see that it's actually appending to the existing
file.
So that's it.
That's pretty straightforward and really that's the basics of output to textfiles.
We have the power of all those stream manipulators which really gives us a lot of power and to how we
format the output files.
Ok so what I want to do now is I want to switch to another project.
It's going to be the copy file.
Underscore one project so I'll switch to that and I'll be right back.
OK so I'm in the section 19 workspace and I've opened up now the copy file underscore one project.
And in this project what we've got is this poem we've got Shakespeare sign it again and we want to do
is we just want to copy it to another file.
So what we can do is I've already written the code and it's really really straightforward it's just
like it was in the slides.
What we can do is we can start here and you can see we've got our includes that we need and we've got
an input file stream called infile which is my poem and then I've got an output file stream called out
file which is my poem underscore out XTi that's the file we want to create but it's going to be a copy
of the poem DXi file.
So again we're basically following the recipe we're instantiating those objects we're making sure that
our file streams are open and ready to read and write and then we've got our our logic and our logic
is really on there just a couple of lines of code.
We've got a line that we want to read file the file input into.
And there's my loop I'm using getline to read a line from in file and when I get that line all I'm going
to do is write it out file.
That's it.
At the end we're going to display a little message that says file copied and we're going to close both
files.
So if we run this it'll save file copy.
That's it.
You can see how quickly this runs and will open up that project the containing folder and we should
see a poem underscore out there it is right here.
That was just created one big and if I select it you can see that the poem is over here.
This is the original poem and this is the copied poem so it's exactly the same.
So it's really easy to copy one file to another.
In this case we used formatted input and output because we're using getline and we're using the insertion
operator with line to write it to the file.
That's it.
Now if we go over to copy file underscore to project you open that up.
It's exactly the same thing the only difference here is that we're using get and put.
So we're using an formatted input output and you could see that the code is exactly the same except
the while loop and the variable declaration right there that's the only difference is we're doing it
one character at a time.
So while we get a character from a file we output that character to outfought that's it.
So let's run this also like that.
Make sure that that project is selected.
Run this it's done and I'll open up that project in the taining folder and right here you'll see poem
dot out and it's right over here you can see it right there.
So that's it for this video.
Here you see a few examples of creating files appending to files and copying files using unformatted
and formatted.
Next is a challenge and then the challenge what we're going to do is we're going to take Shakespeare's
Romeo and Juliet and add line numbers to it and create a new file.
I'll see you there.