In this video I'd like to go over some of the algorithms in the SPL.
Now there are a lot of algorithms in the TLM where they're going to cover a few of them but the techniques
you'll see apply to many of them and you can be very productive with them very quickly.
I'm in the Section 20 workspace and I mean the algorithms project and let me just go over these includes
real quick.
I am including algorithm we need that to use these algorithms.
I'm also including a vector list and CC type.
Now CC type are going to use for the two upper function that converts a character from lowercase to
uppercase.
That's the only reason we're going to do it.
And most of the examples we use a vector.
But there's one that's going to use the list just to change things around a little bit.
OK.
So that's that we're also going to use this person class that I created right here is a really really
simple person class person has a name and age I think we've used a class like this are very similar
to this before have a default constructor that piler will generate.
For me I've got an overloaded constructor that expects a name or an age.
And then I've got these two operators these are really important whenever we use the T.L. it's got to
have a way to compare our own objects.
I use raw user defined types so I need to provide less than and the equality operators and all I'm doing
here is I'm saying that one person is less than another person if as if their age is less than the other
person's age.
It's just totally arbitrary in this example.
This really would depend on whatever business logic you are using and how do I compare two persons.
Well their names have to be the same and their age has to be the same.
So we've got that and here.
So that's a real simple person class that we're going to use in here.
So I've also divided this into functions just like I did with the iterators lecturer.
So let's take a look at this first one here.
What is the algorithm we're using the algorithm is right there.
That function is the find function it finds an element in a container.
OK the first occurrence of the element in the container.
So what are we going to do.
Let's create a vector of integers 1 2 3 4 5 and then I'm going to call stupid find I'm going to give
it the beginning and the end.
Now I notice that the syntax here is a little different.
I just wanted to show you that syntax in case you run into and it's equivalent to Veck dot begin and
Vector.
And like we've seen before but in this case it stood began in the pass in the vector or the container.
It was just another way to do it means exactly the same thing.
So let's get back to this.
I'm calling the Find function I'm passing in where I want to start where I want to end.
Right that's the sequence that I'm going to get back from the container and I'm using these iterators
and that's what I want to find I want to find that element 1.
I know it's there it's right here and now what does this return.
Well if it finds it it will return an iterator pointing to it.
If it doesn't find it it will return an iterator to the end.
So it's really simple to check.
OK so let me clear this and let's look at the logic here.
So we're really executing that function.
And if the location remember location I'm using auto but location is an iterator to a vector of integers.
If the location is not equal to the end of the vector and then we found it we found the number and we
could just the reference it and print it out.
In this case it'll print out one.
Otherwise we couldn't find the number.
So let's execute this and then we'll change the code just a little bit.
So we run this real quick.
We found the number one absolutely it's in there.
Let's change the one to something like a 7.
We know that the 7 is not in the vector.
So let's execute this again.
Couldn't find the number just what we expected.
Now I'm going to change this back to 1 so you guys can play with it when you have the source code on
your end.
That's as simple as it gets and the really cool thing about this is I'm finding the first occurrence
of an element in any container that's mind blowing right because you're not worried about how this stuff
is implemented you've got all these different containers.
How easy is this.
I just want to find something just got called Find where do I start.
Where do I end.
What do I want to find.
That's real classic abstraction.
That's pretty cool.
That's using a primitive type an integer.
What would it look like if we're trying to find a player.
So that's what this example right here is going to show you.
So let's take a look at that.
In this case I'm not using a vector.
I'm using a list but it's all the same.
I've got a list of persons I'm calling them player and initializing it to Larry is 18 years old Moe
is 20 and Curley's 21.
Remember that person classes showed you a little bit ago.
I want to find that person in that list.
Look at the code.
Auto location 1 equals stood find where do I start.
Where do I and what do I want to find the best algorithms he's going to use the equality operator that
I've overloaded for my person class to compare these guys.
So hopefully it'll find this guy right here right.
So if location 1 is not equal to the end then I found ammo.
Otherwise I didn't find Mo.
And how do I know that Mo is Mo Mo has to be his name it has to be Monee has to be 20 members are equalitie
operatives checking for both.
All right so let's give this one a run and we should see found mo.
That's exactly what we get.
Now if I change Mo's age here let's him make them 18 or 12.
That's not in there.
I don't have a 12 in there.
So at this point when I run it I should not find MO and it says Mo not found.
That's exactly what we expected.
So let me change this again back to 20.
OK so that is the test that shows you how to use the Find function superpowerful.
I mean when you think about it how hard is it to write a Find function for an array.
It's not really you started to begetting and you move along and found it.
I'm done.
But what about a list a doubly linked list of priority cueist set.
Wow that's a lot of code you would have to write yourself.
You don't have to worry about any of that you just call find it tell it where to start.
Tell it what it word and tell it what you want to find and you're done.
It's as simple as that.
OK so that's the fine test.
Let me show you the count test now so uncommon that out and let's take a look for the count test.
This one is really really dead simple.
All it does is it counts the number of elements in a container.
But it takes you can take it a little bit further.
You can actually count the number of occurrences of that specific element.
Or we could just use size for the count of the elements but in this case how many times does the one
appear in this container.
Well I've got it here here and here it occurs three times.
So what's my algorithm count from the beginning to the end.
And again you can use a subset if you like.
I'm always going to do beginning to end in these examples.
This will return an integer we get back to zero.
Didn't find it.
Forget back a one or two or three.
That's how many times the one occurred.
So in this case I expect back of three that's run this and there it is three occurrences founts of the
one was there three times.
Again if I put something that's not in there like a 10 in this case and I run this you should get back
zero occurrences found.
And that's exactly what we get.
OK.
Simple as that.
So let's close this one down and let's take a look at a more powerful one called the count if test.
So here's the count if the count if is a little bit different We're going to use the lambda expression
for it.
This was superpowerful.
We're only going to count how many times that element occurs if it matches some condition.
That condition is called a predicate.
It's something that returns a true false value.
So here's my vector and you can see that what's my condition.
Well you can see right here look at the lambda that tells you exactly what I'm doing.
I'm only looking for numbers that made two or zero money looking for even numbers here right.
That's what that predicate right here is doing.
So I'm starting at the beginning and here's my Lamda write it up here and just we understand exactly
what's going on.
There's my Lamda and here's the code for the lamb though which is this piece right here and I won't
write that again.
That's my LAMDA.
So what's going on I'm starting at the beginning of that VAK I'm going toward the end of the vac.
And for each element in that sequence I'm passing it in to here and that's going to return true or false
depending on what it's returned it's going to include in the count here.
So in this case what's being passed into this Lamda here is one and then two and then three and then
four and then five and so forth and all it's doing is if this is true if this predicate right here is
true it's just counting them up.
So in this case how many even numbers do we have we have one.
We have two we have three we have four.
So I would expect the four coming back over here you can see it's the same idea except this time what
am I looking for.
I'm looking for odd numbers.
How many odd numbers do we have.
We have 1 2 3 4 5.
So we've got five I expect four from here.
I expect this to identify.
Now let's write another function we'll write this one together.
How can we determine how many elements in the VEC are greater than or equal to 5.
So what do we do.
What we write the statement real simple numb equals stood count if that's my algorithm we're going to
do vector began.
Let's search the entire vector way to go to vector on end.
Now we could have used a constant iterator here we could use a lot of things I'm just going to do real
simple.
So I'm going from beginning to end and at this point this is where I need my lambda.
So all these elements are being passed into this what am I going to do.
I'm going to put my lambda in here.
It's going to expect a single integer.
I'm going to write my code right in here.
You don't want to close this and close it like that with a semi-colon.
So what is the predicate.
I'm going to return true if x is greater than or equal to 5 just like that.
And I just copy this line right here.
Move it down here.
So all I'm going to do is I'm going to output numb numbers are greater than 5.
How many of those do we expect.
Well we've got to a greater than or equal to five sorry.
So we have the five and the 100 so there's only two.
So let's run this.
We have four even numbers just what we expected.
We've got five odd numbers and two of the numbers are greater than or equal to five I'll change that.
There you go.
Pretty simple.
These lambdas take a little get used to but you get used to them really quickly and are so powerful
it makes programming much much simpler.
OK.
So that's count if the next one will do is replace test.
So let's take a look at replace testing them and comment that out here.
So what does this doing.
Well this is looking through a vector in this case where any container and it's going to replace one
number with another.
Pretty cool.
So here I've got a stood VAK and I've got one two three.
Notice the ones that's all I really care about in this case.
I've got three of those ones right in here.
I'm just displaying them out right now and will display them out and then I'm calling stood replace
and I'm starting at the beginning going to the end and I'm replacing one with 100.
And remember I'm using primitives here but we can use our own objects if you like.
So in this case I'm replacing those three ones with 100 and then I'm just displaying it again.
So let's give that a run and we'll be able to see that we've got one to make move this over just a little
bit.
One two three you can see the three ones here and you can see that the three ones have been replaced
with hundreds.
Really cool really easy.
Let's do a couple of more.
And the point of this is not to show you these specific algorithms.
There's like I said over 50 probably closer to 90 algorithms out there.
If you look at the numeric Hetter as well they all work in a similar way they all use iterators many
of them use predicates So this gives you a pretty good feeling for the power that's out there and the
things you can do.
So this is the all of test.
This is really cool.
Let me show you this one.
So here's my Veck one and I've got a 1 to 3 or 5 or 7 or 9 a 1 to 3 or 13 19 if I'm just some arbitrary
numbers in there.
What this is doing there is the function all of it's going to see whether all of the elements in that
container match this predicate that superpowerful.
So in this case I'm saying if all of those elements are greater than 10 then this will return true.
Otherwise they will return false.
So obviously then they're not all greater than 10 right.
I've got a one in a three to five so I expect this to return false and I expect this to print up.
In this case here all of them starting at the beginning going toward the end I'm checking to see if
all the elements are less than 20.
You can see in here they are less than 20.
Every single one of them has less than 20.
So I expect this guy to display right now.
We have the all of.
There's also another algorithm called.
Any of which.
So if any of them is greater than 10 it will be true.
So you've got the power to compare them all or just compare one of them.
So let's execute this and we can see here not all of the elements are greater than 10.
Absolutely.
We've got some there less than 10 but all the elements are less than 20 and I can impress upon you the
fact enough times about how powerful this is we don't really care about the container and that's the
cool part.
I don't need to worry about it.
It could be implemented in a really really complex way doesn't matter.
The algorithms library handles it for us.
All right so the last example is a string transform test.
This is pretty cool.
There is an algorithm called transform that works not just with strings it works with or with containers
obviously but it's used very often with strings.
Let me show you what it does.
And this is where that two upper function comes in.
So here I've got as one is a stood string and it's initialized to this is a test and all I'm doing is
I'm displaying before the transform I'm displaying the strings so that's just going to display.
This is a test just like that.
Then I'm going to call the Stood transform function and want to tell it where to start.
And as TR one began where to end.
In other words it's processing the entire string and then we're to start policing its results at the
beginning of the string again.
And what do I want to do.
Well I want to make each character too upper and I can pass my own function here.
But we already have the two upper function defined in CC type.
So may as well use it whenever you put that scope resolution operator in the front of something with
nothing here just that guy followed by something else that means global scope.
And that's what's going on here.
So I'm using the two upper method or function actually that's in the global scope.
So what do you think this does.
It makes every single character in that string uppercase superpowerful we can process strain's if you
remember that one example we did a while back with the way back in the course right where we encrypted
a string.
This makes it really easy because you can transform that string you can play all kinds of games with
it.
And the algorithm becomes much cleaner.
So let's run this example and we should see the string and lowercase and then the string in uppercase
there it is.
This is a test.
All right.
So that gives you a little bit of introduction and let me uncomment this out set it up just like that
so I'll save it like that for you guys to be able to download it and play with this from the beginning.
So here you can see the find the count the count if the replace the all of you can play around with
the any of.
And what I would encourage you to do is let me just close this up a little bit.
What I would encourage you to do is play with these lambdas give yourself different conditions make
them a little bit more complicated if you like and just get used to the lambda syntax.
One of the things that we're not going to do in this course or maybe I will in a different section later
on I can add a section just on lambdas that guy right there those two square brackets that's the lambdas
capture block.
That's a real important piece of the lambda that allows you to capture the context so if I have variables
in here I can catch them in there and set them and use them.
We're not doing that in here.
We're just keeping the lambdas really simple.
Hopefully you do understand these lambdas and how powerful they are.
Play around with them get comfortable with them.
It's really the way to go with modern C++.
All right.
So that's it for the algorithms demo.
Now we're going to start talking about the actual containers the first one we'll talk about is stood
a ray.
So I'll be right back to talk about that.