This video we'll learn more about the vector container.
We already know a lot about it since we've been using it since very early in the course as you know
in order to use the vector container you have to include the vector header file.
The vector is probably the main workhorse of the SPL.
It's used in a lot of applications.
The vector allows us to create dynamically sized arrays.
The cool thing is that the vector can expand and contract is needed and it's handled automatically by
the SPL.
We don't have to worry about the details but the vector does give us some control as to how it can grow
the vector elements themselves are stored in contiguous memory.
So as the vector expands a new larger area and memories allocated in the current elements are moved
to it like the dude array the vector provides fast direct access in constant time.
It also allows for rapid insertion and deletion at the back of the vector in constant time.
However inserting elements into any other part of the vector other than the back is not as efficient.
It happens in linear time which means that the running time increases nearly with the size of the vector
the vector supports all of the iterators and the iterators may become invalid.
This is especially true when the vector resizes and a new area and memory is allocated for the extra
storage.
In this light we see a diagram of what a simple vector might look like.
We declare VEC as a vector of integers and initialize it to 1 2 and 3.
The vector has a front end to back the front.
In this case is Element 1 and the back is element 3 we typically add elements to the back of the vector
using the pushback method.
So in this case we're adding the element for using pushback and the force added to the back of the vector
we can add elements anywhere in the vector but the back is the location where the addition of elements
is most efficient.
If there's no room and the vector needs to allocate more space it will automatically usually twice the
amount of the current space is allocated and the current elements are moved over to the newly allocated
area and then the new element is placed at the back.
Let's look at a few ways to initialize vectors and then we'll see some of its member methods.
In the first example in this slide I declare vec is a vector of integers and initialize it to 1 2 3
4 and 5.
The second example I declare Veck one is a vector of integers and amusing an overloaded constructor
here to create 10 integers and initialize them all to 100.
Of course the vector supports copy and move semantics for initialisation and assignment in the third
example I'm declaring Stooges as a vector of stood strings and I'm initializing those strings with both
strings and C-style strings.
Vectors also support assignment via an initializer list just like we did with the array.
So let's look at some other methods provided by the vector
again please refer to the C++ as T.L. documentation for more detail on these and other methods.
There's a lot there and that's the place to look for information.
But let's see some other methods.
Let's start with size.
This method returns the number of elements that are in the vector.
That's pretty straightforward.
The capacity method tells us the current capacity of the vector when this capacity is exceeded.
That's when the vector will expand dynamically and the max size tells us what the max size of a vector
would be in our system.
And that's the number of elements that it can hold.
You see this is a really large number.
Vectors also let us access individual elements either using the subscript operator or the dot at method
just as we've seen before the subscript operator does not do any bounds checking and the DOT method
does.
You can see in the example code that Veck at 0 will refer to the one and Veck someone will refer to
the two
as previously mentioned.
The vector allows for efficiently inserting elements at the back of the vector.
This is done with the pushback method.
In this case we have a vector of person objects.
We can create a person P1 named Larry who is 18 years old and we can use the pushback method to insert
P1 at the back of the vector.
Remember all container classes make copies of the elements they store.
So in this case a copy of P1 is made in the second example we're creating an unnamed person object and
adding it to the back of the vector using move semantics.
The last method we haven't seen yet and it's awesome.
It's called emplace back.
This method expects the parameters that would normally be passed into the person constructor and that's
what it does.
It constructs the person object using a person constructor right in place where it's supposed to be
in the vector.
That's really efficient no moves no copies it just puts it right where it's supposed to be.
Use this method it's awesome.
The empty method will return true if the vector is empty and false otherwise.
Just as we saw withstood arrays we can swap two vectors but in the case of vectors the vector elements
have to be the same type but the sizes can be different.
And finally we can use the sort algorithm in any kind of algorithm to sort vectors with iterators to
copy vectors.
We'll see some of those examples in the ID.
So let's see how we can insert elements into a vector at a place other than the back first will create
two vectors of integers.
Vec one VEC to VEC one is one two three four five and vector is 10 20 30 40 and 50.
Now let's say we want to insert some data before the three and Veck 1.
First we need an iterator to point to the location of the vector we want to insert the data before.
In this case the three we can use the find algorithm to easily find the three as we've already seen.
Once the iterator is pointing to the three in the one then we could call the insert method and pass
in the iterator it and the element we want to insert before it.
In this case the 10.
That's it.
Now Veck 1 contains 1 to 10 3 4 and 5.
So we inserted the 10 before the 3.
That was pretty easy but we can also insert a sequence of elements how with iterators.
Let's insert the entire contents of VEC two before the four in VEC one.
We first find the four and get an iterator to it we'll call it I-T then we can use the insert algorithm
and pass in the iterator I-T that we want to insert before and the two iterators that will provide the
sequence of elements from vector to that we want to insert.
In this case all a victim.
That's it.
Now Veck 1 will be 1 to 10.
3 10 20 30 40 50 4 and 5.
We inserted a copy of Veck two before the four very powerful and easy to do.
All right so let's head over to the idea will see these examples and we'll see some more complex examples
as well.
OK so I'm backing the idea.
I mean the Section 20 workspace in the vector project and this project has a lot of examples I really
believe that the best way to learn the CEO is through the examples are real example driven approach
maybe a little boring sometimes as I'm giving you example after example after example.
But I think it's really the best way to learn it.
I've got a lot of examples here.
I'm going to go through them pretty quickly.
So please feel free to pause the video look at the example and then continue again.
Let's get started.
I'm including IO stream vector and algorithm obviously I'm going to use vectors in this example and
we're going to use some algorithms as well.
And I'm going to use integers mostly but I'm going to use this person class in a few places.
It's the same kind of person class we've used before a person has a name and an age it's a string and
an integer.
I've also overloaded the stream insertion operator just to make life easier.
I've got a default constructor.
I've got an overloaded constructor.
And remember when we're using our own classes with the SBL always always overload less than and the
equality operator.
Those are the two boolean operators that are being used by the as T.L. on your own objects.
So that's it I'm comparing two people and I'm comparing the the one is less than the other.
I'm not really using them in this demo but it's good habit to do as far as the operator.
The insertion operator is right here.
Same as we've always done.
And then what I did was I created these two display functions.
One is called display two and one is just called display and want to use display mostly.
But I'm going to use display too.
And the reason I did display two just so you can see a different way to write this.
Of course I could use a range base for loop to do this and I'm doing that right here.
But I wanted you to see the For Each rhythm we've seen this before as well.
So give me a vector of integers and I'm going to do for each.
What's my sequence from the beginning to the end of the vector that was passed in.
So in other words the entire vector at each iteration this lambda expression is going to be called X
will be passed into it X will be each one of those elements in that sequence.
He says despite.
So it's really the same effect as arranged based Foreland.
This function here I wrote as a template function because sometimes I want to be able to print vectors
of integers.
Other times I want to be able to print vectors of persons.
So it's nice just to have one function to let you do it.
Here's my template parameter right here t.
So I can pass in a vector of anything and I can loop through here using my range based for loop and
the auto takes care of figuring out the type for me.
So it makes life really really easy.
OK so let's start going through these examples the first few are going to be really straightforward
I'm sure you've seen them before.
What I've done is about ready run this and the output is over here on the right side you can see here
in the console.
But what we'll do is we'll go through these examples and then we'll look at the console.
And like I said the first few are really really straightforward.
So let's look at this first one I've got Veck as a vector of integers and I'm initializing it to 1 through
3 4 and 5 and I'm calling that display function that's the template function.
It's going to display the vector and you can see the vector being displayed right appear.
One two three four and five.
Now what I'm doing is remember vector has already been initialized so right now I'm using assignment.
This is assignment using initialization which is really really cool and handy.
So now vec is two four five six and I'm displaying it using that other display function.
So here I am displaying Veck again and you can see vec is now 2 4 5 6.
And then in this case I'm creating one.
It's an object and it's also a vector of integers but I'm not using the Curley's here right so I'm not
using an initialization this I'm using an overloaded constructor.
That's part of the vector class.
This tells me how many do I want.
This tells me what is each one going to be.
So this is going to create 10 100s and on display at Quon you can see them right up here all 10 100.
There are other constructors is a lot of different ways to do that refer to the documentation.
Some of them are really interesting.
These are the ones that I use all the time.
OK so now let's look at test to test two is all about the size the capacity so we understand how this
works.
So what I'm doing here is I'm saying vec is again a vector of integers 1 2 3 4 5 I'm displaying it because
he's displaying right here that I'm asking what's the size of the vector.
What's the max size of the vector and what's the capacity of the vector.
So he could see here the size is five.
I've got five elements in there right now the max size is a really big number that's how many elements
that vector can hold and the capacity is five.
In this case.
What does that mean.
That means that if I exceed that capacity this vector will increase in size right.
In other words the SBL is going to allocate space for a larger vector.
Remember it's all contiguous in memory and copy stuff into it.
So that's exactly what I'm going to force right now.
I'm going to push back six so I'm going to add six to the back of this vector is going to be a 6 right
in there now that I'm going to display it again and then display the size Max sizing capacity we would
expect Max sized not to change right now because I'm not doing anything else.
So I'm pushing it back and displaying it.
So right here you can see the six at the end here.
What's the size of the vector six max size is the same.
But look at the vector capacity here.
Now it's 10.
This is pretty typical whenever you exceed the capacity to do it'll double.
So the next time the capacity will be 20 and then 40 and then 80 and so forth that's a very very typical
behavior.
Keep that in mind because if you've got ten thousand elements in here and you add that ten thousand
one it's going to go to 20000 big when you only maybe need 10000 and a little bit.
So there's ways to help that.
And I'll show you a couple we've got this method called shrink to fit which is pretty cool and this
has came about in see Puss Puss 11.
So if I call shrink to fit it will shrink the amount of storage allocated to exactly the vector size.
And so remember right now we had capacity 10 that I called shrink to fit and I'm displaying it again
and see what's happening here.
Notice it now the capacity is exactly six.
There's one more method I wanted to talk about we don't use it very often but some it's nice to know
that it's there it's reserve 100.
What you're doing here is you're reserving 100 spaces for elements contiguous in memory and of displaying
this memory is a vector again here.
And you can see right here the only differences right there.
This vector now has a capacity of 100 so it won't expand until it hits that hundred in one element.
All right so now let's take a look at test three I'll scroll both of these up again I've got my vec.
One two three four five.
I'm displaying it.
You can see it displaying right here and here all I'm doing is using the subscript operator and the
dot at Methot remember the subscript operator does no bounds checking the AT method does do bounds checking.
So if we exceed the bounds we get an exception.
So all I'm doing is I'm putting 100 here and I'm putting 200 here and I'm displaying the vector.
And you can see that's exactly what we expect.
So let's move on to test for.
And again I know these are a lot of examples.
But after doing this for many many years I think this is the best way to really learn this for test
for We've created Stooges is a vector of person objects.
Remember we created that person class earlier.
One is Larry and he's 18 that's a person that's display Stooges right now it should be empty.
Right.
There it is empty.
Now I'm going to push back the one that's Larry and display it again.
So now you can see that the Stooges vector has just one person in it.
Larry in this case I'm going to push back.
Mo mo Mo's 25.
I'm not creating a named object here so this is going to use move semantics and it's going to push the
back when I display again you can see that now I've got Larry and Moe.
And then the last example I'm using the place back and this is awesome as I said in the slides.
What we do here is we pass in the arguments that we put a passed into a construct you can see right
here right the name and the age and what it's going to do behind the scenes is actually call the constructor
for us and put curly at the back.
And then when I display again you can see I've got Larry Moe and Curly.
Let's move on to test five.
In this case I've got the Stooges vector again right here and I initialize it till they remount curly
and I'm displaying it and you can see it displaying right there.
You can see Larry Moe and Curly being displayed.
We can have the front method and we have a back method the front method returns a reference to the front
of the front element of the vector the back to the back element while the front one is Larry and the
back one is curly.
You can see front and back.
So when we display that we can see front is Larry back is curly.
We also have the pop back and it removes the element from the back of the vector for vectors.
When we insert and delete from the back it's very very efficient.
And that's typically how we use vectors.
So we're going to get rid of curly in this case and then display the Stooges and you can see here there
and moare there Curley's gone.
So here in test six there's my vector of integers 1 2 3 4 5 and I'm displaying it right there.
I can use the clear method to get rid of everything in the vector.
So I just removed everything and I'm displaying the vector right here.
It's empty.
I'm assigning those 10 integers to the vector and displaying it again.
You can see that being displayed right over here and now what I want to do is I want to use the erase
method to erase a piece of this vector.
So I'm going to say Veck Doddie race.
And where do I want to start at the beginning where do I want to stop right before that guy.
Begin plus two.
So here's VEC again.
Here's Veck begin plus two.
So what is going to do is going to get rid of those two elements.
And then when I display you can see right here the one in the two are gone great Now this example is
a little bit more complicated but it's really straightforward as well.
And just using a while loop here.
I'm assigning one through tend to the vector again and then I'm getting an iterator to the beginning
of it and I'm calling it I-T and all I'm doing is moving along that vector and if I see an even number
I'm deleting it or erasing it.
So in this case while I t is not equal to VEC and if what I'm pointing to with the iterator is even
then I'm erasing it.
Now I don't want to increase the iterator here right because I just erased is that would kind of skip
items.
Otherwise I do want to increase the iterator because I didn't see an even number.
And then when I'm done I just want to display that.
And you can see right there.
Vectors even numbers are all gone for test seven.
We've got two vectors and all we're going to do is swap them.
So here's VEC one.
Here's is to displaying both of them and you can see them right here.
Then I'm just saying to swap Veck one.
And I'm displaying those two again and you can see that they've swapped.
What's cool about vectors is they both have to be the same type in this example.
But they can be different sizes so it's a little different from the array that we saw intestate.
What we're doing is we're sorting.
So we've got a vector of a bunch of integers they are unsorted displaying that guy right here and you
can see test Raeder here testate.
So that's displaying the vector I'm calling the sort algorithm.
Veck one 1. again VEC want and are my iterators are the whole vector and then displaying it again and
it's sorted.
We can use reverse to sort it in reverse.
Let's take a look at this one this is really cool.
This is one of my misspelled that right here instructs.
This is one of my favorite insert or she use is called the back inserter.
So Michelle what's going on here.
What we want to do is we've got Veck one which is one two three four and five and we've got Vektor which
is 10 and 20.
So what I want to do is I want to basically insert one two three four and five right after the 10 and
20.
Now we can do with this a whole bunch of different ways.
But I wanted to show you the back inserter because it's a really really cool inserter to use.
First thing we do is this display the two vectors affect one vector.
Remember we're in test 9 so we're right here.
We just displayed them.
Now I'm going to use the copy algorithm put in we're going to copy one when a copy Veck one from Veck
one began to VEC one and some copying the entire vector one.
But where my copying it to vector to and I'm using this guy right here which is a really cool output
iterator called back inserter and what it'll do is it'll insert everything that's passed into it based
on vectors to what it's going to do.
Remember the sequence we're going to get is every integer in Veck one here that's what we're saying.
Each one of those is going to be passed into the back inserter and it's going it into the back of Veck
too.
So when I display Veck wanted to again the what happened right here.
See the 10 and the 20.
Now you see the one two three four and five.
This is really cool.
Let's do the same thing now except that's only copy if the elements are even.
So in order to do that we can start from scratch right here.
So here's my Veck one and two I'm displaying both of them you can see them being displayed right here
and then I'm saying copy if this is a little different from copy this as a predicate.
I'm going to copy from Veck one again to.
So sorry.
Let me say that again I'm going to copy from Veck one began to VEC one.
And that's why I'm copying from in other words the entire vector 1 and I'm copying it to vector 2 using
this back inserter.
Now we're all on a copy.
That's where the predicate comes in and we're doing it with a lambda.
So what does that say even.
Only right to zero.
So even only then I'm displaying these two guys again.
You can see right here I'm displaying VEC one hasn't changed but look at Vector.
It had a tenant of 20 but now it has the to the for the 68 and the 10 that came from Veck 1.
These two guys the back inserter and the copy in copy if really get to know those things and if you're
ever in a technical interview or a job interview and you're asked one of these questions blow the person
away by using this you'll get the job.
Trust me I do that all the time.
Just a couple of left here test 10 is a really interesting one we're going to use the transform algorithm
right here.
And the idea here is I've got these two vectors and I want to transform over both ranges.
So what I want to do is I want to transform over the ranges so I want the one in the 10 and the two
in the 20 and the three in the 30 in the four in the 40 and the 5 in the 50 being handled at the same
time.
So this is what's going on here I'm using transform and I'm starting at Veck Wannop began.
And I'm going all the way to the end of Veck one and I'm just starting at Vector began.
You don't have to say the end here because it's only going to do this five times.
This guy could be really long.
So what's going to happen.
Well I'm going to use my back inserter and insert the results of this into Veck 3 which is empty but
what am I inserting.
Well that's the really cool part.
This is going to be called this lambda here will be called with both the one in between the two in the
20.
So that would be X and Y and all I'm doing is multiplying them and then I'm putting those back into
Veck 3 using this back inserter.
So when I display Veck three you could see right here this is test 10.
Check it out 10 40 91 62 50 What is that.
Well that's one times ten is ten.
Two times twenty is forty three times 30 is 90.
You can see what's happening here.
This is really really neat.
We actually did a challenge that was similar to this when we did a raise way back when you could tweak
that to make this like a one liner.
It's not exactly the same but you can certainly get it to work that way.
All right.
And the last one is inserting and that would be test 11.
And that's where we're at right here.
We've got Veck 1 and VEC 2 VEC 1 is 1 through 10 and 2 is 100 200 300 400.
And what do we want to do.
We want to insert the contents of vector 2 into Veck 1 before that 5 right here.
So here I'm displaying the two vectors.
You can see them right here just as we would expect.
So how do I do this while I have to use an iterator to do this.
Remember it's not as efficient to insert things into the center of a vector as it is on the back of
the vector back is really efficient.
So what I'm doing here is I'm finding that 5 in Veck one right begin and the entire vector I'm finding
the 5 and I get back an iterator if the iterator is not equal to the end I found the 5.
Otherwise I display this.
So in this case I did find the five and I'm outputting inserting You can see that right here.
And then what I'm calling is I'm calling Veck one dot insert.
I'm passing in the iterator and I'm passing the sequence of elements I want to iterate to insert rather
the entire vector too.
So what that's going to do is it's going to insert all of VEC to be for the five.
And you can see right here one two three four.
Then there's Veck two and then five six seven eight and 10.
So that covers this lecture.
There's a lot here to understand.
Please take your time going through this.
Pause the video go back try some examples.
Make these your own and really learn from this.
That's the best way to do it.