Hello welcome to the first challenge of the tail section of the course.
Now I didn't give you any vector challenges because you've done quite a lot of vector challenges in
the course.
So we're going to start with a deck and I know a deck is new to most of you.
So I mean the Section 20 workspace and here you can see the challenge underscore one project and the
challenge under square one solution project the solution project obviously has my solution to this problem.
And the challenge under square one has the source code to get you started.
So let's talk about the challenge.
The challenge is all about using a deck so we know what a palindrome is some of you may not know what
a palindrome is a palindrome is a string that reads the same backwards or forwards.
So a simple example is Mme.
Bob Tuite radar and there's many many many more.
So these are words that read the same forwards or backwards.
Now we can have entire phrases can be palindromes for example a Toyota a Toyota a Santa at NASA a man
a plan a cad a ham a yak yam a hat a canal Panama.
All these are great examples of entire phrases that are palindromes for the purposes of this assignment
we're only going to consider alpha characters.
We're going to omit everything else so spaces.
Commas exclamation points and so forth that apostrophes as we see here will all be eliminated or omitted.
So when we read something like a Santa at NASA what we're going to convert that to is a Santa at NASA
like that all uppercase and get rid of all the special characters.
And obviously you know what to use.
You can use the CC type header file for that.
So how do you solve this problem.
Well a common method to solve the problem is to process the string you end up with something like that.
And then you reverse that string and you compare the two strings.
Obviously if the two strings are the same.
Right.
The one that's normal and the one reversed then it must be a palindrome.
But we're not going to do it that way we're going to use a deck.
I'm providing a main driver for you that will automatically run a bunch of test cases and your challenge
is to write one function.
The function is called is palindrome.
It returns a true false value and it expects a string.
So I'm going to send you a string and you're going to return true or false the function as I said determines
whether that string is a palindrome that function must take care of removing any spaces in any special
characters.
So here's a couple of examples.
Is palindrome a center at NASA that will return true.
Is palindrome.
Hello.
Should return false because hello is not a palindrome.
And what I'd like you to do is to use a deck to solve the problem.
After all that's the section we're in the ACL section of the end the deck is a perfect container to
help us solve this.
If you need a hint please post something in the Q and A forum.
This is a very common question that's used in coding interviews and a lot of times they'll start decoding
interview with.
Solve this problem.
The majority of the applicants will try to come up with the string reversal and compare and at that
point the interviewer will say could you use a data structure like a deck to do it.
And that gets a lot of people because all the books show you how to do it with reversing the string.
But it's interesting to do it with a deck.
Let me run my solution so you can see the sample output.
And here's a sample output.
I've got a result and I've got the string.
So in this case you could see a lowercase letter A is true.
A is true a B.A is true A B B is true.
These are all palindromes But obviously the A B is not a palindrome nor is the ABC radar and Bob and
Anna are as are all these more complicated phrases even C++ is.
Once we get rid of the plus plus we're left with a C.
That's definitely a palindrome.
OK so there's your test cases let me show you what your main would look like.
And this is the code that I'm providing for you.
This is the function you have to write.
Right here it's called is palindrome expects a stood string returns a boolean right now just returning
false.
You have to write this.
And here's the main.
I've got a vector of a bunch of strings and the strings are my test cases and that's it.
You shouldn't have to do anything in the main the main is basically going to loop through all of these
strings and call the palindrome method right there and pass the string into it you'll return TRUE and
FALSE in the main or display it.
So your job is to implement this function right here.
Remember use a deck.
OK so have fun.
Think about it it's actually a pretty simple problem and don't go crazy with iterators you don't have
to use any of that stuff.
Just use the front and the back of the deck.
That's what it's all about and when you're done you can come over to challenge one solution and meet
me in the next video.