OK so welcome back to the SPL challenge one solution.
I'm in Section 20 and I'm going to challenge one solution project and this is the project where we had
to write the palindrome function.
So hopefully you were able to solve this problem it's actually quite simple when you think about it
but.
So let's talk about it.
The idea is we're going to use a deck.
So the idea is let's say that we have a string like A B A A.
That's obviously a palindrome.
Right.
Reads the same from the front or from the back.
So what we then that's coming in here is my string.
So what I'm want to do is I want to create this deck of characters right here and I just want to push
these characters in to the deck.
Someone to grab that and I'm on a pushbacks are going to basically created a deck that looks like this
push the characters onto the deck.
And then what I'm going to do is I want to check the front of the deck and I'm going to check the back
of the deck grab whatever's there.
Compare them if they are the same then I process them.
Remove them and move on to the next ones.
Right.
Compare them.
They're the same and when I remove them at that point if I end up with an empty deck or a deck with
just one item in it then I know it's a palindrome.
It's as simple as that for something like let's say for someone that grabbed that string put it into
the deck.
I'm going to grab the first character here in the front.
I'm going to grab the last character here in the back.
There are not equal.
So there's no way this can be a palindrome so I'm outright there.
OK so let's walk through the code the actual code.
So now you know the algorithm is pretty straightforward.
So let's look at the code right here.
Here's the palindrome function.
And I've got a deck and I'm initializing it to an empty deck I'm just calling it d.
Then for each character in this string s if the character is an alpha.
Right.
So in other words it's not whitespace it's not a digit it's not special characters.
So if it's if it is alpha then what I'm going to do is I'm going to convert it to uppercase and push
it onto the deck and the back.
That's it.
So once this loop is done whatever was in the string is now in the deck minus the special characters
in the white space and everything else that's it.
Now I've got two variables here C1 and C2.
Those are the variables that I'm using to store what I'm reading from the front and from the back of
the deck.
And now I'm going to do something right here this is my loop.
It's really simple.
While the size of the deck is greater than one then I want to keep processing.
Once I hit 0 or 1 I'm done right.
It's got to be a palindrome.
So I'm asking the deck Hey give me your front element.
Give me your back element and I'm storing those and see one and see two I'm getting rid of those two
elements from the deck I don't need them there.
And then I'm comparing them.
So if someone is not equal to see two then the characters can't be the same there's no way this can
be a palindrome I'm returning false immediately.
If I get through the loop I'm returning true it's got to be a palindrome.
So that's it.
That's the solution.
And as I said this is a very common problem given in a coding interview and what the interviewer wants
is for the applicant to try to solve it a different way and then say oh by the way can you solve it
using a deck.
And that's that's it.
So you can see it's a real simple solution no iterators nothing fancy no algorithms are just using the
front and the back of the deck just like we're supposed to.
All right so I hope you enjoyed this challenge.