In this video we'll learn more about the SBL list and forward list containers.
These are both sequenced containers and store the elements in noncontiguous memory that will provide
direct access to elements via the app method or subscript operator.
But they're very efficient when we need to insert and delete elements in the lists.
Once an element is found let's first talk about the list and then we'll talk about the forward list
after.
In order to use the list container we have to include the list header file the list x is a doubly linked
list of elements so we can go from element to element in either direction.
Remember lists do not support direct element access.
The list has a front and a back and we can use all of the iterators but the iterators may become invalid
when deleting elements.
So let's see what a doubly linked list looks like conceptually
in this slide.
We see a diagram of what a simple list looks like.
Notice that the elements are not contiguous in memory and element has a reference to the element after
it and before it if they exist.
That's why it's referred to as a doubly linked list.
So there is some overhead involved with maintaining these links.
We declare L is a list of integers and initialize it to 1 2 and 3.
The list has a front and a back to front in this case is the element one and the back is the element
three with a list.
We can efficiently add or remove elements from the front and the back and we can also efficiently remove
insert elements from anywhere in the list.
All we really have to do is remove or insert development and then really the links to the other elements
around it.
Inserting and removing elements other than at the ends is very efficient.
But in order to do that we need to have an iterator to the element that we want to remove or insert
before.
This is usually done with the find method and it's done in linear time.
If you need a container where you will have lots of insertions and removals from the container and you
don't need direct access to the elements then the list is a good choice.
In the first example in this slide I declared L as the list of integers and initialized it to 1 2 3
and 4 in the second example I declared l 1 is a list of integers and I'm using an overloaded constructor
to create 10 integers and initialize them all to 100.
In the third example on declaring Stooges as a list of strings and initializing them withstood strings
and C-style strings like vectors stood array's index lists also support assignment via initializer list.
So let's see some other common methods provided by the list.
Let's start with the size method.
This method returns the number of elements that are in the list and max size tells us what the maximum
number of elements a list can contain.
Remember list do not allow direct access to elements so we can't use a subscript operator or the dot
at method.
These are not available for lists.
The list also provides front and back methods that return references to the element at the front and
the element at the back of the list.
In this example elde up front refers to one and elde up back refers to the five the list allows for
efficiently inserting elements at the back and at the front.
This is done with the push back method and the push front method.
We can also have pop back and pop front which he Fishell remove elements from the back or the front.
In this slide we have a list of person objects called L..
We can create a person P one named Larry who is 18 years old and we can use the pushback method to insert
the one at the back of the list.
We can also remove it using putback.
Similarly we can add a person object to the front of the list with push front and remove it with pop
front the list container also supports in place front and in place back which are efficient ways to
create and initialize objects that we want to store in the list right in place.
Inserting elements into a list works a little differently from what we've seen with other containers.
We can add a certain element before an existing element using the insert method but the insert method
expects an iterator that's referencing the element we want to insert before.
In this example L is a list of ints and I initialize L to 1 2 3 4 and 5.
Now I need an iterator to point to an element in the list.
We can do this lots of ways but let's use the Find function we can call fine with Elda begin l.com.
And we're looking for the three in this case the iterator I-T now is referencing the element 3 in the
list.
If we now call l.com insert in Pessin I-T which is the iterator and the number we want to insert in
this case 10 the 10 will be inserted very efficiently before the three the iterator will not be invalidated
it still references the 3.
Now if we call Ellicot erase and pass in the iterator the three will be removed from the list and the
iterator will become invalid.
Now this also allow resizing we can resize to a size of two in which case all the elements after the
second will be removed.
If we resize to a value larger than what we currently have the list will be expanded to that many elements
and the default initializer for the type of object the list contains will be called and those elements
stored in a newly created element.
So in this case if we resize L to 5 we'll add 3 new elements to the list and they'll all be initialized
to zero in this case because they are integers.
Finally how do we traverse a list.
We can use a range based for loop or we can use iterators since lists are bidirectional.
We can iterate in both directions.
So in this case we have a list L initialized to the end.
One two three four and five and we have an iterator I-T that will be referring to the three when we
dereference I-T and display the element.
We get a 3 when we dereference I-T and display the element we get a three then we can increment the
iterator and now refers to the four we can display the four in the same way.
Finally we can decrement the iterator and we get right back to the three.
Now let's see what some of the differences are between a list and a forward list
the forward list was added to the T.L. and C plus plus 11 in order to use the forward list.
We must include the forward list header file.
The forward list x is a singly linked list so the list can only be traversed in one direction.
The forward list incurs less overhead than the list but the downside is that we can only use it in one
direction.
But in many cases this is exactly what we want.
Similar to the list the forward list allows for rapid insertion and deletion of elements.
Once we have an iterator to one of the elements.
Also the forward list does not support direct element access as we'll see in a moment the forward list
has no concept of back only front.
It doesn't make much sense to get to the back of a list and then not be able to traverse backwards so
it's not available.
Obviously reverse iterators make no sense either so they're not supported.
So let's see what a forward list might look like in this slide.
We see a diagram of what a simple forward list might look like.
We declare L as a forward list of integers and initialize it to 1 2 and 3.
The forward list has only a front no back the front.
In this case is the element 1 with a forward list.
We can officially add elements to the front using push front.
You can see the pointers are going in only one direction so let's see some of the common methods used
with forward lists.
Let's start with the size method.
It's not available.
There's an interesting discussion about why the decision was made to not provide a size method if you're
interested let me know in the Q&amp;A and we can talk about it.
The max size will tell us the maximum number of elements the forward list can store.
Also notice that we have a front method but no back method.
In this case the front method returns a reference to the element 1.
Since the forward list only uses front and not back we have pushed front pop front and emplace front
available for quick insertion of elements at the front of the forward list.
So since the forward list has a singly linked list it makes sense to insert elements into the forward
list after an iterator reference.
So the forward list supports methods named explicitly like what they do in this example.
L is a forward list of the integers 1 2 3 4 5 and we have an iterator I-T that points to the three.
We can now use Ellicot insert after and pass in the iterator and the object we want to insert.
In this case the 10 will be inserted after the 3.
Notice that there are no insert in place erase method 0 called insert after and place after erase after
the iterator doesn't invalidate.
In this case it still points to the 3 so we can also use in place after any race after in the same way.
And the foodless allows resizing in the same way that the list does.
OK so let's head over to the ID and we'll see some examples using a list and then we'll have a challenge
exercise using a list OK.
BECK any idea I mean the section 20 workspace and I mean the list project and what I'd like to do here
is do the same thing we've been doing the previous videos go over some examples of using the list container.
Now there's a couple of differences here.
One is I'm including this iterator header file here and that's for this advanced function.
I'll talk about that in a second.
It basically allows us to advance an iterator.
We can't really do a plus equals or minus equals on list iterators but we can advance them using the
advanced function.
So I'll say that when I get to it we have the person class that we've had before.
And in this case the only difference from the person class that you've seen before is the default constructor
before we just use the default way that the compiler generated for us here I want the name to be unknown
and I want the H to be zero when nothing is provided and you'll see why in a little bit when we resize
a list it creates objects by using a default and want you to see those that were in that age so you
can actually see when that happens.
Other than that it's exactly the same.
I've got the overloaded constructor here.
I am overloading the less than operator and equality operator.
Those are the two real important operators for the SPL and I've got a friend insertion operator right
here for a stream insertion.
All right.
I've got a template function right here that allows me to display any list of any type.
So the template parameter is t that's being replaced.
Again you've seen this before with Tex and vector so it's just another example here with a list.
So let's go through these examples.
I've got some tests here and I'm start with test one or you can see the output over here as I said I've
already run this so the test is right there.
That's where we're at right now.
Here we're creating a list of integers and you can see the syntax is exactly as you would expect.
I hope that by now you're seeing these patterns right and it's not like oh my goodness in order to use
a list I've got to learn all this new stuff.
The patterns are the same if you know how to use a deck you know how to use a vector you know how to
use a list.
It's just a matter of going to the documentation and see the nuances in the specifics for each container.
But the general patterns are the same.
So in this case I'm creating one as one two three four five and I'm displaying.
You see that being displayed right here and now creating L2 as a list of strings.
And what I'm doing is I'm pushing back to the back and front to the front and then a display and you
can see exactly what you can expect to remember a list has a back and it's got a front.
So we're taking advantage of that.
It's very efficient inserting on both ends.
Here I'm creating three is a list of integers and I'm using the assignment using the initializer list
just like we've done with the other containers and then I'm displaying all three.
And you could see it right there.
And then we're using the same constructor that we've used before and again I know this is becoming old
hat but I do I'm doing this.
There's a method to my madness I'm doing this on purpose so you can see the consistency between all
these containers.
So that's the constructor.
We've got 10 100s and then we're displaying all four of the 10 100s.
Okay perfect.
So let's move on to the second test.
And that's right.
Here you can see the output right over here.
In this case I've got l as a list of integers from 1 through 10 AM initialising and I'm displaying it.
There's the display right there.
What's the list size.
Well it's 10 What's the front the front is the one what's the back.
The back is the 10.
Remember these are references we're getting to them so we can actually change them if we like.
There's the sizes 10 in the front the back.
We can clear the list.
That removes all the elements from it and display it again.
Now it's empty and its size is zero so you can see right there.
Again very very consistent.
So let's look at that.
Take a look at test the.
And artistry has a couple of things that are going to be different for a list.
Here's Elle and we're displaying L which is one through 10.
You can see right here is test three.
And right there is the one through the 10.
Now what we're saying is let's resize this to five.
So what happens here.
What's going to resize it to five.
Basically it's going to stop it right here and all this is gone.
So at this point if I display Well you can see one two three four five here in the output.
Now this is interesting.
If I resize it to 10 what's going to happen well it says remember right now it's 1 2 3 4 and 5.
So he's going to resize it to five new elements.
One two three four five.
But what's it going to put in there.
What it's going to do it's going to call the default initialize for each one of those objects for integers
and for primitive types it's 0.
So you're going to get something like that when I display it.
That's exactly what we see.
One two three four five and five zeros.
But when we have object types it's a whole different story.
In this case that what I'm doing have created persons is a list of person objects right now it's empty.
But if I resize it to five.
Now I've got five person objects.
Which ones does it create.
It uses the default constructor for them.
So if I display it you can see those strings that I talked about earlier in the person class.
Unknown age 0 unknown age 0.
It's exactly what's happening.
This is one of the things that I talked about I think at the beginning of this section was it's very
important when we use the ACL that we overload the less than that we overload the equality operator
that we overload the default constructor.
This is why this is a real important reason why if we provide an overloaded constructor and we don't
provide the default constructor this will error out because the default constructor wouldn't be provided
for us so we've got to be sure that we we've got all our bases covered there tests for let's have a
list here of integers 1 through 10 and display it you can see test for is right on here I should scroll
that up just a little bit so it's a little easier to see if we up.
So here's test for.
Those are my integers 1 through 10.
That's where I'm at right here.
Now I've got an iterator and obviously I'm using auto But obviously if I had to declare that the long
way it would be stood list.
Iterator I.
But in this case the compiler is deducing it based on the return value of the find.
So what am I doing.
I'm finding that 5 in L from beginning to end.
So my iterator I-T is going to be pointing to 5.
Now I know it's there but it's good practice to check.
So if I-T is not equal to the end that means I found it and what I want to do is I want to call the
insert method on the list L and I want insert a 100 where I need the iterator that stop.
This is really important with lists both list and forward list.
So what do I need that iterator the iterator is pointing to the 5 in the case of a list it's going to
insert the 100 before the iterator so it's going to stick 100 right in there.
And then when I display the list you can see right here that the 100 has been inserted between the four
and the 5 right to the left or previous or before the iterator everyone to think about it.
In this case I've got L2 which is a list from 1000 2000 3000.
And now what I'm doing I'm inserting into L member L is this guy right here now it's male is one two
three four then 100 and then five six seven eight nine and ten.
That's L right here.
So what I'm doing is I mean I remember my iterator still pointing to the five it's not invalid because
I haven't deleted it so my iterator is still pointing right here.
So what I want to do is I want to say I want to insert into El starting at that iterator right here
to the left of the iterator What do I want insert I want I insert the entire list L2 from beginning
to end.
So do you think that's going to do right in here it's going to put in 1000 2000 and 3000 and it's in
a do that super efficiently.
Then when I display this here again you can see what's happening.
One two three four.
There's your Hundred and then 1000 2000 3000.
And then the five Where's iterator pointing to now still pointing to the five it's still valid.
OK let me clear this because as a lot of stuff here and this is the advanced function that I was talking
about this is in the iterator header file.
So what we can do here is we can advance any iterator positive or negative assuming it's a bi directional
iterator in this case it is.
There's my iterator and I want to advance at minus 4.
So remember iterator was pointing to the 5 right.
So now the 5 is over here.
I want to move it four to the left.
One two three four it's going to be pointing to the hundred.
That's what the advance lets me do I can also do positive for obviously are positive 2 or anything I
want.
So in this case it's going to be pointing to the 100.
If I display what is pointing to there's 100 and then I can say l dot erase I t.
What's that going to do it's going to erase the element that the iterators point to that I'm displaying
it again you could see the 100 is gone.
At this point my iterator becomes invalid.
I just deleted the element it was pointing to.
So don't use that iterator again if you need it.
Reset it ok.
Test four is good.
Now let's take a look at test five in test five we'll do a couple of things to test five just has a
couple of pieces of input you'll see here it's actually waiting for me to type something in.
So we'll do that in a second in test five.
I've got Stooges which is a list of person objects and initializing it to Larry Moe and Curly and I'm
displaying them that remember the person class overloaded the stream insertion OPERATOR So that's what's
happening here and I'm displaying them that's what I've got right here Larry Moe and Curly.
Now I've got a couple of variables here.
Name and age and what I want to do is I want to ask the user to enter the name of the next stooge and
then enter their age and let's do that right now when to type in right in here I'm just going to type
in James and let's say that James is 50 years old.
Now when I press enter what's going to happen is we're coming right in here online 1:30 right here and
I'm in placing back and I remember here I'm not creating an object here.
I'm letting the list create the object for me that's what the emplace does.
So what's going to happen is James 50 is going to be passed into this method.
This method will create that stooge object and inserted at the back for me.
So when I press Enter I'll display Stooges and I should see James 50 at the back right in here right
after Curly.
So let's do that.
Let me come over here.
I'll press enter and you can see now that we've got Larry Frank Moe Curly and James right at the back.
Super efficient.
And then the last thing we want to do here is we want to insert Frank before Mo.
OK.
So where is Mo I need to find it.
So I need an iterator that's going to point to Mo.
I'm a search stooges from beginning to end and I'm looking for that object.
What's it going to use.
Operator equality operator which I've overloaded.
So it's going to look from Moe 25 mo 25 is right here.
I know it's there.
So my iterator if it's not equal is to just then I found it.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to insert at that iterator before the iterator everything on the
list happens before the iterator I'm going to insert Frank 18 and then I want to display Stooges again
and you can see right here Frank 18 is right before the mo.
Which is exactly as I expected.
All right.
And then the last test is test six and this one's pretty cool.
What we're doing is sorting real real simple.
So in this case I've got Stooges is a list of persons and I've got Larry Moe and Curly.
I'm displaying Stooges.
And you can see it right here Larry Moe and Curly that I'm sorting it.
I'm saying Stooges not sort of displaying it again.
And look what happened.
Curly Larry Moe what operators being used here operator less than we overloaded that and what we're
doing and our operator less than let me go back in case you didn't don't remember the our operator less
than it's comparing ages.
So here we've got 17 18 and 25.
That's how we decided that we were going to sort out we're not sorting by name.
We could have we could have written this name but we decided oh well let's sort by age.
So this is going to sort by that.
OK.
So that's it in the next video we'll do a challenge well we'll simulate a music player using a link
but it's.