In this video we'll learn about the T.L. set containers.
These are associate of containers associate of containers or collections of stored objects that allow
for fast retrieval using a key.
The seal provides both sets and maps.
In this video we learn about sets and we'll learn about maps in the next video depending on the type
of the soci container.
They're usually implemented behind the scenes as a balanced binary tree something like a red black tree
or as a hash that these are very efficient data structure.
So operations on sets and maps are very fast.
The ACL has four types of set containers the set the unordered set the multiset and the unordered multiset
will focus mainly on the set.
Since it's the one most often used but also described the others as well.
Let's first talk about the set in order to use a set you must include the set header file.
The class is similar in concept to a mathematical set.
The elements in the set are ordered by key and no duplicate elements are allowed.
All iterators are available for sets.
Let's initialize a few set objects in the first example in this slide.
I declare s as a set of integers and initialize it to 1 2 3 4 and 5.
And the second example I declare Stooges as a set of stood Strange's and I initialize it to some strings.
Then at the bottom of the slide you can see that sets also support assignment via an initialization
list.
But there are some differences with sets on the first line commercialising S is a set of integers and
then providing the initializers.
But notice that the initializer list contains duplicate elements that's not allowed in a set.
This won't cause an error there.
The duplicates are simply ignored and we end up with a proper set.
Also notice that the set is sorted the size method returns a number of elements that are in the set
and max size tells us what the maximum number of elements a set can hold.
Remember sets do not allow direct access to elements so we can't use the subscript operator or the method
as we have with other containers sets also don't have a front and back.
So methods like push back and pop back into front versions do not apply to sets.
So how do we add elements to sets.
Simple we use the sets insert method.
We can also use the emplace method if we want.
In the last statement on the slide we insert 7 into the set.
If 7 is in the set it won't be added again.
If it's not in the set then it will be added and or will be added in order.
So let's talk a little bit more about the insert method.
Suppose I have an object P1 that's a person object.
In this case Larry 18.
I also have to as a person object mo 25 we can insert P1 into the Stooges set by simply calling Stooges
insert and passing in P..
If the element is not in the set it will be added.
Otherwise it won't be added.
The set class uses the overloaded less than operator to determine if the element exists in a set.
That's fine but sometimes we want to know whether an element was inserted successfully or not.
The insert method returns a string pair remember where we talked about it a few times in this section
and we'll talk about it some more and the maps video as well.
The pair object that's returned has its first attribute as an iterator to the element that we just inserted
or an iterator to the duplicate element that's already in the set and then the second attribute is a
Boolean that indicates whether the operation was successful or not.
That's pretty cool.
Now we have all the information we need and we can do whatever we need in our program.
We can also erase elements in a set very easily estat erase three will erase the 3 and the set as if
it exists.
We can use the set find method to find the five and if it exists delete it by passing the iterator to
the erase method.
Notice that the set's fine method is different from the find function in the as T.L. algorithms library.
You should use the sets find because this sets fine knows all about the internal implementation of the
set and it's going to be much more efficient.
Finally we can use the count method to see how many times an element appears in a set.
If you think about that it doesn't make a lot of sense right.
I mean a set can only have an element in there once at most.
But in this case it's real handy to tell whether an element is in the set or not.
For get back to zero we know it's not in the set.
If we get back a one it isn't the set we're going to use this in multiset because multi sets can have
duplicates.
So this method is really useful there as well.
Finally as with all other ACL containers as not clear removes all of the elements from the set and estat
empty returns true if the set is empty or false otherwise.
Well that's a quick summary of the set class.
Please refer to the set documentation since there is more.
And many of the methods I show you have variants as well.
So let's talk about the other set classes.
First let's talk about the multiset class.
It's also defined in the set header file.
A multiset is a set that's ordered by key but it allows duplicate elements all iterators are available
the unordered set is in the unordered set header file the ordered set is a set that's unordered and
it does not allow duplicate elements due to the way that unordered sets are implemented.
Elements can't be modified in place.
If you need to change an element you have to remove it and then insert the updated one also.
Unordered sets do not allow reverse iterators.
The last type of set provided by the ACL is the unordered multiset the unordered multiset does not order
elements and it does allow duplicates.
Again no reverse iterators are allowed.
As you can see the SL provides powerful set classes for nearly every need.
However by far the most used is the set.
And that's when we're going to focus on.
So let's head over to the idea and we'll look at examples of using sets.
Ok so I'm back on the idea again I'm in the Section 20 workspace and I'm in the set project and what
I've got here is I've got the same person class and I won't bother going over it again we've gone over
to a bunch of times.
I have made any changes to it since the last time but I do want to bring that to your attention again.
The operator that we're using for the operator less than is comparing ages.
OK so we're considering one person less than the other based on the age not the man and that's going
to be important because the set uses that operator.
So when we see these guys sort of you're going to see them sorted by age rather than by name.
And that's important understand a lot of people think that it's this operator right here that's doing
it and it's not OK.
So let's get started.
There's four tests or actually three tests here.
Some Not as long as the other videos but let's start with Test 1 and you can see the output right up
here.
On the right up here you can see that's where the test one is right here.
So let's start.
I'm going to create a set called S1 and you can see it's a set of integers.
You can see this the consistency with the syntax across the entire as well.
And I'm putting in 1 4 3 5 2.
Notice I did that on purpose had changed the order.
The sets are ordered by default.
So when I display a swan you can see that it's being displayed in order in this case it had your order.
If I had to put in the Stooges with ages then we get a different order.
I'm doing that in the next test and this example here I'm assigning this initializer list to us 1.
But notice there are duplicates in here right.
Just to piss all over the place here.
Diplomats aren't allowed in sets.
This will still work.
This works just fine.
When I go to display a swan you can see that duplicates were not handled of course there omitted.
So it's not going to add duplicates to a set that's not going to allow duplicates.
Then we've got right here we're inserting 0 and we're inserting 10 and then we're displaying it again
and you can see that right there is the output.
You can see the zero at the beginning and the 10 at the end.
So there were inserted where they should have been inserted which is exactly right.
Now let me just scroll up here just a little bit and we're right about here on line 50 I'm seeing how
many times has 10 occur in the list.
This is going to return an integer.
It's either going to return 0 or 1 in this case of a set because a set either has the element in it
or not.
There is the multiset which allows multiple entries right duplicates.
In that case this could return two or three or four depending on how many times that element exists.
But in this case I'm saying is the 10 in the list is either return a 1 or 0 1 being true 0 being false.
So 10 is in the set or 10 is not in the set.
We know 10 is in this set because we just added it right here.
So I expect to get back 10 is in the set.
And now I'm using the find method here I'm using as one find them that I'm not using stood find which
is in the algorithms library I'm using the set's version of find a lot of people use the other one.
The other one is a very generic type fine that's going to use an iterator and just search through the
entire set.
This guy is real smart.
This one understands how the set is implemented.
Behind the scenes.
So if it's implemented as a balanced binary tree it's going to use it's going to be pretty smart about
finding things.
So let's find the five in the set is the five in there.
Absolutely it's in there right here.
So what are we going to do.
We're going to assign the results of that.
Iterator if we get back the end of the set.
Obviously it wasn't there.
If we don't get it back then we found the five and with pointing to it.
So that's what we got right here we know it's in there and that's what we got back.
We can clear the set and then display it again and obviously that clears out the set just like it does
with all the containers.
OK.
So there you go.
Hopefully the consistency is paying off.
Like I said there was a method to my madness with all of these examples.
Usually when you see a lot of them and more and more you'll see the pattern and it just really clicks.
So now let's see the test to what we've got here is a set of person objects and we'll call them Stooges
and we said the person had a name or an age.
I just put one two three here because I want to show you the order that these are going to be put in.
So now when I display stooges look at them right here.
That's the order Larry one Motu Kerley 3.
Notice that it's ordering by age 23 it's not ordering by name otherwise Curly would be the first one.
Right.
So that's important.
Understand it's using operator less than to do the ordering.
All right.
So that's what it's using right here.
So we can emplace James 50 and we can display the Stooges again and you can see that at this point James
50 was added at the end because the 50 is what it's using to order.
So this really drives the point home.
Suppose I went to emplace Frank 50.
It won't let me because it's using the 50 to decide whether to put it in there or not.
So it's according to this that 50 is already in there.
Now had I checked to see that the that the less upward or less than was the name and the key and the
age I'm sorry then this would have definitely worked.
But when I display it again right here there's no Frank in there as far as this is concerned it already
exists.
All right so now we've got a couple of more output statements.
Scroll up a bit and I'll show you how these work in this case.
I'm finding Moe two in the list.
I know Motu is there.
I'm going to get an iterator back and if it's not equal to the end of the list then what I'm going to
do is erase mo.
That's all I'm doing.
And that display Mowlam me racing mode that I'm displaying Stooges.
And you see right here that MO right there is gone.
Which is kind of cool.
Now this is the one that really shows you have the power that operator in this case I'm finding a person
whose name is X and whose age is 50.
This doesn't come into play because I'm not using that in my in my overloaded less than operator.
So it's going to find James there at 50 and it's going to erase James.
And then I display Stooges again and you can see that James is gone.
This gets a lot of people when you're first starting out with the T.L. a lot of these containers some
of them use quality some of them use less than the set uses the less than so be aware of that.
The final test is this guy and this is important one because it shows you what happens when we insert
some data into a set.
Let's just start up here first.
I'm creating a set of stood strings and it's called this and I'm putting in there ABC.
Now obviously we're using strings so it's going to use the string order to sort of display as and you
can see ABC right here display.
I see you know what that means scroll that up just a little bit.
So it kind of aligns a little better.
There we go.
So we're displaying ABC right here.
Now I'm inserting the D and I'm displaying.
And you can see the D has been inserted in here.
But notice at this time I assign the return value of the insert method to this guy right here.
Result.
And I'm using auto what I'm getting back here is a stupid pair.
Remember this pair has two attributes first and second.
In this case first is an iterator that's pointing to either the D that we just inserted or the D.
That's already a duplicate in there that didn't allow me to insert in either case I'm getting an iterator
to the element that I'm inserting or it's copy that's already in there.
Hopefully that makes sense.
Then the second part of the pair the second attribute is going to have a boolean true false was the
insertion successful.
So I've changed this to Alfonso displays the true false value.
And here I'm displaying first and we expect to see it right there.
So we either got a D that we inserted or the deal that was already there.
That's when we look here.
So if this guy's true it is right here.
That means our insertion was successful.
Had it been false that means that I already had a duplicate in there can or can be a little confusing
but it's it makes sense when you think about it.
And this is pretty cool if you think about it what's going on here is I've got a return from a function
that's returning multiple items right which is kind of neat.
It's really wrapping it up into a one pair.
But even so I has to get to those pieces of the pair.
Some other functions return tuples which can have even more than two.
OK so let's do that last one right here.
And in this case I am inserting the a in a right here.
This is where I'm at right now inserting the in and displaying s.
Now the 8 was already in there some displaying it right here and now what I'm doing is what's first
what first was the A It's the iterator is pointing to the A that was already there.
That's why I'm getting that.
And when I display the results with the second that should be now I'm getting the faults.
So right here I know that that insertion was not successful because there was a duplicate in there are
any.
So that covers that's what we're going to do in the next video as cover maps and then the challenge
for the sets and the maps is going incorporate using sets and maps together which is kind of cool.
All right.
So in the next video we'll talk about maps.