Welcome back everyone.
Good to see you here again.
In this slide and lecture I want to cover machine learning workflow.
This is one of the key slides that I have to help you in terms of developing a successful and also working
machine learning model that works for you.
Now the first and foremost is this is one of the most crucial step is to define the problem that you
are facing and your definition of the problem.
Define how big a data set you need.
If you do not define your problem properly you may come across a situation whereby you need to collect
a lot of data and the actual training itself will take a long long time.
I'll just give you an example as to to help you understand and appreciate this point.
If I'm training a neural network to distinguish between cats and dogs and pandas then all I need to
do is collect datas for these three types of animals.
But if I want a neural network model that's able to actually tell or distinguish all the different animals
in the world.
You can very quickly see the scale of the problem and how much work you do need to do and whether it
is.
Of course there's the secondary context secondary the second considerations that you need to think about
is that why do you need to easily have a neuron network that actually able to distinguish all the animals
into all including animals in the sea and also deep sea as well.
If you put it in that perspective then it might not make any sense to actually pursue that line of of
of model constructions.
So you need to actually be very clear of the problem that you're actually trying to define here.
If you're just trying to build a model to distinguish cats and dogs for a pet or for a veterinarian
then it's a different story altogether and that that would be a substantially easier model to view and
much faster and to put it into production in a much shorter time as well.
So then lies the key part here is to define your problem your problem definitions what kind of a problem
it is which is the second step.
Is it a binary classification a multi class classification regression clustering or reinforcement learning
understanding your problem is crucial on how to to determine what the next step is.
So I also do have the necessary data and is it easy to get hold of these data.
Some of these some data and often a lot of data are really expensive and difficult to acquire.
Do you have the means to do so if it's for business.
Do you know then it may make sense and but you also have to consider other issues such as data privacy
and ethics offered and also a regulatory constrains.
And these are all the things that need to keep in mind.
The next thing is you have to choose a measure of success.
What kind of success.
Performance measurement or metrics do you use.
Do you use accuracy which is what we have been doing so far or is they are the better means such as
position and recall OCA you see these or apply in different situations.
So those are the things that you need to keep in mind as well.
And the next one is decide on an evaluation protocol hold our validation set or carefully cross validation
really cover this at length.
So I want to draw that out anymore and the next one is data preparation and pre processing.
The part is also clear.
The fifth one is develop a model that performs better than baseline and the next one.
Next step Step six is to scale up develop a model that intentionally over fits.
That's when you start to regularize Step 7 and 2 and you'll have a pair of meetings.
So those are the seven steps to two in building machine learning.
And this is a workflow that is as a reference and that's useful.
This is provided by Charlotte and hope that has been useful.
Thank you once again for watching and really appreciate you for following me all along.
This journey.