Welcome back everyone.
And this session we're going to move into transfer learning right.
One of the things that we've done so far is that we've trained a model a simple one at that and we've
turned trained to identify cats and dogs.
That's all very well.
Of course you can start using it to apply to other pictures of dogs and cats.
The natural question then is this if others have run similar training and if they have done training
on massive massively large image data set and obtain state of the art accuracy can we use their model
for predicting pictures or classifying cats and dogs and all the other animals as well.
The answer turns out to be a resounding yes and that's core transfer learning.
That's what we actually going to go and dig into this is really exciting for you because now you get
the benefit of utilizing trainings that's been done by Google's Facebook and utilized the model that
they share.
And out in the open open sourced for you to actually apply to your day to day use or your business use.
And it turns out to be highly effective.
So this way we actually going to going to have look at it now.
So that's the basic ideas of transfer learning and the file that we're going to look at is called cats
and dogs.
But underscore transfer.
And it's called learning.
So let's dig into that right now.
So this is the file we're still working with cats and dogs.
And let me just pull up our previous training so that you can actually have a reference recall that
we last did the data augmentation.
Let's put this up.
Let me pull up the performance so that you can actually have a comparison.
We after 100 epochs we reach about 80 percent in terms of follow more like eighty four percent in terms
of validation 83 82.
OK just eighty three as high as we weigh whether we observe in terms of validation accuracy.
So let's see if we can actually do likewise if we actually apply this.
Now remember we did talk about veggie 16 and we're going to make use of that once again the usual and
we just walk through the coat with you important umpire in both pandas against TV to implant.
Oh these are exactly the same.
The rose is 128 and importing always and as has utility for data copy.
So these codes are exactly the same.
No change.
We're still working with four thousand data sets training data sets.
Two thousand cards two thousand dogs and 500 validation for both cats and dogs so that means a thousand
pictures of cats and dogs.
Right.
From Karas.
The good thing about Chris is that there are some built in models rigid you 16 is one of them.
And we're going to instantiate a model call using veggie juice extend that's already available in the.
So we're going to call that model is it could do veggie 16 and have a look at the.
So call veggies
architecture.
All right.
So this is a summary of the architecture.
We have the input there's the original sizes two to four.
That's OK.
And then we have to convolution layer and it makes pulling lamb another two more convolution layer another
makes pulling Layer 3 convolution Layer 1 next pool trick convolution one makes for treacle solution
one next for finally flatten to density connected or fully connected.
Dense layer and prediction there's 1000 classes because divided you was originally trained on 1000 data
sets or classes of pictures.
Right.
OK.
So we are removing the so-called top the top are the so-called two fully connected layer including the
prediction.
So when we actually now look at it not just that it stops at the block five pulling layer and there's
no fully connected layer of flatten fully connected layer at all.
OK.
So right again this part is we are importing the from Kerry's should this line of code is unnecessary
from Kerry's.
We import David G G 16.
We are using from the layers import completion to D makes pulling to the global average pulling flatten
dens and drop out and also carers and top model.
Right.
If you look at this.
This is the key part here we are in a way you can call it performing a surgery on our models looking
carefully what you notice is that we are actually removing a few items we have removed the flatten the
fully connected layers.
OK.
And the question now is that if we have removed those.
How does our model actually perform predictions of the cats and dogs.
This is where we actually I'm going to show you but the base model is going to base on a B Jiji 16 and
the weights of the of the neural network is based on based on what was the originally changing which
is the image in it.
OK.
The image net is the massive database that's provided by Stanford to train all the images and we are
removing the top meaning those two connected layer has been removed and the input shape is this at 1
2 8 by 1 2 8.
So that's the model and we store the output to the variable x and then we're performing what's call
a global average pulling in and basically after the base model we apply a global average pulling instead
of Max pulling and followed by a densely connected layer and followed by the prediction layer which
is sigmoid.
In this case rather than soft Max sigmoid being two class problems.
Are the binary one that we've looked at before and that's it.
And we instantiate our model by input being the base model which is the Virgin G 16 and the output as
the prediction that we've defined based on these four lines here.
All right.
The images connect this force so that you can actually clearly see they are connected this way and we
have to loop through each of those layers that we looked at before all of these plot 1 2 5 here and
set it to no training OK.
So we're looping through them and have all the weights that's already been pre-teen pre train frozen.
OK so that's what this laser dot chain equals two false means do not train them because we want to retain
or borrow the learnings from that was done from the original image OK.
So the next thing is that we do need to compile our model.
This is the same as what we've done so far followed by these we're not doing any data augmentation here.
So everything is is exactly as it was before and now is the training.
OK we're training instead of 30 now 50 epoch.
Just to compare and let's have a look at the performance down here.
All right.
Right.
So looking at this I'll let you take a moment to breathe it in look at the validation accuracy the training
accuracy is almost a hundred percent the validation accuracy It's around ninety five percent Yes ninety
five percent and that's really why this is so powerful and it's so crucial to actually take note of
the so-called validation accuracy in terms of the predictability or predictive power of prediction of
this transfer learning the training losses around point eight.
It's a little higher than the model but that's OK because we actually have a very large model with lots
of flexibility so that the so-called Lost bounce would be a little bit on the higher side.
But more importantly is this accuracy score here both the training accuracy is really high and the validation
accuracy is really high as well.
And the conclusion that you can only draw all of these is this it means that prior training prior learning
that is done by this architecture which is rigid 16 him 16 stands for 16 layers is useful in the task
that we're trying to solve here which is trying to separate out cat versus dogs and that's therein lies
the one key lesson that I want to share with you is is this is a really powerful technique called transfer
learning and hopefully that impresses upon you to actually use this technique even more.
A big part of it is because most of us don't have the computational power or ability like Google Facebook
and the likes the tech companies have done all this training they've outsourced it.
If you are a small medium enterprise you can actually leverage on this and run with it and you will
solve most of the problems that you have.
Of course there are some constraints.
If these are all the trains or animals and you try to use it to identify cars or machine parts it might
not perform so well it ought to be that they are in similar few and highly encourage you to look into
this a little bit more just to actually learn how you can you can protect potentially users in your
day to day problem and some of the business problem that you may face with that I'm going to stop.
Thank you once again for watching.