Welcome back.
So what exactly is a deep learning.
Now before we embark into the details of deep learning I want to compare and contrast between the classical
programming and also machine learning now.
Machine learning is a bigger space or a subset and deep learning is a smaller subset of machine learning.
So the purpose of the next slide which is this one here is to help you to understand the difference
between what the classical programming versus machine learning is.
Now classical programming quite often requires a couple of things you need the data.
And on top of it the rules.
These are usually rules written by experts.
You can understand it as if then statements.
So it could be a very very long if then statement.
And that's where you actually get the answer being provided to you the user of the system quite often.
These are called expert systems back in the 80s and even in the early 90s.
So basically the the idea of classical programming is that the S2 data come in the rules provided by
human which is converted into software codes will provide the answer to the user's now.
Machine learning comes from a different paradigm or angle.
It requires data just like classical programming but it dates not rules but answers answers can come
in the form of image or labels or Target.
So the answers provided to the machine learning algorithm as well as the data.
Now from there the machine learning algorithm learned the patterns and decipher it uncover the patterns
and generate those rules by itself.
Now this is where the human intervention part is not included.
The actual understanding and learning part is done by the machine learning hence the term machine learning
algorithm and that's the foundational idea and the difference between classical programming and machine
learning classical programming needs constant human intervention as the world that it actually deals
with evolves new rules need to be written whereby a machine learning because it's supposed more the
angle is to generalize once it learned for example the picture of cards it ought to be able to actually
identify cards even though it hasn't seen cards before.
The image of that or the type of this specific cat before a specific breed before it should be able
to and ought to be able to pick out that it is a cat and that's really where the exciting part of the
machine learning algorithm comes in is that it can and continue to evolve because of the generalization
that it has learned from previous data.
And the other part of all that's exciting about machine learning is that it can continue to evolve and
change and continue to learn as new data come in.
Of course you can have it learning all the time or learning on once a day learning on a monthly basis
so basic that those are the flexibility in terms of the production or goal life system by classical
programming.
It's not the same.
You will not be able to do that.
I just won't allow you to actually while constantly change that part requires the human intervention
to come in so there's the three key difference between classical programming and machine learning.
Now with that I'm going to stop this lesson in the next lesson.
We're going to go into the how does machine actually learn and we're going to talk about this concept
called Learning representation from data.
With that I'm going to stop here.
Thank you once again for watching.