Welcome back everyone.
We're going to start looking at the actual architecture of a neural network.
We're going to start with something that a little bit more complex.
This is a simplified neural network but it's much more complex than the one that we just coded up in
cold.
Looking at there as you can see that there are three layers.
There is the input layer.
There is the hidden layer and there is the output layer.
So let me walk through them one by one the employers are the features.
Okay.
In our example previously we only have one feature.
So in that case you probably represent it as x 1 in this neural network architecture.
There are three input.
Okay so this x1 x2 as far as extreme moving on to the next layer which is called the hidden layer.
The reason is called hidden layer is because it's not exposed to the input neither is it each day exposed
exposed to the output hands.
It is the hidden layer.
Now with the hidden layer we don't actually we don't have any direct influence of the hidden day itself.
And the output layer is the output of our machine learning model.
And that's the layer that actually provide the outcome of all machine learning prediction.
So if you look at this the upper layer has one output meaning it would generate one single value.
So if you look at the whole architecture of this neural network it takes three inputs and will come
up with one output.
The other thing that I want to actually highlight is notice that the lines they each layer this layer
each input is connected to the next layer fully.
Hence this is also sometimes called the fully connected layers.
And this layer is also called the dense less dense network.
And likewise for this as well.
And let me just walk through in terms of the mathematics of this.
You don't need to understand this because you don't need to actually calculate it will be all done by
extensive flow the estimation the computation will be all done by intensive flow.
We start with the N1 which is this neuron here and it takes the input from x1 x2 expel x3.
So these tree mut and X1 is multiplied by the weight of 1 1 which is this represented by this line here
and X2 is multiplied by W2 of x3 is multiplied by W. 13 and then plus advised him B1 here stands for
buys them much as same concept as the intercept in the Y is good and makes plus see from your high school
all right.
So the W eleven the beauty of and W thirteen are in the beginning as I mentioned in the previous lesson
is that these weights are randomized okay when it's first the algorithm doesn't know what's the right
way in which is initialized with any random weights and then or just compute the N1 likewise for N two
as well the result of N1 and end to is being provided as an input to 4 and 3.
So if you look at the formula right here is represented right here here entry is takes in the input
from n 1 and multiplied by another weight and then 2 is multiplied by another weight plus another bias
I'm looking at this you can see that this is actually a much more complex representation of our so-called
propose problem the problem that we all originate and this which was why is the three x plus fifty there's
only one input and there's only again one so called slope plus one intercept that we needed to estimate
but when you look at this there are three inputs obviously it's it's not a problem that there is representation
of the problem that we proposed and is far too complex to represent our problem anyway and is likely
to not what it will be over q and we'll give you a false answer as well so let's look at something much
simpler that we caught up in our coal lab earlier and this is the model that we propose and then compile
and fit as well.
For with this what we have was one input layer which would define it in our P.F. Crystal layer dot dense
we had input shape of 1 which is this one here and for the upper layer we had the units equal to 1 Again
that's 1 output which is what's shown here in our op layer so this is our dense layer of input to this
that's our dense layer of course it's not very dense is only really one input here one output one one
neuron and one output and in terms of the representation this is what it looks like and one is a good
2 The X1 which is the input multiplied by the weight that eleven plus the bias term if you look at the
representation of this is much much closer to the problem statements that we have of course the problems
Edmonds were created by a real function and it's not like the reality is that in real life you're not
going to be able to see that real function.
So we are using the algorithm to actually estimate the function itself.
The final point that I wanted to make here is that our neural network quite often a much more complex
than either of these there can be multiple layers and each layer have many more neurons than one or
two could be three could be substantially higher.
And there are also other So core steps that you can perform in between layers as well.
Right now we only have one hit in here.
It can be four or five.
And many many more but we'll see different architectures too for the flexibility to solve the problems
at hand.
With that I'm going to start.
Thank you for watching.
Just to summarize we've talked about a more complex neural network architecture vs. a much simpler one
which solve our problem and look forward to seeing you in the next lesson.