Hello everyone.
In this lesson we're going to go in to the so-called machine learning per say but before we go into
that in depth we're going to start with again a little bit more of the familiarization of the Python
environment the drill bit and notebook really.
And I'm trying to get you to be comfortable with the environment.
We're gonna start with a project called Iris Project.
But before we started to the machine learning drawing into it I just want to actually explain to you
couple of libraries that we do that use of quite extensively as well as some of the data analysis that
you need to do before going in to full on into the machine learning modelling itself.
So let's just select this project Iris Project and get started of the type of this as Iris Project.
We're going to start with simple data exploration and analysis.
Couple of things that we're doing and also the school library that we make use of num pi is the first
one followed by panthers and by seaborne num pi is the numerical Python.
If I come here and say I'm pi there is actually a Web site dedicated to num pi and it shows you how
to make use of API what it is and how to utilize it fully.
So that's really the point.
So the documentation is very extensive.
It's really well supported it is mature.
It is a very mature library so highly encourage you to actually make use of it and become familiar with
it is really critical when it comes to bit data science data analysis analytics or even machine learning.
The second one is pandas.
Pandas.
We just put it up pandas lock the animal itself pandas.
It's really instrumental in propelling Python to become the forefront of data analysis.
So the it is an open source that is free for you to make use of.
And again this is a really well supported documentation is great.
And you can actually make use of it right now the version is to zero point to five it is due in the
beta stage not quite completely blow it up yet but this lot of functionalities that is highly useful
again this is good for performing analysis on tabular structured data.
So that's the python data Dennis's library and see Bowen is the third library that we can make use of.
And let me just put it up Seabourn is short for statistical data visualization because you can see very
quickly here it renders really beautiful chart and that's the reason why we are making use of it.
It's just really handy for this purpose rather than having to actually code it out.
The last library is the Met plot lit with social visualization library Seabourn is a high level library
which actually made use of met lib Maxwell.
It's been around for quite some time but it's useful it is highly flexible and extremely powerful.
The only problem with that is when ever you have anything that's highly useful or highly functional
and highly customization of all the low customization function day it gets a bit complicated to learn.
So let me just open this up plot lib so visualizations for plot as you can see this is under version
three point one point one is already mature is no longer a beta is for long for you two to be able to
use and c bond is two zero point nine OK.
So looking at this with the first few things that we're doing here is that we are importing pi and we
call it and the OK rather than typing num painfully we used the notation short Shorten notation Cor
MP so that is actually simplify it substantially and this is the custom notation panders is denotes
as PDC bonus s and s then we implement plot lib the PI plot the sub library S P L T and there's a few
of codes here just setting the actual default and plotting the main problem in line so that we can actually
see it within the the notebook itself as before we click play to run oneself OK whoops we have one problem
Mark this is part of the plan to show you how to actually deal with these things as and when it comes
up.
So what it says is this or the error is meant to be informative to a large extent if you get stuck you
can either google it to find out how to solve this problem or if you can understand English or what
the error message is trying to inform you then you probably can actually solve yourself as well right.
It says here module not found error traced back OK the transfer basically tells you which line of code
sixty is giving you the trouble so line one say is important umpire as a piece of basically it seems
that we don't have a more June and none pi now I'm gonna show you two ways to solve this I'm going to
copy this single cell come to Google and search right well I didn't really copy that I solved images
copy
to see that student the work I'm gonna have to move to the next.
OK.
There we go.
Control C import error.
No module name num pi.
So you can see quite often for open source library like mature library like Python pandas and its values
library you'll have people posting questions and steak on the floor.
And this is where you can find answers to this.
Basically no you follow.
This is probably super basic but I'm still learning things.
Okay.
Same here.
Check if there is a directory.
Blah blah.
And the next one is to give a you must download it install a new version.
None quite so very quickly just by reading this is already informing you that you need to install it.
If you don't have you need to install it.
You can either use this or this to install it.
Okay great.
All right.
So we'd roughly get an idea that okay we need to install this.
Okay but wait a second.
These answer were given quite a while back.
This is 2011.
This is 2017 2016.
So is there a newer answer.
Well did you answer is probably exactly the same.
OK.
There are some conditions to suddenly realize oh my goodness they are like it all for the same one question.
There are so many solutions to it and you have to get used to this.
This is actually a common phenomenon when you're actually dealing with open source library you need
to actually quickly sift through it.
Don't get all bombard.
I know you were in the beginning but as you do more and more you come to the realization that this is
some of the barriers that you have to get through or get passed to actually be comfortable with using
this open source library that is free up the road.
It does come at a cost.
OK so we're stuck here.
So what do we do.
That's the first way to do it is just to illustrate.
You stack overflow if you don't have any way of solving that problem.
Then follow some of the suggestions by the community.
Now those are all provided by the community.
Right.
Let me just switch back to Anaconda navigator.
If you do recall previously I did mention that you can actually tackle this and install it yourself.
So I'm going to go over the environment and go but to not install and search for non pi.
OK here we go.
I can't find none pi here.
So what I need to do is select Nan pi and then click apply and this is actually telling you install
package.
All right we'll go through this.
Blue Bar solving and all this falling package will be modified so it's doing that exercise of locating
it and downloading it and no one's actually asking you for confirmation to proceed to install.
So I'm gonna just click apply and now it's installing.
Okay.
As you can see is actually installing empire.
Let that run for a while
OK.
Well so far looks like it's OK and none pi is no longer showing as not in store.
If I switch over the install it is here OK.
It is already in store.
It's no price.
Let's go back to this.
OK so let's run this cell again one more time to see if we do encounter the same problem.
All right.
OK.
This time round is drawing out a different error message.
It seems like well this is one of those.
No news is good news.
It didn't throw out the fact that can't find no pi.
So basically that means at number pi has already been installed.
So that's why that line of code runs safely without any issue.
So that's really the lesson I want to actually cover today I know that for this portion I know that
this is quite a long lesson already.
To actually illustrate to you how to actually deal with errors and how to install this is a step by
step process I hope that you build me this ideally at some point you will be able to go through this
very quickly.
For now I'm going to leave you I'm going to install pandas seaborne met plot live the background and
you come back.
We should have run these cells without any issues at all.
I'll leave that to you as an exercise to actually install pandas Seabourn and Matt Pollard and I'll
see you next time.
In the next lesson.
Thank you for watching
installing pandas.
So right now we just come to not installed under the Environment and type pandas.
Okay.
And you can see here pandas.
That's really what we actually want to its store and our.
That also know that it's already dead.
So if I type pandas again you can see that it's been selected.
What else I want to install Seabourn.
All right.
Select that and then mint plot lib.
It's the third one.
All right.
So I have selected three soldiers apply this kind of search for pandas seaborne as far as I've met.
These are the three main ones that I wanted to install in one go rather than doing it three times.
OK so we can see that map lip Henderson seaborne soldiers apply this and let it install these
all right.
The installation is done so let's commit to install no problems there.
All right let's run this one more time and see if there's any errors being thrown up.
Let's play this
this time.
Oh good.
Finish running without any error being thrown out.
So we are good to go.
So let's have a look at a couple of things here.
I'm printing the actual version so that you can actually see which version of Python abusing which version
of numbers I am using pandas as far as the seaborne.
All right.
So as you can see here these are all the versions are being printed out.
OK.
Right.