OK.
The next thing we want to do is to actually read the data in to our memory.
First thing is that we are looking at reading the final quote Irish data.
That's the source file that we have the data file that we have under the directory called data.
And I know beforehand that this is actually a C as we file so you can see that we are using pandas.
There is a sub module called Read CSP using the read C as we read the Irish stored data fall into our
memory.
So let's show you a little bit within the data.
I do have a couple of sample data for you to utilize and the purpose of our lesson and this is that
I really don't data that already place there.
So let me just hide this so that we can actually have more space.
So let's run this cell and basically I'm reading this and I'm storing it into the variable core D F
DFS shot for data frame remember that I mentioned pandas is good and useful for tabular structure excel
like Excel like data format or the actual formatting of the data.
So let's have a look at the first few rows of the data by using this module core dot head or core method.
So let's run this and you can see there.
Okay.
Right.
Not as I mentioned before.
These are in tabular format in columns and rows format.
There is one problem though is that the this is actually a data.
This row is actually a raw data and what pandas read see as we method think or thought it was the column
header.
And naturally we know that that's actually incorrect.
So what we can do here is that we can add a little parameter here call comma and then Heather is equal
to minus one that basically say look this data this raw data as it comes to has no header at all and
just take the first row as data.
So we're going to read that directly and then show the head.
Okay.
The head meaning the first five rows of data.
So if we run that and I get this interesting error message.
Right.
It's fairly roll.
So what it actually is saying is it's a value error.
Again how do you read.
Error messages passing negative integer to header is invalid for no header use header it could have
none instead.
Oh very good.
OK.
So what happened is that minus one used to be the method to actually say there's no header the library
is changed so we switch it over to none run that again no harm done.
So now the column name is called.
Sure One two three four No.
So that's useful for the purpose of our for this exercise.
And basically this shows us that yeah we have the data and we are able to actually resolve the problem
of not using the first row of data as our column as our column header right.
Seeing that we don't actually have any column header.
What we also want is to extend something that inform us of what these columns in important columns of
data actually meant of course they come with meaning.
So I have actually pre populated this cell here and calling in the variable column name column on this
code name several length several with head or Lang header with and also finally the class.
OK.
So at this point if you don't know what I'm talking about then you probably have not come across the
Irish data set.
There is data set is really great introductory data set to help you get familiar with how to make use
of Python for data analysis using pandas interacting the data pulling into memory for computation for
manipulation to get a really good understanding the Irish dataset is fairly simple it's not complicated.
So a you although you might not know what I'm referring to when I say keep saying the word Iris.
So let me come over here and type Iris dataset using our good friend Google.
You can actually go to this the UCI machine learning repository.
This is actually we obtain the data from the end of Wikipedia.
This Iris flower data set.
There's also Cagle both of these that's fine for the purpose of what we're looking to do right.
So Iris flow data set.
Officials there said is actually origin introduced by Roland Fisher in 1936.
OK.
So let's flip down here.
Couple of things.
Just wanted to highlight to you Iris that Rosa is this flower.
What color is this.
Looks like this and Virginia looks like this.
So there's actually three types of flowers in the actual data center itself.
How we actually measure them or compare them.
Describe the flower itself is you meant you saw before the actual pedal length with and also the simple
language with.
OK so let's come back here the only thing here is that it didn't really describe to you what is simple
What is pedal.
So let's have a look at the Irish Flower said to see if it actually did provide the information.
No it does not.
So we're going to come up with the images and see if we can actually get a little bit more some kind
so has gone in there.
Describe for us.
All right.
Here is some kind soul has already shown us this is what a sport looks like.
This is what a header looks like.
OK great.
This is really what I was looking for.
So we have four measurements the length with the language of both pedal and simple.
And that's where we have the four columns here.
Two described in the last column column them before is to describe the three types of Iris flower set
that we saw earlier.
OK.
So let's run this to store these five column names now that I've stored this and this variable I need
to actually tell tenders to rename these column to these names.
OK.
So that's what I do.
Dot DIA dot columns.
That's how I access the column.
The name itself and replace it and call names run dead and as I run the header again you can see that
the column names now is much more meaningful several laying several with and on and on it goes.
Right I'm going to stop this lesson here.
Just a quick summary of what we've gone through here is that we have very quickly at the beginning of
it a store the pandas sheep on a map plotted I show you how to extract the actual version that we use
how to read data.
Years of we file into a memory how to look at the data inspect it and how to actually change the header
and also how to rename the actual column names and actually converting them or applying that to our
data frame.
Last but not least we see for the first time the ARIAs data set so that you actually get familiar with
it and also show you where you can actually access the data either using Google look at Wikipedia or
Cagle or look out the image search within Google itself so that you can actually quickly visualize some
kind so has already visualized that for you.
Of course there are some videos as well but for now this is what we actually want to access for the
purpose of this simple tutorial.
But I'm going to stop right here.
Thank you once again for watching.