Welcome back everyone.
So let's dig into what exactly is a deep learning.
So in this segment we're going to talk about the architecture of deep learning and what does it actually
look like.
Now some basic fundamentals it is not deep in the sense of knowledge.
The DPA actually refers to the depth of layers.
Each layer is learned basically that each layer learned of a specific representation of the data.
Now I appreciate that the picture that I'm showing here it's little bit not clear.
And if you look at it this is the Alexa net.
It's a computer vision deep learning and neural network architecture.
Let me just walk through the network with you if you have a look at this we start from the left side
from this side.
This is where the input image comes in.
OK.
And followed by this is one layer.
And these are these so-called dimensions of the layer fifty five by fifty.
Don't be too concerned with that for now and then followed by another layer and then another layer by
another layer followed by another layer and then the last few layers are called the dense layer fully
connected dense layer.
So don't be too concerned but those just understand that as this you have the input data and then you
have the output in terms of what the target is and in between what you have is a whole lot of neural
networks that actually learn each layer learn a specific presentation or representation.
I mentioned before this is Layer number five.
And if is first layer then we'll be most likely will be straight edges would be the right line or the
left line and then the horizontal could be the second layer.
And then thirdly you could be the circle and on and on it goes.
So that's specifically what each layer learned.
And each of these layer the depth of the layer actually provides the capacity for the network to learn
more I guess if you think of it in statistics term is called degrees of freedom.
If you think of it as a straightforward equation then instead of y you could do X plus C which is 1
x day one variable then what you have here is many many X as an example not exactly the same but just
just just just as an example to to give you an idea of what each of these are.
Now I appreciate that this is probably still very raw.
And in terms of your understanding but look at this as the architecture for now I'm going to show you
another one right now.
This is another computer vision layer.
It's called BCG 16.
This is an example of again another neural network architecture specifically.
This is for again for convolution all neural network.
If you look at this what you have is that you have the input layer where the raw data is being fed in
and what you have then is sixty four block one block one has a convolution layer one second convolution
there and then pulley.
So this layer here consists of three three guest layer.
You can call it this block consists of three layers.
And then this is followed by another block which has two convolution or layer in a mix pulling and then
followed by block three and block four and then block five.
And on and on it goes.
What is not shown here are the last three layers of fully connected a dense layer.
This may not be three layers of fully connected dense layer but the basic idea is that the before the
output there must be fully connected layer of to actually finish off the second neural network.
And that's really what I wanted to show you in terms of the deep learning part of it.
This is the architecture of what a deep learning neural network looks like and I hope that it gives
you at least if you haven't seen it before.
This is just a start of what it looks like.
I hope that it helps you to actually at least have a better grasp of it.
Now let me illustrate a little bit more of the architecture of what a neural network looks like.
And quite often this is a toy example whereby of the architect of what a neural network looks like and
it's not too different from the real world whereby what I've shown you earlier is a much more complex
and more state of the art.
In fact this is about three years on the state of the art neural network but in its infancy This is
what it is a representation of what a neural net what looks like.
So you have the input.
These are your input.
It could be in the form of your raw data sample data.
And what is this is that is being fed into what's called an input layer.
So these are the three layers that is actually facing the world.
So you have these three layers and noticed that each of these are connected to the next layer and these
one two three layers here are core the hidden layers these layers are hidden for a dozen next to interact
with the outside world.
I guess you can actually say that the data is actually being fed input in directly into the input layers.
Now when you look at this it kind of reminds you of our brain.
In fact the idea of neural network is that it is inspired from biology or from our brain or brain cells.
Now if you look at it again this is the input features or the feature vector.
If you're looking at lots of data is that it's coming in also called features.
It goes through the input layer which directly feed into three hidden layers before it comes to the
output layers and finally the output is the predictions that it actually that the neural network will
actually generate for you.
And that's generally the basic idea
the basic idea of what a neural network is.
So let me actually illustrate a little bit more.
I think it's worthwhile to spend a little bit of time to understand how a neural network actually work.
So let me start with the the bottom one which is directly from I mean just put it up directly from Stanford.
These are Stanford class on convolution or neural networks for visual recognition or computer vision
that I mentioned earlier.
If you look at this.
This is what I wanted to show you.
And what they have very kindly and nicely shown here is the future which is also the layer itself.
This is the second layer.
If you look at it of this is Steve from Alex net and you can see that it actually is.
Well they have the edges.
It's kind of like horizontal or vertical as fairly smooth.
All right.
So let's look at the next one and we're going to go into this 2D convolution all network visualizations
by Adam Holly and this is really quite something else.
Okay let's wait for this to run now what he's done here is that this is a two layer neural network and
it's asking you to draw the number here.
So let's just draw this and I'm going to draw a four.
OK.
Right.
What do you see here.
What you can see here is that this is the input.
This is the next layer.
All right.
It fits into this next layer.
And it actually each and every one of these tells you what is actually going on and how it actually
each of these pixel relate to which part.
And it shows you.
OK from here.
Notice that it links to that layer.
And notice these are the edges.
And it goes on and on finally becomes a single layer.
And then this is the fully connected layer and finally the prediction is for.
And notice that this is quite remarkable and of course from the perspective of a phone from a person
who is learning that this is quite remarkable because it's really easy to understand.
You can actually show the employer or hide it.
You can look at the convolution or layer one hired hide it.
And this is the down sample which is also what's called Max pulling.
And then this layer to.
And this is the down sample also called Max pool.
And then we have the fully connected Layer 1 fully connected Layer 2.
And finally this is the output itself and and I think I really encourage you to play with it.
It really helps to develop a lot of intuition and to see how and how it actually works from from the
picture that I showed you earlier this is three simple layer has three nodes whereas for this you can
see that it has one two three four five six nodes.
OK.
And from there to the next pool layer it has one to one but going to the next one it actually comes
from multiple sources.
OK.
As you can actually see here right.
Let's look at the next.
And I also want to encourage you to play with this 10 sibling playground that's provided for by
Google OK so if you look at this there are a few things.
Now let's start with something extremely simple such as this.
So it's a bit on the small side.
So let's just start with OK.
No hidden layer.
OK.
So in this case it can actually separate out the MI.
We have zero.
OK.
We have two features OK.
Notice that is a straight line.
That's a vertical straight line for this.
And this is a horizontal straight line.
And you can see that the neural network was able to actually learn the segregation line separating the
orange from the blue.
So let us
train this.
We haven't trained it.
There was just randomly generated let's just train this.
OK.
And after a few hundred epochs epochs is mostly means that it takes D.C. all of the data.
It sees all of the data.
How many times or now it has in the same data seven hundred times.
Let's just pause it.
OK.
And you can see that the learning rate is point zero three using this activation function called tangent
hedge.
And if you look at the Test loss and the training lost there's absolutely none whatsoever.
If you think about loss as errors then you can understand that hey what we have is a scenario whereby
this model by say we have two features here X1 and X2 and is able to actually predict the two classes
of blobs or clusters very easily the blue one from the orange one.
OK.
So we can see that actually well learn that really well.
Okay let's move on to regenerate another example.
They're all in the same spot.
Let me add a lot of noise.
Yeah.
Let that regenerate okay and restart the training again.
Notice that again it's quickly learning the test losses down to zero the training loss is pretty low
as well.
And again let's pause this.
It quickly learns the pattern and it finds the best line to actually segregate the two class.
Right now you say OK that's straight straightforward is a simple pattern.
It should be able to pick that out.
So let's have a look at this.
Now we have four.
I can't you can't possibly draw a straight line to separate out the blue one from the orange one because
no matter just convince yourself no matter how you draw one line you are not going to be able to segregate
the two.
So these two features enough let's run all the machine learning model and noticed that it's not getting
any lower.
It is just struggling and the losses are really high at point five and point five for both the test
and train.
OK.
This is not working.
Just basically having two features one vertical one one horizontal one is not working.
So let's just add one more extra to power two and run this and see Is it working.
No.
OK.
Again it's not working.
Let's add another feature extra the power too.
OK.
It's trying very very hard.
This is part of the thing that I really want to encourage you to do.
Try this.
Play around with it to see if you can actually get an intuition and understanding all of this.
So again not working very well at least at another features x1 x2 8.
This is looking better.
They're looking much much better and noticed that the losses are now down to 1 percent.
OK so all right.
So I mean these are the traditional way of what's called feature engineering.
Now via feature engineering providing different kind of features it's able to actually predict the data.
So far what we've done is nothing deep about this.
It's just very one layer of of or predicted there's nothing deep about this.
So let's move on to something like this Circle K we have all of these.
Let's see if it actually can learn right.
Seems is actually very quickly be able to learn that pattern pretty well which is really good because
we have five features it seems to be able to do that.
Now what if I add a hidden layer.
OK.
Just two neurons to see if it actually can improve that.
Remember the lowest earlier was zero point zero five.
OK.
And it seems to now hasn't done that well.
It seems to getting lower might need more.
Ken maybe we'll add a few more hidden layer to see if it actually can lend the pattern better.
And with that you can see that it's starting to drop let's see how it actually improve.
It's not much better than before.
So what we do is it maybe will add to hidden layer and three neurons five new rules for it and see what
happened.
OK.
Now you can see that it actually is starting to drop.
It seems to have a better capacity to learn.
Still though the test loss is actually a little bit on the high side.
In fact it's actually climbing.
Now the more that we train.
OK.
So let's just do this and so.
And again this is the part that I want to highlight.
This is the part of neural network and deep learning.
You do have to play around with it.
It's not straightforward science here.
There's a bit of tinkering play around with it to see if it actually works really well.
And you might have to stop at some point to stop it from continue to learn because this is seems to
start to over fit now.
OK.
And it doesn't seem to do so well in this.
So maybe we actually try and really do and we'll try it is classification.
OK.
We're going to leave that one out.
And let's try this.
OK.
So once I change Rallo the Test loss and the training lost job immediately.
It was hovering around 8 percent earlier.
That dropped immediately and now it's starting to climb again.
So we're starting to go into the overland territory so final pattern is this.
I know that as you watch me play around with this.
It looks really exciting.
But trust me and this is much more fun as you play with it than me playing with it.
You will actually get the intuition much much faster by playing with it yourself.
So for this it's really well it seems to be improving but it seems to also struggle so we're going to
add a few more layers to help it along.
OK.
Let's see if this many layers can actually help.
So let's see.
So it might take a while
yeah.
That's right.
There we go.
It's learning the pattern.
OK.
The Test loss has dropped down to 5 percent now is 4 percent let's continue to learn.
But I think by now you probably get the gist of what I'm trying to actually convey here.
You do need to actually.
Well a couple of things that were done.
Let's summarize.
We have the input data.
We have the features.
We have the many layers.
These are the hidden layers.
And finally we have the output layer and there is the learning rate which will cover later lectures
activation within used his regular lines Asian.
We talk about that.
This is classification.
But again I want to stress that please spend some time to learn this and I'm going to pass this because
it's probably getting a bit of a distraction for you.
Now these are the few things that I wanted to highlight and want to actually demo to you.
They are ready to is out there for you to help you to develop the intuition and really that is what
deep learning is about.
I showed you what Alex net looks like.
This is the video G 16 which is 16 layers and this is what a neural network looks like.
And finally we stop at the neural network visualization.
I hope that has been is useful.
But don't just listen to me talking go and play with it.
You can't break it.
All of these I have the link provided for you.
This was the best way for you to develop intuition.
Thank you once again for watching.
I look forward to seeing you in the next video.