You might be forgiven for thinking that deep learning can really only be used for integers or value
BS problems.
What about text and sequence of tax.
Two years ago.
Probably not a well-known fact by now it is fairly common knowledge that deep learning can be applied
to taxpayers problem just as easily as integer based or value based problems.
I was gonna have a look at one such problem which is binary classification we are applying this to the
I am D.B. database.
What is I am D.B..
I am VB is actually the sole core repository I guess you can call it or the website that collect all
the viewers view of a movie and they do provide these data for for you to utilize is the really rich
database where you have a lot of information and ratings and reviews and people write comments about
it.
If I dig into cable this is one example of it whereby everyone say is one of the other reviewers as
mentioned that after watching just added a lover.
Then you actually have the same core labelling whether it is positive or negative.
So essentially these data allows you to have the so-called perspective of written texts versus the label
to go with it.
With that what you can do is you have essentially a simple vies machine learning problem and the question
then of course for most people will be that how do I actually provide that tags into the machine learning
algorithm for it to decipher the meaning of those sentences or attacks or the words.
The idea is fairly simple and then help here.
This is essentially.
This is essentially a natural language processing problem or door.
It has been simplify in that somewhat the pre processing the steps has already been done for you.
The word has already been converted into integer and so you wouldn't actually have that have to perform
that additional step itself.
But if you are given in totality just pure text and the label then what you will have had to do is that
you can.
You will have to make use of some of the libraries to it to actually convert the word into unique token
right.
Having said all that essentially what we are doing here is still what's called a binary classification
problem.
Of course the features are slightly different now the features we are using the word as of features
and we are using the word as of course you can tell from this that is a really really long and the massive
matrix and substantial and the size in terms of the features.
Of course the target or the label is do very simple as just whether it is positive or negative 0 or
1.
You can read more about the MTV Movie Review sentiment classification that is said here is twenty five
thousand rather than the full fifty thousand and let's run the library and import the data.
So this is x2 farm that carries data says I am D.B..
We're going to just limit the so-called training here so that it doesn't run for too long.
Just make sure that you do have the GPL and also Python 3 running well and looking at fifty five thousand
you can increase that more if you like.
We are saying that we are really looking at the maximum number of features of only 5000 looking at the
data itself.
We have 25000 droves of data.
If you look at the actual underlying data itself the first 200 is what you can see here is that these
are or in numeric format which is what I mentioned before the words has already been converted to introduce
or is basically a sequence of words and each integer represent a specific word and where you have 0
1 1 0 stand for a negative review 1 stands for positive review.
Again looking at the first 2 this is will be a positive review of the second entry will be what's called
a negative review of course from time to time.
You may want to dig in and have a look at the individual word and the actual index to go with it.
This is rather long.
I'm gonna hide it after that so he can see here sorted is 1 8 5 2 2.
Plug in is 5 fifty two thousand two hundred and ninety four.
Let me hide that.
And of course you may want to be looking at it the other way because you all you have is the 16 here
you say OK what the 16 stand for.
Then you can actually look up the value and and the corresponding word to go with it.
The next step that you might want to do is plug this in to pandas and have it sorted in numerical order
for quick searching right.
So you're going to run the this one more thing that we need to do.
Is that because the the features are in the form of integers.
What we want to do is want hot and coded to a matrix of 0 and 1 and 0 when no such word exist.
1 when the word exists in the data itself that way we have the same length.
That's the first thing and the second thing is that this is a lot more friendly for the algorithm to
actually be trained.
So essentially this is how we function.
You provide the data and you define the maximum features which we defined previously as 5000.
So we're going to basically start off with creating a dimension of 5000 zeros in a row of 0 and based
on the length of data 25000 remember currently.
So basically we're creating now a matrix of 25000 by 5000 25000 long rolls 5000 wide.
In terms of the features itself.
Okay.
And we do that for training and tests and would do that and for why we're converting it into a float.
Right.
The important part the architecture itself.
We have the first layer.
It's a dense layer okay.
Our input shape is 5000.
It goes into the first layer which is actually a hidden layer cost the employer is 5000 rolls followed
by first hidden layer is 16 neurons with activation is really second layer of hidden layer is also another
realm too.
And finally the output there is the sigmoid because we want it either 0 or 1.
We're using this across the ground descend for lost function being binary cross entropy.
Looking at this we just reset this restart the runtime.
Yes.
And then I'm gonna clear output and stop running from the top.
OK.
All right so just a touch.
Quick notes here.
What are the activation function that we're using here.
We have really two as I mentioned before is nonlinear.
So the neural network can learn non-linear feature now also will be a purely what's called Alien aid
or linear or fine in nature which is not very useful because in the problem that we have is clearly
non linear.
So this is looking at the data here we have the employer followed by 16 neuron first hit in their second
hidden area is also another 60 neurons and finally the output is is a sigmoid whether it's positive
or negative review.
Splitting the data again to train and validation fitting the model with 50 epochs and the batch update
is 5 to off or let that run and we also provide the validation in terms of the tuple expel and wave
ok I know that the training is done looking at the accuracy of training around eighty six to eighty
eight and the validation is right.
Five to eighty six.
Not too bad.
Let's look at the performance.
Plot you're not.
Did you notice that the training lost continue to go down.
You're starting to see the separation between the validation laws and also the training laws.
They are some of a fitting going on here now and looks like our we need to actually work out how to
actually solve this problem either by increasing the amount of data that we have or creating different
features.
The training and not the validation accuracy paint the same picture.
Well just to summarize we've looked at the application of neural network and this lesson here on non
numeric data which is text based data and basically came in the form of sentences with with the rating
or target being positive or negative.
That labelling part has to be done by human of course.
The sentences each words has been converted and converted to a token and then we convert it into a matrix
so that we can fit it into our neural network.
And there's pretty much everything that we've covered.
Of course the slight variation now is that we have a slightly more complex neural network with two layers
meters high.
This coming back to architecture neural network architecture.
This is for a go with if you take out the input an output we have to hit in the years for this neural
network and that's all for this lesson.
Thank you.