Now I just want to move on to cover visualization as well.
Okay.
The this part is a little bit more on the complex side if you're not familiar with it but just to bear
with me I just want to illustrate to you how you can actually very quickly conduct very beautiful plots
using seaborne for the purpose of analysis and quite often the low of these codes can be recycled.
Right.
Remember that I reassessed our data set a couple of Paramount is that we can provide.
Excuse me.
There are a couple parameters that we can provide.
So let's run this cell.
This is extreme performance pay plot.
Okay.
Throw it away.
I'm getting an error.
Okay.
Use a warning the size parameter has been renamed to height.
Please update your code.
OK.
So that gives me the information and OK to replace that run that again and
and wait for that cell to finish running we no longer get an error message.
And we get this beautiful char All right.
It kindly also provides us with comes some color coding.
Blue is the toes.
This is orange color and green is Virginia Code.
OK.
So very quickly you can see that this is in the form of a pair plot.
Let me see if I can actually minimize this.
So you can see the whole lot OK not very ideal because it's a bit on the small side but there are labels.
The good thing is that you have your own notebook for you to do in further.
So I'm going to do in a little bit.
Now this is 100 percent.
This is several length plotting against several length.
So the diagonal is 60.
Plotting against itself when you are plotting against yourself.
What you see is actually the distribution.
This is the simple length distribution for stores are you can see this it also has the shortest simple
length the receipt color and Virginia Code.
These two is almost you can't distinguish them in terms of their dispersion or those separate for mistletoe
Tulsa you can come to the with you're barely perceptible difference there although you can see it's
also is a bit slightly on the fat side.
Now these are distribution.
OK.
What is distribution.
Again these are better built upon statistical understanding and foundation for machine learning.
You do need to actually refresh all of these basic principle and concepts in statistics.
Basically the this distribution plot is kind of like plotting it has diagram of all the possible data
that within the so-called variable itself and in our case if you look at pedal length you can see it
said Toys R is much much shorter in terms of distribution compared to the other two.
Delta is almost you can't tell.
They're almost basically a lot of overlap but for petal length of the torso you can see that is definitely
shorter than the other two.
Likewise with the all with as well.
So that's what the column or the diagonal actually tells you.
Now if I plot simple with against simple length This is the information that they have.
It's a little bit hard to interpret that's for sure.
If I plot the largest say a pedal length against pedal with I can see that the toes out zone and zone
here there's some mixture.
I mean just blow in.
There's a mixture of the other two species here.
There's actually intermix here which is understandable.
So this is a two dimensional pot plot.
This is a single dimensional plot.
So with this I'm actually plotting the pedal length pedal with here and of course that gives me a little
bit more information as well.
In terms of how to distinguish them this is really a very quick visualization to help you to actually
get a preliminarily preliminary understanding of the actual underlying data distribution so that later
on when you do machine learning it gives you some foundations for now.
That's sufficient for what we actually want to do.
So continue on.
We can actually plot histogram as well so let's just run this and this is the histogram of the iris
data for all four of the numerical data.
So this is actually plotting.
You can see the pattern link with several length and with but this is actually combining all three species
together so you can't really tell which is which is just or the data is being plot right.
So let's the next one is actually plotting the spiral in plot so we have one two three four while in
plot plotting the actual sample length with simple pedal length with this well and looking at these
it will inform you very similar to these pair plot here except this slightly different in the form of
file and plot.
You can see that the parallel with for said Tulsa and the pedal length is definitely much shorter than
the other two.
If you drill into each of these the height dot that white dot there is to mean and then you have the
25th percentile the seventy fifth percentile that's the max test and then.
And the actual distribution itself.
There are a lot of information contained within the Bartlett plot.
So it pays to actually get comfortable with it as well.
Next one is box plot.
This is just really a quick illustration of the different types of plot that you can actually do with
the C bond.
So this is actually box plot.
Box box plot basically have looks kind of similar.
Or rather they actually display similar information to the violent plot.
So if I dig in a little bit and take this for example the Green Line is the mean.
Okay.
This bigger box here.
This is a lower quintile upper quintile lower and upper is the 25th in 70 percent of the solar blah.
Here tells you the minimum and maximum.
And this is for one of the species which is Virginia provided here.
So again box block this is group by species so these are three different species here so that hopefully
provide give or provide you with some useful information to actually judge.
You can see that this 2 plots is actually sharing and favorable for them are actually sharing the same
y axis.
The 0 2 8 and you can see that this is actually squashed way by this is disputed out.
This is more squashed.
This is actually a little bit more widely distributed.
So clearly the pattern with is actually much much shorter as you read these chart.
Just be mindful that they are not quite in the same model or the violent plot you can see the step or
length here and in pedal length for this arrow length is on top followed by the simple length so that
they are in slightly different order so just be mindful of that right.
The next one that I want to show you is the scatter plot and also matrix similar information.
Probably not as useful as the pair plot.
It does have its own place to display different information.
Personally I prefer the purple partially because it's color coded of course to provide this species
to to allow the hue to be generated as well.
And finally just as the purple again but slightly different in that I want the diagonal to be KDE plot
which happens to be the same as before.
So that kind of defeat the purpose of where you can actually change a different kind of plot this file
to look up the actual API provided by Seabourn itself.
So that's pretty much what I wanted to cover in this lesson and a very quick look fairly.
Not really in depth fashion.
I'm mindful of that but just the purpose of this is not so much to teach you a visualization as the
purpose of it is much more to illustrate to you what the some of the possibilities that can be done
using the bond you can see here that you can actually plot really really beautiful which art which is
substantially harder to perform if you're using Excel so you can perform plot using providing a couple
parameters.
Likewise you can see you do perform histogram while in plot box plot scatter as well as to get a matrix
plot.
And finally I would come back to PayPal again.
So that's really a fairly quick will win tool on what you can do with C.
I hope you found a useful and thank you once again for watching.