Hey welcome back.
And this lesson we're going to start looking at some of the building blocks of neural networks.
Now some of the key foundation that you do need to know not to really grasp the concepts is linear algebra.
That's the first one second one is probability as well as information theory and you do need to actually
have a fairly good grasp of numerical computation as well as literacy.
Now the the so-called codes that I showed you in the last lesson.
It requires a certain level thinking of course.
But if you study it carefully and if you actually study it diligently you'll find that the actual sequence
and the actual approach is is it's it's OK.
You can exceed come to Ken come to an understanding of it without much problem for some of you you will
be able to pick up very easily.
It's just a second nature to you and maybe because you have developed excuse over the years for some
of you don't lose heart it just do not you will still be able to get hold of it.
I just need to give it a bit more chance and give yourself a bit more chance as well just to revise
a little bit.
But we actually covered in the last example and code walk through we looked at the immense dataset and
the steps that we covered pretty much is the actual standard steps for all neural network.
And the training of any models.
The first thing is loading the data.
The second one will be defining your neural network architecture before you compile it with the selection
of your optimizer as well as your lost function in the last one what we did use is our mess prop which
did not explain what it is.
OK we will explain that in the later future lesson as well as the lost function the lost function is
across entropy that we use across entropy is for multi class in our case we have zero one two three
four or the eight to nine so we have ten classes that is what you will use which is cross entropy if
it's binary then you use binary.
OK.
The the lost function and after that we do need to compile it this the compilation part which I just
explain.
And before we feed our data through we do need to actually pre process and prepare the data so that
it actually makes it more amenable for the training of the neural network what we did in the previous
lesson to X is to convert or data to or squeeze it to between 0 and 1 it actually speeds up the training
and you don't actually have an error errors drawing everywhere the next thing is that we do need to
prepare our label or targets to ensure that it is appropriately labeled because when it comes to the
machine learning again it doesn't work well with tanks or strings you do have to convert it to integers
ideally in one hard encoding format and the last second lasting is to actually train the model to an
acceptable accuracy level before continue on.
Once you actually happy with it then you actually move on to the actual prediction.
Now this process that I've just described here is not a one off process it's one that you do need to
actually continuously train your data as new data comes in.
You do need to train your model because there's one of those things when it comes to machine learning
algorithm is that it does go through decay or new were so-called algorithm better algorithm comes along
that you do need to improve it and also sometimes if you're working with financial Data's the taste
and the preferences of your customers may change.
So those are the things that them.
It's a it's a broader issue to think about and to consider one that you do need to train your neural
network on a continuous basis so that it actually stay relevant.
All right so that's really what I want to covered when we come back.
We're going to go into a little bit more about the actual tensor itself which is a description that
we use to describe the data and then I'm going to stop and thank you once again for watching this.