Welcome back everyone.
We're going to go through a couple of key attributes as well as some key ideas and concepts of neural
network.
Before we proceed to look at the codes itself.
So the first thing that I want to cover as the key attributes of tenses we talked about the different
dimensions the different types of dimensions of tenses differs from zero dimension one dimensional all
the way to five dimensions or more depending on the type of data that you're working with with Python.
There is Python num pi library.
There is a function core in dim this calculate the number of access for you now three dimension tenses
has three exits.
OK.
Also called rank in mathematics and there is shape which is the number of dimensions that tend to along
each axis.
For an example if we're looking at a two dimension vector to end them or tells you that there is actually
two dimensions so that tells you that this is a 2D tenses but what we don't know is that how many so
core what is the actual shape itself is if one by one or is it two by two.
So that's where in num pi you use dot shape which tells you in this case is four by nine.
Another example three dimensional tensor here the ending would tell you is a 3D but again this is what
you don't know is it is that one by one by one two by two by four.
So that's where the DOT shape would tell you that this is indeed a three by three by four.
Now you probably will vaguely recall that in the M.A. dataset that we were looking at the training data
is sixty thousand followed by 28 and 28 so and also the test data will be ten thousand followed by 28
and 28.
So it's sixty a three dimensional tensor.
Okay.
3D tenses.
All right.
The third thing that I want to cover is the data type.
The type of data that is stored in the actual tensor container you use d d typed in Python.
It could be a float 32.
It could be float 64 or unsigned integer 4 of 8 bit.
All right so those are the key attributes we're going to revisit this using code a bit later and the
next concept I do undercover is data batches
earlier you probably would have seen that when we were looking at the code the data batch that we used
was two five six.
Let me just have a quick look
at a batch where you
take out the batch sizes to five six.
Now when you're building all data learning models you don't usually process the entire data set at once.
When you look through one entire dataset one time it's called one epoch.
The data are usually broken up into small batches hence the term batch.
And how big is the batch will be called batch size the batch size that we specify in our earlier motivational
example is two hundred and fifty six meaning we took 256 sample.
Okay.
There are some other terminology that I do want to cover is that epoch 1 epoch basically means all the
data a batch will be a subset of the data a batch of 1 2 8 in Python code will be an example that looks
like this.
This is from the first all the way to 1 2 8.
So you're looking at the first hundred and 28 batch.
Okay there's the first batch the second eight second batch will be from 128 to 2 5 6 and the next batch
if you want to continue on is 1 2 8 times and and could be one could be 0 could be 2 or the way and
the column here basically specify this is from where and to where that's basically how you specified
in Python num pi code and the last thing that I want to cover is to revisit some of the tensor operations
basically algebra in python.
This are the key concepts that we will be illustrating using Python codes.
We will look at element y's operations broadcasting dot product which is marked matrix multiplication
and finally reshaping
so let's look at that.
We start with tensor operations example.
So I already mentioned these are the four things we're going to look at eleven Y's operations broadcasting
dot product as well as reshaping.
Okay.
So let's start looking at our first example element y's operations element y's operation based means
that one element whatever operation to another element.
OK so that's a little bit like you are doing all the calculations all at the same time but independently
based on the individual index itself.
So let's there's a little bit abstract.
So let's have a look at this.
So now we have X1 next to we're performing element y's operations here X1 plus X2.
This is two plus one.
This is two plus minus one and four plus three.
So that's the actual element y's operations that you are doing here.
It's not a multiplication it's not a complete addition.
This is another example of element y's operations whereby we are calculating the maximum between X1
or zero.
Okay.
So when we run that you'll notice that the maximum is x1.
Is this one here.
Okay.
So is actually an operation between zero and individual elements of X1 two is greater than zero.
So two is taken s to value zero is larger the minus one.
So hence zero is taken s to value for is larger than zero hands for is the value that's being retained
so hence this is what's called element y's operation.
So that's really what element the wise operations means is actually the individual operations later
on when we actually look at dot product it's a contrast to what element y's operation looks like if
you are familiar with matrix then you know that this is not not the same completely and very different
altogether.
So let's look at broadcasting now.
Broadcasting is record the X1 has three elements.
Okay.
So it's a is one dimension.
Now how do you add scalar to a vector this way.
Broadcasting comes in the small tensor will be broadcasted to match the shape of the larger tensor the
X1 matrix is basically three it has three elements.
Two is only one one element.
So basically that the two will be repeated three times or broadcasted to all the individual element
itself.
So let me illustrate.
So what happened here is that two will be added to two.
Two will be added to minus one which gives you a 1 2 will be added to four which gives you a six.
So the broadcasting of scalar the scalar value two or Joe D to the vector itself the one d vector and
hence this is what it looks like.
We're going to create X tree.
So this is another array that we're creating.
If we repeat again adding two to two by two matrix.
Notice that this is a 2D two dimensional tense and now what do you think will happen.
Have a guest.
Yes you'll be right.
The Dignity adds to is broadcasted to every single element and then the actual operation or addition
in this case is performed.
OK.
Right.
Let's look at x 4 which is what we're creating here.
So minus 1 to minus 1 and x tree looks like this.
How do you think.
Well how would it behave.
Extreme plus x 4.
Again pause for a moment.
Have a think done peak
All right.
Let me show you.
Basically it's broadcasted to the two dimensions.
So basically this first then followed by this.
So as one man is one gives you zero 1 minus 1 2 4 0 2 minus 1 gives you 1 to March 1 gives you 1.
So that's how it is broadcasted.
There's a limit to this especially if the shape doesn't match what we have is that scalar is easy to
broadcast to
any impact any dimension for that matter.
When you have more vectors to vectors or vector to matrix or vector to 4D it start to get complicated
especially of his order size then.
Then num pi when it do you figure out what you're trying to do and we'll show you an error.
OK so time to actually have a look at DOT PRODUCT you're probably more familiar with another term which
is matrix multiplication that essentially is what dot product is.
So let me show you.
Well let's start with X1 first.
We skip ahead right.
So if you take a simple dot product name pi dot and if I do X1 with x1.
Do you think that will work go back to your earlier days when you were looking at matrix.
If you have a three by one multiply by three by one and matrix would that work.
You're right it won't.
Well in this case fortunately for it for you it actually works.
But in reality it doesn't.
It should not work but because this is a simple case none pi is smart enough to figure out.
Technically you're supposed to transpose this.
Okay then it work as a good practice to make sure that you are actually working with within the rules
of Matrix so that you don't actually have any weird numbers or unexpected result being thrown out.
Okay.
So let's look at x3 and x4 these are two different ones.
Now the good thing is the X3 is even two by two.
So it's easy to see what they went up and when you actually look at DOT multiplication here which is
a metric most multiplication here would transpose X false x 4.
And we able to actually get the result.
So again let's have a look to see if num pi smart enough to figure out if we don't x2 transpose the
data.
Okay so smart enough to figure that out.
So that's good.
Oh good thing that is able to figure that out.
And but don't assume that it will work just fine for four for Matrix that's more complex.
These are simple matrix.
So a good thing you know and the situation is not bad that works out well.
Right let's have a look at.
I feel obliged to X to demonstrate to X Five.
Okay so num pi array let's see what kind of example we can use here.
Which is use this except that I'm going to change it to this is a two by two matrix.
Four four four five.
OK x six pi array now we have three by two.
So let's create a two by three.
Okay.
So one two three we need to open up one of these followed by three to two.
One that would do and we need to close it all.
OK so none pie so let's do this.
X 5.
Shape x 6 shape okay.
Notice that is true by 2 and 2 by 3.
So a nut pi dot.
And if we takes x 5 and 6 and it creates a matrix that is 3 by 3.
Okay.
Which is exactly what you expect because the when you actually have dot multiplication it takes the
external.
It takes the external dimension.
So if we do this I'm gonna wonder if this is gonna throw an arrow assured.
But let's just see.
Okay.
All right good.
I finally was able to prove this.
Okay.
I was expecting it to but it was smart enough to actually deduce it from your data.
But I think it actually come at the expense of slowing down.
But nevertheless.
So someone who has spent some time writing to assert code at the back.
So here it says shapes treated to two by two and three by two is not aligned.
Because when you X to doing matrix multiplication I'd really hope that you do remember your linear algebra
if not pleased to revise.
This is just a really quick run through or how to actually performed matrix multiplications in num pi
and Python rather than going through from step 1.
So you have two and three does not align.
So when it comes to multiplication matrix matrix multiplication the Inner Dimension must match and the
down to dimension is actually the final shape of our matrix.
Okay.
Right.
So that's really what I wanted to highlight.
Okay.
The last one.
Let me just tidy these the last topic I want to cover is reshaping let's bring up X tree.
This is what extra looks like if we perform minus 1 to 1 and print it out.
Notice that it turns it into a column no format.
Okay for this now for Rose by 1.
So if we do it the other way one minus one we reshaped it.
Okay it it converted from two by two to become a real matrix.
Okay so not as it is for by one.
This is 1 by 4.
Okay so extra if we reshaped it to 1 by 4 we're going to get the same result as that note is that you
can actually define it that way.
If we do it this way it would exactly be the same because we didn't specify the next one and you can
also perform revel and reward does exactly the same as far as our turn it into rule wise.
Okay.
And that's really the whole basic idea reshape essentially the reshape is actually specifying the final
shape that you will like it to be and that's that's the function reshape.
And it's useful for the purpose of tensor operation right.
With that there's quite a lot to cover.
I really hope that you got much all of that and that's detail the concepts that we wanted to cover very
briefly albeit we cover element wise operations broadcasting dot product as well as reshaping.
I hope that has been useful.
There's just one more concept one more thing that I want to cover.
I think I owe you this which is the end game and also a shape.
So let's look at how you actually do this.
So extreme thought and I'm okay.
I would tell you as a two dimension and do extreme shape will tell you as a two by two and the lasting
is extra data type and it would tell you as integer 64.
Okay.
So once again thank you for watching.
I look forward to seeing you in the next video.