Hey guys welcome back to the course.
All right on deck we have our first case study where we're going to take a theoretical business and
show you how you would think through it.
And finally model out everything for it.
In this case we're going to go over the business model of an in-person programming boot camp which is
really quite a growth industry nowadays if you're not familiar with what I'm talking about.
Boot camps are a business that got popular more or less in the last five years.
You see the thing is tech companies have an insatiable demand for programmers and filling programming
positions is one of the hardest things for them to do.
Frankly they're just not enough programmers to fill the demand and thus we see these bizarre market
economics where you have Apple and Google and Facebook paying something like $45000 to a recruiter just
for the introduction to a programmer who needs a job.
It's gotten crazy but we are there.
So boot camp sprung up as a way to help facilitate the growth in supply.
The idea is that you apply or just sign up in the case of the less reputable ones and then you go through
an intensive training course that lasts anywhere from two to four months usually at the end of the boot
camp.
The idea is that you're now effectively vetted by the organization and then they help you find placement
for your job which to be honest isn't terribly hard.
Assuming that he did it even moderate.
Good job of training the person in the first place.
So in this case study we're going to tear down on that specific business model these boot camps typically
cost something like a semester of private college tuition to attend and some are downright cutthroat
to get into if you're still blinking on this.
What I'm talking about.
Just go google programming bootcamp Plus the name of any major city and you'll see them.
You can also look at a site called course report or put in the resources which ranks them out and discusses
their pros and cons.
General Assembly if you ever heard that one it's a well-known company that first started off with bootcamps
and has expanded but still offers classes in a very similar ish model.
So what do you think we're going to run into when we crack open the model of a in-person programming
bootcamp.
Well we're selling a high ticket item to a small to medium sized group of people.
Do we want a million customers.
No.
We can only reasonably handle a handful of them actually.
How do you think will advertising get attention.
Well it really just depends.
But when you're charging upwards of $10000 for two to four months of training I'd say you have some
room to experiment now on the cost side.
What do you think we're going to have to pay for.
While teachers administrators possibly even paid speakers.
We have overhead in that we have to rent or own buildings.
We might have to handle or supply computers and we might need to handle outreach in some way after they
graduate presumably.
So take a sec to make sure you can wrap your head around the bizarre world of the programming bootcamp
and then join us in the next lecture when we start going over what a model for a theoretical bootcamp
called I don't know we'll call it standard assembly might look like.
All right guys.
See you then.