Hey guys welcome back to the course.
I'm sorry I have to break this to you but when it comes to the process of modeling there is no such
thing as perfection.
You're going to make mistakes.
It's going to happen but you don't have to sweat too much about it.
It's not about preventing as much as it is about being able to catch them.
So you can fix them.
You don't want to realize that you made a silly error in your modeling after you've sent it with your
pitch decks and your projections out to potential investors.
So when it comes to hers there are two main types of errors that I want you to be aware of.
One is a logical error.
And the other is a technical error a logical error would be the equivalent of thinking you can sell
600 lemonade cups in an hour.
It's totally wrong but Excel or any other spreadsheet program is going to let you build it and it won't
make any complaints.
All the calculations would still calculate.
So for these types of errors we do what are called sanity checks.
You pause and ask yourself Is this really possible.
Selling 600 cups in an hour.
Reasonable.
Let's see that means I have to sell 10 cups per minute or a cup every six seconds.
Not a chance in hell especially from one lemonade stand in one location.
So we can do sanity checks before and after we create our models.
I prefer to do them beforehand so it sets the stage for what is reasonable.
So I know what range I need to be in to be in the ballpark of reality.
Now technical errors are a little different.
There are the errors that you make in the process of modeling these are putting in the wrong formulas.
Linking to the wrong cells.
This is the equivalent of forgetting to put a semi-colon in your C++ senior project.
And if you don't hear a coder you know what I mean.
Luckily for you it's really easy to do error checking in Excel.
Here's how we might do simple airchecks in her lemonade stand model.
So this was the sanity check that we did before we started building the model.
Right and this is not something that Excel can tell you whether you're right or wrong you're going to
have to check against yourself.
Can you actually sell three cups per minute.
Maybe not.
Right.
And that's where we might have set some more realistic expectations of maybe selling half a cup every
minute.
So this is the sanity check.
Now what do we do with error checking in the models.
So with error checking it's looking at opportunities within your model to see if what the calculations
are for certain values is what you would expect and some of the easiest places for those opportunities
are when you're pulling in or aggregating values from multiple sources.
So in our multiple locations we have a lot of opportunities we could check traffic numbers we could
check purchases we could check pretty much any of these summary lines against what we would expect.
Right.
So let's take a look at the gross revenue number if I want to check to make sure this whole line is
correct.
Okay.
So one way I can do that is I'm going to compare that to say the sum of all the gross revenue.
I'm just going to actually pull some of the gross revenues for each of these locations
so on the surface they look this same or close to being the same.
They look different.
Right.
I'll tell you why it's different in minute in the way you want to compare them than I can write something
simple with an if statement I can say if this all of that which is the sum of all the gross revenues
is equal to this gross revenue that I calculated in a different way.
If it's the same give me empty quotes or give me a blank.
I don't want to see anything if it's correct and don't show anything but if it's not correct.
Give me an error now because it's a message you have put it in quotes as a string or a text.
In this this formula here it's Close's.
Now there's an error.
So it shows up and if I copy this formula all the way across I can visually see if there are any other
errors here.
Now there's no other errors.
Let me see what's going on here in this area.
Well when I look at the formula like hey there's a extra plus one here.
What the hell's going on then I can fix the formula.
And now the error is gone.
So building these kinds of error checks adding an extra line and adding formulas to check each of these
can tell you if you messed up something right.
So I can do this for all of the other items and check and if any of the errors show then you can pinpoint
where the error is coming from and then fix it.
So where and when you do sanity checks and error checks.
Well you do sanity checks of all your key assumptions and outputs is the foot traffic figure reasonable
on a Saturday afternoon is the number of cups I need to sell reasonable.
Now you do error checking of any intermediate and final results or calculations in your models.
This helps you pinpoint any errors you make.
If you only check at the very end and you have a very long and complicated model it can be really hard
for you to go all the way back to finding where that error is by checking out when something is Hauffe.
It's a lot easier to find out.