Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
We're going to take a moment to address some of the questions you might have and a few questions that
we thought would be interesting for you to see.
All right the second three we were talking about some of the things you need to understand before you
model.
So really we're just talking about best practices.
Well so I'll start off with the first question so.
This is totally random sorry.
What I notice is in your models why do you use yellow and blue like yellow background blue font using
a really peculiar choice.
That's a really good question that if you go to UCLA that y has a really good question.
And you know I actually when I first started learning financial modeling and I went to a few of the
workshops and boot camps in Wall Street and learned different kinds of financial modeling and it was
really common practice to use yellow cells with blue fonts.
I didn't really like it at first this seems really got me.
But over time as I built a lot of financial models for different companies for different investors in
different scenarios what I found is that it's impossible to ignore if you're sharing a model with someone
where you want them to know and look at hey this is an assumption.
This is something that you need to look at and then having it in your home is really easy to do that
now it can be any color you want.
You just got to make it very clear to whoever is looking at your model what they represent.
Yeah.
And if you guys have skipped ahead to the case study where I talked about my startup you'll notice that
like the whole thing is color coded.
We didn't we didn't use yellow and blue but we use a whole bunch of like greens and blues and yellows
and stuff like that.
So yeah I mean it's really just like use it like a highlighter.
Right.
You bring used color to bring people's attention toward something.
But then also one thing I will say is that you can also add color and fonts and even small graphics
and like that because it makes your model look more polished right like presentation is so much especially
if you're trying to show it to someone else or in my case.
I like using things that are prettier to look at.
And so I have an iPhone.
But you know on like a like a hardware standpoint it's clearly inferior to all the Samsung and the Android
phones.
But I like it because it looks better.
Right.
So there's is something we said about adding some color as a way to focus attention but then also make
it look more polished even if it's not yeah absolutely as a VC What do you expect out of the model would
you expect a startup to project profits or do you expect them to break even for those years at home
wondering why is even a question.
Startups in general and you guys read my intro to entrepreneurship.
We talk about this what makes a startup a startup while a startup is a company that is designed to grow
as fast as possible.
And so when you're thinking of an organization in terms of we need to grow as fast as possible.
That oftentimes you're not thinking about profit right because if you're taking profit then therefore
you are not growing as fast as possible.
You should be reinvesting that.
So with that in mind we were telling you about startups and we're looking at a model you know I've seen
people do it multiple ways.
Generally what I look for a user look for and what I've seen of the consensus is that people don't want
to invest in something that is permanently going to break even even if they know that like this is the
name of the game right.
We don't make money until we figure out how to make money later on down the road.
We focus on user acquisition at the for at the very beginning.
Generally what I have noticed is people will show heavy heavy investment in the first three years and
then they'll start showing a profit.
That kind of inverses and balloons and gets larger as you get towards like the six year mark.
Now part of the reason why that is and if you're really savvy what you can do is when you're talking
to a venture capitalist look at when they raise their fund.
Right.
So wait venture capital works is there's a bunch of people who are in suits and they find investments
for a fund.
You know at the very beginning what they do is they go to really really rich people or large institutions
and they raise a large like multimillion dollar fund and then it's up to them to go invest that now
in general venture capital funds last seven years.
I don't know why it's just seven years that's like the asset class.
So what you can do is if you're talking to a venture capitalist and you know that they have four years
left in their fund you should probably show that you're going to make profit within four years.
That's one way of doing it.
That's a very savvy way of doing it.
But in general since it's a seven year timeframe you could do fine just showing that hey year five six
we start getting into the situation we have so much profit we don't know what to do with it.
And that's not to say that you don't say like hey we're making tons of money and reinvesting it.
You're just saying in the future it's unavoidable that we're making profit versus at the very beginning
whatever it is we're building up our economies of scale or we're building up our user base or we're
in a change advertising tactics halfway through to something that's more lean.
As long as you show that there's a transition and it happens eventually.
Here's the thing I also have capital.
We all know that it's just B.S. And we just kind of want to believe.
But in general we want to make sure that you understand what profit is right.
So if you don't have profits somewhere in it then we get a little bit worried that this is almost like
a hobby business.
Since you are in mergers and acquisitions.
So there's you guys in mergers and acquisitions you deal with mergers and acquisitions either you're
a consultant as a third party helping facilitate the process of a larger company buying a smaller one
or merging with one or you're someone within a company that does all the due diligence before you buy
a company like selecting them figuring out what they're worth negotiating etc..
So the main reason why people merge or buy each other is because of that horrible buzz word synergy.
Right.
And synergy is just like the simplest way I can explain it is in business terms it's one plus one equals
three.
Right.
So if I have one company that raises cows and one company that sells meat by virtue of sticking those
two together and by virtue of the cooperation and collaboration you can now bring to them bring to this
organization they will do better than the sum of those two pieces separately.
So that's synergy.
So my question was in M&amp;A when you're doing a deal are you're evaluating a deal.
Do you build synergy into your model beforehand like do you show.
This is our.
These are numbers now and here's after we acquire them and this changes something fundamentally And
here's the difference.
Or is it just something you talk about verbally because oftentimes it's so subjective.
That's a good question.
When I was working M&amp;A we actually did not rule out the synergy from a potential acquisition or merger.
So at the time it was with the group where we were underwriting all of them in a deal.
So when we were looking at a potential deal we had a model for what our business was going to be.
You know before the merger and what our business would be after the merger post-merger and we looked
at synergies both on kind of the top line as well as the bottom line so there may be some synergies
where combining would allow some cross-selling of products for instance or some you know cross-pollination
of of of the customers.
And then on the cost side we look at potential ways to cut costs especially redundant parts of the businesses
and then we would quantify that and then looked at how it impacts the bottom line of our main business.
So if you were at a public business and we look at the impact on earnings and I imagine its probably
different from organization organization.
Yeah maybe.
I can imagine Goldman Sachs maybe they don't maybe they do or I don't know.
One other question Nancy.
This kind of relates back to Section 2 but since we're talking about kind of best practices mirror Section
2 we were doing a lemonade stand and we are trying to figure out how much profit we should shoot for.
Right and the way we did that was by figuring out what's our what what is our time worth.
And then using that and going backwards and saying well that's being 40 40 hours a week on it.
I know you paid this much Therefore per week I need to make this much profit.
What do you do with a situation where you're not actively participating in the business and maybe you
don't even have a employee.
Maybe you just have a partner who's running it and that partner does not get compensated or compensated
significantly.
So I would assume that you would still have some sort of an ownership stake or some sort of stake in
the business.
Right.
So one way to do that is as a financial model that is projected for the business you would have an idea
of the profits that would be made from it in any kind of distributions that would be made from that.
And so based on your ownership stake you can see what that would look like over the project or the period
of the projection.
And then he can determine whether that's worth it or not for the initial effort.
You've got to put in in order to get that state.
Yeah I mean have you ever seen it where people instead of valuing their time the value like their equity
like their the value of the company.
And if I put about this amount of time and do it I need to see growth in the company of this much value.
You could I think you could do better I guess depends on kind of what your role with that organization
would be.
I've got a question for you.
I think there may be a lot of students who you know maybe starting businesses that are very new or you
know they may think to themselves Hey even I have a business that has a completely different business
model I can't find anything else out there that you know of anybody that's doing something similar.
What are my options in terms of financial modeling.
How do you know.
Well I mean it's it's tough right.
I mean anytime you blaze your own trail you kind of have to.
You have to invent a lot of things you do along the way.
I mean two things one there really are no financial models that don't have a comparable.
You might say like I've never seen someone do it before.
Yeah I mean maybe you just haven't looked enough.
You can always find something that's at least like 70 percent similar.
I mean you can come up with some crazy pricing but you can also find things that are are similar to
it.
Right.
Even if you had price that was fluctuating based off of astrological signs.
Like you could still find a business that uses external indicators to price their business commodity
businesses do that all the time.
They look at a stock price and based on that stock price which is also just almost as arbitrary as Astrology
will base their whatever so whatever commodity whether they're trying to sell it for.
So one I think you need to do more research is to find something that's comparable.
You might not find a hundred percent fit.
Obviously you might find 50 percent or 60 percent but that's close enough because the number two point
is we're making this stuff up.
I mean when you're projecting something and it's brand new whatever you put down is your best guess.
And as soon as you start getting into it from day one you're going to start getting data back and you're
going to completely change it if you're wrong.
So it's not always something to fret about to watch.
I mean I try to do your best if you have some goofy system but some goofy pricing systems or something
you can still take a guess at how many people are going to be physically looking at your product or
looking at your service.
Right.
So then it's really just a question of can you average out your prices.
Can you itemize it like this whether I'm selling this is it might be average of this price or this price
and kind of just go from there.
Because the thing is that if you have an unknown business model you're doing something brand new.
Well really the financial model that's only like one or two points right early just like your price.
I mean that's it really.
You still have you're still going to employees are still going.
A basic expenses start up expenses.
You're still going to have unit costs.
Cost of goods sold well depending on where it is.
So really changes a couple of things.
I really wouldn't fret about it.
We make this stuff up.
I know last point I probably say is like if you're trying to if you're saying like no I haven't I need
to have this exactly right right now.
And you haven't even stepped one foot into the business.
Well then you kind of have like a lead nightmare right.
You don't.
What are you trying to do are you trying to raise money before you've even tried the business.
I understand that's a thing like some people do raise money before they even try something like jet
dot com right.
That has raised billions of dollars on an idea.
But I would just generally say if that's the case you have way bigger problems.
That's a terrible way of going about it.
Yeah I would just like to add you know whatever your business is you're still going to have customers
hopefully that are going to pay you for something.
So think about that process that you're going to have to go through.
Your customer is going to have to go through to become a customer and then to pay you what are the decisions
that they got to make.
What are the offers that they're going to see and how you can use that as a basis for building out your
model.
Yeah it makes sense.
So the way that we're teaching this course we haven't figure this out as we start out with the fundamentals
right.
The things that everybody has in common and we slowly get more complex.
And then we start branching off in individual industries.
So my question is do you know of any industries off the top of your head or situations that are common
enough you know about it where the fundamentals don't necessarily apply.
Like for instance a business where they don't have operating costs or they don't have employees.
They only have robots or something like that where the foundation is significantly different.
Yeah I can think of an example for kind of exactly what we're doing if you're creating more of a digital
product or something that is where all of the effort is pretty much up front are primarily up front
and there's no inventory there's nothing that gets spoiled.
You don't have rent you don't have office space you don't have employees you're creating a digital asset
that then gets sold on a regular basis.
That's a very different model than say if you're running a restaurant where you know every time you
make a sale you still have to pay for the food.
You still got to pay for the labor.
You have lights that keep buying the AC you have all of those things that are baked into each incremental
sale.
But on the digital side may be very different.
But I think also one thing it's worth pointing out there is like even if you're doing a digital good
that doesn't have costs of goods sold well one technically it does have cost of goods sold.
Technically your storage is not free.
Technically your bandwidth is not free.
I mean it's peanuts but it's not.
You can never escape that completely.
Another thing is like OK so maybe you don't have operating expenses but at that point like if your friend
sends let's say you're mailing a course business right like going online courses.
Sure.
From the perspective of my first course I didn't have operating expenses because once I put it up you
know I didn't really have to do anything to it.
But if your idea is to make the second one then the upfront work you do for the second one then becomes
your operating expenses.
Right because now you are running.
You have revenue.
You are not a big question mark as to how you're running this business so you see that a lot.
Often with digital goods it's like up front work well your upfront work is no longer your startup costs
because you're not starting a business for every single new product.
Yeah it's one of those things it's like.
Sure it might be different but it's going be different by one small thing.
Or if you really think about it it's not really that different go.
OK so guys if you have any other questions ask them in the.
And then just tag Simon or I or him put in the Q&amp;A if you want to make us work for it.
Otherwise we will see you in the next section.
See you later.