All right so now we're looking at the revenue worksheet so we're looking at something like the standard
Assembly we might have some products like this.
Right.
We have some full time bootcamps some part time bootcamps and online course offerings in and we want
to think about it is you're going to start off with a certain number of these courses for each of them
and you're going to be adding some over time.
So but there's a limit to how many you can do.
Right.
So depending on the space the only rooms you have there's really a limit for how many full time bootcamps
you can do and how many part time bootcamps you can do.
OK.
And how how often you can.
Adam So when we did think about that is we think about some starting value.
How many there starting off with.
And then we think about eventually what is the max number of courses that we can do and how often are
we going to be adding a course for each of these.
How many seats are available for each class.
So we're looking at the spaces before we can fit about 100 chairs and some tables and so the max capacity
we're going to say for these courses these in-person courses is 100.
Technically the online courses don't have an upper limit.
However this business model requires that there is a tutor and that does one on ones with with the students.
So there is going to be a little bit limit.
And so we're going to put a limit of 500 for now and there's going to be a price for each of these products.
Right.
And there's going to be some cost of acquiring a student.
OK.
So right now we're going to make some assumptions here but we can change this later we're just putting
some dummy numbers here where basically if you're able to charge 13 grand you better be able to spend
a few hundred bucks to acquire a student.
So the other thing that we're going to think about for these products is you know we're going to start
off with a certain number of seats available for those courses right but we're not going to start off
100 percent sold or utilize initially it's going to take us some time to ramp up and do marketing and
kind of fill things up so we may start with much lower utilization rates.
On day one when a launch is slow you get to higher utilization.
We may be nearly fully utilized for the full time 2 cans for the part time is a little bit last money
for online even less than that.
And how long is it going to take us to go from here.
The starting point to the stabilized point.
Right.
So that's where this is and the length of the program the way we're going to model it to keep things
simple is because we you know if you have length of a program they're paying for three months of the
program for this price.
Right.
But then you don't get to collect that every month.
It's a one time payment and then you have them for three months now over time as you run this program
we're going to be able to do is we're just going to take that and assume you get it evenly across the
length of the program.
Just to simplify the model.
Right now now we're going to also assume that there is some sort of a refund rate not all students are
going to stay there.
So then when we have these starting assumptions then we can start to kind of build things out a little
bit.
Now this right here the timing of it this actually came from what we were doing before and the start
of work.
Right.
Remember more of this and this year.
So net Let's see how that works now.
So here we have the months and for the permitting.
We're doing everything here we're doing something called the dummy numbers.
We're either putting a 1 or 0 or a 1 is means that we are in that period a period permitting period
in months 1 to three because what the assumptions are.
And once that's done see how construction kicks in for our assumption I think we had it at six months
so then it goes from four to nine.
And then the launch happens after construction.
And I think we set it for another three months which happens.
So then total happening throughout during the build that period on launch is 12 months.
And then once we're active we will get active post-launch starting in month 13 here.
We don't we just care about putting ones and zeroes in these for just to know where they're at.
Okay.
And we're going to see how this is relevant to later because we need to keep track of things because
the active part we're not going to be able to have students paying students while you're getting Permatang
And while you're doing construction right.
But during those periods we're still need we still need to track it because we're actually spending
money at that time.
OK so now that we have the timing let's start with how we can start thinking about the courses.
Right.
So we may start with thinking about how many courses do we have and we all know what that kick in though
after we actually go active we see that so see here it kicks in when we start going active and it kicks
in at these starting values that we started with.
And the way it's modeled here it allows us to go from the starting point and then to grow at the rates
that we put put there where a certain number of courses.
Right.
So we're adding online courses a lot faster than we're adding full time boot camps.
And we see that we slowly at the course count until we reach some sort of a stabilized rate for 9:24
which actually came from the column D here.
See that great.
So once we have the course count then what we're going to have then we can start tackling the total
available capacity.
So this one is pretty easy it's going to be the number of courses times the max capacity for each course
right.
We have the assumptions earlier right here.
A hundred.
One hundred and five hundred.
So then we just have the number of courses times the capacity.
And sometimes in modeling there's a reason why created left so much space here is because sometimes
when you have these different assumptions it's easier to pull them to the side here.
So the 100 500 you know pull them here and so I can look at it when I do the modeling.
At this level.
So I can just refer to those values.
If you look at this I'm just referring to this value here rather than having go back to the top.
All right then utilization remember from here to here we're doing the same thing right.
So we got to wait till it's the correct month when we launch and when we launch we're starting at the
initial utilization and then we're slowly going all the way to the stabilize utilization rate which
is like what we set here.
So then based on a realization then we have the actual number of seats sold for each of these programs.
That's going to be the utilization times the seats that are available.
So initially it's not going to be as high.
Right.
But then afterwards it starts to get higher then the revenue becomes easier.
Right then the revenue for us is going to be the number of seats sold for each of the programs times
the price but divided by the length of the program so that we're not overcounting the revenue.
Now there's a harder way to do this the harder way to do this is to track when it's paid and then only
only have it come in for one hour of the length of the program.
So if it's one out if it's three months then it only paid in the first month not the second and third
but if you're running this on a monthly basis what you can do is just divide it by the length of the
program because it kind of averages out to be the same.
If you if you have multiple classes from.
So it's like three if you get a third of the first month a third of the second month a third of third
month and you add it up.
You basically have the full price right.
And it would be the same as having the people paying just the full rate in that month.
So the difference is pretty insignificant.
And to model it the other way is a lot harder than what the formula is a lot harder to explain as well.
So there's ways a much simpler and you pretty much can use resolve say you can work with.
So that's why we do it that way.
Now once we have the girls revenues then we can say hooray we will Let's see what the refunds are right.
So we take away the refunds and the refunds because we want to visually track that it's a negative number.
We're going to make it negative.
So then then the combination of the two the gross revenue minus the refunds equals to the net revenues.
Okay so now we have the revenue here in the next lecture.
Let's see how the expenses are model.