Hey welcome back.
This lecture we're going to do the revenue modeling for the smoke chili case study.
Now for this one the big part of modeling the revenue for this is understanding this part what it's
saying is when we actually open the restaurant we're going to start at some sales rate and then we're
going to ramp up to some sort of a honeymoon sales rate.
This is when everybody is super excited but eventually it's going to stabilize at some other rate.
OK so we're going to start off and this is going to take this amount of time to ramp up to the really
high sales figure and then take some other amount of time and then it cools down or ramps back down
to a stabilized figure.
Then after that sales are going to grow at this percentage rate per year.
So why why do it like that right.
Well that's kind of how a lot of restaurants actually operate.
You know if it's a restaurant that is expected to eventually do 1.7 million they're not going to start
there.
They can start as something much lower for grand opening and usually takes some time to ramp up for
them to drive awareness.
And but you know for these kinds of new restaurants sometimes if they're doing well they also go through
a honeymoon period where they're doing sales that are going to be above and beyond what is sustainable.
Then they cool off and then they stabilize at some stabilized rate.
Okay.
So that's what that is.
Now in order to do that we've got to first decide when to actually start the sales.
So this part right here we've done this many times before right.
We're breaking down the startup period into different parts of the start.
So we have a build out period right now that from the start up worksheet where we're seeing it takes
six months this is where you're actually building out the restaurant putting all the fixtures in and
putting all the furniture and appliances in.
And then we accounted for a month of training and then to month grand opening period.
So that's when we want the sales to actually kick in.
The reason we still track the grand opening is because there was a grand opening marketing budget that
was going to be spent there right.
All right so then the next thing we're going to look at is the sales growth.
But we don't want to grow sales before Open's we only only start to count it after it opens right so
we'll see when it starts.
We know that grand opening right here is in month.
So there that's when it actually starts to start increasing at that 3 percent per year rate.
So then that's how you get 12 months you're looking at about 3 percent.
And then after that it continues to grow at that rate.
But this is not something where it's lock step right sales is something that kind of grows consistently
or continuously It's not something where oh a year later you're going to get this jump and then it stays
flat and then another year later you know there's not like rent.
So that's why it's continuous.
It grows a little bit every month.
Now in order to model out the actual topline sales for this we have to treat the timing of the ramp
up the ramp down in the stabilized differently.
We've got to track when it's actually happening right.
So the ramp up happens from grand opening in our case the eighth month.
And then we set the time which was what is it 12 months here.
So that's ramp up so whenever the grand opening happens it's going to go 12 months after that and then
the next 12 months we'll have the cool down.
And then after that it is stabilize what you'll see if we look at this part right here is well see the
this is the ramp up period.
Okay.
And then after that we'll see the ramp down period.
So basically happens after that.
And then after that we get the stabilize.
Okay.
The reason we do that is because we want to be able to do the calculations for the sales for each period
in time.
When our sales is zero before it's grand opening but once it is open we started at that starting rate
right.
What do we have at the starting rate.
We had it at six hundred thousand six hundred thousand sales a year.
Six hundred thousand in sales for the year.
That rate means for that month is going to be fifty thousand six hundred divided by 12 equals to 50000.
And then we're going to grow it to over a year 12 months to the 2.5 million mark.
Right.
So we can do a simple check right here which is have that times 12 see if we're growing it to the correct
figure.
So we are at that point it's at the peak honeymoon phase.
And then what we're doing is we're then ramping it down right so we're going to ramp down to the stabilize
figure.
Right.
So then we're going to ramp it down all the way to here.
And then after that is going to be growing at that the growth rate.
Okay.
So there you go we have that.
So then the sales gross sales would just be the sum of the sales coming from those three periods of
time see that we sum it up now we get this full sales right there.
Gross sales now for a lot of restaurants so you're going to have some promotions you're going to have
also some employee meals and you're going to comp some meals you know to maybe some customers who had
a bad experience or they got the wrong orders or you know there's going to be some things that you're
going to have to replace
that.
Well you will have to determine what that is what the right amount is.
But for a fast casual restaurant you're typically not looking at doing more than five percent of your
sales in terms of promotions.
And for employee meals that's really just the food costs because obviously you're you're not trying
to charge your employees for that but it is thought of as lost sales.
Right.
So we're going to make that adjustment and add all of these in here for these adjustments as a percentage
of the sales.
And then once we adjust for that we have net sales k.
So there you go we have sales and that was actually pretty quick to do.
Right.
Using some known benchmarks we can target what that value is.
Now if you think that hey there's no way I'm going to get close to that because I am not sure Poley
were smoke chili maybe we're going to do it you know to like one point twenty five million mark and
the peak honeymoon is just going to be you know this.
That's right.
You can leave it at what ever you want in that phase here.
And the model will adjust accordingly.
Okay.
So one of the good things to do when you have these projections by month is you may want to just do
a summary by year.
Okay so for here have years 1 through 5 and then use something called a sum if so have this year in
operations here that's calculating when the store actually opens then it starts counting the year.
Right.
So one can only look at once it starts to open and operating.
I want to look at all the figures so they have all the years 1 and going on forward.
And then what I have is then it's some's the appropriate role.
Only if this line here matches the year that it's from.
So when I do that it only some's the gross sales from year 1 and then from year to and then from year
3 and so forth we see that it starts off at some rate it grows it because due to a honeymoon you know
part of the honeymoon here.
Still it's doing better and then it starts slow down and then slowly wraps back up over time.
Okay do the same for taking the sales adjustments and then calculating the net sales as well.
Now in the next lecture we're going to look at the expense side of this.