Hey welcome back to the course and this lecture.
We're going to talk about user segmentation Specifically we're going to do an example of segmenting
users by their usage of a product or service.
Now usage might not be relevant for those of you who are selling one off products where the customer
either buys it or they don't.
So just focus on the process of segmentation and how we do that in spreadsheets.
You can use these techniques to segment your customers based on different factors.
For those of you who might be building an app where how much money you make or how you charge depends
on how often or how much someone uses your product.
Listen up in this example we're going to look at how segmenting users by usage can help you model a
business model that has different pricing tiers based on usage.
Let's see what that looks like.
All right let's look at an example of segmenting by usage.
OK.
So let's say this is all given to us it is a user growth figures that have been derived already and
there's some sort of attrition and that's bottom roll.
Here's the actual active users in any given month.
So with that as a given and let's say we want to look at the usage of the users based on how many sessions
they use so this is some sort of service that is a paper use and it is segmented by the usage.
Okay.
And let's say that the team that's doing this they've done something similar before they kind of have
an idea.
They've tested it out they think that the distribution is going to look something like this.
And then over time they think the vast majority are going to kind of lump in the early parts here that
are going to use very little versus a few power users here that are going to use a lot.
That's going to make up the bulk of the revenue.
OK.
So how will we model that out.
Right.
So here we have four distributions in four years now with four years.
We're going to need to know what year we're in right.
And so that's why we have a column here year depending on the months.
Now this is really easy to generate.
Right.
We know that there's months there so we may just put ones in the first 12 months here and then in month
13.
We go back to the first month and then we add one and then we copy that formula all the way across then
it will automatically add the other years there.
Okay.
So we have that now and how we correctly you have the right distribution in each of these columns.
Well the way we're going to do that is through a triple A nested IF statement because we're choosing
between four things here.
Okay.
So it sounds complicated but it really isn't.
When you see it in action.
All right let's see how it works.
So here we're going to say if if the year.
Now we want to fix the ROE of the year rates.
We're going to put a little dollar sign in front of it to cause every formula is going to refer to that
row right there.
We'll see if it equals to 1 then we want it to equal to that value right here.
Right.
If it isn't let's do another check we go if is equal to 2.
Then I want it to equal to the second value here.
And if not then let's check one more time.
If it is equal to 3 that third year then we want to take this one and if it's none of those then we
want it to equal up to that one.
Right now here this formula is going to give us the correct answer for the first year but it's going
to give us an error for all the other years.
The reason for that is we we as we move this formula across to the right.
We want to make sure the references to the this box here stays the same.
OK.
So what that means if this here would copy it down first row.
It looks correct.
It matches the first year right.
But if we move across now it's going to refer to the second year.
You see that that's because these formulas here have been shifted.
OK.
So we're going to fix that now the way we're going to fix that is we're going to go to this where all
the values are.
We're going to fix the columns so we're going to put a dollar sign in front of all of the letters for
those values that we're pulling from the front of the B C D.
So all of all of these references here now that we have that we're going to copy that again and you'll
see this is correct.
OK so now that it's correct we can we can do this for the rest of the cells we're in copy and we're
in a piece of formulas.
And just for a sanity check we know that it's got to change from year one to two 2 to three.
Right.
So let's just visually see that looks right.
So in months 12 and 13.
OK that changes that change looks right from 24 to 25 years two to three.
OK that looks correct.
And then for the last one month 36 and 37.
OK.
It looks right now.
So you can visually see whether you've done it correctly or not.
When it's something like this.
All right so now that we have the distribution percentage correct distribution percentages for these
uses screws for every month of the projection we start calculating the actual number of users.
And when you're thinking about users and people you know usually we want to do something where it's
a whole person or whole customer not just a partial one.
What does a half customer mean.
Right.
So one way to do that is through a function call round rounds.
Any number that you put in by to the number of digits.
OK but we want to round down so that because you know if it's half a user you don't want to round it
to four users so we're going to round down the number.
OK.
What are we going around down we're going to round down the active number of users times the the percentage
that is of that usage group.
OK.
So we're going to round that down and we go around to zero digits.
So that's a whole number.
You see that as a whole number of users and we're going to see the same for all of these here because
if we didn't do that we get all these fractions and it really doesn't make sense.
Fractional customers.
OK so now we have that we can copy pace in and now we have these usage distributions actual user accounts.
Now once where the user counts you can start thinking about pricing and the number of sessions right.
So let's make some assumptions maybe maybe they are going to give away a free it's free for the first
five sessions.
You know anybody that uses that is is going to be free.
They just want to get people used to it so that they can sign up for Pete Sessions.
OK.
And then you know but once they get past 10 sessions it's going to be you know a dollar a session.
OK so a dollar a session here and this is going to be 90 cents you know maybe then it goes down to 75
to 65 to 55 to 45 whatever that is we're just going to put some numbers in here just so we can work
with it.
OK.
And within each group.
This is how we're categorizing them so.
So like let's look at the set group here it means a use at least 200 sessions right.
But that bandwidth error that ranges from 200 to 500 So we've got to say make an assumption about what
is the average usage for that group right for each of these groups.
OK so we're going to make some assumptions here.
This is going to be one is going to be say five.
The average number of sessions here is going to be you know let's say 10 and this one is going to be
let's say from 2015 maybe the average sessions is 30 and this one is going to be 65 125 300 50.
I'm just making stuff up.
Right.
But you get the idea.
You know it should be based on what they're seeing.
Right.
If they have more data around it.
But right now we're going to make some some stuff up just so we have some numbers to work with so you
can see how this plays out.
OK.
So let's say these are going to be the average number of sessions.
So then how do we calculate the revenue in this case.
In this case well we've got the actual number of users here and this is the average number of sessions
that's being used.
Now we've got to fix the column and that's the price that we're paying.
Again fixing the column.
So that's the revenue for that group in that month.
And we do that across all the usage groups.
Now we can get this revenue projection here.
We're going to copy and paste that over and there we go.
Let's see what the total revenue looks like.
So now.
OK.
So then there we go we have to use our distribution right segmented by the usage groups.
It looks like if they have these numbers they're going to be making a whole lot of money later on at
these rates.
OK.
So it's really quite easy to segment if you have some data to go with a ready.
Right.
Otherwise we're going to be guessing.
But you know these this one session five cent it could be anything you could you could label whatever
you want most who you're not going to need this many categories.
You know maybe you just have low medium high or whatever that is it's going to be easy for you to do
that.
The main thing is you need to make some assumptions around the distribution and it means that up to
100 percent obviously based on your users and then that way your numbers can flow correctly from there.
So you can have the distribution than the actual users in each group.
And then from that we can do pricing and usage to calculate revenue.
Now this year we could have separated this in for better practice.
We would separate and just do a whole row on total sessions by each group and then price for the revenue.
Right.
But for simplicity just for this one it's not too complicated it's pretty easy to tell.
So it's you can make that tradeoff.
So why did we model out 10 plus user segments.
Why didn't we just segment by the pricing tears.
Well since we have the data and since the pricing tiers might change in the future modeling the segments
that are available gives the model a bit more flexibility if you're pricing to your changes.
The modifications are pretty easy to implement in the model but if you had just a lump the usage groups
altogether you may have to and lump them or undo the model or build the brand new one if you're changing
things if you change the labels to how we segment the users based on other factors like maybe what channel
they came from or geography or whatever is relevant to your business.
You can segment based on different factors.
The key here is to make sure you have a separate role and a separate label for each segment.