Her I remember when we first did the Ewart's case study we had something like this right.
We had some assumptions around the subscription of the spots for the shared desks we get oversubscribed
because not everybody is going to show up at the same time.
But for the private desk in the private offices we don't oversubscribed and then we were able to model
things out starting with occupancy going to calculating gross rents and then tackling a vacancy.
Now the problem with this is that it assumes on month one we have something that doesn't factor in the
startup period right.
We're doing build now we're doing a launch and we're kind of spending a lot of cash before we're actually
able to pull in revenue.
So in our updated model we have to factor that in.
So in our updated model the assumptions here look the same up top up what we need to know is the timing
of it.
So here we have the timing of closing is just basically when we actually bought things.
Okay so closing what happened in the first month but then permitting starts right away and then at last
for you know in our assumption 3 months.
And then there was then construction that happens some period after that.
Right now I have nine months and then we have the launch that's happening here.
Okay.
And then so from there all the way from the beginning is kind of a through out period of before it becomes
active before we start taking in revenue right.
Then after that only after that when it's no longer doing all that stuff we're like fully activated.
Okay.
Right here.
And that's when we start pulling in getting customers to come in and start paying.
So that's why we needed to adjust this model in this way because you can't bring people in before you're
done with construction be doing your launch and everything right.
So then then only after that we can calculate again.
Same way we calculate the girl's rents and the vacancies and then we can get to net rents.
So the big difference here is looking at the timing here and the timing comes from looking at this the
startup page closing is always a good way to just say it's happening right away basically in the first
month.
And then you know for things that have a real estate element to it usually you can have some sort of
a permuting period getting approvals zoning and then you can start construction right.
Then after you do construction you have some sort of a launch period.
OK.
So that's what we're doing here.
We have all these startup expenses but you're not spending them all on day one you're spending them
in those corresponding parts.
Now we do the timing and the revenue as well because we don't want to kick that in again before the
actual timing starts.
So there you go.
That is our revenue and in the next like we're going to talk about the expenses.