You guys will come back to the course.
OK so we're moving on in this mega model and we're going to start talking about the second and third
tabs.
And my guess we get into the fourth So it's year one use of funds monthly income statement right here.
And then just the regular income statement.
So most of these numbers that are set up in this are coming from our assumptions and data sheet here.
This is where most of these variables are.
And if you click into these you can usually see it's usually you can see that it's still referenced
backwards.
You'll see that it's looking at a specific sheet.
So this is taking it from right here like this is referring back to the CEO salary.
I believe that was back in the original one and then of like here for instance you can see school acquisition
per sales that's pulling it from over here.
Yeah that's point from right here.
Yes.
So as we mess with this you would obviously see these things changing quite a bit.
Okay.
So we did Year One use of funds.
So the idea here was we were raising money right.
And we need to show what we're going to spend their money on.
I mean that's a pretty standard one.
You know if you aren't raising money generally you will want to make an expense sheet.
And I generally suggest making expenses each separate than your revenue.
It's a lot easier to just say here's all the things that cost money.
Next she hears all the things that make money and then later kind of merge them together.
When you get into more of these standard things like an income statement why did we do an income statement.
Well in general corporations have three different types of essentially financial sheets to show you
have income statements balance sheets and then profit and loss.
Right.
So PNL income statements and then balance sheet balance sheets really focus more on the assets you own
monthly income is kind of just a way of looking at are you making money this month or losing it and
then profit and loss is more of a macro view.
How is going to look this year versus next year.
Really it's like a summary a profit and loss is probably the most kind of 10000 you can get with a company's
financial model.
So we put an income statement.
And the reason why was because we were a startup and we dealing largely a start up investors are investors
just don't have time for those other ones.
I mean nice that you put a balance sheet or profit and loss but they just don't care.
A lot of that stuff is just bureaucratic and it's helpful for a Fortune 500 company because they already
have six thousand employees for a startup you're just kind of wasting time.
So generally I just suggest go is an income statement.
I mean it's easiest way of doing it.
The rest of it just doesn't particularly matter or it's not high priority.
So let's look at the year one use of funds.
So we did year one because we assumed we would spend all of the money we made essentially in one year
generally speaking.
And this is an interesting old tidbit takeaway.
Nowadays the standard is when you are raising money.
Investors want to make sure that you're raising enough for at least 18 months.
18 months is a year and a half.
You can raise a little bit more at 24 but they're going to put you somewhere they want you to be in
that range.
A year is too short.
They just don't think that's realistic.
One thing to keep in mind is that fundraising takes a lot of time.
So you have to do that once a year.
That's crazy.
But then also if this money is in the last two three years then you should probably just raise less
money.
Right.
So why are we risking their extra capital if we can go 18 months with a quarter or giving year half
of what we're giving you.
So that's the general thinking behind it.
That's why we focus on year 1.
And you kind of see if you do look at this well we spend about two thirds of it.
So this is the most immediate way or most immediate use of the investor cash.
So what we did is we just split it up into sections that had payroll we had technology consulting marketing
and other SDN a as TNA is selling general and administrative.
It's just an accounting term.
A lot of this jargon you guys see you might think in going to business school how can I possibly figure
out all this jargon.
It doesn't really matter as long as you know accounting costs money legal costs money rent costs money.
You only have a couple things when your profit is you really should be fine.
Also if someone just looks it over for you they can often find these mistakes or you know you're going
to just Google accounting terms.
And I swear in 30 minutes you can figure out a lot of these terms.
You only have to learn at once what's gross profit gross profit is how much money you make on selling
something compared to how much it cost to make that that individual thing not including things like
overhead which are fixed expenses of nothing.
Are there regardless of how many things you make or sell you know those things you can learn very very
quickly.
So as DNA is kind of just like the miscellaneous been you know I guess you put it down here but regardless
there Miscellanies right here.
And really it's more buffer.
So this is like a contingency or things we just didn't know where to put you know like we said before
contingencies are always very important and that's why we put buffer.
We also know that we kind of baked in our contingency into the assumptions over here and a lot of places
we put these numbers higher or lower.
Just to give us extra padding.
All right so back to this.
So you can see over here is underneath payroll.
We actually then took those positions over here and we can collapse them into an easier way to look
at it.
So we said executive was these three you know technology and sales and so we just kind of collapsed
them down here.
So you can get a really quick look at what does the organization look like at the very beginning and
over time.
And then what we did over here is we put the percentage of the total.
Right.
So really this is just a calculation you add up all your payroll and then divide it by how much that
cost.
And the reason why we did this was because people do have opinions on how much you should be spending
for executives or how much you should be spending on sales or development.
Some investors want to see massive amount of spending on development because they think that's an asset
and a competitive advantage regardless of what you do.
And the other ones you know might be more sales oriented or think that you're spending too much on sales.
People have opinions about that.
So it's very easy to say look at this and go oh 20 years on an executive that is too much or too little.
Whatever.
So if I look at that and go exactly as you high I'll go back here and edit this out maybe and delete
them on fire myself.
Then you can see down here re-adjusted did the payroll total and taxes and benefits taxes and benefits.
As you can see right here percentage of the total up here it's about 3 percent.
But we got that taxes and benefits remember from the assumption sheet because we did we guessed it was
like 30 percent for a big 20 percent for benefits.
Change that and you'll change the numbers.
And then over here you can kind of see this is pretty static as it moves across.
But you see that we Franzen's are hiring data entry as we go.
And you'll notice actually I guess all look pretty static except for data entry and then we just add
Q1 Q2 Q3 to Q4 which I'll admit is a little bit corporate But again it's helpful to look at this.
I go OK you spent you're going to spend $120000 in payroll your first three months basically you just
give them reference points to dispute it or just answer questions more quickly.
Sometimes they don't want to look into the details so it's a lot easier to look at these technology
and web hosting and software I don't know why are spending 20 grand on web hosting software and subscriptions
are just expensive especially when you start getting into these enterprise softwares where you know
you have to do a demo.
You sign a contract to use them.
I'm kind of surprised we put that as low as it was.
I figured we'd probably use more.
But while retrospection in total technologies you can see and then it just becomes well 2 percent of
everything added up together.
We could have done it.
So it's like what's the percentage of the technology group and these are the percentages of the payroll
group.
But I mean that's a little excessive.
I see them consulting.
OK well we kind of figured we would need consultants just because what we are trying to put together
had a lot of expertise in it and it's hard to find one CTO can cover all of that.
And we also wanted to work with contract developers at the very beginning to get it up and off the ground
so that's where we put this informational architecture.
Specifically it's called I say what it refers to is people who specialize in what text you should say
on your Web site in what area in what order.
So they're focused kind of on the structure of your web site for the maximum absorption for the student.
The problem was that with this application it's not immediately obvious how it works why it's a benefit
and how realistic a student should be with regards to how much money they're going to make in a scholarship.
So we were concerned that people would use it get confused and leave and that's why we thought it be
worthwhile to consult with someone to help kind of do user studies and put it together.
If I had to do it again I would obviously just do this myself.
But you know when you're raising 1.5 million it's not hard to slip in three grand for a consultant for
a month then pass that figure database security Well you're storing people's information for scholarships
you might get some of their personal information and that would be a nightmare if you lost some of that
data.
So it made sense to spend some on getting set up in something that's a little bit more secure than whatever
keeps getting hacked like Sony and Yahoo.
And basically everyone then marketing informational material 60 K for international Mercurials.
Well we kind of figured that we were going to do a direct mail campaign and that's just because the
people that we were working with universities and scholarships are basically in the technological stone
age you'll talk to them on the phone and they'll be like Oh okay great can you fax over your requirements
and I'll be honest I have only used a fax machine one time in my entire life.
I don't even know where I would get a fax machine so that was kind of our thinking there was wow maybe
direct mails the only way to do this is the way we can get our big a big blast of leads coming in to
get this kind of rolling.
And then you know as DNA then we just did accounting right we figured like 300 bucks a month is pretty
good for a part time accountant legal at the very beginning we assumed that there was the inflection
point where it has to be a lot of money mainly because this would probably be around incorporation giving
stock to employees setting up the investor structure and what we call a cap table is a lot at the very
beginning and then ongoing.
We assume that it only be about 3000 a month but there's still a lot and in reality probably what would
have happened is you probably spend 50 in a month and then nothing in the next six months or something
like that.
But it's OK to spread it out like no one's going to call you out on that because you can't see the future.
But you can guess you know 3000 a month on average is pretty good.
How do you get this number.
Well it's relatively easy.
We just had a lawyer we worked with and we also just kind of looked on some Web sites.
You know if you get to like law trades dot.com or Although Avey Oh you can see people's rates and just
look at their activities and figure just guess how many hours they rotate generally lawyers are very
fast they get a lot done in 10 hours so that's kind of we did that recruiting.
We originally I think we got this number from like we write it was from Job posts.
We had post job posts and before we knew how many people responded to a job post we know how much it
costs to put it up.
And then we also knew how much it would cost to like hire someone to go look for someone to hire.
And that's kind of how we bake that together and then travel remember came from the assumptions and
data where we said $500 per month per salesperson.
Well there's three salespeople and I think it was an extra 3000 or something you know office related
expenses of a year 10000.
Yeah it's a lot of staplers I know.
But you'd be surprised if you spend money on.
And let's see past that.
Then we had a big blast of money that we'd have to spend on getting the scholarships up and running.
OK let's look at the income statement.
OK so we know our costs for the first year or how we're getting set up.
So over here this is just our best guess at how our cash is going to look like how much are we going
to spend.
How much do you mean the bank where essentially are we going to be in a year and a half.
Or are we going to need to raise money again.
These are all things that investors want to know.
So kind of just set it up in a way that you could kind of follow along.
So here we assumed get eight schools added per month.
Now this is a little it's not entirely accurate because the sales cycle to get to school is probably
like four months.
And so our assumption was over the course of four months you could get on average a.
In reality we'd only get them over here and you'll see that this is this is actually why it changes
down here.
So anyway on average you're guessing or eating it eight schools per month.
And we got that by memor figuring out how many a salesperson could get and then multiplying it by how
many salespeople we had.
And then down here we were just using some quick numbers just for math.
That's not something you necessarily have to do and you can usually hide these kind of behind the scenes
numbers just to make it look a little bit better.
Get it down here even at market size.
Now market size we put because while we have eight schools on average based on the previous thing or
we said we had a mixed we're heavy on big or heavy on small schools.
Well how many students does that mean.
All right so how many are we actually talking about.
The reason why we did this is because if we left this out people would assume well hey you said your
market was 7 million students.
Why are your numbers so low at the very beginning.
Well because we've only actually message this many students early working with schools for this many
students.
That's why you put that there.
Then down here you have actual subscribers renewal subscriptions doesn't really come into play until
we get farther out.
Remember because it's a yearly subscription if we wanted to change yearly to monthly It would take a
pretty significant reworking of the model but it could be done down here revenue.
Obviously we have no revenue costs.
We're just pulling this from the assumption sheet college acquisition fee.
Remember we said it was like $5000 and we just multiply that by eight.
Remember that's kind of a nebulous number.
We would've figured this out pretty quickly whether or not it's $5000 or there's any real cost associated
at all outside of the person's salary.
So I don't know.
Yeah we kind of did this separately than the salary.
Now down here we put contribution profit.
Now I don't know if you guys had this in school but I did not have contribution profit ever taught to
me.
I use gross profit or cost of goods sold contribution profit.
It's like a British thing or something but basically means all of the expenses associated with delivering
your product.
And then how much you can sell it.
So if we had eight schools and added message anyone or we sent $41000 on getting them then that's where
the whole 41000.
But over here we actually start getting into the area where they start messaging their students.
And then these are the penetration rate numbers.
Remember like 10 percent ish.
And then if they start paying then we're comparing it again to that 41000 that we just spent plus the
maintenance fees of our calculating before him and it was like two bucks per month per person and that's
how we get contribution profit.
The basic idea behind contribution profit is you just want to make sure that on an individual basis
like an individual product basis.
Are you profitable are you not conscious of a negative contribution profit that you seriously have something
wrong.
It's nice to very quickly see this and go ah you have a great amount of contribution profit this will
give you plenty of room to deal with contingency down area people.
This is all just pulled from before and you'll see over here that the salaries come in at the months
that we designated them being added.
That's why you see data entry kind of ramps up later marketing and media.
We pulled this again before and where it's direct mail campaign and printing of marketing materials
is quite expensive and the rest of it you can see here we just did red and black to get that point across
for you know we are not making money when we are making money then what we had was interest on income
interest on debt and tax.
OK.
Those are three things that are worth putting although not necessarily necessary you will impress them
on if you put them because it's like wow you actually thought about that.
Basically what this says is if you gave us one half million dollars we can't spend that all in the first
month.
So over the next six months it will set in a checking or a CD account or something.
So it's going to get some money generated from it.
The negligible especially if you spend the money slowly over time but that's not huge.
So that's what that is.
And then also with debt you pay interest on debt.
So if we end up spending more than we raise then we might end up paying interest on debt or if we just
took a loan on this and this wasn't for equity then we might be paying interest on debt like you took
a bank loan.
I don't know you may be going to say 7 percent a year rates you divide that out and it's like half a
percent per month or something and then you can see net income.
And then this is a great way of just showing where is our cash situation.
And as you can see it goes we just spend spend spend and then while they start messing their students
and then it gets a little bit better and then it starts going.
And then you know we hit another inflection point.
Next school comes on and it just kind of goes down and then up again.
Now the reason why it does that is you look at actual subscribers so this is just kind of a function
of email marketing.
If the school starts promoting your system and they send out an e-mail in the first month that's where
we see that penetration rate 36000.
But then the next one yeah you'll see people trickle in.
The market is not saturated yet.
So generally we just saw it like this like it kind of just habes all the way down until it's done and
that's how we kind of build up to I think the penetration rate that we were expecting.
Although this ends up I think making it a little bit higher.
But yeah that's something you should definitely take into consideration.
You don't make all of your sales right when you send an e-mail.
You do get those over time.
How do we get these numbers.
I think we just pulled these from some benchmark somewhere about email marketing and how many people
have signed up.
I think we also might have pulled it from the Miami-Dade test because we they e-mailed it out but then
we had people sign up at the very beginning but then over the next two months we still had people signing
up.
So we kind of use that as an as an indication.
But you can also tell by the symmetry of this you know slowly going down is largely guesswork.
And so that kind of explains why revenue spikes and then continues to go up.
And then here it kind of evens out with expenses goes down and then spikes again over here and you'll
see that when we get to the graphs and then the next step was the income statement.
Now this one was across three years which is pretty standard usually three to five is what you want
to do.
Certainly for fund raising anything past three or five years you're just projecting too much.
Even Fortune 500 companies have a really hard time projecting what's going to happen in five years.
So that's why I don't it's kind of a waste of time to go past that.
Last thing is just the income statement and really all this is is the monthly one condensed down into
something you can see very quickly.
Well you can see here is the first year you are going to make like $5 million off of this amount of
subscriptions.
This is our gross profit and or that's because it doesn't really cost us that much to put them on the
system.
So digital good essentially our gross profit is pretty much the same thing.
This is a cumulative schools member because we're adding them over time.
They don't disappear and we didn't have school churn which is probably something we could have put into
consideration.
But then you have down here the contribution profit how much we're spending on staffing on point two
of the five the thing on marketing now it's nothing right.
And then everything else I mean didn't we actually have tax sweet sweet tax 600 K spent on basically
nothing.
And then this is your net income now this is and you might have heard of sogers in the Q&amp;A.
Should you show off profit immediately in your financial model to try to fundraise.
I usually say yes but you don't need to show it in the first two three years.
People expect that you know you might be in the red for a while.
The only thing with this was we were pretty close to just making sales.
And it's a SAS System so we weren't trying to raise another round or trying to ramp up marketing in
the middle of this process or anything like that.
So we kind of figured that well we'd actually make some profit pretty quickly and then it would start
to kind of build what you can see here though is it goes up quite a bit and this is because as you bring
on account managers and sales people at first they're not you know it turns into account managers are
only going to be managing a certain amount of people and then they start filling up at a certain point
and then you start hiring more.
And is kind of a threshold problem.
And then let's see the net income you can tell over here you can see here that we predicted on ramping
up quite a bit in sales.
Also keep in mind that these numbers reflect that only 70 percent of the people who sign up and pay
here make it to this group rate.
So if we have a new set of 183 schools Wow this is created by a combination of leftovers here.
But then also average amount of students times the average penetration rate and that's kind of how we
get to this.
OK guys so in the next lecture we'll try to finish it out.
We'll look at the graphs and charts simple revenue and the two scenarios that should do it over.
You guys are enjoying this.
I apologize if this is less structured than what you're used to but I figured to be kind of interesting
for you guys to peer into a real model that was used to raise real money.
OK guys see the next lecture.