Hey guys welcome back to the course this lecture.
We're going to introduce you to a basic marketing concept that you can use as a very useful lens for
understanding your financial models.
This lecture we're going to talk about the concept of funnels Yes funnels like you funnel something
into your mouth or you funnel money out of your ex-husband or wife's business that's called embezzlement.
But with regards to financial models what exactly am I talking about.
Well same isn't any marketing campaign.
We generally like to think of our progress or more specifically our acquisition of users or customers
in distinct phases.
Marketers generally delineate this process into phases because it allows them to see which areas need
focus.
And it's kind of measuring stick for their progress specifically.
Let's say I'm marketing a Web site and I go and run some ads.
How do I measure how effective that ad campaign is.
Slash was well you would have to look at a number of things.
First you'd have to look at the number of people that saw your and then the number clicked then the
number that stayed on your page and didn't immediately leave what we called Bounce.
Then the ones that maybe put say an item in their cart and then finally by the number that end up purchasing
something from you.
So marketers will even go farther and track who for instance than refers others to buy from you if you
guys are in my growth market or class you'll probably remember that one because the number in each phase
progressively gets smaller and smaller.
Remember anything past that first phase of seeing the ad is is obviously going to be a subset of people
that saw the ad and moved on to the next phase because each section is a subset.
You could display this process in the shape of a funnel something probably like this.
If you guys Google marketing funnel you'll see just hundreds of these lots of people go in the top often
called Top funnel by hip marketers and the people that make it all the way through the end are the absolute
number that buy from you sign up or whatever your conversion goal is.
We call that area down the funnel Obviously now with a lot of different disciplines we can gain a certain
level of insight by cross-pollinating these concepts.
Financial modeling really is no different in that regard if you can take manufacturing concepts like
economies of scale or even economics concepts like price sensitivity or even concepts from sales such
as price leverage.
Then you could certainly borrow the concepts of funneling and thinking about things through the paradigm
of a funnel from marketing disciplines.
And we strongly suggest you do so.
In fact I find it really useful when you model to constantly ask yourself could I think of this like
a funnel.
In most cases the most useful way of applying this concept is to user acquisition it's obvious it's
the most obvious way of doing it.
You have to pay money either directly or indirectly to get customers.
So it's probably worth knowing which of your efforts to get them is the most effective and what their
respective funnels look like.
So let's say we run Twitter.
Yes.
That big blue bloated bird that makes us Jack Dorsey and who are the other guy is biz plan guy.
How do we look at users and a basic funnel if we were looking at Twitter.
Well it would be similar to that e-commerce example but a little bit different.
They are obviously a social network and they don't actually sell you anything yet.
So remember that part in their case well they might track the number of people that saw an ad or say
a sponsorship or a news story.
Then the number that went to Twitter the number that didn't immediately leave or bounce and then say
like the number that clicked sign up but abandoned then we could say maybe the number that finally signed
up OK but since the application has a lot more depth than that we might want to go farther and incorporate
more user behaviors into our funnel.
So after that we might track say the number of users that completely fill out their profile.
Then we could say the number of users that add 20 followers for Twitter that's a really big metric for
them.
Then we can do that number of users that send their first tweet.
We can even go and then track them in a linear fashion by how often they come back to the app every
day every week every month whatever.
This in Twitter's case would be helpful because we're essentially tracking who ends up using the system
the most.
They make their money off advertisements and so the more someone clicks refresh and the more pages they
view the more ads they're displayed and theoretically more the more money that Twitter makes.
If I were actually modeling Twitter I would probably make a separate.
In my excel sheet that tracked this process I could then pull in like what percentage of my new users
got to a certain point in the funnel and even what the cost per user getting to that specific point
in the fall was not a fun concept is really helpful because it's a way of imagining what appears to
be a flurry of customer behaviors and it puts them into this linear and logical step by step by step
process.
If you acquire your customers or even just have a landing page that people sign up through you'll probably
want to track this with some sort of a funnel like design in a model a basic funnel could look as simple
as this in the first column you could mark off the stage in your process.
Then next to it Mark the total number of users that made it to that part.
You can then add percentages if you want one thing that's common is to calculate the percentage decrease
from each step to the next.
That is obviously incredibly useful because you might see a 90 percent drop off of one spot and a 5
percent drop off somewhere else.
Guess where are you going to point your attention towards.
So when you put together the model for whatever your business may be ask yourself how do I get my customers
would it be helpful to understand and visualize that acquisition process.
And then last.
Is there actually any other part of my business that I could visualize in a similar way if I ship out
a physical product.
For instance how many break after a week how many break after two weeks how many get returned to me.
That is also a funnel that you could use.
So try to think in terms of funnels if it applies and not only helps you better visualize your process
but it can give you key insights on how to improve and debug your process as it stands.
Not sure what your funnel might look like.
Well actually just google it.
I'm not even joking if you just Google your industry your type of business.
Plus funnel you can you actually see a lot of different examples.
It'll either give you inspiration to make your own or you'll find the exact same model that you need.
We can't honestly cover funnels for every single industry but they're usually pretty simple protip don't
search this specific business.
Don't say pet rock enthusiast subscription model search for subscription business model or funnels for
subscription business the fact factors like pet rocks is nothing to do with it.
OK guys I'll see you in the next lecture.