Hey guys welcome back to the course.
OK.
I want you to go and build a financial model that does everything.
All right.
Got it.
Yeah.
Not possible right.
Well that's a mistake that many entrepreneurs make when they're trying to build a model for their.
They try to do.
Way too many things.
So another useful best practice for modeling is to clearly define your constraints.
It's related to mapping it all out.
But this one is more about limiting what your model actually needs to do.
So too broad and the logic and technical ability required to build the model gets really complicated
if you follow the advice of starting simple and smarm.
You're already off to a good start.
But you still want to further define your constraints.
Yes.
In our lemonade example we started with one location and one product.
But what do we want to look at.
We also limited ourselves to looking at revenue and gross profits.
Only we didn't look at overhead we didn't look at financing.
We didn't look beyond the first two years setting clear constraints can make your model building process
more efficient.
So in addition to deciding what your model needs to be able to do it's just as helpful.
Defining what it does not need to do.