Hey guys welcome back to the course.
Last Lecture we went over one of the best practices that can really help you add some clarity to your
sales and operations part of your model if you've forgotten already.
We're talking about the paradigm of looking at your numbers when applicable as a funnel.
Anytime you have a user or a customer or a prospect progress from one stage to another and then presumably
you want them to go through these stages and that signifies that they're paying you more money or are
more likely to pay you money or they're doing whatever it is that you want them to do like sign up the
best practice in that scenario is to model it like a funnel.
Now let's try to connect this concept back to the case study that we had finished last.
S. coworking space example.
Now what might be an example of a funnel in that type of situation.
Mary this is the coworking space we very UN originally called you works well of course.
The obvious answer to this is we have the standard application of a funnel we could make a marketing
funnel Now Simon obviously didn't model this part yet but one of the costs we will definitely have to
calculate later on when we pick it back up in the course is the cost of customer acquisition what we
pay for every paid customer that comes in the door.
Now depending on how you acquire your customers the funnel process and the cost could vary wildly.
Let's say we were sponsoring events as a way to bring in sales.
My guess is that the funnel might look like we'll say step one.
We contact companies about sponsoring them.
Step two we agree to sponsor them.
Step three we sponsor our first event set for receive a lead or a message of interest from someone who
is in contact with that event and then step five.
We have our sales contact them and then step 6 they become a customer.
Now of course if we didn't use sales and really use like an online form that it might be a little bit
simpler.
But most of these co-working spaces actually have some form of hand-holding to get you in the door and
get you situated.
What we could do with this funnel then is to take the total amount of money we spent sponsoring and
merely divide it by the number of people that reached stage 6 and that funnel for that marketing channel.
That would be our cost of acquisition per customer and we were running ads instead.
We would see a much more traditional funnel displaying ads seeing the ads cooking the ad reading the
page and then signing up.
We could then attribute a cost for each part of the funnel as a way of diagnosing internally what we
need to improve.
Not necessarily something you put in an outward facing model you share with other people but if you're
doing this for internal reasons.
Absolutely.
But then the question is is that the only way we could use funnels with new works.
Well actually of course not.
You could use it on the operations side like we kind of alluded to last lecture.
Let's say you had a very particular process for people becoming customers.
Let's say they have to go through an interview in an onboarding session.
Then they have to go through a free trial.
Then they have to start paying.
It might be maybe a little over the top but we can just imagine that it's like step by step process
every co-working space has a similar process.
Maybe they're just not as intense.
So how would you model that process I just described.
Well you know you could just list out each phase and then list the number of people over a given period
that made it through each stage then you can get a percentage of how many of your leads became a long
term paying customers.
Do you see it when you're modeling something out.
It's a lot easier and more accurate to estimate two things.
The cost of getting a lead and then the percentage of leads that convert then just say getting one thing
calculated which is the cost of getting a converting customer.
It might sound like it's easier but it actually kind of screws you over a little bit.
It won't give you nearly as much insight to use that one number.
Then if you use both of these metrics separately and then use them in tandem to come up with the numbers
you wanted to stick them together.
You just lose a lot of information.
So in almost any case where you have an outbound marketing effort as people are just streaming to you
from everywhere through word of mouth then you need to build out a funnel or at a very minimum just
think of this process like a funnel in order to correctly get the insight and the metrics you need in
your model.
And if you think it's just limited to marketing.
Remember in the multi-step process that someone might complete can be displayed and used like a funnel
trying to calculate say the cost of training your employees funnel trying to calculate the cost of recruiting
new employees funnel.
Try to calculate the number or the percentage of retention of customers over five years funnel.
So in short funnel funnel funnel funnel funnel funnel see in the next Lechter.