You guys will come back and we're going to talk about the last sections of the financial model graphs
charts simple revenue and then two different scenarios.
See the graphs and charts over here.
Is this a reflection of what we covered in these three.
So right here we just seen a graph of three years and showing our cash balance.
And then the expected profit to the cash balance is the red as you see here it's like we spend spend
spend spend spend.
Then we start making some revenue and then we start kind of evening it out and then we get another school
and it kind of just has a bunny hop effect here and it starts compounding as we keep adding schools
and schools kind of continue to promote them because once you get them on it's not really a one and
done thing.
They keep advertising so that's kind of a factor that worked well for us down here.
Revenue year one by month again it's just spike down then spike again and these are just based off those
numbers before we assumed half as many people in the second month would would sign up as the first one
and then half of that and then half of that and half of that descrive essentially just to show them
that we understand the function of how our revenue is going to work if we're doing B2B that then essentially
advertises to students because then it's B to C that's what this is going to look like.
And then this is more or less just to show them hey look we have a graph and it goes up and this is
what it should look like we should have more cash as we go along.
And then this is since this is a month by month that's why this doesn't.
You don't really notice it's going up to the right because it's literally one month is how much you
make the money you make per month per month.
We put this into a year then we start seeing it kind of go up or at least like a cumulative quarter
even.
All right so this is really not much to say about that great here.
I feel like we just had to get a graph in here somewhere.
Here's a simpler revenue.
And this is just a concept that you can use and I generally suggest you do it.
Now you noticed how we had a monthly income statement and this thing was blown up and had all sorts
of detail and stuff in it.
Then this one was a contracted version that you could look at very quickly.
Now people who are looking at this model need to be able to get the information they want relatively
quickly without having to really kind of weed through the forest here.
So this is the idea.
We put it down here.
We really tried to distill down this is how we grow.
And this is where we're going to get our money from.
Total one year is 106.
How many we're going to add schools or an add 88 all the way across and you can start seeing that.
Well here's the cumulative effect.
And here is the available student market as it grows.
We could have done this in one long line but visually it is just easier to stack them like this.
These are really just the same stats we used before we just pick the ones that were the most important.
And then just showed kind of the totals down here and then and as you can see it goes up.
That's really the main point.
Yeah.
Not much else really to say on that.
It's just a simplified version.
It's really like the regular condensed income statement version of this or this is just only focusing
on revenue growth and nothing else.
Now the scenarios over here what we did and I explain this in the first lecture we picked out two scenarios
that we had heard people say or had gotten pushback on and we modeled out what would happen in those
scenarios.
And these are both two scenarios that are bad.
We're an early model of the ones that we're good.
We could have done that.
We'd rather show we can protect ourselves from the bad things that happen.
Now the first scenario was a missed deadline and I believe the way that this was set up was that if
we started off and we didn't have the application ready in time to start having the first batch of schools
advertise like I think we're saying that is going to take four months to make it.
So this is assumption that maybe it takes eight months or nine months to make it which is actually more
reasonable than anything what would happen.
Well really all it does is it just pushes everything out.
So then if you look over here we just don't have that first hump that you would expect around here.
It just gets pushed out to our break even is later.
And our cumulative revenue for the first year is smaller.
But in the grand scheme of things it doesn't really matter.
And now it's kind of something we were trying to show them.
Our cash still never hits the ground so we are for the most part fine.
And then also down here we just are a quick income statement.
I think we kind of rushed to this one because we probably should have put this in a separate.
Not just a tab made this little bit easier to read.
So really there's just Year One if this is income statement for one year.
If we had that issue and we didn't end up doing it for two or three because the deadline really only
affects the first year.
OK.
So that's it.
People say to us hey what happens if your development takes longer than you think of getting scholarships
on Zong and then you think well here you go.
This is what happens and it's as you conceive are grasses it's not that big of a deal.
And this one is the pushback to what people would sometimes say is they thought our sales was too aggressive.
What if we get into it realize it's way more complicated when we try to scale we can't possibly add
that many schools or you know we end up spending the money on other things not sales mostly on development
or something like that.
So what we said here was OK well why don't we just make a model saying that we're only going to get
15 schools for the first year.
So just 15 and then we wanted to show them what that looks like if we were really on a slower sales
trajectory.
So that was the case then you can see right here that our subscribers are smaller.
They come in later.
But it really kind of has the same structural impact.
The only difference is it's the revenue numbers are lower and then the costs.
Over here the ones that are more variable end up being lower like our data entry.
So we just we kind of adjusted it in the sense that if only adding three well then we can kind of slow
down probably data entry and probably slow down account management and sales.
So that's one way of doing the only thing that doesn't change most likely is the management rights of
management doesn't change.
Well that's I mean that's one way of showing the impact if we could only put on 15 schools in the first
year as opposed to what we were saying before like a hundred something like that.
So we're shown them wow this is the scenario if we totally bomb the sales estimations.
And again it looks pretty much fine.
I think we just didn't.
Honestly I don't think we just finished it over here but we would probably just keep going putting zeros
there.
And so then you can see here again our cash goes down but we never really run into a situation where
we're hurting for cash and need to raise again which is really what we were trying to avoid.
Again investors they like that they generally like seeing that hey you're not going have to get more
money just to make our first investment work.
OK guys so that is the entirety of the scholar pro financial model.
This again was what we use to raise our second round of one and a half million that we ended up actually
only raising a million because the fundraising around it took so long that we kind of closed what we
had just moved on and adjusted the numbers accordingly.
Again we just kind of fiddle with numbers over here and that's how we had a new operational model.
You guys have any questions about this.
Feel free to ask again.
This is rather it wasn't like a structured lecture.
I just thought it would be interesting to show you guys what a real one looks like and kind of look
over the shoulder of kind of an autopsy of a company that went up and then went down and and this is
kind of what it looked like during the middle where it looked like we're doing fine.
All right guys I'll catch you later.