All right welcome back.
So we had a lot of assumptions that we started off with.
Right.
And then we had model out the different sales opportunity revenue options and then we looked at the
cost side of things as well as making some of the calculations there.
So when you have something like this what might you show.
Right.
So some of the things that we decided to show in terms of a summary was one well we definitely wanted
to show what the revenues and expenses and I look like over time you know first year second year maybe
the fifth year once its day was and what would happen if there were some changes to major changes to
the big assumptions right to revenue to expenses.
I mean the timing of this one is pretty cord's a little thing where what if the period to get it to
opening took two months longer right than where you're going to see revenues drop a little bit more
in the first year and maybe a little and second year and you're going to go down.
Right.
So we see that.
But if you do it two months earlier than is going to go up by a good amount as well.
So if we put it back to zero it goes back to the base case.
Now some other things you want to do in a situation like this where you have a lot of assumptions you
want to pull out some of the core assumptions right.
So we made a lot of assumptions but a few of the core assumptions were going to be the utilization of
the sims that dictates pretty much everything right.
And how long it takes you to get from the initial to stabilize utilization.
So one of the things you want to do is run these scenarios and then look at some of the key stats and
then copy and paste the values and then do it again but change the core assumptions to say a worst case
and then a best case right.
So we're kind of looking at three different scenarios.
This is the base case then you know what's kind of the worst case and what's the best case.
And then you can kind of see with how that impacts the why and how long it takes to break even.
This one is to show the pricing of the sims in the hours of operation this is sources and uses is very
common to put in summary of the startup costs including working capital so there's total capital that's
needed.
And then where are you going to get it from.
Right.
So if you can get some of that from a loan that that's how much you need in terms of equity investment
and you as an entrepreneur might come up with some of that.
But then the rest of it will be sought from an investor.
This is another summary that was used in the report.
There you go.
This is the golf tee lounge called the lounge is kind of like a high end indoor golf range with alcohol
and tapas style foods and you can see from what we did that there are a lot of elements here that if
you are thinking about doing some sort of a brick and mortar type of business pretty much all the technique
that you need to know in order to model any brick and mortar type of business is in this model.
So I know some of it might be new and some maybe might be a little difficult.
Biggest thing is just go through you know look at what the purpose of this is review.
You know what we discuss in the videos and then if you want to see how it's done then trace it right.
So you want to know for instance hey I want to know how for example how the discounts are done.
Right.
So then if you want to know how this is done and how it's used in the model you highlight the sell go
to the formula and in that tab formula tab right and then go to trace dependence on that does is going
to give you this little arrow and or if you highlight the arrow you see how the mouse goes from a plus
sign to an arrow that will click and it will give you the worksheet as well as the cells.
So right here it seems like row 87 in simulation sales uses this reference.
So I'm going to go to simulation sales row 87 grand opening discount.
OK.
Now when you look at the formula so I can see is checking if the month is less than main assumption
when twenty plus one.
Okay so if it's less the main assumption plus one what is an assumption plus one main assumption the
128 is the duration.
How long is the grand opening discounts will last.
So where are we where so.
Oh okay if the month is less than that plus one which is three plus one it was less than four.
That means month 1 through 3 then it's subtracting that percentage times the sales revenue.
So was just calculating that discount rate there.
Okay.
So when it does that it should calculate it in the first three months.
And that's what it does there.
So any time you want to see how something works go to the actual assumption itself the variable right.
Highlight it and then trace it and look at the dependence.
And then you can trace the formulas back and figure out how it's done.