All right.
So welcome back to the you works case study part 2.
This is the summary Now we've done the revenues and we've done the expenses.
So in the summary we can just kind of put it all together.
Right.
A lot of times it's very useful to visualize the timing and then the all the revenue related assumptions.
So it's not kicking in it's not doing anything until afterwards.
Right.
And you see that now one of the things when you're building models like this where it goes really far
to the right.
But you've got these columns here and the months up there a useful thing to do is to go to layouts and
there's something called Free's pain.
And if you freeze pain with you make sure that we keep the headers for ourselves so you can see the
months and we can see the labels wherever we go in the model to see that they're so very useful to see.
So then we see that right now is when it starts to be active everything else before that was kind of
trying to get it ready to launch it.
And then this is when we start to get some sales and start to build up.
But early part of it is has a lot of startup related costs right.
So for this one here we bought the building and had some initial Permatang spend and is still permitting
then we start the construction period.
Construction is quite expensive.
And after you can search construction with the launch.
Here is the headcount earlier on is maybe just some senior team and some early hires and then it was
getting all the associates and others there that is needed.
And then slowly increasing the headcount over time.
So then we also have the comp. And the other overhead expenses in any of your monthly expenses.
Now again the monthly expenses we had them only kicking in in month 15 but none earlier than that because
it wasn't launch yet.
You're not running the facility full blast.
You're not doing a lot of other things or you're not spending as much at that time.
Okay.
Are we just going to assume it's 0 before then.
Now if you wanted to do some sort of a lower spend before that you know like maybe you have like utilities
where you think hey it's just us and is no.
You know people there were you spending maybe 30 percent of the utility run rate the way to do that
then is we go to the the monthly thing here and we can start something in month 1 I just say pre launch
utilities.
Right.
And you know it's maybe it's 2300 instead of 1000.
And then so it then goes like that.
So then we have that earlier spend in when we go back to the summary.
Now that other Monkley spend now we got that 4300 early on as the pre-launch utilities and then post-launch
will have some of that.
So now the only thing you got to do is you need to adjust that down as make sure that this is the difference
of what you have right.
So post-launch if you want the total to be 5000 post-launch then this needs to be 3500 Now that's how
you can do it in such a way where after launch it's still 5000.
What we did before but we have some lower amount initially.
Now that's there.
So then we have our total spen total cash flow out.
So during the startup period we have no revenues so it's just all cash out.
That's why it's all negative like this.
But once we start generating some money and we stop spending on the startup we're going to be cash flow
positive right.
And as we grow the number of customers we're going to start to grow our revenue per month.
So then what we do is if we look at the cumulative cash position so we look at net whether it was spent
or earned I and keep track just keep tracking that the net cash cumulative position.
We can then calculate what is the most that we're going to need in terms of the cash flow.
So the the biggest point the biggest cash the cash need happens towards the end of startup which is
not surprising right because that's your are you spending all that money and it adds up.
Well that part that is the maximum that is the cash that you need to calculate the max cash deficit
since is a negative number we use the mean function to find that we found that there and then we can
go back to where the startup thing is and put something here.
So we kind of can have a little bit of padding.
So here's the max cash deficit that we calculated earlier.
We added another 10 percent of contingency or padding to it.
So then we calculate our total funding asset base aren't all funding us.
And here's all the startup costs then the difference is that working capital mostly coming from contingency
but is it's helpful for you to have that to make sure that you do have some wiggle room to do your launch.
So there you have it.
This is a more complete you works business model which is not just the revenue but we're looking at
the expenses we're looking at the then the cash statement the whole cash flow and to calculate how much
cash is needed to actually launch.