And we are back.
All right.
Let's wrap up the unit economics analysis of our warm up business and get you onto the more complicated
stuff recap so far we're making a lemonade stand.
We took the time to sit down and think through the ingredients and the product.
The auxiliary items needed to service the product and then we dwelled on the fixed costs associated
with setting up the stand and getting a sign that silently screams at the passer bys.
Last year we focused on unit economics i.e. here is some lemonade.
How much did that just cost me to give you.
Why do we need to know that.
Well because it's a metric you constantly need to monitor in any business.
Most businesses will strive to have their unit costs under control and are generally going to shoot
at a minimum for having their unit cost lower than the average sales price.
Of course as we'll get into this later this varies heavily by industry.
So we only use this metric in the broader context of our business.
Food and beverage businesses generally have to rely on high unit margins just to make the whole thing
balance out because they have really high overheads and fixed costs.
Anyway we're looking at this lovely excel sheet over here and we can see that we've just calculated
with a little research the per ounce cost of each ingredient and then the per cup cost of each ingredient.
And then finally the total cost to make some lemonade.
Now a lot of people might be tempted to just flip the table and call it quits right here.
After all we know what bar we have to jump over.
But if anyone Oh I don't know someone that smoke cigars and wears a pinstripe suit looks at this they'll
think you're not serious.
Right.
Well why is that.
Because we're not accounting for two very common things.
Number one is waste.
Number two is contingency waste means any of the product that you lose without recouping any payment
for it.
If you hadn't thought about that well welcome to food and beverage land.
You can't exactly restock that cup eliminated for a month that the lemon slice can all like Squishy.
So we need to accommodate that and we need to in general add in some element of cushion or contingency.
There's a broader lesson that needs to be learned here that we will explore more in depth in the course
when you're making a model.
It's virtually impossible to predict every single thing that's going to happen to your business.
The wind could blow away some of your cups.
CBS could go on sale in a desperate bid to lower its stock of sugar.
Your younger brother could accidentally run his bike into your stand because well that's exactly what
he would do because it's in his little brother DNA.
The point with modeling is that you are trying your best to predict what's going to happen but you're
aware of the fact that it's just not entirely possible.
People will judge your models based on how realistic they are and how they demonstrate the level to
which you understand your industry.
Being realistic includes understanding you can't know everything.
Don't worry we'll get more into this later.
Now back to lemonade.
In this case since we're already acknowledging waste we can actually just roll that up into contingency
and let's say we're pretty aggressive with this and we assume that waste and our o fund is going to
represent 10 percent of the total cost of eliminate.
And I mean aggressive as in you really think you're going to run on a tight ship.
You're not giving yourself a whole lot of room to screw up.
So after all that's said and done we're going to add another eight cents to our total cost to make a
cup of lemonade bringing us up to 89 cents.
So still barely anything in the grand scheme of things.
Now how exactly does this knowledge that it's 89 cents per cop inform us going forward.
Well now that we know what it costs to sell one cup we know what the bare minimum we need to charge
for one cup is.
That's assuming obviously that we want to maintain profitability from the get go which we do in this
case.
OK great.
So that's it.
Right.
We just charge anything over 89 cents and we'll be loads of money in no time.
Well no.
In order to further refine our model and get even closer to a truer estimate of the cost of a couple
eliminate.
We have to take a page out of the playbook of the oh so many failed on demand startups and not to forget
Labor prepping eliminate takes time and selling it takes time.
It's not reasonable to assume that you and only yourself will forever man the booth and squeeze the
lemons.
I know that sounds weird as a pure zero dollar an hour volunteer.
You have effectively in this scenario made yourself a terrible job.
And on that disheartening note I will see your next lecture.