Hey guys welcome back to the course.
We cover a lot of good stuff in this course with our examples but we're not going to be able to cover
all the scenarios for all of you.
We try to provide a good mix of case studies that will help most of you get most of the way there if
we try to cover the full gamut of specific examples.
Then also this course is going to be irrelevant to any given student.
So we try to just focus on the common elements and themes that are important to the vast majority of
you but there will be times when you want to do something very specific for your situation.
You'll have a solid foundation and framework for approaching your modeling by taking this course.
But when you need something super specific Your best bet is to go to Google.
Chances are good that someone else out there in the world has had the same issues that you're experiencing
and you might find it in forums like stack overflow or Excel or other modeling related discussion boards.
The point is to go look.
There might even be partial or fully completed models that you can build on top of.
So don't reinvent the wheel if you don't have to and don't be shy to look to see if someone else has
already tried.
When you're trying to do.
And hey if you find a useful case study that you think is interesting Feel free to share in the discussion
board or share and evidence channel for this course.
Thanks.