And we are back back making the lemon drink extravaganza.
Now before we take our lemonade stand public and cash in on people's retirement funds we need to get
back to the grind and calculate the cost of labor associated with each cup.
Now are we going to bake in the cost of labor into our model and increase the cost of each cup from
the eighty nine cents we established previously to something higher.
Well no and for two reasons.
One traditionally you want to isolate the gross cost of each item by itself and keep that separate from
Labor.
Labor can fluctuate and can include many different elements itself.
So combining the two metrics is a recipe for confusion down the road.
The second reason is we're assuming this is a sole proprietorship where it's just you manning the booth.
In that case you're not going to be paying yourself as if you were per hour labor.
Instead we're going to calculate the cost of labor.
Remember that's due to inform our profit requirements going forward.
Instead if we say profitable but that profitability didn't even cover labor Well that's generally bad.
You didn't make a profitable business anyway.
Let's get back to it.
If we wanted to theoretically calculate out the costs of labor how would we do it.
Well we do it something like this.
We'd first estimate the time it takes to make a certain batch of lemonade.
We're lucky because this is something we can easily test.
And it's something that stays reasonably static throughout your business.
And then we need to calculate the time it takes to sell it which to be honest is going to be some guesswork.
So let's say you drink a case of Red Bull and in your cookie monster like mania.
You find out that you can squeeze in assemble about five gallons of lemonade in two hours five gallons
again apologizing for overly American izing this.
But it's about 80 cups.
At 12 ounces each.
OK.
So we have half of the equation now.
How would we try to estimate out how long it takes to sell.
Well Intel we have concrete data to work with.
We really just have to guess what some people might do is stake out a location and then count the number
of passers by then try your best to make a conservative guess at what percentage of people might stop
by the booth and what percentage would then buy.
In this case we're just going to estimate with the idea that we would adjust the model later on when
we get real data let's say in a good location you could sell 40 cups an hour for a total session of
five hours.
So two hundred cups of lemonade before the streetlights come on and you have to go home.
So if you can make 40 cups in an hour of prep you can make 200 cups in five hours of prep.
Basic multiplication that's five hours of prep and five hours of sales to sell 200 cups of lemonade.
If you want you could make a blended rate of one hour prep and sales per 20 cups.
We're not going to bake this into our model just yet but I would write it off to the side.
The question then becomes how much per hour would you like to get paid or more reasonably what per hour
rate would make this worth it for you in general.
Because after all there are plenty of other neighborhood industries you could be disrupting.
We got to optimize our time.
Let's say you thought about it and 30 dollars an hour is enough for you to make this worth it for you.
That means at 10 hours of total time.
Remember it's five hours of prep five hours of selling.
You'd need to make about 300 dollars in profits after all of your costs in order for this to be worthwhile.
10 hours.
You want 30 an hour you need 300.
And we know that in that same 10 hours we can make and sell roughly 200 cups.
So I think you see where I'm going with this.
If we sell 200 cups then we have to consider our unit costs which end up being one hundred and seventy
eight dollars.
No.
Each cup is eighty nine cents at the end of the day.
So just multiply that by 200.
So really we need to recoup four hundred and seventy eight for two hundred cups sold in two hours to
both cover the costs the eighty nine cents and that 30 dollar an hour return you want for your time.
And so with that knowledge what do we have to sell our cups of lemonade for anyone anyone.
Four hundred and seventy eight divided by 200 is about two dollars and thirty nine cents and because
we love contingency and planning for the worst let's like round that up to two dollars and fifty cents.
Yes.
Some of the smarties in the crowd are probably wondering if the demand for eliminate is elastic as in
does the purchase rate on any given day they get affected by the increase or decrease in price applied
to it.
And yes it does.
But we're not really going to tackle that right now.
We're just projecting we would actually need real empirical data to do that.
So there you go.
We have our unit economics squared away.
And we know what we have to charge to get the right amount of profit.
Good times.
Next lecture.
Simon's going to take you through location selection and handling fluctuations in demand.
And you thought running a lemonade stand was simple.
Still is.
All right see you next lecture.