Hey guys welcome back to the course in this lecture.
We're going to look at the tear pricing revenue model now structurally and logically at least in terms
of the modeling it's going to look very similar to what we did in terms of the subscription business
model.
The only difference here is that the subscription plans we have tiers of plans that are going to mix
it up a little bit in this example to show you some differences but structurally you're going to see
that it's very similar and it's not so difficult to do.
Let's take a look.
Hey All right let's do a quick sanity check of what a business like this might look like that's going
to look pretty simple right.
We're going to start with some leads some of them are going to convert into clients.
And if we have three tiers of services we break them down into those three tiers and we can calculate
how many clients are within each tier and if they're paying a monthly fee within each of the tears then
we can calculate the total revenue for each tier by multiplying the number of clients in the Tier 2
times the price that they pay each month.
And we do the same.
We get the total monthly revenue.
So this is simple enough so lets look at a simple model for this as well.
If we start with say some ads some of them become leads and of those leads we convert 5 percent so every
month we're adding 50 new clients right.
And then the total number of clients cumulative clients in any given month is here.
It gets to 600 clients at the end of the month.
So then if we look at the price or the number of clients within each tier we can calculate that for
each month same as the front and then we do the same for the revenue.
Right.
So this is pretty simple here.
But let's turn it up a notch in the next nado.
So in the next model we're looking at the same kind of set up up here.
Okay let's say that same number of ads and then some of them become leads the leads become clients.
All of this here is the same.
All right.
With these tears.
So the first part actually is the same as well is you know we have the number of clients times the cumulative
number of clients that are there.
Okay.
And then this one we got to do the first one there.
So when we have this what we can do then is we can start factoring things like say attrition.
So if we have different attrition rates for different tiers then we can calculate the number of clients
that are going to be there after attrition.
So post attrition is going to be the number of clients for that tier times one minus the attrition rate
for that here.
Now what we have is we have our clients that are actually still there after attrition.
But one thing that we may see in these kinds of businesses is that there is going to be some movement
between the tiers we may see some movement from Tier 1 to 2 and 3 from Tier 2 to 1 and 3 and from Tier
3 to 1 and 2.
And when you make some assumptions around that to monitor that out you know this is sometimes a good
metric to keep as well for these kinds of businesses because if they start to see something really wonky
like there is really high attrition rate going from 3 to then we know there is something going on that
not keeping the clients in the Tier 3 maybe they got to change up some of the services or maybe change
of pricing or whatever it is they got to see what's going on that's create making that kind of movement.
Okay let's see.
Once we make some assumptions around that we can calculate the actual movements that are going to be
happening throughout these tiers right.
So when there's three tiers MI 6 movements we have to track.
Okay.
So the movement from 1 to 2.
Right.
So we're going to calculate is then we're going to have the movement from one to two times the number
of clients that are moving from Tier 1 right.
So there's the number of clients there.
So we have that kind of movement.
And that's the number of movement for from 1 to 3.
We're not going to worry about whole numbers right now I'm just going to try to introduce this framework
for you.
We can always round to the nearest customers.
Okay.
Since you know how to do that by now.
All right.
And we do the same for the other ones.
So we're going to have the Tier 2 clients times this movement to one and then we're going to do the
same.
This is the Tier 2 clients with the movement 2 3.
Right.
So we're going around that we're going to just make it nice and clean and then copy it across.
Do the same for the we just copy this but we have to change the reference here right to the correct
row.
So we'll have that and move this across.
Okay.
So then now we have this kind of movement.
So then we can calculate the actual number of clients post movement.
Now we're going to assume all of this movement happens at the beginning of the pain cycle for simplicity
so and so is of attrition.
Everything is happening at the beginning of the month.
Now we're going to see what the final Klein count is right.
So the final clean count is going to be what we started with before the movement.
And we're going to minus what moved out minus that minus that going.
And what came in for each of these.
You see that now we're going to do the same for the Tier 2 1 or 2 Tier 2 minus what moved out right
both of these.
And then we're going to add what came in.
That's what came in and that's what came in.
Make sure we did this correctly.
Yes.
And then now is the third one starting point minus what was going out of Tier 3 and then Plus what's
coming in that's coming in.
And so is that one coming in now that we have all of those.
Now we have a final user account and then we can calculate the revenues for that month.
Right.
So then we have to clear the number of clients in each tier times.
The pricing for that here and then we can calculate the monthly and then the the sum is just going to
be the sum of those.
So when you have tears sometimes you can think about not just the attrition but you think about the
movement in between the tiers as well.
And this is one way to account for that.