Hey guys welcome back to the course.
In the last lecture Evan walk you through how we arrive at the detailed cost economics of a single cup
of lemonade.
And he showed you how to calculate how many cups you'd need to sell in order to achieve a certain profit
per hour of time that you put into this bad boy.
We know our cost economics.
Eighty nine cents per cup and the price point we want to sell it at 250.
But how much you sell will depend on the location that you choose.
Some locations might have more potential customers some other locations might have customers who are
more ready to buy.
So you scoped out three potential locations.
You tracked and measured the foot traffic.
The number of people who stopped that food and drink stands and the portion of those who actually made
purchases.
You also made a note that some customers bought more than one while others but just one thing.
Now the data is different for all these locations but there is a difference.
And you think that could make a difference for your business.
So let's see how we would do that model it out to choose the right location.
So we are looking at the per cup cost economics.
So in the previous lecture we talked about the individual items that make up the lemonade cup right
the ice the water and the sugar the juice still them and garnish the cup that holds the napkins and
the straws we have the bulk purchase costs.
We have the cost per unit or the cost per ounce and then the costs in it.
In the cup or in the single cup of lemonade.
So we arrived that about eighty one cent per costs per cup but we wanted to add some padding because
there might be some spillage of water or waste of sugar and make some lemons might not juice as well
whatever that may be we're gonna put a 10 percent padding to that.
So now our final cost per cup is eighty nine cents.
Next let's do a sanity check given what we know now.
Right.
So if we know we want to charge a per cup price of 250 and our cost is eighty nine cents from what we
found and let's say we want to have a certain desire profit per day Okay we're gonna put two thousand
in there right now and we know on average we're going to operate for five hours a day.
Okay.
So then what would be our desired profit per hour.
Well that's going to equal to our profit per day that we desire the two thousand divided by the hours
we're going to operate per day.
Right.
So it's 400 dollars in profit per hour.
Now given that how many cups do we have to sell per hour in order to make 400 dollars a profit.
So we're gonna take the desired profits per hour then we're gonna divide it by the profit per cup which
is going to equal to the price minus the cost per cup.
So when we have this now he calculates the number of cups we need to sell in an hour in order to make
the desired profit.
So that's number they're two hundred and forty eight cups per hour which amounts to when we divide by
60 four cups per minute.
Do you think you can sell a cup every 15 seconds.
Probably not.
This desire profits is likely to be very aggressive not realistic.
Right.
What if we wanted to make two hundred fifty dollars in profit per hour now how many cups do we need
to sell per minute.
About half a cup maybe we sell about a cup every two minutes.
That sounds a lot more reasonable right.
So you can see from some simple calculations like this you can know right away if your assumptions are
in the ballpark of being real or not.
All right.
Now that you have the sanity checking your cost economics let's look at how we might choose among three
locations.
Right.
So for each location we have these data points.
We know what the foot traffic is per hour because we measure did we know the stop percentage because
we measured it and observed it with the Food and Beverage stands in those locations.
We also notice of the people who made stops.
How many of them actually made purchases.
Right.
So some locations had lower foot traffic but had higher stop percentage and purchase percentages as
in location A whereas Location C for instance has higher foot traffic but slower stop percentage same
purchase percentage just lower stopped percentage.
Now if we assume that the cost per cup is going to be the same for all three locations they're going
to have the same lemonade recipe and let's assume that they are going to sell for the same price as
well in all three locations.
Right.
And if they have the same hours of operation and also have the same average cups sold per purchase.
Now some people were going to come and buy more than a cup.
Not all of them just as some of them they won't want to get it for a friend.
Right.
So you're gonna make that assumption here as well.
Then with all of this these assumptions let's see what the economics look like for each location so
we might be able to pick a better location.
So let's start with the top line assumption which is the foot traffic per hour.
This one you already observed that so we'll just take it from the measurements from that roll and put
pull it down here.
That way we can kind of see it closer as we do more calculations.
Now the percentage of stops.
Again we observe that as well.
So we're even just equal make it equal to Road 3 for each of the columns here and the average stops
per hour is going to equal to the average traffic per hour times the stop percentage.
So when we have that we're gonna get the average stops per hour.
Now we're going to copy this formula when you highlight a cell in Excel at the bottom right corner you
see it turn to like a black crosshair from white that's when you've selected it and you're able to drag
it across and it will copy the formula there.
So it calculates for the other columns as well and you'll see that it's making the correct references
to each column.
Now if you're not familiar with Excel pause this real quick and Google relative versus absolute references.
Okay.
And you know what I mean.
Percentage that makes a purchase.
Well this one we also observe it up here.
Right.
So we're gonna have it equal to the row for just so we can see it clearly here.
And then the first the average number of purchases is going to equal to the stops per hour times the
percentage of the stops that actually purchase.
So now we have these purchase calculations.
Now again we're gonna copy that formula across the other cells because the economics work exactly the
same way.
Right.
Okay.
So we have the average purchases per hour and we got the average number of cups per purchase.
Now we can get an idea of the average cups per sold per hour which is the number of purchases per hour
times the average number of cups per purchase.
So that's how many cups we're gonna sell per hour in each of these locations.
Now given those assumptions then over the course of a five hours of selling it's that times the number
of hours.
Right.
And we pull that across.
Okay.
So now we can start looking at revenue and profits.
So let's look at the gross revenue per our gross revenue power is going to equal to the number of cups
sold for our times the price for cup and then the average gross profit per hour is going to equal to
the number of cups sold for our times the profit per cup which is going to equal to the price per cup
minus the cost per cup
now if we copy this formula across we'll see that the location a right now has the highest expected
profit per hour.
OK so if we look at it for the whole day since all the other assumptions are going to be the same we
should see similar results.
Right.
But instead of cost per hour is going to be cups sold for the whole five hour day.
OK.
So that times the price and then is the cup sold in a whole day times the profit per cup
so that's the profit for the day.
Okay
and if we copy that across highlight both of those cells and go to the bottom right corner and drag
it across it will calculate for the other columns as well.
So now we have this calculation here.
What if we change some of our assumptions.
Right.
What if location C we were wrong about the stop percentage.
It was just that day there was something going on.
But on average people walk a lot slower and they stop just as frequently as location a.
So if we make that change here you'll see the calculations at the bottom change immediately.
Now there's a big difference right.
Because if the stop percentage is the same as location and the purchase percentage is same but it has
almost twice the traffic we expect that the profit is almost twice.
Location A.
So you can see when you structure a simple analysis like this it can allow you to pick the right location.
What if we change this back to 15 percent but location C is able to operate more hours.
So now we see that the hourly profit it's kind of in the middle but it's day full day operation profit
is gonna be more just because it operates three more hours than the other locations.
Right.
So this gives you an idea of what you can expect from each of the locations
we're going gonna put that back in.
We're going to move forward to building the actual model.
All right.
Great.
Now that you picked a location and you can start to model out what the business actually looks like
I'm going to show you how we can build a financial model for a single location single product lemonade
stand.
It's just gonna be lemonade and nothing else.
And let's say that you aren't ready to go full time on this yet so you're only going to be doing this
on weekends since more people are going to be out on the streets on a Saturday anyway.
So what would two years of revenues look like.
Let's see how that would work out.
Okay we're gonna build a single location lemonade stand financial model right now and a few things as
we go through this.
I'm going to be going through this kind of quickly but you'll be able to reference a solution in this
lecture you can download to files the file that's empty like this when you open it and then the file
that has it all filled in and one of the things that can really help you learn is to then try this out
and then look at the solution look at the formulas that I use to actually do this.
Okay.
So let's get started right away.
We're going to do a two year projection of the revenues for this.
So we're going to look at 24 months.
Right.
So in the first row row one we got month and it goes from 1 to 3 all the way to row 24.
Okay.
Now a few assumptions that we're gonna keep here top of mind is our assumption about the price we're
gonna charge our cost per cup.
And the hours of operations per day that we operate.
Okay.
Sell it for two fifty.
We have a cost of eighty nine cents per cup and we're going to operate five hours a day.
All right.
Now we maybe are only going to sell this on Saturdays every month.
So maybe we assume that for every month we have four days we're actually selling and we don't expect
that to change.
So we want all the other months to equal to our assumption in the first month.
So we're just gonna say equal to the month next to it.
Okay.
Now if we copy this sell and then if we select the other cells command shift arrow for a mac users and
control shift arrow for PCI users then you select it and then you paste it and we see that there's the
formula for all of them there.
That's equal to the previous month.
If you select that each cell it's going to say equal to the previous.
Now let's assume we pick the location that has on average an hourly foot traffic of two hundred fifty
that walk by.
Okay.
And we stick with that same location.
Right.
So again we're doing the same thing here as we did for the day selling we equal to the previous month.
And then we can triple copy paste it to the other cells we have the formula.
What this does is if we change any of the assumptions for the first month it'll change it for all the
other months as well.
Right.
So if I change that or if I change this you'll see that it changes.
Okay we're going to put it back to four we'll put it back to 250.
So how do we calculate the average foot traffic per day then.
Right.
Well that's going to equal to are the number of hours that we operate in a day okay.
Which here actually it's going to be b 3.
Right.
So be three times the average foot traffic per hour.
So then that gives us the total foot traffic.
Right.
So total foot traffic of twelve fifty.
And because everything else the same we expect the other months to look exactly the same.
Now when I copy the formula over though.
There's nothing wrong here.
It's equal to zero.
Let's see what's going on.
If we put here it says it's two fifty times zero.
So the formula is not staying fix to this cell right.
This is what's called absolute reference that we need to make to this cell right here.
Okay.
So we're gonna change that formula.
We're gonna make it be three but a better way to do that is to fix it in the original formula we go
to the B three and what we do is instead of having it just look like that we're gonna put some dollar
signs in front of the row and column.
Labels so B and 3 there's now dollar signs for them which means don't change that reference.
It will always reference that cell no matter where it's copy too.
Okay so if we copy that now we see that the calculations are correct.
Right.
So we're going to just put it over to all of the cells so then how do we calculate the total foot traffic
per month then.
Well that's going to equal to the average foot traffic per day times the number of days we're operating
in that month which is five thousand.
So we expect all of the other ones to equal the same thing as well.
Let's look at our stop percentage.
Let's assume that the stop percentage for this location is gonna be 25 percent.
And we're gonna assume it's the same for each month on average.
All right.
So.
So again we're gonna do the similar thing there.
So then what's our total monthly stops at the stand.
Well that's going to equal to the total foot traffic rank for the month times the stop percentage so
that's about twelve fifty now.
Notice the before we do the next one.
Notice that the logic here.
Right.
We're starting with foot traffic.
Then we're going to the stops.
And then of the stops then where you're going to think about purchases.
Right.
And then once we have purchases we're going to look at the cups per purchase or total cups sold because
well some people buy more than one.
So when we have cups sold then we can start looking at the revenue and the cost of the goods sold and
then we can look at profits.
So there's a top down kind of downward flow to the logic.
Okay.
So let's say 60 percent of the folks will buy once they stop.
All right.
So we're gonna make that same assumption that every month is the same.
So what's the purchase percentage.
Well then the purchase is going to be the total number of stops for the month times the actual purchase
percentage.
Right.
So now we have that many purchases in a given month.
And let's say it's one point two cups sold per purchase.
So we're gonna copy that and we're gonna paste that again.
All right.
Now how many cups sold are we going to have.
Well we have that many purchases per month times from one point two cups per purchase.
So that's how many cups we expect to sell.
So now we control copy that and paste the rest in the other cells.
So then what is monthly gross revenue.
Well monthly gross revenue is going to equal to the number of cups sold for the month times.
Well actually at times be 1.
Right.
The price per cup.
Now again we want the all the other references to reference this specific cell only.
And we don't want the formula to change for this be one reference because the price not going to change.
Right.
So we're gonna make this a absolute reference.
I don't like that but like best so that's the monthly gross revenue.
And now we can copy that formula and pace it to the other ones and you can do a sanity check here.
It should be the same.
So if it looks different than the formula is not copying correctly.
OK now how do we calculate the cost of goods sold.
Well it's going to be the number of cups sold during the month times the costs per cup which is be two
right there.
Right.
But again we want that to be an absolute reference here.
So we're gonna make it an absolute reference and then we're gonna copy this and we're gonna paste it
to the rest.
All right.
Now we can look at the profits.
The profit is going to be gross revenue minus the cost of goods.
So now we have the gross profits per month
so there you go in a few short minutes.
We have a financial model for this lemonade stand in a single location and we're able to look at the
profits the gross profits for a two month period.
So we want to look at something like what it's year.
Year 1 profits are what it's year to profits are all we've got to do is just add up the profits for
the first year and the second year.
Right.
So let's look at what that would be then.
The first year which there's a function called sum which is sums all the things that you put into it
we're going to say some and we're gonna select cells for the first month through the 12th month.
Okay.
So there's see that there's 12 columns selected and then we close the parentheses and we say equal.
That's the profit that is expected in the first year.
Right.
And if we do the same for the second year it's going to be from month 13 to month 24.
Now this is a simple one.
We're gonna be doing something more complicated later.
And I hope that gives you an idea of how to quickly build a simple model to evaluate your simple case
first.
Now take some time if you're new to excel if you've never done modeling this might seem a little weird
or a little difficult.
So what I suggest is start with a blank sheet and try to follow along with this video pause when you
need to and then look at the solution and really look at the formulas right.
Go in there and look at what it's referring to what is each cell actually referring to.
And make sure you understand logically how it's constructed.