[Autogenerated] to get started with spring integration.
We need a simple spring application, so I've prepared a simple web application.
Let's take a look at this starting point.
The demo application has a page where people can register for
the tech conference off a fictional company,
Globomantics.
You can choose a ticket type and then enter your name,
email address, etcetera and click the register button.
All it does now is safe your registration in a
database and show you will thank you.
Page.
You can take a look at the source code of the application.
It's a spring boot application,
which has a spring web MVC controller and a bunch of JPA entities and Spring
data JPA error repositories to work with the database.
It has a typical layered architecture.
Er.
There is a web player that contains two controller,
then a service layer that contains the registration service and,
at the bottom, the database layer containing the entities and repositories.
When you fill in the form and click on the register button,
then the submit method in the controller will be called,
which calls the registration service.
The registration service creates the necessary entities and calls
the database layer to save them in the database.
To keep it simple, the database is an in memory age to database.
You can build and run the application yourself using your IDE or from the
command line using the command Mavin Spring Boot rum.
When it has started, point your browser to local host Port 80 80.
When you've entered the registration,
you can use these E H to console to look at the content of the database.
Navigate to local host sport 80 80 slash H two dash console used.
The J D B C URL J D B C H two men Globomantics username s A
and no password to connect to the database.
After entering a registration, you'll see that our records in the tables,
attendees and at and tickets that's our starting point. Let's now start working with spring integration.