[Autogenerated] we're now going to ach bring integration to do demo application.
We will start simple with a single point to point
channel and a service activator.
We are going to use spring integration to decouple the
web player from the surface layer.
At the moment, the controller, which is in the web player,
has a direct dependency on the registration service.
Instead of having the control are directly, call the service.
We're going to make this work via a message channel.
The submit method of the controller will put a message on the channel,
and the service will be called by your service activator to process the message.
Let's see how we can do this.
The first thing we have to do is add a dependency on
spring integration to the project.
There is a spring Bootstrap artur for spring integration,
so we will add a dependency on that starter in the May even POM file.
We will be using XML configuration for the spring integration components.
In this example, let's add a spring XML configuration file to the project.
You can give this file any name you like.
Let's name it integration dash conflict got to XML and
save it in the resource is directory.
Now we have to tell Spring to Lotus Configuration File.
Go to the Spring Boot Application Class,
which is class Globomantics registration application at
an import resource annotation to make spring look for the
XML file in the class path.
That's all the set up we have to do to get screen
integration included in our spring boot project.
As you see,
it's very easy now we can create ping integration
components in the configuration file.
Let's first declared the spring integration XML name, space and schema location.
You can choose any name space prefix you like,
but it is recommended conventional name.
So let's use that we're going to create to spring integration
components a message general on a service activator.
Let's create our first message.
General, this is super simple.
We use in channel to create a channel and give it an ID.
Let's give this generally IDE registration request.
Creating the service activator is just as easy.
The service activator pattern is one off the enterprise integration patterns.
It's a simple type of endpoint that calls some business project whenever it
receives a message on the channel that it's connected to.
We have to specify a few attributes on the service activator element here.
First, the channel that it listens on.
Then we use the wrath and method attributes to specify that it should
call the register method off the registration services.
The value off the raft attribute is a spring be name,
so we used to be name off the registration service here.
The value off the method attribute is just the name off the
method that we want to service activated.
To go next, we have to modify to control her.
Let's take a look at class registration controller.
We don't want the controller to directly call the registration service anymore.
So will first remove the dependency on the registration services.
We do want to control her to send a message to the channel.
Let's injected you and only to the controller.
The channel definition that we put in the XML configuration file
registers the message channel as a regular spring bean so we can use
dependency injection here to get it into to controller.
A typical spring integration application has multiple message generals and
spring integration also registers a few special channels itself.
So we have to use the qualifier annotation here to tell
spring which message general being we want,
which is in this case, of course,
the channel with the IDE registration requests that we
just created in the submit method, we now have to first create a message,
which we can then send to the channel.
An easy way to create a message is by using class message builder.
Let's use the with payload method to create a message with the
Henry registration object as the payload.
Here's a small issue to take care off when you're using message Builder,
you might notice that are actually two classes named Message Builder.
Available to import.
One is in the package or code spring framework integration not support,
and the other one is in the package or code spring framework dot messaging,
not support.
This is a bit confusing, which one should use.
The reason why there are two has to do with history.
Originally,
Message Builder and some other classes were part of spring integration,
but at some point the people developing the spring framework
found out that the number off core messaging classes were so
useful that they added them to the core spring framework as well
but for backward compatibility,
they didn't remove the causes from spring integration.
So now we are,
unfortunately stuck with glasses with the same names in multiple places.
My recommendation is to prefer the core spring messaging classes
from the package or code spring framework that messaging above the
spring integration specific classes.
So I take care here to import message Builder from the package ordinal
Spring Framework thought messaging that support now that we have a
message sending into the general is very simple.
We just have to call the scent method on the channel, passing it the message.
That's it.
We now have our first spring integration application.
Let's run it and see if it still works.
As you can see, the applications still does the same thing.
When you fill in the registration form and click the register button, the registration is still saved in the database.