[Autogenerated] The third way to configure spring integration
components is by using the domain specific language.
We won't cover this in detail in this course,
but I do want to make you aware of this and give you a
starting point to discover more by yourself.
The domain specific language gives you a set of builders
with the fluent API to configure spring integration flows
in a concise and readable way.
Let's take a look at the next example to see what it's like.
The registration controller and service in this example
are the same as in the previous example,
except that we've removed the service activator annotation from the
register method in the registration services.
Instead of using an annotation,
we're going to use these DSL to set up the service
activator and the message General,
Let's take a look at the configuration class Globomantics integration conflict.
This is where we're going to use the DSL.
First, we need to create the message channel.
Just like in the previous example,
we'll add a method named Registration Request with the being annotation,
which returns a message general object.
But instead of instantiate ing and direct channel here directly,
let's use a method from the DSL.
The class message channels provides a number of methods to
build message generals to create a directional will use one
off the methods named Direct here,
and we'll posit the idea of the message channel.
Then we call, get to let the builder created channel and return it to us.
The second thing we want to do is define an integration flow.
An integration flow is really a special spring bean that initializer is a
set offspring integration components on Dwyer's them.
Together, we'll add a method that returns an integration flow.
This method should also have Urbina notation inside.
The method will use the DSL to define a flow containing a
service activator that receives messages from the general
we've just defined to use the DSL, we'll start with class integration flows.
This class has a long list of methods named from to
start our flow from a starting point.
In this case, the starting point is the Registration Requests channel.
We can use the from method that takes the name off the generalized a string.
This method returns a builder that we can use to further built a flow.
This building has many methods that we can use at this point
to connect many different types of components to the channel
to connect the service activator, we will use one off the handle methods.
We passed this method,
the registration service and the name off the method we
want to service activated to call, which is registered.
Finally,
we could all get on the builder that she turned by the handle
method to get the finished integration flow object.
This is a simple example that shows only a small
fraction off what you can do with the DSL,
but I hope it gives you an idea of how this is useful by chaining method calls.
You can in this way defined integration flows that clearly show how
components are connected to each other with message channels.
That's all I'll show you off the DSL.
For the moment,
the spring integration reference documentation explains to the usual in much more detail, so you can look it up to learn more