[Autogenerated] so we're going to use Rapid MQ in this module.
Let's take a moment to look at what exactly?
Your message broker is what rabbit MQ is and how we can
set it up for the demo application.
In the demo application that we have so far.
We have a web player on a service layer that both run in the same process.
We have some what the couple them by having them use messaging
with spring integration message channels.
But what if we want to have separate processes,
communicate with each other using messages?
Then you'll want to use a message broker.
The message broker is a piece of software that provides messaging capabilities,
such as persistent message queues and ways to route messages from senders to
receivers in the enterprise Integration Patterns book.
Each of the patterns is introduced by stating a question
that the pattern being described answers.
The message Broker pattern is introduced with the following question.
How can you decouple the destination off a message from the center and
maintain central control over the flow of messages?
From this question, you can see that it's about decoupling,
senders and receivers,
as I've already mentioned and also about being able to monitor
and manage the flow of messages in the system.
We will be using rabid and QSR message broker.
It's open source and being developed by pivotal,
the same company that takes care of the spring framework So rapid,
um que is very well supported by spring,
which makes it easy to use for a demo.
Let's get rapid and running on our computer and take a
quick look at its management in the face.
You can, of course, download rapid mq and install it on your computer directly,
but I'll be using Docker to run it.
You will see that this makes it super easy to run rabbit MQ.
If you've never used Docker before, don't worry.
We're not going to do complicated things with it,
and you don't need to understand it in detail.
To follow this course, you don't even need to use Docker if you prefer.
You can also just download and install rapid mq on your computer.
However, I highly recommend that you learn the basics off Docker.
Since it's so useful for software development,
I use it every day when developing software,
for example, to run database is in Docker containers.
The software you run in a docker container runs in a kind of sandbox,
so it doesn't pollute the rest of the system and it makes it very easy.
For example,
to create a new container with a fresh database whenever you need it,
you can, of course,
find a number of good courses on Docker at Pluralsight to run rabbit MQ In
Docker you don't need to download or install rabbit.
Mq you do of course, need to have Docker on your computer When you have Docker,
it's just a single command to create and start a docker container
running resident que When you do this for the first time,
Docker will automatically download an image containing
rabbit Mq When this command is done,
you can see that the container is running by using the command Docker IOPS.
Once the container is created,
you can stop it using Docker stop rabbit MQ and restarted using Docker start
rebel MQ you can delete to container using Docker RM rabid mq.
When you delete a container, all the data that's in it is also lost.
So if you had message queues and messages in your reverent you,
they will be gone.
When you delete a container,
let's recreate and start my rabbit MQ Docker container again and
then take a look at the management in the face.
When it's running,
you can get to the management interface by pointing your
browser at local host Port 15 6 72.
Use username, guest and password guest to log in.
I'm not going to say too much about the management in the face.
The most interesting part for our demo is to Q steps,
so let's click that here you can see an overview of the message queues.
Currently, there are no queues for our demo.
We need to define one cube in the Add a new Q section.
Let's enter the name of our Q Globomantics DOM registration request.
We want this cute to be durable,
which means that they will persist messages on disk
and not just keep them in memory.
We don't need to set any of the other options, so let's click at Kew.
There's a new Q so now we have rapid mq running,
and we've defined the queue that we need for our demo application.
As I explained, when you stop and restart the Docker container,
the Q will still be there.
But if you delete the Docker container and recreated later,
you'll also have to create a queue again with Reverend Q.
Ready?
Let's now take a look at how we can split the demo application into a separate front end and back end.