[Autogenerated] We will split our demo application into
two separate spring boot applications.
The front end, which contains the web player on the back end,
which contains the servers and database layers.
We will connect both applications to Rebel mq so
that they can exchange messages.
Let's take a look at the next example Project.
The Example Project is now a multi module maven project with three modules,
Model service and web.
The model module only contains class at any registration,
which is the data transfer object that's used in both
the web player and the service layer.
It's in a separate module that both the service and web
modules depend on so that we can use it in both the front
and and the back end applications.
The service module contains the back and application.
It's now a separate spring good application that contains only the service
layer with class registration service and the database layer.
The web module contains two from the application,
which is just a web player with class registration controller.
What our goal is now is to have the front and applications send
messages to the rabid em que que that we defined and after back and
application receive and process the messages.
Let's first see how we can get the front and to send its messages to rabid MQ.
First of all,
let's take a quick look at the Maven POM file for the front and application.
I've added a dependency.
They're on spring integration.
Am Q B am kubectl and for advanced message queueing Protocol is a standard
protocol that applications used to work with message brokers,
including Robin M Que.
By including this dependency, Spring Boot will automatically configure a number.
Offspring means that we need to connect to Rabid MQ.
Next, let's take a look at Class Globomantics web application,
which is the spring boot application class for the front and
application for this demo we're using XML configuration.
So I've added an import resource annotation here to
include the XML configuration file.
Let's see what we need to configure their to get the front
and to send its messages to rabid MQ.
We'll need to define a few spring integration components here.
First, the registration requests General.
That's the channel that the controller will send a message to when you
submit the registration form on the web-page of the application just
like we had in earlier versions off the demo.
Remember that the message is that the controller sense having at
and registration object as the payload and the daytime header
containing the date and time the registration was submitted in the
previous version off the demo,
such a message was delivered to the service layer by a service activator
that listened on the channel and that got the payload and header from the
message and passed it to the registration services.
In this new version, we want to send this message to rabid MQ.
To be able to do this, we need to convert the payload to a suitable format.
There are, of course, many formats that you can choose to use.
You could, for example, use Jaffa serialization, but this has drawbacks.
A serialized Jaffa object is a binary blog off data,
which is not easily human readable.
And another problem with JavaScript serialization is that it's tightly
coupled with a specific version off a Java class.
If you make changes to the class,
then you might get an incompatible class change error when you try to read
an object that was serialized with an older version.
So it's better to use a human readable standard format.
Let's use JSON here.
Well, define an object to JSON Transformer,
which bring integration conveniently has available for us.
It will receive messages from the Registration Request channel,
convert a payload to JSON and center converted messages to a new channel,
which we'll call to Rabbit.
To get the messages that are sent to this channel to Rabbit, MQ.
We're going to use an outbound channel adapter.
The channel adaptor pattern is another enterprise integration pattern.
Channel adapters are the glue between spring integration message
channels and other components and systems,
and are very important part of spring integration.
One of the main features offspring integration is that it comes with
many different channel adaptor implementations,
which allow you to connect to many different types
of systems to connect to Rabbit.
MQ.
We're going to using a M Q P outbound channel adapter,
spring integration am kubectl its own XML name space to
define am kubectl components so well.
First at that name space to the header off the XML file.
Then we can define the outbound channel adapter.
We will have to set a few attributes on the channel adapter
first the channel that it should receive messages from
which is the two Rabbit channel.
Next, we have to shut the AM code ping template.
Attribute the AM CUPE template.
Bean is a spring bean that used to connect to the message broker.
It's similar to a spring J D B C template or rest template that you
used to connect to a database or arrest web services because we have
a dependency on spring integration.
Am code ping This project spring boot automatically creates a spring bean
named rabbit template to connect to rabbit MQ that we can use here in the
spring Boot Application Properties file.
There are a number of properties that you can set to configure
the connection to rapid mq these settings error used by
Springwood to configure the rabbit template.
They are configured here to point to rabbit mq
that's running on the local machine.
The last attributes we have to set on the outbound
channel adaptor is the routing key.
This tells rather than queue, which Q the message should go to.
In this case,
it's just the name off the queue we created in rabid MQ named
Globomantics Docker registration request.
That's it Let's see it in action.
Let's start the front and by running class Globomantics web application,
we can now navigate to the registration page again.
Fill in the form and click to register bottom.
Now let's take a look at the rabbit and queue management in
the face again and click on the Cube.
You can see that there is now a message on the Q,
and you can also look at the content of the message.
As you can see, it contains an at and registration message in JSON format.
Notice that we have now really decoupled the front end and
the back end of the demo application.
We don't even need to have the back and running to be
able to use the front and application.
As long as there is nothing receiving messages from the Q and rabid MQ.
The messages will just stay there.
This shows you one of the big advantages off a synchronous messaging.
You can take down the back and service, and it's still possible to register,
and the registrations will wait in the queue until the
back and is available to process them.
Next is, of course, changing the back and so that it can receive messages from rebel Um que