[Autogenerated] Besides sending an email,
we also need to let the Globomantics billing system No
to send an invoice for the ticket.
Let's imagine that the billing system as a web service that we need to
call for this we're going to add another listener to to published
subscribed channel that will call the billing system web services when
a registration event happens.
First of all, to simulate the billing system,
I've added another module to the demo application.
This contains a very simple spring boot application with the
class building controller with just one method,
which,
except HTTP Post requests It doesn't really do anything besides
writing a lock message when it's called The building application
is configured tradition on Port 80 83.
Let's see what we need to do in the service module to
call the building web services.
We're going to use an HTTP outbound channel adapter to do this,
just like with a M.
Q.
P and male.
These HTTP outbound channel adaptor is in its own spring integration library.
We have to add a dependency on spring integration.
HTTP to be able to use it also just like the other libraries.
It has its own XML name space.
So we have to add the name space declaration to the header
or spring integration configuration file.
Now let's at the HTTP album Channel adapter,
Just like in the previous clip, I'm going to put it inside the chain.
So let's first define a chain with IDE building chain that listens to
the registration event channel inside the chain.
I'll at an inn, HTTP outbound channel and after element to configure it,
we have to set these URL attribute to HTTP local host 80
83 HTTP method to post Just like with the outbound channel
adapter for sending email, we have to do some processing.
Before we passed the registration event message to the Channel adapter.
We'll need to add Header and Richer, which shuts the content type to application.
JSON note that we're using the common header and
richer from the inter name space here,
not one that's specific to spring integration.
HTTP, that's all we need to do.
The HDP outbound channel adaptor will pick up the content iPad er on
automatically understand that it has to convert the registration event,
object to JSON and send it to the billing system.
Using an HTTP Post request.
To run the complete example,
we'll have to make sure that all the parts are running.
First, make sure that Ravid, MQ and Green Mill are running in docker containers.
Then start up the building service and the front end and back end
over demo at When you now enter a registration,
you'll see that the front and sends a message to the back
and fear rapid mq and then in the back.
And the registration is saved in the database,
and the registration event is sent to the published subscribed channel.
From there,
it's received by the confirmation email chain as well as the building chain,
which will send an email and call the building web services.
You can find a complete code for what we've built so far.
In example, Project eight.
Take a look at the code yourself and play with it and make sure that you understand how it works.