[Autogenerated] in the examples you've seen until now in this module,
we've used channels that called our receivers on the same threat as the center.
That might not always be how you want to do things in your integration flow.
Sometimes you will want to use an executed channel to make listeners
error a known threats from a threat pool or acute channel to be
able to buffer messages before processing them.
When you use these types off message generals and the
message Chandler throws an exception, then where does it go?
It can't be thrown back to the center directly because the
message Chandler is running in a different threat.
Spring integration as a mechanism for this,
what happens is that the original message that the handler was processing is
package together with the exception in an error message object,
which is sent to a special error channel,
spring integration automatically creates a published subscribed
channel with the name Error channel for this purpose.
By default, spring integration subscribes a logging handler to this channel,
which just locks the exception that occurred.
You can, of course, subscribe your own handler,
Students channel to handle errors if necessary.
You can also define a channel named Error Channel Yourself,
which will override the default error channel that spring integration provides.
Let's see how we can use this in the demo application.
The From Rabbit Channel that we have now is a simple direct colonel.
Whenever the A M Q B inbound channel adaptor sends a message to this channel,
it runs its receiver,
which is the JSON to object transformer and the rest of the integration flow.
On the same threat,
suppose that we would want to run the integration
flow on a threat from a threat pool.
Let's add a task executable ping that manages a number of threats.
Then let's at an inn dispatcher element to the From Rabbit
Channel that refers to this task executable.
Doing this makes the from Rabbit Channel and executed
channel instead of a direct channel.
Now the handlers in the flow, starting from the From Rabbit Channel,
will run on one off the threats off the threat pool instead of on the rabbit.
MQ message listeners threat.
I can now remove the error and the attributes on the AM Coop inbound
general adapter because it's not useful anymore.
Exceptions will not cross their boundaries,
so the error handler that you said he will not be called anymore to
handle exceptions that occur in the message handlers.
Changing the threading model also has consequences
for the transaction boundaries.
Since transactions are threat local and the Rabbit Am Coalition ER and
the registration service now run in different threats.
They will not be participating in the same transaction anymore.
The Rabbit DOM Coalition ER and the registration service will each have
their own independent transactions in their own threats.
Since the transaction for the Rabbit and Coalition ER is now not useful anymore.
I can just as well removed,
the channel transacted and transaction manager attributes from the
inbound channel adapter whenever an exception occurs in one of the
handlers off the integration flow.
What happens now is that an error message will be sent to the Error Channel.
Let's run the application, cause an error and look at the logging.
Let's stop the building service and then enter registration.
If you look at the logging off the service application,
you'll see the following.
You will see a D buck message that shows that the message
is being sent to the Error Channel, then the logging handler.
That's bring integration by default subscribes to the error channel is executed,
which locks the error,
including the stack Trace off the exception that occurred
to handle errors in an appropriate way.
For your application,
you can subscribe your own handlers to the error
channel that do whatever is needed.
For this example.
Let's add an exception type router.
This is a router that listens on the channel,
looks at the exception,
type in error messages on the channel and then decides what
other channel to pass the message on to.
We'll add an exception type router that recognizes data excess exceptions email,
send exceptions and resource excess exceptions and passes
them on to three separate channels.
These three exception types correspond to the exceptions of the car when
a database error occurs and when an error happens when sending email or
sending a request to the building services.
Let's stop at this point.
I could, of course,
now at more components that listen to the three different error channels, but I think you now understand enough about how the error channel works