[Autogenerated] This is just the first module and
you've already learned quite a lot.
Spring integration is an implementation off the Enterprise Integration patterns,
which is a set off 65 design patterns that are described in
the book enterprise integration patterns.
Like Gregor Hope and Bobby Wolf.
The patterns focus on integrating software,
components and systems,
using a synchronous messaging a synchronous messaging as a number of
advantages over synchronous communication techniques that help make
systems more responsive and able to deal with failures.
You've learned to core concepts of enterprise integration patterns.
A message consists off a payload and headers and is transported from
the center to the receiver through a message channel.
There are two main types of channels which are point to
point and published subscribe channels.
Message endpoints are the way to connect to message generals.
There are many different types off message and points.
You will learn about channel adapters, gateways,
service,
activators and other types of endpoints as we go along to other main categories.
Off enterprise integration patterns are message,
transformation and message routing.
Spring integration gives you many ready to use message endpoint
implementations that you can use to connect to different types of
systems using different interfaces and protocols.
By using these endpoints, you don't have to write a lot of plumbing code.
After all this theory, it's time we start working this spring.
Integration hands on in the next module will start
building our demo application by first learning how to
implement point to point messaging. Let's go.