[Autogenerated] Greetings machine learners, and welcome to this next module.
In the course, I'm embrace real JSON.
We're moving right along.
In the last module we trained and evaluated the model,
and now the time has come to deploy it and make it available to the world.
In this module will tackle the next two steps of the machine learning process.
When deploying the model we need to take into
account architecture er and security.
Best practices will review those and for monitoring.
We'll take a look at CloudWatch and CloudTrail.
As always,
we'll go through all of these things conceptually and
then also see them in action in a demo, starting with deploying the model,
which is here in the overall process almost to the end.
Now, if you already know the basics of AWS,
I'll assume you're generally familiar with some architecture.
Best practices like building for high availability and fault tolerance.
And I'll just point out that those best practices and
others apply to machine learning,
just like they do any other type of application you're building on top of AWS.
One way to achieve those is through loose coupling.
Another concept you've no doubt heard about this just means you're
separating the components in the system so that if one fails,
it doesn't take down the rest.
Amazon Simple Cue Service or SQs and AWS Step
functions are two ways you could do that.
Sqs is a messaging service, and in this example,
you could do something like get your videos into an S3
bucket and then Q them into sqs in your code,
grab them from the Q.
Do some kind of processing and then send them to recognition video.
So that s que s component just decouple Azure code from the S3 bucket If
something goes wrong with your code or the bucket.
Sqs is there with retry logic and such to keep you going until things RBAC up.
Some other best practices here for sage maker include deploying your
sage maker endpoints to multiple availability zones.
Arrays ease and use auto scaling.
This will protect you if one of the A's C's goes down.
And secondly,
it's a good idea to provide separate Docker images for training code
and inference code and keep them separated is far as.
Security goes with sage maker.
There's a few things to know.
First, it supports.
I am role based access, and we've seen a little bit of that in the demos.
This means, for instance,
you can control access to the S3 buckets that you're
using to your notebooks to training, job execution and more.
Your data is encrypted at rest with either kms the key
management service or a transient key, and it's also encrypted in transit.
Using to s 1.2 encryption.
Your training data is stored and transferred within your account,
not the sage maker managed account.
And finally,
your E c two instances can do launched inside of a VPC that you
manage to deploy your model in sage Maker.
You need three things.
First, you need the model that you previously created.
Next, you'll need to set up an endpoint configuration for an HTTPS endpoint.
And then finally, you create the HTTPS endpoint itself,
and I should note, this is the steps.
When you deploy the model using the console,
it'll look a little bit different through code,
which you'll see in a few minutes.
Once it's been deployed, a client application will call your endpoint,
using the invoke endpoint method in passing in the data for which they want a prediction