[Autogenerated] artificial intelligence services.
At the top of the diagram you'll see the are some major buckets for AI services,
vision, speech, language, chatbots forecasting and recommendations.
And with these,
you're not going to have to worry about picking the right algorithm or
tuning your hyper parameters deploying and so forth.
These services do all that work for you.
Starting with vision.
There are three services to know about here.
Recognition, image recognition video and textract recognition.
Images used for things like facial recognition,
image search sentiment analysis,
image moderation and face based verification recognition.
Video, as you might suspect from the name is for videos,
things like video search or video moderation.
And then, finally, with Textract,
you can use this for document import and processing or text
extraction for natural language processing.
This service just extracts the text out,
and then you can use other services like Comprehend to make sense of it.
For speech.
We have a couple of services.
Those are going to be Polly and transcribe Polly.
Is these text to speech services?
You'll sometimes see.
The poly logo has a parrot on it, So just remember that like a parrot,
Polly is going to talk.
Some use cases here are reading e books and training materials to
the visually impaired and announcement systems.
Transcribe is sort of the reverse here with speech to text.
Here.
Somebody talks and then transcribe is going to type or transcribe what you said.
Some use cases here would be closed captioning and subtitles,
or maybe transcribing customer service calls.
Now looking at language services here,
we have translate and comprehend and comprehend medical,
which is targeted to the health care industry.
Translate produces natural sounding language.
Translation.
So, for example, input English and output French.
A great use case here is when you need to localize your applications for
global audience or do sentiment analysis on multiple languages.
Comprehend and comprehend.
Medical.
These are all about making sense of your data.
You can use this to make sense of unstructured data like emails,
social media posts, reviews and support tickets.
How about Chat Box?
We have support for that as well.
The services called Lex.
With Lex, you could build conversational interfaces,
leveraging the same technology that powers Alexa.
Some common use cases here are call center bots where you
could do the initial intake and then pass the customer off
to someone else if needed.
Informational bots.
Things like the weather forecast for next week and productivity
bots to do things like schedule meetings,
book travel, tickets and so forth forecasting.
With so much data at our fingertips today,
wouldn't it be nice to be able to forecast the future?
And that's what forecast is all about This Does time series
forecasting using historical and related data some common use
cases Here are Salesforce casting,
financial planning and resource planning recommendations
We've touched on this a little bit.
Is far as a different algorithms that could be used to build in train a model?
But there's also a service for that, and it's called Personalized.
This is all about personalizing the user experience in real time,
so things like similar item recommendations,
content recommendations and personalized rankings and that
wraps it up for the top layer of AI services. Now let's move down a layer to ML services