[Autogenerated] you've created the training job and sage maker is often running.
But when it's done, how do you know if it's any good?
Can it accurately make predictions?
And that's why we're going to cover in this phase.
The goal of the machine learning model is to generalize.
Well,
we want to train it on the existing data and then be able to
pass in new data data that it's never seen before and have the
model make accurate predictions.
But sometimes it doesn't happen.
Sometimes your model over fits.
If you look at the chart here.
This is an example of a model that's over fitting that green line.
This model is too dependent on the training data,
almost like it's memorized it,
and it probably won't perform well on new data that it's never seen.
What we want is the smooth black line here,
which is a better fit for all the data.
There are a few things that you can do to prevent over.
Fitting First is to just use more data.
You can also add some noise to the data,
which is basically a form of augmentation that makes the dataset larger.
You could remove features Maybe your algorithm automatically selected features,
but some of them aren't relevance, and you can remove them.
You can also do early stopping Azure training, the model with each iteration.
It's improving,
but at a certain point it starts to over fit or memorize
the data so you could just stop it.
Before that happens, the flip side of over fitting is under fitting.
This means the model is just too simple,
and it doesn't accurately reflect the data.
Basically, it hasn't learned enough.
The blue line in this chart is under fitted.
We're looking for the black line now.
Some ways to prevent under fitting include using more data,
adding more features.
Maybe the dataset itself is too simple,
resulting in a trained model being too simple.
And you can also train longer.
Maybe the model just hasn't had enough time to train
and iterate and find the right fit.
So you want to iterate through the steps,
often tuning the model until you get it just right during evaluation.
Ask yourself.
Do we need to change the algorithm?
Do we need to do more feature engineering?
Do we need new or different data and then you loop around,
make minor tweaks, continue to train and evaluate until you've got the model ready to deploy