[Autogenerated] we'll start at the beginning of the process with fetching data.
As you already know, without data, there is no machine learning,
and these first three steps in the process fetch,
clean and prepare are the most time consuming part of the process.
And these are usually iterative as well,
where you'll fetch some data clean and analyze.
Go back and get more data and keep iterating until you have what you need.
The goal of all three of these steps is to get your data from one or more
sources into sage maker so you can train the model,
starting with this first step of fetch.
This is also commonly referred to as data ingestion.
Your data is probably in many places in many different formats.
You've got your structured data.
Things like database is where the data is stored in tables of rows and columns.
You might also have unstructured data.
Unlike database is this data doesn't have a defined scheme up here.
We're talking about things like images, PDFs or videos,
and then you might also have semi structured data that's kind of in between.
There's a little bit of structure, but not enough to go on a database.
This includes things like no SQL CSV files and JSON code,
and all of that needs to get into sage maker.
But how exactly does that part work?
Well, you actually need to get your data into S3 first,
and then S3 serves up that data as input into sage maker.
Just a quick word about the asterisk here.
In late 2019, we got the ability to use FSX for luster,
which is a file system services.
This will serve a pure S3 data at higher speeds.
So you get better performance,
and then if your data is already in elastic file system or AD FS,
you can use that Azure data sources well,
but we're going to be using S3 for this course.
So this piece about getting your data in to S3, how exactly does that part work?
Well, if you have a lot of different data formats, a data lake is the way to go.
AWS Lake Formation was released in August 2019,
and it's Amazons Data Lake solution.
It's actually built on top of AWS glue.
If you're familiar with that which is an extract
transform and load or TLS solution, we'll see more about that later,
but with like formation, you can fetch, organize and clean your data,
and you can use S3 as storage for the data,
which can then feed into sage maker.
And the information is good for large enterprise solutions,
where you have data in a lot of formats and a lot of places,
but you don't have to use it.
If you're working with a symbol or small dataset,
maybe a single CSV file,
then just upload that directly to S3 and runs age maker against it.
There are also other services you could use instead
or in addition to lake formation.
And the service depends on the type of ingestion you need to do there.
Two types.
The first is batch processing with batch processing.
UWP periodically collect and send data in batches.
As the name implies,
You could do this ingestion based on some triggering event or on a set schedule,
And this is the recommended approach when you don't really
have a need for real time processing.
In other words, if you get your data every couple hours or once a day,
then that's just fine.
This option is generally going to be cheaper and easier than stream processing.
Now, if you've worked with AWS for any length of time,
you know there are multiple ways of doing things,
and that's definitely true here.
There are several different services you can use for batch processing.
The first is A W s glue, which is a fully managed detail services.
We'll talk more about the transform part later,
but this could be a great way to get the data from wherever
it is in to S3 more to other AWS services.
This is a serve URL is solution, and it runs on Apache Spark.
And it works by setting up crawlers that will crawl your
data source and try to infer the schema.
Then it stores.
Those schema is in what's called the data catalog.
Data Pipeline is a managed orchestration service for data driven work flows.
This lets you move your data between AWS compute and storage.
Resource is, and you can also move things from on Prem to AWS.
This lets you store data and dynamodb AD DS,
which is the relational database service,
or Red Shift, which is a data warehouse and S3.
Finally, we have the database Migration Service or D M.
s as you might guess from the name.
This is used to migrate data between databases either in AWS or on Prem.
With this, you can do homogeneous migrations,
say an on Prem Oracle database to Amazon.
RDS for Oracle or heterogeneous jobs like Oracle to Aurora and D.
M s manages the infrastructure for you.
The second type of data ingestion you could do is stream
processing rather than running this once a day.
For instance,
this is real time processing data is loaded and manipulated as it's recognized,
and the way that's possible is through constant monitoring.
You want to use this one real time data is required, such as for stock prices.
This is gonna be the more expensive option,
though, as compared to batch processing.
Any time you think of stream processing, think of Amazon Kinesis.
That's really what it's all about.
Therefore, services in the can is is family,
which you'll see here and let me highlight just a few
things about each of them video streams.
As the name implies.
This is for ingesting processing and storing streaming video and audio.
You can also stream video and audio into an application with this
service and this will automatically provisioned and scale the
infrastructure for you with data streams.
You're also working with streaming data and here the data is broken into shards.
One key differentiator with data streams is that the data has to be processed,
maybe using a lambda function or data analytics before it could be stored.
You can't use data streams to store directly into S3,
for instance, and storage it all is optional.
You might just want to run a lamb to function on the data and then toss it out.
Data retention is 24 hours by default, so you can increase that up to seven days.
Data firehose is similar to data streams,
but here you aren't dealing with shards.
And with this you can stream the data directly into storage,
and the processing part is optional.
You do get automatic re tries here if your data delivery fails,
but if it fails for more than 24 hours, the data is discarded.
So if data attention's important,
this is probably not the right option for you and
Data Analytics with this service, your analyzing streaming data.
So you have a bunch of stores around the world that
are streaming their sales data in, and you need to analyze that in real times.
You can make adjustments to promotions throughout the day.
Here again, the underlying infrastructure is handled for you,
and you're able to use SQL queries on the data and or
build Custom Java applications building.
On top of that last point of being able to query your data using SQL,
there's two other services you should know about for the same thing.
Amazon,
Athena and Red Shift Spectrum both let you run SQL queries on your data in S3.
The main difference between the two is that with red shift spectrum,
you'll need to set up a red shift cluster.
So if you're already using red shift for other things, this is a good option.
But otherwise it's going to be overkill,
and you'll want to go with Athena and then one other service to be familiar
with for the exam is Amazon elastic Map Reduce or EMR e.
M.
R is based on Apache Hadoop and allows you to process
massive amounts of data across multiple E.
C.
Two instances.
It's all about big, big data.
It works with various open source frameworks like
Apache spark hive Presto and more.
And there's tight integration for sparks ml lib capabilities.
If your data is already in an EMR cluster,
you can use some of those other services we've talked about to get the data and to S3.