[Autogenerated] I mentioned at the beginning of the module that
deep learning is a subset of machine learning,
and it underlies a lot of the AWS services and
algorithms that you'll be working with,
particularly when it comes to things like image recognition and speech.
Let's do a quick lap around the important concepts you need to know
first going back to our definition of machine learning,
we said It starts with data when it's passed into an
algorithm that identifies patterns, and at the end of the process,
we have a trained model or simplifying even more.
We have input.
We do stuff to that input, and then we have output.
For example, the input could be a transaction date,
a customer name and the fact that a credit card was reported stolen.
We pass that data in we do stuff,
and the output is that we can predict that this is a case of fraud.
So super easy.
We have limited known data for input and just two options for output.
Either fraud or not.
But what if we have something more complex?
Take, for instance, this hand written digit, too.
This image is 28 pixels by 28 pixels or 784 total pixels.
And this is just a single digit.
You could imagine if we're dealing with images of people or the input
is an audio stream that you want to make sense of.
But sticking with our example of a digit to what happens here
is we're going to take each of those pixels,
all 784 of them and put them into this input layer.
The next step is what we call the hidden layers,
and we'll have one or more hidden layers.
There's an art and science to the number of layers
and the number of nodes in them.
But for illustration purposes,
I'm just going with two and some number of nodes in each.
For now, we're just going to say that these layers do stuff.
The nodes in the first hidden layer are connected to
the nodes in the second layer, and so on.
These connections are called edges, and then finally, the output layer.
After all of the doing stuff,
we want to get an output that identifies the hand written digit as a to,
and this entire structure is called a neural network.
Now going back to that in middle part of doing stuff.
What's happening here is the neural network is identifying patterns,
so it's these pixels in a certain pattern,
and it can identify a line that makes up part of the digit,
for instance,
or it can identify loops that make up part the digit
or looky loos and squid lease,
and eventually it will get to the full digit of to now under the covers.
There's a few things happening,
and I'll take this back down to a super simple example with just a few neurons.
So you have your input, and here are input.
Values are for no particular reason.
12 and three.
Then you have your connections or edges.
Each connection has a weight associated with it,
and these are just numbers that I made up with the top one having a
weight of three the middle of five in the bottom of seven.
If you multiply those weights together with the input,
you get the values that we pass into the next neuron.
So one times three equals three,
two times five equals 10 and three times seven equals 21 you,
then some those up and you get 34 there in the middle node.
Now, in this note, a couple of things happen first,
to apply what's called an activation function.
A common activation function is one that will cause your
output to be between zero and one, or in some cases,
between negative one and one,
and then each node also has a bias associated with it,
and that bias gets added in, and all of that will result in an output value.
Now that's just for the couple of notes that we saw there,
not the entire network.
So rinse and repeat a lot, and when you get to the final output,
compare the output that you got with the output that you expected.
And that difference equals these cost or the error.
And really,
the goal of learning is to find which weights and biases minimize that cost.
So Azure algorithm is making its passes,
its tweaking those numbers to find the right combinations.
We'll talk more about cost functions and things like
radiant dissent in future modules,
but hopefully that gives you the intuition for how neural
networks behave and with the ultimate goal is now. Let's take a look at some common use cases for machine learning