[Autogenerated] Now that we know the different
types of machine learning problems,
let's talk about how you to find your business
problem as a machine learning problem.
First, what is the problem you're trying to solve?
It's super important that you're clear on this,
because how you ask the business question will
determine the machine learning problem.
For example,
maybe the business problem is the company needs to predict sales of
products in order to inform manufacturing decisions.
You don't want to commit a lot of time,
and resource is to manufacturing products that aren't likely to sell One
way you could frame this is a machine learning problem would be predict
which products will sell more than 100 units,
and then we need to figure out the target and type.
The target is the final output you're trying to predict to show you what I mean.
Here's some data for existing products for the problem we're trying to solve.
We want to know of each of these products sold more than 100 units,
true or false.
After we've trained on this data,
we should be able to pass in any other product and figure
out if it will sell more than 100 units.
So this last column here is the target.
Now you'll sometimes hear the word label and target used interchangeably,
but that's not 100% correct for the data that you sent into the model.
This is the label e labeled data,
and then when you're describing the output or the
thing you're trying to predict, that's the target.
So similar, but slightly different.
Some other terminology to cover.
While we're here, the columns are called features.
You'll also sometimes hear them called attributes.
But I'll be using features and the rest of this course.
And then the rows are called the observations.
So we have seven observations in this particular dataset back to our example.
Our target in this case is binary,
meaning tour faults and the type of problem is binary classification,
which, of course, is the broader category of a supervised learning problem.
Let's look at another example where we've worded
the problem a little differently.
Here.
We want to predict the number of sales for each product,
so not true or false, whether we sold more than 100 or not.
But we want the prediction for the number of sales you remember
that when you're predicting prices or sales,
you're working with continuous values.
We could predict sales of zero products or a million products,
and anything in between.
Our target will be a numeric value.
The number of products sold and it's continuous.
And then the type of ML problem is regression,
which is also the broader category of supervised learning Azure trying
to frame your business problem as an ML problem here,
some additional things to consider.
What is your current pain point?
How are you currently solving this problem?
What data do we have?
Is that data labeled?
How will we define success?
What are the trade offs and what is out of scope? Now let's apply these concepts we just talked about.