[Autogenerated] machine Learning services.
As I mentioned earlier, we've seen a lot of these in previous modules,
but let me just go out to the dashboard and highlight a few additional
things here on the sage maker Dashboard over on the left.
You can see that we have ground truth, and this is all about labeling your data.
You can use automatic labeling to do some of this and
then pull in humans as necessary.
And that human workforce is called mechanical Turk scrolling down.
We've seen notebooks, training and inference capabilities already,
but we haven't really talked about the marketplace,
so let's take a quick look at that.
I'll click into all products in the AWS marketplace.
You can purchase things like pre built models,
algorithms and data exchange products,
and this page is only surfacing the featured ones.
But there's a lot more.
If you look at all products, so say you need a very specialized dataset.
Say something like these synthetic data for lung cancer.
If we click in here to view product here,
we can view more detail about what's included in here and
actually purchased the dataset and backing up.
Maybe there's other things.
Say, for instance, up here.
We've got abusive text content detection.
We could be the details for this.
This might be a great way to get the functionality you
need and something that's kind of tried and true without
having to start from scratch.
So there's nothing real specific I want to call out here,
but just be aware that the marketplace is out there and sage maker can do work with products that you purchase here.