[Autogenerated] as they say, all good things must come to an end,
and we've come to the end of our course.
As you take this course and start using machine learning on AWS.
I'd love to hear from you post your questions or comments on the discussion
board for the course and let me know how things were going.
Also, Please take a minute to rate the course and let me know how I did.
Also,
if you're working on a team who recently started doing
machine learning at AWS and you feel that others on the
team would benefit from this course, please share it.
And with that, I'll say thank you so much for watching.
I hope you found the course helpful, and I wish you all the very best in your machine learning adventures.