[Autogenerated] next up data, visualization and analysis.
Once you've got your data cleaned up, then you want to start to make sense of it.
Better understand what you have and how the
different features relate to each other.
First, you want to look at the descriptive statistics for your dataset.
This includes things like the number of rows or
columns in the dataset mean median,
standard deviation and things like count or the most or
least frequent values that you find.
The point of this is just to get a better sense of the
underlying data that you're working with.
And then with visualization, you can answer things like,
Is there correlation between features?
You config really see the mean the men, the max values.
You can identify interesting patterns as well as any outliers in the data,
and you can more readily see if there's any features that you need to add.
Let's look at some common visualizations that you'll use.
First is the scatter plot.
Scatter plots are great way to show relationship between two variables.
As an example,
I've taken this one from Wikipedia showing data for old faithful eruptions.
If you don't know,
old faithful is a Geiser in Yellowstone National Park in the U.
S.
On the X axis.
We have the eruption duration in minutes,
and on the Y axis we have the waiting time between eruptions.
Also in minutes, and with scatter plots,
we show a positive correlation if the line ______ from the lower
left to the upper right like this one does,
and a negative correlation of the line ______ the other
way from upper left to lower right.
In this example, we have a positive correlation between weight,
time and duration.
We have either short wait short duration eruptions or
long wait long duration eruptions.
It would be pretty hard to see this relationship if you
were just looking at the table of data.
So this is a great illustration of the power of data visualization.
Another really important insight we need into our
data is how things are correlated.
A correlation matrix lets us quantify the relationship between variables.
Here's an example of a correlation matrix showing the relationship
between poverty and various health conditions.
A correlation of one means that the variables are perfectly correlated,
meaning that they move in the same direction.
In other words, as one increases these other increases or as one decreases,
the other decreases.
The correlation of negative one means that they're
perfectly negatively correlated, meaning they move in opposite directions.
One goes up, the other goes down and vice versa.
And if the correlation is zero, that means there's no linear relationship.
Now you might notice down the middle diagonal.
These are all ones.
For instance.
Poverty is perfectly correlated with itself.
Breast cancer is perfectly correlated with itself and so on,
so that middle diagonal will always be one.
Sometimes you'll see these matrices with the right upper squares blank,
since they basically mirror the lower left squares.
But I'm going to use the Foley Field out version.
But we can Docker a few things from this matrix.
There's a strong positive correlation between obesity and high
blood pressure shown here in the orange squares.
We can also see a moderate positive correlation between breast
cancer and ______ and no significant meaning.
The numbers are all pretty close to zero correlation
between poverty and any of these conditions.
So that's the correlation matrix,
a really important one for understanding the relationships in your data.
Next up is the histogram.
This shows the distribution of your data.
Like the travel times for people shown here on the left,
the values are grouped into bins,
which are the rectangles are bars you see on the chart and in this
example we can see the at the majority of people are commuting less
than 30 minutes to wherever they're going.
Box plots are another way to show distribution of data,
but in a very consolidated way.
In this example, we have temperature readings, these upper and lower lines here.
These are called whiskers.
Like a cat.
These show the maximum and minimum values.
And then the line in the middle is the mean value.
We can see the at the majority of cases meaning 50% or more,
earned the range shown in this box.
And then we've got a few outliers on the top and bottom of that range.
In this example, the majority of temperatures are between 67 75 degrees.
The max temp is 79 degrees, men is 57 degrees and the mean temp is 70.
And then we've got a couple of outliers,
so that wraps it up for some of the common data visualizations that you'll see.
There's definitely others that you come across,
but hopefully that gives you an idea of how powerful they are in understanding your data.