[Autogenerated] Now we're up to a topic called Feature Engineering.
This is the process of transforming raw data into features
that better represent the underlying problem.
You could do this by adding removing,
combining features and encoding the data in those features.
For instance, changing text into numerical values.
And the goal here is to increase the predictive power of the model.
I've got a sample dataset here for approval of auto loans.
One thing to address during this feature engineering
process is removal of unnecessary features.
Now there are actually algorithms that can help with this.
But up front,
just go through your features and ask if there's
anything that doesn't seem relevant.
Prediction.
Generally speaking, the simpler your dataset,
the better performance you're going to get when it
comes to training and predictions, for instance,
with the size of the car really play a role in whether
somebody was approved for the loan or not?
Perhaps not.
When in doubt, you want to check with the domain expert for the data,
and they should be able to give you input on what to keep or what to drop.
In our case,
I'm actually gonna keep this one because I want to
show you how to in code that column, assuming that you need it.
But in general, make that first pass and remove anything that's unnecessary.
Another thing you need to do is handle scale.
For instance,
you might have measurement data that is in inches kilometers and yards
and scales for those are going to be very different.
Or let's say you have features for age and income.
Age might only be between 21 65 but salary could be 100,000 plus so
very different scales or magnitudes for those numbers.
Some algorithms don't perform well with big numbers like
that and Italy to inaccurate results.
They're a couple of ways to handle.
This one is called Normalization,
where you re scale the data so that your values are between zero and one.
I won't get into all the formulas here,
but there are built in functions for things like this in the machine
learning libraries like scikit-learn for python and then standardization is
where your re scaling thebe S3 BUE shin of the data so that the mean is
zero and standard deviation is one again.
The point to all of this is to ensure that you're
treating your variables the same.
We also need to encode the data.
A lot of machine learning algorithms can only work with numerical data,
not the different things that we have here in our dataset.
We have our target,
which is the thing that we're ultimately trying to predict in this case,
whether the auto loan was approved or not.
In that column, we have yes or no.
We have another column of yes or no, which is these e used column,
meaning it was a used automobile or not.
And these are examples of binary, categorical values.
There's two choices, yes or no, true or false, that kind of thing.
So if you have binary values like in this example,
it's really easy to change them into numbers like here.
We've changed the yes to one and no has been changed to zero.
Now that word I used a minute ago categorical.
That's an important one to know.
Categorical data basically describes categories or groups,
and within that definition there's two types.
Nominal data means that order doesn't matter.
I like to remember that one by remembering the end means not matter
examples of nominal data would be things like red,
yellow, blue or yes and no.
On the flip side of that, we have ordinal data, and here the order does matter.
I remember this using the O.
R D in ordinal to mean org That order does matter.
And here's some examples of ordinal small,
medium, large, hot, hotter and hottest.
Now that we know what categorical means and the
difference between ordinal a nominal, let's look at these next features for size.
We have values of medium, small and large,
and we want to convert those into numbers as well.
When the order matters,
what we do is basically a mapping between the word and a number.
So it maintains that order of going from small values to larger values.
And now it's in a format that the algorithm can understand.
These features are already numerical values,
so we're good with these,
though we might wanna handle scale like we talked about earlier,
and finally we have the type of automobile truck,
SUV sedan or coupe here.
Order doesn't matter like it did with small medium large,
so these are nominal values, and generally it's not recommended that,
um, code nominal values like the mapping we use before.
For instance,
how would you decide if the truck was 10 or the coop was 20 and so forth?
The solution for this is one hot encoding,
and this is definitely a concept you'll need to
understand for the exam with one hot encoding.
You basically take each value for the type of automobile and
create a new feature or column for it.
So type underscore truck type, underscore SUV type,
underscore sedan and so forth.
And then you're gonna use zeros and ones to denote what type it is.
For instance, this top row here for truck.
We have a one in the type underscore truck column and
then zeros for everything else.
And you'll see it continues that way for the remaining rows or
observations so that just about does it for feature engineering.
But you might be wondering how you actually do this
cleaning and preparing of the data.
It's obviously not done in PowerPoint slides, right?
Depending on the size of your data, you have a few different options.
Azure starting out in learning.
Sometimes all you need is an Excel workbook,
but for doing anything more serious,
you want to Use Jupyter notebooks in sage Maker There's several
libraries that make this work really easy.
AWS glue is also a great option as a fully managed detail solution.
It's a little bit more robust and repeatable.
And if you're more on the B I or analyst side of things
and you don't want to write any code, you can use a tool called quicksight.
One other service to know about when it comes to preparing
your data is SATA Maker Ground Truth Ground Truth can
automatically label a lot of your data,
but there are times when you really do need to have a human step in.
In cases where a human workforce is needed, Amazon engages Mechanical Turk.
These folks will manually label your data and or validate
that the automatic labeling was correct.
Ground truth can also be set up to allow labeling from your own
private workforce or from other third-party vendors. Now let's get into a demo