In this last section of the course,
I'll be completing the implementation of the batch job.
I'm going to focus on writing items that were passed
from the ItemProcessor into a database.
To do this, I'll first need to add a database table to write to.
As I'm using Liquibase to manage the database changes for the project,
I just need to add a new changelog.
This changelog will define the table and columns that
map to our PatientEntity class.
I'll also need to add this file name to the master changelog.
Let's do that now.
I'm going to demonstrate adding the patient database changelog
to the project's Liquibase configuration.
Note that I'll be following Demo 19 found in the DEMOS.
md file of the root project directory.
To support writing items to the database,
I'm going to demonstrate adding the patient database schema
to be managed as a Liquibase changelog.
Make sure that you've opened up to the folder
resources/config/liquibase/changelog.
We're going to add a new file here.
I'm going to drop in the name of the file.
Note here that the prefix of the file name has a timestamp.
Let's paste in the database changelog.
This changelog defines the table and columns for patient data.
Note that these columns directly map to the PatientEntity JPA entity class
that we created in the previous section in the course.
Next, I need to add this file path to the master changelog.
Let's open up the master.
xml file now.
I'm going to drop in the path to the file that we just created.
Finally, let's run the application to assure that Liquibase started correctly.
We see here that the server started.
Now let's open up a browser.
I've once again navigated to the H2 Console at the URL localhost:8080/console.
Again,
use the settings that were used previously when we
looked at the console and click Connect,
and here we see on the left side of this form that we have our PATIENT table.
Let's expand it, and we see all of our patient columns.
This verifies that Liquibase loaded up our schema correctly and completes the demo.