As part of this course, I provided you with a starter template.
It contains all of the non-Spring Batch dependencies and configurations.
This project will be the foundation for configuring a new Spring Batch job.
Let's see how you can get the project locally so that you
can follow along with the demonstration.
The application template can be found in the demo files for this course.
You can also retrieve the latest code from my GitHub site at github.
com/michaelhoffmantech/patient-batch-loader.
I've tagged the initial template with the name Start.
I'll be showing you the retrieval of this project from GitHub shortly.
There are several prerequisites you'll need to follow along
with the demonstrations in the course.
First, you will need the latest version of the Java Development Kit, 1.
8.
Note you can use version 9; however,
there will be some additional modifications needed to
support dependent modules like JAXB.
I won't be demonstrating installation of this in the course.
Next, the application uses Gradle for its build tool.
I've included the Gradle wrapper,
so you should not have to download anything to support it.
I'm using the latest version of Git for supporting the project in GitHub.
I'm using the IntelliJ IDEA IDE; however,
please feel free to choose the IDE of your liking.
This project is leveraging the release version of Spring Boot, version 2.
0.
As version 2.
0 was just released at the time of writing this course,
it's recommended that you upgrade to the latest minor version as it's released.
Finally, this course will focus on Spring Batch version 4.
0, which is the latest as of the writing of this course.
I'm going to show you where you can download the project from if
you would prefer to retrieve it from GitHub.
I'll be displaying the Releases page of the project found at the URL shown.
Let's look at that page now.
Here I'm showing the project page on GitHub.
Again, the URL is github.
com/michaelhoffmantech/patient-batch-loader.
I'm on the Releases page.
From here, you can download assets.
Depending on your OS, you could either download a Zip file or a Gzip file.
Now once that download's complete,
you can move it into whatever folder you want for the project.
Now, let's look at a description of the project contents.
While I don't plan to review every line of the template application,
I do want to give you a high-level overview of the files in the structure.
Let's start with the root directory of the project.
The data folder contains a few sample files of dummy patient data.
These data files will be used for testing during the demonstrations.
The gradle folder includes additional scripts that extend the main build script.
There is a script that supports build tasks specific to a Spring profile.
Also, there's a script that is specific to Liquibase database schema management.
As you would expect,
the src folder contains all of the main and test
source code for the application.
The build.
gradle file contains the build script and dependencies for the application.
And finally, the gradle.
properties file contains externalized properties for the Gradle build scripts.
Next, let's look at the resources folder.
Under the folder src/main/resources/config are several
properties used throughout the application.
The liquibase folder contains the database schema
management files used by Liquibase.
If you're not familiar with Liquibase,
it supports schema management and versioning for databases.
We'll be using it to prepopulate database objects when starting the application.
The file application.
yml provides the base properties for the application.
It includes properties such as the application name,
JPA settings, and management configuration.
The file application-dev.
yml contains properties that are only used when
running the development Spring profile.
This includes the development data source configuration,
H2 configuration, and Liquibase configuration.
The file application-prod.
yml contains properties only used when writing the production Spring profile.
The final item I want to cover is the DatabaseConfiguration class.
One of the primary goals of Spring Boot is to be opinionated out of
the box and then back away as requirements dictate.
With Spring Batch,
it's been my experience that it's best to overwrite Spring Boot's
database configuration right from the start.
By configuring Beans for the EntityManagerFactory,
DataSource, and TransactionManager,
you get visibility and gain control over these dependencies when
they are wired into the Spring Batch configuration.
We're going to see more of this as we go along.
With this overview of the application template complete,
you should have everything you need to continue with the
demos for the remainder of this course.
In this module,
I showed you the steps needed to get started with the
remaining demonstrations in this course.
I started by showing you the location for retrieving the project template.
I also provided you with the prerequisites needed to get the
project up and running in your local environment.
Next, I walked through the structure of folders and files in the project.
You saw the location of key aspects including configurations and properties. Now let's get started with configuring the project for Spring Batch.