Now that the Spring Batch dependencies are in the project,
the next step is to configure Spring Batch to be
available in the Spring container at runtime.
To do this, I'll be creating a Spring configuration class,
which I'm displaying a snippet from now.
First,
you'll notice that I'm annotating this class as a component even
though I'm defining this as a configuration class.
The second annotation will explain why.
I've also annotated the class with EnableBatchProcessing.
This annotation triggers Spring Batch to include and configure
its features at runtime as Spring beans.
This class will then provide a strategy for how
several of these beans are configured.
Next,
I've declared that this class will implement the
Spring Batch interface BatchConfigurer.
The interface simply defines getters for the JobRepository,
JobExplorer, JobLauncher, and TransactionManager.
The implementation of this interface is then responsible for the
strategy of how these attributes are defined.
Spring Batch provides you with a default
BatchConfigurer implementation; however,
I prefer to provide my own implementation as it allows me to
control the configuration of these attributes.
Finally, I've defined three of the attributes needed for BatchConfiguration.
Let's look at these in a little bit more detail.
The first attribute is of the type JobRepository.
This class is responsible for persisting metadata about
batch jobs configured in the project.
This metadata gets persisted either in memory or in a database.
The most common way to use the JobRepository is with a database,
so I'll be demonstrating that shortly.
In order to use the database approach,
there are some obvious configurations we will need on the JobRepository,
including the data source and the TransactionManager.
The next attribute is of the type JobExplorer.
This class provides you with getters and find methods to retrieve
information for the metadata stored in the JobRepository.
Again, I'll need to configure the JobExplorer, in this case, with a data source.
The final attribute is of the type JobLauncher.
As the name implies,
this class is responsible for running a job with a given set of parameters.
I'll be using the JobLauncher to execute our job on demand
when I create it later in the course.
Let's create this new configuration class in the project.
Please note, I'll be following Demo 3 found in the DEMOS.
md file in the root project directory.
I'm going to walk you through the creation of the BatchConfiguration class.
Again,
this class is going to allow Spring Batch to register up beans
in your Spring container of the project.
Specifically, we're going to register JobRepository,
JobLauncher, and JobExplorer.
I've opened up the project, and I've expanded the src folder to the package com.
Pluralsight.
springbatch.
patientbatchloader.
config.
Let's create our class.
I'm going to name the class BatchConfiguration.
To start with, I want to register this class as a Spring component,
so therefore, I'm going to add the Component annotation.
I also want to use the EnableBatchProcessing annotation on this class,
so let's add that now.
With these two annotations in place,
we've turned down Spring Batch features and will assure this
class gets scanned with our configuration.
Next,
I want to add reference to the interface that this class
will implement named BatchConfigurer.
Let's update the class definition.
Notice here that we got an error.
We haven't implemented the interface methods yet, so we can ignore this for now.
With the class definition complete,
the next step is to add attributes to this class for the JobRepository,
JobExplorer, and JobLauncher.
Let's do that now.
Note that all of these attributes are part of the core Spring Batch dependency.
I also need to autowire two beans for supporting these attributes,
specifically the DataSource and the TransactionManager.
Let's add those.
If you remember earlier,
I overrode the default Spring Boot database configuration.
Here we see one of the drivers for doing so.
As I need to leverage the TransactionManager and DataSource for the repository,
explorer, and jobs,
I have control over the naming and configuration of these dependencies.
Here I've Autowired the batchTransactionManager and batchDataSource
that I defined in the DatabaseConfiguration class.
Now that we have the attributes in place,
let's define the getters on the interface to resolve our compilation error.
With these four getters,
Spring Batch has access now to our batch configuration beans.
The last step is to define the strategy for how these beans are defined.
First, let's define the JobLauncher.
What I've done here is I've configured the launcher
to be of type SimpleJobLauncher.
This launcher just executes a job task on demand.
Note that I've set the JobRepository on the Launcher and
called afterPropertiesSet to ensure that the dependencies of
the JobRepository have been set.
Next, let's create the JobRepository.
I'll go ahead and drop that in.
I've configured this JobRepository to be created
with a JobRepositoryFactoryBean.
I set the batchDataSource and
batchTransactionManager to be used by the repository,
then I call afterPropertiesSet to ensure dependencies have been set.
The final step is to configure a method to be called after dependency
injection has been performed by the Spring container.
This method will handle the actual bean configuration.
Now, as part of initialization, we will set the JobRepository,
JobExplorer, and JobLauncher.
I'll use the JobExplorerFactoryBean to set the
DataSource on the JobExplorer instance.
That completes the configuration for the Spring Batch JobExplorer,
JobRepository, and JobLauncher.
As part of configuration, there are a few properties that we need to change,
so let's do that now.
I'm going to go ahead and close this class and open back up the Project tab.
Spring and Spring Boot provide you with support for defining the
application properties to configure your project,
as well as your project dependencies.
There are two properties that I want to add for
support in the project moving forward.
We're going to start by opening up the resources folder.
And under the config folder, I have a properties file named application.
yml.
Let's open that now.
This property file contains the base properties for configuring
your project and your project dependencies.
By default,
the annotation that we added on the BatchConfiguration class
with the name EnableBatchProcessing will create a runner by
default and execute your jobs on startup.
If this is the behavior you want, then you can skip this step.
But in our case, I want to start jobs on demand; therefore,
I'm going to change the configuration spring.
batch.
job.
enable to false.
Let me drop that in now.
Next,
I want to define the input path for files that will
be processed by the batch job.
These files will contain patient records that get
transformed and saved in a database.
I'm going to define the input path as an application-specific property.
Let's scroll down to the bottom of the application.
yml file.
I'm going to drop in the property now.
Note that I'm using the inputPath as the project's data folder.
A few things to consider.
As this is a demo, I've defined the property in the base file; however,
there are also property files for the Spring dev profile and prod profile.
It's recommended that you override this property within
those property files individually.
In order for me to access these properties,
I've created an ApplicationProperties class that maps
to the property names and values.
Let's open that up now.
I'm going to close the application.
yml file, open back up the Project tab,
and we see here at the top the ApplicationProperties class.
It's in the config folder.
As you can see,
this class is annotated with the ConfigurationProperties annotation.
Note that the prefix matches the property name we
defined in the Properties file.
I'll define a value for this now including a static class for the mapping.
Now, at runtime,
I'll be able to access the inputPath for the Batch job
using this ApplicationProperties file.
Note that I also set the default of the inputPath just in
case the property doesn't get defined. That completes the initial Spring Batch configuration.