Much like Spring Batch's support for FlatFiles when reading items,
Spring Batch also supports different strategies for item writing.
In this course, I'll be taking advantage of the JPAItemWriter.
The JPAItemWriter makes use of a JPAEntityManager instance.
At the beginning of the course,
I showed you how I configured the EntityManager as
part of the database configuration.
It's important to note that the ItemWriter requires a
transaction as part of processing.
While I'm leveraging JPA in this demonstration,
you should evaluate whether this is really required for your batch job.
You may not require the additional layer of JPA and could take
advantage of other Spring Batch item writers if needed.
Now let's look at the implementation for the JPAItemWriter.
I'm displaying the code for the new ItemWriter in
the BatchJobConfiguration Class.
First note that I again have annotated the Bean method for a StepScope.
I'll now be returning the type JpaItemWriter for the Bean.
The only configuration I need to make to the ItemWriter is
to pass in the EntityManagerFactory that I configured in the
database configuration class.
Just like with the ItemProcessor,
there will be some additional changes I need to make to the
BatchJobConfiguration class to remove the old writer and
update the job step configuration.
Let's do that now.
I'm going to demonstrate adding the new
JPAItemWriter to the BatchJobConfiguration.
Note that I'll be following demo 20 found in the DEMOS.
md file of the project root directory.
I'll be making the final modifications to the
BatchJobConfiguration to support writing items to the database.
I'm going to open back up the BatchJobConfiguration class,
and I'm going to start by scrolling down to the writer method.
I'm just going to go ahead and remove this method.
Now I'll add the new JpaItemWriter implementation code.
This code just creates an instance of JpaItemWriter for our PatientEntity and
then sets the EntityManagerFactory configured in the project.
As I've yet to autowire the EntityManagerFactory, let's do it now.
I'm going to scroll back up to the top, and I'll add the factory.
This autowires the EntityManagerFactory with a qualifier to assure I
get the correct Bean instance that I configured.
The last change I need to make is to update the job step.
Let's scroll down to that now.
I'm going to remove the code for the step, and I'll drop in the new code.
The only change here was to add the JpaItemWriter as an
argument to the method and change the writer call to use
the writer that was passed in. This completes the coding for the ItemProcessor.