Now that the ItemReader is implemented, I want to be able to unit test it.
Spring Batch provides strong support for unit testing
as you're going to see shortly.
I'm displaying the first part of updates I'll be making to the
existing BatchJobConfigurationTest class.
First, I'll autowire the FlatFileItemReader that I just created.
Then, as part of test setup,
I'll be defining the JobParameter for the ItemReader test.
The file name will be a test csv file, which includes only one test record.
We can find this file in the data folder of the project.
Next, let's look at the test.
Here is the full test case I'll implement for the file ItemReader.
I'm going to use the Spring Batch construct
MetaDataInstanceFactory to create a StepExecution using the
jobParameters that I defined for testing.
I'm going to use Spring Batch's StepScopeTestUtils to execute the step
with the scope that will include our fileName parameter.
I'm going to get the count of PatientRecords for later assertion.
I'll then read the record in the test file and perform
assertions on each field of the record.
Finally, I'll perform the assertion on the record count.
This is a fairly robust test of the reader.
If I wanted to simulate other situations with the reader,
I could create other simple unit test files that
set up fixtures for these cases.
Now let's implement the test.
We're going to add the FlatFileItemReader test and test setup
to the existing ConfigurationTest class.
Note that I'll be following Demo 13 found in the DEMOS.
md file in the root project directory.
For this demo,
I'll be adding the FlatFileItemReader implementation to the
BatchConfigurationTest case to verify its configuration.
Open up the class BatchJobConfigurationTest.
I'm going to start by autowiring the reader as a member on this Test class.
This will inject the FlatFileItemReader
implementation from the Configuration class.
To support the reader, we need to create job parameters for testing.
Let's drop those in now.
Now, before each test,
the JobParameter map will be initialized with a test input file.
The input file only contains a limited number of
records for the purpose of unit testing.
Now I'm going to drop in the test case for the FlatFileItemReader.
Note that this test method uses the Spring Batch
StepScopeTestUtils class to test the execution of the reader.
Just like in a full execution,
the parameter for the file name will be passed into the step
and the reader will read from the file.
Note that I've added several assertions for the content of
the file and the count of records read.
Let's look at that count check now.
Here we see at the bottom of the test the check for an assertion of 1.
Now let's try to run the test, and our test passed successfully. This completes the implementation of the test case for the new ItemReader.