In this section of the course,
I covered the first part of chunk-oriented processing,
which is the ItemReader.
First,
I updated the step we configured earlier to now use
chunk-oriented processing instead of the simple tasklet.
I noted that chunking is a process where items are read,
processed, and then chunked together for output.
Given this, I defined a reader, a processor,
and a writer as part of building the step.
Next, I used the Spring Batch FlatFileItemReader builder to build a reader.
The reader defined a name, a path for the file,
the number of lines to skip in the file,
and the mapping from the file record to a domain object.
Then I stubbed out an item processor and writer to allow for
testing the full execution of the new ItemReader.
Finally, I showed you how to unit test the ItemReader using a test file record.
I also showed you execution of the reader using the
stubbed processor and writer.
In the next section of the course,
I'm going to replace the stub processor with a real processor.
The processor will convert our patient records into database entity classes that can later be persisted to the database with an ItemWriter.