Hi there, and welcome back.
In this video we're going
to be learning about if statements.
If statements allow our programmes to make decisions
depending on a Boolean.
Let's get started with a friend name.
Let's say we've got a friend called Rolf
and we want to check whether the user's name is Rolf.
So the first thing we have to do
is ask the user for their name,
and then we're gonna start typing our first if statement.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna start
with the first keyword if.
The if keyword is followed by a space
and then we put the Boolean.
If this Boolean is true, then we will execute some code.
So if true, we will execute some code.
So we're gonna say hello, friend.
Now of course, true is always true,
so this if statement is always going to execute.
So what we want to put in here instead of true,
is a Boolean condition that depends on our variables,
one of which is something dynamic that the user types.
That way every time the user runs the programme,
they can type something different
and this if statement will behave in one way or another.
What we're gonna put here is,
if user underscore name, equal equal, friend.
Now, whenever we run this programme,
the friend variable will equal to Rolf,
and the username variable will equal
to whatever the user types.
Then we will compare them,
and if this evaluates to true,
the if statement will run this code here.
If it evaluates to false, then the if statement
will not run this code.
Now, let's talk about the syntax of the if statement.
First of all we have the if keyword,
then we have our Boolean, then we have this colon,
which is necessary in the if statement
at the end of the first line.
And then we have the body of the if statement.
Now something very important about if statements
is that they have to have spaces in front of each line.
Usually we use four spaces in Python.
That's important because if you want to add another thing
inside the if statement, such as print this runs too,
this also has four spaces in front of it,
and therefore Python knows that both of these prints
are inside the if statement, and they should run
only if this evaluates to true.
As soon as you eliminate those spaces
and you type something else,
this is no longer part of the if statement.
It always runs.
Because it's outside the if statement.
So to recap, this if statement will run this code
inside the body, only if this is true,
and these lines need to have some spacing
so that Python knows that they are both
inside the if statement.
Then when you take away the spaces,
Python knows that the if statement is terminated.
Notice that you cannot do this,
because Python would give you an error.
This follows a line that doesn't have spaces in front
so it's not part of the if statement,
it's just a line with spaces in front,
and Python won't like that.
So make sure that all the lines
that are inside the if statement
have these spaces.
As soon as you terminate the spaces,
you terminate the if statement.
Let's run this just to show you how it works.
I'll type in Rolf, and you see the three things printed out.
Hello friend, this runs too, and this runs anyway,
and now if I run it again and I type Bob,
you'll see that this runs anyway is printed out.
That's this line here.
And these two lines don't get printed out
because the username was not equal
to the friend in this case.
Now imagine you wanted to do something
if the username is equal to the friend,
such as print hello friend,
and also something if they are not equal to one another,
such as hello stranger.
You could do something like this.
You can do this, but it is a little bit verbose.
There's a lot of typing involved,
and there's a lot of similarities
between these two statements.
In fact, Python comes in with another keyword,
the else keyword, that is precisely for this thing.
This if statement is now called a compound if statement
or an if statement with two branches,
and what happens is if this one is not true,
it will jump to the else one.
So if the username is not equal to the friend,
this will be false, and we will jump here
and we will print hello, stranger.
Let's run this.
And I will type in Bob.
And you'll see that hello, stranger gets printed out.
So what's happened here is that Python knows
that these two statements are related,
because they come one after another
without any other commands in between.
What I mean by that is you've got this if statement
then you've got the body,
and the next line without these spaces in front
is the else.
So Python can build a relationship between these two
and say they're related.
And then what happens is, if this is not true,
we jump here.
Notice that if you put anything else here,
you're going to get problems.
Now, Python does not know
that this else is related to this if.
And therefore it tells you that this is invalid Python code
because it doesn't make sense to just have an else statement
on its own.
Earlier in the course we mentioned that we could turn
any value into a Boolean by passing it
through the bool function.
For example, print bool of five.
Here we're given five to the bool function
by putting it inside the brackets
and then we're giving that to the print function
to show it to the user.
So if we run this, you'll see that true gets printed out
because bool of five is true.
Bool of zero for example, is false.
So why is this important?
Well you can do if five, then print something like this.
What this means is that, if you do this by the way
this will always print out runs,
because five is true when passed through bool.
And behind the scenes,
Python is always passing everything here
through the bool function to check
whether it evaluates to true or false.
I just wanted to show you that the thing
that you put in the if statement does not have
to be a Boolean comparison.
It can just be a value.
For example, if we ask the user for their name,
we can just say if name.
Here, what we're doing is if the name evaluates to true
then we will print we know your name.
Now this is interesting,
because if we print the bool of name,
you will see that no matter what we type,
such as Rolf, it evaluates to true.
If we type something else, such as Bob,
it evaluates to true.
If we type something else, such as nothing,
that's when it evaluates to false.
So the bool of an empty string,
i.e. if we don't type anything, is false.
So this is one of these scenarios
where putting the variable directly in the if statement
can be useful.
Simply if we don't have a value for name
or if the names value is an empty string,
we don't run this.
Imagine you've got this code,
and you have a list of your friends,
Rolf, Bob and Anne, and a list of your family members,
Jen and Charlie.
Now we want to ask the user for their name,
and then print hello friend,
if they are one of your friends,
hello family if they are one of your family members,
or I don't know you if they are neither of them.
We'll start by doing if user underscore name,
equal equal friends.
Now, here we've got a problem.
Equal equal compares two things directly.
And username is always going to be a string.
That's what the input function always give us.
But friends is a list.
So these two things are never going
to be equal to one another,
just because they are not even the same type of data.
So what we want to do is we want
to use Python's keyword in.
The in keyword checks for whether the username
is a value contained within the friends collection.
So if this is true, then we will print hello, friend.
Now, we wanna check whether the username is
in the family members.
So you may be tempted to do something like
if username in family,
and then of course your else statement.
What we print, I don't know you.
You may be tempted to do this,
but alas that is a problem.
Let's run this programme and I'll type Rolf.
And now you could see that we get two things printed out,
which is not ideal.
We get hello friend, and then I don't know you.
Clearly not the case if we print hello friend,
we must know this person.
So here's what happened in the code.
We have Rolf inside our friends list,
but we don't have Rolf inside our family list.
Then the username was Rolf, so Rolf in friends is true.
So we printed hello, friend.
Now in an unrelated if statement, we checked
whether the username it was in family.
So Rolf in family is false.
So because these two if statements are related
to one another, we jump directly to the else,
and we printed I don't know you.
So really what we want to do,
is we wanna chain all of these if statements,
so that only one of them ever runs.
Of course Python comes with that too.
Just type elif.
What this means is if this, else if this, else that.
So we will do if Rolf in friends, print hello friend,
otherwise, if the username is in family, print hello family,
otherwise if neither of those were true,
print I don't know you.
Now if we run this, and we type Rolf,
you see that hello friend gets printed out,
and nothing else.
Similarly if we type here something like Smith,
you'll see I don't know you.
You can put as many elif statements as you want
inside one of these chains,
so you can have multiple of those if you wanted
and as many of you want of course
if they have the same comparison then that's kinda pointless
but you can put as many of them as you want
and they get evaluated in order,
so this one gets evaluated first,
then this one and so on.
The first one that runs means that the others don't run.
So if the username is in friends, these all get skipped.
If the username is not in friends,
then we will try this one.
And if this is true, then this gets skipped.
Finally, if none of them are true, then we run this.
By the way I wanted to say that these four spaces
in front of the lines have a special name
and that is called indentation.
I say that because you'll hear me say this more often
and also you may hear it when you're reading about code.
The indentation is the spaces in front of a line
that denote that this is inside a block.
And in this case the block in question is the if body.
Usually we use four spaces for indentation in Python code,
but you can use two if you want
or indeed any other number of spaces.
However, four is the normal amount to use
and I would recommend that you use that.
Many problems for beginner programmers
in Python are caused by indentation.
Just take special care when indenting your code
and putting spaces in front of it or removing spaces
from the front of it, as that can sometimes cause
a bit of confusion, and can cause some problems.
That's everything for this video though.
We've learned about if statements.
Thank you for joining me, and I'll see you in the next one.