Hi, and welcome back. In this video,
I wanted to guide you through some
of the most popular Python libraries that can be used
for a variety of things.
Here we're going to talk about some libraries you can use
to interact with databases, some that you've already seen
and some that you already haven't to look
at web development, a couple to do communications,
like sending emails or SMS texts, a couple for GUI design,
for Graphical User Interfaces, like desktop apps, a bunch
of them that can be used for data science
and that are very popular, and then some
for computer vision, and we're gonna look at a couple
of development tools as well you can use to make your life
a bit easier when you're working with Python.
For databases, you're already looked at sqlite3,
which comes with Python, and you can use sqlite3 to interact
with sqlite databases.
There's another library that is actually fairly similar to
sqlite3 in some cases, although it is more advanced,
and that's called psycopg2.
Psycopg2 can be used to interact with Postgres databases
as opposed to sqlite databases.
Postgres databases are also relational databases,
like sqlite databases are,
but they are much more advanced and they let you do
more things, and generally they perform better,
but they're also much more complicated.
Similarly to psycopg2, you've also got aiopg which
is the asynchronous version of psycopg2.
It lets you do things like asynch connections
to a database and sort of run other code while you wait
for code to come back from the database,
and things like that.
So if you're looking into high-performance PostgresSQL
database connections from within Python
and your application is asynchronous,
I recommend you use aiopg.
And then you've also got SQLAlchemy.
SQLAlchemy is sort of a different beast altogether.
It can be used to connect to sqlite, or Postgres, or MySQL,
or Oracle, or indeed any other type of database,
and it sort of wraps the entire database connection
in a different format.
So what SQLAlchemy allows you to do,
and we're gonna look at this later on in the course,
in this section, what SQLAlchemy allows you to do
is define classes and each class has a table
and a bunch of columns, and then whenever you create
an object, that sort of creates its corresponding role
in the database.
So it lets you work with Python only
and not really worry about the database.
It just gets taken care of for you.
This is known as an object-relational mapping
and SQLAlchemy is the most popular one in Python.
For web development libraries, you've already seen Flask.
I really like Flask, it's a very simple framework
that nonetheless is very extensible and quite powerful,
but a lot of people have heard of Django, which is sort
of the big brother of web development in Python,
and Django is a really powerful web framework,
but it's also quite complicated.
If you want to start learning Python,
er, sorry, learning Django, there's a lot of stuff you have
to learn about how Django does things
and what structure it wants you to follow in your code,
and how it wants you to handle X and Y and so forth.
So the learning curve is much steeper.
This is why I prefer Flask, especially
when you're starting out.
So, Django can be really useful for making specific types
of web applications because Django gives you a lot
of things out of the box when you're,
you can just tell Django to create an app for you,
and it will give you an app with a bunch of things
in it like user authentication, an administration panel,
and so forth, but then of course that code
is not code you've written, so it can limit you
in what you can do to change it.
You sort of have to follow its structure.
As well as Flask and Django, you've got a bunch
of asynchronous frameworks for web development.
These are very powerful, but they are also more complicated
than Flask, particularly aiohttp, that we've already seen,
and on Tornado, they are pretty challenging to really grasp,
but they are quite powerful.
They give you a lot of stuff you can do.
For example, aiohttp, as we know, gives you a client
as well that you can use to make asynchronous requests
as well as do development with it.
Sanic and Quart are two new frameworks that
actually don't have a lot of popularity yet,
but they have been developed to be simple frameworks
for web development that are asynchronous.
They very much are similar to Flask in that regard,
but they are asynchronous.
Quart particularly actually was recently suggested to me
by one of the students and it is an exact mimic,
or copy, of Flask, but made asynchronous,
and as such it works with a lot of the Flask extensions.
Flask is a very popular framework because
of the extensions that sort of enhance Flask's power.
Sanic doesn't have those extensions,
and as such is a bit more limited in that regard.
So, if you want to do asynchronous web development,
maybe look into Quart if you're already familiar with Flask.
There's also a very popular web development framework
in Python called Bottle that is the precursor to Flask,
and is another simple framework.
I can't say much about it, though,
because I've never actually used it,
but I know that it exists and a lot
of people do know about it.
For communications, and this is something we're going
to look at throughout the rest of this section,
you've got smtplib that comes built-in with Python.
This allows you to connect to an smpt server.
These are normally email servers, like Gmail
and so forth, and they let you authenticate
on those servers with a user name and password
and then send emails from that server using your account.
So you could use smptlib to log into your Gmail account
and send an email through your account.
So it can be really powerful, but also slightly limiting
in some cases because you have to send the email using your
own Gmail account.
As such, we have Mailgun.
Mailgun is another breed of email sending libraries.
You've got a bunch of others like SendGrid that
do the same job, and these essentially give you
an email service that you can send emails
from without requiring that you use
your own personal account.
So they give you an email address,
and you can send emails from there.
It also has a nice API that you can interact with
in order to send those emails,
and we're going to look at this shortly.
You've got also got a very popular and very powerful library
and, indeed, a company called Twilio,
and Twilio does tools for communication,
and they have a lot of ways to talking to their products
using Python, and they can do things like
send text messages, SMS.
They also do things like call centre products and a bunch
of other stuff like real-time chats and things like that,
and you can interact with all of those using Python.
So if you are thinking of by,
of making simple chat application
or you want to send text messages, look into Twilio.
They are really quite good and their pricing
is fairly reasonable.
It's not terribly expensive.
If you have a small company and you're sending a
small amount of text messages, or chat sessions,
things like that, it's actually pretty cheap.
If you are a large company that's sending a lot
of text messages or chat sessions, the price actually
goes down as you increase your volume,
so it ends up still being fairly reasonable.
Also I've spoken with them in a corporate setting,
and they're willing to play around with the price as well.
So it's definitely something worth considering
if that's something you wanna build.
For GUI design, which stands for Graphical User Interface,
this is something that a lot
of people actually don't know Python can do.
For a lot of people, Python is sort of a data science
and web development language, and that's it.
But actually you're got some Graphical User Interface
libraries that you can use to make desktop applications,
and the most popular one, or I'd say maybe the best one,
is called Kivy, and Kivy can be used for,
in designing Graphical User Interfaces,
but also for making games.
Now, I haven't looked too in-depth into Kivy.
I've not really use it in a professional setting,
but I have read through their documentation and some
of their guides and it actually looks
fairly straightforward.
Not too easy, but it looks doable to make games
and graphical user interfaces in Kivy...
Whereas if you look into Tkinter, I don't even know how
to say this word, it's not so simple.
This is the previous, eh, it's a much older library used
for making Graphical User Interfaces,
but it's not as straightforward.
So if you want to build Graphical User Interfaces,
I definitely recommend you look into Kivy.
For data science, you've got a bunch of libraries that
can be used for scientific computing as well
as advanced mathematics and things like that.
You've got NumPy and SciPy which are used for just that.
These are things that allow you to work with matrices
and vectors, and things like that, and again,
I'm not much of a scientist so I don't know much
about these things, but they are the staple
in the data science community.
So if you've done any data science,
you probably have seen these already,
and if not you definitely want to look into them.
You've also got Pandas and Matplotlib.
These are, again, used in data science very extensively,
and Matplotlib particularly also outside
of data science used for creating graphs.
So if you want to make like bar charts, or line charts
and things like that with Python, Matplotlib
is a good way of doing that.
Also a popular thing in data science are Jupyter notebooks.
This is not really a library in Python as much
as a tool that you can use to create a notebook,
essentially just written notes,
and you can embed within that notebook Python code,
and not only that, but you can run bits
of that Python code within the notebook.
So if you're taking notes for a course like this one,
it can be useful to create your own Jupyter notebook,
take notes, and write the code that we teach you
in these lectures into the notebook,
and then whenever you go back to it,
you can run the different code excerpts
for the lecture without having to search
through your files and many folders, things like that.
So, a pretty useful tool,
but not something I've used very extensively.
And of course there are many other tools that use Python
in data science such as TensorFlow, which is,
you know, not really a library per se but still uses Python.
For computer vision, it's not really something I'd recommend
using Python for necessarily.
I'm sure there are better ways of doing computer vision
than with a language that only runs on one thread,
but nonetheless you've got OpenCV and SimpleCV.
OpenCV is a large behemoth of computer vision.
SimpleCV is a wrapper around it that it a bit simpler.
So if you want to do computer vision in a sort
of small scale, for example, make your application
able to recognise faces and things like that, use SimpleCV.
For development tools that we are going to look at
in this section as well, you've got pylint,
which is a linter.
Linters, essentially you can run them and give them one
of your Python files, and it will tell you if you messed up.
That's essentially it.
If you've got some unused variables, or maybe you forgot
to import something, or you forgot to add a comment
somewhere, pylint is one of the family of linters in Python.
This is the most popular one, the one I'd recommend using,
and it's really helpful.
It tells you when you've messed up or when you've done
something that you shouldn't do,
and it tells you how to fix it most of the time,
so a great thing to include in your workflow.
We're going to look at how to use pylint soon.
You've also got flake8, yapf, and Black.
These are formatters.
So, what they do is,
you can run them on a Python form and it will reformat it,
add spaces and new lines where required,
to make your file more readable.
Now, I always recommend you make your own files readable,
but it can be useful to run through a formatter
after you've made your file so that
it always has the same style.
You know, if you're working with someone else
and you like putting spaces around an equals sign,
and they like putting the equals sign stuck to the variable,
I don't like that but, hey, some people do,
then you can run both pieces of code through the formatter
and they'll end up looking similar.
So, the style will be consistent and you won't hate each
other for using different styles.
We're gonna look at this in the section,
but if you wanna read a bit more you can go over to our blog
and we've got a link there
on handy Python development tools.
This is going to be linked in the resources section
of this lecture as well, so feel free to give it a click
and have a wee read at the blog post.
Finally, something we didn't mention at the start,
but there are a lot of IDEs,
or Integrated Development Environments you can use
with Python.
The most popular one, the one we've been using, is PyCharm.
PyCharm is made by Jet Brains,
and it's probably the most powerful IDE you can use
in Python.
It has a lot of nice features like run configurations
which allow you to run many different things
from within PyCharm.
It's got things like database connection handlers,
it's got a built-in debugger that you can use to step
through your code and that's extremely powerful
and really handy, and of course it sort of does
everything you need for Python.
However, it can be a bit large.
It can be cumbersome.
It can be quite slow to start up and to
do things like searching, and things like that.
Also, if you open very large files with PyCharm
it can sometimes struggle.
So, a very popular thing to do is to have PyCharm
for your sort of normal development flow,
and when you require those more advanced pieces
of functionality...
But they also have what I like to a call
a glorified text editor when you wanna make quick changes,
when you have a small project that you don't really
need the power of PyCharm for.
And in those cases, I like using Visual Studio Code,
which is also an integrated development environment,
an IDE, but it's much more toned down.
It doesn't do as much for you, and it can be a little bit
trickier to set up nice, but then it's fast, it's snappy.
You can do basically anything you want with it
and it looks really nice as well,
so I like Visual Studio Code.
Some people like to use Atom or Sublime Text,
and these are three what I sort
of called glorified text editors.
You can try them and give them a ago as well.
One of the great things about these three text editors
is that you can change them very easily
to suit what you like.
So you can sort of change the themes, the colours,
the way tabs show up, the icons, and everything about them,
normally using cascading style sheets to do that, CSS.
But of course, if you want to learn more about IDEs
in Python and what sort of things you can do, we've got
also a blog post, part of our 100 Days of Python series,
that you can look at, and it goes in-depth
into why I think using PyCharm is the best thing to do
and sort of a few other options as well
in case you wanna have a look.
So that's it for this video.
I hope you've enjoyed this brief walkthrough of some
of the most important Python libraries out there.
Let's go into the next one.
So, I'll see you there.