Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're just going to be setting up our project
that we're going to be creating in this section.
I've created a folder here in my documents
and the only thing you need
is to create a folder for your project,
then remember where the folder is
so that you can find it in your terminal.
Once you created a folder for your project,
let's go into the terminal
and create our environment using Pipenv.
Okay, once you are in your terminal,
let's go into this directory.
Remember on Unix systems like Mac OS X and Linux,
we're gonna do cd and then find the folder.
In Windows, you're gonna do chdir
and then you're gonna find the folder like C:\
wherever the folder is.
Here the folder is in my Documents/teclado-projects
/your-first-flask-app/
so we're gonna cd into that
and then we're going to use pipenv to instal Flask.
Flask is the library we're going to be using in this section
to create our website.
It's a really lightweight library.
We're gonna learn a lot about how it works
throughout this section.
Once you do pipenv instal Flask,
make sure that it is creating a virtual environment
using the correct version of Python,
in this case Python 3.7.
I know you can't see that very well,
but version 3.7 there.
3.6 is fine, 3.5.
Just don't go under 3
just because of some of the syntax we're gonna be using.
Once it's installed,
you'll have a virtual environment created as well.
You know this already.
Pipenv creates a virtual environment for you.
Remembering this virtual environment
is gonna be very important
because we're gonna need to give it to PyCharm
in order for PyCharm to use the correct Python version.
Okay, so now that we've got this created,
we've got, if we do ls or dir in Windows,
we've got a Pipfile and that Pipfile.lock.
They're under the Pipfile.
It gives us what libraries we're installing.
Pipfile.lock gives us a bit of security
and also instals the correct versions.
If we share both with other people,
then they'll be able to instal exactly the same versions
that we installed when we set up the project.
Now that we've got this,
again remember the location of this virtual environment,
and let's go over to PyCharm to create our new project.
Once you've opened PyCharm, you'll see a window like this.
Just create a new project
and here make sure to select the location of your project.
So in my case, this is in my Documents/teclado-projects
/your-first-flask-app.
Be sure to select this folder
and then in the interpreter,
let's go and find the virtual environment
that was created for us by Pipenv.
Notice when I open this here,
I get a lot of virtual environments
in various different places.
We're gonna need to go and add a local virtual environment
and then find the virtual environment that we had before
so going back over to the terminal,
in my case this is in /users/jslvtr.local and so forth.
So PyCharm allows you to copy this
and then just put it in here in the path.
This is the virtual environment.
Then you're gonna open it up,
find the bin folder,
and find python.
Okay, make sure to select python inside the bin folder
and then press OK and now PyCharm knows
that this is the Python version you want to use.
It's gonna allow you to use Python 3.7 syntax.
It's going to use the packages that are installed
in this interpreter and not in the system Python.
Then we can press create and it will ask us
whether we want to create a project from existing sources.
That's because we've got the Pipfile and the Pipfile.lock
in there already and we're gonna say yes
and then we're going to get our new project
that has our two files there already.
Whenever you want to instal new libraries,
now you must not go through
or you could go through the PyCharm
settings here, this thing here,
but I'd recommend you go through the Pipenv settings
using the terminal.
That's because this is going to instal something
directly in the virtual environment,
but it's not going to update your Pipfile.
So if you want to instal more things,
you can go through PyCharm,
but you probably want to go through the terminal.
Just do pipenv instal whatever else you need.
For this project, we're not gonna need anything else
so Flask is the only thing we need and we've got that now.
If you create a new Python file and you call it app.py,
you should be able to do from flask_import Flask.
Okay, if this doesn't give you any errors,
then you're good to go.
If this gives you any errors,
just check your settings, check your Pipfile,
make sure everything's setup correctly.
It's possible that
either something wasn't installed correctly,
in which case your Pipfile will not show Flask,
or it's possible that
you're not using the correct virtual environment,
in which case you want to go back
and make sure to select the correct virtual environment here
or add a local virtual environment and find the correct one.
Okay, make sure that Flask is here
and then you can import Flask.
Once that's all ready,
you're good to continue into the next video
where we're going to be implementing
our first web application.
I'll see you there.