I just wanted to take a few moments
to say thank you for joining me throughout this course.
I hope you've really enjoyed learning all about Python.
We've gone from the very fundamentals back at the start;
numbers, printing, strings and so forth
and we've ended up in a much more advanced stage.
We've even learned about one of the most difficult topics
in Python which is asynchronous development.
Over the way we've also looked at databases,
files, generators.
We've looked at Flask.
We've looked at web scraping and all sorts of stuff.
Now you are ready to continue your Python journey
and learn more about the topics that really interest you.
So thank you for joining me once again
and I'll see you in the next course.