Hi there and welcome back,
in this video we're looking at
a more advanced Python concept called typing.
Python is what's known as a dynamic language,
in a dynamic language we don't specify what type
of data a variable holds, for example,
here we've got a cursor and we're not saying that
this cursor has to be a specific type
like an integer or a string or a cursor object.
In other programming languages like Java for example,
you would say Cursor cursor you know?
This cursor has to be of type Cursor whatever class this is.
But in Python you don't have to say that.
Similarly if you create a variable with the value five
in Java you would have to say int x is five,
because that specifies that x has to be
an integer at all times,
and if you were to do this you would get an error.
Because this string five is not an integer.
Java is a statically typed language,
a language where you have to specify the type of variables
as you create them.
But Python is a dynamically typed language,
which means you don't have to do that.
It means you are a bit more flexible
because your variable can change types
between executions if you want,
and also there is a bit less code to write
because you don't have to constantly define
what every variable is.
However it also has some drawbacks,
and the main drawback is that sometimes you can use
a variable, thinking it is one thing
but it is really something else and you're not clear
about that because you don't have anything
that tells you what type it is.
For example if you have a variable called friends
and it's a tuple of your friends.
At some point later on in the programme maybe you forget
that it's a tuple and down here you try to do friends.append
something, obviously this wouldn't work
because you can't append on a tuple but because you weren't
seeing this code at that moment in time
you didn't realise that.
That's one of the problems with dynamically typed languages
like Python so Python has introduced in Python three,
the concept of typing where you can tell your editor
PyCharm and some other third party programmes
what your functions return and what your parameter types
should be so that when you're programming
it's a bit clearer what you're doing.
Here's an example on how you might tell Python
what your function returns,
for example this create book table returns none
and we know that because all Python functions
return none by default if you don't include
a return statement, so what can you do?
You can tell Python that when you call this function
you expect it to return none.
You do this like so.
After the function definition, but before the colon
you put this dash greater than, none.
Now when you go back to app.py
and you've got here database.create book table.
You can say something like my variable equals that
but notice how now PyCharm gives you this squiggly line
underneath and it says create book table
doesn't return anything.
Therefore you probably don't want to assign it
to a variable because that's pretty pointless.
Since the value's going to be none.
If you remove the none which you can do of course
it's totally optional that now disappears,
because PyCharm is not aware that the function
doesn't return anything.
Okay, so again you can include these type hints,
that's what they're called.
But, they are not enforced by Python.
These are only useful when you're developing
in PyCharm or when you use a couple other
pieces of software that will analyse your code
and tell you when you are doing things like assigning
a variable to a function that is meant
to return none, when you run your programme,
Python completely ignores these type hints
and it doesn't do anything with them.
You won't get any errors for using them incorrectly,
or for assigning to a variable the return value
of this function even if it is none.
So again these are only just for you,
and the most common use case is when you are developing
with PyCharm because PyCharm makes good use of these things.
Okay similarly the add book function also returns none
so we can make it return none there.
Now when you call the function if you try to assign it
to a variable, once again you'll get a wee message
saying hey this function doesn't return anything,
are you sure you want to do this?
So that's for each function.
Let's go and add a return value for each function
in our database interface.
I'm going to ignore the get all books for now,
we'll do this one at the end.
So as you can see all our functions return none,
and we can add that in, now we can go back to get all books
and we can say that this is going to return
a list of dicts because it returns a list
of dictionaries here, of course we get red squiggly lines,
because PyCharm doesn't know what these two are.
So we have to go and import them.
Whenever you want to import anything that's related
to type hinting like this here,
we can import it from the typing module.
This is new in Python 3.5,
and there we have it, now it's happy that it's returning
a list of dictionaries.
If you want you can also tell it what each
of the keys and values are.
So you could say inside brackets, str which means string.
This is the string class for the keys,
and str for the values.
That would say that every key is a string
and every value is a string.
Now of course we know that the red status
can be an integer.
Therefore we must do something else,
we have to do that they keys can be strings,
all of the keys are strings.
Name author in red but the values are a union
of string and integer, and again we have to import this
of course from the typing module.
Now this says that this function returns a list
of dictionaries where each key is a string
and each value is either a string or an integer.
Notice that's what the union does
and this is what the dict does.
Now in order to simplify we can actually create
our own types which is pretty exciting.
We can cut this code here I'm gonna cut it with Command + X
or Control + X in Windows and say that it's going to return
a list of books, then we can go up to the top
and say that Book is what we cut earlier.
A Book type is a new type that is a dict
of strings to strings or integers
and then down here we can use our new Book type
to simplify our code and make it a bit more explicit,
exactly what's going on.
Notice that when you create a new type
because it's sort of like a class,
even though it's not used as a class.
You normally would give them a capital letter to begin with.
This is just the convention you can of course give them
lowercase letters if you want and that's totally fine.
Okay now that we've looked at return values,
we can now look at the parameters.
The name is going to be a string,
so you'd think that we would do this.
However this dash and greater than is only used
for return values, when you want to determine
or define the type of a parameter you use the colon here.
Mildly confusing because the colon's normally
used to signal the start of a block.
This is one of the few times where you use a colon
to determine something else,
this and list splicing are two examples
that come to the top of my head.
Author is also going to be a string, so that's that.
Notice that if you go over to app.py
into the add book function and you replace name
by something that's not a string like five
PyCharm now gives you that yellow background that
is not so readable and it says expected type str
got int, so it can help you when you are
developing but Python is not going to enforce this
when yo uare coding so if you do type five there
and you run the programme
you won't get any errors you'll just input
the name as five and then you get an error
in SQLite because the type is defined as a text.
Going back to database we can do the same for any other
functions that need parameters like mark book as read
also a string and delete book also a string.
Okay, not too many of Python's libraries
and projects and things like that use type hinting.
Because it is quite new, but I can recommend using it
in your projects it will help you over time
as your projects grow and also it sort of gives you
a bit more readability in terms
of okay what's going to happen with a name here?
It's a strong so probably gonna use it as a string
then you won't try to append things to it
inside this function for example.
Indeed if you try to do name.append it'll tell you
that this is unlikely, unresolved reference append
for class string PyCharm now thinks that
name is a string even though it doesn't have any context
on where it was defined just because you said
that it should be a string.
So if you try to append something as if it were a list,
it will tell you this is wrong.
Of course if you change this to a list,
now you can do name.append
and notice how it already likes it
and it tells you hey you can append here.
Okay so type hinting pretty useful,
helps you helps PyCharm give you good suggestions
and overall as your apps grow,
it's gonna help them stay a bit more maintainable.
So definitely a good thing to be doing.
Feel free to do that for other functions in here,
but the most important functions for you to do that in
are those functions that you're going to call
and receive values from.
Your menus and things like that probably not so important
since nothing's calling them and they are not taking
any parameters, there's not much to define there.
You could return the function,
you could define the function returns none.
But because nothing's calling this function
other than you up here, it doesn't matter much
I wouldn't worry too much about doing that.
Okay we can go over to the database connection
and we can also define that the enter method
is going to return something
and what it's going to return is not a type
from the typing module but a type from the SQLite3 module
that SQLite3.connection.
Notice that the connection here is not a type per-se
it is an actual class, it is something that you can
create and that indeed this connection gets created
when you call SQLite3.connect,
and that's fine you can tell PyCharm
that this is going to return a proper class.
Totally cool it doesn't have to be a type
from the typing model it doesn't have to be str or int.
It can be an actual class that you have defined
or that is defined in some other module.
Now when we go over to database.py PyCharm will be able
to advise us that the connection object
has all these things from the SQLite module.
Which is pretty handy, okay.
So again good for you, good for PyCharm,
good for your projects as they grow.
Definitely recommend that you do this.
So that's it for this video,
and I'll see you in the next one.