Hi, guys, and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be encapsulating our logic
into our page so that it the app dot py becomes much simpler
and we can very easily reproduce a search.
I'm gonna start off at app dot py again by asking the user
what author they want and what tag they want.
Now, I'm no longer going to be showing the user what tags
there are available because I want to run
through the search very quickly
so this is just an alternative way of doing things.
Instead of getting the available tags and printing that,
we're going to just delete that, we're gonna delete that,
we're gonna delete that,
and we're left with the central part of the logic
which is select an author, select a tag,
and click the search button.
So we're going to cut that and we're gonna
instead do page dot search for quotes, author, and tag
or select a tag rather.
I'm just gonna rename it to tag.
Now, we're also going to print this
because we wanna be as simple as possible.
So what this is gonna do is something slightly different.
It's no longer saying, hey, I wanna do this with the page.
Now this is saying I wanna use this page to search
for quotes and I don't actually care
what happens to the page itself.
This is a slightly different way of going
about interacting with the page using selenium
but it's a perfectly valid way
and something I'll encourage you to do.
If you can encapsulate actions within the page,
it's gonna make using the page very easy.
So going over to quotes page now down here,
we're gonna add our method
and that is going to be search for quotes.
Takes in an author name which a string and a tag name
which is a string and it's gonna return
a list of quote parser.
Okay, the first thing it's gonna do is
is going to do self select author, author name.
So just gonna call this method here.
Then, it's going to try to do something
and what it's going to try to do is select a tag
and that's gonna be the tag name.
But it's possible that it won't find it.
No such element exception.
And this one here has to be imported by the way
from selenium so import selenium and there you go.
So you wanna do from selenium common exceptions,
import no such element exception.
If it can't find it, that means that this tag didn't exist
for this author so we're gonna raise an invalid tag
for author error and finally if that doesn't happen,
it's gonna do self dot search button, click,
and then return self dot quote.
Now we do need to have this invalid tag for author error
which is going to be a value error subclass
and it's not going to do anything.
Okay, and capital F, there you go.
So, went a bit quickly there but all this is doing
is selecting and author, then selecting a tag,
then clicking the button, and then returning quotes.
And notice that all this is doing
is it's using other methods and properties
that we have previously defined and used in app dot py.
This is a very natural progression for your applications.
First, you define your application as doing something
and then you encapsulate that application logic
into a method or a function.
Here, pulling it inside this page makes sense
because it modifies and interacts with the page itself.
By allowing the page to give us everything that you need
in order to search and find quotes,
it means that your apps become much simpler
and also the page can still work as normal
using the other methods if you want.
We've added some error handling with this try, except
just in case that this tag name is invalid
because we're no longer telling the user
what tags are valid so doing that will raise an error
if the tag doesn't exist.
Let's go over to app dot py and run it.
And now you'll see that we've done another improvement.
We ask for the author and the tag first
and then we do the slow thing, which is launch in chrome.
So we're gonna do Bob Marley and music.
And now here comes chrome and everything happens instantly.
It's now waiting for us to type so there you have
your programme and then you have your quote.
Because this application only ever prints out one quote
for this tag, you get a list of one element
but if there were more, you would get a list of all quotes.
This is how we can encapsulate some logic into our page
and this is really helpful to simplify your applications.
Thanks for joining me in this video
and I'll see you in the next one.