Hi and welcome back, in this video we're going to
be creating our locator files by getting data out of the
HTML here using Chrome.
So we said that earlier we've got two locator files in our
project, the quote locators, and the quotes page locators.
The quotes page is this page you see here, and the HTML
is down here on the right, so let's centre on the HTML,
and look at what the quote page has to offer.
We have a bunch of quotes in divs, and as you can see
they are each down here, so the page is essentially
something that contains these quotes, and it also contains
a few other things like the tags and a title, and so forth.
For our project, the quotes page is going to allow us to
retrieve these divs here, these quotes.
Now then, the quote locators are going to be the locators
that are within a single quote.
So our quotes page has only to worry about finding this
div, and this div, and this div, and so forth, and then
we're gonna give that entire element, to our quote locators
and they're gonna be able to find, this span, this other
author, and also the tags, so let's go over into PyCharm
and start by creating the quotes page locators, OK?
So, go over quotes_page_locators and we're gonna create
a class here called QuotesPageLocators, and all this is
gonna contain is a single constant, a constant in Python,
I'm not sure if we've mentioned this before, is normally
a variable that's all in upper case, and this is gonna
contain "div.quote", and if we go back to Chrome, we can
see that "div.quote" is going to give us this div here,
with this "class" quote.
But if we find many of them, it's gonna give us this one,
this one, this one, this one, it's gonna give us all of
these in this page.
So when we use that locator, we'll be able to find
all of these divs, for each div, we're going to use
the locators in here, so if we now go to the quote locators,
we're going to create some quote locators, and these
are going to be one for each thing that we want to extract
from a quote.
So that's an author,
a content or a quote, and also a tags locator.
OK, let's fill these in, the author, content, and tags.
So for the author, we're going to look for this small
class "author", this tag here, so if we go back to PyCharm,
in the author we can put "small.author", that's going to
look again for the "small" tag that has class "author".
For the content, we are looking for "span" with a class
of "text",
and finally for the tags, we are looking for a "div"
that has class "tags", this one here, but we are actually
looking for each of these "a" tags, so that we can extract
the different tags that are in there.
So we're gonna look for "div.tags", and inside it
"a.tag", and we're gonna find multiple of them.
So there's gonna be "div.tags", and in it "a.tag", OK?
These are locators so given one of these quotes, with
this locator, we'll be able to find the author.
So once again, going back to the HTML, given one of these
quotes, one of these divs specifically, these locators are
unique enough that we'll be able to find the quote contents
using "span.text", the author using "small.author",
and the tags using "div.tags", "a.tag".
Now if we were given this entire page, we would not know
whether to extract the quote contents from the first quote
or from the second quote, or from the third quote, and
so forth, so what we're going to do, is we are going to give
our, a parser, what's gonna use those locators, only one
of these divs, and then with that one, it's gonna be able to
find the correct element, and we're gonna treat them
independently, I know this doesn't make much sense just yet,
but believe me, as we progress through this app, it's going
to make more and more sense, for now, just trust me that
this is the way to go forward, and let's go over to the
next video, where we're going to look at creating our pages.
I'll see you there.