Hi, and welcome back.
Something that really bugs me about our application
is that once you're in a post,
you can't go back to the homepage
unless you press the back button.
Similarly, you can't really easily create a new post
unless you type the URL yourself,
you know, slash post slash create,
and even when you're here,
you can't go back to the homepage either.
So it's always a good idea to add some proper navigation
to your pages just so your users and yourself
can go through them a bit easier.
Let's go over to PyCharm and do this just now.
I'm gonna stop the app first of all and minimise that,
and in order to add the links,
all I have to do is think
about where we wanna put them.
Personally, I think that every page should have a link
to the homepage.
So I'm gonna add the link to the homepage
inside based on HTML.
This block content will be replaced
by the child's content every page.
So if you put something in here,
it won't be present in any of the pages
just because when you have home.jinja2, for example,
this is going to replace this.
It's not going to add to it.
So if you wanna put something in every page,
put it outside of the block of content.
What we're gonna do here is add a URL to the homepage.
And I think you can do this.
Add a new anchor tag, add the HREF
and make it point to the URL for of the homepage.
Try that out.
Pause the video and give it a go.
I'm sure you managed.
All that you do is create a new A sign,
give it a new HREF of URL for and the homepage in here.
Then close the tag and type in home, for example.
Notice how the HREF needs these quotation marks around it
because the HREF contents have to be
inside quotation marks for HTML.
This here will be replaced by the URL or the endpoint
of your home function, this one.
If we run the app now and we go back to Chrome
and we refresh, we can see that we've lost the blog post,
first of all, but we have this Home there.
If we go into a specific post, that Home is still there.
Something that isn't there, though,
is the ability to create a new post.
I think that creating a new post should only be
in the homepage.
So let's stop our app, minimise that
and go over to the homepage,
and down below, add another link.
Once again, I think you can do this.
Hopefully, you got that.
In order to create a new post,
all we have to do is again the same.
So create an A tag, which an anchor tag.
In the HREF, type URL for,
and then here, the name of the function
that will give you your create.jinja2.
That's the create function, so let's go there.
It doesn't need any arguments.
Any arguments could go here after a comma,
but it doesn't need any because it doesn't
take any parameters.
That's it.
Pressed something too many times there,
and then type create post,
create new post, for example, close the A tag,
and that's it.
Again, we can run our app.
Go over here, refresh,
and now we can see this Create new post thing there.
So now we've got a bit of a nicer navigation there
that we can navigate our page
without having to type out the URLs ourselves.
I want you to realise these are just building blocks.
You know, you've got your links,
you've got your P tags, your lists
and a few things in Flask like URL for,
redirect, render templates,
the ability to show information,
and there are countless things you can do
with this knowledge already.
Granted, the website could look a bit nicer.
You wanna look at CSS for that.
This is not the course for that
because this is not a web course,
but if you want to look at CSS for styling the page,
make it look a bit nicer, add some colour,
different font sizes, maybe not put everything just
on the left of the page,
maybe put things centred in the middle
or something like that.
You can learn about that,
and it's actually fairly straightforward
to do some simple but nice looking website.
And now with Python, you can do a lotta stuff.
You know Python pretty well by now.
You can store things in a database
and do countless other things
in terms of giving the use and information
and calculating things.
Hopefully, this opens new doors for you
in terms of communicating with your users.
I hope you've enjoyed this section,
and I've been glad to guide you through Flask development,
and I'll see you in the next video.