Hi, and welcome back.
Let's look at deleting nodes from a binary tree
when they have two children.
So when the to_delete node has two children,
we must do something a bit special.
Let me bring up my diagram once again.
We've looked at this before, just a quick recap.
Let's say we want to delete the node nine.
What we must do
is find the rightmost node in the left branch,
so eight, or, if you prefer,
the leftmost node in the right branch, 11.
Because we've coded a find_rightmost,
we're gonna stick to that.
We're gonna use eight, in this case,
but you can use 11 if you prefer,
so we're gonna find the rightmost node in the left branch.
We will also need its parent,
because the parent will have to point to the children.
Something that we know,
is that the rightmost node in this branch
has nothing to its right.
Hopefully that makes sense.
The rightmost node in this branch
doesn't have anything to its right,
because if it did, that would be the rightmost.
So when you go as far right as you can,
this node has either zero or one children,
not two.
So that is important because as part of deleting nine,
we are going to have to delete eight, essentially.
We're going to move eight up here,
which means that seven has to point down here
like that.
So essentially we have deleted eight,
and if eight had two children
this would get extremely complicated
because we'd be deleting a node of two children
by deleting another node of two children,
this is quite simple.
If 7.5 had other children, this would be fine,
'cause seven points to 7.5,
7.5's children stay there, so that's okay.
And of course, if eight has no children, then that's fine.
We don't have to worry about it, so no problem.
Let's start with this scenario,
the scenario where we want to delete, say nine,
and that has a node in this structure here.
So the first thing we have to do
is see whether the node we want to delete
is at the left or at the right of its parent.
So if to_delete
equal to_delete_parent.left, let's say,
I'm gonna delete this pass, by the way,
elif to_delete is equal to to_delete_parent.right,
and of course else,
what happens when they're the same,
when you wanna delete the root and it has two children.
Now, for all of these we're going to need
the rightmost node in the left branch,
so we're gonna say rightmost
equal self.find_rightmost
of to_delete.left,
and rightmost parent
is going to be self.find_parent
of the rightmost.value.
Once again, find_parent,
which is up here, takes in a value,
and sort of goes through the tree,
and tells us what the parent is
of the value we're looking for.
So here we've got the rightmost node in the left branch,
and we've also got the rightmost_parent of that node.
We know that it is a rightmost node
because that is a left branch.
To delete left, return true,
or it wasn't none,
so we know that this is not going to be none,
so therefore this is fine.
Accessing rightmost.value like that,
without checking or without catching any exceptions is okay,
because rightmost.value will return something.
We know that because we have two children.
Now, if we wanna delete something on the left,
what do we have to do?
Let's go back to the diagram.
Let's say we want to delete
Well, let's start with the right one.
Let's say we wanna delete nine.
So the first thing we have to do is find out eight,
which we've done that, we've done the rightmost node.
Then we have to say,
the rightmost node's right
now has to be equal to 12, right?
If eight is going to replace nine,
eight's right must be what used to be nine's right.
Let's start with that.
Rightmost.right has to be equal to to_delete.right,
so that means that the rightmost node here, eight,
is going to replace nine by pointing at 12.
The to_delete's parent now no longer has to point at nine.
It has to point at eight.
So to_delete's parent has to point to the rightmost node.
Let's do that.
To_delete_parent.right equal rightmost.
And by the way, I apologise profusely.
We said we were gonna do the right first, so that's there.
If you wanted to do the left, it would be exactly the same,
but this would be in the left.
So we found that the rightmost node's right
must point to what used to be the to_delete's right,
so eight is gonna point to 12.
To_delete_parent.right has to point to eight
because to_delete is equal to to_delete's right,
so we're deleting nine,
therefore the parent's right has to point somewhere else.
If we had another two-child node here on the left,
it would be this left,
that has to point somewhere else,
so that is what this is doing.
Hopefully that makes sense.
Finally, if we are deleting this one,
if we are deleting the head,
we're gonna find the rightmost node, again,
in the left subtree, which is gonna be five,
and what we have to do is say
the rightmost node right must be nine,
which is, again, this line here,
but now, to_delete_parent equals rightmost,
this is sort of correct,
but to_delete_parent is to_delete,
so it's the same node because they're both the head,
so what we'll do is self.head is rightmost.
So if we wanna delete this one,
the head must become the rightmost node.
That's the five, so the five would move up to here.
Hopefully this makes a little bit of sense.
There is, however,
one more thing that we have to think about.
Let's run, again, through our algorithm
for deleting the nodes.
Notice how we've not used the rightmost parent, by the way.
That's really the problem.
Let's imagine we're trying to delete nine.
So to_delete is the parent's right, so this is correct.
The first thing we're doing is
we're finding the rightmost node
and setting its right to be the to_delete.right,
so essentially moving this 12 down to the eight, like that.
This is correct: if we wanna move the eight up here,
that's what it has to do.
Then we're setting the parent to_delete_parent.right
to be the rightmost node,
and as you can see,
there is something that's a little bit off,
which is that we've deleted the nine,
but we've also deleted the seven,
'cause nothing's pointing to the seven.
So we have to fix this.
What we have to do is say,
eight left must point to seven.
Seven's right must point to eight's left.
So what we have to do is
rightmost_parent.right equals rightmost.left,
and then rightmost.left equal to_delete.left.
Now once again, we're gonna go through this algorithm.
We're gonna change the others in just a moment.
The first thing we're doing
is setting rightmost_parent's right, so that's this guy,
equal to rightmost's left
Oh sorry, rightmost_parent is this guy, seven.
Seven's right is gonna be, now, 7.5.
The rightmost.left is now gonna be to_delete's left,
so seven, so the eight
is now going to point to seven.
The rightmost's right
is going to point to to_delete's right,
and to_delete_parent's right
is going to point to the rightmost node.
Now, as you can see, this is a bit convoluted.
I'm just gonna move it in a moment.
It's gonna make sense.
Nothing is pointing to nine, so we can delete it.
These arrows we can delete.
We can move the eight up here.
Does that make sense?
I hope so.
So these four steps get us to this position.
Of course this one is here to the right.
I'm gonna undo these changes,
just because we have, still,
one more scenario to go through, unfortunately.
I'm sorry: you did not see that. (laughs)
This is for the next bit.
And we also need these bits of code here
in the other parts as well.
So this is needed in all occasions.
So
we have one more scenario.
Let me show it to you.
We have this scenario here.
So I'm gonna copy this, then I'm gonna do this,
then I'm gonna delete it, and I'm gonna paste it in here.
This is another scenario that we have to think about.
What I'm going to do is
I'm just going to modify it slightly.
I'm going to add another node here,
let's say 6.5,
that's going to be to the left of seven, of course.
So we have this scenario here.
Nine is the node we want to delete.
Seven is the rightmost node; it's got nothing to its right.
Nine is also the rightmost parent
because seven is the rightmost,
therefore the parent is nine.
Six is still to_delete_parent.
Let's try to delete nine using our little algorithm.
First, the rightmost_parent's right
is going to be the rightmost's left.
So this guy
is going to point to 6.5.
This is what we're doing here.
Rightmost_parent, nine, is the rightmost's left, 6.5.
Then we're saying rightmost.left is to_delete.left,
which this makes very little sense
because it is going to point to itself.
Rightmost.right is to_delete.right.
Okay, so finally something that makes a little bit of sense.
This is okay.
We wanna do that.
Finally, to_delete_parent's right is the rightmost.
Nothing points to nine.
We get rid of all of them,
but also we've accidentally deleted 6.5,
and seven points to itself, which is not ideal either.
We're gonna get into many infinite loops if we do that.
We don't wanna do that, so how do we do this?
Well, it's actually pretty simple.
The whole problem in this scenario is that
to_delete is equal to the rightmost_parent,
and then we're sort of setting some properties
that we have to move around
from to_delete and rightmost_parent, like say these,
that we just cannot do because they are the same thing.
When they are the same thing, the only thing we have to do
is get the rightmost's right node
and make it 12,
and get six and point it to seven.
This is all we have to do when they are the same.
Now, nothing points to nine,
and seven becomes the one we wanted.
So as you can see,
maybe that was a bit too fast,
all we have to do is rightmost.right,
which is seven's right equal to_delete.right,
and to_delete_parent's right is the rightmost.
So we only want to do these two lines.
That means we need these two for when they are not the same.
So if
rightmost_parent
is not equal to to_delete,
run these two lines.
If rightmost_parent is not equal to to_delete,
run those two lines,
and down here,
if rightmost_parent is not equal to to_delete,
run those two lines.
Notice how we've got our if statements here,
and these blocks of code are always the same
in all if statements, so we can just extract them.
We can just remove them from the if statements there
and move them up here.
Similarly, rightmost.right is to_delete.right,
this can also be extracted and put here,
and this now becomes a little bit simpler.
So once again, going back to our diagram,
I'm gonna just delete
or actually, let's not delete those clouds just yet.
Let's say, once again, we wanna delete nine,
so we've got our little algorithm.
We find the rightmost node, which is seven.
We find the rightmost_parent, which is nine.
Is the node we wanna delete equal to the rightmost_parent?
Yes, so we jump straight through this if statement
and into here.
The rightmost.right node,
this one down here which doesn't exist yet,
is going to be to_delete's right.
Now, is to_delete the parent's right
uh, left node?
Is it the parent's right?
Yes.
So we point that there.
That's all we need.
Now, let's go back to having something like an eight here.
Now, the rightmost node becomes the eight.
The rightmost_parent becomes the seven.
To_delete becomes nine, to_delete_parent is six.
So this is our other scenario,
and what we wanna do is, once again, we wanna delete nine,
find eight, find seven as rightmost's rightmost_parent.
Is rightmost_parent equal to to_delete?
No, so we go into this if statement.
Rightmost_parent.right
must equal to the rightmost's left,
and by the way,
we'll just add this 7.5 back here.
7.6, that's okay.
So the rightmost_parent's right
must equal the rightmost's left,
so it has to point to 7.6.
The rightmost's left must equal to_delete's left,
so this eight here must now point to seven.
The rightmost's right, this guy was the rightmost,
the right must point to to_delete's right, so down here.
And finally, because nine is at the right of the parent,
six must point on the right to the rightmost node,
which is eight.
Then we can delete nine, move it up here, and we got it.
We got exactly what we wanted.
Now, this is an extreme mind-boggling algorithm,
at least when you're starting,
and I would not expect you to sort of grasp it immediately,
and again, draw this out on paper.
Don't feel bad for drawing it out.
Everybody draws it out.
I have many drawings of this stuff,
and even with these diagrams
I can see that it's not so obvious to understand,
and especially when you have 100 lines of code
well, not 100, but 50 lines of code
to delete a node in a data structure,
you know that it's pretty complicated.
Hopefully this helps, though.
It can pop up in interviews.
It can pop up in coding challenges.
It's sort of a good thing to know in general
for when you're dealing with databases,
and data that you have to search through very quickly
and so forth,
and generally, just knowing about binary trees,
and that they exist,
and a little bit of a notion on how to use them,
is gonna make you a more well-rounded developer,
but I've never had to use them in my day-to-day job.
So understand it.
Know it's there.
Don't feel like
you have to remember this algorithm line-by-line,
'cause you don't have to,
and you can always come back to the course
and watch the video again if you need to.
So that's it for this video.
Hopefully this help, and I'll see on the next one.