Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to look
at something substantially more complicated.
So please stay with me, and let's look
at queuing in threads with shared state.
The first thing I'm going to do is, import a few things.
So I'm gonna import time and random,
as we know to do our phasing, and I'm going to import queue.
The queue module has a queue in it which is going
to be essential for our programme to work,
and I'm gonna explain exactly what this queue does
and why it's different from a deck.
And then, of course from threading,
we're gonna import thread to start with.
We'll then use a thread pool executor later.
We're gonna have our global counter,
and we're also gonna have two queues.
We're gonna have a job queue,
and we're gonna have a counter queue.
Okay.
Job queue
is going to be the comma, the things to be printed out,
the counter queue is amount by which to increase counter.
Okay.
Alright, now we are going to be doing something which is
every time we want to increase counter,
we're going to put one into the queue.
So, we're gonna put the number one into this queue.
Then we're gonna have some code looking through this
queue and whenever a number appears, it's going
to increase counter by that amount.
At the same time, we're gonna have another thread
going through this job queue and whenever it sees
something up here in there, it's gonna print it out.
That's essentially how this programme is gonna work.
So, let's do it.
We're gonna first define our increment manager.
We're just gonna take in our global counter.
Remember multiple threads could be doing this
at the same time, and then we're gonna do
while true
it's going to get the counter from this counter queue
and this counter queue here has a queue
of multiple numbers potentially
by which we want to increase the counter.
So increment is going to be counter queue.get.
Okay.
And this is important because this
waits until an item is available
and then locks the queue.
Okay, so, this is going to wait until an item is
available and when it is, it's not going to allow
any other threads to get anything until we are done.
Then we're gonna say old counter
is counter,
counter is now old counter plus
the increment.
Then, we are going to put something into the job queue
a new counter value is counter
and we're also going to put in our lines,
okay, we're gonna put in these two things
and finally counter queue.task done.
This unlocks the queue,
so now another thread could go
back and get something if they wanted.
So as soon as something comes in here,
this counter queue is now locked,
the thread has that resource,
no other thread can access this resource
until we call task done and that marks the queue as
not locked anymore, another thread can
then go through this get.
Okay.
Go.
We're gonna run this
target is gonna be the increment manager,
and daemon is gonna be true, and what this means is
this thread is going to run continuously
forever until we, until it finds an error essentially.
And then we're gonna start that, okay.
So this thread is gonna run forever always while true,
always checking this counter queue, trying to get a thing,
it's gonna wait until an item is available and it's gonna
lock it and then it's gonna go through it and it's gonna
call task done, then it's gonna repeat again,
it's gonna wait for something
to become available and so forth.
Now, if we want to print,
we're gonna create a printer manager.
So I scroll down here, again this is gonna be
while true, it's gonna get the lines in the job queue
for line in job queue.get
and again this locks the queue,
and waits for an item to be available,
it's gonna print the line out
and at the end it's gonna
be job queue.task done.
Okay.
Once again we are going to run this as a daemon thread.
Then, we're gonna start that.
Okay, so the printer manager and the increment manager
are gonna run continuously because of that daemon flag.
The final part of our programme is to deal with increasing
the counter itself,
so this is going to be running constantly,
getting values out of counter queue
and increasing the counter by them.
This is going to be running continuously
printing things out,
all we have to do is to put something
into our queue, so let's create another thread,
or another function that is going
to be our increment counter
and this is all is going to do is
do counter queue.put one, it's gonna put the number
one into the queue, then it's gonna get received
by this increment manager which is going to increment
the counter by that amount, and it's going to put
two things into the job queue which is then going
to print them out as it runs.
Okay.
Then, we're gonna make a few worker threads.
Worker threads these are gonna be threads
where the target is this increment counter
for thread in range 10, we're gonna make 10 of them,
and all we gonna do is start them.
So for thread in worker threads, thread start,
and we're gonna wait for them to finish for thread
in worker threads, thread.join
and at the end we're gonna wait
for the counter queue
to finish, to not have anything left in the queue
and the job queue to also not have anything left in it.
Notice how we are joining the queues, not the daemon
threads because this daemon threads are never gonna stop,
they're always gonna be running, okay.
So, we're joining on the queue.
When they become empty,
we will essentially be done.
As you can see this is substantially more complicated,
now that you have shared state, you have to start
having queues in there, so that your threads
cannot interrupt one another.
Let's run this code
and see what happens.
Oh, I think, oh yeah, sorry I forgot a pair of brackets.
What you put in the queue has to be
a double, my bad.
Let's run this again
and there you have it.
Now you get your code that looks sequential.
Okay.
Again you could just not use threads and it
would achieve the same purpose but if you wanted
to use threads you'd have to use these queues,
and indeed if you add the random weights,
which we will do,
you'll see that this still works, so we're gonna
add these weights everywhere
like there, we're gonna add some here,
we're gonna add some here,
and then we're gonna run it again.
And you can see that now we are waiting for our code
to sort of go through this queue
but only one thread is able
to go though this increment at once.
So, this still happen one by one.
So not terribly simple, let me tell you that.
Not terribly simple, again you could use a thread pool
executer to improve this code down here if you want,
we're not gonna get into that but the code indicator
does have this in there.
So again just to recap what happens is,
we say we're gonna access this global counter variable,
essentially just to tell Python that we don't want
to create a new variable called counter,
we wanna use the global counter.
In here, by the time we access the counter's value,
this has already prevented two threads from doing that
at the same time, so get waits until the item is available,
and then locks, so that only one thread can execute
this at a time and get a value out.
If you have 10 threads calling this,
only one is going to be able
to use that resource.
The other nine are going to wait until task done is called
and this becomes available again.
So you've got a single thread getting
the increment which is one, then you access
the current counter's value which will be zero,
then you'll increase it by the increment which is one,
make it one and put these two things here
into the job queue,
then task done so you go back to the top
and another thread is able to do the get.
When they access the counter value, that's one now,
because the previous state already incremented it.
And then you can increase it again and so forth.
So essentially what you doing here, is you are creating
this bottle neck for threads to only be able to access
a resource at one at a time, okay.
Again, this is essentially single threaded code,
but it goes to show that when you need threads
to share a state, you need these queues.
Think of the printer in your office,
if you have one, the printer in your office
can receive jobs from a lot of different people at once,
but it can only print one at a time.
So that's what we've got here, we've got a queue
of print jobs and the printer is then just continuously
printing them out as soon as it sees them but it doesn't
do them all at the same time, it does them one by one.
Similarly because we're accessing a unique resource
the counter we also must do that one by one, if we get
two things incremented by the counter at once,
we saw that happens in the last video, they just sort
of go mental and with this start changing at the same time.
If you got your printer to print two things at once,
you can imagine how that wouldn't go so well either,
it sees sort of words from one document
and words from another all printed out together,
it wouldn't be pretty.
When you want a shared resource, you must use a queue,
and the queue.Queue package here the queue package is
good because is has this locking thing and this
task done thing, so this is made
for multi threaded access to a queue.
The deck which is something that is atomic,
does not get interrupted when you add or remove elements
from it, but it also does not lock, so you can have multiple
things, appending things to a deck at the same time,
and that can be handy in other situations as
you'll see from the talks that are linked
to you later on.
That's it for this video,
hopefully this didn't melt you brains
and I'll see you on the next one.