Hi and welcome back.
Let's talk about regular expressions.
First thing, and most important thing, is that when we write
regular expressions we are writing with a language.
Now, regular expressions are not a programming language,
but there is still some syntax and some keywords
that we have to know when we use regular expressions.
And we use the syntax and the keywords
to express what we want.
So let's look at some examples of regular expressions
so we know, sort of, what it is.
Here's some text.
And, as you can see in this text, there are some patterns.
You can broadly spot this pattern, I think it's a
reasonably straightforward pattern,
you can see an a, followed by a number, followed by a space,
and that sort of repeats five times.
You've got a, number, space, a, number, space,
a, number, space, a, number, space, a, number.
Notice how there's no space at the end,
so that's an interesting one.
The other pattern that is there, is this one:
a1 space, a3 space, a9 space, a5 space, a4.
So that's the entire string.
So, in regular expressions, we can
use the language to
define the patterns that we're looking for.
So here we could define, let's look for a pattern which is
an a followed by a number followed by a space.
And the regular expression runners would then give us,
"Hey, we've found some instances of this pattern
in this text".
Okay.
Let's look at another example we're gonna look,
just a couple examples of patterns so that
you know, sort of a bit of what we're looking for.
Here's another pattern.
We've got Jose comma space, Rolf comma space,
Charlie comma space, Adam.
So what I see here are some characters, like letters,
followed by a comma, followed by a space. Okay?
This is a pattern, potentially.
Of course the other pattern is the entire string again,
but that's gonna be a case for every instance.
Let's look at this one. Here's some URLs,
some addresses of the internet.
And what I see are one of two things.
The first one, I see a bunch of characters, followed by
a newline character, remember the backslash n,
that we've looked at before.
So here the characters include letters, they include
the dot, the colon, the forward slashes.
You've got a bunch of characters there, and you've got
a newline at the end.
So that's one of the patterns I see in here.
The other pattern where you analyse each line,
you can see that every line is fairly similar
with the line below.
You have http at the start. All of these patterns,
all of these lines have http at the start.
Sometimes https is followed by an s.
In three of the cases you've got http, followed by an s.
And in all cases that is then followed by colon,
forward slash, forward slash.
Sometimes that is followed by www.
And that is followed by some characters, like google,
facebook, twitter, udemy, tecladocode.
And finally, this is always followed by dot com.
So as you can see, this isn't
a definition of all URLs, because some URLs as you know
end in dot net, or dot me, or in dot it, or whatever.
This is just at the finish of the patterns that we can see
in the text that we're analysing.
So, http is always there, sometimes you've got an s.
Following either of those, you've got the colon,
forward slash, forward slash. Sometimes you've got www,
in other cases you just have the characters,
and you always have dot com.
Here's one final example. You've got some emails.
So what I see here is a combination
of letters, numbers, periods, and underscores,
which you can see for example,
"Jose" is a combination of letters, "rolf" is
a combination of letters, "char.lie" is a combination of
letters and periods, "Anna" is a combination of letters,
"jen45" is a combination of letters and numbers,
and "someone_is_awesome" is a combination
of letters and underscores.
So you've got this combination of
potentially different characters, and that's always followed
by an @ symbol.
As you can see, in all cases, no matter the combination,
you end up having an @ symbol.
And that's always followed by some characters,
and it seems that those characters are always letters.
You've got tecladocode, you've got google, twitter, gmail,
icloud, and example.
Those are followed by a dot, a period.
You've got tecladocode and then you've got dot,
google and then you've got dot, twitter then you've got dot,
and so forth.
And finally you have some characters.
And it seems from this example that these characters are
always gonna be either com, me, or net.
And then you end up with dot com, dot me, or dot net.
But of course we can be fairly smart and we can say
you know, it's possible that if what we're looking at
are emails, the characters at the end
may be slightly different, in some cases.
We're not seeing them here, but you know, it could be,
could be different.
Let's not say that it can only be com, me and net.
Maybe lets say that they can be any character.
So, getting regex, regular expressions,
is a matter of seeing the patterns,
being able to identify the patterns,
being able to look at a text and say, "Okay, these are
the potential characters and symbols that I can see,
this is the order they're gonna appear them"
and of course, you have to be able to express those patterns
using the language.
So that's what we're gonna be learning in the next video.
But I'll tell you there are four most important components
in regex.
You're going to be using these essentially all the time.
First one is the dot. The dot means "anything".
Letters, number, symbols, anything you can think of
except newlines.
Remember the newline character, back slash n,
the dot means "anything" except that.
The plus symbols means "one or more of".
The asterisk means "zero or more of",
and the question mark means "zero or one of".
So, let's analyse one expression using these
pieces of syntax.
Jose@tecladocode.com.
You could say this is dot star. The dot means "anything",
the start means "zero or more of".
So that's "zero or more of anything".
Naturally, pretty much any pattern is going to match that,
because you've got zero or more of anything,
that can be any character or symbol or anything else,
so of course this pattern is going to match that.
You've got dot plus, the plus means "one or more of".
So here you've got a dot, you have at least one character
in the pattern, so it is going to match.
You could also have something like "jose@tecladocode\.com".
So here you're matching the entire pattern,
but of course you have to put a backslash in front of any
symbol that means something in regular expressions,
otherwise it means "anything".
Like we know the dot in a regular expression pattern means
"anything", so you have to put a backslash in front of it
so it means the dot, and not just any symbol.
This is a bit abstract, so let's go to a better regex editor
and we're going to look at a bunch of examples in the next
video, so that you sort of start getting a bit more
of an idea of how these regular expressions work.
So with that said, I'll see you on the next video.