Python and welcome bacK.
In this video we're looking at importing our own files.
Importing just means ,
allowing a file we're currently working on
to use code defined in some other file.
And we've done this with the JSON module in the last video.
And that just meant we're getting the code in that module,
available for us to use.
Now it's time to import code that we ourselves have written,
that way we will be able to split our programmes
into multiple files,
and that's of course is going to help,
because our programme will have better organisation,
and when it comes to changing it,
and improving it's going to be a bit easier.
Let's start by creating a new file,
inside our Programme project
after the new Python project here.
And I'm going to call it, file operations,
so that's file_operations
run but don't put any spaces in file names,
that's a recipe for disaster in pretty much any computer,
but especially when working with Python.
Now inside this file,
we're gonna write a couple of functions.
One, to save Some content we file,
and the other one to read some content from a file.
So save to file,
the content we wanna write is gonna be a first parameter,
and the file name is gonna be the second parameter,
and all is gonna do,
is use a context manager to open the file
and then write the content.
And then read file is going to be pretty similar
it's gonna take the file name,
and it's going to use a context manager to open the file,
and read the contents out fully as a single string,
and return them.
Now I think you can implement this
knowing what you know already,
and if you have to look at the code for the section
make sure to not look at the import project,
and which is also available on GitHub,
but look at the other files we've already written,
and then implement these functions using,
what you already know.
Don't copy and paste code, just type it out.
And once you've done that come back to the video,
and we shall continue.
I hope you managed,
all we have to do is use a context manager to open
the file name in write mode,
and then what we're going to do
is a file.write content.
Am sorry, of course you need as file in there.
In order to have a variable.
This is optional by the way,
but then you don't have anything pointing to
whatever you've opened,
and then you cannot write to it
if you don't have a variable write points to open.
Then of course for the reading,
we're gonna do open,
or file name but this time in reading mode.
And what we gonna do is return file.read.
Notice how this is not going to give us,
the lines or anything like that,
but this is going to be one long string ,
that could contain things like this.
See, now if we wanted lines after it,
we can split on the backslash,
and .split on backslash,
and it's going to give us something like this Rolf, Charlie,
and so forth.
So this is going to give us one long string,
we can then split it into a lines if we want.
If your file is extremely long,
you may have some problems
with reading the entire file at once.
But let's forget about this problem for now.
Look at some relatively simple stuff,
writing to a file and reading from it,
We've already done this.
But it's going to be useful as an example
to look into importing,
and in deed,
this is essentially our first library.
This library, we're going to import these two files,
these two functions,
and we're going to now very easily save things to a file,
and read them from a file,
without having to worry about opening them.
Let's create a new file in our imports project
called app.py.
And now we're going to import,
the things from file operations.
There are two ways that we can do that.
First one is we can import file operations.
And then we can do file_operations.save_to_file
whatever you want to say Rolf,
and data.txt, for example.
We can do this, call the fiLe operations module.
Whenever you import something, by the way,
the thing you're importing is now called a module.
And it is executed in module mode,
which is essentially the same as executing it
in normal mode, or script mode
but there are some minor differences
that we're gonna look at in a moment.
So whenever you import something ,that's a module,
Whenever you're running something like
if you run app.py
that's called a script.
Okay, normally you're have one script
that's app py ,
and a bunch of modules,
and that's everything else that you import.
File operations is the module,
and then we're accessing inside of it with a dot,
then save to file function.
And to which we gave the two arguments that it needs,
the content that we wanna save,
and the file name.
So let's right click app.py and run it.
Notice how nothing happens,
but data.txt does get created,
and Rolf is in it.
This file has been closed as well,
because the save to file function in file operations
has this context manager,
which closes the file at the end.
So this is pretty cool.
I mean, in a single line now,
because we've got our library here,
we are opening, saving and closing the file
without having to worry about doing that manually.
The other option,
I said there were two options for importing,
is to do from file operations import save to file,
and then the save to file is what becomes
the globally available thing in this script,
and you can just run back,
save to file directly.
Of course, this is not so good
if you're importing from many places,
and two things have the same name.
It can happen,
then of course Python will be very confused,
and you would only ever be able to use
the one you import last.
So if you have things with multiple,
multiple things with the same name,
use the former import file operations,
if you only have a couple of things
that you wanna import and use,
feel free to import them like this.
But at the end of the day it's up to you,
whatever you feel is more readable.
Now, we can also have a comma after it,
and import write to file or read file, sorry,
save to file is write to file same thing read file,
and then we can print the read file of data.txt.
Let's run that again,
and now we get Rolf printed out down here at the bottom,
because we've saved Rolf to data.txt,
and then we've read it and print it out,
notice when the file is opened and then closed,
and opened and then closed in every function.
Now in a larger application,
we would start separating our files into folders ,
so that things are more organised,
and it's easier to find what we need.
If all your Python files potentially many 100s of them
would be in the same import project folder,
you would have a lot of trouble
finding the things you want,
and it would get very messy very quickly.
So instead, you normally would create a new directory,
and I'm gonna call it something like utils for utilities,
file operations is gonna be part of such utilities.
Let's drag file operations into utils,
and if you get asked to search for references,
make sure to not check it,
for that is going to completely moot the point
that I'm about to show you.
So don't search for references and press okay.
Now we see a couple of things.
File operations has moved into utils,
and red lines have appeared everywhere.
Of course, this is now an unresolved reference,
it doesn't know what final operations is,
because it's no longer in the same directory as app.py.
In fact, I'll even go as far as saying
it's not in the same directory imports project
which is the top level directory of our project.
So you can only do this
from file operations import something,
if file operations is a module available
on the top level of your project.
Okay?
Because now it's inside details,
we cannot do this,
so what can we do?
Well, we can run the file first of all,
to see that we get a module not found error,
just wanted to show you that this is what you get,
if you import something that doesn't exist.
And we must do two things.
We must first of all,
give Python the full path to import,
starting from the top level folder,
so the full path is utils,
and inside utils we've got file operations.
So utils,
and inside utils and we say dot,
we've got file operations.
There we have it.
Now we've got utils,
inside file operations,
we can import these two things.
Now it works.
Frequently though,
is a good idea to tell Python that the utils package,
the utils directory here is actually a Python package,
and I'm not sure if,
actually not sure if this has changed recently in Python,
but it's used to be that you would have to tell python,
this is a Python package.
Before you could import things from it,
and maybe it's no longer required but nonetheless,
for compliance with previous Python versions
it's always a good idea to tell Python that this folder,
this directory is a Python package,
and it's a folder where Python files live,
and where you want to import.
The way to do that is to right click it,
and create a new Python file,
and it must be called __init__.py
that's two underscore at the start,
two underscores at the end.py.
You can close on file
for we do not need to write anything in it,
but this is just what you should do,
for compliance with older Python versions.
You're Okay?
So now this directory here is called a package,
so that Python knows that it can import things from there,
at least in older versions, okay?
And this is how you gave the full path to Python,
so that it knows where to look for your files.
So that's it for this video,
we've looked at importing our own files,
We're gonna look at relative imports in the very next video,
now see you there.