Hi, guys, and welcome back.
In this video we're going to start checking for changes.
What that means is when we know
whether a file has been changed
we will be able to then tell the user that
they're about to quit without saving their changes.
So, it's important that our text editor
has this functionality just in case
they close it by accident.
How we're going to do is we're going to keep track
of the contents of each text field.
And when the contents change,
then we will mark that specific text field as modified.
Okay, so how we're gonna do that specifically
is we're going to define a variable called text contents
and it's going to be a dictionary,
and then what we're going to do is when we create a file
we're gonna say text contents of the text area
that we've just created is going to be
equal to a hash of empty string,
so this may look like a little bit of magic,
but here's what's happening.
We're going to have an empty
dictionary called text contents.
When we create a new file
we're going to start populating this dictionary
and we will say that an entry for this specific
text area has a content of empty string.
Now, we're not going to put
the actual content in the dictionary.
We're going to put a hash of the content.
Hashing is essentially turning a piece of data
of arbitrary length into a piece of data of specific length.
So, no matter how long the contents of a file are,
when we hash them they will become a certain length.
That's so that if we have very long files
we don't have them all inside a dictionary.
We only have a hash of the contents.
If the file contents change, the hash will change,
so this is just as good for keeping track
of whether something's changed or not.
So, whenever we create an empty file or a new file,
that is going to have a hash of empty string.
Now, instead of empty string, which is the content,
we can just put content in here
in case we're using this for opening a file.
Next up, we do want to make sure that when
we save a file this text contents gets updated.
So, in save file down here we will say
text contents of the current widget
is equal to a hash of the current content.
Now, str of text widget actually
gives you the name of the widget,
and you can have a look at it when
you, for example, create a file.
I'll just print str of text area,
and you'll see what it does.
It prints out a tcl name of .!frame.!notebook.!text.
This is just their specific notation.
Every time you create a new one
it will have a different name down there,
and you can see that it's text2 when I've created a new one.
I know that you couldn't see me create a new one,
but nonetheless, I did.
All right, next up what we want to do is go ahead
and implement something that will check for changes.
So, we're going to create a new function down here,
and I'm gonna call it check_for_changes,
and all this function is going to do is
it is going to get the currently selected text widget.
So, it will do current equal,
and you can remember that we've got
the currently selected text widget here
when we did root.nametowidget.
So, what I'm also gonna do is I'm gonna
extract that into a function,
so we'll do get_text_widget,
and it will just return this.
So, it'll do that and then return text widget.
Then in here we can use that instead.
And here we can also use it.
All right, so back to our original function.
Check for changes gets the currently open text widget.
Why does it get the currently open text widget?
Well, because whenever you're typing
we're going to be checking for changes,
and you can only be typing in the currently selected widget,
so it makes sense to only check
for changes in the current widget,
as you cannot possibly have made changes to another widget.
Then we'll get the content, which is current.get
from 1.0 to end minus one c,
and then we will get the name of the current tab,
which is notebook.tab, current, text.
Next up, if the hash of the content is different
from what we've got already in our dictionary,
that means that it has changed.
So, we will say if the hash of content
is different from text contents, str current,
then we want to append a asterisk
to the end of the file name just to tell
the user that this is currently unsaved,
so we'll say if the name minus 1 is not equal to asterisk,
we will say notebook tab, current,
text equal name plus asterisk.
All right, so what this is doing is
if the file is currently unsaved
and if the name doesn't currently
have an asterisk at the end,
then we're gonna put an asterisk at the end,
and that is quite normal is text editors
and this signifies that the file is unsaved.
Finally, if the name minus one is equal to asterisk,
then we're going to remove it.
That is because if this did not happen,
that means that the file is not modified.
So, what we want to do if the file has not been modified,
but the last character is the asterisk,
we want to remove that last character
because it in no longer necessary.
The last character being an asterisk
means the file is unsaved,
but because this did not run
it means the file is not unsaved.
So, we'll say notebook.tab, current,
text equal name, except the last character.
All right, so I know this is a little bit confusing.
This is probably the most confusing code
that we will write in this section,
but it is to do with adding or removing
the asterisk from the file name
depending on whether it is unsaved or not.
The last thing we have to do is
to make sure that we call this function,
so we will go down here to our root binds,
and we're gonna do root.bind,
and now it is KeyPress, with the K and the P uppercase,
and the event is check_for_changes, like that.
Let's run it, and I'll bring it down here
and you can see that as soon as
I start typing the asterisk appears,
and if I remove the H the asterisk disappears
because it realises that the contents right now
are the same as the contents
that it's got in the dictionary.
Now, if I type in "H" and then I save it,
I'll do test2.txt, then notice that the asterisk disappears,
but if I type an "e" now, the asterisk comes back,
and if I remove the e the asterisk disappears
because the contents currently
in the dictionary is when it was last saved,
as we did here when we did the save file
we replaced the text contents of our widget
with the new contents that we've just saved.
So, this is how you can signal a user whether
some of their files are saved or pending saving
so that they don't close this by accident
without saving all their files.
However, even if you have an unsaved file
you can still close this and it will go away
without telling you that you have unsaved changes.
So, that's what we're gonna do in the next video.
I'll see you there.