Hi and welcome back.
In this video we're going to be creating our quotes page
and I think everything's gonna make sense,
and it's gonna click, once we finish creating this
and we write a couple of lines of code in our app .py.
What I'm going to do in the quote pages
is import BeautifulSoup.
Notice how I didn't do that in the quotes page,
because we didn't need to.
Then I am going to import our quote page locator,
and also I'm going to import our quote parser.
Then, creating a quotes page,
we're going to define an innate method,
and this one is going to take in the page content,
so that's the entire html of the entire page.
And we're going to load that using requests, in a moment.
Now this, already we know and love.
We've done this in the past.
We're gonna say self.soup is BeautifulSoup of page,
I'm giving it an html parser.
Then, we're going to define a property in here,
which is the quotes,
and what this is going to do is,
it's going to grab the locator,
which is the QuotesPageLocators.QUOTE,
then it's going to...
Quote_tags...
It's going to find all of them,
so it's gonna do self.soup.select with that locator,
and finally what it's going to do is,
it's going to return a quote parser
for each element in quote tags.
OK, so hopefully this starts to make
a little bit more sense.
What we do is we find each of the divs
that we're looking for,
and each of the divs,
we pass each one to a quote parser object.
That quote parser can then use that pairing
to find children inside it,
so it here is doing self.parent, which is the div,
dot select one of the content locators.
So it's going to find the content locator
within this parent and not within any other parent.
Similarly for the author, and similarly for the tags.
So now this page has this quotes property,
and what it returns are a group of objects
of type quote parser, from which we can access
the name of the author, the content of the quote,
and the tags.
So if we go to our app .py now,
you'll see that this starts to make a bit more sense.
I'm gonna import requests,
and from the quotes page I'm gonna import the quotes page...
QuotesPage, that one!
Now the first thing to do of course,
is to get the page content,
which we must do using requests.
So request.get, http://quotes.toscrape.com.content.
This is going to get the page
and this is going to give me the content of the page.
Now, this entire content, everything we've loaded,
we give it to our quotes page object.
This now gets parsed using BeautifulSoup,
because the constructor here, the init method,
does that.
It gets the BeautifulSoup, and parses the entire page.
Going back to app .py,
we can then do for_quote in page.quotes, print, quote.
When we print quote, that's gonna,
well first of all page.quotes is going to give us
quote parser objects,
and each quote parser object has a repr method
that is going to get called when we print it out.
So when we print, it's going to go through each quote
in the quotes and list we got back,
and it's going to print it out.
Let's right click .py, and run it,
and there you have it.
We get our quote objects like that.
If you wanted to just print the name,
sorry, dot content,
not the name, the content of the quote,
you could do that,
and then you just get the content of the quote here.
Hopefully this makes a little bit more sense.
Let's go over it again in the very next video.
I'll see you there.