Hi welcome back.
In this video we're taking about properties.
Remember how we mentioned that
the values defined here in the constructor
in the init method, these are called properties
because the object has this value now defined inside of it.
Name, school, marks and salary.
Indeed when we create an object,
then we can print rolf.salary.
And what this tells us is that we're accessing
a value inside the object.
As soon as we want to access a function
we have to call the function
by including the brackets at the end.
And this is all good,
but for example, let's think of the
weekly salary, let's delete that.
I think of the weekly salary of rolf.
We've learned in the past that functions
and therefore methods, since they are
just function inside a class
are pieces of code that do something, perform an action.
However the weekly salary method
doesn't perform and actions, it just calculates a value.
So it would be quite nice if we could have
weekly salary like so.
Rolf the weekly salary, it's not a function anymore.
Now it's just a property of the object
because there's no action to do.
It's not like we're telling rolf to, you know,
go to work or do something.
We're just getting a value from the object.
And you can only do this when the function
doesn't take any arguments other than self, okay.
If the function only takes a self argument
and the function isn't one that does things
but rather just calculates a value
based on self's properties,
I think this starts to make sense to do it this way,
because now you're accessing the weekly salary
and you know, you don't care if that's calculated.
And you don't care if that's just static.
You know, that this weekly salary is rolf's weekly salary.
And if that changes because you increase the salary
that's fine, you know.
You don't necessarily care about that,
you just care that you getting the right value out.
So obviously if we do this it's not going to work
because Python is going to expect
the opening and closing bracket.
Let's run it and I will show you.
See now what we get is a bound method
WorkingStudent.weekly_salary of WorkingStudent object.
What this is telling us
is what we've printed out is this method.
We've printed out the definition of this method.
Inside it we've got, you know, the memory address
of the object and so on.
If we want to do this
we have to use what's called the delarator.
And this is a very popular declarator called @property.
The @property declarator turns this method
into something that can be used like so.
Now we get 581.25, and remember
we've not added the brackets.
So this a decalarator,
we're going to look at declarators
later on in the course, not just now.
I just wanted to introduce this one declarator here,
because it's a nice way of, you know,
adding some advanced Python things
as we go along the course.
This is not something terribly complex
although understanding the way declarators work
is more complex, we don't need to do that just now.
We're gonna look at that later on.
And I want you to start getting more advanced.
This is how you can change a simple
no argument method into a property,
or something that can be accessed
as if it were are property.
And that's great because now we know
that no action is going to arise
as a result of using this property.
We just know that this is a value that we're getting out.
Again I stress this important.
If you are doing an action, like connecting to a database,
or opening file, or, you know,
communicating with some sort of web service,
or you are interacting with another object,
or anything, any action,
please do not use the @property declarator.
Use it only when you're calculating values
from the object's properties themselves.
Alright that's it for this video,
and I'll see you on the next one.