Hi, and welcome back.
In this video, I just wanted to go over the quiz
you've just done, at least, I hope you've tackled it,
and guide you through some of the answers,
and then also give you the code that I would use
to avoid the problems that Ben and Dan had in this quiz.
I'm just doing this for this quiz because it's a tricky one,
but it's interesting, and it's a problem
that you'll see happen over and over again.
So, let's start the quiz.
We've got a quick question to warm us up, first of all,
and we get some background.
Now, for this quiz, if you haven't done it yet,
I'd encourage you to sort of take it seriously.
Think as though you were one of these two developers
and how you would implement this bit of code.
So Ben and Dan are two novice software developers,
and they are trying to build a function that asks the user
for a number and calculate its power of two.
And here's the first version of their code.
So we've got a function called power_of_two,
and the first thing it does is it asks the user
for a number, multiplies it, well, powers it by two,
squares it, rather, that then returns n_square.
So, what do we think?
Will this work?
My immediate thinking for this is, you know,
input gives you a string,
so this is not gonna work, because a string
to the power of two is gonna break,
so I'm gonna say the programme will break in all cases,
and that's the correct thinking.
Of course, for me, it's a bit easier,
'cause I've actually made the quiz,
so I sort of know the answers.
But I would expect you to be aware of the input function
returning a string in all cases at this point.
The second question starts getting a little bit trickier.
So they realise their error, and they have a second version
where now they are putting the user input
into a variable called user_input,
and then they're turning that into a float.
So that's a decimal point number.
Then they're gonna square that float and return it.
And it's pretty common for people to do something like this,
even professional software engineers.
You've got your input.
You're asking the user to enter a number,
so of course, they're gonna enter a number,
and you're gonna turn that into a Python float,
and then you're gonna square that,
and it's all gonna be fine.
But the users don't always play nice.
Sometimes, you know, you'll ask them to enter a number,
and they'll by accident, like, type out the number "ten,"
or maybe they'll type something else by mistake entirely,
or they won't understand what you want them to do.
So now there are three options:
it will work in all cases, and a lot of people will say,
you know, yes, it'll work in all cases,
because the assumption is the user is gonna enter a number.
But that assumption is flawed, because the user may not.
So it's yes and no, the programme will work
on some inputs but break on other inputs.
And that's correct.
Then we've got version three,
and this code starts getting a little bit trickier.
So after shipping their version two code,
Ben and Dan had some serious complaints.
This is a frequent thing.
You will get complaints if your code is broken,
if you have users using your code, of course.
So now, it becomes a little bit more contrived.
Now we're getting the user input put into a variable,
and then we're initialising a try except finally block.
Inside the try, we're trying to put the user input
into a float and inside the variable n.
Remember, n is defined inside the try block,
so it doesn't exist anywhere else.
If that fails with a value error,
which means the user entered a string,
we print your input was invalid,
and finally, at the end, we square n and return that.
But of course n was defined in the try block.
It's possible that if that failed with a value error,
we don't have n, so n_square will be error,
because n is not defined.
So in this case, they are trying out the code
with two different inputs.
This is good.
You should try out your code with multiple inputs.
In the first case, he's gonna enter four,
and in the second case, he's gonna enter the string dan.
So, for four it's gonna work, because the float of four
is gonna give you something.
Then you're gonna go and jump down here, but for dan,
you're gonna get a value error, which means you're gonna try
to multiply something that doesn't exist.
So you're gonna get 16.0 and error as the solution.
Now, for this version,
we've got something a little bit different.
Fairly similar in many regards.
We've got the user input as a string.
Then we try to convert it into a float
and put it into the variable n,
and then if an error happens, we print out
the input was invalid, and we say n is zero.
So what is going to happen in this case?
Well, the else block, now this has been replaced,
replacing the finally block,
the else block only runs if there was no error.
We've seen that just recently in the last video.
So, if we run through the try block successfully,
we will then multiply our square and return that.
If we get an error, we're gonna jump into the except block.
N is gonna be zero, but we're not going to run
the else block, and we're not going to return the square.
So we're gonna return none by default.
In this case, the answer is 16.0 and none,
because the first test case will return 16.0.
The second one will return none, because the function
doesn't return anything if it doesn't succeed in the try.
So that's the correct answer there.
Then we've got a slightly more complicated version,
and, you know, you may now be able to see
how to fix this code, and you may be thinking,
this code is now way too complicated.
Why would anybody write this code?
And you're right.
If you know how to solve the problem
and you're coming at it with a pair of fresh eyes,
you may never write something that looks like this.
But if you have made a mistake and then another one
and then another one and suddenly there's a pressure
for you to do it right, there's a pressure for users
to be happy, there's a pressure for you to give this code
to your users quickly, mistakes start to happen,
and you start getting a narrow focus on the problem,
and what you start thinking is, you know,
what do we add quickly to fix the problem,
and you stop thinking about, how do we restructure this code
so that it solves the problem
without any cruft or any useless code?
So in this case, we're getting user_input
is the input of the user.
Then we try to turn it into a float.
If we fail to do that, we print out
that your input was invalid, and we assign n to zero.
If we succeed in getting n, we type out n_square is n
to the power of two, and then we finally return n_square.
Of course, same problem as before.
When we type four, the try succeeds, so we get n,
and then we jump straight to the else,
and we get n_square is 16.0, and then we return it.
But, when we get dan, we don't get a value for n.
We instead jump to the except.
We get n equal to zero.
We don't run the else, because the else only runs
if we succeed in the try.
We jump to finally, where we return n_square,
but n_square was defined here, so we get an error.
The answer here will be 16.0 and error.
Now, it gets a bit more complicated.
We've got the user_input as the user's, what the user types.
Then n is a float of user_input.
If we fail to get the user_input, we return zero,
and finally, at the very end, we get n_square
is n to the power of two, and then we return n_square.
So, this is a tricky question.
It's a trick question, in fact, because you see
the returned zero here, and you think, hey, you know,
we are gonna return zero in the except, right?
But that's not really what happens.
So, what we're gonna see is we're gonna run through the try
with the input four, and that's gonna give us 16.0.
Then we're gonna jump right to the finally,
sorry, four, and then we're gonna do
four to the power of two is gonna give us 16.0.
We're gonna return 16.0.
All is good.
So for now, we've got one of these things.
The first return is gonna be 16.0.
But the second one with dan, what you may think
is, you know, float of dan is gonna give you an error.
So you're gonna jump right into the accept,
and you're gonna return zero.
So a pretty reasonable thing to think
would be the C would be the answer, 16.0 and zero.
Notice how it can never be 16.0 and 0.0,
because here, we're returning zero, not 0.0.
But actually what happens
is a pretty interesting thing in Python.
If you return inside an except, and then you return
inside the finally, the finally takes precedence.
So this will return.
So what you're gonna get instead is 16.0 and error,
because n_square does not exist.
So the finally is always going to run
if you have a return in it.
If you don't have a return in the finally,
the code would work, but it wouldn't return 16.0 at first.
It would return none.
But, this return 0 would work.
You would not try to run this line,
which is a bit of a bizarre thing.
Just something to remember:
if you have a return in the finally, the finally
will always run, no matter what you do in the except.
Okay?
So the answer would be 16.0 and error.
And that's that.
And it says here, the finally block will get executed
regardless of the return statement
in both the try block and an except block.
Okay.
So, there you have it.
And you have the results, and you will be able to see
a couple of lectures that you can check out
if you did get any wrong in there.
Now, if we go over back to PyCharm,
we'll see that we've got here their latest answer.
Power_of_two asks the user for an input,
and then we try to turn it into a float.
And we can try this out indeed with the inputs
that they typed.
So we can do power_of_two and then power_of_two again.
We can run this app and see what happens.
We're gonna enter four at first,
and of course we're not printing anything,
so we're gonna stop this and make it print.
There.
Let's run this again.
First thing, we're gonna enter four.
We get 16.0.
Then we're gonna enter dan, and notice how it doesn't
quite work, because the finally there is being executed.
This thing here is saying n_square is n to the power of two,
which means we did not exit
the function in this return, okay.
Now, the way to implement something like this
is if possible, and really, the way you wanna do
try, except, and finally is everything you want to try,
put it in the try.
So in this case, what we wanna try
is to deal with user input.
So, what you would want to do is you would want to put
this in here and get rid of the finally entirely,
because the finally is used
to do something at the closing of a block.
And here, we don't really have a closing of a block.
We've got things we want to try,
and if we don't succeed to get user_input
or we don't succeed to multiply it, to square it,
then we don't want to do anything.
Potentially, we want to return zero.
So that may be what you want to do in your function.
And so this would now work.
If you enter four, you get 16.0.
If you enter dan, you get your input was invalid.
Using default value 0, and you get zero, okay?
So, again, the thing to take away from this is,
there's two things, in fact.
The first one, it's really easy to have, become close-minded
when you're dealing with a problem for a long time
and sort of lose sight of the big picture.
It's a common thing to do.
What you can do is you can go grab a cup of coffee
or go for a nap and then come back to it
and it'll be simpler, or of course you can
ask a question in the course Q&amp;A.
We very frequently find student questions that are,
you know, things that you can spot after you've
not looked at something for a few hours, for example,
like a comma there or something like that.
If you put a comma at the end of here
and you've been working on this for many hours,
you know, it may not even cross your mind
that this can cause a problem.
So if you've been working on something for a long time,
sometimes that can cause narrow focus,
and it can cause that you don't see the big picture,
and you start just thinking about,
what is the one line of code I can add to make this work,
and you stop thinking of, how do I think of the problem
in a different way entirely so that the solution is simpler.
And the second thing to take away from it is,
put everything you wanna try in the try block.
Everything that depends on one another,
just put them in the same block,
because that's gonna make your life much simpler.
And then, any problem that can result from this code
will be, will be caught by this value error here.
And if necessary, if there are multiple problems
that can result out of tying this, as you know,
you can just chain errors here,
like RuntimeError or something.
You can chain these here
so that the error gets caught no matter what.
In the unlikely event that you want to use
a finally or an else block, just remember,
the else block only runs when you succeed,
and the finally should be used to close down something.
So, don't use them indiscriminately, because that's
gonna bring you problems like it did for Dan and Ben.
That's it for this video.
Hope you've enjoyed it, and I'll see you in the next one.