Hi, welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be constructing
our first task scheduler using generators
instead of threads.
Previously, we created a bunch of threads
and we started them,
and there was a task scheduler in the background,
the operating system,
bringing in threads to a core
and removing them from the core.
Now we're gonna do the same thing,
but using a generator instead.
By the way, the code I'm about to show you here
is partially taken from another talk by David Beasley,
which is a fantastic guy.
I'm gonna link you to couple of his talks afterwords.
But I wanted to show you again, in my own words,
how to do this just to help you understand.
So threads are not performing so well in Python,
with the communication overhead and the GIL issues,
but using generators is another way of achieving
multitasking and doing multiple things at once in Python.
But again, remember multitasking is doing things
that look like they are happening at the same time,
but they are really not.
Parallelism is about doing things actually at the same time,
and in Python we cannot do parallelism
because of the GIL unless we launch multiple processes.
So here we've got our countdown,
and what we're gonna do
is we're going to create a set of tasks.
So here we've created three tasks that are all similar,
they're all this generator.
A countdown from ten, a countdown from five,
and a countdown from 20.
But now, we can start providing them slices,
instead of on a core,
we can start providing them slices on the main thread.
So while tasks, this just means while it is not empty,
we are going to do the task is tasks zero,
that's the first task in here.
We're gonna remove the task from the list
and then we're gonna try to do x is next of the task,
we're gonna print x,
and then we're going to append the task again.
Okay, so all that we're doing here is we're gonna
get the first task in our list,
we're gonna remove it from the list.
Our list is gonna end up as these two tasks.
We're going to get a new variable x,
which is gonna be the next of the tasks,
or in this case, ten for the first one.
We're gonna print it out,
and then we're gonna append it
over to the end of our list again.
If we encounter an "except" on stop iteration,
remember this is what gets raised
when we run out of values of a generator,
then we're just going to print "task finished,"
and that's it.
When we print "task finished,"
because we try to get the next value
of something but it fails,
we are not going to append it back to the task.
When we try to get the next,
and that gives us stop iteration,
we will not run either of these two.
All right, let's run this file.
And as you can see,
we start at the top with ten, five, and 20,
and they go down one by one
until you see task finished, that's the five,
then you see task finished, that's for the ten,
and then the 20 sort of takes up all the time in the CPU,
or in this case, in the main thread
and eventually finishes as well.
Whereas these tasks are all quite simple,
they don't really do much.
But this is an example of
multitasking in Python without using threads.
You've got a task doing something,
another task doing something else,
another task doing something entirely separate,
and they are collaborating doing
collaborative multitasking in order to complete
the things all at the same time.
You can see how we can use yield
in any circumstance to suspend a task temporarily
and then bring it back at some point in the future.
So for example if you asked for user input,
you could then yield and run your
complex mathematical operation.
When the user applies,
you could yield your mathematical operation
and go back to your user input and deal with that.
Going back to the example in the lecture a few videos ago.
So these yields, all you have to do is
put them in the right place
and then you could potentially avoid blocking operations,
you could avoid points in time where your Python code
is just waiting to do things.
Of course, if you've got a task that doesn't yield,
then you have a problem because that one
is just gonna clog the CPU,
and if you have a task that yields
but it takes a very long time between one yield and another,
that task is gonna take up a lot of time
and the other task is not gonna have enough time.
If that's the case,
if you have a task that takes a long time to run
while the others take a very small amount of time to run,
you could offload the work to a separate thread
or to a separate process using,
as we've seen already, the thread pool executor,
or the process pool executor.
And actually, calling next on a function
and going back to a suspended function
is cheaper than changing from one thread to another.
Python has been developed so this is really cheap,
really easy to do.
So it can be really fast to use these generators
instead of threads if that's what you need.
Now in the next video,
we're going to look at some more of this,
and the purpose of the next few videos
is to build up your knowledge of how
this asynchronous development works
up until we arrive at modern Python
and how modern Python does asynchronous development.
Okay, I'll see you on the next video.