Hi, welcome back.
In this video I just wanted to guide you through
exactly what we're going to be getting from our html
and the path or the locators that we're going to be getting,
just because I know it's not so easy
to look at in the browser.
So this is our site, as you know.
And we're going to start crafting
our locators for the books.
So we're going to retrieve each book as an entity
and we're going to feed that to our book parser.
So this is the div dot page inner.
It contains essentially all of the page content
except the header.
The only reason why you might want to scrape the header
is if you don't know the title of your site.
But because we know that, we can start here
at the div dot page underscore inner.
Inside that we have a section which contains this content,
so as soon as we start narrowing down our locator
into the section, it loses context of the topics
at the site and the breadcrumbs
and the number of results and things like that.
And finally each individual book is a list item.
And list items on this website are each individual book
and they also have a few classes in them, like col xs 6.
These columns are used for sizing,
and so at this point in time the website has decided
to use these sizes for the columns
but they may change in the future
so just keep and eye out in case it's not exactly
this col xs 6 class, in case it's a bit different.
Okay, so when we use this locator and we ask
BeautifulSoup to you know select all of the elements,
it's gonna give us a bunch of tags,
which are gonna be these li tags that it has found
and each tag contains the info for a single book
but we must still go deeper and get that information out
so we need some deeper locators.
The locators I'm about to show you
are those that are inside this li tag.
So for example, the title or the name of the book,
we can extract from that element there in the green,
and that will be article dot product pod h3 a.
So inside the article dot product pod tag,
which is essentially the entire book as well,
there is an h3 tag, a heading tag,
and inside that h3 there's an a tag, which is a link.
And alight in the dot dot dot is the text content
inside that tag.
But also the tag has a couple other properties,
and we can extract the book's title
from those properties as well.
If we wanted the link and, for example if we wanted to
click through and go to the book page,
not the whole set of books but just the individual book
in case we wanted to, sort of,
read some more information about the book
or scrape some more information about the book,
there is a link in that title that you can click and
go to the other page and of course the selector or
the locator is gonna be the same
if we wanna extract the link, only we're gonna have to
access the href property of that.
If you wanted to get the price out,
that element down there, you will be looking for
article dot product pod and the name site
that there's a p tag which has a class price colour.
So we can use that tag to extract the price
and then you'll be using regular expressions
to actually get the price out as a number.
We've looked at that in the past
in the regular special section how to do that.
We're gonna go over it again in this section.
Finally we're gonna look at the rating.
This book has three stars and if we wanted
to get the star rating, we are looking for
article dot product pod and then p dot star dash rating.
Notice the dash is not an underscore,
just one of the quirks of this website.
We'll also find that the number of stars
that we can see is not what we're gonna be scraping
so this p tag here, this p dot star rating,
actually has a property that contains the rating
so we're gonna be using that instead of
looking at the number of stars that are filled.
That's just a bit more difficult.
Okay so just to recap, each book is that li tag.
The name of the book which is inside the li tag
is the article dot product pod h3 a.
The link is also in that same tag.
The price is inside p dot price colour.
And the rating is inside p dot star dash rating.
So with this we can construct our locator files.
Let's do that in the next video.