Hi, guys,nd welcome back.
In this video, I wanted to tell you about slicing.
Slicing is the process of getting
a part of a list or other iterable.
Imagine you've got a list of your friends,
and you wanted your friends
between two and four.
You can do print, friends,
and then in square brackets,
2 colon 4.
And what this means is
you're going to get Anna and Bob.
That's two, three, and stops at
four so it doesn't get you four.
This here is list slicing
and you can do this with strings as well
if you want or with tuples
and what it allows you to do
is to get a segment of a list
or a tuple or a string.
It can be really useful at times,
but it is particularly useful
because you can actually skip
some of these numbers.
For example, if you want to only get
elements in the list,
except the first one,
you can do one colon nothing.
And what that means is one to the end
of the list.
So if you do this, you're going to get
all your friends, except the first one.
Similarly, if you put four in here,
it will start at the very start of the list,
colon, and at four.
So, we will get Rolf, Charlie,
Anna, and Bob, and we will skip
the fourth one and any later ones as well.
Now, if you remove both numbers
so you just do colon inside square brackets,
you'll actually get all the elements back,
but with a key difference.
You're not getting the same list.
It is a new list that you're building.
And at this point, that doesn't really matter.
It doesn't have a lot of meaning to you,
but it just gives you a new list, and this is
the way to do that in Python. If you want
a new list which contains all of the elements
of the previous list, you can do this.
If you just do this, you're just getting
the same list. So exactly the same thing.
Now with list slicing you can actually use
negative numbers. For example,
minus three up to the end of the list.
And what this does is it starts counting
from the end. So, you will get back, Anna,
which is, the element starting from the end,
the third one. Bob and Jen.
Because again, minus three is the starting point,
and when you skip the ending point,
that is the end of the list.
So you could do minus three to four, for example,
and you get Anna and Bob because it stops at four.
Or you can do minus three colon empty,
and then it'll run to the end of the list.
You can do this here so it will go from
the start of the list
because you haven't put anything in there
up to the second to last element: Bob.
So you get Rolf, Charlie, and Anna.
This is useful if you wanted all your friends
except the last two, for example.
Finally, you can also do minus three,
and for example minus one. And again,
that gives you from the third element from the end Anna,
up to the first element from the end, Jen.
But, it does not include this one as always,
so you just get Anna and Bob.
There's a lot more stuff you can do with slices,
but I just wanted to give you a very quick primer.
The first number is the starting point,
and the second number is the ending point.
We're gonna link, in the researching section
of this lecture, a few blog posts that we've written
on list slicing. Some of them may be a bit advanced,
but you can read them or bookmark them
to come back to them in the future.
And there's quite a lot of stuff you can do.
They are very powerful tools in Python.
Thanks for joining me in this video.
I hope you've learned something, and I'll see you
in the next one.