Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to learn about
actually getting data from our users,
so that our programmes can start being a bit more dynamic.
Imagine you've got your name,
and it's Jose, and you want the user's name.
But, how do you get it?
Do you expect the user to edit the programme
so they can put their name in here?
Finally, what you'll want to do is to print,
you know something like "Hello .
"My name is ."
Let's say we have a simple programme like this.
So how do you get the user's name?
Because if you run this right now,
you'll get "Hello, empty string.
"My name is Jose."
If the user has to come in and edit the programme,
then, you know, this'll work, right?
But, how are you gonna share this with users
that don't know any programming?
So, what we have to do is we have to first
ask the user for their name,
and allow them to type something here in this text console
and then use that name inside our programme.
So here is where the input function comes in.
So we will type input("Enter your name: ")
and what this is going to do is it's going to
open up a prompt here in the console
and notice that the programme is stopped
until we press the Enter key.
So if I type Rolf now, then you'll see that we get back
"Hello Rolf.
"My name is Jose."
This tells you one thing about the input function,
which is that the thing that the user typed
came back to us, and it must have been a string.
Because it contains characters, it is not an integer
and it is not a float, otherwise it would have to be numbers
and you would be able to do maths on it.
So it must be a string.
And that is something that always happens
with the input function.
Anything the user types, even if it is
the number 35, is a string.
A string that contains the characters three and five.
With that in mind, let's try something else.
Let's try asking the user for their age.
And then we're going to print
"You have lived for  months."
So a very popular first programme,
we're gonna ask the user for their age,
and then we're going to say, for example,
they might in there enter three there,
we're gonna say, "You have lived for 36 months."
Right?
But remember, that the age variable has a string in it.
The input function always gives you back a string,
even if you enter a number.
So, we aren't turning this into a number.
What is going to happen when we multiply a string by 12?
Well, let me type three in here.
And you get 333333333333.
You get 12 threes.
Because age times 12 is more or less the same as
age plus age plus age plus age 12 times.
And remember what happens when we add two strings together?
They get joined together.
They get concatenated.
So, by multiplying a string by a number,
really what you're getting is 12 of those strings.
What you have to do is you have to turn it into an integer.
So, the same way that we used S-T-R to turn a integer,
or another number into a string,
we can use I-N-T or int to turn a string into an integer.
So, we will turn age into an integer
and put it inside age_num,
and then we will do age_num times 12.
And that works just as well.
Now something important about Python
that you're gonna see quite a lot
is that when you evaluate one of these things here,
that becomes the value that the user has given you.
So, here's what I mean.
This text that I've got selected here
is three when your programme runs.
So, if the user is going to enter three in your programme,
this entire text I've got selected
is exactly identical to you just typing three in there.
Means exactly the same thing.
Of course, the user can enter something different,
if they'd like, so this is why this is a dynamic value.
But, if they enter three, it's the same thing
as having three in there.
If they enter 35, it's the same thing as having 35 in there.
So, we could do age equal int of 35, right?
And then we would not need this age_num there,
and we could do this.
But, how do we get the dynamic value
instead of the static 35 string?
We use the input function that we had just a moment ago.
So you can do this in Python
because the things inside the brackets always run first.
So, the input function will run,
and the programme will wait until the user presses Enter.
And then, this entire selected text will be replaced
by what the user enters.
For example, the string three.
And then we will pass that to the int function,
which will give us an integer equivalent
to the string that we got passed.
So we will get the integer three.
And then we will put that inside age.
This type of nesting is very common
and you will be doing this quite often.
However, it's also easy to go a bit overboard with it.
You don't wanna be doing that.
You don't want to nest like 20 times,
otherwise the code gets almost unreadable.
But a couple of functions inside each other
can actually shorten your code
and make it a bit easier to read.
Remember what we had before is we have an age variable.
And then we also have an age_num variable.
But, the age variable was only useful
to calculate age_num.
It wasn't used anywhere else in our programme.
So it's kinda pointless to keep it around.
We might as well nest these here
and only have one variable that we actually want and use,
and not have two variables, one of which is pointless.
Now instead of doing the multiplication inside the f-string,
which you can do, we can separate this into a new variable.
Why might you do that?
Well the main reason for separating a value like that
into a variable is so that you can
give it a name that has meaning.
Now when you read this programme, it's pretty obvious
that first you're getting the user's age,
then you're calculating how many months that equals to,
and then you're printing that out.
And it's quite obvious
because your variable is called months.
If your variable was called x,
then it might not be so obvious
until you read through the entire thing.
Giving variables good names, good descriptive names,
is a bit of an art form and it can be quite tricky at times,
but it's really important.
You will get better at it over time.
In the next lecture, we've got a small exercise for you,
which is to, instead of printing the number of months
the user has lived for, you can print the number of seconds
they have lived for.
Just slightly different maths here,
but more or less the same.
Do try to complete that exercise on your own
without looking back at this code,
and if you've forgotten how to do it,
then do look back of course
so that you can complete the exercise.
Through practise, and through typing code,
you're going to learn much faster
than just by watching the videos.
That's everything for this one though.
Thank you for joining me, and I'll see you in the next one.
Good luck with the exercise.