Hi and welcome back.
In this video we're going to finish our milestone project
by including the update and delete statements.
We've added the create_book_table,
which creates our table if it doesn't exist already.
We've inserted a new book into our table.
And we've also looked at selecting all of the books
from our table and returning them as dictionaries.
Now we've got two more functions, mark_book_as_read
and delete_book.
With our files, what these did, was, read the entire file,
find the appropriate book, update it,
and then save all the books back.
With SQL we can actually find the correct book by name
on the database and update it in place,
so we no longer need to get all the books,
change one and then save them all back.
For that reason, I'm going to delete this save_all_books
function, and that's a good reason why it had the underscore
in the beginning.
It was something that we wanted to use internally
to make our interface work, but it wasn't something
we wanted the app use.
So that's why it had the underscore before,
to mark it as, sort of, private.
So that other part of our programme
wouldn't want to use it too.
To mark a book as read, you know how to do this now,
'cause we have to initialise a connection, get a cursor,
execute our update statement with a where clause
that would where by the name,
and then commit and close the connection.
We don't even need to return anything
or get any data out of the database in order to do this.
I think you can implement this function on your own,
so give it a go.
I'm sure you managed to do that.
We've just looked at the update, and all we have to do,
is again, copy this boilerplate sqlite3.connect
to data.db.
Make sure to use the correct data file.
Get a cursor.
Then execute our SQL, and this is going to be,
update the books table, set the read to one,
where the name is equal to a question mark.
Remember, you must not use f-strings here,
because that opens you up
for potential SQL injection attacks.
So what we're gonna put here is a tuple of name.
And notice that, in order to make a tuple,
we have to include the quote, the brackets, sorry,
as well as the comma, in order to say this is a tuple,
it's not a mathematical thing
that we want to evaluate first.
And certainly, if you don't put the brackets in
and you just do this, it thinks that this is an entirely
new argument to the execute method, which we don't wanna do.
We wanna make sure it's a tuple, so we do it like this.
Now that we've ran this, we want to make sure that
these changes get saved to disc.
So connection.commit and finally connection.close,
and that's it.
Now we've updated our book,
set the red flag to one, where the name was equal to name.
Going over to delete_book.
I think you can also implement this.
For, what we have to do is pretty much the same.
Once again, pause the video and give this a go.
Now, I'm sure you really managed to get this,
what I'm going to do is copy this boilerplate,
not something you should be doing very often.
But, instead of updating, we're gonna say DELETE FROM books,
where the name is this question mark.
And once again, the name gets passed in
as an argument there.
Then we commit once again and we close.
We don't have to fetch any rules or anything,
'cause there's nothing for us to return
from this DELETE statement.
And that's it, we've got all the data
in and out of our database that we needed.
We can go back to app.py and all we have to do,
is potentially update this book['read'] flag here.
We could say,
YES, if the book's read status is true, otherwise NO.
But what you didn't know, is that if zero
actually evaluates to false and if one evaluates to true.
So if book['read'] is one, contains the integer one,
we're going to get YES.
If it contains the integer zero, we're going to get NO.
So we don't actually have to change this at all.
Python automatically treats one and zero as true and false
as well, which is pretty handy.
So we don't actually have to make any changes at all
to our app.py, which tells us that we've done
an excellent job isolating our data storage device,
our database, from our business logic.
And I keep going on and on about this interface,
because it's really important part of programming,
to be able to decouple your different components,
and make sure that they can operate without knowing
how the other one is implemented, that's really important.
Let's go ahead and run our app.
And then we can look at adding a new book.
Ooh, and we get an error.
We get an error, that says,
IntegrityError: UNIQUE constraint failed on books.name.
That means that a book with this name
already existed in our database.
Interesting error.
Of course, we know that this should be an error,
we don't want the same book twice.
So, what happened is that our data.db was existing
from the last time we ran this and I entered the same book.
So, if you want to get rid of this error just temporarily,
delete data.db and run your app again.
Then, you can enter Clean Code.
Then you can list all your books now
and that gives you Clean Code by Robert C. Martin.
You can, of course, mark a book as read,
then you can list the books again
and it gives you Clean Code by Robert C. Martin.
You can delete a book,
not that you'd want to delete this book,
and then you get nothing when you list the books back again.
So we've made our programme work with a database,
a SQLite database, which is very very similar
to a Postgres or a MySQL database.
The way we interact with it, using SQL,
is pretty much the same.
Postgres and MySQL are more powerful,
they do more things for you,
and they also have a bit more functionality,
more different types of data you can store, and so forth.
But really, what we've covered is the same amongst
all major databases, which is really cool.
Of course, we haven't gotten rid of the insert error,
when we insert something that already exists,
but you could do that.
You could put a try accept here on a integrity error,
and just print out something that says,
we can put out your book
or you can return false potentially,
and then in your app.py, say, if this succeeded,
print nothing and then if it didn't succeed, print,
you've already got that book in your database.
Feel free to extend this as far as you want,
and of course ask questions in the course journey
if you encounter any issues, we'd be happy to help you.
I'm not going to bore you any longer
with continuing with this project,
we can move on to better things.
So with that said, I'll see you on the next video.
We're gonna talk briefly about one more thing in SQL
that we didn't get to use in this project
but still pretty important, and then we can go over
to the following section.
I'll see you soon.