Hi, and welcome back.
In this video we're going to start
with our book-scraping project.
It is going to be set-up very similarly
to our quote-scraping project,
just so you fully understand how I
recommend setting up the scraping projects.
So, once again let's create our files.
We've got app.py and for this project app.py is going
to be a sort of test file type thing
where we're going to be running some
of the commands written in our other files.
Then, we're going to have a few Python packages.
Locators is going to be one of them
and that's the one we're going
to be working on in this video.
We are also gonna have pages,
of course, for the different pages
we'll have and parsers
which are for specific sections of the page
that we want to extract data from.
So, pages and parsers pretty similar.
Think of it as sort of containers and components
if you've ever done any component development.
Or, just as, you know, whole pages
that interact with parsers to extract information.
In the locators, we're gonna add two files for now.
The old books page, which is going
to be that page we've already seen, and we're also going
to add books locators, book locators. Okay?
Inside the book locators we are going
to create a class BookLocators:
And, in here, we are going to put in the locators
that we came up with earlier
that I showed you in the previous video
in that presentation.
We're gonna have a NAME_LOCATOR
and this is going to be article.product_pod h3 a'
And, we're gonna press command d or control d
if you're on Windows.
Just duplicate this and we're gonna
name this Link_Locator.
Notice how these two are the same for now?
But, I'm keeping them as a separate locators
just in case the website decides to change later on.
This is going to make my programme
a little bit more resilient.
Then, we're gonna have a PRICE_LOCATOR
which is going to be used to get that p tag
that contains the price.
So, again article.product_pod p.price_color'
It's interesting that it's got this class here price colour.
That's just because the price of the item has a colour,
so that's what the website's decided to go for
in terms of the class name and but depending on the website,
it may be different.
Finally, we've got a RATING_LOCATOR
Which again, article.product_pod p.star-rating'
If you make any typos on this,
you'll get some errors later on.
So, just make sure that these are correct.
All of them have a article.product.pod to start
because the entire book is enclosed in this article tag.
And, then we are looking for a h3
within that article anywhere inside it.
And, then a that should be within this h3.
Similarly here and same with these.
Now, let's go over to our page locators.
We're gonna have class AllBooksPageLocators:
And, here we're going to just have one thing for now.
We're going to add more later.
And, this is going to allow us to find all of the books.
So, the locator that we place here should be able to find
each list item that contains a book.
The contents of that list item we're then gonna pass
to the book parser which is going to use these locators
to locate exact information.
So, here we're gonna go
for div.page_inner section li.col-xs-6'
If you want to be more explicit and you want
to add all of the classes inside this li tag you can do that
by just doing .col-sm-4.col-md-3.col-lg-3'.
So, I'm gonna leave it as this.
Feel free to skip on these classes,
or maybe just include one of them.
But, I'd recommend including at least one class.
Just in case there are other list items
elsewhere on the page.
Well, elsewhere inside this section,
that people may get confused.
So, make sure to include at least one
of the classes just to be sure.
Now, with these locators we are ready now
to move on to the next video.
We're going to be using them to extract information.
I'll see you there.