Hi, welcome back.
Let's look at some examples
of class method and static method.
There was some terrible examples in the last video,
so I just wanted to apologise,
but I wanted to show you the syntax
for those two types of method,
the class method and the static method.
Let's have a class here,
which is going to be the basis
of the example in this video,
and I think it's gonna be a better example
for you to understand in which situations
do you use which type of method.
We've got this FixedFloat class.
It's got an init method in which an amount property
gets initialised in the object,
and then it's got a repr method,
which returns a string representing the object.
We've looked at this type of method,
at this exact method before,
and all it's doing is it's printing FixedFloat,
the class name, and then self.amount,
which is the amount that we initialised earlier.
And this is a interesting Python construct,
that allows us to print the amount
to two decimal places;
not three, not four, not five, not one, just two.
So for example, if were printing 15.50,
Python would normally print 15.5.
But with this construct here, it will print 15.50.
So this is a FixedFloat,
a float to a fixed number of decimal places.
If we wanted to create our number,
and it be a FixedFloat like 18.5746,
then we can print the number and it will print out
that this is a FixedFloat of 18.57
So okay, this does something.
What is a use case that this could be useful for?
Well, for example, for a currency,
you could imagine using something like this.
For some currencies, that are always to two decimal places
but sometimes they trade in the stock markets
to many more decimal places, in the currency markets.
So anyway, it could be useful in some scenarios.
Now imagine we wanted to get a new FixedFloat object
as a result from summing two floats.
We could something like this, from_sum.
And then of course, this is an instance method,
so it takes self, it takes value1 and value2.
And what this is going to return
is a new FixedFloat object of value1 plus value2.
So again, maybe not something you would wanna do.
You could just add the values together
and then create a FixedFloat object from the result.
But lets say we want to do this for
a particular reason that you'll see in a moment.
Now if we wanted to create a new FixedFloat object,
that is a result of two values,
we could say, new_number is number.from_sum,
Notice how we have to do number.from_sum
because this is an instance method;
it doesn't have any decorators on top.
And it'll be something like 19.575 and 0.789
Then we can print the new_number, like so.
Now we get a new FixedFloat object, which is 20.36.
That's the FixedFloat that has been returned
which adds up the two numbers together, 19 and 0.7
However, I don't really like this.
Because in order to call the from_sum method,
we've had to first create a FixedFloat object,
that we never used, right?
We only used it to call this method,
we never used self inside this method
and we never used this number anywhere else.
So really creating an object for this
is not that useful.
You should only create objects
when you're gonna use them.
So instead, we could make this a staticmethod.
Remove the self, and now you no longer
need the object there.
Which means that instead of calling it with the object,
you can just call it with the class.
Remember, we no longer need to pass the object in here,
so just call it with the class
and don't pass the object in.
And then, value1 is this and value2 is that.
We can run it again and see the same thing comes out.
So that looks a bit better.
Now we don't have the useless parameter
and we don't need to create an object
before we call the method.
Awesome.
However, lets extend this example a bit more
and create a new class, which is going to be
a currency class that extends that FixedFloat class.
Lets call it Euro.
And this is going to extend this FixedFloat class
because Euros are normally printed out
as two decimal places too.
Now we have another init method,
where self and amount are called.
We are going to call super, init with amount.
And also we're going to define a new property,
specific to Euro objects,
which is going to be the symbol.
And that's gonna be the Euro symbol.
But it you're using Python 2.7,
it probably won't like this.
So make sure you're using Python 3.6,
as this symbol is a Unicode symbol.
Okay.
Now we've got this here.
Lets also, override this repr method,
in order to return now a Euro class.
Euro, and were gonna say self.symbol,
self.amount to two decimal places.
Okay.
Now if we create a new Euro object,
which we shall do it right here.
And money is
Euro of 18.786,
and then we can print money out.
So lets run that.
You can see that we have this Euro now,
which was the currency code, sorry the currency symbol,
which is pretty cool, it's a bit nice.
Now we've defined this class that
extends the FixedFloat class.
And it's got its init method and that
calls the parent's init method to set the amount.
And the repr method that overrides
the parent's repr method to include the symbol and so forth.
It doesn't have the from_sum method though.
So what happens, when do that money is Euro,
from_sum of 16.758
and 9.999?
What are we gonna see printed out?
I hope you guessed correctly.
The Euro.from_sum method,
has been inherited from FixedFloat.
So it's just going to be this one here.
What it's going to return is a FixedFloat object.
So this Euro.from_sum, really is going to return,
a FixedFloat object, which doesn't make any sense.
It should be a Euro object surely,
since that's what we called it with.
Lets run this, and you see that I'm correct
in saying that a FixedFloat comes out.
So we don't want that.
What we want to do instead is make sure
that we are returning an object of the type
of the class we called it with,
so that we are never faced with this bug, really.
The way we can do that is by changing
this staticmethod to a classmethod.
And I'll need cls value there.
Now this is the class that we called it with.
If we call Euro.from_sum, Python is smart enough
to include Euro as the first argument
and therefore as the first parameter to this method.
Then we return, we don't wanna
return a FixedFloat of course.
What we're gonna do is return
cls and use it as if it were the class.
Because it is.
So if we call it from a FixedFloat number,
that's gonna be a FixedFloat.
If we call it from a Euro, like here,
it's gonna be a Euro.
Okay. Lets run it.
And now you can see that we get it correct.
And we have the symbol and the Euro in here
as we would expect.
Okay.
So that's really cool.
When we call Euro.from_sum, Euro is the cls.
When we call FixedFloat.from_sum, FixedFloat is the cls,
which is really cool.
This is one of the examples where
you would use a class method.
And a lot of the Python community is
quite strongly against static methods as a whole.
They say, a static method is just a class method
with slightly less functionality and no benefits.
And I am tempted to agree with them.
I would recommend that you use a class method
whenever you want something that doesn't need self.
And whenever you want to call FixedFloat
inside a class method, just replace it for cls.
If you then inherit form that class,
all the methods will still be usable
in the way you'd expect,
because cls will automatically be populated
from the class that you're using
and not the class that you programmed in.
So it just lets you make your methods
a bit more generic and generally is a bit nicer.
Static method, you can also call it,
for example, if this is a static method as it was before,
you call it in the same way, FixedFloat.from_sum,
only now you've lost that reference to FixedFloat.
So how the static method doesn't actually add anything,
it doesn't make your code any simpler.
Your code looks the same,
but you've lost that functionality which is the cls.
So generally, I would advice using class methods
whenever possible.
Oh wait. Not whenever possible.
My apologies. Not that.
Use class methods whenever you want
to use a method that doesn't use self.
Don't use static methods, generally.
I don't see that they are that useful
when you've got class methods.
However, there are a couple instances
when using a static method can be interesting.
And that's, for example, when you know
that the class you're developing is
not gonna get inherited from,
and in fact, when I am coding, and I use a static method,
it tells me that this class is
not going to get inherited from.
It's something that, when I use a static method,
it's like telling myself, it's safe to do this
because I'm not going to use this class
anywhere else to inherit from.
Whereas when you use a class method,
you sort of telling, I don't know if
this class is gonna get inherited from later on.
So that's the only place where
I would use a static method when I know
and I wanna make sure that I'm not gonna
inherit from that class.
The fact that it's used static methods
tells me that I don't want to inherit from here.
You'll see, you'll understand more about what I mean
as we move over to future sections.
We're gonna use static methods a couple of times,
but we're normally going to stick with class methods.
Anyway, this was, hopefully a slightly better example,
helps you understand where to use static
and where to use class methods,
and exactly what they are useful for.
Also remember, static and class methods
can be called from the object,
so you could have your object
calling the from_sum method and that would be totally fine.
You would just see the class of the object that called it
or you can call it with the class
and then the class is just that, class too.
And so what I mean by that is that this is fine.
new_number.from_sum is fine.
It just gonna see the class as the class of this object.
It's not really something you should do normally though.
Normally, just use the class name, FixedFloat.from_sum.
That's a better way of going about things.
Anyway that's it for this video.
Hopefully I haven't confused you
anymore that you were before.
And this helped a little bit.
I'll see you on the next video.