[Jose Salvatierra] Hi welcome back.
In this video we're going to introduce async and await.
These two pieces of syntax are fairly new in Python
and they are extremely used nowadays
whenever you write any Python code
that uses asynchronous development.
For example, there are many Python frameworks
and sort of libraries that you can use
that allow you to run things together more or less
all in the same thread but yielding to one another
in order to avoid waiting times.
And nobody understood yield from
so a new keyword was invented in order
to get rid of yield from.
And this keyword is called the await keyword.
So we're going to rewrite this code,
it's going to be a small rewrite,
in order to use async and await
and you'll see how suddenly it just makes a lot more sense.
So let's rewrite this to use the new Python syntax
and you'll see how it makes a lot more sense.
We are going to essentially leave this exactly the same
but we now must tell Python that this
is not a generator that can somehow accept data.
We now have to say this is a coroutine.
So we say @coroutine and it's red
because it doesn't know what it is
so we have to import it, so from types import coroutine.
And then it likes it.
You must do this in order for us
to be able to do the following
which is await_g.
It doesn't like this because you must do async def there.
Now that we've got our async function
this tells Python that it can await coroutines.
And when we await a coroutine
that is exactly the same as yield from.
Now we can accept data via this send
that gets passed over to g which is this generator here
this coroutine which accepts it through the yield
and gets sent to greeting and then it prints things out.
Notice that when we await the same way as when we yield from
this waits for this entire function to finish.
So here the while loop, essentially this is waiting
for the entire while loop to finish.
But it can suspend halfway through,
that's the whole point of the yield.
So, when you send something, this gets passed over
to g, which then resumes the function
after the yield and then if you go back
over to the start of the yield and then it suspends
and this function this line here
still hasn't finished running.
When you send some more, then it gets passed over to g
and then it continues this function running.
But await_g still hasn't finished running
until this coroutine has ended.
If we print something like Starting
and here something like Ending
you'll see what I mean.
If we press play, you can see that we print Starting
but Ending is never printed out
because we've not finished running the coroutine.
The coroutine has a loop and it continues running
until friends is empty and we've not gone
through all of the friends, we've only gone
through two of the friends with our two greetings.
If we wanted to go through all of the friends
we can do that and just by doing this.
And now if we run this again you can see
that we get Ending at the end
and then we get our StopIteration
because the coroutine ended and you know
when you end the coroutine or a generator
you get a StopIteration to signal that this is the end.
So this is really important.
The await, just like yield from,
they are exactly the same thing,
waits for this to finish but you can suspend
the function in the middle.
So a slightly better way of going about this
could be that instead of sending arbitrary greetings there
one of the great things is, you can send,
for example, Hello.
But then you can get another thing from the user
and then you can do greeter.send(greeting).
And then you can sort of copy them and paste them again.
This is now proper multitasking.
Because when you run it, now you get the user to type
and as soon as the user types,
this then continues running the function above
and it prints out, oh Sorry, Jose, Jose.
Howdy.
Howdy Charlie.
And then your programme ends.
We've now gone through all of our friends.
So this how the programme ends there.
There are more uses, many more uses of course,
for this async and await syntax
and for concurrent programming in Python as a whole.
So all you've seen so far is some sort
of abstract examples I've just shown you there
but we need to look at a way
to use these functions in the real world.
In the next video I'm going to suggest
that you watch a few talks, and those talks
again will walk you through what async and await mean
and how you do concurrency in Python
and they will also include some real world examples.
And then afterwards we're working to add some more content
on the course about some real world examples
of using async and await.
So if that's not yet in the course
just check back later on and we will be adding it in.
Hopefully though, now you understand
how async and await work
and that's by using these generators.
With that said, I'll see you in the next video.