Hi and welcome back.
In this video let's talk about Python logging.
In the simplest terms the logging module is used
to print things out.
Very much like the print function that you've used before
but the logging module's a bit more powerful.
It can be used to print things out to a console
or to a file, and essentially it's used to print out logs.
I don't know if we've mentioned logs before but a log
is essentially everything that happened in your application.
For example you could have a log of your day which you
write down in some sort of notebook,
everything that happened in your day.
You could have a log of a holiday in which you write down
everything that happened during your holiday.
And you can have a log of your app which you write down
everything that happened during your app's run time.
For example whether an error happened, a critical problem,
some information about some method that's running.
Basically anything and these logs are used for developers
to look into to understand how the applications are running.
Of course if you have a very small app,
this maybe not so useful.
As your app starts growing decent logging in there
is going to be very handy.
The good thing about the logging module is,
one of the good things about the logging module,
is that it has various levels of logging.
And you can sort of enable levels and disable others.
So for example as you are developing you may want to use
the logger to output informative messages about what's
happening in your application.
Once you deploy your application, you share it
with your users and it's running and you've got a lot
of people using it, maybe you don't want
informative messages, you only want messages that are
related to errors.
So with a logging module you can do that.
If you've got print statements everywhere you cannot
enable some and disable others.
So the logging module, pretty cool.
We can import logging and the first thing we have to do
is we have to get a new logger.
So we're gonna create a variable logger and there's gonna be
logging.getLogger and then we have to give it the name
of the logger we want.
So we're gonna call it test logger.
The good thing about this is that it's meant to be used
across multiple files.
So if you have a logger called test logger,
and you call this from a different file entirely,
it's actually going to give you the same object.
And that's good because you can configure loggers
to print things out differently.
You can configure loggers to export to a file
or to the console so it's quite nice that you can do this.
So that when you get the same logger from a different file
it will be configured the same way.
We're gonna look at configuring them in a moment.
Then it's very simple when you wanna print things out,
all you do is say logger.info for example and
this will not show up.
Or you can do something logger.warning and This will.
Then you can run it.
And as you can see you get warning: test_logger:This will
Your informative message did not show up because
my default all loggers are configured so that they only
show messages warning and above.
So here are the levels that you've got.
You've got debug, that's the lowest level.
You've got info, that's the level above.
And these two don't show up by default on new loggers.
You have to say I want these in order for them to show.
The next one up is warning, this ones do show.
As you can see the warning messages show up.
Then you've got error and then you've got critical.
Critical is the most critical one, of course
as the sort of most important.
Debug is meant to only to be used
while you are developing the application.
So again use the debug level if you are developing
or debugging and basically things you don't want users,
well none of these are for users, but basically
things that you only wanna see while you are developing
not while your application's is running for your users.
And of course if your program's about to crash because
you found some critical exception or something,
you can use logger.critical.
The way you configure your logger is that just before
you create it, you must say logging.basicConfig
and in here you can say level=logging.debug
in upper case here.
Or .info if that's the minimum one you want to show.
.debug if debug is the minimum level you want to show.
However this doesn't quite work in repl.it.
So let's go over the Python to give this a go.
I moved over to Python now I've just copied the code.
So again we have import logging, logging.basicConfig
where the level that we're gonna show is at least debug.
Then we've created a logger by calling logging.getLogger.
And then we've printed out two messages, one that says
this will not show up and one that says this will.
So let's run the app.
And you can see that we get now
the info message there as well.
I think this is because the test logger here
actually inherits from what's called the root logger
and I think that repl it has configured their root logger
so that debug and info messages do not show up.
So that's why that may not work in repl for you
but it would most definitely work in Python
since you have control of everything.
Repl is after all running the Python
in their own environment so they also have some of their own
configurations there as well.
Now you can configure the output to show a bit more info
rather than just the level and the logger
that printed things out.
In basicConfig you can have something like format
and then in a string you can put whatever it is
that you wanna format your log messages as.
For example (asctime)s.
This is the way old school Python syntax
for string formatting and it's going to use the asctime
variable that will be available when this gets used.
The s means turn it with string.
So (asctime)s for example %(levelname)s
and then %(message)s.
So this thing here is going to look pretty similar
to our existing message but asctime is actually going
to print out the time at which the log was printed out.
Instead of the level, sorry the levelname is gonna
be printed out here so what we're now going to print out
is the name of the logger.
If we run the app, you'll see that now we get the time
in which we printed out,
the level info and then the message.
I think this is slightly nicer 'cause now if you have
a larger app and you've got a logs sort of appearing,
you'll be able to tell when each log happened.
Then if you're looking back you'll be able to see sort of
yeah I logged this message at this point in time
and then I logged this message and then an error happened.
So you can then sort of reconstruct from these logs
what happened in your application.
If you wanna configure your logger for maximum readability,
I've got an example that I think is pretty good.
It's taken from stack overflow but I think it's good.
I pasted it in here just for you.
And then what it does this here prints out the time
as you know.
This print out the level but the level name is actually
formatted as eight spaces.
So for example you have down here info that takes up four
spaces while the -8s is going to add four spaces after it.
That way all of your levels are going to take up
the same amount of room and your log messages are going to
appear sort of one beside the other.
Then inside square brackets, these are just good old
normal square brackets.
We're gonna print out the file name in which the log
was printed out and the line number as a number.
That's what the d means.
And then we're gonna print out the message finally.
So let's run this again and now you'll see that this is
quite readable and also quite useful.
You're getting the time and what type of message it is.
You're also getting where the message was logged
and this is fantastic.
This is really why logging is brilliant 'cause
you can see exactly where things happened.
And finally you can see your message there
and notice how it's quite readable.
So I like this example here, feel free to use this
in your logging of course as you choose.
Now I give you some other examples of debug message,
this is debug message.
And you can do of course logger.critical,
critical error occurred.
You can log these out and as you can see they'll
all appear and they all take up eight spaces
because critical is the longest one that takes up
eight characters.
And so this is pretty handy.
Now you can also log to a file instead of to the console.
We're going to look at how to do that
in the very next video, I'll just quickly show you.
And yeah this is how you do logs in Python.
You'll see many, many large Python apps using this exactly.
This logger and it's really that simple.
You just get a logger, you call it whatever you want,
and normally it's related to your app or sort of
to the part of your app that you're working with
and then you can logout messages.
You normally see a lot of these messages being logged
because then you can choose to only show error and critical
in some cases.
All the way down from debug when you are working.
So it's really quite nice, it's very flexible.
Definitely recommend doing this.
Do keep using print when you wanna communicate
with your users.
Don't use logs to communicate with your users.
They'll be very confused so do keep using print
if you wanna talk to your users.
The log should be something completely separate and
they should normally go to a file or something like that.
We're gonna look at how to do that in just a moment.
So that's it for this video.
I'll see you in the very next one.