Hi and welcome to the curriculum overview.
Just a quick video to show you
what we're gonna be building in this course.
We're gonna build projects
and we're always going to be working with a project.
The first project we'll build is a movie collection system
to manage your movies.
We'll learn about Python basics,
how to interact with users
and send them data and get data back.
We'll also learn about if statements to control
the flow of our programs and also about functions and loops.
Functions would allow us to structure
our programs nicer and loops will allow us
to repeat things over and over again.
Then we move on to project number two,
which is gonna be a library manager.
Here, we'll learn about object oriented programming,
which is a cornerstone of modern software development.
We're going to learn about errors
and how to handle them in Python
and also, how Python does flow control using errors,
as well as if statements as we learned earlier on.
We'll learn about files and how to store things
and we'll also learn about relative imports
and import errors.
Then we do an extension to this project
that will include database interactions, context managers
and type hinting, which is a new feature in Python 3.6.
Now after this project, we move onto web scraping.
Web scraping is just extracting data from websites
so that we can use it in our own programs
and we're gonna learn a bunch of these skills
in order to do that.
We're gonna look at built-in functions, generators,
regular expressions, working with date and time,
advanced data manipulation,
as well as some external libraries
that we'll need in order to perform web scraping.
Throughout the entire course,
as well as building these projects,
we'll also be learning a lot of advanced Python knowledge.
One of the topics you need to this course
is that we'll be covering
how to do asynchronous Python development,
which is usually a very confusing topic
that we will cover in depth.
We'll learn about how to use Python in the wild,
how to manage your projects with Python,
how to do web development using
a very popular library called Flask
and we'll also learn about algorithms and data structures
on how to implement those with Python.
This is very useful for interviews, for example.
There's also a bunch of popular Python libraries
that you can use to do a whole host of other things
and we're going to look at some of those
so that you know more about what you can do with Python.
This is the most complete Python course available today.
We're gonna do concise explanations
with a little bit of theory,
then we're gonna give you a whole bunch of examples
and finally, you're gonna apply
your knowledge by building a project
and we're gonna do this over and over again
so you're always getting practical, up to date knowledge.
Thanks for joining me in this video.
I'll see you on the next one.