Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be running
a couple of things in the terminal,
just to show you how it goes.
What we looked at in the last video
is that if you have Python in your path,
you should be able to launch the terminal app on Mac,
terminal on Linux, or CMD.exe on Windows
in order to open up Python.
So let's do just that, I'm gonna type Python
and then press Enter, and as you can see,
I get Python 2.7 because that's the default on Mac.
Here we've got our Python interactive interpreter.
Python comes with this programme,
and essentially when you run it,
it just opens up an interpreter in Python
that you can type Python commands into,
and it will execute them immediately.
So you can type something like print hello world,
and it'll print it out to you.
You can define functions
and then as soon as you type the code wrong,
this realises that you're typing
a more complex command, and it gives you a new line
where you can type, make sure to press Tab
at this point to add the spacing
that the function needs, you know that functions
need to be indented more at the beginning.
Inside the block, and then you can
type Enter twice in order to execute the function,
then you can run the function and it will return the result.
This is pretty powerful, having an
interactive interpreter like this.
As you are typing Python code to include
the new programmes, very frequently
I'll have something like this open on the side
where I will copy and paste from my code
just to see that everything's working as intended.
Instead of writing a code and then running it,
and waiting for it to work,
you can make sure it works by putting it
here first, and checking it first.
This is something that I do very frequently.
Once you want to exit from this interactive interpreter,
instead of closing the window,
which is something you can do, of course,
you can press Ctrl+D, so that's gonna be
Control and D, and I'm gonna press
those two keys simultaneously and then
notice how CTRL+D gets printed out here
and this exits fully.
Now Python runs the default Python version
of macOS X, which is Python 2.7.
If you don't have macOS X, running Python
probably runs the Python version you've installed
at the start of the course, maybe Python 3.6 or 3.7.
If you are on Mac or on Linux,
and you've got multiple version of Python installed,
you can always type Python3.7, for example.
I believe this will work on Windows as well,
but Windows can be a bit picky with the things
that do work and don't work on a terminal.
As you can see, typing Python3.7 brings me
to Python 3.7.0 beta1, this is the early adopter version
of Python that I'm running,
and here you've got exactly the same thing as before,
another interactive interpreter
and now it's running Python 3.7.
What does that mean?
Well, it means you've got access to things
like f strings and things like that,
and not that you'd want to do this,
but just to show you that, in Python 3.7 now,
you have access to all the new Python features,
as you would expect, so if you're typing
a Python 3.7 code in your editor, in your programme,
you'll want to launch a Python 3.7
interactive interpreter in order to test out your code.
If you want to write your programmes in Python 3,
but you launch a Python 2.7 interpreter,
you may find that things
don't quite work as you would expect,
so that's something to keep in mind.
Again, I'm going to exit this interpreter
by pressing Ctrl+D, and now I'm going to show you
a command that is only available in macOS X and Linux,
but it can be used to look at what,
where rather what programme you're running
when you type Python3.7.
See when you type Python3.7 in your terminal,
what's actually happening is that
you're looking for the Python 3.7 programme
across all your folders in your path, okay?
So I'm gonna print out the path,
and you can see that the first folder here
is this Library Frameworks Python.Frameworks Versions 3.7
build, then a colon separates this folder from the next.
When I type Python3.7, I wanna type which before it,
it tells me what programme I'm running when I type Python3.7,
and that is this programme.
This programme is inside Library,
the Library folder, Frameworks folder,
Python.framework versions 3.7 bin,
so you can see matches exactly the first folder in the path,
and then inside bin you've got python3.7.
So this tells us that the python3.7 programme exists
within our path and it also tell us
where exactly in our computer it is.
If you type which of something that isn't
in your path, like asdf, it just won't say anything.
So this is a good way to check
whether you've got things in your path or not.
Similarly, if you type asdf, it'll tell you
come on, not found, so yeah.
If it's not in your path, you'll get a command not found
or similar error in Windows and in Linux.
Now that we know a little bit
about how to actually do this in the terminal,
we can go and look at how we can create
and manage our projects using the terminal
with a couple of tools that we're
going to be introducing in this section.
I'll see you on the next video.