Hi, and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to look at Pylint
and what it is and how you can use it.
What I've done is I've created
a new project here in PyCharm,
and I'm going to show you some code
that Pylint would complain about.
I'm gonna create a file called app.py.
And then we're gonna do something like,
app is flask name,
if name equaled main, and app.run.
So, you can see that there are
a couple of mistakes in this code, I'm sure.
And first of all, we've got flask here,
but we haven't imported FLask at the top of the file.
And we also forgot to put our colon after the if statement.
So, this is not valid Python code, exactly.
But PyCharm realises that we probably wanted
to write Python code, because our file ends in .py.
And therefore, instead of just saying,
this is complete gibberish, it says
you may have made a couple of mistakes.
Of course, maybe we didn't make a couple of mistakes
and maybe this another programming language
that is very similar to Python, that isn't actually Python.
And this would be fine but under the assumption
that we are coding in Python,
this has a couple of problems in it.
Which is that we've forgotten to import
FLask, or rather, FLask is something that Python
doesn't know what it is, it could be a variable.
For example, you could of course define FLask here
to be something else.
And then it wouldn't complain about
FLask not existing.
It would complain about, you're calling
this using the brackets, but this is a string.
So, it doesn't know what you're doing.
And so, anyway, this is the current problem.
Is that, FLask is not defined.
That means we've either
forgotten to import it or we've forgotten to define it.
And also, there's a clear problem here,
which is we've forgotten a colon.
And Pycharm tells you, you've forgotten a colon here.
So, PyCharm has a way of somehow determining
that these two things here are problems.
Right.
And, this is a computer programme, it as such,
it must have some sort of other programme or some code
inside PyCharm that tells us
that these two things are problems.
And PyCharm has its own way of doing this,
but there are more standard ways doing this
outside of PyCharm.
There are ways of finding out
problems within a file outside of PyCharm.
And that's what a linter is for.
A linter essentially goes through your file
and applies a bunch of rules.
And if any of your lines failed that rule,
it says there's a problem here.
In this case, it would go through these files
and it would say Flask is not defined.
And then, it would go through this one and say
you're missing a semi-colon, a colon there.
So, lets go ahead into a terminal and
we're going to instal the most popular linter in Python.
And we're gonna run it through this file,
and we're gonna see what it says.
Let's open up a terminal just now.
We've got a terminal here, and the first thing we're
going to do is, we are going to navigate to the folder
that contains our file that we've just written.
So, if you remember, we are going to do c, d, and
then we're going to type out the path
that will take us to our folder.
So in my case, that's in Dropbox, teclado, courses,
complete Python course, section 18.
That's where we are now.
And then we're in video code Pylint, and end.
So this is the path to my project.
And notice how the project is called end,
that's just before we structure the code
for the course a bit better.
Then, if we type l, s, or dir, if you're in Windows.
You'll see that you've got app dot p, y, in here.
So, this is where our file exists in our disc.
You can of course, navigate to this path using
a visual or a graphical explorer,
like Windows Explorer, or Finder.
But in order to run the linter,
we're gonna need the terminal.
So, let's navigate using the terminal,
and then instal Pylint.
If you only have one version
of Python installed, i.e you've never installed Python
other than a single version, you're gonna do
pip instal Pylint.
If you have multiple versions
of Python installed, make sure to select
the right one with pip.
So, that may be either pip three,
if you have two version of Python installed.
One Python two and one Python three.
Or, it may even be pip three point six, if you have
multiple versions of Python three installed.
We've gone through this earlier on in the course.
So again, just a brief reminder here.
In my case, I'm going to instal Pylint using
Python three point six, because that's the
latest version of Python in which Pylint works.
At time of recording, Pylint did not work in
Python three point seven.
So just something to keep in mind.
It's possible that by the time you're watching this
it already does work.
So, we're gonna do pip three point six, instal Pylint.
And then my guess it that it's gonna tell me it's already
satisfied because, I've already got it installed.
But if you don't have it installed, it'll tell you.
And the progress would eventually instal it.
The next thing you want to do, is type out
which Pylint, and that, because when you instal Pylint
using pip, is actually going to put an executable programme
in your path.
So, you will be able to do which Pylint
and this Pylint here is the Pylint programme
that we can now run.
And if here you get, programme not found,
or you don't get anything, then make sure that Pylint has
been installed correctly.
And make sure that the
three point six slash bin Python folder is in your path.
Again, we looked at this earlier on in the course,
I believe it was section 13.
So just go back if you need
to remind yourself as to how this works.
But if you get something here when you type which
Pylint, which by the way I'm not sure it works on Windows.
But none the less, if this works, or if you can just
type Pylint, and you get something out.
That means Pylint is working, it's installed correctly.
And what you get out when you type Pylint, is just the help.
Sort of telling you how it works
and how you run it and so forth.
For the majority of your runs,
you won't need all of these options.
All you have to do is Pylint,
and then give it your app.
So in this case I'm gonna type Pylint,
space, at dot p, y.
And it tells me the problems that are in the file.
So here it says no config file found.
So it's using default configuration,
and then it's saying in line 3, there's invalid syntax.
Saying syntax error.
So what we can do is we can go ahead
and open up the line 3 and see what happens there.
And you'll notice that it says, line 3, syntax error.
The fact that you've seen a syntax error in line 3,
should prompt you immediately to look at line 3,
and sort of, use all your brain power determining
what could the problem be.
Because PyCharm tells us that there's a colon expected,
we don't have to use much brain power.
But if you were using a different editor
that maybe didn't tell you that, you just have to
look at it carefully and make sure you haven't missed
anything that PyCharm would consider essential.
In this case, it's a colon.
So we can add our colon there.
And then, go back to our terminal and run Pylint again.
And now, we get a few more errors.
Notice that Pylint runs through the Python file first.
And it analyses that if you don't have valid syntax,
like the missing semi-colon, Pylint can not process
the file and can't tell you what's wrong.
So it only tells you syntax error if there's an invalid
syntax, like proper, invalid Python code.
But if you have valid Python code that's just missing
a few things.
It will be able to do that.
And now, here you can see that it says
three different things.
It says that its missing a module docstring,
the constant name app doesn't conform
to the uppercase naming style,
and also undefined variable Flask.
So, we can fix those three things.
Let's go back and start with the first one.
The missing module docstring.
Every file in Python,
should allegedly, according to Pylint, have a small
comment at the top that uses triple quotation marks.
Explaining what this file is about.
So we can write a short comment here, explaining
what app dot p, y, does.
There we go.
That was a bit more difficult than it should.
And that's it.
Now if we go back to Pylint and
we run it again, you'll see that now we only get two things.
Previously, our code had a score of minus 13.
Now, it has a score of minus 10.
So we're getting better.
Not very good though.
Now, we've got a constant named app
doesn't conform to uppercase naming style,
and we've got undefined variable Flask.
The undefined variable Flask is substantially worse
thing to have, than a constant name app doesn't
conform to uppercase naming style.
As you can see this here is a style thing.
This here, is a proper error.
So, we are going to go back
and fix the missing variable Flask.
Underneath the docstring, we can put
from Flask, import Flask.
Make sure you have Flask installed
if you're gonna copy along with me.
But none the less,
as you can see there's import Flask.
Now we don't have an undefined variable.
We can go back to Pylint and run it again.
And now you can see that our code actually goes
in the positive, and we get seven point five out of 10.
This means that the code is going to run,
and it will as we've done in the past.
But it says constant named app doesn't conform to
uppercase naming style.
Now, this is a style thing so you don't have to do it.
The same way as you don't have to add
a docstring to your file.
But what this is saying is you're defining app,
and then you're never doing
at any point in the rest of the file, app equals something.
So, you're never doing app equal anything else.
That means that app is a constant.
A constant that never changes.
And in Python, constants are by default always named
using all uppercase letters.
So be something like this yeah,
then if we go back to Pylint,
we will get a 10 out of 10.
It says no problems, your code has been rated 10 out of 10.
Which is awesome, essentially.
In Flask, this is actually not a very common thing to do.
Normally, you would name your main app as app, in lowercase.
But, Pylint doesn't quite like that.
So, just wanted to say that the style is something
that varies depending on the language you're using
and the people you're working with and so forth.
And also, you can name your variable as an
all uppercase thing here,
but if you then potentially want to make changes.
The linter doesn't know that.
The linter doesn't know that in the future
you're gonna want to change this variable.
So, if you only have this code
it says, this is a constant, use all uppercase
if you then wanted in the future to make changes,
like say, app equals five, this would now be
sort of, invalid style.
You should have used lowercase letters.
So, the linter isn't all powerful and all seeing.
It just makes recommendations.
And often those recommendations are things you
should really listen to.
And, especially if those recommendations
are problems within your code
that you have to fix, otherwise it won't run.
But the style recommendations can sometimes be ignored,
if you prefer.
Okay, notice that a reminder, PyCharm has it's own linter.
So you don't have to
use Pylint if you are working with PyCharm.
But some people like using other IDEs that maybe
don't have such good error handling, as PyCharm does.
And in those cases, using Pylint can be very useful.
So, that's it for this video.
Just wanted to show you quickly how to use
a linter in Python.
Hope you enjoyed it, and I'll see you on the next one.