Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to learn about
two Python keywords, and and or.
Let's start by asking the user for their age,
then we're going to determine whether the user
has a age good enough to learn programming,
so what we'll do is, can_learn_programming,
and we'll say age is greater than zero.
Here we have created a boolean comparison,
age greater than zero,
and we have given it a name, can_learn_programming,
however, sometimes users can be too old
to learn programming, so we can use the Python keyword and,
and for example, age less than 150, and what this does
is it says if the age is greater than zero
and the age is less than 150,
then the whole thing is true.
If the age is not greater than zero
then the whole thing is false,
and if age is greater than 150
then the whole thing is false.
So, if we enter our age here, then we will get,
You can learn programming: True.
By the way, let me say at this point,
there is no limit to learning programming,
you can learn programming at any age,
and that's because programming is all about problem solving,
and it's not really all that much about learning syntax
or working with any difficult tools or anything like that.
Alright, now that we've got and out of the way,
we're gonna learn more about it in just a moment,
let's ask the user again for their age,
and now we ask them whether they are usually retired,
so we will have usually_not_working,
and this will be if the age is less than 18,
people are usually not working,
or if the age is greater than 65,
people are usually not working because they're retired.
So then we can print, At age, you are usually not working,
and then usually_not_working, like that.
So let's run this, and if we enter 34, then we will get,
At 34, you are usually not working: False.
If we run it again and we type 10,
At 10, you are usually not working: True,
although you are going to school,
which is pretty complicated as well at times.
Now, there is a small problem with this boolean,
usually you don't want to write booleans as negatives
because it can get quite confusing to read later on,
so ideally, you would want to have usually work instead.
If you have a boolean like this,
then it's easier to think about, just the same way
that in English, double negatives can get quite confusing,
in programming, working with negatives is an added strain
on your brain that you want to avoid generally.
So, we can rewrite this to usually_working,
and what that means is that they have to be
age greater than or equal to 18,
or age less than or equal to 65,
and that is when people are usually working.
So if we run this then we write 65 then,
At 65 you are usually working: True,
so that's unfortunate, but that is how it goes these days.
So, how does it work internally?
Here we've got another function called bool,
this is similar to int and str in that it takes in the value
and converts it to a boolean,
so what will we get if we turn 35 into a boolean?
Well, you get True.
So, what if you turn the string Rolf into a boolean?
Well, you get True as well.
So what happens if you change these
to zero and empty string?
Now you get False.
So in Python, there are some values that,
when converted into a boolean, evaluate to True or False.
Most values evaluate to True, but things like zero, 0.0,
empty string, things like that evaluate to False.
So here's how and and or work for real.
If you have True and False, what and is doing
is it's gonna look at the first value, is it True,
and if the first value is True,
then it's gonna give you the second value.
So, we will say x equal True and False, and then print x,
and what this is gonna do is, again, look at the first value
it's True, so it gives you the second one,
so if we print x, you get False,
and this is very easy to double-check
with something that isn't True and False,
so we'll do 35 and zero, and again,
it's gonna look at the first value,
it's gonna look and see if it's True, and if it is,
then it's gonna give you the second one, so you get zero.
Remember, it knows that this is a True value
because if you pass it through bool, it evaluates to True.
So and, the way it works is it gives you the first value
if it is False, if the first value is True,
then it gives you the second value, so if we put zero first
and 35 after, again it gives you the first value
which is the zero.
Or works in slightly the opposite way.
Or will give you the first value if it is true,
otherwise, it will give you the second value.
So, if the first value is True,
it will give you the first value,
otherwise, it'll give you the second value,
so here it gives you the 35 because 35 is True.
And if you do the other way around,
zero is False so it gives you the second value, again, 35.
You can use this in quite a lot of places actually,
for example, imagine you've got a name and a surname,
and it just so happens that the user
hasn't given you their name, so you can do something like,
greeting could be name or Mr. Surname,
assuming that you know that the person's
gonna be man of course.
So you can then run this, and you get Mr. Smith.
Why?
Because name is an empty string, which means it is False,
or it is False to you when you pass it through bool,
so instead of giving you the first value,
the or gives you the second value.
This is even better if you add in user input.
Let's run this again, and now I'm going to not give them
my name because I care deeply about my privacy,
so I don't want to give them my name,
but I will give them my surname,
and then it prints out Mr. Salvatierra there.
So, situations like this one,
which may seem useless to you at the moment,
are actually all over programming,
so knowing how and and or work internally
can be really useful.
So again to recap, and gives you the first value
if it is False, and otherwise it gives you the second one,
and or gives you the first value if it is True,
otherwise it gives you the second one.
Finally, you've also got not, and that essentially
does the opposite, so not False is gonna be True,
and not True is going to be False.
So this is how the not keyword operates,
it goes in front of a boolean and it does the opposite
of whatever that boolean is,
so for example, not bool of 35 will give you False,
because bool 35 is True, so not True is False.
If you do not of 35, you also get False
because Python realises that not is something
that you use with a boolean,
so it turns the 35 into a boolean before applying not.
I appreciate that this video
has been a little bit confusing,
do bear with me as we go into
more advanced programing territory,
and if you have any questions,
ask them away in the course Q&amp;A, we're always there to help.
Thanks for joining me in this one,
and I'll see you in the next video.