Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to look
at sorting through our books
to find only the best books by rating
and by price.
Then, in the next video we're going
to add that to a menu.
For now, we're going to make our app
return or, rather, export these books
so that we can import them from our menu.
So we're gonna delete this for books, for booking books
and we're gonna end with this books being equal
to page dot books.
In Python, every variable that you see here,
requests, all books page, page content,
page and books are automatically exported
so that anybody else can import them.
For example, as another example
of what's happening here,
if we go to our all books page,
you can see that it creates a few things,
it creates this class all books page,
this books parser, all books page locators
and beautiful soup.
These four things are all available
sort of at the top level of the file.
When you go into app.py,
you could import beautiful soup,
it would be a weird thing to do
but this is something you can do.
And so the purpose of me telling you this
is as soon as you create a variable
like books equal page dot books
which the result of launching this scraper
you know and getting all that data out,
this variable can now be imported
by another file.
When that file tries to import books,
we will run through this entire file,
end up calculating books
and be able to import.
So let's go over and create a new file
that I'm going to call menu in the top level
and from app we're going to import books, okay?
Then we're gonna
define a function print best books for example.
What this is going to do is it's going to sort
the books that we've got here,
this list of book parser objects
and it's only gonna give me the top five books,
which means they're gonna be the five star books,
some of them at least are going to be five stars.
Okay, so the best books are going to be
and what we need to do here is sort the books
by their rating, so what we're going to do
is say sorted books
and the key
is going to be lamda x, x dot rating.
Okay.
All this does,
oops sorry about that,
all this does is it takes the books list
or the collection and it sorts it
for every element it's going to look at this key function
to see what it's sorting by
and in here we're telling it to sort by the rating property.
So what it's doing is it's getting the first book,
calling this function on it,
that's gonna give it the books rating
and then it's gonna sort by that,
so we're gonna end up sorting, you know,
with this rating key.
Then we can say for book
in best books, print.
Now this is going to give you a list of books
because that's what we gave it in.
So if you wanted, you could slice this list
to only get the top say 10 books.
Just like so, as we know from our list slicing.
Now of course we must run
this function in order for it to do something
and again just to recap, the first thing
we're gonna do is we're gonna import books
from the app file so that's gonna go over
to app and it's gonna run app
and it's going to go through all of this,
this is going to take a while
'cause it has to get the books page
and sort of parse through it
and eventually it's gonna end this
and then we're gonna import books
which is now gonna be available
and then we're gonna sort them and print them out.
So let's right click our menu and run it.
And there you have it, now we get 10 books
that are all one star.
By the way, a small side improvement you could try
is this one stars, it should probably be one star
without the S but you do want the S if you have many stars,
so this is a small improvement you can try out if you want.
Notice how all these books have one star,
one star, one star, two stars, two stars, three stars.
So we are sorting by default here on ascending okay?
And the easiest way to sort in a descending way,
is to multiply this by minus one.
Now, instead of starting at one and going up,
we're gonna start at the lowest number and go up
so instead of one to five, we're gonna sort
from minus five to minus one, which is gonna
give us the order that we want.
If we run this again,
you can see now we get our five star books
and then our four star books
and our three star books.
Okay, I hope this makes sense.
All we're doing is we're essentially reversing
the order of things.
This is how you could get your best books.
If you wanted your cheapest books,
it would be exactly the same thing really.
So much so that I'm going to copy
and paste which is not something you should do.
And now instead of sorting by rating,
multiplied by minus one,
we're gonna sort by price and that's gonna give you
your cheapest books.
I'm gonna use a PyCharm shortcut here
which is shift and the F6 key
and that's gonna allow me to
rename all the usage
of this variable everywhere in this function
so as you can see this one got renamed as well.
So that's shift F6, if you're interested.
We can also print the cheapest books now.
And you can see there,
that we get, this starts here,
this is the cheapest book, or is it?
Yeah, it's possible that this one is the,
this one must be the cheapest book.
This one here is where it starts,
this is the cheapest book and then it goes up
to 17, 17.20 and so far up until 37.
If you wanted to make it a bit more obvious,
you could print
something like that.
Just so it's a bit easier
to see where it starts and where it ends
and these are indeed the cheapest ones.
Notice how there's little correlation
between the quality the book and price,
in terms of the star rating because this page is random,
okay the prices and the stars are assigned randomly
so there's no logic that goes on in here.
Okay?
Now if you wanted
to sort by multiple things,
you can also do that
so that's something you can do as well.
Let's have a look at how to do that.
All you've gotta do if you want to sort by two things
is instead of returning here the value
that you wanna sort by, as you can see here,
we're sorting by best so only by stars,
so 44 point, 54.23 at the start.
You can actually, don't do that,
you can return a tuple
of things and it's gonna sort by this one first
and if it finds a few books that have the same rating,
it's gonna sort them by price
and you can continue adding keys here
if you want so if we run this again,
now you can see that we get the cheaper
book in front and its cheaper book as well
until we get to the more expensive ones, okay?
But these are all five stars,
then you have a cheaper book here,
but it's four stars.
So the most important sorting criteria was the stars
because that was the first thing in our tuple,
the second most important was the price, okay?
So this is how you can do multiple sorting
if you need to.
So that's pretty useful.
Okay that's it for this video,
I just wanted to show you
how to do the sorting of these books.
Now we're gonna look at constructing the menu itself.
I'll see you in the next video.