Hi and welcome back.
In this video we're going to be constructing our menu.
It's going to be really straightforward.
What we're going to do is we're gonna give the user
some choices to make.
And I'm gonna paste in here,
what exactly the choices gonna be.
So let's say the user has these choices.
They can enter one of the following,
the character B to look at five-star books,
the best books, C to look at the five cheapest books,
or the 10 cheapest books,
N to just get the next available book on the collection,
let's say catalogue here instead
and they can type Q to exit.
And then they gonna enter their choice.
So you know exactly how to do this now.
You have all the tools you need,
this one here has not been implemented for you,
how to get the next available book on the catalogue,
but I'm sure you can use generators to do this.
So give it a go.
Try to implement this menu yourself.
Allow the user to get cheapest books, five-star books,
the next book and also run that on a loop,
so that they can always exit the application.
I hope you managed.
Let's get started on creating our menu.
So down here I'm going to create our menu property here.
And I'm gonna say user input is input of user choice,
while the user input is not Q, we're going to run our menu.
So we're gonna say if user input is equal to B,
we're gonna print the best books.
And if the user input is equal to C, we are gonna print
the cheapest books.
And if the user input is equal to N,
we're going to somehow get the next book.
We're gonna implement that in a moment.
Else we're going to print, please choose a valued command,
I think that's a reasonable thing to do
and finally we're gonna once again,
give them the choice to give us another thing
that they wanna do.
Then at the very end,
we're going to, from the menu.
Let's implement the get next book function.
All that we have to do, in order to get the next book,
is create a generator on the books.
And then get next book
can just print out the next of that.
That is how simple it can be using generators.
You don't have to worry about, you know,
what was the last book you looked at, or keeping an index,
or something, or how many books you've gone through, no.
Just create a generator for the list, very efficient,
because it doesn't actually do anything,
until you start getting the next book.
So it doesn't take up any memory,
or not a lot of memory, it's not completely free,
but it's essentially free.
It doesn't take up any processing power.
Every time you press next, it just gives you
the next book in that.
Generator it doesn't actually go through the entire list,
or anything like that.
So that's a great way of setting up this
getting the next of something.
Let's run it and see what happens.
I get to enter one of the following,
let's type B and then I see sort of the best books in here.
Five-star books, four-star books, it's pretty awesome.
Maybe I wanna buy one of these.
C you can look a the cheapest books,
just in case you're wanting to spend a little less money
on a book, some of them are not so good,
but you know others are pretty good,
so maybe you can find something good there.
And if you just wanna go through the books,
just press N and then you get one, "A Light in the Attic",
N again, "Tipping the Velvet", it's not a very good one,
"Sous Michon", I guess that's French,
or maybe it's some sort of weird submission thing.
That's also not very good.
And that's it.
Now you cannot go back on the catalogue,
I'll leave that to you to implement.
But this is how you can see the different things
that are in the catalogue.
I guess you could go back just by scrolling up.
So that works too.
And you can press Q to terminate.
Okay so there are a few more improvements we're gonna make
on this project.
This first improvement we're gonna make
is we are going to scrape all of the pages in the catalogue
not just one.
That way we're gonna get a much larger collection.
So we're gonna look at how to scrape multiple pages,
how to go through the different pages of this site.
And we can also add logging, just so it's a bit easier
to spot when things go wrong
and also what's goin' on in the programme.
I'd encourage you to try to do these two,
particularly the logging,
because we've already looked at logging,
you know it's quite simple.
All you have to do is import logging,
set up the logger and start logging in different places.
I'd encourage you to do that.
And try to set up the looking at different pages if you can,
but if not just wait and we will do it here.
For the logging,
one of the most important things about logging
and why I'm recommending that you do it
is deciding where to log and what to log.
Because you can log at every line
and that's gonna make your code look really ugly.
Or you can log too little
and then you're not gonna get enough information.
So definitely keep an eye out for that.
Try to implement the logging yourself,
then we'll go back in the video and do it here
just so you can see how much I would log
and where I would log.
That's it for this video.
So I'll see you on the next one.