Hi and welcome back.
I'm really excited to guide you
through turning our scraper into an async scraper.
We're gonna see a few things that
may be a little bit surprising throughout this video
but generally, you're gonna see
massive performance improvements
from doing this.
We're gonna start with re-implementing
our functions in order to make them async.
So, we're gonna have our fetch page
and our get multiple pages in here.
I'm going to go to the async request
and just copy them because they're gonna
be exactly the same, that's the reason
why we've covered these two functions
is in order to allow you to reuse them
throughout any project.
Of course, we've got a few imports missing
so let's make sure to import them.
We no longer need requests, so we can get rid of that.
We can import asyncio, aiohttp,
async_timeout and time.
Time is just for the timing,
we can remove it later on if we want.
Notice how we've got this requests page here
so actually, we do have this separate requests
in there just to get the number of pages
that we're gonna request.
Remember we started at one
and we got up till page count.
So actually I revert what I said earlier,
we still need import requests.
And that's totally fine,
you can have synchronous code surrounded
or joined by asynchronous code side by side,
that's totally fine.
I just forgot we were doing this
to get the number of pages, this is okay.
You could potentially turn this into an asynchronous request
but because it's a single request that we're doing first,
in order to get the count,
it doesn't make sense to treat this asynchronously,
after all it's just one request,
you have to wait for it to finish
before you can get the data.
So there's no benefit from running
one thing simultaneously as itself.
So this is gonna still be synchronous,
that's okay.
And then we're gonna have our two functions here
in order to fetch the page and get multiple pages
and then we can call them down in our loop.
Notice how our loop is iterating
over the page count and then it's gonna get
each URL using requests.
We no longer want to do this.
We no longer want to iterate over the range
and get each page, now what we want to do
is get all the URLs and pass them into our multiple,
get multiple pages function.
So what to do is to copy this
and put it in a list comprehension.
Like so
and you can call them
URLs for example.
Again all we're doing here, and by the way I'm gonna
close the side bar just for your benefit there
so we have a bit more room.
What we're doing here is just putting this
inside the list comprehension between the range
of one and the count.
Exactly the same as we were doing here
but except we're no longer iterating over it,
we're just creating the URLs.
Then we're gonna start a timer,
just to check out how long it takes.
I wanna do pages equal
loop dot run until complete,
get multiple pages with the loop that we create
and all our URLs.
We're gonna create the loop at the top,
that's just sort of the normal thing to do,
to create the loop at the top.
We're gonna say loop is asyncio dot get event loop.
That's all, now we can use this loop
to run things until they're complete, okay?
Then at the end, we can print that it took
some amount of time.
Print.
Total page requests took time dot time minus start.
Okay?
Now these pages,
what is the value of them?
Because the loop has ran this thing here
until it completed but this thing here
returned an await of the grouped tasks.
So what is the result?
Well fortunately, this works
exactly as you would hope.
These grouped tasks, which is this gather thing
then gets returned as individual
elements in a list of the results
of all the tasks that were ran.
Notice how each task returns the response dot status?
So in this return grouped task,
what we're gonna get is a list of statuses
for each page that returned.
Okay they could be in order,
they could not be in order depending
on how long each one took, okay?
So instead of returning the response status,
we're gonna return the response text.
That's just the HTML contents of the page
but because this can take a while to download,
aiohttp actually, let's just await it,
so that we can suspend before we start downloading
and resume once download has completed.
So really great stuff there.
Now that we are awaiting the response text,
these pages here are actually going to be
a list of all the pages that we've downloaded
using our tasks.
So what we can do then,
is say for page content in pages
and here is where we're gonna create our all books page
and extend our books list so we're gonna
copy that there.
And that's it.
This is all we need in order
to make this code asynchronous.
Okay, so let's
cut that off and run this
and see what happens.
Bringing back this side bar here,
we're gonna right click the menu and run it.
And you can see what's happening here,
it is not so fast.
It is in fact pretty slow, what's going on?
Google was so much faster.
And you can see that, they didn't all run at the same time
you know there's one here that took point 23 seconds
and then there's one here that says it took eight seconds.
And you know the first thing I saw this when
I was preparing the notes for this course,
it actually took me a wee while
to realise what was happening, I thought
why is one of them taking point two seconds
and the other one is taking eight seconds?
I thought, are we maybe running these not asynchronously
are we doing something wrong?
But as we've seen we've just
literally copied what we did earlier
that did work for Google.
So this is the reason why we copy and pasted this code
just to make sure that it was all correct,
sometimes it can be a bit difficult
to debug and find out the issue
with asynchronous code just because you know,
you're suspending you're resuming many times
throughout various functions, especially
if you have something like 50 functions like we do here,
all suspending and resuming it can be difficult to debug
if you use PyCharm's debugger.
So it's easier to start simple,
start small like we did earlier on
in our async request file
and then try it out with a larger thing
and the problem here is just that
the books dot to scrape server
doesn't allow us to do all these requests at the same time.
It just does them one by one
and they return one by one and because we've sent him
50 at the same time, the first one is gonna be quick
but then it's doing the first one
and when that's done, it's doing the second one
and so forth, so by the time it's getting to the end,
what you're essentially looking at is the sum
of all the requests you've done.
Each one takes around point 23 seconds
so the first one take point 23,
the second one takes point four, point six, point eight
so forth, so just gets added each time.
You can see that it's returning them one by one.
So this is a problem with the thing
we're scraping, not with our code
which is a good thing.
If you were to scrape a page
that isn't a test page, something like
Craigslist or GumTree,
or John Lewis or some big reseller like that,
some big department store,
you'll see that these will all
come back at the same time, okay?
And if we changed this
to google.com again, just to go back to what we know
and run this again,
you can see that you know it's instant,
they are all running at the same time
it's just that the other one, the other page
doesn't let us get them all at the same time.
So we're gonna stop this, remember to stop your programmes
when you're running in PyCharm,
it can be something you forget.
So if we
were able to run our book dot toscrape.com asynchronously,
you'd expect it to take around point three seconds,
point four seconds in total.
But because it doesn't, it takes much longer.
Okay that's just a limitation of what
we're scraping, not of our code.
I'm assuming that when you're building your own
scraping projects, you're not going to be using
this test scraper, this test website,
you're going to be using a proper website
and that's almost definitely going to work just fine.
I've tried it with a bunch of other websites,
and they all seem to work okay.
So that's it for this video.
This is all you need to turn this
into an asynchronous scraper.
Remember the majority of our code,
creating the all books page you know and going through
and parsing and stuff like that, that's instant.
There's no waiting involved here, that's just Python
doing work, there's no waiting for somebody else
to give us things.
The only waits are happening
when we make the web requests and that's what
we're running asynchronously,
the rest of our code is running synchronously because
it doesn't need to run asynchronously it's really quick,
there's really no waiting time.
The performance here is not an issue.
So that's it for this video again,
thanks for watching and I'll see you on the next one.