Hi, welcome back.
I just wanted to give you a little bit of information
about Mac OS, if you're using Mac OS,
and https URLs.
As you can see here, we've requested http://google.com.
In our app, we've requested http://books.toscrape.com.
And we never made an https request.
For example, something like this one.
This is John Lewis's pretty big shop in the UK,
but its website has https.
If you have just now installed Python,
maybe at the start of the course or recently,
and you're using Python 3.6 or 3.7,
it's possible that when you run this programme it will fail.
Linked to this lecture I've got a bit of code
that you can run to see if your Python is set up correctly.
If running this code fails,
that means that you've got a missing piece of configuration
in your Python code.
This is fine if you are using Mac OS X.
Your Python doesn't come with a library that it needs
in order to essentially verify
that these domains are actually secure.
So, OS X, Mac OS X provides deprecated or older versions
of an important library for verification.
This library is called OpenSSL
and Python 3.6 and 3.7 got tired
of using these deprecated old versions,
so now Python 3.6 and 3.7, and probably older versions...
Newer versions as well, are shipping with their own version
of this library.
Because it's their own version, it means that
all the certificates, you know, keys and things like that,
that your computer trusts by default,
you computer says, johnlewis.com is, you know,
this is secure because this certificate was created
by this organisation that we trust.
Python doesn't trust those organisations by default
because it's a completely different library
than the one that comes in your computer.
So if you want to make Python
usable with https, what you have to do
is you have to instal something
that is inside your Python folder.
So I'm gonna bring it up.
What you want to look at is, you wanna find
your Python folder in your applications,
and notice how it's Python 3.6
and then I've got Python 3.7 here which is a new version,
there is a thing here called Instal Certificates.command.
All you have to do is double-click that.
When you do that, this will work.
Okay, so all you have to do is double-click that,
that is gonna instal the certificates
that you need in order to trust these secure domains.
Again, the code linked in this lecture has some more
information on why this is happening
and, you know, how you can fix it.
So that's it for this video,
just wanted to tell you about this
because it's a frequent problem when you start
making these requests and it can be a big pain in the ass
to solve, especially if you don't know
what you're looking for.
That's it for this video, I'll see you on the next one.