Hi guys, and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to learn about
default values for parameters.
Let's say you've got a function called add,
and it digs through numbers x and y,
and calculates a total, and then returns it.
Then, let's say we call it with
the values five and 10, and print it out.
So, if we run this, you get 15
because five gets assigned to x,
10 gets assigned to y,
and then the sum, 15, gets assigned to the variable total.
The value of the variable is returned,
and then that value is printed out.
In Python, you can say, y equal three, for example,
and what that means is that
if you don't pass in this second value,
then it will be three by default.
So, you can call this function with a single value
if you prefer.
So, you can say, add
and just pass in five inside the brackets
and then y, because it doesn't have a value,
will take the value of three.
So, if we run this, you'll get eight.
Notice that you can still pass in a value if you want,
and that just means that y will be this value,
and it will not take the default value.
Also, let's take this opportunity to talk
about named arguments.
In Python, to make calling the function a bit more readable,
you can say, x equal three,
when you're calling the function.
And what this says is x, this parameter here,
will take the value three.
Y will still take the value three
because that's the default value.
If you run this, you'll see that the value is six.
You can say something like,
x equal five and y equals two,
and that's also totally fine.
Now the result will be seven.
And again, what this says is the parameter x
has the value of five,
the parameter y will take the value two.
Notice that this, here, is something we're doing
when we call the function.
So, when we use it.
And this, here, is something we do
when we define the function.
These are called named arguments,
and they're there so that when you call a function,
it's clearer what each number is for.
So, here the five is for x,
the two is for y.
But when you define a function,
y equal three means a default parameter.
So, if you don't pass a value, y will be three.
Even though the syntax are the same,
y equal three and y equal two,
they do mean slightly different things
depending on where you use them.
Something important to remember is that
you cannot do this.
If you do x equal five comma two,
you'll get an error.
And that's because the argument that doesn't have a name
cannot be used after an argument that has a name.
So, if the first argument has a name, such as x,
then all subsequent arguments also must have a name.
Otherwise it will give you the error.
The opposite can be done, though.
The first argument can not have a name
and the second one can have a name, and this is fine.
So, it just means that if the first one has a name,
the second one needs to have a name, too.
But if the first one doesn't have a name,
the second one can still have one.
So, that applies for all the arguments.
Similarly, if you just do y equal two,
Python knows that you want the value two
to go to the parameter y.
So, instead of three, which is the default value,
we will use two.
That's all well and good,
but we don't have a value for x.
So, Python will give you an error telling you that
you are missing one required positional argument.
A positional argument is just an argument
that doesn't have a name.
So, here, we have a named argument,
also called keyword argument,
and the x is a positional argument
if we do something, like, five.
So, you do need to provide a value for x
because it doesn't have a default value.
The same thing applies when
defining a function, by the way.
So, you cannot have x equal five comma y
because you've got a default value here,
but not here.
Default values must go at the end.
So, if one parameter has a default value,
all subsequent parameters must have default values as well.
So, this would also give you an error
because it says,
"non-default argument follows default argument."
Many functions in Python have these named,
or keyword, arguments.
For example, the print function.
Say you print one, two, three, four, and five.
What we're doing here is we're passing the value one
to the print function,
and then we're passing the value two to the print function,
and then three, and then four, and then five.
So, we're passing five different arguments
to the print function.
If we run this, you'll see that you get them printed out
with a space in between each.
But you can actually pass a special argument called sep,
and make it equal to whatever string you want.
And then, instead of the space,
it will use that separator.
That's what sep stands for.
So, here's an example of one of the built-in functions,
print, that has one of these named arguments
that you can use as well.
If you have a variable such as default y,
and you want to create a function that uses it
as one of its default values,
this is highly discouraged.
Here's this function which has a parameter x
and a parameter y with a default prop value of
the value of default y.
What this does is when Python reaches line three,
and it defines the function,
it remembers the name of the function, add,
and then it also calculates the default value
which is, at this point in time, three.
So, if you do add two,
that means that x will take the value two,
and y will take the value three.
If we run this, you'll see that five is printed out.
But if you now change default y to, say, four,
and then you add two again,
you'll see that five gets printed out again.
So, what this tells us is that
when Python defines the function,
it also stores the default value at the time.
So, even if you change the variable
that is the default value,
it will not change when you use the function.
It still keeps the value that was used
when you defined the function initially.
Therefore, it is highly discouraged to use
variables as default values because of this thing.
The fact that you use the variable
doesn't mean that this value is going to change
whenever you change the variable.
I'll say at this point,
be careful when using lists or dictionaries
as default parameter values.
That's because unlike strings and integers,
these will update if you change them inside the functions.
And this is due to a language feature called mutability.
It's not important for you to understand this now,
but just bear in mind that lists and dictionaries
behave differently than strings and integers
behind the scenes.
That's it for this video.
Hope you've learned something
and I'll see you in the next one.