Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're looking
at default values for parameters.
If you already know a bit of Python,
you may wonder why we didn't cover this earlier.
And quite simply the reason is that we didn't need it.
Now we do and we're gonna start looking
at a couple of instances where having default values
with parameters is gonna be useful.
So let's get right on it.
Whenever we call a function that has parameters,
we are expected to give it an equal number of parameters.
We already know this, so I'll show you some example code.
Here's some accounts, like a checking account.
Let's see, that has $1,958 in it
or pounds if you're in the UK.
3695.50 in your savings.
That's a pretty respectable amount of money.
Then we're gonna have a function add_balance,
which is going to take an amount,
which is going to be a float and a name,
which is going to be a string.
And it's going to return a float.
The reason I'm including it here,
the type hinting that we've looked at in the past.
Also, just for completeness, I am going to say function
to update the balance of an account
and return the new balance.
Include that log string in there
just so you know what this function's all about.
As you can see, this function, add_balance,
is going to update the balance of an account
and return the new balance.
The two arguments it takes are the amount
to increase the balance by
and the name of the account that we're gonna change.
Then it's gonna go over to your accounts global dictionary
and it's going to change it.
So, accounts name
plus equal amount
and then it's going to return accounts name.
It's going to return the new balance of the account.
Accounts name, for example, for checking
is going to be 1958.
Let's say we say 200 in here is gonna go,
increase it by 200.
I'm not even gonna try to do the math here.
Then it's going to return the new amount
of accounts name, so that should be a float.
However, what we can do, of course,
is add balance 500.00 to savings
and then print account savings
and it should tell us the new balance
which should be in the four thousands.
Oh, sorry, accounts savings.
As you can see, 4,195.5.
Notice how the zero at the end gets dropped,
but in my code I like having two decimal places
for currency just to keep things clearer.
What you didn't know that you could do is you can say
that by default, all new balances are going to go
to your checking account.
So the name here is going to be checking, by default.
And the way we do that is we add equal checking.
Okay, so the name is a string
and its' default value is checking.
That means that if we do not pass a string
through this argument, which we can do now,
we can not pass a string to it.
We can not pass anything to it
and we print out the checking at the end,
we should see it has increased by $500,
not 500 units.
If you don't wanna use type hinting,
then all you have to do is get rid of that.
Okay and this stays the same, name equals checking.
And that's that, okay.
Frequently, actually, if you don't have type hinting,
you'll see this written like so, without the spaces
and when you do have type hinting,
you'll see it written like so, all with spaces.
It's up to you how many spaces you want
to put in there, whether you wanna put spaces
or not spaces, totally fine.
Now, something important that you have to know
about these names arguments, this is what they're called
as soon as you have the default argument there,
is that you cannot have this
here, oops sorry,
you cannot have this here.
This will be illegal.
When you run it, it'll tell you here.
Syntax error, known default argument
follows default argument.
So you cannot do this.
Any argument that has a default value
has to follow arguments that do not
have default values.
So in this case, the amount
does not have a default value.
The name does, so the name has to go at the end.
If you have many arguments,
some of which have default values,
they must all go at the end.
Okay?
That's it.
This is default values for arguments.
You can have many arguments, many default values.
One default value per argument,
of course and we're gonna learn more
about these default values
and how to use them in subsequent videos,
in just a couple of videos.
In fact, in the next video,
and in coming videos too.
So, that's it for this one.
I'll see you on the next one.