In this video, we're going to be creating
our first programme that interacts with an API.
We're gonna need to instal the requests package,
so go over to your project interpreter
and press the plus icon
and instal the requests package.
If you've got it installed already,
because we used it in the past,
then that's fine, you can just keep that one
but I have created a new project,
so I have to instal it again.
Once that's installed,
just close that and press OK
and that's everything we'll need for this section.
So, let's go over and create our new file
which is gonna be called app.py as usual.
Now, we're going to need to import requests
and we will need to get our APP_ID in here,
so just copy what you had in your dashboard
in open exchange rates.
Next up, we need to go and look
at the open exchange rates documentation
to see what they can give us,
so if you go over to openexchangerates.org
and click on the documentation,
you will see the different parts of the API
that you can access.
You can read through this
and it's actually quite good documentation
but normally what you'll see
is a section called API endpoints.
So, these are the different things that you can access
in this API.
Essentially this is the data
that the API needs from you
in order to know what to give you back.
If we make a request to this address here,
then the API will know
that what we want is the latest exchange rates available
from the API.
So, it will return you those latest exchange rates.
This is what an API is.
It has a definition of what it accepts,
in this case, a request on this endpoint
and a definition on what it responds with.
And that is really what an API is.
So, if you make a request like this
to /api/latest.json,
then it will give you a few different fields
and all the rates that it currently has.
The base rate is always United States dollars,
at least in the free plan,
so you'll get all the rates parting from USD.
This ?app_id=YOUR_APP_ID
is called a query string parameter.
This is how we sent extra information
to APIs and to websites over the internet.
Just put a question mark
and then the key which is app_id
equal and then the value which is the value
of your app ID, so knowing this,
let's copy all of that here
and go back to PyCharm
and we're gonna say that the ENDPOINT is this one there.
Now we're gonna make a request,
so we'll say response equals requests.get
and we will go for the ENDPOINT ?app_id=APP_ID
and this builds out the address like we had
on the documentation and then the exchange_rates
will be the response.json
and we will access the rates value inside this dictionary.
Response.json gives us a Python dictionary
containing the response
and as you can see from here,
this dictionary has a key called rates.
So, we're accessing the rates key inside that response.
Next, let's try to convert $1,000 into pounds.
So, we will say the usd_amount
multiplied by the exchange_rates GBP.
Remember that the base rate of this response
is United States dollars
and that means that the GBP rates
inside this response is the equivalent
of $1, so by multiplying $1,000 by the rate,
you get something like 800 something pounds
and then we can print that USD usd_amount
is GBP gbp_amount.
Let's right click that and run it.
And you see down here
that you get USD1000 is GBP791.2.
Sometimes this number can get really long
depending on the division and how Python does it.
Don't worry too much about it,
we'll learn how to format this
to a certain number of decimal places
in a later video.
So, this is how you interact with an API.
Usually the API requires some form
of authentication or authorization.
In this case, the APP_ID is our form of authorization,
it's just a string that we include
and that tells the API that we are a valid user
when they receive it.
Then it also have a set of data that it requires.
In this case, all the data it requires
is the endpoint that we wanna access
and the app_id
and then it gives us back some data
that is already predetermined
and is always in the documentation or should be
in the documentation and that is the rates.
So, once you have the rates,
you can multiple the usd_amount by that
and get a pound amount or indeed, any other currency.
Thanks for joining me in this video,
I'll see you in the next one.