Hi guys and welcome back.
In this section, we're gonna have a Stata code,
which is the code from the last section,
the web scraping code.
Let's go over it real quick,
just in case you haven't seen it in a while.
We've got the entry point to our code, app.py,
and that makes the requests to quotes.toscrape.com,
which is just a quotes website
that contains some quotes by famous people
and gives us the HTML content of the page.
That HTML content is passed on to our QuotesPage class.
What that does is it creates a BeautifulSoup object,
which will allow us to traverse the HTML that we've received
and find things inside the HTML,
which is what we do down here in the Quote property.
We go into that BeautifulSoup object.
And we find elements, using the select method,
matching this selector here.
The selector is just any div in the page
that has the class, quote.
If you haven't seen the last section,
I would recommend going through that first,
just because it contains a bunch of explanations
that you will need for this section as well.
Now, after finding all the divs with that class with quote,
it passes them into a QuoteParser object that we also made.
And this one stores the parent,
which is basically the container of the quote.
And then, has if you properties, as well;
content, author, and tags.
The content property, once again,
gets a locator from QuoteLocators file in this case
and then, finds an element inside
this quote with that locator.
Same for author and tags.
So basically, what is gonna happen is
here we're gonna get a bunch of QuoteParcers,
one for each div,
and then, each of these objects,
we can use to get the content author
and tags of that quote.
Then, at the end, we print out the page quotes.
So you can actually run this just by right-clicking
and running app.py and it's gonna launch
and it's gonna give us all these quotes that we've got.
So that has actually launched the page.
Well, not launched the page, but it's gone to the page
and got the HTML content using the requests module.
And once we can the HTML content,
it returned it to us and we've performed our searches.
There's a problem, of course,
which is that if we use JavaScript, then this won't work.
Or if we were to navigate any other page
that uses JavaScript, this won't work.
I'll show you an example.
Here, I've launched another quotes.toscrape.com instance,
but this one is /search.aspx.
This is a slightly different page that uses JavaScript,
so we can use this to try out our JavaScript scrapping.
Notice that, if we were to use the requests module
to get the HTML content of this page,
we would get what the inspector
gives us at this point in time.
So we've got a couple drop-downs
and a search button that is now partially hidden.
I will move that a bit.
There you go, my search button down there.
Now that has a problem because the author drop-down,
that you can see, here has a bunch of authors inside it.
You can see them if you click on it
and you can see it in the HTML.
But the tag drop-down does not have any elements.
It is only when you select an author that the tags change
for tags that are available for this author.
So basically, you're gonna be able to only select tags
that match that author or things that the author sent.
Because that change happens after the page is loaded,
it means that our requests code
cannot deal with something like this for two reasons.
The first one is that the content of the page
is changing using JavaScript.
That is the only way to change page content
and when we load a page using requests,
we cannot execute JavaScript, so that is a problem.
The second problem is we cannot use the requests module
to interact with a drop-down inside the page.
The requests module allows us to get the HTML content,
so we would be able to see there is a drop-down,
but we won't be able to click on it and make a change,
so the requests code is not going
to allow us to use this page.
Then, if you click the search button,
a further JavaScript change happens.
That shows you a quote matching the results.
What we have to do is we have to actually
launch the Chrome browser, navigate to this page,
and modify these drop-downs ourselves,
then click the search button
and finally, extract the result.
So that's what we're gonna be doing in this section.
As I mentioned earlier on, we've seen the code as it is now
and that code as it is now is just for this page here,
which doesn't use JavaScript.
For our new page,
we're gonna be doing everything in this section,
so I'll see you in the next video.