Hi guys, and welcome back.
In this video we're going to learn about while loops.
Loops in programming are used to repeat things
a number of times.
And there are two types of loops in Python.
We've got while loops, and we've got for loops.
In this video we'll learn about while loops.
Let's start with a simple boolean.
We will have a variable called is_learning,
and we will make it equal to true.
So at the moment we are learning,
so we can type while is_learning,
print "You're learning!"
So this is our first while loop.
What we've got here is the while key word,
and then very much like an if statement,
we have a boolean, and this can be a variable
such as is_learning, which is true,
it can be a comparison, it can be a number or anything else,
then we have the colon which, just like in the if statement,
signals the start of the body, and the body
comes underneath that and is always indented with
usually four spaces, and then we have the print statement.
Again, just like the if statement, you can put
multiple things in the body as long as they're all indented,
and you can un-indent a line in order to signal
the end of the while loop.
I must say at this point that if you just leave it
like this, that's totally fine,
Python knows that you've reached the end of the file
so that also terminates the while loop,
but if you do want to add something else, you can do,
as long as it's un-indented.
Now what will happen if we run this while loop
is something maybe unexpected.
The while loop repeats this code in the body
for as long as this condition is true.
So for how long will this condition be true?
Well, here's the thing, this condition never changes.
It's always true because we don't set it
to anything else anywhere else.
So if we run this, you will see
that we're learning a lot, and we maybe
don't want to do that, we do want to take a break
every now and then, and you see that we've printed
a lot of these "You're learning!"
Which is good, but what if we only wanted to run this
a certain amount of times?
Say, until the user told us that they're no longer learning?
Well, in order to do that, in order to stop
this loop from running at some point,
we have to set is_learning to false.
So if we do that like this, is_learning equals false,
here's what will happen.
We will start the loop, is_learning is true,
so we will run it at least once.
We will print that "You're learning!"
and then we will set is_learning to false.
Then we go back to the top, and we will evaluate this again.
Now we will check if it's true again,
but it's not, it's false, so it will stop,
and it will continue from after the while loop onwards.
If it were true, it would just repeat over and over
as you've seen, but because we set it to false
the first time that we run it, it only runs once.
Just like that.
So what we do is instead we will ask the user
whether they are learning, we will say input,
"Are you still learning?"
And we will run this.
So now we'll see that "You're learning!" at least once,
because is_learning is true initially, and then
we ask the user whether they are still learning.
Now, what do we have to type here in order
to continue the loop?
Well, anything will go, such as yes.
That is because now is_learning is no longer true,
now is_learning is the string "yes" that we've typed.
And if you remember from our if statements video,
this gets passed through the bool function,
and it evaluates to true when it's yes.
The boolean of yes is true, but if we type an empty string,
then the loop ends because we have terminated the loop.
So maybe this is not what we want, maybe what we want
is to get some user input, and then say that is_learning
is equal to user_input == "yes".
And what happens here, is that first of all we store
the user's input into its own variable,
and then we compare it with the string "yes".
If they are the same, then this will be true,
and if they are not the same, then it will be false,
and we put that into is_learning.
So now, only if we type "yes" will the loop continue,
otherwise, if we type "no" for example, the loop will end.
This here is a very common way of doing user menus,
or running applications where users can repeat
something multiple times.
Here is an example of one such menu.
The first thing we do in this programme is
we get the user's input and we ask them
if they wish to run the programme.
Then, we have our while loop which checks
that the user_input variable is equal to "yes".
If it is, we will start the loop,
and we print that we're running.
Then we ask for the user_input again,
exactly the same thing.
And after that, we will go back to the start
of the while loop, and we will compare user_input,
which now has the new value, against "yes".
If they are still the same, then we run again,
and we ask again, and so on.
This is how you can repeat a piece of code
many times, until a user tells you to stop.
So when would you want to use a while loop?
When you want to repeat something
an undefined number of times.
For example, until a user tells you to stop.
You don't know how many times you're going to repeat it.
You depend on the user's input.
The for loop, on the other hand, will be used to repeat
something a defined number of times.
Let's learn about that in the next video.
I'll see you there!