Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video we're going to learn about first class functions in Python.
Functions are first class citizens and that means that just like strings and integers and anything else
really we can assign functions to variables and we can pass them in as arguments to other functions.
We're going to learn more about doing just that in a later video.
In this course.
But for now let's focus on assigning them to variables and using them as values in lists and things
like that and why that can be useful.
Let's get started let's say that we've got a greet function that prints hello.
You know that of course we can call the greet function and that's going to run it.
And the calling of the function happens when you use the brackets after the function name.
So what happens if you just use the function name.
Well we know that that's not going to run the function.
So we get no output but this is still valid python syntax.
What this does python is that we're talking about this function here about the value of the function
itself.
We don't want to run it but we aren't talking about it.
We are referring to it when we have a value just as a number a string or anything else including a function
we can assign it to a variable we can say this name here this Hello name is now a name for the value
that this references and that is the function.
So now after this line hello and greet are the same value and therefore that means that we can run the
Hello Function and you can see here that that's going to print out Hello.
This is what I mean when I say that a function is a first class citizen.
You can assign it to variables.
And as we learn you can put it inside lists or dictionaries or anything else like I mentioned earlier
you can also pass functions to other functions as arguments but we won't look at that until much later
on in the course.
And this is not a particularly useful example.
So let's move on to a more useful one.
Imagine that.
I want to create a function that calculates the average of a sequence.
So for example def average like that takes in a sequence and then returns the sum of sequence divided
by the length of the sequence
pretty normal function.
We've seen this before.
So we can recreate this as a lambda function just for shortness and we covered how to do this earlier
on there would be lambda seq is a sum of that divided by that.
So this is the same stuff just this one is as a lambda function.
The reason why I'm making this a lambda function and not a normal function is just because a little
bit shorter and these other functions that we're going to create here are also good lambda functions
just like that.
So now we've got three functions.
Average total and top.
The average one calculates the average total.
Calculate the sum and top calculates the maximum value of a sequence.
Now let's say we've got a list of students that I'm gonna paste in here.
We've got a list of dictionaries and each student has a bunch of grades associated with them and that
is a couple of numbers.
So that's let's say the grades that they got in an exam.
Let's use these functions now to operate on these grades.
How we do it is we'd say for student in students we're going to get the name as a student name and the
grades as a student grades just like that then we're going to print out the student name
and finally we're going to ask the user what they want to do.
Do they want to calculate the average of their grades.
The total of their grades or the top value that they got.
So we'll say that the operation is input and we'll ask them to enter either average total or top.
I'm sorry that this has gone into two lines that I'm just gonna move that a bit.
There we go.
So now we're going to ask for each student what the user wants to do with their grades.
Now comes the simple part which is to write an if statement that deals with this user input we know
how to do this we've done this a lot of times before.
If the operation is equal to average then we will print the average of grades.
So nothing new here we're saying that if the user entered the word average.
Exactly.
Then we're going to print the result of calling the a v g function which was defined up here on the
student grades which are each tuple for each student.
So let's just run this at this point and of course if we enter average then we get the average grade
for Roth.
If we enter average again then we get the average grade for Bob.
If we end does something else like total we get nothing because we haven't quoted that part of the if
statement yet.
Let me stop this here.
If we completed the other operations they would look like this.
If the operation is total then we print out the total.
Otherwise if it stop we print out the top nothing new there.
So how can we make this code a bit better a bit shorter a bit simpler.
The first thing that we have to realize is that we're asking the user to select what they want to do
using code language if you will.
And so what we're doing here is we're giving the user a few specific options and then we're selecting
one of those options that matches something in our code a function that we want to run.
Therefore if we can say select whatever the user entered and run the function associated with that that's
going to make our code a bit simpler.
So how do we create associations in Python.
We use dictionaries.
So we'll create an operations dictionary and we'll associate each thing that the user can enter with
one of the functions that we defined above
just like that.
So now we've got an operations dictionary that maps user inputs to functions and once we have that all
we have to do is get the operation function by saying operations operation.
So that is going to go into the operations dictionary and get us the key that matches the user's input.
So if they entered average then that's going to get us a VIP.
The ABC function not the result of running the ABC function but the ABC function itself and so on with
the others.
Therefore once we have the operation function we can call it with the student grades.
So now if we run that you'll see that we can enter for example top.
And we get one hundred which is the top grade for Ralf for Bob.
We can enter average and we get seventy six which is their average.
And if we enter something completely random like something else we get an error.
Now this is the compromise that we're making when we use a dictionary instead of an if statement with
a dictionary we're going to get an error when we're trying to access a key that doesn't exist.
But with an if statement we would not get an error there.
What we can do is we can use error handling to catch the error and print a nice error message instead.
But we're going to learn how to do that later on in this course.
Something else to remember is that we can make this code even shorter if we want.
And if we're comfortable with that by in lining the lambda functions into this dictionary I'm not entirely
sure how I feel about this.
I think it's getting a bit complicated but you can do it if you want.
With these functions that are relatively small and simple I think it's probably OK but if it gets more
complicated if your functions are doing more things you'll definitely want to separate them out and
use the operations dictionary to sort of compile them into one readable block of things that a user
can do in your code.
Something else that I wanted to mention at this point is that we've got here sort of like a proxy function
something that we define as a function that just calls another function with the same arguments.
So you can see that our function here is just receiving an argument passing it to the sum function and
calling that.
So instead of doing that we could just use the sum function directly.
Why.
Because now when we access the some function through these operations dictionary and we call it will
essentially be calling some of grades which is what we were doing before.
But just we've removed one layer of our own functions but wasn't really doing anything.
So that's just the small optimization thing you can do there.
You can use some and Max directly instead of coding your own lambda functions of course we can't do
that for this one because it's not just passing the argument to another function it's actually using
two functions there.
So we can do that there but we can simplify those too.
Now in lining the functions makes more sense because we're just using some buildings we're not really
adding any complexity.
All right.
I hope this makes sense.
I know it's a little bit tricky to deal with these first class functions but just remember any function
is just a value and it just so happens that if you put a better brackets after its name it's going to
run and it's going to execute the code inside it but you can still refer to them by name and use them
as values.
So I hope this has been useful and I'll see you in the next video.