Hi Guys, and Welcome back.
In this video I wanted to tell you about join.
Join allows you to print out your lists a bit better.
Imagine you've got a list of friends
and you wanna print it out in a string,
you wanna say something like,
my friends are friends.
If we run this, you'll see that you get my friends are,
and then square brackets,
and then string Rolf string
Anne string Charlie.
Maybe you wanna print it out a bit more nicely.
So what you can do create a new variable,
comma_separated, for example.
And then type comma space
dot join friends.
And what this is gonna do is
it's going to get the different values in this list,
and is gonna join them together
using the comma as the separator.
So here's what you'll end up with.
Let's see we print my friends are comma_separated,
and then we run this, you'll see that the output
is a little bit different.
Now you get my friends are Rolf, Anne, Charlie.
What's happened here is we've taken
each of the values of the list,
and we've made one long string
which is all of this stuff here.
The comma and the space is used as the separator
between values in a list,
but you can use anything else you want.
Now for example, that,
it won't be as nice to read, of course,
but just to show you that these are how it's printed out.
You can see my friends are Rolf and Anne and Charlie.
If you wanted this last one
to say and so that the output would be my friends
are Rolf, Anne, and Charlie,
you're actually gonna have to wait a little bit
because we need to learn a few more things
before we can do specific things
just with the last element of the list.
When we cover list slicing in the next section,
you'll be able to do that.
But for now, thanks for joining me,
I hope you've learned something,
I'll see you next time video.