Hi, and welcome back.
Once you've opened up PyCharm for the first time,
you'll get something that looks more or less like this.
If you get asked to import any settings
from a previous PyCharm version, just say "no,"
because you don't have any previous PyCharm versions.
Unless, of course, you do have a previous PyCharm version
that you want to import settings from.
But if you don't know what it means,
just say "no" or "cancel" or "exit."
Then make sure you open up PyCharm,
and you'll have a window that looks more or less like this,
or possibly like one we'll see in just a moment.
Nonetheless, what we wanna do is go into Create New Project.
Let's create a new project, and then you've got
two things that you have to pick:
the location of your project, where in your computer
this project is going to live, and also the Interpreter.
This is the Python version that
you want to use for this project.
Notice that, for example, macOS comes with
Python 2.7 already installed.
However, when you create a new Python project,
you can choose whether you want to use Python 2.7
or Python 3.6 that we've just installed.
Python works fine if you have multiple versions
all installed at the same time in your computer,
and it is on a per-project basis
that you'll choose which Python version to use.
So, you can instal Python 3.7 when it comes out,
alongside 3.6, and that's totally fine.
Let's pick out a location for our project.
So, what I'm going to do here is
I am going to go over to my desktop.
Now, okay.
So, I'll open up the desktop here,
and I'm going to create a new folder,
which is going to be called "milestone_1."
Now, my project is going to be in this folder here.
So any new files I create are going to appear
inside that folder, and basically all the contents
of the core of this project
are going to be inside that folder.
Make sure to pick out a folder that you like.
For the Interpreter, I have a lot of options here,
and you won't have so many options,
but what you wanna go and find is 3.6, presumably .4,
which is the one we've just downloaded,
or 3.7 or, you know, 3.5, or whatever version
you've got installed at the time of this video.
Now, the latest version currently is 3.6.4,
but I've got 3.6.0 installed, and, you know,
that's fine for the purposes of this course.
So, make sure you find 3.6.
Make sure you don't select an invalid one, if you have any.
Select only the valid ones.
And we'll look at why I have so many versions later on.
Then you can go and press Create.
And really, that's it.
So, a couple of things.
PyCharm shows you a tip of the day.
These things are pretty useful,
and it tells you some information on how to use PyCharm.
I recommend that you don't untick the box
so that every time you open PyCharm,
you get this, and maybe you can learn a thing or two.
So, I normally do read them.
I won't read them today.
Then, what we've got is our project here on the left.
If this was the first screen you saw
when you opened up PyCharm, you can always go over
to create a new project by pressing on File, New Project,
and that will let you create a brand new project.
Okay, then you've got a bunch more menu options,
and we're gonna be learning a lot about those
as we go through the course, so don't worry
if you don't know what they do just yet.
You've got the usual Edits, Undo,
Redo, Cut, and Copy, and so forth,
and they can be pretty handy in a lot of scenarios.
Then what we've got is our tree.
Here we've got our project, project files, problems,
and scratches, which is a really bad name.
We'll only be working with Project in this course.
This gives you the project files
and also any external libraries that we're using.
At the moment, this project is only using
one external library, which is Python 3.6.
That's the Interpreter we chose earlier on.
And our project is a folder called "milestone_1,"
that doesn't have anything inside it,
but we can add things to it.
For example, you can right click on it
and add a new Python file.
Then you'll get this dialogue, and you can choose
what type of file you're gonna add,
Python file or Python unit test.
Don't click on that just yet.
We'll look at that later on.
Just click on "Python file," and I'm gonna call it "app."
"App" how is created inside our project."
Look, we've got our file "app.py,"
and the ".py" has been appended at the end,
and that just means that this is a Python file.
The name, "app.py," can be anything you'd like,
but "app.py" is a pretty popular name
for your sort of main file in a Python programme.
Whenever you run your programme,
likely this is the file that you're gonna be running.
So, "app.py" is a pretty popular name,
and I advise that you go for that
for the main, most important file in your programme.
Now, over the next few videos, we're going to be looking at
developing our milestone project.
But first, of course, I'm going to give you the brief
so that you can tackle this milestone project on your own.
It's gonna be a challenge, and you may have to do
some research in order to do so, but please do.
Don't just move over to the next lecture.
Give it a go.
Try developing this application on your own first,
and doing that is going to ensure that you learn
much faster than just watching the video.
And also, I'm going to plug my laptop in,
because I'm running low on battery.
So with that said, I'll see you in the very next video.