Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to talk
about binary trees.
A binary tree, like a list or a set,
is another data structure
that we can use to hold some values.
However, it is structured a little differently from a list.
Let's have a look.
In the last video,
We looked at binary search,
where we started at the middle of our list,
and then sort of constructed an algorithm
that allowed us to search.
If you take the values that this algorithm comes up with,
you actually end up with a binary tree.
Let's have a look.
If you start at the middle of this list,
and you take the first value,
let's make that value the starting point of our tree.
So we'll just move it down.
And this is gonna be the starting point.
In binary search,
we then discarded one half of these values
and moved over to the middle of the remaining segment.
We're gonna do, without discarding any values,
we're gonna do that for both segments.
So we're gonna move over to the middle
of the remaining segments.
So we're gonna start in the middle of each segment here,
which takes us to seven and 59.
And we're going to take those two values,
and we're gonna make them appear underneath 38.
So this tree is now starting to be constructed.
38 has, sort of, what we say two children, seven and 59.
Seven is at the left,
59 is at the right.
If we do this again,
now we're gonna end up with four values,
because we're gonna move over
to the middle of the remaining segments in each case.
And once again,
we're gonna move these values down
and make them children of the previous one.
So now seven has two children,
59 has two children.
Once again, we're gonna repeat,
and get the half point of the remaining segments.
Now we end up with eight values.
And we move them down here.
And finally, there's not that many left,
there's not 16 values left,
so we're gonna move over to the remaining few values,
and we're gonna move them down as a group.
So, as you can see,
we end up with something that looks like a tree.
If we add the branches in, it becomes a bit clearer.
We have elements that have children below them.
And then a child can have children as well,
it can have two children,
or it can have one child.
And what happens is,
every node has an element,
or another node that is smaller than it to the left,
and an element that is bigger than it to the right.
Taking the example of 38,
it has the node seven to the left, which is smaller than 38,
and it has the node 59 to the right, that is bigger than 38.
So with this structure, we can very easily perform
a binary search.
So the binary tree is used to perform binary searches.
Let's look for the element 90.
90, you can see, is down there on the right.
To perform a binary search, now all we have to do
is start at the top of the tree,
and then decide whether we wanna go left or right.
Because 90 is bigger than 38,
we go right.
Then, because 90 is bigger than 59, we'll go right.
And now, 90 is smaller than 717, so we go left.
And that's that, we found it.
So it's just the same as performing a binary search.
The binary tree is structured this way
so that we can search easily
and we end up with smaller elements on the left,
larger elements on the right,
and we just have to sort of go through each.
Of course, the binary tree has to be ordered in this way
for it to work.
We're going to look at how to create binary trees
like this in the next few videos.
So once again, the binary tree is just,
well, you can think of it as a representation
of the ordered list after you perform a binary search on it.
If you take the list, and if you take
the binary tree left to right,
notice how the left most value in this tree,
the one on the very left is the number one,
and the next value to the right is the number three,
the next one is number four, the next one is number five,
and the next one number seven, and so forth.
So if you take the entire tree,
and you put it left to right,
when you end up with is, once again,
your sorted list.
So this is a pretty interesting piece of knowledge.
You may not find yourself using binary trees
all that often in your software development careers,
but nonetheless, they are sort of everywhere
when you do software.
You get them in data bases,
you've got them when you need
to search through a large list.
And so it's interesting to know about these binary trees.
In the next few videos,
we're going to learn about how to construct
binary trees, how to search through a binary tree in code,
and so on.
So, hopefully, what a binary tree is makes sense.
It's just a structure that has branches
with the larger branches to the right,
smaller branches to the left,
and then allows us to produce,
to very easily implement a binary search algorithm.
And that's it for this video,
and I'll see you on the next one.