Hi welcome back,
in this video we're gonna look
at how to keep our function names and docstrings
when we use a decorator.
It's really straightforward,
all we have to do is tell Python
that this function here
is actually wrapping around our original function, func
because that's what it's doing.
This function does a bunch of things
before running the original function
so you could think of it as a wrapper
or a bubble around the original function,
adding some functionality to it,
so if we tell it that this,
this function here wraps around this one,
it will say "ah, okay I understand,
"what you want to do is sort
"of extend the functionality of this function,
"but you still want to keep the name and the docstring,"
and in order to that, very straightforward,
all we have to do is import functools.
Function Tools is a package that comes with Python
and then add a decorator in here,
functools dot wraps func.
It's funny how you have to use a decorator
to extend the functionality of a decorated function,
but nonetheless, what this does is say
"hey, secure func, you are wrapping
"around this original function,
"so keep the name and the docstring."
Now when we run this,
we can see that the names that we printed out down here
are actually my function and another.
So that's exactly what we wanted,
we can now decorate multiple functions
and they're each gonna keep their name
and all is gonna be good,
particularly when we use some libraries and frameworks,
that look at the name of the function
as opposed to just the variable name,
we can have some problems if we don't do this,
so my recommendation
is always use functools wraps.
It's just gonna make your life easier
and it really doesn't take a lot of effort.
So that's it for this video
and I'll see you on the next one.