Hi, welcome back.
In this video, we're going to briefly talk a bit more
about ABCs and why it can be useful
to have this functionality num_legs
defined in another class
that isn't either of your child classes.
The main reason why you'd like this--
Well there are two reasons.
The first one is that when you read your code
and you see okay,
dog is an animal, monkey's an animal,
you'll know without reading all of the contents
that they will have implemented num_legs.
So you'll know that.
Otherwise you won't be able to use them.
Unless of course these are then subclassed by other things
which implements the method.
But generally you'll know that
they must have implemented the method
in order for you to be able to instantiate them,
create objects.
The other thing that's really useful is that
if you have a list of animals,
for example a dog which is Rolf
and a monkey which is Bob,
you can
do a.numb_legs.
See this?
This is quite a magical thing.
And it may not seem it just now.
But what you've got here
are two completely different objects in this list.
But because you know they're animals,
you can call a.num_legs on all of them.
Okay, so let's run this again.
Now you can see we get four and two
which is as you'd expect.
After all, all that's happening in the background is
you know, A is this dog called the num_legs methods.
You call this thing here,
so nothing magical is going on.
A is this monkey,
so you call the num_legs method on that.
Nothing magical,
but none the less the fact that you know
that these are animals means that you can do this.
Furthermore,
you can print whether
A is an instance of animal,
you should not forget the commas,
and you get true every time.
This is the same for all inheritance in Python,
you know, A is an instance of animal,
but it has also been extended by the subclass.
So Python says yes, this is an animal
in that it has all the methods and the properties
of the animal,
but it can also have methods and properties
of whatever it is that the class they find as well.
The usefulness of this is for you to say
okay, these are animals,
therefore I can call animal methods on all of them
and I don't care whether they are more specific,
whether they are dogs or monkeys or cats.
Because they're animals,
you can call the methods in them,
and because you define this num_legs method on the animal,
you know that all the subclasses
must have implemented that as well
so it's safe for you to call it.
Now let's go back in the next video
to our users and our admins
and make a little bit more sense
on where this can be useful.
As part of that,
we're also going to be talking about
what an interface is.
I'll see you there.