Hi and welcome back.
In this video we will be going
to look at adding error pages.
If we run our app and we go back to Chrome,
we can refresh and see that this still works.
But if we change this to post number one
for example, it does not.
It just sort of breaks and nothing really happens.
What we're seeing here
is that there is no content
to be put in here in the template
so instead of you know getting a page
that says we can't find this post,
what we're getting is nothing.
This is not great so let's stop our app,
remember to stop your app every time
and hide this away
and what we're going to do is,
if we can't find the post in our database
which is our dictionary here, we're going to return
a different template which is going to be an error page
or a not found page.
So again we're going to extract
this back to a variable just because
we need to use it in multiple places now.
We're going to say post is that
and if not post,
remember post will be none
if it is not found because the get method returns none
if it wasn't found in the dictionary.
So post will evaluate to true
if it is something and to false if it is none.
Not false will be true.
So then we will run this if statement,
so if the post was not found,
we will run the if statement.
Just gonna run a wee comment here
to make this a bit clearer.
Post will be none if not found,
not none evaluates to true
because none evaluates to false
and as you know, the if statement only runs
when the condition here is true
so if this was not found,
we want to run
return render template
and we're going to do a 404 dot HTML page.
And then we're gonna pass it in a message to say,
something like, a post with ID, post ID,
was not found, okay?
And of course down here, post is going to be equal to post
which is what we created up here.
Notice that there is a grey squiggly line,
that's because the variable has
the same name as the function,
not a great convention, this is my bad,
I don't recommend naming the function and the variables
the same way, but it's normally fine.
It's only not fine if you wanna call
this function from within your code
which would be a bit of a strange thing to do.
So this is okay, maybe not the best idea,
PyCharm doesn't like it very much but it still works.
So what we've got here is,
if the post was not found, we're gonna return
this other template and we're gonna give it
this variable that the template can use.
So let's go into our templates and create
a new HTML file, which we're gonna call
404 dot HTML.
Notice how when you create a new HTML file,
this is already all prefilled for you
so you can keep some of this,
like the title of the page and so forth,
or you can just delete it and we're gonna add in
our body here, what we want the page to return.
So it's gonna be H1 and we're gonna say 404,
post not found and then just add a P tag,
we're gonna put our message.
Our message remember is the variable we passed in
that is going to get replaced by a post
with ID, post ID was not found.
So make sure that you've stopped running your app earlier,
we can run it again.
Go back to Chrome, refresh this page
that didn't return anything before
and now you can see we get a nice 404, post not found
and then it says a post with ID one was not found.
If we go back to post zero, we get our post contents
so this is great,
we're now dealing with user input
in a very nice way.
If we couldn't do what they needed,
we can return a message that is appropriate
as opposed to nothing or potentially an error message.
Again remember to stop your app
and minimise that, and now we're gonna look
at a couple improvements to this multi-template.
As you can see, both our pages,
404 and post have essentially the same structure,
they've got this doctype that's got this HTML,
and empty head, a body and the only difference between
the two, other than the indentation
is this, the post has this H1 and the P tag
with this post title and content
and the 404 has an H1 and P tag
with a different message entirely.
Jinja2 which is the engine that's driving this templating
does have support for, you know,
this sort of inheritance.
So we can make a base template
that will contain all of this body and HTML
and then we can make these two child templates
that only include this content here.
That way we'll have a little bit less duplicated content.
Let's go ahead, right click our templates
and create a new file.
I wanna call this file, base dot Jinja2.
Now the reason I'm going for Jinja2 and not HTML here
is because in some editors, not in PyCharm Community Edition
but in some editors, you'll get
a bit better syntax highlighting
if you use dot Jinja2.
If you are using PyCharm Community Edition,
I advise you stick with dot HTML
just because you're gonna get slightly nicer highlighting.
If you're using other editors,
I recommend you use dot Jinja2 and you instal
any packages you need in order
to get the syntax highlighting to work, okay?
In this editor, you're not gonna see syntax highlighting
but this is the best thing to do
if you are using a different editor
that does support that.
Optionally, if you are using PyCharm Professional Edition,
which is not free, you'll also get
nice syntax highlighting with this.
So as part of this, creating this superclass,
per se, super template, we're going to be changing over
to Jinja2.
First thing we're going to do, is to say
what is in a base template?
Well in a base template you've got,
essentially all of this
but you don't want the content,
you want this content, this H1 tag and the P tags
to come from the children.
So instead, in Jinja2, now we can use
this syntax to say block content
and down here end block.
As you can see there is an opening curly brace
and a percent symbol,
then we've got block content
and percent symbol and a closing brace.
Then we've got, you know, some content in here
if we want and at the end we've got
this end block set of tags.
You can put any content you want here
but more interestingly, you can copy this
and put it into 404 HTML,
now the 404 HTML tag can have its content here
and it will be replaced for this stuff in base dot Jinja2.
So I'm gonna undo that
and just put it up here just so I can then copy this,
put it in there and get rid of that.
As you can see 404 HTML now looks much simpler
and if we go over to post dot HTML, we can do the same.
So we can go and copy this
paste it in here,
copy this,
paste it in here, make sure to fix the annotation.
Now post dot HTML also looks a bit simpler.
These pages are just children on base dot Jinja2,
they don't need all the duplicate code for the HTML
and you know head tags, body tags,
because the content here will be injected into this block
that we've defined at base dot Jinja2.
Of course, the million dollar question is,
how do they know they are children of that?
We've not said it anywhere.
Indeed we have to say that.
So we'll say extend base dot Jinja2.
We'll copy that and put it in post as well,
make sure we do not forget that.
Now these children are actually extending base dot Jinja2.
When we render this template using Flask,
the first thing it'll do,
sorry about that,
first thing it'll do is it'll go
and extend Jinja2 so all the scaffolding
from base dot Jinja2 is going to be applied
to this template and this block of content
is going to replace this block of content here
so we're gonna get a nice HTML file without the
bloat and the duplication.
So that's good.
As part of this again, we're going to migrate
to dot Jinja2 just to make sure, make it clear
that these templates are Jinja2 templates
and not HTML only templates, so I'm going to rename these
by right clicking them, go to refactor and rename
and change that to Jinja2.
We're gonna lose the syntax highlighting
which is not great in this editor
so again if you are using PyCharm Community Edition
like I am, don't do this,
stick to HTML, it may be slightly easier.
You won't get syntax highlighting for Jinja
but you will get syntax highlighting for HTML.
If you are using a different editor though,
feel free to move to Jinja2 and instal whatever it is
you need to instal to get the syntax highlighting.
It's up to you, it doesn't really matter
to Python at all.
Now instead of HTML here in these templates,
make sure to use dot Jinja2.
Just because the names have to be correct,
doesn't matter what it is at the end
but it has to be correct.
Now that we've got this, we can press play
and make sure this is all working
by going to Chrome and refreshing,
this seems to be fine.
Go to a different post, this seems to be fine still.
So all our changes here are working,
remember to stop your app,
minimise that and we can do a short review
of what we've just looked at.
All that we've done is added this error page,
so if the post was not found and we're returning
a different template entirely,
and we're passing this short message.
Now we've also create a base Jinja file
which is all the HTML scaffolding
plus this special block syntax.
In any child that extends that file,
we then have this block again
and we can include any HTML we want inside that block
and it will replace the contents in base dot Jinja2.
Make sure the spell these blocks correctly, you know,
block should be lowercase b, you should have these tags
opening at the end.
Some of my students insist on typing block with a capital B,
that won't work, you know, it has to be lowercase b.
This here though, the content block
is essentially a name, so you can call it whatever you want
you can put whatever you want inside content,
you can call it something else if that makes more sense
to you, you can call it block body for example
if that makes more sense to you.
And that's it.
That simplifies our code greatly
and allows us to give the users this nice error message.
That's it for this video,
and I'll see you on the next one.