Hi and welcome back.
In this video we are going to continue with our
student class and we're going
to look at the average function.
So in the last video we discovered that
when we call a class that creates a blank object
and that gets passed to the Dunder init method as self
and then we can modify that by creating
new variables inside that blank object.
That's how these things here end up with a name property.
Lest, I just said property, and let's start calling
things by what they are.
When we define a variable inside an object,
that's no longer a variable now it's called a property.
A property of the object.
Similarly when we define a function like this
average function, inside a class that is no longer
called a function, that is now called a method.
Same thing it's just a different name in order for,
when you talk about programming to be able to
quickly differentiate between what you're talking about.
So student one and student two, know that they are students.
They are off type student, because that's the way
this was created when we called the class.
Therefore, because they're off type student
they know that they have this
average function inside of them.
Now we can call student_one.average
we're calling the average function which is inside
of our student one.
Now you can see that there's a self parameter here
which we are clearly not fully filling.
So what do you think is going to happen
when we print this out?
Let's run it!
And, hmm, we get a value and a valued one at that.
So why is that?
Well Python is pretty smart and when you use an object
to call a function of the class, it automatically
populates self as the object that called that function.
Okay, let me give you another example that you
may understand a bit more easily.
Let's call the function, sorry the method here in the class.
The way that you'd sort of expect it to do that is by
saying student, which is the class, dot to access
something inside of it, average.
Right?
We've got the class, we access something inside of it
and what we are accessing is the average function.
However if we do this and we run it, now we see that
it says, there's something not very readable,
average, the average function is missing
one required argument which is self.
Hmm, so Python obviously cannot tell what object
you want to get the average of,
because you've not called it with an object,
you've called it with the class which is the
definition of an object.
So what to do?
Is to pass in a particular object,
ooh not my student that's a dictionary.
Student one, now when you call this student one
will be self as normal in Python functions and you will
return that so we can once again run it.
And now you can see we get the correct value.
When you do student_one.average Python in the background
is doing this, so there's no magic going on
whatsoever, it's just that in order to save you
from typing a bunch of stuff,
you can just call it on the student and that also
sort of makes sense, because now you're getting the
average of student one,
you don't have to include the student class in there,
you know, self gets automatically populated for you
when you call any method, remember that safe function
within a class, with the student as the caller.
And the student here is the caller because
that's where we're calling this function from.
Okay that's what this called.
Okay so let's think about this average method again.
We've got student one being passed as self,
and we must remember now that student one was this
object that was created and emptied here,
also called self but that's just a side effect
of the naming conventions in Python.
Student one is the self thing here and we know it has
a name and it also has a grades.
So when we access student_one.grades that is what
we passed initially up here.
And here we're also accessing student_one.grades
however in order to make this a bit more generic,
we're not using average only on student one,
but on self because we define self.grades,
we know that we have self.grades available
to use in the average function so we can use self.grades
and self.grades and it depends on which student object
we call it on that it's gonna use either these grades
if we call it with student one or these grades
if we call it with student two.
We can re-write this function entirely, by the way,
down here... while making it accept a student
and it's gonna return the sum of student.grades
and the length of student.grades.
Okay, we're gonna print student_one.grades
and then we're gonna call the average function call
of student one.
The first thing we're gonna do is print out the
student's grades which we know should be 70, 88, 90, and 99.
And indeed there we get them here,
then we define this function that takes in a student object,
returns the sum of it's grades property
the one that we just printed up here,
and the length and then divides one by another.
Then we call that function with our student one object
passed in as an argument.
So student one, this is student one, this is student one,
student_one.grades is the same thing we just
printed up here.
And student_one.grades is the same things we printed up here
and then that is how the average gets calculated.
Again, just a recap, when you call student_one.average
what's happening in the background
is student.average(student_one)
student one is being passed as self.
Same function we just defined only the argument
which is really the parameter is called self.
Again you could call this student if you wanted.
But it is not common to do that.
Normally in methods the first parameter
is always called self because it refers
to the object that you're currently modifying
or acting on.
Okay, and that's how that works.
That's how the methods work and now we are able
to both define the dates now that we're acting on,
and the action we're performing in the same structure.
Now it's a class instead of a dictionary
but essentially it's the same thing,
it allows us to store some data and now it extends
that functionality by allowing us to store some
functions that act on that data as well.
Now of course the average function could receive
some extra arguments, some extra parameters
if you wanted, just as the Dunder init method does.
So you could pass in some name as well if you wanted
and then student_one.average now would just
get something, a friend, some argument there as well.
That would be the second argument,
the second parameter.
Okay so self is populated first by the current object
any other parameters get populated after
from whatever it is inside these brackets.
Anyway, I think I've gone on and on about this enough,
hopefully it's more or less clear that a student
class is just something that allows us to define
what properties are in a student and also
what actions a student can do on it's own data,
or indeed if we so desired on other data
by passing in some arguments.
So that's what a class is,
and that's what an object is.
A way to store some data and
store some actions that relate to it.
That allows us to encapsulate and hold
all relevant functionality in the same structure,
as opposed to having it split over two separate
structures like we did up here.
So that's it for this video,
hopefully that's clear.
And over the coming sections we're gonna
be using this more and more and as you
programme more and more it's gonna sort of be
second nature you're gonna start understanding this
a bit more thoroughly and I'm sure it will get
better and better, if you are confused
please ask a question in the course Q&amp;A
and we'll be happy to help you but it normally
takes a few months to fully click
so of course I'm gonna try to get that to click
earlier by providing with good explanations
but if you are just you know mildly uncomfortable
with all of this, that's fine.
Just keep going, keep programming,
keep writing code and it's gonna all settle down
in your subconscious as you move along.
So that's it for this video, I'll see you on the next one.