Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to look at
separating locators into classes.
So, what we're gonna do is not hard code
these locators into the class ParsedItem.
The ParsedItem is the item that represents
the data that is in the html.
It shouldn't represent, also, how to get that data.
So, how to get that data should be in a different place.
So we're going to create a new class,
which I'm gonna call ParsedItemLocators.
And I've got it placed in a docstring here
I have for my notes.
Just, just so it's a bit easier for you.
Look at this item in the html page.
This allows us to easily see what our code
would be looking at, as well as change it quickly
if we notice it is now different.
So, this may not make much sense until
I start writing here.
Name Locator is going to be article of product
pod h3 a.
Okay, that's the locator we used down here for the name.
What if this changes?
The website changes and when we get the html back,
it's slightly different?
The ParsedItem shouldn't care
because the ParsedItem represents the item itself
and not how to get the data from it.
So, this is a small, but important distinction.
And it all about how you think of your programme,
how your program's different parts interact
with one another.
Separating the how and the what
is going to make your programmes much simpler.
And also simpler to work with.
So, instead of putting a string here,
we're gonna, and do ParsedItemLocators.NAME LOCATOR.
These would potentially and probably be in different files
altogether.
In this case, I'm leaving them in one file
just for simplicity, but they would likely
be in two different files, one for the locators
and one for the item.
The good thing is that as long as the website
doesn't change massively, for example,
if they just remove this class
and maybe add a different class
or something like that, you don't have to go
and look at the item and read through all this code.
No, all you have to do is go to the site,
find out the new html locator and change it.
So, it's very straight forward.
So, we're gonna do that for the others,
and, once again, I'm gonna copy them
just to save you some time.
I think you're getting much better at programming
by this stage of the course,
so I think I'm allowed to now copy some code
from my notes and save you some time.
So, there we have our link, price, and rating locator
and then we're just gonna replace them down here.
And so this is the ParsedItemLocators.LINK LOCATOR.
ParsedItemLocators.PRICE LOCATOR.
And also, the ParsedItemLocators.RATING LOCATOR.
Now, there are a couple of things in these methods here,
like this pattern or this class that we're filtering out,
that could possible be in another place,
so that the item doesn't really care at all
of where it's coming from.
But, sometimes that's just not feasible
and other times it's just too complicated
in order to be worth the effort.
So, by all means, try to do that if you want,
but I would leave it like this
and I think this is a great way
of separating out where the item is on the page
from how you're going to extract the data
and, sort of, what the item represents.
So, hopefully this makes a bit of sense.
This way of separating concerns
is something that we do all the time
and this is how we structure our tests
at work, professionally.
And so, it's definitely a great way to go about it
and it's gonna simplify your code greatly.
I hope this makes sense and I'll see you on the next video,
where we're going to start looking at retrieving the page
using another library.
I'll see you there.