Hi, and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to use
a virtualenv with the pipenv.
In the last video, we saw that when we did pipenv instal,
this created a virtual environment for our project,
but there is no virtual environment folder
inside our project, there's only
a Pipfile and a Pipfile.lock.
Indeed, the virtualenv location
is a different folder entirely,
it's this /User/jslvtr/.local/share/
virtualenvs/scraping-books dash random numbers and letters.
Now sorry about that.
So pipenv has actually created the virtual environment
in an entirely different place, which is
a unique folder just for this project.
Whenever you use pipenv, you can do run python
and this is going to run the Python interpreter
in that virtual environment, so when you proceed
anything by pipenv run, that's going to use
a virtual environment that was created for you,
not inside this folder but in somewhere else,
as where your programmes are running.
So now you no longer need to activate and deactivate,
all you have to do is ask pipenv
to run whatever it is you want to run.
So as you can see when we type pipenv run python,
that went straight to Python 3.7,
which is what we used in our virtual environment
that was created by pipenv.
If we exit here by typing control d,
and we type pipenv run python menu.py,
you can see that it all works.
All the packages are installed in the virtual environment,
but the virtual environment is not inside this folder,
it's somewhere else, and that's everything working there.
So, pipenv actually helps you clean up
your development environment, you can no longer have the vn,
or you will no longer have the vn inside this folder here
because pipenv says this folder is
for your code and for your project,
it's not for, you know, your Python installation,
that doesn't make any sense.
So, you keep your Pipfile and your Pipfile.lock
in your project and if you share
this project with someone else,
they will also have a Pipfile and Pipfile.lock,
they can also type pipenv instal.
They will get their own virtual environment
created somewhere else unique to them in their own computers
and not inside the project folder.
So whenever you create a new project,
now instead of creating a virtual environment,
just use pipenv and it will be
easy to manage all your projects.
In addition, you don't have
to remember to activate and deactivate.
Pipenv will manage your virtual environments for you,
whenever you type pipenv run, it will know
how to use the correct virtual environment.
However, there's a caveat for that.
If you move your project,
we've got this scraping-books folder,
if I move that folder somewhere else,
pipenv will no longer be able to find
the correct virtual environment,
so you'll have to recreate it.
Okay, that's the only problem with pipenv,
if you move the project, you'll have to recreate
the virtual environment, and that is because of the way
that it creates the virtual environment,
it creates it, and depending on where your project is,
and if you move it, it sort of loses
that knowledge of where it was.
That's it for this video, I just wanted to show you
how to use pipenv, and there's a bit more to pipenv
that you can use if you type pipenv,
you'll get a few other commands like,
and you know how to uninstall libraries
and things like that.
There's some investigation you can do if
you want to go into more advanced pipenv stuff,
but don't worry too much about it.
What you need to know is how to instal it,
how to run it, in order to simplify your project management.
Again, that's it for this video
and I'll see you on the next one.