Hi, guys and welcome back.
Next up we're going to be testing classes.
So, we're gonna first of all
create a new Python file
that's gonna be our printer.
And here we're going to create a printer class
that has a simple, in it, method
with the pages per second
and the capacity of the print.
And we're gonna have a simple class here
that just allows to mock a print.
So we've created this simple printer class
and what it does is it takes two values,
how many pages this printer prints in one second
and how many pages it has capacity for.
How much ink it's got left, if you will.
Then there is a print method
that prints a certain number of pages
unless the pages are above the current capacity
in which case, it raises a printer error.
After that, the capacity decreases
by the number of pages printed
and it returns a nice message there
that tells you how many pages were printed.
We've autograted a custom printer error class
that is what is raised here.
Now, let's go ahead
and create a new file called test_printer.py.
And here is where we're gonna be writing our tests
for this printer.
Now, there is a couple of things that we need to look at
when testing a class.
The first thing is that we need to create a class object
so we need to think about
whether we wanna create that on every test
or we wanna create it once
for the entire test case.
We're going to look at how to do that
and also on writing tests for this printer
in the next video, so I'll see you there.