Hi guys
and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be
interacting with our first drop down.
And in Selenium, they're called selects.
Let's go over to our quotes page
and add a couple of imports.
The first one is gonna be just from the typing module,
and the second one is from Selenium web driver support UI.
And we're going to import select.
The typing one is just so that we can do this
in there, which was missing.
And then we're gonna add another property
which is for the author dropdown.
And this is going to return a Select Object from Selenium.
And what it's gonna do is
it's going to first of all find this.
So self dot browser,
dot find element by CSS selector,
and this is the quotes page locators dot author drop down.
And then we're just going to return
a Select of that element.
What that does in Selenium terms,
is it takes whatever arbitrary
or generic Selenium element you've got,
and it tries to put it inside a select wrapper.
And what that does is it gives that element,
some methods that we can use to interact with a Select.
Now, you better hope
that the element you're passing into this is a drop down.
If it's not, you're gonna have some problems.
And so now that we have the element there,
that lets us create something like select author.
And that takes in an author name,
which is going to be a string,
and that is going to do self dot author dropdown,
which is these property here.
Don't select by visible text.
This is one of these methods that you get
when you make a select
and select by visible text is going to be author name.
What that does in Selenium terms is
it opens the drop down, sees what's there
and then selects the one that
matches this string if it's there.
So that is how we're going to
select an author from the drop down.
Let's go over to App dot py
and modify this code so that it actually does that.
So let's first of all ask the user
what author they want.
Enter the author you'd like quotes from.
And then we're going to do page dot select author,
with that author.
All right, so making sure that we've got everything there.
And it seems like we do.
Go ahead
and run this.
And chrome will open first because
that's that line five there.
Then we get asked what author we'd like
so we're going to say something like Bob Marley
just because his name is quite short.
And then we have our first bug.
You can see that the error
says attribute error this object has no attribute tack name.
That suggests that we've tried to do something on an object,
but that thing was a list instead of
whatever we were expecting.
So something comes to mind immediately
when something like this happens.
And that is that we use the wrong method.
And indeed we did for the author drop down,
we said self dot browser dot find elements by CSS selector,
you want find elements because there's only going to be one
and you want just a single element,
so that you can make a select out of it.
You don't want multiple elements,
or at least offer one element,
because then it will be very confused.
Okay, let's run app dot py again.
Notice that this launches a completely new chrome instance
when you do that,
so you can end up with a bunch of different Chrome's.
There you have it.
And Bob Marley has been selected in our drop down.
If you read the error messages you can
try to glean something about Selenium's internal workings.
But it can be tricky.
If you do have any problems, ask away in the course Q&amp;A
or in the Slack channel, we'll be more than happy to help.
Just make sure you give us your code
and you know, as much information as you can,
so that we can help you better.
That's how you interact with one select or one drop down.
I'm sure you can do the same for the tag name,
but we're going to do that in the next video.
I'll see you there.