Hi and welcome back.
In this video, we're going to look at databases.
Let's first talk about databases as a general concept,
and then over the next few videos
we'll move on to talk more concisely
about what SQLite is and what it does,
and then we will re-implement our milestone project
using databases.
A database is a place where we can store data.
Now, we all know this already,
but let me give you a bit more information
about how databases work.
Normally, databases are organised into tables,
and each table holds information about one thing
in your system, such as cars, or customers,
or shops, et cetera.
Something more or less like this
could be for your customers.
On the left, you've got an ID column,
that's an identifier for each customer.
Then you've got a name and then you've got an address.
The reason we've got an identifier
is because two customers could have the same name
or the same address, so neither name or address
allows us to identify one customer.
They could identify multiple customers.
So that's why we have an ID.
If each customer had a unique email address, for example,
we could use that as the ID instead of a number.
But frequently, we use numeric IDs for things in our tables.
Normally it starts at one and it goes up one per row
that you've got.
As you can see, this table has three columns,
ID, name, and address,
and four rows from one to four.
SQLite, which is the database we're gonna be using,
is a small, fast, and reliable database engine
which can run in memory, more or less
like our Python List did, without saving any data
to the actual, physical disc.
Or, it can also run by saving all data
to a single data file.
That's it, one file on your computer that contains
all your data in your database.
Now, there is a benefit to having a single data file,
which is that it makes everything quite lightweight,
quite small, quite easy to move around
from one computer to another or from one device to another.
And SQLite is frequently used with small devices
like your phones, smartphones, iPhones, Android phones.
It's also used with embedded applications,
and it's also used in reasonably light
and simple desktop and ware applications as well.
You interact with SQLite using SQL,
and that means Structured Query Language,
and the Structured Query Language
is an English-like language
that's developed specifically for interacting
with relational databases.
We're gonna look at what a relational database means
in a moment.
SQL allows for things like selecting data from a database,
or inserting it, creating tables, filtering through data,
ordering data, and a lot more stuff.
By the way, some people say S-Q-L instead of SQL,
it's up to you which one you say.
Don't hate for me saying SQL.
And there are other database systems apart from SQLite,
such as the oh-so-popular MySQL, and others like PostgreSQL,
Oracle, and many more.
Okay, so let's look at an example of a relational database.
SQLite, Postgre, MySQL are all relational database systems.
And in a relational database, there is functionality
to extract and analyse data in ways tailored
for when some data is related to some other data.
Here's an example.
Here we've got two tables, Users and Purchases.
Now, it may not be directly obvious
that these two pieces of data are related,
but if you see, the Users has an ID column,
the Purchases has a customer ID column,
so the data here's related because
by looking at this data together, you can see that
two of these purchases were made by the user number one,
and that has a name and an address.
So you can relate these pieces of data
by using the customer ID column on the Purchases table,
and the ID column on the Users table.
So that's pretty handy.
Most database engines create complex folder structures
and save data in various different ways,
but SQLite is quite simple in that it creates
a single file that contains all your data.
SQLite has a limitation, which is that we can only perform
one write operation at a time.
That means that if you've got two users
trying to write some data to the database at the same time,
they are not going to be able to do that.
Only one person is going to be able to write,
and then the other will have to write afterwards.
They will have to wait.
However, SQLite does allow multiple read operations
at the same time, so if you have a lot of users
using your programme at the same time,
interacting with the same SQLite database,
they can all read data at the same time.
Most database systems, like PostgreSQL or MySQL,
allow for many of those at once, either write or read.
For example, imagine you were writing a Python app
handling hundreds of users at once performing operations
like purchasing items, SQLite would not be suitable
because only one user could save their purchase
and commit their purchase at a time.
So another database type could be better in that scenario.
However, if you've got SQLite on your phone,
well you're the only user,
SQLite could be pretty nice for that.
So SQLite is very fast at reading data,
not so fast and not so efficient at writing data.
Now, when we interact with a SQLite database,
you can either open the data file with a text editor,
that's just a blank, or not a blank, but a text file
that has a bunch of SQLite data in it,
but normally I recommend using a proper data browser
like this one, sqlitebrowser.org.
As we progress through this section,
I am going to be using sqlitebrowser.org
to look at the data in our database.
Feel free to download it as well
so that you can interact
with your SQLite databases a bit more easily.
That is the end of this video.
Just wanted to look quickly at what a database is,
what tables are, what relational tables
and relational databases are,
and how SQLite compares to some of its competitors.
Just remember, it's not so good for many users.
It's pretty good for a single user.
And give you a bit more information
on how to look at the data in your database,
sqlitebrowser.org.
It's a pretty good and free software that you can use
to look at that.
So that's it for this video.
I'll see you on the next one.