Hi and welcome back.
In this video,
we're going to be creating our first HTML form,
which is going to allow our users
to create new posts in our in-memory database.
In order to do that, we're going to create
two new Flask endpoints.
Let's go over down here, and create the first one,
which is going to be very simple.
It's going to give the users the form that they can fill in.
So we're gonna do app.route /post/form.
And then here we're gonna define a function
that is going to return render template of create.jinja2.
This is gonna be a file that we're gonna give our users
which is going to contain the fields that they can fill in
in order to create a new post.
Let's go and do this first.
We always want to go step-by-step
when we do software development.
We wanna do this, make sure it works,
and then we can move on to the next bit.
If you implement everything together,
and then try to see if it works, you may find
that it's not so easy to realise where the problem lies.
So, going step-by-step, always a good idea.
Let's go ahead into our templates, create a new file,
which is going to be called create.jinja2,
and in here we're gonna do the usual extends base.jinja2
and then a block of content there.
And inside this block we're going to put our form.
First thing is a wee title,
just so the user knows where they are.
Then, we're going to include our form.
Mark it.
And inside a form, we're going to include a div.
A div in HTML is just a horizontal block,
so if you have two divs, for example this one here,
and then this one here, they will appear
one below the other, as opposed to one beside the other.
So it's a good way of separating content in HTML.
It doesn't really do anything on its own,
but it's a good way of separating content.
And the content we're going to separate
is the different fields.
First thing we're gonna do is add a label
and the label is gonna be for this title field.
The title field is gonna be here, input type text
and the name is going to be title.
Notice how the label has an opening tag and a closing tag,
and inside it, you put what you want to go in the label.
But the input field doesn't have anything inside it,
because it's a blank field
so you get what's called a self-closing tag.
You get a tag that has this weird syntax
where it's only a single tag
but it has this forward slash at the end,
this is called a self-closing tag.
A tag that closes itself.
The name of the field is what this for is going to target.
So this tells HTML users that this label is for this field.
Of course, when you see the text title beside a field,
you know that that title is for that field.
But if you're blind and you're using a screen reader,
you may not see the contents of the label,
but the screen reader will
be able to look at this for property
and tell you that this input field is a title.
So it's always a good idea to have these fors,
they're for screen readers, not for the rest of us,
but it's a good idea nonetheless.
Then in the other div, we're going to include a field
for the contents of the post.
So we're going to do label for content, content, like that,
and then instead of an input type text,
which is a single line text field,
we're going to use a text area.
A text area is just a multi-line field.
Like that.
And a text area does have to close, like that.
It shouldn't be a self-closing tag.
This is just another type of input
which can span multiple lines.
And finally we're going to include a final div,
which is going to be an input of type submit.
An input of type submit, essentially,
is a button that the user can press,
and when the user presses the button,
they're going to send the data of the form to the server.
Now that we've got this, let's go over to our app,
run it, and see what happens when we access this endpoint.
Let's go over to Chrome and access post/form
and you get this nice looking form.
Okay, I'll give you that is not terribly pretty,
but nonetheless it is functional.
You can put in your title here, like "My first blog post,"
and the content can be, "Hello, how are you doing?"
Then you can submit and now look at what happens to the URL.
The URL has changed, right?
Now it has all of this stuff here.
But it seemed like it loaded something.
Now the fields are blank, but the URL has changed.
So how to explain this?
What was happening is the form
is sending the data to a page.
That page can then choose to use that data or not.
What happens is, when you press submit,
the browser sends another GET request
to this URL /post/form
and it includes behind that
this, that is called the query string parameter, okay?
This ?title= something and content equals something else.
But because our Python code here,
when you access this endpoint, only rendered a template,
it doesn't use the data that it received
in the query string parameters.
It is unable to do anything with them,
and all that happens is we re-rend the template
and we don't use that data at all.
We're gonna stop the app again
because we're gonna restart it momentarily,
but what we're going to do is,
instead of sending the data to this endpoint,
we're gonna send the data to a different endpoint.
So, here in the form, we're gonna say
action equals /post/create, okay?
Instead of /post/form, now it's going to go
into /post/create and we can create that endpoint.
App.route/post/create, create post,
and this, I'm actually just gonna call it create,
just to keep it simple, this is going to access
that data that's coming through the URL.
Remember, this here is one server number one 5,000
/post/create?title= blah blah
and content equals something else.
Yeah?
We can access this stuff here,
we can retrieve the title and the content.
So let's do just that.
Inside our create function,
we're gonna say title is request.args.get title
and we have to import request from Flask
so let's go to the very top and say import request.
This request thing here, it's a variable,
it's like a global variable,
is the request that is coming in to this endpoint.
So the request right now, is this
and it has some arguments which are these.
And you can get a particular argument
in order to retrieve its content.
Essentially, Flask, behind-the-scenes,
it's turning this into a dictionary and that's request.args.
Then you can get a particular thing in that dictionary
and we'll give you the content of that.
Similarly, we can do content = request.args.get content
then we can generate a new post ID,
which is going to be len of posts.
And finally we can say posts, post ID equal
title is gonna be the title
and content is gonna be the content.
Like that.
Now's a good point in time to make sure
to also include an ID for the post in the body of the post.
Like that.
Just so when you access a particular post,
you'll also have access to its ID.
It's a useful thing to include in every post.
So we're gonna go up here and also include that here.
Okay, just a good thing to include
in order to have the complete information
when you do retrieve a post.
Now that we've added this new post to our posts,
we can return the user something else.
So again, all this does is it accesses these arguments
using request.args and gets a title
and the content that came from the form,
generates a new post ID,
and then puts it into our dictionary.
For example, if we create a new post
and pass it some values here, len of posts will be one
because we've got one post right now,
and what we'll do is we'll say post one equal this new post.
And at the end, we're gonna say return
and here's a bit more complicated
redirect URL for post,
post ID equal
post ID.
So a couple of things are going on here.
The first thing is this URL for.
The URL for, which we're gonna import in just a moment,
URL for takes in a function name,
takes in the function name and returns a URL,
an address that we want.
In this case, it takes the post function name,
which is this function defined up here,
and it's gonna give us this URL.
Instead of hard-coding the URL
in here directly, we can use the URL for,
and that way we can change this later on if we want.
For example, let's say we wanna change it to, I don't know,
posts/something, this will still work,
because we've not changed the function name.
So Flask recommends using this URL for
in order to generate URLs instead of hard-coding them.
And it also allows us to give the arguments that it needs.
So the post URL needs a post ID in order to be complete,
and we can do that inside the URL for function.
The redirect is wrapping this URL for
and what it does is it sends a response back
to the browser telling the browser
that it should actually not load this page,
it should go and load this page instead.
So, essentially, the browser loads this
and then it receives this information
and then it goes and loads the other thing.
Browsers are already wired up to understand this,
so that's why it works, you can send the browser
to go to somewhere else and they'll do it.
Okay, let's go up and import those two.
We wanna import URL for and redirect
and now when we create a new post,
we pass it in the title and content,
we add it to our database,
and then we send the user to the post page
for that specific post.
So as soon as you create a post, you'll be sent back
to the post page that you've just created.
Let's go and run our app, and try this out.
So what we're gonna do,
is we are going to delete this query string parameter.
We're going to refresh this page
and now we're gonna enter something here.
"My first blog post," and "Hey, what are you reading?"
And then submit, and as soon as submit happens,
you know what's gonna happen, the URL's gonna change,
we're gonna send a request to /post/create,
that's gonna process this function here,
add something to our database,
and then it's gonna redirect us to /post/one.
Let's press submit and there you have it.
And it happens so quickly, you can't even see it
because there's really nothing much happening
in the background, but this has now been added
to our database, you can see we're in /post/one,
and our new post contents have appeared here.
So this is starting to get really cool.
Now we can get information from our users,
add it to a database, you know, send them to other places,
display information and so forth.
I hope you're starting to see the power
of what Flask can do.
I really love Flask and I'm really passionate
about developing Flask applications
because it's so simple.
And it's all Python, all that's happening here is this.
This is what Flask gives you, really.
This routing, you know, access to the request,
rendering templates, the rest, databases,
all your business logic in terms of creating new posts
and so forth, is all Python.
And that gives you a lot of flexibility.
There are other web frameworks apart from Flask
that can be a bit more complex to use, such as Django,
that require a bit more up-front knowledge,
but Flask does not,
that's why I'm really liking how Flask works.
And this is what I do at my job
and in many other quarters as well.
So this was the end of the video,
just wanted to show you how to send the user
to a post they've just created
and how to create new posts.
We're going to move over to the next video
to add posts in a slightly different manner.
I'll see you there.