Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video I wanted to talk with you briefly
about the project we're gonna be building in
the next few videos.
And it is this text editor you see here.
In this text editor we can type, we can see the saved
or unsaved status of any element,
we can create new elements using that or a keyboard shortcut
and of course we can save files and they get written to
the disc and we can also open files so that we can
edit them with our text editor.
It may look complicated but there's actually a lot
of different inter components here working together
that make developing something like this fairly
straight forward.
We're gonna develop it in just a few videos
so let's get started in the very next one.
I'll see you there.