Hi, and welcome back.
In this video, we're talking about how to see the HTML
using your browser so that you'll know how to scrape it,
and how to parse it, and how to understand it.
What I've got here is this website books.toscrape.com.
Which is a website that was specifically designed
for practising scraping.
Scraping is the act of loading a page using Python,
or another programming language and extracting data from it.
So this page was designed for scraping,
which means you're free to use it for scraping,
practise it, give it a go and see what happens.
Now before you even think of
downloading the page using Python, you have to understand
what's going on in a browser.
Because what's going on in Python is very similar
to what goes on in the browser.
So whenever your browser loads a page,
such as if you go to books.toscrape.com,
it's actually downloading the page.
It's asking the place where the page is hosted,
where the page lives.
Then it's asking to download the data in it.
It doesn't store the page in your downloads
or anything like that.
But the page is downloaded so the browser can use it.
And we can also get Python to download a page
and that gives Python the ability to look at the code,
and look at the HTML, look at the page content,
to see what's there.
We can load an HTML page with Python
and that will give us the HTML as a string.
And then we can parse it and we can extract data from it.
The act of doing all of that, from downloading the page,
to extracting data, is called scraping.
So when you load the page using your browser,
I recommend using Google Chrome for this, by the way.
If you don't have Google Chrome I advise using Chrome.
It's the best browser for web development generally.
You can select or find what you want to extract.
So imagine you wanted to use Python to get the price,
then what you would do is you would right click,
and you would press inspect.
What you then get is this side window.
It could be at the bottom,
or it could be in an entirely separate window.
But you get something that looks a lot like this
and what you've got here on the left is,
I'm going to just make it a bit bigger for you guys to see.
What you've got here on the left, this is the right,
this is the left, and here you've got
some extra things at the bottom.
What you've got here is the HTML of the page.
This is the entirety of the page content.
As you can see it starts up here with HTML
and then you've got the head tag,
you've got the body tag, that has the main set of content.
You've got a header, which is a HTML tag
for sort of the top of the page,
and then you've got a lot of different nested components.
You've got a div, which is just a block of content.
That div has another block of content
and that has some sort of list.
UL stands for unordered list.
And that's this up here, this breadcrumbs,
that's the page you're currently at.
You've then got another div, on the inside.
You've got sort of a bunch of other things.
You can use Google Chrome here
to very easily see what each element is.
For example, this aside here is the sort of
left hand bit that has the navigation,
different types of books you can look at,
and then you've got this one here
that is the rest of the page.
So if you could only see this,
and you wanted to get the price,
You would sort of hover over here
and find out this blue section.
This is where, what you're interested in
is inside this section.
Then you would sort of go in and you would find this div.
You'd then see this UL,
but what you're interested in is not in here.
So you'd look at this div, the price is inside this div
because it's inside the blue area.
Then you'd look at this side,
the blue thing doesn't include the price,
so it's probably not inside here.
Then you'd find this div, and this div
does contain the price, so then you could go into it
by opening it up and sort of navigate that way
until you find the section that you're interested in.
So you'd find the section, then you'd find this div,
then that, then this list item, this article,
and then you've got there the price eventually.
And then you can find it.
So what we found here is essentially
the hierarchy of elements that end up containing
the thing that we're interested in.
So as you can see, we've got the P that contains the price
and that's inside a div, which is inside an article
and so forth.
So this is going to be really important
for you to be able to understand
the HTML when you download it.
The interesting thing is also that you can see
that there are a lot of similar elements.
And that's one for each book in the page.
You can see that as I hover over these,
different books get selected.
And each of these elements is one book.
So if you wanted to load the price of
all elements on the site,
once you've managed to download the HTML,
which we will look at soon,
all you have to do is find each LI element
with these classes here and that's going to give you
all the books.
Well, it will give you at tag objects
in Beautiful Soup for each of the books.
Then, for each of the books you could
pass it to the class that we created
and parse the price out, and the name and so forth.
So you could then start working with these books
in Python as opposed to in HTML.
Okay, now when you want to get the data out
and use it from within Python,
it's not enough to load it in your browser.
Of course you have to get Python to do it.
And in order to do that, we're going to instal
another library called requests
that is used to essentially request
some data from a page and download it.
So that you can then use it, or look at it,
or print it out, or anything you want.
So that library will be used to get the page contents,
this HTML, and then we will use Beautiful Soup
to understand that and extract the data.
Lets look at that in the very next video.
So I'll see you there.