Hi, welcome back.
In this video, I just wanted to tell you
a little bit about killing threads.
I've gone back here in the code to the code before
using the ThreadPoolExecutor,
and notice that we've got thread1.start
and thread2.start.
Then we've got space to write more code,
and then we wait for them to finish.
Inside this space here, you could write some code
to kill the thread, for example, if it meets some criteria
or maybe you no longer need it or something.
You could write some code to kill the thread,
but you should not do that.
Don't kill a thread. Wait for it to finish.
If you kill a thread manually without being really careful,
what can happen is that your thread has acquired the GIL,
you kill it before it releases the GIL,
and then what you've got is the GIL is gone.
No other thread can pick it up
because it wasn't released before.
Threads will not release the resources
just by killing them.
You need to release the resources manually
in the thread code itself.
If you have your thread and it's started,
and it's using the GIL and then you kill it,
the GIL is gone, no other thread can get the GIL,
your Python programme will stop.
It won't terminate, because the thread here
will be waiting to finish,
but it won't be able to do anything,
and if that happens, if you have a resource
that's being used and nothing else can use it,
this is called a deadlock in computing,
and it's a bad thing.
So, just be careful. Don't kill threads.
And that's just all I say.
Don't kill threads, it's not easy to do,
and I don't recommend it.
If you kill threads, you're going to have problems,
so don't do it.
That's it for this video. I'll see you in the next one.