Hi guys, and welcome back!
In this video, we're going to learn
about iterating over dictionaries.
Just as we iterated over lists or tuples
with the for loop, we can iterate over dictionaries.
Imagine you've got a dictionary of your friend names
to their ages, such that you can access friend_ages Rolf
to get 25, or friend_ages Anne to get 37.
You can do for name in friend_ages.
And again, this is a variable that we can name
whatever we want, but I'm calling it name at this point.
And you can print name.
What happens when you do this is,
you're iterating over the dictionary's keys.
So what you would get here is Rolf, Anne, Charlie, and Bob.
The values, 25, 37, 31, 22, will be ignored
and won't be present anywhere in here.
So if we run this, you'll see that you get the keys back.
If you wanted the values, you could iterate
over friend_ages.values.
And then if we run this, now you'll get
25, 37, 31, 22, so just the ages.
Name, age in friend_ages.items.
And what you're gonna get now
is this tuple of names and ages
that you can de-structure into two variables directly here
in the for loop, and you'll get the name and the age.
This here is the most common way
of iterating over a dictionary.
Usually, you'll either iterate over the keys only
or you will iterate over the key and the value
by using .items on your dictionary variable.
This is great because it allows you to get
both the key, in case you want to show the key information
when you're printing it out, and also the value.
Remember that if this value is a list,
or another dictionary, or a tuple,
you will still get it in here, just the entire
list or dictionary or tuple.
So anything that is here will be age
and the key will be name.
So there's iteration over dictionaries,
and that's why I introduced to you tuple de-structuring
earlier on in the course.
Thanks for joining me in this video,
and I'll see you in the next one.