Hi guys, welcome back.
In this video, we're going to look at selecting a tag.
We're gonna go about it the opposite way
than we've been going about things until now.
We're gonna start off at app.py,
and then we're gonna move over to the quotes page.
And this way of developing can be really good
as well, so I'm just gonna try it out
so that you can see what I mean by it,
and maybe you can do this on your projects.
And what I mean is we're gonna first decide
what we want to do and then we're gonna go over
to our quotes page and implement how that's done.
So what we wanna achieve is to select an author,
then we wanna look at what tags are available.
We wanna tell the user look you've got
these tags, which one do you want?
And then we're gonna select a tag from those.
So we can do something like tags = something like
page.get_available_tags,
and notice that this doesn't exist yet,
but this is just me using something
that I know doesn't exist yet
because I'm trying to decide
how I wanna interact with a page object,
so that I can then go
and implemented these meth--
Then we can say something like select one
of these tags, and we're gonna put a list there
with format
that .join tags.
So this tells us a little bit
about get_available tags.
Get_available tags is gonna give us
a list of strings, and then we're going to join
those strings using this pipe character,
which is gonna essentially give us
something like love/music
and anything else.
And so on, this is what that join is gonna do,
and it's gonna print it out in this string
inside these square brackets.
And then we're gonna ask the user
for their selected_tag.
We're gonna say input enter your tag,
and finally we're gonna do page.select_tag,
and we're gonna pass in this selected_tag there.
So what this means is that we've now decided
how we want to use the page,
the QuotesPage, class.
If we are happy with this implementation,
we can go and actually write these methods
in the class, so let's go and do that.
We're gonna go over to QuotesPage,
and it's gonna be very similar
to what we have here.
All we're gonna do is add another drop-down,
very much like this one,
that says tags_dropdown,
and it's gonna find by TAG_DROPDOWN there,
and it's just the same thing as before.
And as well as select_author we're gonna have
get_available_tags, which returns a list
of strings as we agreed earlier.
And that is gonna return option.text.strip
for_option in_self.tags_dropdown.options.
And once you have a select,
you can access all the options inside it,
and then you can do option.text
for the actual contents of the option,
.strip is gonna remove any white space
at the end and at the start of an option,
so that it doesn't have any extraneous
white space when you print it out.
And then we also need select_tag,
which takes in a tag_name
which is a string, and then just
a self.tags_dropdown
.select_by_visible_text tag name.
Too many brackets there.
There you go.
So these are methods that we wanted to use
from our app.py and, like I said earlier,
this is just going
the other way round for developing.
Instead of trying to get the whole programme
in your head, and implement all the methods
and then go and try to use them,
you can decide what you wanna achieve first,
and then go and implements the methods you need
in order to do that.
I actually do this quite often,
and you may like this way of going
about things as well.
Let's go and run this,
and Chrome will appear first,
then we can select Bob Marley,
and then you get here select one
of these tags, which are all the tags
in the drop-down.
Notice that in order to get these tags,
the browser has already selected
Bob Marley from the drop-down,
so then we can enter our tag
and, by the way, this here is the first element
of the drop-down, the one that you can see
selected right now.
And then you've got love, music and friendship.
So these are the other elements
in the drop-down,
you could get rid of this one if you really wanted to,
but to be honest I think is a problem
with the website more so than anything else.
This is a thing that you can select,
so I think it makes sense to leave it in there,
and then we're gonna select love,
for example, and there you have that
selected in the drop-down.
The next step is, of course,
to press the search button
and get the quote information out.
All right, that's everything for this video.
Just wanted to show you this alternative approach
and, of course, implement
the tag selection in our programme.
We can move onto the next video
where we're gonna do some searching.
I'll see you there.