Hi, and welcome back, in this video we are
looking at generic decorators for any function.
We saw this code a few videos ago, when we defined our
user_has_permission decorator, notice that this decorator
doesn't take any arguments,
and then we have a function inside it, that takes in
an argument, the original function takes in an argument too,
and we talked about how, making the decorator have this
argument here, in order for it to be able to pass to
the original function, it actually couples the decorator
to this function specifically because they must have
the same signatures, the secure_func and the my_function
must have the same signature, the same number of arguments,
and indeed we looked at that when we use this,
in another() function...
We got something that, an error, essentially, we said
print(another('movies')), we get...
This, "another() takes 0 positional arguments but
1 was given", because we passed in a panel to that function,
but this function did not accept a panel, and if we didn't
call it with 'movies' there, because that wouldn't make
any sense, if we call it like this function suggests,
and we run it, we now get another error which is
"secure_func missing 1 required positional argument".
Remember, another() gets replaced by secure_func using the
decorator, and secure_func does require the panel.
But we are not calling it with a panel, so it cannot work.
As you can see neither of these functions is happy,
with or without the argument, so what we must do is make our
decorator take in any number of arguments, and then pass
them all into the original function, so...
Like so, (*args, **kwargs), this takes any number of
positional arguments, and this takes any number of named
arguments, this is a tuple, this is a dictionary now.
So, we must pass them further into the original function.
We must pass all the arguments in this tuple, and to do that
we are going to do *args, and we must pass all the arguments
in this dictionary as named arguments, and in order to
do that, **kwargs.
Now they are happy, and if we run it, you'll see that we
get exactly what we'd expect.
"Password for movies panel is 1234."
And then "None", because this another() function doesn't
return anything, but if we were to print something out
or to return something, something would appear here.
This is how you make a decorator generic for any function
that it affects, and it's really important that you do that,
otherwise your decorator is only gonna work with some
functions and not others, and that can be quite confusing.
Particularly when you have a decorator like this one.
When they have a name that sort of makes sense and you
maybe wanna apply it on any function, you must remember
to make it generic.
This doesn't change at all by the way, if you have another
level of functions, if you have a decorator that accepts
arguments itself, this stays the same, and it will still
be a generic decorator.
So that's it for this video, I wanted to show you how to
make generic decorators for any function, and you'll be
encountering decorators throughout your Python journey
and also you'll be encountering situations where using a
decorator will be the best solution, and now you'll know
that they exist and how to use them.
I'll see you in the next video.