Hi and welcome back.
In this video we're looking at scraping
this quotes page that you see here
and we're going to do that before moving on to the books
just because this one's a little bit simpler.
And what I'm going to teach you over the next few videos
is how to structure your scraping applications
so that you can do anything you want with them.
In this section we're going to build two projects.
The quotes page scraper,
and then the books page scraper which is going to be
actually very similar, at least in structure.
Let's start by analysing this this quotes page.
The URL, by the way, is quotes.toscrape.com
so feel free to have a look yourself as well
if you want to sort of play around with it.
What we've got is, as you can see
a few different elements in the screen.
We've got some sort of title up here,
we've got a login page down here on the top right,
we've got top 10 tags,
so these things are presumably clickable so these are links.
Then you've got individual quotes in these rectangles here
these sort of cards.
Whenever you see something that looks structured like this,
you know it's going to be an easy scrape.
This page is designed for scraping so of course it's going
to be slightly simpler than other pages
you may see out in the wild.
But what we're going to learn in this section
is really going to help us scrape any page,
not just these simpler pages.
So what we've got here are a number of different cards.
And each card contains a quote as well as the author
and a bunch of tags here that we can scrape.
What we're going to do is we're going to create a programme
that will give us the quote contents and also the author.
That's it, pretty simple programme.
Again, what you learn will mean that you will be able to
extend that programme beyond that by any amount.
So let's start by inspecting the page source
just to know what it looks like.
As you can see here on the right, we have ourselves
the body of the HTML that contains all of the content.
Inside there we've got a div which has a class container.
That contains all of the content as well.
And then we have a row which is a header box,
and beside it we have another row,
which is the rest of the content.
Inside that row we have a number of, well two columns.
One that is col-nd-8,
and the other ne that is col-nd-4.
And it also has another class called tags-box.
So this is the tags, this is the quotes.
In the quotes we have a number of divs,
each div with a class quote that has one of the quotes.
So we know that each of these divs is going to be
exactly identical to all the others except in the content.
But inside one div, we have a span which has a class text,
and that contains the quote,
and another span which contains by and also a small tag
which contains the author,
also a link which contains the about page of that author.
Then it's got another div which contains the tags.
There's a few things in here, and amongst them is an a tag
and that has a class tag.
So inside that tag we have change, deep thoughts,
thinking, world, and so forth.
If you were to look at any other of these quotes,
you would see that it is essentially the same.
A span with class tags and that contains a quote.
Another span that contains a by and small tag which contains
the author, and then another div here with the tags.
And so forth.
So we know that as long as we manage to get these divs
and for each div get this data, we'll be able to extract
all of the data that we need from the page.
So we're going to do that in the very next video.
We're going to structure our new application in order to
be able to understand this page.
I'll see you in the very next video.