Hi and welcome back.
In this video, I just wanted to give you a small tidbit
of extra info regarding arguments and parameter naming.
Remember, object-only programming is used to help
conceptualise the interactions between objects.
So, in between parts of your system.
So when you have a student, now you know that you
can interact with something that represents a student.
If you had a movie class, you'd know that you
can interact with something that represents a movie.
So, let's define this movie.
Remember, we've got a class, and then we've
got the name of the class, a colon, and then we
can define functions underneath it.
All I wanted to do is define a dunder init function.
That takes three parameters: self, that's the
current object that we're dealing with that
was just created before we called this function.
Name and year, those are two parameters.
Then what we're going to do is a self.name is name,
self.year is year.
And this normally confuses my students a fair bit,
because we've got this variable we're creating here,
name and as you go to this variable you
already created up here, which is also name,
so name=name, what is going on?
This name here, remember, it's not a variable,
it is a property of self.
This variable is not getting created here,
it's getting created inside of self,
that's what the dot means.
So we're defining a new variable or property
inside self, which is called name, and that is equal
to the value of name variable that exists
in the current scope, this function,
that's this parameter here.
So this is totally fine.
Now our object is going to have a property name,
just like our student had, and its value
is equal to this parameter here.
These are two entirely distinct parts of our code
and parts of the structure of classes and objects.
So we can print (Movie('TheMatrix, 1994').name).
This is, by the way, just a shorthand way
of doing this, it's pretty not very useful
'cause you're just creating this movie
and you're not assigning it to a variable.
But you know, you can do that, you can create a movie,
you can print out its name, you can run it,
and you get The Matrix out, okay.
Of course you can store this movie inside a matrix variable.
And then you can print out matrix.name,
that's totally cool as well.
You can put objects inside lists and as it topples,
you can put them in dictionaries, you can put them
anywhere you would want, okay?
An object is just a value, like a string is, or an int.
You can put objects anywhere you could put a string,
or an integer, as long as it makes sense,
for example, you can not add an object to
another object, that probably doesn't make much sense.
We'll be looking later on at how you can do that,
but not yet, you can't do that yet.
Similarly, you cannot, for example,
multiply an object by another.
That probably doesn't make sense,
you cannot multiply two students together.
Okay, this is probably getting mildly inappropriate.
You cannot multiply two movies together, for example.
So, that's what objects are.
They are conceptualizations of entities in your programme,
and that's a pretty lingo-filled phrase,
but that's what they are.
They're used to represent things
that you want to interact with.
Okay, and that's it for this video, I just wanted
to once again reiterate what this is all about.
And let's move on over to the next one, see you there.