Hi guys and welcome back.
In this video, we're gonna be pressing that search button.
So, let's start with app.py.
We're gonna do page.search_button.click.
That's how you interact with something in Selenium
and in this case it's gonna be that search button
that doesn't exist on the quotes page yet
and then we're gonna do print page.quotes.
So, let's go over to the quotes page
and add our search button.
I'm just gonna add it down here
underneath the tags dropdown.
It's gonna be a property search_button
and what this is gonna do
is return self.browser.find_element_by_css_selector
and that is gonna be the QuotesPageLocators.SEARCH_BUTTON.
And that's it, you've got the button,
you can click on it now,
we can run app.py, Bob Marley.
We're gonna type love
and there you have your quote.
And if you go back to the site,
you'll see that this has actually worked.
The button has been clicked
and this is how you interact with websites using Selenium.
As you can see, it's not all that complicated.
You have to have a page model
that reflects what the page contains
and what it looks like
so that you can then very easily just say okay,
I wanna click this button,
I wanna select this thing and so on.
It is the app.py though
that is starting to get a little bit more complicated
just because it contains all the logic
about how we're gonna interact with the page.
We're gonna ask what author you want,
then we're gonna select an author,
then we're gonna get the available tags,
then we're gonna print them
and then we're gonna ask for which one you want
and so on and so forth.
We can make that a bit simpler
by encapsulating some of this logic
into the page as well.
Remember that this page here
doesn't only have to contain page elements.
It can also contain page actions
like selecting an author,
getting available tags, or potentially performing
the whole search flow.
Let's go and do that in the next video.
I'll see you there.