Let's go to an example Spring Data REST project and add in the Springfox
dependencies and a class to configure Swagger. We'll then build it and see
what the default documentation looks like.
Here's our example Spring Data REST Project.
We have an Employee entity that has a few different attributes, id, name,
title, and department, with the basic constructors.
Spring Data is handling all of the endpoints that are generated for this entity.
We've set up a repository for the Employee object, and we're using Spring Boot.
We've also added an example service that has a simple get request.
We've configured it to run on port 8080 and enabled
some of the Spring actuator endpoints.
If we try to hit the Swagger UI right now, we get an error.
We haven't added anything yet,
so we need to configure this project to include the necessary libraries.
First, we'll add in the repository for the Springfox artifacts. Next,
we'll define the Springfox version that we're going to use. Currently
we'll be using the 3.0.0‑SNAPSHOT, because there's some things in 2.9.2
that don't quite work with our Spring Data REST setup. Finally, we'll add
in the three dependencies, springfox‑swagger2, springfox‑swagger‑ui, and
springfox‑data‑rest.
That's it for the POM. Now let's go create the
configuration class for our Swagger.
I'll call it ApplicationSwaggerConfig. We'll add the required
annotations, @Configuration, @EnableSwagger2WebMvc, and we'll
import the SpringDataRestConfiguration.class.
Next, we'll add our method to create the Docket object.
Remember to add the @Bean annotation to the method.
It doesn't matter what you call it, I'll just call it employeeApi,
and it will simply return a new Docket object.
We'll be using the SWAGGER_2 spec for this project.
That's why we specified DocumentationType.SWAGGER_2.
Everything else is just the default for the Docket object. We'll get into
some of the customizations for this in the next module.
But for now,
let's restart the app so it can pick up the Swagger UI, and we'll check it out.
We'll go back to our web page and refresh,
and now we have our default Swagger UI. Notice how the Employee Entity and
the other endpoints are automatically picked up by Swagger.
We can expand to see the different methods and even try hitting
some of the services with the REST client.
So that's all it takes.
We added three dependencies and a repository to our POM and a configuration class to generate the Swagger Docket.