When someone says, "Let's use Swagger in this project",
what exactly do they mean?
Swagger started out as a simple open source specification
for designing RESTful APIs in 2010.
In 2015, the Swagger project was acquired by SmartBear Software.
The Swagger specification was donated to the Linux
Foundation and renamed the OpenAPI.
The OpenAPI specification is a standard for RESTful APIs. For example,
here is a JSON document that was generated from this Spring
Data REST project that describes the API in a way that
follows the OpenAPI specification.
Swagger UI is the software that can read that JSON document
generated from your project and display the information about
your API in a human‑readable form.
The Swagger API is also a REST client you can use to interact with your API.
There are several other Swagger tools available to
help with design, documentation, test, and deployment of your API.
You can learn more at http://swagger.io. Springfox is a library that
makes it easy to generate Swagger from a Spring project.
It utilizes existing Spring annotations to generate the Swagger document and
also supports Swagger annotations you may use in your code.
Overall,
you want to maintain a balance of not adding
documentation information just to add it.
For example, if you had an Employee class with a name attribute,
it doesn't really add much clarity to put Employee name.
Let me say that again.
Sometimes less documentation is more clear to the end user.
If there's nothing more to say than the class name and the attribute name,
then don't bother.
Leave it alone.
Your code and documentation will be more clear and easier to maintain.
Springfox tries to maintain defaults that makes sense for a Spring project so
you're not forced to add annotations all over the place.
Now that you understand a little more about Swagger,
and you've seen the end result, join me in the next module,
where we'll go through the details of how to use Swagger in your Spring Data REST API project.