Hayes and welcome to this new tutorial in the previous Statoil we just made this first GET request to
mine a new block and now we're going to make a second GET request which will be to get the full block
chain displayed in our user interface postman.
So we're going to do exactly the same as what we did for our mind block request meaning that we're going
to use the route decorator to specify the name of that request and more specifically the URL of this
request and to specify also that TO GET request.
So that's why I'm copying this right now.
I am pasting that here and here we just need to replace this name mind block by the name of our new
request and we're going to call this new request get change.
As in we're going to get the food chain and this method is still going to be a GET request.
By the way you're going to understand much better the difference between a GET request and a POST request
in Mudgal to where we will introduce as well that POST request.
But for now we only need to get request and that's exactly what our Get chain request is going to be.
All right and now exactly as we did before we were going to define a new function.
So I'm starting with Def and this function we're going to call it well get chain and same.
It doesn't take any argument.
We are ready to start defining it.
So it's going to be a much more simple function than the mind block function we made previously because
basically in this function we're just going to display the fool chain in our block chain.
And therefore what I'm going to do directly now it's going to look surprising but I'm directly going
to get my response variable which will contain what will be displayed when we send the get request when
we make that request you know the response that will Jayson ify same as we did before will contain this
whole block chain in the Jayson format.
All right.
So I'm introducing here some brackets because we are going to input two keys and of course two values
and these two keys are going to be first the chain which will be nothing else than this chain list in
our block chain object.
So in the end it functions as chain list is initialized as an empty list.
But of course you know when we mine some block with this mind block function that we get with the mind
block we quest.
Well this chain here is going to be populated with the blocks containing all their keys and we are going
to display in this response here all these blocks with all their keys.
So the response is going to be long but things to this change very well that will be populated.
Well we simply need to input here to change key and therefore here we are starting with the chain key
and the value of this key is simply going to be the chain of our blotching block chain the chain you
know block is our object.
And from this object we get the chain attribute that is the chain variable.
Perfect That will give us the whole chain displayed in this response.
And now we are just going to add something else which will be quite practical when our chain is getting
long very long.
It's the length of the chain.
You know we don't want to count the blocks in the whole chain when it's getting huge.
It would be quite practical to have the length of this chain displayed at the end of the response and
therefore I'm going to introduce here Nuki which will be in quotes length and that will be of course
the length of the chain.
And how do we get exactly the length of this chain.
Well very simply we can use the len function inside which we input the chain of our block chains.
I'm just copying this and pasting it here and there we go.
We will get the length of our chain.
Perfect.
So that's our response.
That's it.
We were ready to return it in the Jayson format with same the HGP status code 200.
To tell that everything is OK and therefore I'm going to copy this right now.
Copy and paste it just below like this.
And there we go.
I have very exciting news for you now.
We are ready to start the demo.
We're going to do this in the next its oil.
I can't wait to show you this.
And until then and Joe bludgeons.