Hello and welcome back to the course on blotching.
And today we're going to be talking about mining.
It's going to be a two part tutorial.
All right so let's have a look where we are on our map.
We've talked about hash cryptography the immutable ledger.
We've now also checked off distributed peer to peer networks.
And finally we're moving on to the mining in these two tutorials we're going to find out exactly what's
the whole system is about why is there mining.
What's the competition that everybody's participating in.
Why is so why are so many resources allocated or dedicated to mining block chain bitcoins and things
like that so let's have a look.
Here is our block in a block chain.
And as we discussed it's got a couple of fields so it's got the block number at the top.
It's got some data.
And as you can see here I put in some fake data where I said sent I'd love 500 odd coins.
Then I bought something on ebay for a hundred odd coins at once and some person named Joe 70 odd coins
and what I'd coin is is a cryptocurrency that you'll be creating together for on line in module two
of this course is a short preview of the exciting stuff that's coming up ahead.
And something I wanted to point out here is that notice how I put not just one transaction into this
block but several We'll discuss this in more detail in module 2 but it's already a good idea to keep
in mind that a blog doesn't just store one single transaction or block stores multiple transactions
so several transactions get put into a blog.
And then with watching moves onto the next one.
So just something to keep in mind and we'll discuss this in more detail later.
Then also in the blog we've got a field for the previous hash or the hash of the previous block and
this is a very important feature of block chains because that's how the cryptographic link is facilitated
between them.
Had this feel the blocking wouldn't be blocking.
And finally we've got a field for the hash of the current block.
And how do we get the hash of the current block where we take the block number of the data and the previous
hash put all of that into all that together into a hashing algorithm and it spits out a hash for us.
And there it is.
That's our hash.
And so here this instantly asks for a question and the question is if it's so simple to just take the
block number the data and the previous hash put into hashing algorithm and get a hash out like in which
takes a half a second if it's so simple then how come black What's the whole fuss about mining.
How come there's so many like hundreds of thousands of mining rigs around the world are like nodes around
the world and lots of mining rigs and a lot of competition powers dedicate to them.
Why is this all happening and what's this competition that everybody is in.
If this is all there is to mining a block Well in reality it's not as simple as that.
There is actually another field in a block and it's time to reveal this field.
The field is called non-SS and not stands for number used on the once.
And so this field is what mining is all about as we'll see from the story on the next one.
Everybody is just changing this field all the time.
So to understand this let's have a look at what is it that now controls the hatch.
What is it that now dictates the hash of the block in this new updated structure that we see.
Well it's these things how it in the Green Square.
We've got the block number the non-SS is now included in that party.
And then we've got the data and the previous hash.
So now we take all these four components we put them into a hashing algorithm and then it will spit
out the hash value.
And so all of a sudden now what the non-SS gives us it gives us extra control gives us extra flexibility.
Now we can manipulate the hash value by changing the non-SS so we don't have to change the block and
we can change the block number because the block number is the block where we can change the previous
hash because it's linked directly to what we have in the previous block and we can change the data because
that would mean we're tampering with the data and that would defeat the purpose of a blockade.
It has to be an immutable nature.
We want to prevent tampering.
So now because we have the nons we are free to change the value of rods and the nonces just basically
a number we were free to change the value of insurance and that will allow us to change or to manipulate
the Hashi to vary the hash.
The proper word is very Because as we know they're hashing out with them we cannot predict in advance
what it will spit out.
We put in a nonce and it will spit out something that we cannot control the hash.
But at least we can vary the hash by varying the not so let's have a look at how that works.
So let's put in 19.
So here let's go back for a second.
So nuance is like zero.
Right now it's empty and that's why we have a certain hash then we put in like a random number 19.
We get a higher and different hash 20 different hash 21 again different hash 22 23 then we can do I
O something I wanted to point out here so you can see that the hash is changing.
And also notice how where do we go from let's say 20 from 21 to 22.
Notice how the hash is changing absolutely like dramatically.
And why is that happening.
Or that's the avalanche effect in action.
What's happening is in the block itself.
Essentially we just changing one bit of information.
So if you write it out in binary code you will see that this blog has like some combination of ones
and zeros.
And to go from this to this we're just changing literally one bit somewhere from 0 to 1.
And that is that's all the change we're doing.
But at the same time the hash used is completely unrecognizable completely different to what we had
before.
And that is important and will be important why we'll see in the next tutorial.
But that's the avalanche effect and actually I just wanted to illustrate that.
OK.
So that's how we change and also just take a random number this turn and 43 like there's ten thousand
nine hundred fifty five.
So non-SS is a number that can go up to like four billion something.
So it's quite a large number there's a lot of variety that you can play around with the nonce.
And that gives you variability in the hash.
So there we go that's a starts to mining.
We'll end the first part first tutorial of this two part series here because that was like an important
concept that might be the blocks have nots which we can control.
We can change to vary the hash and in the next tutorial we'll put it all together and you'll see why
exactly that's important and what the miners are actually doing with their electricity and all their
power.
All right.
So intro this Tauriel and of course he likes them.
Until then enjoy bludgeons.