Hello and welcome back to the course nonblocking.
And today we're talking about the Non's range.
So what do we know about the notes so far.
Well we know that it's a field in the block which allows minors to purchase space in the cryptographic
puzzle challenge.
And how is that.
Well minors cannot change any of these fields except for the nonce and therefore they have to variate
the non-SS in order for all of this to change and for the hash to change and varing and ons they vary
the hash and they hope to get a hash closer and target as soon as that happens then they win the puzzle
and they can add this block to the chain and they get the reward.
And so that's what we know about the not so far.
But here's some additional information.
The nonce is not infinite.
We cannot keep incrementing the odds forever.
The non-SS is a city to be at number meaning that there's only 32 bits of memory allocated in every
single block for the knots.
And to illustrate that that means that non-SS is an integer which has a range.
It can only be anywhere between 0 and approximately 4 billion.
So the node has a limit has a cap of four billion.
And that's that's very important.
And for those Oh's that are marked for those of you or techies out there who are programmers is a 32
bit unsigned integer meaning it doesn't have a sign at the start.
And it can therefore it's all usually say two numbers are up to two billion.
But here it's up to 4 billion because it doesn't sign anyway.
So the conclusion here is that the nodes has a cap.
It can only go up to 4 billion and you might be thinking Well Carol that's very interesting.
Good.
Good trivia fact.
But why is that important for us.
Well let's have a look.
Let's do some estimations and we were done the first part.
We've done the difficult estimations but practice makes perfect.
So let's do them again.
Total possible 64 digit hexadecimal numbers that exist in the world is 16 to about 64.
Approximately 10 to the power of seven then total valid hashes with 18 Anything that are assuming the
current difficulty of 8 leading is 16 to the policies for my safety and approximate two times tenth
of our acreage.
And that means as we discussed previously probability that a randomly picked hash is valid.
Or you know is will solve the cryptographic puzzle is the second number.
The Kuroda valid hushes divided by the total number of possible hashes and gives us two constants of
power of minus 22.
That's very very small percentage.
This is the likelihood of you solving a cryptographic puzzle.
If you pick a random just pick a random hash or that's the same as saying if you pick a random.
OK so we're going to underline this number because we all need it in the next concussion.
Now for the nonce.
Right.
So now we know additional information about the nuance that's getting here the nuances of 32 bit number
of the max nodes nonces two to about three to approximately four billion.
So let's run that to 4 billion.
And we'll underline that in green.
And so this is the important part.
So the question we're trying to answer is is the nons enough to brute force with 100 percent certainty.
Our hash of the puzzle so assuming no collisions meaning that all of these are going to generate unique
nonces unique high hashes.
This means that there will be for 10 cents a bar of nine different hashes from the if you go through
the whole long range you try every single number and that among those four billion you will end up trying
four times ten to the power of nine.
So four billion different hashes.
And so the probability that one of them will be valid.
That's just one of them will be valid is if we take this and we multiply it.
So that's our all the hashes that we try now we multiplied by the percentage likelihood of one of them
becoming valid.
And they would go multiply by that and we get 8 10 percent above minus 13.
Approximately 10 to the power of minus 12 if we're on the top 10.
And that gives us 0.00 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 1 percent chance.
So it is tiny still.
So basically even if we go through a whole range of the Unknowns from 0 to 4 billion and something we
go through a whole range of the nodes we will still this is still the likelihood that we will find a
solution to a cryptographic puzzle.
So the conclusion here is that one non-stranger is not enough that even if you go through the whole
knowns you are very still unlikely to find the golden ones a golden gods and.
And so this puts everything we've been discussing before under the magnifying glass and puts so much
doubt.
Instill some alleged talent in us right now right.
Like can you feel it that before we were pretty confident that you know like we just going through the
nuance and then and then we we will find a hash solution to the puzzle so let's go here.
So we are going like OK so we're just going to try the non-SS of it you'll find that hash.
But now all of a sudden we got you know one first first element of news that we got is while the nonces
only limited up to four billion.
So there's not much you can go really far only up to 4 billion.
And the second Going to the information that we derive now is that the nuance is actually not enough
so that 4 billion is not enough.
So does that put the whole cryptographic puzzle under question is this Is there even a solution if if
the probability is the probability is this small that we will get a solution.
Then what's the point of trying to solve it.
What was going to happen when we get to that 4 billion.
And and you know like what's the what's what's a new world look like.
Well let's say let's say this first thing that's a modest miner does about 100 million hashes per second
and that's like not the fastest not the slowest type of mining rig that you can get 100 quite modest
100 million hashes per second.
It has 100 million.
Hundred million different hashes.
And that means 4 billion.
Our 4 billion is that four billion iterations of the non-SS that you're going to have will be done in
if you do Eifel billion by a hundred million.
It'll be done in 40 seconds so.
So what does that mean.
That means like in 40 seconds we will be done if we have this minor ribeyes minor in 40 seconds will
be done with the whole long range and then once and that's the ends right.
Nothing we can do anything from.
Well not exactly.
And here everything is thought through Here's where we introduce a new field again.
In reality there is an extra field which we haven't talked about yet and it is the time stamp.
It is the time stamp.
All of you know when this blog is being mind and the time stamp updates every single second.
So here I want to show you a Web site so if we go here.
Time to I-Slash Unix time now with Kevil you.
This is the current Unix time.
And what's the Unix time is.
Is the number of seconds that have passed since first of January 1970.
So this is how many seconds it was since then.
And so this is a time is often used in computers and programming and so on because it's so convenient
it's pretty much universal.
And so if we go back here that's the Unix time stamp and it gets updated every single second.
So what that does for us is it creates a loophole.
It creates a solution to our problem meaning that every single time every single second this this information
and this block will be updated because the time stamp will increase by one second.
And as I remember from the avalanche effect the hash even if we don't change is on all and CVN which
won't change anything.
The hash if we rehash that will be absolutely different.
So we know that and therefore what that means if we illustrated is that if we draw a non-trained here
from 0 to 4 billion and then we put a timer.
So we only have 1 second.
So basically we have one second to go through this non-stranger before the time or upgrade of that.
So what happens is we go through non-stranger bam one second past we only go that far.
So we tried all those nonces none of them match.
We didn't get a hash.
Most likely.
And what happens next is time updates.
So one new and you second and that means all of these nonces are valid.
Again this is the important part.
All of these nuances are again valid we can try them again because the information inside has changed
even though it's changed by probably like one bit in here in the timestamp.
It still has change so what this time.
Tiny thing.
So every single lawn's now can go into this block again and we can try it again.
So there we go.
We go again.
Boom another second pass.
Who hasn't been passed.
And you can see that this you know this miner is going in you know doing different range of ranges every
time.
I just did that for illustration is you be a prick.
Approximately the same range you know unless it's like overheating or like or too cold or whatever.
But the point is here that you can see that every single time we go through a certain number of nonces
and then the Times time gifts.
So what I wanted to point out it's not a bad thing that we never get to these and nonces it doesn't
matter at all.
It's actually a good thing that we have an opportunity to reuse the nuances that we were used otherwise
if this wasn't updating if there was no timestamp.
We just get to the 4 billion we wouldn't find on ASH and then we'd have nothing to do but because the
timestamp is updating every second and it takes this miner 40 seconds to do the 4 billion.
Well this is actually generous so this should be like 140 of from here to here.
This purple thing should be up to get up to 148 like tiny but for illustration purposes so here maybe
this is a more efficient manner.
And so basically what that's showing is that again the time stamp is updating where we're going through
as much as we can of the non-SS timestep update.
OK cool we can start again and start again and start again.
So that gives us and effectively infinite number of combinations of times and plus.
So we can go through and get the hash.
All right.
So that's that's really cool.
That solves the problem for one miner for one miner that's doing 100 mega hundreds mega hashes per second
hundred million hushes per second.
OK but how about the mining pool right.
What about the money pool.
So let's have a look.
Will that solve the problem for a mining pool.
If we go here data and go to charts and we go to high Schritt
OK I hope you sit.
Sit tight on your chair.
Don't let this knock you over your shoulder off your feet.
So the current hash rate looks like it's 25 right.
Twenty five million.
Looks like it's $25 million.
No this is the current hash of the whole network and the current hash of the whole network is shown
here in Terre hashes second trillions of hashes per second.
So the current hash rate of the network is that's that's were eventually going to say we invented you
that.
But at current rate of the network is 22 million trillion hashes per second.
I'm going to say that again just because it's such record number 22 million trillion hashes per second
that's how much rate the rate is now by the way you can check it out for all time.
You'll see how it's changed throughout history.
Like 22 million trillion the hashes per second.
They will.
Like of course they're not all working together.
There are a lot of them competing against each other.
But even if we go to go hear back to charts and we find the hash redistribution we know that BTC dot
com is 27 percent of that 22 million trillion hash rate per second.
Right.
So basically.
So even if we take this one via BTC or slush pool 10 percent right 10 percent of 22 million trillion
hash it hashes are second is 2 million trillion hushes per percent.
So basically that slush pool will smash through we'll smash through that non-SS range in no time.
Like in in 0.00 zero or something seconds they'll smash their super quickly.
And so what we discussed here if I go back this this solution that it takes us 40 seconds to go through
a nuance.
And we only have one second Intel updates.
It works for one miner but it's not a solution for a mining pool.
The money will be gone through the nons even before the second bureau even before like this clock has
has barely started will be really gone through a lot.
And so that begs the question What is the solution for a mining pool.
How does a mining pool approaches this problem because if the money pool goes to the nonce in from 0
to 4 billion like like that clicking my finger and trying to go my finger goes like super fast forebear
and then they have to wait until this updates you know until the second is over until they can do it
again.
Then there is so much wasted capacity.
They just like sitting idly doing nothing.
And that is not acceptable.
That's not how the system should work.
It shouldn't have that constraint.
So that's the question for now.
And that's the question we're going to answer in the next tutorial.
I hope you enjoy this one.
That is pretty interesting stuff like we are slowly building up on the Hill knowledge so non-SS tons.
Up next we're going to have some more.
Hope you're enjoying this quest into the world of a blog chain and bitcoin mining and yet our next attorney
is going to be fun.
We're going to learn how mining pools are how hard potentially this problem is solved.
That even mining pools can participate and without you know all the answers.
How this constraint is actually lost error constraint.
There's something else that we haven't discussed yet that helps avoid this constraint.
All right so on that note thank you so much for being here today and I look forward to seeing you next
time.
Until then enjoy bludgeons.