A little collective of course on block chain.
And today we're talking about soft forks and hard for us.
So we already mentioned folks a couple of times the most recent time was when we spoke about the Dow
attack and how they solved the problem by creating a hard for.
So let's have a look at what that means what is hard for it was for.
And what are some examples.
So this is what happened back then you 3M in July 2016.
BLOCK number 1 9 1 9 9 9 9.
So one hundred nineteen thousand nine hundred ninety nine.
What they did is they introduced new rules that would allow to reverse the logic in the contract that
allows the attacker to steal either from the doll.
And what that meant is after that that turned into a hard fork and basically we'll talk about exactly
what hard for kids.
But after that the theorem chain continued and they reversed the funds and returned them back to other
people that contributed them and close down the dollar.
At the same time there were people as we discussed that were unhappy with this decision because they
said that look it's very sad that the money was stolen.
But at the same time rules are rules.
If we said that contracts are binding on the blog chain then they have to be such.
And it's your fault that you made a mistake in the code and we will not agree to changing it so some
minors decided not to go ahead with that not to change their software to the new hard fought so hard
for Wisky mean there's a new software than you and you upgrade to the Bauchi software which allows for
certain things that previously were not allowed that were not possible.
And so what happens then is what happened then is the chain.
Those miners continued mining the old way that didn't upgrade.
They split off so they split off into their own version and that version is now called ethereal classic.
So right now there's two you can look at them on the exchange you'll see that there's a theorem and
is at the classic And that's the reason why it happened because there was the doll attack and some people
didn't agree to bending the rules to returning money back into back from such an attack.
And so yeah majority went with this but some still went with this.
And so you can see that theme classic is traded is actually quite a big cryptocurrency.
Another example of a hard Forgue is Bitcoin bitcoin in July 2017 in July 2013 on 20th July 2017.
Bitcoin accepted segregated witness but that happened as a sophomore and that happened on block number
four hundred and seventy six thousand seven hundred sixty eight.
That's where Bitcoin except the or more C-grade witness we've already touched on segregate this before.
And the interesting thing it was the software.
So there's no reason for this to happen this doesn't happen.
And so folks that really will understand exactly why it is second in the next couple of slides of this
and why we saw that doesn't happen.
As you can see everything went smoothly.
However there were still people who are unhappy with this decision to desegregate witness because they
thought that doing segregated witness is a way like favors people who want to treat bitcoin as a digital
investment rather than actual actual currency because this doesn't increase the books.
So there were people who before so agreed with this were arguing that we shouldn't have Remember cigarette
witness or die.
What it did is it stripped out the signature from the block and put it into its own messaging system
meaning that now effectively you can put two megabytes or two between two and four megabytes of transactions
or two or four minutes which was actually the blog.
You get all the blocks has to worry about it because out-of-home for the signatures will be stripped
and the transaction the core transactions themselves are only going to take up less than 1 megabyte.
But they were people before security.
Witness like before here who are saying they were opposing C-grade with and they were saying that look
C-grade witness is like a patch solution is a temporary solution to the problem we have let's increase
the block size to 8 megabytes and let's have it that way we just can put in more transactions into a
book anyway.
Let's do that and increase the block size.
And so the majority of you know the bitcoin network and community said no we want to keep.
We want to go has agreed with this official they did this of course here.
And everything went nice well but people who were posing with this there were still unhappy and they
decided to just buy themselves to do that upgrade to 8 megabytes to increase the block size.
And so what happened this happened on the first of August so that it was this was 20th of July this
was first of all was not that far away like 10 days.
What happened.
So that was good for so forth.
They don't block 4 7 8 5 5 8.
What happened is Bitcoin continued.
But there were some miners who switched to Bitcoin cash.
This uses the most called that cash and why.
Why was it Bitcoin cash.
Well because that's just the name they chose.
Well the difference here is that on this version the block size has increased it's eight megabytes Whereas
on this version it's still 1 megabytes.
And that's that's the difference why they changed I started doing this and that inevitably the chain
split into two that happened in August 2017 and then interestingly enough if we move this here.
So interesting enough the ethereal energy was just continued.
And but this was in 2006.
So this is how this one group that was that way.
But in the Bitcoin world it continued but actually in on 24th of October 2017.
So not that many months afterwards.
Blog number 4 9 1 4 0 7.
Another hard for Copland's So another hard for.
What happened was people were unhappy with this whole situation.
Remember we're talking about a sick mining and that they completely made DGP use redundant.
Some people are unhappy with that and they decided we want to go back to GP you mining.
And so at that blog they changed their software to make it a sick resistant so that miners miners could
no longer mine it and therefore they went to Bitcoin gold.
And that happened in October.
So this is actually for the Southfork 20th of July this happened first of August the hard for to Bitcoin
cash and 24th of October happened hard for Bitcoin gold so there's always reason so there's a reason
for the dollar tax.
They had to change the software to raise the money here.
Bitcoin cash was on happy the Segway so they changed their software to increase book size to 4 megabytes
and because these are not compatible they're inevitably a chain split.
And here the reason was that these miners were not happy with aligning with asix because A-6 are very
expensive devices they want just continue mining with GP use like back in the old days.
And so they just pull it off and they change their software to become a sick resistant like they get
3M hashing is a separate system.
And so they split off into Bitcoin gold as you can see this can happen very freely because it is a distributed
system.
So the participants decide its future for themselves and if somebody is unhappy or something and there's
enough there's enough support for that cause they can just split off into their own network and start
you know they're all watching.
No there is no central authority to say no we're not doing this or this is not allowed.
No they can do whatever they want.
And that's the beauty of the system and so maybe maybe after some time some of these boards might be
like turn out to be and like people stop liking them people don't want to mind them and then they'll
just die off or maybe they'll continue growing or maybe they'll grow something big that concussions
is pretty big right now.
Yeah.
So that's how this thing works.
Couple of things to mention here.
So first of all we'll talk about some folks just now and we'll talk about hardcore acts as well.
The thing I wanted to mention here is that if you are on funds before a hard for is first of all.
First of all this sort of this part fork's don't have to result in a split.
So the owners are split if there's people who are unhappy with certain things.
So it's as if we couldn't catch the people who wanted to go to a big buy so the hole between that were
just 28 megabytes.
Everybody would go down this route and it would be just called Bitcoin but would go like that way with
eight megabytes.
And so that for a hard for it's a term that's is like reference's software.
So they're forking the software and they're forking the change.
Is a soft form of the software.
There's a hard fork of the software here but as you can see it results in a physical form of the chain
simply because there are people who are unhappy with the way the hard work work.
So in reality this is the hard for the software is the hard fork.
But what we do see is we actually see a physical fault because people decide.
Some people choose to chose to serve the old version.
So that's important to understand that forking refer is a good hub a common term that is there for to
take making a copy of the software.
And if it's a software we'll discuss It's one thing hard for Wasil discusses different thing but it
just happens that if there are people who are unhappy with the heart for it then we'll see the split
the physical split in the chain.
So the term originates from what we do with the software and we do the change.
The other thing is that if there is a physical split in the chain like we see here if you own fonds
at the start.
Like here for instance of a theory if the theory is you don't either.
And there's a hard fork like that which actually results in the chain then you will keep on.
So let's say you own 100 E-3 here you will own 100 either here but you will also get 100 E-3 classic.
Why is that.
Well because the 3M chain is this one.
But the classic chain is not just this little bit.
It's this whole bit all the way up to here.
So classic actually has the exact same history up until this blog as a theory.
So any transactions any any mind goy mind currency that happened before the split will be present in
both chains and that explains how the hacker could steal you know some money here they stole from the
dollar they stole 50 million worth of either.
And then that a mob got reverted back to the people of the Dow.
The the investors of the Dow they got the money back.
But then the hacker also walked away with 50 million worth of either classic in the end.
How did that happen.
Well because of this for obviously when the hag happened like it was 150 million dollars the hack happened.
It was all in the ether.
And I think that it was all either so soon as it had happened the price were either dropped because
you know there was uncertainty and so then it also splits.
The prices change or so maybe at the time of the.
It wasn't as much as he actually walked away with 67 billion dollars.
It wasn't as much as that.
That's according to the Bloomberg article that we mentioned previously the Brister.
So at some point the Bloomberg article mentioned measured it to be 67 million dollars.
Doesn't that doesn't mean it was right there was out of money.
But the point is in term in terms of gold in terms of either.
Yes.
All of that gets duplicated so all there was a hacker duplicated here and got reverted back to the owners.
And here it stayed with that Tiger because the new rules were not adopted by the classic in terms of
Bitcoin.
Same thing if you own Bitcoin here if you own if you own one bitcoin before 20 of July just before June
and July before first of all it was thousands of because 20th July was over here.
This label should be over here.
This is first of August 2013.
If you own one bitcoin before.
First of all we sell 17th 17 stores here then right now you will have one bitcoin cash you'll have one
bitcoin gold and you'll have one bitcoin.
That's how these things work because again the whole history is surance if you owned that say one bitcoin
if you purchase the Bitcoin between the first of August and 24th of October somewhere in here right
now you'll have zero bid on cash and they should purchase it separately but you also have one Bitcoin
and one bitcoin gold.