Welcome to this module on penetration testing and security vulnerability
assessment. Before we dive deep into this module, let's begin to
understand what AWS shared responsibility model is.
The AWS offers three different types of services.
First one is infrastructure services.
Second, container services. And the third one is abstract
services. In AWS shared responsibility model, AWS is responsible
for the security 'OF' the cloud, and you as a customer are
responsible for security 'IN' the cloud.
The shared responsibility model for each of these services differs slightly,
and we are going to look at infrastructure service in detail.
When we says security of the cloud,
we are referring to the security of the infrastructure ranging from
physical security, network security, and regulatory complaints. As a
customer, you'll be more focused on securing your instances by
applying security patches on time,
protecting data at rest and in transit, keeping users
policies and configurations all up to date.
Services like Amazon EC2, ELB, auto‑scaling, and VPC
follow infrastructure services model.
Each of these infrastructure services are provisioned by AWS and operated
within the specific region where they have been launched.
Just like on‑premises infrastructure, you will then install the required OS,
and then you install your applications, and customer data will be
residing at the top, which is managed by your applications.
Customers are responsible for patching, upgrading, and
maintaining compliance to security standards.
Most of the AWS customers felt that their existing
vulnerability tools were hard to adapt,
and they were looking to AWS for more cloud‑native solutions that they
can use to complement shared security model so that they can automate
the vulnerability detection and recommendations as how to run and
manage their EC2 instances securely.
This resulted in AWS coming up with a new service, and that is Amazon Inspector.
It's a security service that assesses applications for exposure,
vulnerabilities, and deviations from best practices, and produce a
detailed list of security findings.
Let's look at some of the key features offered by Amazon Inspector.
Automated assessment. With Amazon Inspector, you can make security
vulnerability assessment as part of your regular ID operations by
integrating it with your development and deployment pipelines.
The assessments are done by an agent that gets installed in your EC2 instances.
These agents can be installed manually using the run command in System
Administrator, or they can be installed manually.
Pay‑as‑you‑go pricing strategy.
You can start your Amazon Inspector for free, and you won't
be charged for your first 250 assessments.
And then they will start charging you 15 cents for every
assessment, which will go down to 4 cents as the number of
assessments keeps increasing.
Flexible operation. Amazon Inspector can be accessed from the
management console, SDK, and there is an HTTPS API as well that you
can use to access these APIs programmatically.
Let's look at some of the terminologies used in Amazon Inspector. Inspector
agent. This is the agent that needs to be installed in your EC2 instances that
collects the data and checks for vulnerabilities.
Rules packages.
This is a collection of rules that your agent will check against
before generating the vulnerability reports.
You can think of these as security goals that you would
like to enforce in your EC2 instances.
Assessment target.
It is a list of EC2 instances where these
vulnerability checks will be performed.
Assessment run.
This is an operation where the agent monitors, collects, and
analyzes the configuration data from resources that are mentioned in
your assessment target. Assessment template is a configuration that
is used during the assessment run,
which defines the rules packages, SNS topics, tags of your instances,
and the duration of the assessment run. Findings.
This is a potential security issue that Amazon Inspector
discovered during the assessment run.
In Amazon Inspector, different security rules that are used to identify
potential security issues and vulnerabilities are grouped as rule packages.
There are checks to be run against your instances.
You can include all the rules, or select a few of them to target a specific
area of concern, how to address a specific security problem.
Here are the rule packages that are used in Amazon Inspector.
The first one is common vulnerabilities and exposures.
The rules in this package help you identify if your
instances are exposed to the latest vulnerabilities that
can compromise the confidentiality,
integrity, and availability. Center for Internet Security benchmarks.
These benchmarks provides an industry‑recognized best practices that
help organizations improve and assess the security. Security best
practices. Amazon Inspector has a list of best practice recommendations
that help identify if the systems are optimally configured. The last
one is network reachability.
This helps identify those restricted ports that may be reachable from the internet, either via internet directly or through a VPC gateway.