With the security threats increasing day by day, it's very
important that we follow best practices recommended by AWS
in securing the key pairs.
Maintain one SSH key purpose.
If you're using a functional account that is being used by multiple users,
make sure that the keys are rotated on a constant basis.
Add passphrase to your keys. Without the passphrase, anyone that have access
to the keys will be able to log in to the instance. Restrict the sudo
access. Sudo access needs to be given on a case‑by‑case basis only. A
read‑only user should never have sudo access.
There is a reason why they were given read‑only access to begin with.
You can also set up monitoring tools to check if
someone is illegally trying to use sudo.
Never store your private keys in your temp directories or home directories.
Best practice is to keep them in a hidden directory that's known only to you.
AWS has presented you with many services and tools to monitor the
user activities in EC2 instances. Let's look at a demo and see how
to view user activities in CloudWatch.
The first step is to create a role that can create a log group and publish logs
to CloudWatch. I just logged in to IAM console. I already created a role named
CloudWatchEC2. It is associated with one policy.
Let me expand the policy, and you can see the policy allows four actions,
and it is not specific to a resource.
Second step is to attach this role to the EC2 instance.
Let me go back to EC2 console. Click on Running instances.
Let me select the instance that is running, and the IAM role is linked
to CloudWatchEC2 role that we initially created.
Next step is to install the CloudWatch Log agent in the EC2 instance.
Let me use yum install to install AWS Logs agent.
Since I had already installed the agent,
I'm getting a message saying nothing to do.
If you are setting up this for the first time,
this command would install the Log agent under etc
directory, and the output will be very different.
Once the AWS Logs agent is installed successfully,
you will see a new directory named awslogs. Let me open awslogs.conf,
where you can configure the file name under
corresponding log group and log stream name.
I'm going to stream the secure file that is under /var/log.
This file keeps track of all the user activities.
When you are setting up the config file,
please pay close attention to the datetime format,
and this should match the timestamp used in your log file.
If not, the logs will not be pushed to the CloudWatch,
and you will see an exception in the log file. Let me open awscli.conf where
you can configure the region where the logs will be pushed.
Let me start the agent and make sure that it is up and running
now. Switch to /var/log, and open awslogs.log, and check for
any errors in running the agent.
Next step is to monitor the logs in CloudWatch.
I just logged into CloudWatch console.
Click Log groups to your left.
Switch to the region where you configure your log agent. Click on secure‑log.
Open the log stream.
You can see it lists all the user activities.
You can filter the logs to narrow down to any specific events,
like sudo access that you would like to monitor.
Let me monitor the logs in the last 30 minutes. You can see our action of
editing awslogs.conf file has been recorded and reported.
There are multiple ways where you can track user activities using
CloudTrail and CloudWatch, and this is just one of the options recommended by AWS using the CloudWatch logs agent.