In this clip, you're going to see some of the common security threats that you,
as a security administrator,
need to be aware of while designing the security of your application.
Before looking at some of the common security threats,
let's quickly revisit and understand AWS shared responsibility model.
To explain this, let me draw on an analogy.
Let's assume that you own one of the shops in your local mall.
The property owners will take the responsibility of securing the entire mall by
providing mall cops and security agents who will be constantly patrolling the
property with the intention of providing safety,
responding to emergencies, and preventing criminal activities.
But you, as a sharp owner, will be responsible for securing your shop,
setting up monitoring equipment,
and protecting the customers and goods that are within the shop.
Similarly, at a high level in AWS shared responsibility model,
AWS is responsible for security of the cloud,
and you, as a customer, are responsible for security in the cloud.
AWS offers three different types of services.
The first one is infrastructure services.
The second one is container services.
And the next one is abstract services.
When we say security after cloud,
we are referring to the security of the
infrastructure ranging from physical security,
network security, and regulatory complaints.
As a customer,
you'll be more focused on securing your instances by
applying security patches on time, protecting data at rest and in transit,
keeping user policies and configurations up to date.
Let's look at some of the common security threats
that need to be addressed by you, as a customer.
First and foremost is improperly configured IAM privileges that
allow individuals access to restricted resources.
So as a security administrator,
you will need a thorough understanding of AWS IAM.
And when in doubt,
always start with least privileges and provide more access as needed.
The next one is security group configurations.
When you are setting up your EC2 instances,
you need to make sure that the inbound and outbound rules are
configured properly by allowing traffic from the right resources
and expose only those ports that are needed.
Never let your inbound rules have CIDR blocks that
open up access to the entire world.
Later on in this module,
you will see how _____ alerts you in case of improperly configured
security groups that allow access to unrestricted ports and how to
set up a CloudWatch event to monitor it.
Next is to protect the data in your S3 buckets.
An improperly configured S3 bucket with a wrong bucket
policy that allows users to read or write data stored in
S3 buckets might prove disaster.
As mentioned before,
it is always recommended to be conservative by starting with
minimum required privileges and never allow read or write
access to your S3 buckets to everyone.
Next is improperly configured CloudTrail.
Though CloudTrail is enabled by default,
it provides 90 days of event history for all management events.
It is not a permanent record, and it also doesn't record data events.
For auditing purposes,
you must create a trail that delivers logs to S3 buckets
that are configured with write privileges.
To make sure you obtain a complete record of events
happening all through your AWS account,
you should configure the trails to log events in all AWS regions.
As a best practice preventative measure,
AWS recommends using a centralized Amazon S3 bucket that is
dedicated to capture all CloudTrail logs and encrypt it using
server‑side encryption with AWS KMS.
With this approach,
all your security controls and access policies will be in one single place.
The next one is setting up more restrictive network ACL rules.
Network ACLs access a firewall and control traffic
that is going in and out of a subnet.
By default, they allow all inbound and outbound traffic, unlike security groups.
Network ACL rules are prioritized based on the rule numbers.
A lower number rule will always be executed first.
So it's very important that you don't set up a lenient access
that opens up all the ports and IP addresses,
and start with a restrictive one and allow traffic from known IP addresses only.
Creating public AMIs.
In the first module,
you saw the role of AMIs in launching an EC2 instance and how you, as a
customer, can customize and create your own AMIs.
Since these AMIs can contain proprietary and sensitive data,
AWS recommends to set up these AMIs as private, and any public AMIs need to go through a thorough review process.