Let's log into AWS admin console and look at different AMIs in
the AWS Marketplace and launch an EC2 instance.
Click on EC2.
I currently have one running instance.
Click on AMIs to your left.
From the drop‑down, select Public images.
This lists all the AMIs that are currently available and
ready to create an EC2 instance from.
The search bar lets you filter the AMIs based on different attributes of AMI.
Let me select Architecture as the key and choose 64‑bit as the value.
Then, let me select the platform as the key,
and you have the option to choose any Linux images,
and I'm going to choose Amazon Linux.
Let me select the first image,
and you can see that the virtualization type is HVM,
and the root device type is EBS.
You have the option to launch an EC2 instance directly from here using
this AMI and selecting one of the machine types.
Let me cancel this as I would like to explore further details about AMIs in
AWS Marketplace. Click on Instances, choose Launch Instance. As a quickstart,
AWS offers AMIs that are eligible for free tier,
but let's go to AWS Marketplace. Under Categories,
select Infrastructure Software.
Select Security This lists all AMIs that are custom‑built by third party
vendors with security being the primary focus area.
Let's take a look at Kali Linux,
which is free tier‑eligible. And this is a Debian‑based Linux
that is aimed at advanced penetration testing.
Let me select this image,
and you will have detailed information about this AMI, including the
pricing options for different tiers. Under Highlights,
you can see the standard features of this AMI. Click on View
Additional Details in AWS Marketplace. A typical, per‑hour
price is listed to your top right.
Let me click on Pricing,
and you need to pay special attention that pricing has two components to
it. First one is software pricing, and the other one is infrastructure
pricing. And as the infrastructure size grows up,
the cost increases as well..
Click on Continue to Subscribe.
After reviewing the software pricing policy, click on Accept Terms.
It will take a few seconds before the subscription gets activated.
Once activation completes, you will see an effective date and expiration date.
Click on Continue to Configuration.
Estimated software pricing information is to your right.
Select the fulfillment option, software version, and region
where you would like to launch this instance.
Click on Continue to Launch. Choose Usage Instructions under Configuration
Details to get a brief overview on how to connect to the instance and some
additional information if you are planning to perform penetration testing.
Select the drop‑down under Choose Actions, and you have multiple options
to launch this instance. I'm going to choose Launch through EC2. Click on
Launch, and you'll be taken to EC2 console. Click on Review and Launch.
I'm going to accept all the default values.
Click Launch.
Select the acknowledgement and choose Launch Instances.
Click on View Instances to see the instance that we just launched. Under
Description, you can see the public IP, the security groups, and the inbound
and outbound rules. To explain the pricing a little bit more in detail, I
just logged into AWS Marketplace again.
This time, I'm going to choose Machine Learning under Categories.
Select ML Solutions.
Let me select the Deep Learning Notebook that was free tier‑eligible.
Click on View Additional Details.
You can see that this comes ready with plenty of software that are
required for a typical machine learning modelling process.
This AMI has pricing both for software and infrastructure.
When you are calculating the total cost,
you need to keep in mind to include both the cost and not
just the infrastructure cost alone. Again,
as we saw before, the infrastructure price goes up as we move to a larger infrastructure.