Let's switch our attention to AWS GuardDuty.
When you enter some of the large retail stores,
you may have seen people wearing a vest that say's Loss
Prevention Officer whose primary duty is to monitor the stores
and to promote the safety and security.
AWS GuardDuty is the loss prevention officer of your AWS account.
AWS GuardDuty uses machine learning to identify
malicious activities in your account, like exposed credentials,
communication with malicious IP addresses,
unauthorized infrastructure deployments,
and password policy changes.
AWS GuardDuty can analyze CloudTrail logs,
VPC Flow logs, and DNS logs for any unauthorized activities.
You can set up a trusted IP list that are highly secure so that GuardDuty
doesn't generate findings from these set of IP addresses.
And you can also set up a threat IP list so that you can pay more
attention if you see them in GuardDuty findings.
This AWS service is disabled by default,
and once enabled, you will have a free 30 days trial.
Let's jump into a quick demo and learn about AWS GuardDuty.
I just logged into AWS Console. Search for AWS GuardDuty. Click on Get
started. Before enabling the GuardDuty, let's take a look at the
service role permissions. This lists the permissions that are needed by
GuardDuty to generate the findings.
You can see the DescribeInstance and DescribeImages actions have been
included. Click on Enable GuardDuty. And it may take a few seconds
before GuardDuty console gets activity.
Findings tab lists all the current findings.
Click on Settings, and you'll see an option to export your findings
to a specific location at a specific interval.
You can either create a new S3 bucket or use an existing bucket to store these
findings. In order to preview how the real findings might look, GuardDuty gives
you the option to generate a few sample findings.
Click on Generate sample findings.
Click on Findings to your left, and you will see a
bunch of findings sorted by severity.
Click on the first one, which alerts you that a potential
denial‑of‑service attack might be going on.
It shows the instance ID, Availability Zone, private IP address, and
public IP address. Click on Lists to your left.
You can add the trusted IP list and threat IP list here.
Under Accounts, you can add other AWS accounts that needs
to be monitored by GuardDuty.
In that case,
your account will be considered as master account, and the other account will become your member account.