I'm sure if you have been working in any security‑related work,
you may have performed penetration testing to test
the stability of your network.
Recently,
AWS has changed the rule, and they will allow conducting penetration tests
without any approval for these eight selected AWS services. From the list,
you can see that these are some of the core AWS services that most of the
applications will be using. Previously,
AWS had strict rules on performing penetration tests, and AWS
customers were asked to submit penetration testing request form,
and an account needs to be authorized by AWS before they can
conduct a penetration test.
Along with granting the services,
they also have restricted the activities that cannot be performed
during penetration testing, and here is the list of prohibited
activities. Zone walking is a technique that it's used by attackers to
enumerate the full content of DNSSEC signed DNS zones. DNS zone
walking via Amazon Route 53 hosted zones is strictly not allowed
during penetration testing.
Denial of service or distributed denial of service or simulated DoS and
DDoS are prohibited during penetration testing as well.
Port flooding includes UDP flags, ICMP flags, and any other
spoofed packet flooding is strictly prohibited.
You are allowed to use any open source tools and services to
simulate and perform security assessment like port scanning,
vulnerability scanning, a web application scanning, SQL
injection, and forgery activities.
However,
you are not allowed to use any tool or service to simulate
protocol flooding attacks like SYN flooding and resource request
flooding attacks like HTTP request flooding, login request
flooding, and API request flooding.
Now,
if you need to test your network for other simulated events, you need to
send an email to Amazon with the plan dates, account details, other assets
that are part of under contact information.
Since each submission is manually reviewed, you need to plan your
testing and send this request ahead of time.
Now, if you are planning to stress test your network,
the policies are very different.
Before we look at the policy,
let's see what qualifies as a network stress test. If you are trying to
generate traffic over 1 billion bits per second or 1 billion packets per
second that sustains for more than a minute, or if your traffic has a
potential to impact other associated entities, like a shared service
infrastructure, then you need to fill out on Amazon EC2 Network Stress test intake form, which is obtained by sending an email to Amazon.