Before we wrap up this course,
let's quickly look at two different scenarios that will help you gauge how well
you understood the concepts that you learned in this module.
Here is our first scenario.
Steve is a security architect of Globomantics Corporation.
He was approached by his boss because he just learned that some of the EC2
instances has ports that can be accessed from the internet.
Steve has been asked to run a vulnerability test to make sure all the
restricted ports are secure. Which rule packages must he include as part of
his security assessment? Let's look at a second scenario.
Andrew is a security engineer with Globomantics. He has been assigned to a
new project team where he needs to create user accounts and enforce strict
password policies that the user needs to adhere to.
It has been a month after he has set up the user accounts,
and he wants to make sure that the password policies has been strictly followed.
Which rules package he must include during his assessment
process? Try to come up with your recommendations, and we will review these scenarios in the next clip.