In this clip,
we will take a look at Amazon SES and the security
protocols that you can use to connect to it.
Amazon SES is an email service provided by Amazon that can be leveraged to
send and receive email in a cost‑effective way by setting up your own
domains. Where enterprise needs an email service, it often needs to deal with
infrastructure cost, email server management,
network configuration, and so on.
Amazon SES eliminates all these challenges and lets you
leverage the infrastructure provided by Amazon.
The biggest value proposition offered by SES is that it seamlessly
integrates with many other core AWS services, like EC2, EBS, SNS,
IAM, S3, Lambda, CloudWatch, and CloudTrail. AWS SES offers multiple ways in
sending email. Once an email address is validated, you can send an email
directly from the console or using SMTP interface provided by SES, or you can
use the AWS SDK and use Amazon SES API.
Now let's turn our attention and look at the security protocols that you
can use to connect to Amazon SES. First one is HTTPS.
If you are using AWS SDK,
all email communications are encrypted by TLS. Amazon SES
supports TLS 1.0, TLS 1.1, and TLS 1.2.
If you're using SES SMTP protocol,
you are required to encrypt your connection using TLS and SES supports,
StartTLS and TLS wrapper. StartTLS is a means of upgrading an
unencrypted connection to an encrypted connection.
And when you use TLS wrapper, the SMTP endpoint does not perform TLS
negotiation and it initiates an encrypted connection directly. By
default, SES uses opportunistic TLS, meaning it attempts to make a secure
connection to the recipient email server, and if it could not, an SES
will send the messages unencrypted.
This default behavior of SES can be overridden by using
the APIs that are provided by AWS SDK.
This concludes the module on application environment
security. In the next module, we will take a detailed look at AWS config and AWS GuardDuty.