[Autogenerated] Hi, everyone.
My name is Dustin.
Bring Berry and welcome to my course demystifying the EBS
Certified Solutions Architect Associate Exam.
I am a senior solutions architect at a small startup company.
Have almost 10 years of experience using NBS and
currently hold five AWS certifications,
including the CSS Certified Solutions Architect associate.
This course is a quick introduction to help you prepare to sit for the
AWS Certified Solutions Architect associate exam.
We will identify key AD DS services that you must master,
and I will then offer you exam pips to help you crush the exam.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include Key
Resource is to build a mental model of AWS.
What is quick laps and how do you use it?
Breaking down the exam blueprint into tangible services.
Best practices for passing the exam, including practice Question.
By the end of this course,
you'll have a plan to master AWS and ultimately passed the certification exam.
If that's your goal before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with AWS because this course is not
designed to teach you how to use AWS.
It is designed to show you how to locate resource is needed to build a
mental model and then walk you through the exam blueprint,
offering best practices,
exam guidance and practice questions to help you crush the exam.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn AWS with
demystifying the AWS Certified Solutions Architect associate exam course at Pluralsight.