[Autogenerated] we're not going to discuss our next exam.
Objective-C Designing high performance architectures In
order to really grasp what's here,
you need to understand storage things like S3 things like apps,
things like AD FS different storage types.
You also need to be familiar with different compute options,
both serverless computing like Lambda Functions or containers,
as well as two instances.
Networking is also another factor that can come up,
so make sure you're familiar with VPC and virtual
private gateways and even direct connect.
We've covered these a little bit and other objectives,
but you may want to spend more time researching these things.
You also wanna be familiar with different types of database
is we won't cover them specifically here.
You need to have study these on your own need to make sure you're
familiar with our AD DS with dynamodb with document DB With red shift
with elastic cache These are key database is even Neptune that you
need to be familiar with them.
You don't even know a lot of detail,
but you need to know the basics so that you can answer
questions to help you when you are asked for a particular type
of database to use for a given solution.
This will help you tackle these tough questions on the exam,
so make sure you'd spend time in this area.
Understanding, storage and database is is key to creating performance,
storage and architectures.
These topics can be quite deep,
so it's important that you have experience with each of
these and understand the key features.
We talked about EBS volumes earlier from a different perspective.
Talking about resiliency and reliability.
The focus in this area of the exam is to choose the
correct volume type for a given need,
knowing the performance characteristics of the volume,
it's important to understand when an SSD Docker is best and when
traditional hard Docker technology is best.
SSD technology dominates when you have random reads from the Docker.
But if you're looking for sequential reads and writes than a
traditional HDD is going to provide much better performance.
The exam questions will attempt to confuse you on
when to use which storage type,
so make sure you understand when to use each type for a given use case.
The next area of storage will look at is S3.
If you're not familiar with the various storage classes within S3,
you should learn them and know when to use one storage class versus another.
The cost aspects of S3 are important to understand.
For this knowledge area,
make sure that you know that you only pay for what you use
and it's measured in gigabytes per month.
Also,
make sure you understand that you pay for transferring data
out of the region where the data resides.
You also will pay for puts copies post list and get requests
from your S3 bucket and off those get requests or the most
expensive operation you can perform in S3.
If you need to cache frequently access data such as
company logos or product manuals.
Other static content, then S3 convey a great place to store this type of data.
Although there are other types of database is available within AD DS,
the exam tends to focus on three of these,
and knowing when to use each one for a given use case is important.
RDS is Amazon's manage relational database,
and there are several database types to choose from
within our AD DS for the exam.
Make sure you know all six database engines that are supported.
Also, make sure you understand how read replicas are used with our AD DS,
as well as how multi ese deployments function within RDS,
particularly,
you need to understand that replication from the master to the
standby instantiate is done synchronously.
If you need to manage no SQL database is,
then you can use dynamodb, which allows you to allocate throughput based on read.
Write capacity requirements.
Reads can either be what we call strongly consistent,
which are measured in one read per second or eventually consistent,
which gives you two reads per second.
Rights will always be measured.
Is one right per second.
If any of this is unclear,
go back and review other Pluralsight courses that deep dive into dynamodb.
If you need to set up a data warehouse within Amazon,
Red shift is a much more efficient and cheaper option than
a commercial products such as Oracle.
Since this is an Amazon exam,
you should never expect Oracle to be the correct answer unless the
question focuses on least efficient or most expensive.
But typically, Amazon does not word their questions this way.
It's important to understand the use cases in the question and select the
appropriate database technology when you need to cache content.
In AWS, there are many ways this could be accomplished,
but the exam we only focus on three of these.
The first of these is cloudfront,
which can be used to cache both dynamic and static content at the edge.
When we use cloudfront to cache the content close to our end users,
Cloudfront takes advantage of the AWS edge locations.
How it works is the user request is routed to the lowest latency edge location.
It may not be the closest one geographically,
but it will have the lowest latency.
Non cache content is then copied from the origin to the edge,
and as soon as the first bite is received from the origin and into cloudfront,
the content is then served out to the user.
When the next user requests the same data, it will already be in the cache.
If you want to protect content with cloud front, you can use Oh a uh, SSL.
Ohh stands for origin, access identity,
and it's used to restrict access by only allowing access to the origin by
going through cloudfront and it's URL instead of directly,
maybe like you could within S3 bucket.
Cloudfront also supports SSL certificates This works great
for the web layer of our architecture.
But what about the application and database layers?
How does caching work for those services?
Well, we have a couple of options.
The first of these is the last two cache men cache D.
And with this,
we're gonna place in the last two cache note in front of
our database to cache frequently access queries to take
pressure off of the database.
The whole focus of caching is to take the pressure off the database.
Men cache is best served and best suited to cache
content from relational databases,
whereas Red is is a better choice when we're dealing with.
No SQL database is such as dynamodb, even though it's not covered in the exam.
Dax or Dynamo DB accelerator is actually a better choice
when we're working with Dynamodb because it's designed to
work specifically with it.
Many modern online games make use of red is because of its ability to
create leaderboards and perform calculations in real time.
Also,
its support for read replicas makes it very powerful because if you lose a node,
you don't lose all your data that's in cache.
Unlike men, cache T in order to make our infrastructure perform,
regardless of customer traffic, we must be able to scale it.
There are two types of scaling that you should be familiar with for the exam,
horizontal scaling and vertical scaling With vertical scaling.
There's upper limits to to how far we can scale.
Because we're gonna hit physical hardware limitations because we're
increasing the number of CPUC and the amount of RAM and we can only
increase these by so much they have finite limits.
The other type of scaling is horizontal scaling,
and with horizontal scaling,
it is only limited by the capacity allocation of your account.
If you need more instances,
you can always submit a ticket and requests a limit increase for your account.
Horizontal scaling takes advantage of auto scaling,
which allows instances to be created and terminated
automatically whenever you use auto scaling.
You will also want to take advantage of the elastic load
balance or capabilities to help you evenly distribute
traffic between your instances.
When you use theological load balancer,
you can also distribute traffic across multiple availability zones to
provide high availability as well as fault tolerance.
To answer questions on the exam related to auto scaling make sure you understand
the three components of auto scaling launch configurations,
which specifies the instant size in the AM I that you're gonna use.
These can only be copied or replaced.
You cannot modify a launch configuration.
So if an exam question says, modify the launch configuration,
you can immediately eliminated because that's not possible.
The second aspect of auto scaling is auto scaling groups.
They will reference the launch config.
They'll specify the men,
the max and the desired size of the auto scaling
group with the elastic load balancer.
You can also references the auto skip from the auto Scaling group,
and health checks can be set up for the group.
The third component is three auto scaling policy.
This specifies how much we should scale in and out,
and multiple policies can be attached to an auto scaling group.
The third area to pay attention to on the exam is CloudWatch metrics.
Make sure you know what metrics can do monitored at the hyper visor
level like CPU utilization and network bandwidth,
as well as metrics like disk space utilization that can't be seen
at the hyper visor level that require CloudWatch agent to be
installed inside of the two instance.
Also remember that default monitoring is at five minute intervals,
and detailed monitoring is at one minute intervals.
Make sure you know how to read CloudWatch logs and
understand the metrics involved with those.
When you put all of these components together,
it's common moving to the next exam objectives.
Let's take a look officially auto scale.
Your internet get you ready for me to understand how these all
fit together and how we can use CloudWatch alarms to monitor
metrics like CPI utilization in scale.
Based on that other services that are covered on the exam around
this objective are as follows CloudFormation What you need to
remember about CloudFormation that is,
uses a declarative programming language for resource deployment.
It supports both JSON and YAML file in CloudFormation is used to create
automated and repeatable deployments of our cloud infrastructure,
using something called stacks.
CloudFormation is a very large subject by itself,
so please make sure to review the recommended
resource is before attempting the exam.
The next thing we want to look at is auto scaling auto.
Skilling was discussed in another portion of this module.
The key take away is that it is an important component for
designing scalable and resilient architectures.
The last service that you wanna pay attention to on the exam for
this component is Lambda Lambda is a fully managed compute service
that runs stateless code multiple programming languages supported
with lambda like python and C#, for example,
Lambda actually has the support to bring other languages.
So if an engineer wanted to use something like COBOL, that would be possible.
Lambda is what is known as serve.
URL is computing because you can execute code without having to
manage servers before we move on to the next exam.
Objective-C.
Let's take a few minutes to review a couple of sample
exam questions and discuss how to tackle these types of
questions When taking the exam.
Take a look at our first practice question.
The RDS.
My SQL database is getting lots of reads and has become
a bottleneck for the application.
What actions can be performed to ensure that the database
does not remain a performance bottleneck?
Set up a cloudfront distribution in front of the database set up
in elastic load balancer in front of the database set up in the
last two cache cluster in front of the database or D set up s and
s in front of the database.
Take a moment and think about it.
Pause your video, and when you're ready to answer, come back.
So the answer is C.
We already know from the question that the database has become a
performance bottleneck for the application.
So we need to address that.
Well, a cloudfront distribution is not gonna help you in front of a database.
That's not a typical architecture that we see.
So that's not a good answer.
So they could be eliminated,
be to set up in elastic load balancer in front of the database.
We don't typically do that because you don't use database is that
way where you put him behind a load balancers.
Those are for application servers and Web servers.
And then option D is to set up S and s in front of the database.
That's not gonna help you, either.
All that's going to do is send notifications.
C is the only choice in this case to set up in Alaska cache
cluster in front of the database because the Alaska cache cluster
can do take pressure off of the database.
If you remember when we talked about databases and caching?
We talked about men.
Cache de and read is men cache D would be what we would use for
this RDS database to take the pressure off of it.
Let's look at another question.
A company has an application hosted in AWS.
The applications deployed on a set of E C two
instances across two availability zones.
For high availability.
The infrastructure is deployed behind application load balancer.
The following are requirements from an administrative perspective.
Make sure notifications are sent when read requests
exceed 1000 requests for a minute.
Ensure notifications are sent when latency exceeds 15 seconds.
And any API activity, which calls sensitive data, has to be monitored.
So those are the requirements that must be met.
For this to be a good answer.
What meets the requirement choose to In this case,
some of the exam questions will have you choose more than one answer.
It will always be clear because the question itself
won't let you pick too many or too few.
When you're answering the questions, the exam ege and is set up to.
Check that,
And so if you try to have too many choices it'll give you an Arab
won't let you advance to the next question.
By the same token, if you have too few choices, it won't let you advance.
So what meets the requirements?
CloudTrail.
To monitor API activity CloudWatch logs to monitor app activity
CloudWatch metrics to create customer metrics and set up an alarm to
send out notifications when the threshold is reached,
or custom blog software to monitor latency and read request
to the application load balancer again.
Take a minute,
pause the video and think about the answer to the question and come back.
As you can see, the answer is A and C.
If we look at the answer choices,
you can see it says use CloudTrail to monitor API activity in choice.
Be says, use CloudWatch logs to monitor API activity.
CloudWatch is not used to monitor API activity.
That is a function of CloudTrail, so you can eliminate Be immediately.
CloudTrail is for monitoring API activity.
The other option is to use CloudWatch metrics to create
custom metrics and set up an alarm to send notifications
when the thresholds are reached.
Both of those address the key requirements in the question
Option D is really a distracter because we don't need custom
log software for these purpose.
CloudWatch metrics will work great because we can create custom metrics.
Let's look at another example.
An application is being designed for deployment in to S3 application will
use Amazon S3 buckets restoring as well as reading data.
The right traffic is expected to be 6500 requests per second,
and the re traffic is around 8000 requests per second.
What is the best way to architect this solution for maximum
Amazon S3 performance uses many S3 prefixes,
as you need in parallel to achieve the required throughput,
prefix each object name with a hex hash value along with the current date.
Enable versioning on the S3 bucket or set up cross region replication
and performed reads from the secondary bucket Again.
Pause the video and think about it.
The correct answer is B.
Did you get that one?
It says prefix each object name with a hex hash key along with the current date.
Because of the amount of data that we're sending into the S3
bucket because of all the right request going on,
we're creating a lot of objects,
and we're gonna want to randomize these values as much as
possible so that our keys are clearly distinctive.
The problem with not doing this is we can create hot
partitions and S3 and make it more difficult to achieve
the performance were looking for.
So Option B is the correct answer.
Did you get that one right?
Let's take a look at one more question.
A company has a workflow that sends video files through their data
center into the cloud for trans coded they use to worker instances
to pull trans coating jobs from sqs.
Why is Sqs the best choice for creating a decoupled architectures?
Sqs guarantees the order of messages.
Sqs checks the health of the worker instances.
Sqs makes it easier to carry out horizontal scaling of the encoding tasks
or D sqs synchronously provides trans coating output.
Again.
Pause the video and think about it.
The answer is C.
Did you get that one?
Sqs makes it easier to carry out horizontal scaling of the encoding tasks.
If you remember,
cues can help us with our worker processes because we can store
the jobs in the queues and we can monitor the queues with
CloudWatch as the queues get large.
We could scale up more systems as we need to,
and we can do this horizontally for our encoding tasks.
That makes see the the best answer for this question.
Let's take a look at the exam takeaways for this objective.
First of all, for unstructured data, S3 is usually a good storage choice to pick.
Look for caching options to improve performance like we saw in that question,
Alaska cache I can Be very useful to take pressure off of our database is know
when to use auto scaling for a given architectures again.
If you go back and study the well architected framework white
paper that will help you with this Objective-C.
And finally, you want to select the best instantiation size for a given workload.
You know, for a Web application, maybe you wanna use a T two.
But if you're dealing with some CPU intensive operations,
a T two might not be the best option.
Maybe a C five again.
You just have to look at what's there,
and you need to understand all of the available options that
that can be created for two instances. Let's move on to the next objective for the exam