[Autogenerated] Now that we understand a little better what
quick labs is and what it can do for us.
Let me walk you through a simple demo of creating an
account for quick labs from our web browser.
We're gonna want to browse to the Quick Labs website.
Quick labs dot com We're gonna want to find the
joint option at the top of the page.
We're going to click on the joint option.
This is gonna present us with two options.
We can either join with Google or join with email.
We're gonna choose the joint with Google option,
but you could use the joint with email option if you wanted to.
And it's a very simple process.
I'll select my Google account that I want to use, and it's that simple. Your Quick Labs account is now being created using your Google account.