Hello this is Carol from for ex-beau dot com.
And welcome back to the course on forex trading.
So there's going to be a very fun story and we're going to talk about Forex charts very often when you
hear about Fricks charts so you hear the abbreviation o h l c.
So what does it even stand for and what does it mean.
Oh Etchells see stands for open high low and close.
And to get to know the situation a bit better we're going to start by throwing two axes.
The horizontal axis will be time and the vertical axes will be price.
Now these are four blue lines represent each one of them represents the start of a new day on our timeline
.
So right now on our chart we have three days.
Day one day two and day three.
Now let's for a second forget about day one and day three and just focus on day two we're going to use
this chart to represent how the price of a certain currency pair changed through time.
So let's assume for instance that we're looking at the Euro use dollar currency peg when Day 2 started
this currency has already had a price a certain price.
So at midnight of day two there was a certain price.
Let's Martis price move for simple dash at the correct price level.
Also when the day finished at midnight between Day two and day three the Euros dollar currency pair
also had a price.
Let's mark that as well.
So the first dash the one on the left is called the Open price because the day they two opened with
that price and the second dash the one on the right is called the close price because they too closed
with that price.
And also throughout day two the price naturally moved up and down and somewhere there there was a minimum
price of that day.
So let's start at minimum price of an X on the other hand there was also a maximum price throughout
the day.
Let's mark that one for next as well.
If we now connect the x's on the vertical bar and forget about the Xs themselves then we have now created
a complete bar for the euro used all currency pair for that day for day two.
And as we saw through the creation process and Ubar has four price points the open price which is the
Dashon the left the low price which is the bottom of the vertical bar the high price which is the top
of the vertical bar and the close price which is the dash on the right.
So to quickly sum up every bar has an open a low a high and a close price and that's where the abreviation
o h l c comes from.
Now we put multiple of these bars together.
Then we will get a 4 X bar chart.
As you can see the closing price of one day is actually the opening price of the next day.
There are some exceptions to this rule especially if you're looking at a Friday on Monday because something
might have happened over the weekend and the opening price on Monday might be different to the closing
price on Friday.
But generally speaking in most cases bars flow on from each other.
Now sometimes these bar charts can be colored into red and green rather than just black to help traders
see right away which bars are going down and which bars are going up.
Bars that are going down are called Barish bars and bars that are going up are called bullish bars.
But we'll talk more about bears and bulls in one of the upcoming tutorials.
Now this is a bar chart and for us there are actually two more other types of charts that are very popular
with traders.
So the next type of chart and perhaps you've even heard about this one.
But if you haven't doesn't matter.
It's called the candle chart and I'm just going to transition this bar chart into a candle chart and
watch how this transition happens in front of us.
We have the same chart but now it looks different.
Instead of vertical bars and horizontal dashes we've got these rectangles with lines sticking out of
them at the top at the bottom and some of the rectangles a hollow and some of them are filled.
In essence this chart carries the same information that just visually presented differently.
First thing we can notice is that because of these vertical lines some of the rectangles actually do
look like candles and that's why it's called the candle chart.
Now every one of these candles has three elements to it.
It's got a body and it's got two shadows.
Sometimes the shadows are also called tails.
The shadows are very easy to understand because they're the same as what we had with a bar chart.
The top of the top shadow represent the maximum price or the high price and the bottom of the bottom
Sharrow represents the minimum price or the low price.
The body is a bit trickier than with the bar chart.
The bottom of the body can represent either the open price or the close price and the top of the body
can represent the close price or the open price as well.
So how do you understand which one is which.
Well there's a general convention that hollow candles a bullish candles meaning the ones going up and
filled candles are the ones that are going down or Barish candles.
And here a all means the same color as the background filled means a different color the way to remember
this is that hollow are lighter than FILDES because filled have more paint in them or color they're
heavier so they're going down on the whole the ones are larger So they're going up.
That's the way I personally remember it.
So knowing whether a candle is going up or down it's very easy to understand whether open prices and
where the clothes prices this is because for a bullish candle the bottom edge will always be the open
price and the top edge will be the close price.
Whereas for a bearish candle the top edge will be the open price and the bottom edge will be the close
price.
Also candle charts can sometimes be colored just as we sort of bar charts and that helps traders see
patterns quicker.
In this case Red means bearish candles green means bullish candles.
And finally this brings us to the last type of forex chart which is a line chart a line chart basically
simplifies this whole process by representing only one single price.
It only represents the close price.
So instead of looking at open high low and close luncher will only look at the close price so if we
now take the close prices of every single day and we connect them then we will get a line chart.
As you can see it's much simpler and carries less information but sometimes it can be very convenient
to make rough estimations and see overall patterns and then further after this analysis go into more
detail.
Nullus have a look at a couple of real Forex charts.
Here is the year is dollar daily line chart.
So as you can see this is just what we talked about only the clothes prices for every single day at
the bottom you can see the days on the rise you can see the prices.
But most importantly we can see the line chart which is showing us that currently the euro is dollar
seems to be falling down.
Now let's look at the same chart but represented by a bar chart.
As you can see now how much more information might be a bit more cluttered.
But we can see where the highs and lows were and exactly how this progression or this trend is developing
.
And now I'll change this bar chart into a candle chart and you should decide for itself which one you
like more.
So there is a candle chart.
The field bars are the beverage bars.
Bars are the bullish bars and it's actually a matter of personal preference whether you like the bar
charts or the candle charts more.
Some people use candle charts some people use bar charts.
It all depends which one is visually more plausible to you.
And finally I wanted to show you the same bar chart but in a different color scheme because we will
be working with military force and you'll notice that by default the color scheme is different.
It is green on black so I'm just going to transform this now.
And as you can see here this is the typical metal Treader for bar chart.
It's got a black background and it's got black and white bars.
This might be a bit confusing at first because here the black bars are bullish and the white bars are
bearish as opposed to what we had on the previous slide.
But the way to remember is is not black and white but hollow and filled.
In this case the background of the charred is black so hollow will be black and therefore the bullish
bars are black.
In this instance and whereas white is the opposite of black and therefore the Barish bars are white
and they're filled with color in this case.
And before we finish up this tutorial I'd like to mention that forex charts are available not only at
the deli level but at many different timeframes so you could have one minute charge so you can have
10 minute shots you can have 15 minute chance 30 minute charge weekly charts monthly charts and you
can actually have any kind of chart in between because there are special tools to create those charts
for you.
But we'll go into more detail on this in further tutorials and you'll see how we naturally will work
with 15 minute time frames and already time frames all of the concepts stay the same.
On that note we'll wrap up today's tutorial.
Thank you very much for your attention and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy trading