Hello this is Kirill forum for Expo dot com.
And welcome back to the course on forex trading in desultorily We will talk about currency pairs and
how to read them.
So let's have a look at a chart.
This is the Eurodollar daily chart and you can see that the current price for the year is dollar is
one point to five to four.
So what does that mean.
And how do we understand that.
Well let's look at the currency pair at the bottom.
The currency on the left of the pair is called the base currency.
In this case it's the euro and the currency and the right is called the quoted currency in this case
it's the U.S. dollar.
You may see this price of one point to five to four for the Euros dollar currency pair written the following
way.
This is equivalent to writing it out as a Euro slash U.S. dollar equals one point to five to four.
Now let's quickly simplify this example to understand it a bit better.
Let's replace the euro currency with apples and let's say that we're quoting the price of outpolls in
U.S. dollars.
Personally I really like this approach because it takes one of the Unknowns out of the equation.
If you think about Euros like any other money is a tangible object you can hold in your hands you can
measure it.
You can weigh it up you can counter it.
It's something that actually physically exists.
So that means we can easily replace it with something else.
Also physically exists but it is better known to us like apples for example and you can count apples
you can weigh them up and you can hold them in your hand just like yours.
So there's no harm in replacing euros with apples just for the sake of this example.
So here you can see that a price of a single apple in American dollars is one point to five to four
.
And that's exactly what this equation means.
And now if we go back to the euro we can quickly understand that the chart in fact represents the price
of one single euro in terms of U.S. dollars.
So this means that at the point in time when the snapshot was taken for one euro you would get one point
to five to four U.S. dollars.
And conversely to buy one euro you would need 1.2 five to four U.S. dollars.
And this principle applies to any currency pair.
The charge simply expresses the value of the base currency which is on the left quoted in terms of the
quoted currency which is on the right.
So as Paul candle's appear throughout the day and the price changes on your chart you always know that
this is simply the price of the base currency changing in terms of the quarried currency.
Now let's look at another example let's take U.S. dollar Canadian dollar for instance and this example
be a bit more tricky because the U.S. dollar is on the left.
Now as you can see the U.S. dollar is the base currency in this example and the Canadian dollar is the
quoted currency.
How do we read this chart.
Very similar approach.
U.S. dollar Canadian equals one point 1 2 8 7.
It's the same as putting a slash in between the currencies.
And now we can replace the U.S. dollar with apples.
As you can see here we're replacing the base currency with Apple and it doesn't matter that it's the
US dollar.
There's nothing special about the U.S. dollar in terms of forex charts.
The dollar can be on the left is dollar can be on the right.
It doesn't matter what we're looking to do right now is we are looking to replace the base currency
with something that we know quite well.
In this case Apple's.
So in this example we can see that the price of one apple is one point 1 2 8 7 Canadian dollars or approximately
one Canadian dollar and 13 cents.
So now going back to U.S. dollars we can see that the price of one U.S. dollar is approximately one
point thirteen Canadian dollars.
This means that for one U.S. dollar you will get one Canadian dollar and 13 Canadian cents wore converse
to buy one U.S. dollar you would need one Canadian dollar and 13 Canadian cents.
And now when we look at the chart we know that the price is simply telling us how much an American dollar
is worth in Canadian dollars.
And as the price goes up and down throughout the day that's simply the price of American dollars expressed
in Canadian dollars also changing throughout the day.
There are over one hundred and eighty currencies in the world and you can combine any two of them to
give you a currency pair.
Most traders identified two main groups of currency pairs and these are the majors.
The euro U.S. dollar the dollar yen the British pound dollar the Australian dollar American dollar the
dollar Swiss franc and the dollar Canadian dollar and also the second group is the Krause's crosses
.
Or simply put all currency pairs that do not include the American dollar such as the euro.
British pound British pound yen Australian dollar Canadian dollar and so on.
And of course there are also all other currency pairs.
One more final note before we finish today's tutorial is that the order in which two currencies go into
their currency pair is fixed.
So for instance you will never see a currency pair called you as dollar euro or a currency pair called
U.S. dollar Australian dollar.
That's because it has historically developed.
In each case how the currency pair is fixed and people just choose not to change it.
So in order to avoid confusion.
So a Euro U.S. dollar chart will always be a euro used dollar chart and therefore you will always know
that it is quoting the price of one euro in terms of American dollars.
On that note we will wrap up today's tutorial.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then happy trading