Fundamental analysis this type of market analysis is based on that belief or de-emphasis that somewhere
out there in the world there's information or knowledge that is not yet reflected in the market price
.
And traders who use fundamental analysis believe that they can take advantage of that by entering into
the right position whether it's a buy or sell.
Fundamental analysis involves things like reading and understanding news about certain currencies understanding
the global economic climate and what trends are happening there and what was going on in the world.
That is actually affecting these currencies.
Understanding what's happening with resources because a lot of currencies actually correlate with resources
or are heavily dependent on the supply and demand for certain resources.
One of the very convenient ways of doing all of this is through a economic calendar a calendar of economic
events.
It kind of sums up all these things that are happening in the world for you of course you have to do
your own research but it's a good starting point.
And that's exactly what we'll be looking at in the fundamental analysis section.
I'll show you how to properly read a faux economic calendar or issue a really good one.
How to derive insights from it and how to actually trade currencies based on the calendar of economic
events.
Also one more thing that you should keep in mind is that fundamental traders get very attached and very
intimate with the currency pairs that trade so fundamental trader wouldn't be diverse across all the
currency that you have in your terminal.
But Hughes pick one two or three like for example the British pound all the British pound Australian
dollar maybe the euro a British pound he would because he would know a lot about the British pound.
He could trade Krause's of the British pound and also each one of them would be very unique because
only certain events are affected only certain types of resource affected.
And being a fundamental trader you have to develop this and you will develop this kind of intimacy with
the currency pairs you trade to become very good at them and so on one hand you become like a expert
at those kind of spares that you trade.
But on the other hand a lot of the knowledge and skill that you develop in within those currency pairs
are not applicable on other currency pairs.
And that's kind of the two sided coin of fundamental analysis.