Sentiment analysis.
So personally I think that sentiment analysis is valuable but at the same time it's not substantial
enough to be a stand alone type of analysis that you can base your Forth decisions on.
I think sentiment analysis is more of an auxillary type analysis that you can and you probably should
add to your own analysis to make it more robust.
So sentiment analysis implies trying to assess and understand the general mood in the market.
What traders are thinking what what their expectations are and a good starting point for that is Twitter
and Facebook.
So you can go on Twitter Search your currency pair and see what people are thinking what they're talking
about what they're kind of expecting.
And also you can find that out on Facebook and certain groups in certain circles other social networks
like Google Plus basically any type of social network including forums.
Why it's important will because at the end of the day people make transactions in the market and it
matters what people think especially when it's a lot of people think you know how ideas can be viral
sometimes and something can pick up out of nothing.
Like somebody says the euro is going up and and then just spreads very quickly across Twitter and everybody
starts feeling that way and then you know in a matter of an hour or so you could actually see the euro
going up once again because it is rare that just purely sentimental sentiment drives the market.
But it's good to assess it and keep in the back of the mind also sentiment is reflected often in currency
pairs.
You'll be you'll eventually learn how to pick it up from the charts.
Some types of sentiments for instance a good one is when traders are uncertain and they're nervous.
You'll see consolidation on the chart.
So the price Samplitude will be reducing substantially and moreover will actually witness some of these
situations in our live trading on a real account in the further sections of the score's