Hello this is Kirill from Forex boat dot com.
And welcome back to the course and forex trading today we're going to talk about the non-farm payrolls
and unemployment rate for the U.S. as you can see I've got the calendar open it's calendar open.
I've got the chart behind me.
And as you can see already now the price in your dollar is tumbling down.
And I'll just quickly bring this chart out.
The first five she counted back up.
And if we update these news elements you'll see that they have been just released.
The time is 8:29 am and the price is tumbling down for the Eurodollar.
What does that mean.
The Under the non-farm was positive for the U.S dollar.
The unemployment rate didn't really change.
So that means good news for the dollar and that means bad news for the Euro this is a Eurodollar M5
chart.
And as you can see we've got a massive bar going down right now it is exactly 8:30 in New York time
.
The news has just come out.
And what we can see is an incredible dip in prices.
This is December 2014.
And what is happening is just crazy.
This is a massive massive drop.
What how much pips do we have here.
That's about 70 pips in less than five minutes.
Seventy Pip movement in less than five minutes.
And this is happening right in front of your eyes so we can zoom in a little bit more.
This is a massive candle as you can see this is not something you see often.
This is the first Friday of December 2014.
The U.S. have just released non-farm and unemployment.
As you can see the market was waiting for this.
There was a consolidation over here.
And as the news came out right now the market has already dipped about 70 pips.
Now it's really 70 72 73 pips all in the space of minutes so let's just switch to one chart quickly
.
You can see this wall.
This all happened in the space of one minute.
And this is this is why trading the news can be profitable but can be very volatile as well.
We didn't conduct any trades because I find it very risky.
But some people profit from movements like this.
This is incredible.
As you saw the price went down in one minute sixty five pips and then kept going and now is going back
up.
That's something that naturally happens sometimes when the price goes down.
Some traders will try to push it back up at the bottom.
You never know what we're how we'll go afterwards.
But as you can see that is one incredible move and you don't often see things like this.
But if you do want to see them look for them on the first Friday of every month.
So let's go back to the calendar and just reconcile so we've got a lot of news coming out at 8:30.
It was 29 when I opened the calendar so I can just refresh this page now to see what's happened.
So it's 8:32 but you just have to click this button again because it hasn't come through exactly yet
as you can see the prices going back up right now.
So once again unemployment rate hasn't changed and that just doesn't mean anything.
But the non-farm employment change so they were expecting a rise of about 230 1000.
It actually rose by three hundred and twenty one thousand.
And the previous actual was actually worse than the forecast.
This actual is much better than the forecast.
So this is nearly by 100000 better so that's nearly by 50 percent better than the because it's actually
less than 50 percent but much better than the forecasted value.
And that's why the U.S. That's very good for the U.S. as you can see here actually green forecasts good
for currency.
So that's really good for the U.S. dollar.
And that's why the euro dollar tumbled down.
Meaning that the U.S. dollar got stronger as compared to the euro dollar.
And what do we see here.
The price is going went down went up a bit and now it's going back down again.
And that's one of those just standard situations when some traders try to push it up and then just keeps
going down.
So we'll keep this chart open.
And right now what I'll do is I'll open up another chart.
Let's look at the dollar yen.
As you can see here we've also got a massive spike here that's the one on the chart if we look at the
five minute chart you'll see a massive spike here as well.
So let me just get rid of this grid.
So a massive boost in the dollar yen going up Eurodollar still going down.
Let's look at another one.
As you can see the markets are going crazy if you look at the market watch on the left.
Prices are changing very rapidly.
That's also because the euro dollar.
The euro U.S. markets have just opened up and this news came out at the same time.
So lots of factors coming together on a Friday well for me it's Friday night for the U.S. It's Friday
morning in early December 2014.
Also it's more significant because this is the last time that non-farm and unemployment are released
for the year because it's December and that adds to the mix as well.
So let's look at dollar Canadian for instance and we'll switch to five right away or even Let's look
at them one chart see what happened here.
Right now this is great.
Get rid of it.
Maybe hit the grid.
What do we see here we see a massive increase so this is happening virtually on every currency pair
that has the U.S. dollar currency in involved.
So there was a massive increase here massive increase here massive drop here and it just keeps on dropping
as you can see so we can zoom out just look at the magnitude of these movements.
This is already 73 pips in about the space of five minutes.
So you can earn massive amounts of money here if you choose to trade fundamental analysis.
All right.
So that's pretty much it for today.
Just wanted to mention that.
Personally I try to avoid situations like this because if my forex robot or my technical analysis has
a certain pattern it's looking for things like this can actually really skew the results.
So using the 4 x calendar can be also beneficial for those who use technical analysis because it will
allow you to avoid situations like this.
All right so we'll finish up this Tauriel on that.
Look out for every first Friday of every month.
Very important day because these two pieces of news are released.
Thanks for attention and I'll look forward to seeing you next time.