Hello and welcome back to the course and Forex trading in today's tutorial we will discuss how to trade
fundamental news.
Now we're going to look at an example of what we saw for the non-farm and unemployment news that came
out on the first Friday of December 2014.
So I've got a snapshot of the chart that we were looking at in the previous tutorial.
Right in front of me here.
And as you can see we saw a huge drop in the Euros dollar currency pair.
Once the news was released at 8:30 a.m. New York time.
And so this massive spike how would we go about trading it if we're waiting for it and we're watching
the news well.
Generally speaking all conceptually speaking the method is quite simple.
So what you would do first of all is you would obviously look at the news you would figure out when
your important piece of news is coming out or a piece of news that you think will be important and then
if you have some sort of predictions on whether it's going to be beneficial or detrimental for the currency
then you would open a buy or sell order just before the news comes out so somewhere over here.
But in most cases you cannot predict what the news will be.
A lot of the time we don't know if the news is going to be beneficial or detrimental for the currency
pair and therefore there isn't.
Actually actually there's a strategy that allows you to make a profit in either case.
So what the strategy implies is you wait for just before when the news comes out.
So maybe one or two minutes before.
And normally if it is important news and the markets will consolidate and there won't be any sporadic
movement in the markets so everybody will be like quieting down and waiting for the big rush that's
going to come just now.
And so one or two minutes before the news comes out you should set to stop orders so a Buy Stop order
somewhere over here above the current price and they sell stop order below the current price.
And so what that will do is as soon as the news comes out currency parable jump either up or down.
And as you saw in the previous tutorial it just goes that way without moving backwards.
So it just there's no retracement in that movement just keeps going for that one minute or two minutes
in that one direction.
So that means that your Buy Stop order or sell stock order will be triggered and the currency will just
go plowing straight through it and keep going in that same direction.
And that way it will actually reach your take profit which should be maybe 10 20 30 or 40 or whatever
number of pips that you think the currency pair will travel in that movement.
And so that in essence is a very reliable way or quite a reliable way to trade currency pairs because
you will pick up the movement whichever way it goes.
So just waiting for an impulse up or down doesn't matter and you're setting it take profits like a conservative
50 Pipp take profit and you're very likely to get it.
So that's in theory but in practice there is one major drawback.
When news like this happens and the markets are going crazy Most brokers will have trouble actually
executing your order so even though the prices reach the sell stop or bust or pull in this case it would
have been the sell stop over here.
So because the markets are going crazy and the prices change so quickly your broker might not even execute
it and even though the price has reached a sell stop and even past the sell stuff you sell stock might
not even be opened yet.
And more so when the price reaches your take profit the order might have problems closing.
And so in order to implement the strategies you do have to find a reliable broker that can guarantee
you execution of your orders and their respective stop losses or take profits.
So basically that means that the choice of broker is a very important part of trading especially if
you're planning on trading fundamental signals.
Be careful that choose your broker wisely.
What I can do is recommend my review of brokers which is a www dot forex boat dot com slash brokers
.
Those are the brokers that are used predominantly for algorithmic trading but they have proved to be
reliable through my experience and maybe that's a good point for you to start investigating what is
a good broker for your trading.
But otherwise I wish you good luck with your trading if you are trading fundamental trading.
You can be very profitable and hopefully you'll be able to master it.
I look forward to seeing on the next tutorial.
And until then happy trading