Trends flats.
So one of the most common themes in the Forex market is a trend.
Let's try to understand what a trend is exactly.
For example this is how the price has been moving over a certain period of time.
Then as you see here we can draw a diagonal line underneath the price which the price seems to be bouncing
off.
This line is called the support line.
It indicates an upward trend.
It means that the price is bouncing off upwards of this line and continuing its upward movement.
And so what you can expect in a situation like this is that the price will once again come close to
line and bounce off it and keep moving upwards.
That's how user support.
So if you notice that the price has bounced off a dagger like a couple of times in a row then there
is a good chance that it will bounce off the support line.
One more time.
At least one more time.
And that's how traders using technical analysis would enter into a buy order.
The downward trend is very similar but it's just happening in the opposite direction.
So here we can draw a red line a bar of the price and which is kind of not letting the price go up which
is forcing the price to go down.
And this price this line therefore is called a resistance line.
And once again here you can expect that the price will go towards the line.
And there's a high chance that the price will bounce off the line again and continue its movement downward
.
So this is called a downward trend and lines called the resistance line.
And the third type of market is a flat market.
And this in this case we can't draw a support line or resistance line because the market is kind of
flat it's moving sideways.
Some people call the flat market a sideways trend.
I kind of try to stay away from that definition because there is actually no trend in the market so
why bother calling it a side restaurant.
Finally in regards to trends it's always important to check the overall trend on the market.
So if the euro dollar is going down then whatever your other technical name suggests it's always more
favorable to trade downwards.
If the British pound dollars going up overall then you would favor more.
The signals that tell you to try and trade upwards so it's called Trading with the trend and you'll
notice that we will be doing that in our live real trading in this course.