Hello this is Kirill from for ex-beau dot com.
And welcome back to the course and for extruding in today's tutorial we will be talking about the triangle
power.
Now the triangle pattern is a very powerful yet extremely simple formation the 4 X market.
And right now we're going to learn how to use it and make profits with it.
So here we've got a chart a hypothetical chart that's kind of moving sideways.
And if we draw a line above and below the chart we'll see right away that the price is in a triangle
formation.
Where can we go from here.
Next Well it can continue going in the Triangle had more often than not that's exactly what happens
the price keeps progressing in the triangle.
But then there's an issue.
There's nowhere to go the triangle ends and that's exactly when this happens the price shoots out.
Now the shoot out can go up or down depends on the situation the outcome can be different and often
very often unpredictable.
However the main core concept of the triangle is the fact that the price the amplitude of the price
movements is increasing.
So you can kind of witness a consolidation in the market and it's not a coincidence.
It means that there's something happening in the world or in the traders minds that is forcing them
to slow down their trading and is increasing the level uncertainty for this particular currency pair
.
And therefore the market consolidates and then bam all of a sudden something happens and movement picks
up and it shoots out.
So more often than not it will happen exactly in this way.
So the triangle will progress towards very close to its end and then the market will exhibit an impulse
and the price will shoot out up or down.
And that's exactly what we will be taking advantage of.
So the triangle is also a very good pattern because it actually gives you targets.
So if you measure the base of the triangle.
And then you copy this measurement to the place where you think the price will shoot out them.
An aggressive target is exactly the size of the base.
But it is always recommended to go with a more conservative target which is more reliable.
Half of the base.
So if you measure half of the base from the point where you think the price will shoot out that's where
you should such a take profit.
So let's look at the same situation.
But when the price shoots are downwards here you also measure your base copy it over there and said
Chittick profit at about half the distance of the base.
So that's all good but in reality we don't know which way the price will shoot up.
So what do we do do we buy it or do we sell.
Well this is the beauty of training and trying and that's why I love the triangle pattern so much is
because the price amplitude is narrowing down.
And you know we're you are forecasting that with a very high probability they'll be an impulse but you
don't know which way but on the forex market you can set stop orders he can said pending orders.
And that's exactly what you should do in this case.
So instead of buying or selling and taking our chances with that what we're going to do is we're going
to set two pending orders one by stop order and once sell stop order.
So which ever way the prize goes we're going to earn a profit as long as there is an impulse.
It doesn't matter whether it's upwards or downwards we can earn a profit from that.
And that is a massive advantage of technical analysis over fundamental because in situations like this
you don't have to predict where the price will go.
You just have to predict that it'll go somewhere.
And so we set these two orders and the take profit of each of the orders is set at about half the base
of the triangle.
So that's exactly how you trade the triangle.
And moreover further in this course you will see a live example from a real account where I do exactly
that and the trial does shoot out and we do earn a profit.
It's just mind blowing how well the strategy works.
So to sum up of the triangle the three main points first of all triangle means market consolidation
and it's one of those instruments of technical analysis that can actually picture the psychology of
traders on the chart.
So that is very powerful so it combines technical analysis and sentiment analysis in one pattern.
The second point is that the most likely exit out of triangle's an impulse doesn't happen 100 percent
of the time but definitely happens more often than not.
And the best part about this is you don't have to predict which way the market will go.
All you have to do is set a Buy stop and assess stop order.
And whichever way the market goes you have a good chance of earning a profit.
And finally the triangle gives you a defined target which is a very strong advantage of the parent because
it makes it straightforward and very easy to incorporate into your trading system.