Hey guys curial here I wonder how you're going with the chorus.
Hope you're enjoying it so far.
You're through the live testing results.
And I wanted to post a quick update.
So today's Monday the 24th of August 2015 it's 1:30 p.m. in Brisbane Australia and carga I'm just testing
out a broker which I'm kind of interested in checking out and I am I've created a few orders today morning
just just to see what's going on in the market and so on.
And I was actually going to share with you another triangle pattern that I found I really I really think
that they're very powerful and as you saw from the previous videos of the life testing we've had some
good results.
And today once again I just wanted to show you what happened here so this is the euro Frank.
And so as you can see this is triangled switched back to the bars and you can see how nicely it's forming
this is the five minute time frame I could.
First time I spoke it was like an hour timeframe when you whenever you see on the hour each time things
turn from something going on like that.
So right now the euro currency pairs are going up.
So euros going up all across the board.
And also you can see the franc currency pairs while Dola franc is going down meaning that franc is going
up right.
So let's buy another one British pound of Swiss franc is going down.
So both.
What does that tell us that tells us that both the franc is is getting stronger and the euro is getting
stronger so they I moved onto the euro franc currency pair and I like because they're both getting stronger
they're kind of battling It's like I haven't made this go into myself like Battle Of The Titans for
today anyway.
They started the strong strong day both him and that's why you can see like this flat movement because
one is going very strong against other currency pairs and the other is going very strong against other
currency pairs.
And it's for them it's like they're fighting for the first place you can say it that way.
And when you see something like this on a high timeframe you move down slowly and you see that it's
actually it's not just the flat it's actually a triangle that's forming here.
And once I saw that I was like yep I'm in I'm going to get into a get in on this and once again this
is just because I'm testing out the broker I don't want to you know commit to a full throttle trading
strategy or anything that this is I'm just you know kind of having fun but this is a real real accounting
.
Just to clarify I've got 2000 Australian dollars and today I made 55 Australian dollars just by testing
a broker.
So I don't really.
This is test funds this is this is not money that I'm like relying on or or battling for oil or you
know working to get this is just just to test it out anyway.
So so the triangle and decided to put as I advised or not advise I don't advise as I showed you in the
course as I normally do I put two orders so one by stop you can see row here.
So I'll just put a line through it.
That's a by stop and the cell stop was over here you can see it on the chart because it's gone.
But let's see what happens if I drag it on.
So there's a cell stop and just delete that.
That's where I put the cell stop.
And you can see where I put it.
So this vertical line I'm going to UPS that's not a vertical line.
Gonna fix this one up.
This is an unplanned tutorial for this course so excuse me if it's a bit ad hoc.
OK so I've got the vertical line here and let's make it a bit wider.
OK so this is where I placed both the tray the cell stop and by stop so I placed them at this point
in time and was well according to the server time.
By the way this broker doesn't have servers and Australia has servers in America.
Whole different story anyway.
So I pray a place by stop and say stop over here as you can see like triangle.
It just works there.
It's too strong currency at the moment something is going to happen and it happened.
And where did I place my take profit.
You see this line over here.
This is how I measured the base just like we discussed in the course so if I just move this back just
remember that we're where the take profit was it was hit exactly at the top of this movement how do
we get the top of the movement.
Well look this is how I got this line in the first place.
I measured the base of my triangle right.
So somewhere like that.
And then I placed it so I thought OK maybe it won't shoot out right away.
So from here it won't shoot out like immediately you'll probably shoot out in like a couple of bars
at least.
So then I put the line where I thought it would shoot out.
Right.
And then I put the tape proffered just below half of the base and that's exactly what we discussed the
course that you place your take profit at around half the size of the base of the triangle as you can
see worked perfectly here like the take profit closed.
And then the price turned around.
Well if you look at the bars there was a bit of a movement more upwards right but not that much more
and you don't want to run after these little things.
And the other point is that it didn't go all the whole base of the triangle it just went past half the
base and then turned around.
And so yeah that's that's the triangle Paran.
What else that I did today.
There was a good trade over here somewhere.
This one.
No it was on Gimme a second.
It was see everyone got common here Test 0 2 test 0 5.
Was it through your frank.
No it was the British Canadian.
There we go.
So here was a good trade.
So what can we see here.
I'm going to just switch this grid office so you can see more.
OK.
So here what happened was I don't usually trade against the trend.
Right.
But what you could see here was a strong trend all the way.
And then I just opened the chart I could see this candle forming.
So this is something we haven't discussed in the course.
But you know it's another thing you see this candle shooting upwards very quickly so that's a point
that I saw it form extremely quickly as it just went bam very fast upwards.
What happens in these situations if it's not if it's not some news or something that's forcing the market
to go and that's the end is going to keep going that way.
It was just like a spontaneous maybe a session opened or you know a company announced it's that it or
a bank is having like not a major but a minor intervention or something is happening in the world.
Some Joe Joe demographical cataclysm or something something happened very quickly but it's not major
.
Right.
So I didn't hear anything on the news.
I know it's not a Friday so I don't think that there's something major going.
What usually happens after that is the currency traces a little bit.
So people go in and then what happens people see this movement is going fast if I put the tick volume
back on here you see you see the tick volume here in Forex tick volume is basically it's not the same
as volume on the stock market or anything is just how many ticks there were in this bar like how many
times did the price change in this bar.
And so there was there's a lot of volume so people will like it was moving very quickly and people could
see that.
And what the traders do especially know these traders they try to jump onto that movement they try to
get on to all this that the bars are going fast upwards.
You know I got I got to get in to get in on this.
I'm going to miss out and never do that.
That's that's not good.
If you miss the train you've missed the train so you can see here like it took a couple of minutes this
is the minute time frame maybe like half an hour or something but it was going very quickly like in
a minute here you can see it when what 13 pips.
And then like very quick its just.
This is a Monday morning.
This is just the Asia trading session.
We talked about trading sessions also in this course as well.
And then at the start.
So you know that it shouldn't be very quick it should be kind of like lazy and slow and it's like going
very quick very quick.
People are trying to jump onto this movement and what happens the the late traders they jump in over
here and that's when the smart traders start selling like the traders that are late.
They want to buy and that's when the smart traders are selling off this movement that they got from
from the bottom to the top and now they're getting out of the market.
So there's a lot of currency being so British pound.
There's a little British pound being released into the market and all the late traders they're buying
it while the traders came in early they just get rid of the currency and because there's so much currency
excess currency the price is going down and that's when you jump in like it doesn't always happen.
But if you can see that it's happening that this exact scenario is happening then in this case what
I did is I jumped in and I just you know capitalized on that movement back like kind of little retracement
that happens after quick movements like that quick unexpected and unexplained movements like that and
that's it.
And and then I got out.
I even put a stop order by limit order some way here.
So as you can see it somewhere here by a limit there.
So I was expecting no drag on torture.
I was expecting the price to turn around so I knew that it's against the trade trend it's not going
to last forever.
This downward movement is going to keep going up.
Right.
So I put a limit.
And I said OK so if it if this retracement goes through a little bit more then I'll get in on a buy
but it just didn't didn't trigger my limit.
So you can see the price crossed here.
But as you know this is the bid price that's illustrated and by orders get opened at the ask price and
ask price was just about I could see it.
I could see it here and then just it went away and then I was like OK now I'm I don't want to get in
here it's a bit too late because if I got in here on a board I would have to sit through all of this
and not not not good especially if I'm just testing these things out.
So that's the two trading trades that I did today too I did a couple more but those are the two most
interesting ones.
There's another big one somewhere or big you know quotation marks big.
ahm no those those are the two bigger ones because I went I went in like zero point to 5 watts and 0.2
Watts anyway.
Hope you enjoyed this.
And my main focus of course was triangle parent.
That it does work.
So keep keep you know maybe learning the triangle parent and researching it more and heads up.
I'm testing out this broker and maybe maybe just maybe I might update my preferred brokers this soon
and I will let you know if that happens.
And until next time enjoy the course and trade well trade safe trade fun and happy trading.
I look forward to seeing you later on.