In this last part of the course,
I will teach you how to use the long awaited,
brand new edition to the CSS language,
which is the CSS Grid Layout module,
or in short, just CSS Grids.
So CSS Grids will allow you to build layouts so easily,
like you've never done before.
It really is a game changer for CSS,
and that's why all the important experts
are so excited about it.
Now, for this section, I hope you're just as excited
as they are.
So just like in the Flexbox section,
we will build yet another really cool project
and this time, using all the power that CSS Grids offers us.
We will also compare grids with Flexbox,
and actually, we will use them together
in some parts of the project
because that's really becoming the standard these days.
So yet another really cool section,
and I can't wait to show you all of this.
(uptempo electronic music)