Hey, there, welcome back.
This is once again an extremely important lecture
because we're gonna talk about CSS architecture,
how we should think about layouts,
and how we should mark up our code in a professional way.
So this one is technically not about how CSS works
but it still made sense to put it here in this section.
So, remember that we want code that is clean,
modular, reusable, that makes it easy
to add more and more features
to our webpage or app if it needs to grow.
So because of all of these reasons,
we cannot just dive into a new project
and leave architecture behind just as a second thought.
Instead, we need to take important decisions
concerning our HTML and CSS code
right from the beginning of the project.
And that's what I wanna help you with in this lecture.
So we need a good strategy here, a good mindset,
and from my experience, the best strategy
is something I like to call
the think, build, architect mindset.
We need to think about the layout of our webpage
or web app before we actually write the code.
After having the layout figured out,
we should build it in HTML and CSS
with a consistent structure for naming our classes.
Also, at the same time, we should create a logical
CSS architecture by using multiple files and folders.
So starting with the think part,
I like to use something called component-driven design,
which is actually a principle
that is used across all software development.
In CSS, with component-driven design,
we try to divide our page into modular components.
So, what are these components?
Components are the building blocks that we use
to construct our interfaces.
So we can basically think of our interface
as a collection of components
held together by the overall layout of the page.
Probably the most important thing about components
is that they should be reusable across a project
and also between different projects.
That's really important.
So you can build a library of your components
and then reuse them across projects,
which will speed up your development.
Plus, components should be independent
so that we can use them completely on their own
no matter where on the page.
What this means is that components
should not depend on their parent elements.
Once again, all of this will make your CSS code
easier to maintain and to scale if necessary.
Now of course, these are all the general rules,
and they can be broken if it's strictly necessary
as long as you have a good reason.
Now I don't want you to memorize anything here, okay?
This is just a discussion that we need to have
in order to become better CSS developers.
Over time with practice, all of this
will become really intuitive to you,
and of course, we're actually gonna apply this
in a later project that we already started coding.
All right, and just as a side note,
this whole thinking component strategy
is actually a bit similar to Brad Frost's
super popular atomic design philosophy,
which maybe you have heard of by now.
So according to atomic design,
the smallest units on a page are atoms,
which together form molecules,
which combine together to form organisms.
And these organisms can be seen as our components
in some situations.
Now we're not gonna focus so much on atomic design
in the course though.
I just wanted to let you know
that there are other ways of thinking about our interfaces.
You can take a look at atomic design if you're interested
and if you haven't heard about it.
All right, so after thinking about your design,
we need to code the design using HTML and CSS,
and in this step, it's important
to have a consistent strategy
and structure for naming our classes.
There are many approaches for naming classes.
Things like object-oriented CSS or S Max
but the one I like the most is BEM,
which is becoming more and more popular
by developers around the world.
It's a nice clean system for marking up our layouts.
So, BEM stands for Block Element Modifier.
And this is how class notes usually look like
using the BEM methodology.
So, if you've ever seen code that looks like this
example here, now you know that it used the BEM system.
So, first, in BEM a block is a standalone component
that is meaningful on its own.
And what this means is that the component
as we defined in the last slide are the blocks in BEM.
In this example, the recipe is a block
and also the button because both of them
are standalone components that can be reused
anywhere in the project.
And note how these two blocks are actually nested.
So the button block is inside the recipe block,
and that's perfectly normal and acceptable.
Next, an element is a part of a block
and has no meaning on its own.
So in our example, that could be the info panel
or the stats box,
but there are a lot of other elements there.
But again, if we take one of these elements out of the block
then they wouldn't be useful at al.
They wouldn't have any meaning.
Now what's important to note here
is how the recipe block still appears
in all the class names within the block.
Do you see that?
That's why we have the word recipe
all over the place in this HTML code.
Also, notice how this creates selectors
with really low specificities because we always use classes
and they are never nested.
And so they always have a pretty low specificity,
and this is one of the big reasons why BEM
is so widely used for easy to maintain and reusable code.
All right, and last, we have the modifier,
and the modifier is a flag that we can put on a block
or an element in order to make it different
from the regular blocks or elements.
To make a different version, let's say.
In our example, we have a modifier to make the button round.
So for instance, there may be some rules for all buttons,
and then we use a modifier
to make a more specific, different button.
And in this case, a round one.
Now, try to read that entire HTML markup
I just showed you, okay?
Seriously, try to stop the video and read the code
because just by reading the markup
with these class names in it,
you can instantly see how all elements are related
and what each of them does.
Now imagine this with a whole page,
and the effect would become even better.
Now again, you're gonna get used to all this
once we start using it in practice throughout the project
in one of the next lectures.
All right, and just to finish this part,
I know that many people really hate BEM
because they say it looks ugly and it's hard to write
and yeah, I agree that it might look a bit funny actually
and that you might have to type a bit more code,
but believe me that it's really worth it.
You should absolutely try it with me
once we start coding again.
And now the last part of our strategy,
which is architecting CSS.
And remember by that I mean to create a logical folder
and file structure for our CSS to live in.
Once again, there are different options here
like the ITCSS method or S Max,
but I like to use something called the 7-1 Pattern
introduced by Hugo Giraudel.
I'm not sure if I spelled his name right, but let's hope.
Okay, so the 7-1 Pattern is extremely simple.
All it means is that we have seven different folders
where we put partial Sass files,
and then one main Sass file in which we import
all of our partial files into one final
compiled CSS stylesheet.
Of course, when I say Sass here,
I could mean any other CSS pre-processor
because all of them allow to implement this pattern, okay?
And we'll see how that works in practice
once again a bit later.
So the seven folders I've mentioned
that are used in this method are the base folder
where we put the basic product definitions,
the components folder where we have one file
for each component, the layout folder,
where we define the overall layout of the project,
the pages folder where we have styles
for specific pages of the project,
the themes folder if you want to implement
different visual themes, the abstracts folder
where we put code that doesn't output any CSS,
such as variables or mix-ins,
and finally, the vendors folder
where all third party CSS goes.
So that's just a big overview,
but I'll go into further details about these folders
once we really implement them in a project.
Now we don't always need to use all of these folders.
It's gonna depend on the size and the scope of the project.
All right, and that's it about CSS architecture,
BEM, and component-based design.
I hope this made sense to you
and that you can see and appreciate
the huge value that these techniques
can add to our workflow.
I'm sure that putting this into practice
will help with that, so
stay tuned for the next lectures
where we're gonna do exactly that.