Let's now continue
building the tours section.
And this is where we left off after the last lecture.
And in this small break, I actually noticed some problem
with this card so with this movement here,
and let me show you what happens.
So I'm gonna make this here really slow.
So, like, eight seconds, let's say.
And so let's take a look at what happens here.
It actually moves in the wrong direction.
You see that?
We want it to move in the opposite direction
so that then it seems that the card's continuous moving
while the orange sides moves to the front.
And right now, that's not really what's happening.
You see that?
So this should move in the opposite direction, okay?
And so what we want to happen
is to not rotate to 180 degrees
but minus 180 degrees.
So basically just in the other direction.
And once again, that's what the minus symbol does here.
It moves the element in the other direction.
Just like as if we're setting a margin to negative value,
it also moves the element to the other direction,
so the opposite direction.
So let's check it out now.
And so this is what we want, right?
So now it's really a moving card.
So I had a small mistake in the code.
You see that?
Now it is actually perfect.
Once again, just to make sure, and yep.
So in this transition, there's a small moment
where you don't see any card.
And so in there we can see that it's perfect now this way.
Right now.
All right, so let's put it back to 0.8,
give it a save.
And yep, so this looks natural now.
All right, so just a small mistake.
But again, that's completely normal
to happen for everyone.
As long as we fixed these before we ship a product,
it's no problem.
Now let's move on and start styling the card some more.
And so basically you have three elements
on the front side of the card.
So let's take a look at them.
So we have the background image in the first place,
so this image, then the textbox,
and then the list down there.
So three parts I am going to put here in the markup now.
So first one is the card heading.
Card heading, next we have a card picture.
And actually it'll let me put the picture first.
So card picture.
Oh, something's wrong here.
Oh, something weird here going on with my editor.
But nevermind.
Last thing is the card details.
Now one thing about the BEM methodology
is that we do not nest the element names.
Okay?
So this here is not a card side picture, okay?
So card, then card side, and card side picture.
That could make sense, but that's not how
the BEM methodology says we should do it.
So these are elements that are not,
they should not be dependent here on the side, okay?
So we keep the block which is card in this case,
so the block is kept in the name,
but then it's a complete, new element down here, okay?
And so we have the picture,
the heading, and the details, so.
Details,
heading, and the image.
Now as for the image, I'm gonna use a background image
in CSS actually, another img element in the HTML.
And I'm gonna do that because I wanna show you
some background blend modes, okay?
So some great effects that we can apply
on background images, but not on normal images.
And so I'm gonna just leave this one empty,
so no image in here.
Well actually, we should put something in here,
and so I'll just put a space,
and so I'm putting the HTML special symbol for space,
which is nbsp.
I'm not really sure why that is,
but this basically means like an empty space in HTML, okay?
So instead of just leaving the div empty,
I put this in here.
It looks the same, but at least then it's
not completely just empty sitting there.
Okay, and let's actually start with our picture.
And keep in mind that we have three cards,
so we're gonna have three different pictures.
And so I need to add here a modifier.
Right?
So picture one here in this case.
And then later we will have two and three.
So, back to our CSS, or SASS actually.
Let's now come down here and write
"picture."
And so let's add some comments here.
Maybe you've been adding comments before to your SASS.
So let me just right here that
this is basically for functionality.
So functionality.
And this now is,
front side styling.
So the picture's of course on the front side,
and so let's style that.
And so we select the very first one, so.
This card picture one here, right?
And so now let's give it to start,
a simple background image.
Okay?
And so now we have to move up one level.
And so now img, and the image
that I want here is called nat-5.
Now why do I actually have to move up only one level?
Well, I do, because I have to assume
that this code will be written later
in the style of the CSS file, right?
So after the SASS code is compiled,
it will be written into the style that CSS file
and so from there, I have to move up one level
out of the CSS folder and into the product folder,
which is this NATO folder.
And then from there, I move to the img folder.
And then in there, we have this nat-5.
So this image here.
All right?
By the way, I got most, or maybe all, of these images
at a very nice website
which is called unsplash.com, I think.
And yeah, right.
So here you have a lot of great, free images
that you can get for free.
And there's a lot to explore here.
But once again, you have a link to this one
and to other similar websites on my resources page.
All right, so we have a background image here,
and we want to set it background size
to cover here, okay?
And I'm doing that outside of this selector here,
because of course I want this
to happen for all of the images.
And so instead of repeating it then,
for the two and three, when I put them here already.
So two and three.
So if I were to write this in here,
then I would have to repeat it for this one and for this one
and that doesn't make much sense.
And so I'm applying it just
on the more general selector here.
All right, let's just take a look.
And well, for some reason, it's not there.
Let's inspect.
So the picture, and okay, of course.
Well, another small mistake.
And now here we go.
Now the element is just really small,
because there are no content at all in it, okay?
So that's a reason why we only have this very small picture.
So once again, we have to define the height here.
And I'm setting it to 23 rem and I came
to this number here by experimentation once again.
So now it should look better, okay.
That's actually how it's supposed to be.
Now about this background blend modes
that I talked to you about earlier.
What actually is that?
Well, the background blend mode property describes
how the elements, background images, should blend.
And that's basically it.
So imagine we have multiple backgrounds,
and we want them to blend.
And so we can use that property to do that.
Now just blending two images
wouldn't make much sense, right?
and so what we're doing here is to blend the image
with a linear gradient,
which is also defined a background image in CSS.
And so let's try that out.
Okay, so the background image
is not just the actual image here,
but it also contains a gradient.
And I can actually get that one from up here,
because it's the exact same one.
So it's also to the right button
and with these two yellow colors.
So, one background and then a comma
and the second background, okay?
And if we now take a look,
you'll only see the one that's on top
which is the gradient,
but that's because we didn't actually blend them, not yet.
So.
Background blend mode.
And once again, this is a brand new CSS property
and so it doesn't work at all in Internet Explorer
and neither on Microsoft Etch, okay?
So only Safari, Firefox, and Google Chrome of course.
So there are many different options here,
and I'm going to use screen, okay?
And I'm gonna show you all the different possibilities
in the def tools.
All right, and that's what it looks like.
Let's inspect.
So, well.
For some reason, it doesn't work.
All right, so now, after refreshing,
sometimes that's necessary.
So let's delete it and then in here can see
the different possibilities.
Well, okay, so.
Color, color burn, color dodge,
and so these are all the different blend modes
that we have available in CSS.
Maybe you are familiar with blend modes
from a graphical program like Photoshop
or something like that.
And so before if you wanted to have
some background blending going on like this,
you would have to do it in Photoshop, then export it,
and use it in CSS, but now with this modern CSS properties,
you can do it right in CSS.
So it's getting more and more powerful, okay?
So we have all of these effects going on.
Multiply also looks quite dramatic, I think.
Then overlay, saturation.
Screen, that's the one that I'm using,
because it looks, I think, the most normal here.
Soft light and so we're back to the beginning,
so color also looks dramatic and great, I think.
But again, I'm going with green here.
And so that's the one I'm looking for.
Okay.
Now maybe you're noticing up here
in the corners of these images
so I cannot touch it, but here in the corners
that they are no longer around it, right?
Well, if I zoom this up a little bit,
now let me zoom it really high.
So you can see they are no longer around it.
And that's because the image
is basically overlapping the parent element.
But there's an easy fix.
And so on the parent element, which is actually where
the border radius is defined,
we can see the property that's called overflow,
and then hit it, okay?
Because basically that's what's happening.
So the image is overflowing
the parent in these corners, okay?
So where the corners are, the image should not be
and so we can simply hide these parts.
So overflow hidden does that for us.
And so now if we zoom in, it should be back to normal.
And yeah, we see that it actually works now.
At least it looks like it.
Let's check it out.
So if we had some more moderators here.
So you see that now it's working, okay?
It's really dramatic.
But just to show you that it works now.
All right.
Now what we also want to happen here on this picture
is to have the similar effect that we have on the header.
So take it out.
So this line here, okay.
I cannot hover it.
But you see this cut out part just like here in the header,
this part, right?
So once again, let's use clip for that.
So the clip path property.
Clip path.
And once again, we're defining a polygon here.
And now that we can actually use other things
different from polygon.
For example, circle or ellipsis.
And we're actually gonna do a circle
in one of the next lectures.
In order to clip a perfect circle.
Now in this case, that's not what we want,
so a polygon.
And I hope we remember how it works.
So we define a couple of coordinates,
starting from the top left corner.
And so we want (0,0) in there.
Then the second one is 100% in the x direction.
Okay?
And zero in the y direction.
Remember that?
So let me show it to you.
So (0,0) then 100% in the x direction
but zero movement in the y direction,
so up and down.
And now here comes the third coordinate
which will be somewhere here.
So this is where they actually like, the cutting happens.
So we will want 100% on the x.
And then on the y axis, something like 80 or 85%.
So, 100% in the x direction.
And lets say 85% in the y direction.
And then finally the last coordinate will be,
again back to zero in the x direction
because it's back to the beginning.
And 100% in the y direction.
Okay, let's check that one out.
And yep, so, that looks good.
Okay, so once again, this clip path here
is very modern CSS property.
And in order to actually make it work
across all the browsers, we should actually prefix it
with the webkit prefix.
So then it works in all browsers like Chrome
and Safari as well, okay?
So the same thing here now.
So clip path and webkit clip path.
And actually it should be the other way around.
So first, the prefixed.
Then the official version.
Because this is just a blender prefix.
So prefix implemented by different browsers.
And actually since we're doing that,
let's also do the same thing here at the header
where we also used a clip path, okay?
So, let me copy that one.
Clip path, all right.
Okay, and such as the background blend mode,
clip path is not going to work
on Internet Explorer and Microsoft Etch.
So if you need to develop for these ones,
you can at this point, not use these properties, okay?
Or you can use them with a fall back.
And we're gonna take care of that later.
So we actually will take care
of supporting different browsers in different ways.
But let's leave that for later.
Okay, and with the picture done, let's now take care
of the heading, okay?
So it's called card heading here, okay?
So let's do that.
So how should it look?
And where should it be positioned?
So let's take a look.
And so it's on top of the image.
Basically, we want it to have this nice background.
The wide, big text, and so, yeah.
Let's do that then.
Now notice once again that each of these titles
have a different background color
according to the image and of course to the backside.
So let's start with the font size
of 2.8 rem for example.
A font weight of 300.
Text transform to uppercase.
And color, remember it was white.
So color,
white, all right.
And I think I actually set the color somewhere up here, okay
but remember this was just for testing and this as well.
So let's remove that testing part we had set up before.
So what should be here?
And now actually I'm seeing that I have a div here.
But that's not really semantic.
So semantic means that we're using
the right HTML tag for the right content.
And so if it's a heading, we should actually use an h tag.
So h4, so we used h1, 2, and 3.
And now it's time to use h4 element on this one.
And so it says the first one is "The Sea Explorer."
Let's check that out.
And well, it's hidden behind here because it's white.
So here it is, actually.
Now remember, we want this to be on top of the image, right?
So what can we do?
We will use absolute positioning once again.
So let's do that.
So down here.
Position, absolute.
And we want it from the top at 12 rem.
And from the right side at 2 rem.
And also since we're at it,
let's align the text to the right.
So we have everything nicely aligned
to the right side of the card.
So let's see that now.
And so now it's almost the way that we want it.
Well not perfectly, but we're gonna take care
of that right now.
Now in order to create this look that we have here,
with these two lines and with basically
the gradient applying on each of them,
we need to use a new CSS property
called "box decoration break."
And in order for that to work,
I need to create the new element inside of this h4.
So again, this will make more sense a bit later.
For now, let's just do it this way.
So, in here,
let me simply add a span element here, okay?
So this is just something to wrap around the text card.
We wanna call this one "heading span."
And now "The Sea Explorer" text goes in here.
Also, I'll need a modifier class here
because I wanted three different gradients, right?
So one yellow, one green, and one blue.
And so this is the way I have to do it.
So you see it's getting rather complex,
such as I was saying in the beginning of the lecture.
But since we're building it step by step
and really explaining everything on the way,
it should not really be a problem, right?
So let's copy this one,
or actually we don't need because our SASS nesting.
So all we have to do is to add the span here now.
Or actually, that's not really a good practice, okay?
So let me add heading, span,
because this is not really a child of the heading.
This is a whole new element called "heading span."
So it's not a modifier of heading,
and it's not an element of heading,
so it's a new element in the BEM system, okay?
And so I will have a separate selector for that one.
And now the next thing I wanna do
is to give it this nice background gradient, okay?
And so now I'm selecting one with the modifier one.
So card heading span one.
And so I want the background image here for the gradient
background image, linear gradient to right bottom.
Was writing it outside the parenthesis for some reason.
So and now I want it to be slightly transparent.
So I need to use some rgbas here.
So that we can still see through the element.
So this is the color here,
for the number one as well.
So all of the ones have the same yellow colors.
And then 0.85 off value.
And then in here, it is the dark.
Also with 0.85.
Okay, so this looks rather complex.
Let's break it up a little bit here.
All right.
So let's take a look now.
Now, let me make this slightly narrower, okay?
So give it a width of not 100%, what it has right now.
Because it's a block element, but give it just 75%.
Sorry about that.
And well, that didn't change anything.
Why is that?
Let me see what happens if I decrease it even further.
Ah, Okay.
So it should simply be a smaller value here, okay.
So if you go to 100,
then it's back to occupying the entire width that it can.
So you see that by the blue box.
Now by just adding some padding here,
let's say 10 pixels top, bottom,
and 1.5 rem in here.
Then that should actually fix it
because this will create some more space
and so yeah, so here we go.
And so now this already looks pretty close
to the end result that we want, right?
Now you see that we edit the padding here, okay?
So you see the padding going around on this entire element.
But you see that here besides "a", we don't have any space
like we have on the other side beside the "t."
And down here at the "e,"
at the beginning of "explorer,"
we also don't have any padding.
And that's because this element
is treated as one line of text.
And so basically acts as one element
where the padding gets applied
on the left and on the right side.
And the left is left at the "the,"
and the right side is right of the "explorer" word.
So what we want is to exactly treat
these two entities like these two lines
as if they were two different elements, right?
And there's actually a way of doing that.
And so that magic happens when we use
the box decoration break property.
So box decoration break.
And we're gonna set it to clone.
And actually, this doesn't work right now
at Google Chrome without the webkit prefix, okay?
So we need this, this prefix here in order to make it work.
And so let's take a look.
And here we go.
So that's how you want this to look like.
Let me actually disable here this hover.
In fact, we can do so by clicking here.
Then we click here on hover.
And so then we can see the styles.
Which apply when we hover.
They should be somewhere down here.
Well actually, this is not where we want to hover of course.
We hover the entire card.
So sorry.
Imagine that we hover this.
And now we can disable the styles.
Well at least we should be able to.
Ah yeah, so here.
Here we go, so.
This part rotates and where is the other one?
Yeah, it's the backside.
And so, so now we should be able to touch it
without it rotating all the time, you like crazy.
So, let's take away this property here and see what happens.
So this is what it looked like before.
So we didn't have this space here that we wanted.
And not here.
But only here in the beginning and here at the end.
And to fix that, we use this property.
And for some reason, it doesn't work without checking
and un-checking this one.
But now, here we are, so.
Now these are, like, two completely different entities.
And that's what the clone does.
So what clone does is to simply apply all the declarations
that we have in the selector which in this case
is only the padding to all of the boxes
that I created by an element.
Just like in this case.
So one element, two boxes, both styled.
Now in the same way.
Both with the same padding.
All right, and so we have that part as well.
So two or three parts are done.
And now the final one is just this list.
And that should be the easiest part.
So let's do that real quick before we end up
with a one hour video here, okay?
So simply a list.
And so we create a ul element.
Now I could go crazy here with the BEM notation
and add card list now, and then to all of the items in there
I could add card item and so we would end up
with a bunch of different class names,
but let's not do that.
And that's very simply create an unordered list in here
that we can then select with the card details selector.
Okay?
So ul, then remember that with Emmet,
we can do it like this so we can create some child elements.
And remember that we want five li elements in there.
And so we can write li times five.
Hit tab and here we go.
So the first one says "3 day tour."
Hitting tab moves me to the next one, okay?
"Up to 30 people."
"2 tour guides."
"Sleep in cozy hotels."
And finally the difficulty
is easy.
So an easy tour is this one.
So card details and so let's now go style that one.
So we have the picture, the heading,
and now the card
details.
Okay, so in the details, we have the ul.
So we simply have to write "ul" here.
And then in here, we have the lis.
Right?
So list style, none.
This is pretty standard.
We basically do it all the time
when we use an unordered list.
We say we want it to have a width of 80%
so that it doesn't occupy all of the space in here, okay?
So remember this is what it looks like.
And we want all of these items then
to have a line under them.
So they should be slightly underlined.
But we don't want that to go completely
from the left to the right side.
And so this complete list should only have a width of 80%.
And so this way we take care of that.
Okay?
And now just item, you saw that it had centered text.
So text align, center.
Font size, 1.5 rem.
Let's give it also some padding.
And then the border at the bottom of one pixels.
Now we don't want it to happen on all of them.
But on all of them except the last one.
So how do we do that?
We already learned it and used it multiple times by now.
So we say that we want the li elements
that are not the last child.
I want them to be this solid gray.
This "eee" gray.
Okay, and since we're using a color,
let's create a new variables.
So, we have one light color already
but this one is a little bit darker.
So we use a new variable for that one.
Let me copy it right away.
So all we have to do now
is to paste it in here.
All right, let's take a look.
Okay, so we see these 80% width going on,
but of course, they should be in the center of the card,
not pushed all the way to the left side.
And we should also probably have some space here.
Well, in the beginning basically off the list, okay?
So let's take care of that.
Basically, we can set a padding in here
of 3 rem and that will take care of that.
And then remember that we want this ul here
which has this 80% width to be centered in the container.
And so how do we do that?
Do you know a good way of doing that?
Well, whenever I can, I like to use the most simple methods.
And so I'm not going to go with absolute positioning
or stuff like that.
I'm using a simple way.
So we're centering a block element inside
of a block element.
And so the simplest way
is to simply use margin: 0 auto.
So 0, top and bottom, and left and right
automatically calculated by the browser.
So I already explained that to you
when we did the rows in the grid system, all right?
So let's take a look at it now.
And that looks pretty good to me.
Maybe we want some more space down there
and we can do that by actually increasing the entire card.
So let's add some 10 pixels for example.
Maybe even some more 10 pixels.
Remember we have to set it here in two places
because one, we have the height of the entire card
and then for both the sides.
And so, yeah, now it looks good.
It looks fantastic in fact.
So the front part is ready.
Now all we have to do is to style the back part.
But that should be a lot more easy
than the front part, okay?
So that's what we're going to do in the next lecture.