So let's finish up the gallery
that we were building.
And I actually want to do this as a small challenge for you.
So you already know how it's gonna look like in the end,
and so I'm sure that you're gonna be able
to place all the remaining 13 images here
on the grid, just like this.
So I'm sure you can do it,
and so pause the video now,
and I'm gonna be back in a minute
and show you how I did solve this.
So, did you manage to do it?
Let me now show you my solution,
so my way of doing this.
And first of all, I'm gonna include
all of the images in the markup.
Now instead of copying this here
and then changing this number one
here in the item, in the name, and the alt text,
I'm going to use Emmet to actually do all of this
in one line of code.
Okay, so this is going to be the most complex Emmet code
that we ever wrote.
So let me show you how I did it.
So we want a figure with the name gallery_item,
so nothing new up until this point.
And also gallery_item number,
and then automatic numbering here again, right.
Then in there, we want an image
called gallery_image.
And now we can also specify the attributes here.
And that's using the square brackets, just like this.
So we can say that the source should be image,
gal, and then the number
and then JPEG.
And that works because the images that we used for this
are named like this,
like gallery one, two, three, four, five,
all the way to 14.
And so that's why we can use this numbering here as well.
So that's the source attribute,
and then I can also specify the alt attribute.
And so,
gallery image and then a number.
Okay, and now that, so that Emmet understands this really,
let me put this here in parenthesis
and then write 14 times,
hit tab, and bam!
Here we go.
So we have now all of these 14 figures
with the 14 images, all named from one to 14
such as the image names and the alt text.
So I can now get rid of this first part here
which is exactly the same as this one.
So let's check it out here.
And indeed, here we have our 14 different images.
Now all we have to do is to place them
on the grid just like this.
And so let's actually use this one here as a reference.
So again, in order to come up with this layout here,
I had to go through kind of a lot of experimentation,
but that would way too much to do in a video like this,
and so I'm just gonna place them like they are here
and if you wanna go through all that experimentation
by yourself, then please feel free to do that.
So you can of course try to position them
in a completely different way,
and try to come up with your own gallery.
But I'm just gonna show you the way that I did this.
So this one here is the second one,
and we see that it starts on column number one,
and then spans across three tracks,
and the same four lines.
So from line one, spanning across three tracks.
So, let's copy this.
So grid-row and span three,
and grid-column starts on number three,
so line number three, and spans across three.
And of course, here, number two.
And that's it.
So next up, from one,
and spanning two rows and just one column.
So number three from row one, spanning two,
and then just one column.
So just from column one to column number three.
Just to confirm, oh,
something didn't go quite well,
and yeah of course it starts at column six
and goes to seven,
so that's of course a mistake.
But now that's fixed.
So next one occupies then
all the way until the end of the grid
and across two rows.
So number four,
grid-row and spans two,
and the columns, it starts at number eight,
and until the end of the grid.
And actually it starts at number seven,
okay so grid line number seven,
and of course, yeah that was kind of obvious
because this one ended at line number seven
and so this one of course had to start
at line number seven, right.
So next one then here starts at line
number three and goes all the way
to line number six.
So it spans across three rows,
and spans across two columns.
And so now you can actually see how useful it is
to use these Firefox dev tools for grid
because without it, we would have a hard time
of course visualizing this grid,
and then also keeping track of the line numbers.
So it's really great by Mozilla that they did it like this.
Okay, started grid-row number three
and spans across three, and two columns.
I think it's good like this.
Yeah, so that looks good.
Next one, we have this one here
with the pool,
and it starts at number four,
spanning two rows and starts at column number three,
spanning two as well.
Four and three.
Okay, now maybe this may seem
like a bit of a boring task,
to having to align all these items like this
and I kind of agree with that,
but there's really no way around it.
And of course if you were to do this
without the grid, then it would be
1000 times worse.
Okay, so I'm really thankful for having this method
and I'm not complaining at all.
So the next one is this here,
and it starts at row four and column five.
So four and five.
Four, and five.
And actually, four and five here.
And it's only one cell.
And so that should work.
Yeah.
Next up, there's this one here
starting from row three
and column six.
So three, and six.
At number eight.
Yep!
The next one is this here,
starting from row number three,
and column number eight.
And it goes all the way across three tracks,
so three row tracks.
So row three, and span across three,
and grid-column eight,
to minus one.
So the last one.
So perfect again.
And only five more to go.
So the next one is this one here.
So row number six, spanning two row tracks.
And of course column from number one to two.
Number ten now.
There you go.
And now the next one, from row six to row eight,
and column two to four.
So six, and two,
spanning two.
I believe.
And yeah, kind of.
It's number 11 here of course.
Yeah, so that's better.
And now we can already see how the next ones will be,
so the next one is going to fill up this remaining space,
and then this one will fill up this here,
and then the last one will probably fill up this space here.
So let's confirm that,
and yeah, so this space here,
then this one,
and then this one.
So the next one starts at row six and column four.
So let's copy that.
And column four.
And yeah, it actually doesn't span the column.
So just column number five.
The next one we don't have to actually see the solution,
we already know that it's gonna be here.
So from row five and column five,
spanning across three tracks in each direction.
So five, five, and
spanning three tracks.
Oh and something's wrong there.
Ah, (sighs) right.
And now just one to go.
So this one is from row six
and column number eight.
Row six, span two so that's correct.
And column eight,
to minus one.
Don't forget to change this,
and that is it.
Alright, awesome.
So our images are nicely aligned here,
let's take a look at it
without this grid overlay.
And yeah, so that looks fantastic.
And it's all thanks of the grid of course,
and of the object fit property.
So lets actually take that one out
so just to see how it would look like without it.
And also without the height property here.
So that is how it would look like, right.
So if we would just place the images on the grid
and they would try to keep their intrinsic aspect ratios,
then that's the result we would end up with.
So that's a bit weird.
If we then set the height to 100%,
then we would keep our gaps here very nicely,
but then the aspect ratio would be gone
and we would end up with weird results
like this one, where the image is very stretched
or here, you can also see it very stretched,
and also here.
And so that's not what we want at all,
and so object fit,
see the difference now?
So object fit is really what makes this possible,
along with, of course, CSS grid.
So I hope you liked that,
and see you in the next one.