So, over these last lectures,
I promised that I would show you some more stuff
that you can do with npm packages
and npm scripts, right?
Like automatically adding prefixes to some properties,
or compressing code.
And so that's what we're gonna do in this lecture.
We are going to build something
developers call a build process.
And what is a build process?
Well, it's basically just a sequence of tasks
that we perform automatically
after we finish developing a product
or a certain feature of a product.
And the result of the build process
are one or more final files,
which are then ready for production.
Which means basically,
ready to be deployed to a web server.
So, what you see here is the very simple build process,
that we're gonna implement in a second.
We just start with our main.sass file
and then of course compile it to a css file
as we've been doing all this time.
Then, we want to merge the content of that css file
with the css and the icon-font file
so that we can go from including two css files in our page
to only one, which is a lot better.
And that process is called concatenation.
Then, from there, we wanna automatically
add prefixes to our code, right?
And so that's the next step in the build process.
And then finally, the last step,
is to compress the entire code we have at this stage.
And that's it, just four simple steps.
Nothing all too complicated.
So, let's now create this build process with npm scripts.
Alright, and we do that right here in the package.json file.
Now, the first thing that I wanna do is
to actually change the name of this script
that we already have,
which is called compile:sass,
and I wanna change it to watch:sass.
Because next, I wanna add a script
which will compile the sass but without watching it, okay?
So, it's actually pretty much the same as this.
We have to add a comma here
if you want to add a new one, okay?
And this one I wanna call compile.
But, as I said, without the watch part, okay?
And actually I wanna compile it to another file.
So, we go from main, of course,
which is our main.sass file,
and I wanna call it style.comp.css, okay?
So, comp stands for compiled.
Now, right now we still have our code running in here,
so let's actually close these two.
So, terminate, add a new tab, and then close this one.
Okay?
So, if we now run our compile sass script,
we should actually end up with the same code
as we had before, right?
The only difference is that it puts that into a new file
and that it's not going to watch for changes, okay?
So let's just test that out.
npm run compile:sass.
And alright, so you saw that it finished, you know,
and it created a new file here as well.
So, style.comp.css, alright?
And I'm doing that here in a different script
or a different task because these here
are actually called tasks, okay?
So, I'm doing this in a different task
because then later I want to combine
all of these tasks for our build process
and then that one should, of course,
not be watching for changes, okay?
And so we want one that watches the changes,
which is this one,
and then we want one that we can use
at the end of our project
when we run the build process.
So, the next step is to concatenate
our existing css files, right?
So, concat:css.
And of course, these names that I'm using here
don't have to be these exact names.
So, you can just call it concat,
or concatenation, or whatever you want.
I just like to use this format
where we first describe what we do
and then we say to what type of code it is applied.
And so this case, concat.
Now, how do we concatenate multiple css files?
Well, once again, there is an npm package for that.
And it's called just concat.
So, let's install it.
So, npm install concat,
and then remember we're gonna save it to dev,
so as a dev dependency,
so that it's added to our package.json file.
And so that's it.
Now, how do we actually use this?
Well, in case that you don't know, for example,
you can usually just Google like npm concat
and usually the first result
is the one that you're looking for,
which will take you to npmjs.com.
And so here, each npm package has its own page
where you can look up how it's actually used.
You can see the stats, so how many people download it.
You can check out the source code on Github,
and all of that stuff.
So, down here you have an example.
And so this here is how you use
the concat package in the terminal, okay?
You could also use it from Node.js directly like this,
but we're interested in the command line, basically.
So, let's just copy this in order to make it easier for us.
And then we can paste it here.
So, o here stands for output,
and so here we can put the name
of the output file that we want.
And we want it to be in a css folder
and called style.concat.css.
And the input files are, of course, not these ones,
this is just for example.
So, our input files are css/icon-font.css, right?
And actually it's a dash, not point.
So, it's the icon-font and then the style.comp.css.
So, the result of the first step, right?
So, css/style.comp.css, okay?
So, again, let me separate this here.
Again, this is our first step
where we compile our sass file
to our compiled css file.
Then the next step is to concatenate
these two files that we have,
the icon-font and the style from the first step,
so, this one here,
into a new file which is called style.concat.css, okay?
And so for this concatenation,
we installed a new npm package
and looked up how we can actually use it, alright?
So, let's now test the step out.
And again, in the end we will have one global task
which runs all of these at the same time.
So, we're not going to do them one by one in the real world.
This is just for testing purposes,
just to see if each of the step
is actually working.
So, let's now try out concat:css.
So, npm run concat:css.
And you see, it added the new file here,
so let's take a look.
And alright, so we have the content
of the icon-font file here, right?
So, all of this stuff.
And then down here somewhere, yeah,
so down here starts our own code, the code that we wrote.
Great, so that worked.
So, we have now all of the css code in one single file.
Which is a lot better, because like this,
we only need one HTTP request instead of two
when we had two files, right?
Okay, next step
is the prefix.
So, prefix:css.
And so we need yet another npm package.
And this one is called npm install autoprefixer.
And of course, save it as a dev dependency.
So, autoprefixer, yeah, I think that's right.
Now, in order for the autoprefixer to work,
we actually need to install another package
which is called postcss.
So, npm install postcss,
and then cli, which means command line interface.
So, the name of this package is postcss-cli,
and then of course, save dev once more.
Okay, and we need this one here
because the autoprefixer is actually
part of this postcss plugin or package.
Okay, so let's just wait until this installs.
And so, here we go.
And so now the command here is actually postcss.
And then we say use autoprefixer.
Okay?
And so this one is a bit more complicated,
and so I'm gonna just show it to you
instead of Googling how it works.
So, postcss is the package that we use,
and then we use the use option here with autoprefixer
in order to actually make the autoprefix work.
So, next, the b option,
which basically stands for browsers.
And here we can specify which browsers we want to target.
And the easiest options is to just say,
like the last x browsers.
So, for example, the last five browsers,
or versions actually, or whatever.
And so with this here,
it'll target the last five versions
of all the major browsers.
And this data actually comes from
the caniuse.com website that I showed you before.
So, it's always super up-to-date here.
Now, I like to use ten versions here,
then we can be really sure
that it's gonna add all the prefixes that we need, okay?
So, next is the input file
and it's the one from the step before.
So, style.concat.css.
And then we specify the output parameter,
so -o, and then the output that we want.
So, css/style.prefix.css.
And here I forgot the css part, okay?
And so now it's gonna go into the css folder,
grab the file that we outputted before,
so this one here,
and then write the output to the style.prefix.css file.
So, let's test that one out as well.
So, npm run prefix:css.
And alright.
And let's close this one here.
And so style.prefix, let's actually see
how many lines this file has.
Whoa, what's all of this here?
Well, maybe we don't have to
take a look at the number of lines.
I just wanted to check out
if the file is now larger than before,
but we can actually see that it's
added here a lot of prefixes.
So, like this webkit here
on all the transform properties, okay?
So, you'll see that all of these transforms here
now have the webkit prefix.
Then, you'll probably see,
let's go up here to the animations.
Ah, here we also have it on the box shadow,
the webkit prefix.
So, it added these on a bunch of things.
I just wanted to see the animations,
but they are probably a bit
more up.
Ah, here we go.
So, in the animations,
it also should've added,
yeah, here it did.
So, webkit in the beginning of the at rule, okay?
And so, yeah.
We see that this actually worked quite well, right?
Now, all of this can look a bit scary,
but that's not really a problem, right?
Because you just have to write this once
and then you can keep using it in the future.
Okay, and so we actually already arrived at our last step.
So, compress:css.
And for this one,
we actually don't need to install a new package
because our node-sass package here
can actually do that job, okay?
And it's very simple, we just have to write node-sass
then the input file, which is this one here.
So, the output from the step before,
and then the output file.
And I'm gonna call this one simply style.css.
So, that will be our final file.
You could also call it style.min, like this.
And you will usually see it as this,
but I don't wanna do that for one simple reason.
It's because if I do that, then I would have to change
in the HTML the href here as well, right?
And so I would have a different one
for the development phase,
and then a different one for the production code.
And I don't want that.
Well, actually what I can do here right now
is to comment out this part of the code
because we don't need it anymore, right?
Because it's now already included in our style.css file.
Now, in order for this to work,
we actually have to add an option here to this command
which is called output-style
and then compressed, okay?
And so basically, with this option here
setting the output style to compressed,
it will simply compress the code.
There's nothing to compile from sass to css
because the input is already in css,
but that's not a problem,
all it's gonna do here is to simply compress our code, okay?
So, of course, let's test that one out as well.
So, npm run compress:css.
And so, style.css,
whoa, so that's our final code now.
This is how it looks.
And it's just one line of code,
a huge line of code with all the code in there.
So, basically without all of the whitespace
that we included and without
all the comments also, of course.
Let's actually compare the sizes of these, okay?
'Cause I'm really curious now.
So, all the css files that we created here.
So, the input was the prefix one, right?
And it had 109 K.
And then the compressed one, which is the style.css,
has only 33.
So, that's actually a big difference.
So, like 76 K, okay?
So with that very simple step,
we just reduced our page load by almost 80 kilobyte, right?
So, that's great.
Now, as I promised,
I would in the end write a task
that will run all of these four here at the same time.
So, compiling, concatenation, prefixing, and compressing.
And I'm gonna call that one build:css.
And so this one is going to build our css
which is gonna be ready for production.
And so, how do we do that?
Well, the best option,
in order for it to work on all platforms,
so on Mac and Windows and Linux
all at the same time,
is to use, once again, an npm package.
And this one is called npm-run-all.
And so the name here actually says all,
so we just call this package,
so npm-run-all,
and then all we have to do
is to put the name of the tasks in there.
So, compile, concat,
prefix,
and compress.
Alright, now let's actually delete all of these files here.
Okay?
Except the icon-font, of course.
Because that one we have to keep.
And so let's now test this out.
So, npm run build:css.
Alright, so you saw that it
run all of our tasks here one by one,
and now it's finished,
and it created all of this files here.
Meaning that our build process is actually working.
Fantastic, that's a great job, really.
That's really cool.
But there's actually more that I want to show you.
I wanna show you another use case of this npm-run-all, okay?
So, this is here our build process,
so our build workflow.
Now, what we also want is basically a development workflow.
And we already set that up before, right?
So, basically as we develop,
we are running this watch.css process here,
and at the same time,
we're running the live server process, right?
So, that process that makes it so that
each time that we save a file
it automatically reloads the browser, right?
But remember that we had to run both of these
in a different command line.
And so that's not really handy, right?
We can do better than that.
So, let us first add another task called
devserver,
and this is just for live-server.
So, basically, devserver will be
the same as the live server.
But here in this step that I'm gonna show you next,
I cannot directly call live-server,
and so I have to create this task here
which I can then call,
because what I'm gonna do now is a task called start.
And that's a very common name
that developers use for a development process, okay?
So, I'm gonna call start
and I wanna run npm-run-all,
watch:css, and devserver.
And actually let's put the devserver here before.
Alright, now, in order to make this work,
so basically that they run at the same time,
I have to specify another argument, another option.
And that one is simply called parallel, okay?
And that's because I want these two
to run at exact same time.
While down here, I want them to run
in a sequence, so first this one,
then this one, then this one, then this one.
And so that is different, okay?
So, here they have to run both at the same time, okay?
And so if we now do npm,
npm run start,
then it gives me this error here, okay?
But I see why that is,
and it's because here it's not css,
but it's called watch:sass, right?
So, watch:sass here, and then of course,
watch:sass over there as well.
So now it should run.
Clear.
Now, alright, so here we go.
So, we can close the previous one that we had.
And so you'll see, if you take a look at our console now,
that it's working the node-sass with a watch
and the live-server here, right?
And so with one command,
we basically started our development workflow.
So, just to test things out,
let's change something.
For example, let's set it here to something really huge.
Alright, so,
that's not what we want, of course,
but what this means is that basically,
it's working, right?
So, it's watching our sass file
and it's running our live web server.
So, that is absolutely great.
Now, by doing that, of course it overwrote
the style.css file that we outputted before, right?
Because now it created a new one.
And so, during development,
this one here cannot be commented out,
because otherwise we will not be able
to access the icon-font, right?
So, you can only put this comment here,
so you can only take out this entire code,
so basically when you're ready to deploy it
to a live web server, okay?
But for now I'm gonna leave it like this
and come back to my package.json file.
But actually, I think we're already done here.
So, we now have our development process here
nicely on the top,
and then our build process in here.
And it works for this project,
and it can work the exact same way
on all your next projects.
So, all you have to do is to then come back here
and like copy this part here of the script.
Copy these dev dependencies.
And then you're good to go.
So, I hope that you found this useful,
because there is really a huge value
in automating all this kind of stuff.
And that's what all real developers
actually do in the real world.
And so that's why I wanted to show you this
because I think it's really important for you.
So, we're almost, almost ready with our project.
There's only one lecture left
to finish up our Natours project.
And so, don't wait, and come check that one out right now.