Let's just take three minutes to
quickly finish the sidebar of our page.
So once more you will just apply some of the concepts
that you have learned before in the course.
So all we're going to do is to add this small button here
that we have in the sidebar
and actually when we click it here
then nothing really happens.
So this is just a button so that something
is in here, okay.
So I just didn't want to leave this empty here
and so I just packed this button in there, okay.
So in our HTML right at the beginning,
because that's where our sidebar element is,
I'm just going to put a button here and call it
the nav button.
Okay, and no content in there and then
here in the sidebar file
let's quickly style this.
So since it's a button we have to get rid
of the border radius
and of the border itself.
So no border
and no border radius.
Okay, and so how are we going to do that?
Well once again we're just going to create
like a very small white rectangle here
and then with a before and an after pseudo element
we are going to create the other one.
Okay, so
this will have a white background color
and it's only going to be two pixels high,
so two pixels and a width
of 45 pixels, so 4.5 rem.
Okay, and then let's just add
the before and the after pseudo element.
So just like this nav button itself
it will have the three properties
and in order to make them actually visible
we need to give them the content property.
So content and set it to empty
and I'm also going to display them as a block.
Okay, and now finally we have to move
one of them up and one down.
So the before is the one we're going to move up.
So transform translate in the Y direction
minus 1.5 rem
and the one after we're going to move it down,
so plus 1.5 rem.
So let's take a look at that.
Well that looks kind of weird
and not really as expected.
So let's take a look at what's happening here
with the sidebar and this button here.
So there's not really any style here applying to it,
and why is that?
So let's see if we have some error
maybe in the terminal here, and actually yeah.
So there are some kind of error.
So it's apparently here in this part of the code.
So yeah, so it's because I have the semicolon
inside of these parenthesis
and that's not where they should be of course.
Okay, so that's that,
and I think we cannot see the one before,
because it is actually now outside of the page.
So we need to move all of this here down a little bit.
So the entire button,
so margin top
like four rem
and let's take a look at that now,
and yeah that looks much better.
Now all there's left to do is to really center
this here inside of the container.
For that a good way to do it is to use Flexbox.
So remember that I said that
Flexbox is great for these very, very small applications
like aligning and centering small stuff.
Okay, and so this is a perfect use case
for using Flexbox.
So here on the sidebar container
display flex and then all we have to do
is to say justify content center,
because remember that justify content
aligns all of the items along the main axis,
and that's the one that we want, so horizontally,
and we want to center it.
So that is the result.
Now just a small problem here, I see that here
this distance here is slightly smaller than this one here
and that's because we translated both
1.5 rem,
but the place where it starts counting
this offset is not really centered here apparently.
So we just have to move this one here
so that the after one a bit up.
So probably like two pixels.
So instead of 1.5 let's give it 1.3
and that fixes it, and okay
so we're good to go, another component that is ready now.
So all that's left to do is to really finish now this header
and this realtors part.