Welcome back.
I hope you're ready for the next part of our Trillo project,
which will be the hotel overview
So, in this section, the new things you will learn
are how to create an infinite animation
and also how to use the power of margin auto
together with flexbox.
And of course you're gonna continue using flexbox properties
for easy positioning and alignment of our elements.
So, the hotel overview is basically just this part here
where we get a quick overview about the name,
the stars and the location and then the average
rating of the users.
But before that, we also have these images here.
Okay, and so, let's quickly start with that
before we actually do the hotel overview.
And that's just gonna take us like five minutes.
So let's start with that.
So right here in the hotel view,
we are gonna add an element called the gallery.
And then we have the three images.
And I'm gonna wrap each of them in a figure element.
Okay, so figure and gallery item.
And then in there, we have the actual image
called gallery photo.
Now, the images that I want here I called
I think just hotel, yeah, hotel one,
and then here simply photo of hotel one.
And that's it.
So I'm actually wrapping these images here
in a figure element so that you could later like add
a fig caption element here, so to give these images
a caption, but I'm not gonna do that right now.
You could maybe do it later if you feel like it.
So, hotel one
becomes two, and then this one is just a number three.
And then here the same in the description.
And that's actually it.
So, let's go to our components file here.
And style this.
Now just this comment here.
And the first thing that we want to format
is actually the photo.
So, gallery photo, which is the image element.
So, remember that in responsive design,
we also want flexible images.
And so, we always have to define a width
or a height in percentages so that the image stays fluid.
So let's set a width to 100% here.
Okay, and then what we're gonna do to put the figure
elements side by side is once again to use flexbox.
Okay, so all we have to do is set the display to flex.
And then all these figure elements should be side by side.
And another thing here is that the image
should be displayed as a blog.
And that's about having a small space
underneath an image, which happens when we leave it
as an inline element.
Okay, so an image should always be a block
or an inline block if we don't want that wide space.
So let's check that out, ask actually, first of all,
we should get rid of this orange background.
But you see that the images are actually already
perfectly aligned here.
So, first of all, let's get rid of that orange background.
And where is it?
Ah, here.
Ah, that's much nicer.
So let's just inspect these figures.
And you see that because of flexbox,
they are now side by side.
So, if there was no flexbox here on the gallery,
then this is what they would look like.
So occupying 100% of the available width.
Now, we could also set these items here
or these images to 1/3, so like to 33.333%,
and then use float on these figures here.
So that would produce the same effect.
And then we would have to use a clear fix
on the parent, and all of that is a bunch of work.
And so, once again, we just use flexbox
in order to achieve the same result.
So put these images side by side
without any clear fix hack or anything like that.
Okay, so that part is done, so let's now move on
to the hotel overview itself.
So there are four parts in here.
First we have this heading, so this will be her
H one element, meaning that it's like
the main title of this document.
Then we have the stars here.
Then after that the location on this side.
And then the overall user rating.
So let's mark it up in our HTML.
And so, this one I'm gonna call it the overview.
Okay, and then our H one that I was talking about,
so overview heading,
and this hotel is simply called Hotel Las Palmas.
Maybe not the most creative name.
But it serves our purpose here.
Okay, so the next one is the stars.
And so, I'm simply gonna put them in a container first,
so overview stars.
And then in there we put our five stars.
So one SVG icon for each of them.
Such as we did before with all the other icons.
So let me actually copy that part
instead of having to write it out all over again.
And this one, let's see how it's called.
It's probably just star, and, yeah, you see it is.
So icon star, and now we just need this five times.
And so, these are our five stars.
So, next up, we have our location.
So, overview
location.
Now, let's just take a quick look at that
in a finished example.
So you see that here we have this location icon
and then this underlying text.
And this here is actually what I call an inline button
because down here we have it again.
So it's this button here
that we use up here in the location.
And then down here for this show all button here again.
And it actually has this nice effect that I
was telling you about, so this infinite animation,
which is this one.
So when the button is focused,
it will have this permanent and infinite
pulsating animation here.
But we're gonna leave that one for later.
So for now I just wanted to tell you
that we have this icon and this button here.
And then in the next one, we have this rating element here
and then this text, and then the number of votes down there.
Okay, so we start with the icon here.
Once again, I'm gonna get that from here.
And it is called the location pin.
So, location pin, and then down here the button
called button inline.
And the location of this innocent Albufeira.
So, in the sunny southern part of beautiful Portugal.
Okay, so that is the location and of finally the rating.
Then we have the average,
which was in our case, 8.6.
And the overview rating count.
So, 429 votes.
And I'm putting votes because it's shorter than ratings.
So that's the only reason.
All right, so now we're ready to take a look at it.
And that already looks pretty nice.
Now, this is already formatted here
with this gray color.
And that's probably because when I copied it,
it came with this wrong class name here.
So that's of course not what I want.
And actually down here as well,
so what I want here is really overview
icon star, and down here actually location.
So these ones here for the icon stars,
and this here is the icon location.
And so, now they look huge of course
because they are still completely unformatted.
So, in order to be able to work with this,
let's actually start by formatting these icons here.
So, a new component here.
And let me copy this one here again.
So, writing all our selectors,
we start with the heading,
then we have the stars,
and we have the icon stars.
And let's see what else we have.
So, we have location, icon location, rating,
rating average, and rating count.
Then we have the icon location, and we can probably group
that together with the icon star.
So, icon location in here.
Then we have the rating.
And finally the rating count and rating average.
All right, so once again, a lot of selectors here,
but that's just how it works when you're coding up
such a big and detailed interface.
So, let's give it here a width
of 1.75 rem, and of course the same height
such as we've been doing all the time.
So 1.75 rem as well.
And then the color, so we use fill again.
Setting it to the primary color.
So, color primary.
So let's take a look.
And so, that looks much better.
Next step is to pit all of these four boxes
side by side, and so, that's really easy, nothing new here.
So we use flexbox of course.
And flexbox will do its magic.
And so, now it looks like this.
All of these side by side.
Now this is of course still not perfect.
So let's fix that as well.
And the first way I want to do it
is to of course use justify content.
So let's use space between here
so that it will evenly distribute all the space
between all the elements along the main axis.
And so, that is the result that we get.
Now, the thing is that this is not quite what we have
in our demo example.
So, this one here, this is not quite what we have.
So we have the stars actually close to the heading.
And then the location close to the rating.
And then a huge space in the middle of these two.
And so, therefore, justify content is not a good way
of doing that, because it doesn't allow us to create
a space only between two of the four elements.
And so, let's remove that.
So I just wanted to show it to you
why it doesn't work.
And so, the next thing we can try is to use flex
on, for example, the location.
So what I want is this.
We can say flex to one, and what this is is that
this flex item should grow and occupy
all the available space.
And this will actually be pretty close to what we want.
So let me show that to you.
So, yeah, now it occupied all of this entire space here.
And actually we probably would want that
on the stars.
So, that's how it would look like.
And that is exactly what we want here in this demo.
Now, in order to show you that this isn't really ideal.
Let me give this a background color.
And so, you will see that now this element here
is occupying this entire space,
just as we told it to do.
So we told it to expand, to grow and occupy
all the space that is available.
And that's what it did.
Now, this is not ideal, because this element should only
be the size of its content,
so in this case the size of these stars.
We don't want it to have all of this size.
Imagine that we would have a hover effect on this
and then all of this entire element here
would be hovered and would change the background,
for example, and that's not what we want.
We only want the hypothetical hover effect
to occur right here on this box
where the stars actually are.
So what we want is a way to create this space here
without actually stretching out this entire element.
And that is where the power of margin auto comes in.
So let me show that to you.
So we remove flex one, and instead we can use margin right
and set it to auto.
And that's a very powerful trick in flexbox.
And that's what happens.
So, the same result, but with our element actually
only occupying the space that it needs here.
So this is the space that it needs.
And so, that's all that's occupied.
And then all of this space is
the automatically calculated margin.
So this is a great trick.
You should probably write it down because it's really
helpful in flexbox to use margin auto.
Each time we have a situation like this,
we want to create some space like this,
we can use margin auto.
We could also have used margin left auto
on this element here that would have created
the exact same space.
And so, again, this is a very good trick to know
and to use with flexbox.
Okay, so let's just get rid of that background.
Color, of course.
And so, in terms of layout, we're getting pretty close
to the original version.
All we have to do now is to actually format
each of these four smaller components here.
But I'm gonna leave that to the next video
so that you can take a quick break.
So see you in a second.