So in the last lecture, we learned
how to align grid items to grid areas.
And so let's now learn how to align
entire grid tracks to our grid container.
Now, before we can do that, we actually need
to make a couple of changes here,
and let me start by adding a comment here,
so "Align grid items to grid areas,"
and so next, we're gonna learn about
"Align grid tracks to grid container."
And this one here, of course, should be in here.
So let's put this all together a bit, okay,
and now what I need to change is actually
the columns here, because I no longer want them
to occupy the entire container,
because then I cannot really show you
how all of this works, okay?
So let me comment this one out here,
or I can actually just copy it,
and so let me put it here, where we learn about this.
So let's say I just want
150 pixel wide columns, or maybe 200.
Okay, and actually, let's also comment out
this one here from the last lecture,
so that makes it a bit more easier to understand.
Okay, just like this.
Maybe we can also decrease the rows a little bit,
so let me change that as well.
So let's say 100 pixels.
Now, we already have the width here of the container,
which is these 1000 pixels, right,
so let's also just set the height
of the container to 1000 pixels.
Okay, and so now you'll see that
the container actually continues down here,
and then also here on the side of the grid, okay?
So basically, our entire container is this,
so all of this is our container,
but our grid tracks, they only occupy
this part of the container, okay?
And so all the rest here is empty.
And so now we're ready to actually align the tracks
to the container, which is the goal of this lecture, right?
So what do I actually mean with that?
So let me show it to you,
and I'm gonna start with justify-content.
And again, this property exists in Flexbox,
and it actually works the exact same way.
So it's just gonna align the tracks inside of
the container across the row axis, so horizontally.
So let's set it to center, and here we go.
So it moved right to the center of the container.
And so just as we center flex items
inside of a flex container with justify-content,
we do it the exact same way with the grid tracks
here in CSS Grid, okay?
So this is what we will use if we want to really center
the entire content, basically, of the grid
inside of the container.
Now, there are other values, of course,
just like in Flexbox, and actually
there are the exact same possibilities.
So, one is center, as I just showed you,
and of course, there is start,
which we already saw how it looks like,
so just like this, then there's end.
So let me write down the options here for you.
And then, beside these three very basic ones,
there are the ones that we also have in Flexbox.
So we have space-between, and so let me
actually write it here as well, so space-between,
and see what happens now.
So it pushed each of the columns
to one of the sides of the grid container.
Right, so basically, it divided all of the empty space here
between these two columns, so these two tracks.
And so that's the exact same behavior
as in Flexbox with space-between.
Now, we also have space-around, and so, as you would expect,
it works just the same way as in Flexbox, so basically,
the space on the left side is the same as on the right side,
so basically, it's like this square here,
but then here, in this grid track here,
it's the exact same thing.
So the same space here on
the right side as on the left side,
which makes it so that the space here
in between these two is double the space
than we have here on both the left and the right side.
So let me write down the option for you here again.
And then the last one here is space-evenly,
and what this is going to do is that
the space is now all the same here, and here, and here.
So the space between the items is the exact same space
as on the left and the right side of each of the items.
Okay, so these are different possibilities
to build different types of layouts.
Now, we also have, of course, justify-items.
Now, if we can horizontally align these tracks,
then of course we can do the same vertically, right?
And so, what we do for that is align-content.
Okay, and so let's start again with center here,
because I think that's always the most useful,
and so you see that now, all of it moved
into the middle of the container vertically.
And let's zoom out a bit again to see this happening.
Okay, just like this, maybe just like this, yeah.
So you have this entire container here,
and now we see that our tracks here, or rows,
they're now vertically inside of this gray container.
So let's actually remove this here
so you can see it a bit better,
and yeah, so you'll see that exactly happening.
Turn it back on, and yeah, and let's go back
to the size that we had, okay.
Then in here, you have actually all the exact same options
as you have here in justify-content.
Let's just set this one here to center as well,
and so, well, what's going on here now?
Ah, the semi-colon is missing.
And yeah, so now it's completely centered here,
so both vertically and horizontally inside the container.
And you see that it kind of adds these huge gutters here
at the top and on the left side here,
in order to put us here in the center of the grid.
Right, but that doesn't really matter,
it's just to see how Grid actually handles this centering.
So let's try, just for example, end,
moving it down all the way to the end.
Yeah, just like expected.
Or let's try space-between as well.
So let's see what that does, and yeah,
so it's the exact same thing as it does
with justify-content, so basically
the space between all of these row tracks
are now the same, so that it occupies
the entire height of the container.
Then, of course, space-around,
so that also works the same way.
Okay, so the space here on top
is the same as all of this space here.
Well, it doesn't really look like that,
but, well, it should, it should be like that.
Okay, so let's go back to center here,
because again, that's actually the most useful case.
So basically, if you want to center
all of our items inside of a grid container,
that's how we do it.
We set justify-content and align-content to center,
and that's it, okay?
So you see that basically, whenever we have items here
in the property name, so align-items and justify-items,
that is for the individual items,
and if we have content here in property names
like we have in justify-content and align-content,
then it means that it's gonna align the entire tracks.
Then the align part of the name always means
the vertical direction, or the column axis,
so that's the same.
So align-content and also align-items means
the vertical direction, so the column axis.
And at the same time, justify always means
that it's the horizontal direction, so the row axis,
both for justify-items and justify-content.
So that is the logic behind these names,
and I think that's helpful to memorize
and to understand what each of these four properties does.
Okay, so I hope that this makes sense to you
and that you fully understand how we can
place our items and our tracks
exactly where we want them to be
inside of the grid container.
So now there's just one more small thing
that I want to show you in this small demo project,
and so let me just add a small change here
to one of these items, so let me style
the item number 6.
Let's give it a background-color of light coral,
and then make it span across two row tracks.
So grid-row and span 2.
So let's see how that looks like.
And so yeah, so it spans now these two rows.
And then what I wanted to create here
is this empty cell, and this empty cell here
comes from the fact that the automatic placement algorithm,
it kind of tries to keep the sequence of these items here
in the source code, it tries to kind of follow that
when it places the grid items on our grid.
And so sometimes, that can create these kind of holes here,
okay, and we not always want them.
And so let me show you how we can actually fix that.
Let's just take this out here so we can
see it a bit better, and let me also
take off this, because it overlays here all our code.
I'm not really sure why, but it looks better like this.
Okay, so let me actually zoom out here a bit again,
and so this is our grid, and this is here the hole,
basically, in the grid that I was talking about.
And again, that's because the automatic placement algorithm,
it tries to keep these eight items here that we have
kind of in order, okay, so it tries to follow that order,
but if we want to fix that, we can actually do it,
and it's very easy, it's very simple.
All we have to do is to come here to this property,
to grid-auto-flow, and in here we defined
that it should flow in rows, right,
so that the items should be placed in rows, not in columns.
All we have to do here is to add the dense keyword.
Okay, and so with this, we say that
we actually want no holes in there,
and that we want a more dense grid.
So with no holes, all the items packed
so that all the grid cells are filled
with some kind of item, okay?
So let's take a look at that again,
and so now you'll see that the track that we had down here
is now gone, so let me
take that out again to show it to you, and you see.
So now we had this additional track here,
then this hole, and then, yeah, this here
you can also call a hole,
so another cell without any item in there, okay?
And so if you set it back to dense,
you will see that now this one here, which said "great,"
it's now moved to this place, which was empty before.
Okay, and this can be useful sometimes,
like if we have an image gallery or something like that,
so we may place some images in different grid cells
in order to make a good-looking grid of images,
and then sometimes they may be some kind of hole,
and then we just use the dense keyword
in order to fill that hole,
and end up with a dense, full-packed grid
like this one, without any holes.
Okay, so that was just another quick thing
that I wanted to show you, and so now
we're actually done with this small demo project.
So again, you're moving on with a great pace.
You already have most of the fundamentals that it takes
to start building real-world grid layouts.
There's just a couple of more advanced things
that we have to learn, and we're gonna do that
over the next couple of lectures, okay?
So we're gonna start another very small demo project,
and then I'm gonna teach you a little bit more
advanced stuff in there, okay?
So if you wanna do that right now,
then let's move on together right to the next video.