Let's continue to build the overview of our hotel.
So the first thing I wanna do is to add a border
to the bottom of this element here.
A small gray line such as the header has, or should have,
because it doesn't have the line here that it should have.
So probably something's going wrong there.
So let's check that out.
So right here in the layout, the header, border-bottom,
oh okay, so (laughs) I only specified the color.
Of course I also have to specify the width and the type.
So one pixel solid, and it's actually the exact same one
that I want
here on the hotel overview.
(clicking)
Yeah, now that's better.
So now you see the border here separating the header
from the rest of the page,
and that's specially visible here on this image,
which is also white on the top.
And down here we have it in the overview as well.
Next, we should probably vertically center
these four elements in this box.
And so we're going to use Flexbox,
which we already have active here,
and using the align-items: property, right?
So aligning the items along the cross axis,
and you want center.
And with one simple line of CSS
all of this is now vertically aligned.
Next up is the header,
or the heading.
So font-size:, I chose 2.25rem here,
as a font-weight: we only want 300,
so big text but small font weight.
Then text-transform: to uppercase,
and also a very slight letter-spacing:
of one pixel, that makes it look slightly better.
Then of course, some padding: here
to give it some breathing space around it.
And 1.5rem top and bottom, and three left and right.
And so, let's take a look at that.
Alright, that looks a lot better already.
And you saw that all of the items, of course,
automatically adjusted and are still vertically centered.
And so next up are our stars.
And for some reason you see that they are not,
really not 100 percent vertically aligned,
so lets take a look at that.
Right, so this here is the element,
so the container of these stars.
And you see that there is like,
a small space below each of the stars.
And that happens because these SVG elements,
they behave like in-line elements,
and so it's a bit like text.
That produces that small white space that we see here.
We can remove that by setting the line height
and the font size to zero, for example,
but we have a simpler way of doing that.
And that is by simply setting
their parent element to Flexbox.
So just do display: flex;
and all of these icon star elements,
these here,
they will now become flex items
and then that space will be gone.
And there you see it.
So you see that now this parent element,
which is now a flex container,
has the exact same height as the stars themselves.
So now it's vertically centered perfectly and also,
they are now really nicely side by side,
which they weren't before.
So let's take that out.
So that's without flex and that's with flex,
and so that looks a lot better.
Next up, let's actually format this in line button here.
So that is a whole new component, right?
So it's called btn-inline here,
so let's create a new component for that one.
I also want to comment here.
(clicking)
And so, button inline.
So, first thing is we want to remove the border
of this button,
because these buttons by default
always come with this border
and we don't want that of course.
Then we want the color: to be the primary color.
(clicking)
And we want a font-size:
of, actually we want it to be inherit.
Okay, and why is that?
Well, let me show you the example here.
So in this case, for example, the text is really small
and down here where we use it again, it's bigger.
And so we do that by setting one font size here
on this parent element,
for example this huge parent element here,
and then we can also set a font size
on the parent element of this button,
and then all we have to do is to set the font size
on that button itself to inherit.
And so by that it becomes a bit more modular, more reusable.
Next we want it to have a border at the bottom,
of one pixel
solid
and now is the time where I'm gonna use currentColor again.
Okay, and that's because this way,
the border will have the exact same color as the text,
and that's what we want.
And later when I then add the hover effect,
which I can actually do right now,
(clicking)
all I have to say then is that I want the
color to be
the dark gray.
So (--color-grey-dark-1).
So all I have to do is to change the text color
in the hover state and then the border
will automatically update as well, right?
So let's check that out.
So here you go, as we hover the button
the border becomes the exact same color as the text.
So without currentColor,
I would now have to add another line here
and say border bottom and then also with this gray color.
But with currentColor we don't have to do
anything like that, and that's great.
So next, we want a small padding at the bottom as well
of two pixels, to create some space
between the text and the border.
And also we want this to be displayed
as an inline-block and not just as inline.
And I saw that the background was this weird gray
and I also don't want that,
so background-color and I'm gonna set it to transparent,
so once again this helps making the button
a bit more modular because here in this case,
for example, it is on a gray background,
but here it's on a white background.
So we don't want to attribute a fixed color
for that background.
Okay now all we have to do is set the cursor: to pointer
and then add the transition of course,
so transition: all
.2 seconds.
So that is the basic functionality,
so it works great,
but remember that we also had this focus effect.
So this animation effect here.
And I put it here so that I could show you
another cool thing with animations.
Okay, so let me show that to you.
(clicking)
So, focus
and the first thing is outline: none;
which is going to remove that default blue border,
but then we have to actually create
that pulsating animation that we just saw okay?
So that is a CSS animation using the keyframes at rule.
Alright, because we have no way of doing that
with a transition animation,
so we write what we want to happen using
the keyframes at rule.
Okay, so @keyframes and I'm gonna call this
animation pulsate.
(clicking)
And then I define what happens at the beginning,
at the end, and also in the middle.
So we have three states here,
so one at zero, one at 50% of the time,
and then 100%.
So let's take a close look at what actually happens here
so that we can code up this animation.
So basically in the beginning nothing happens,
then in the middle it is scaled up a little bit,
and it has this shadow going on,
and then in the end it goes back to the normal.
And so that's what we have to code up here.
So the state in the middle basically
is just a transform with a scale.
So we scale this just a little bit,
like 1.05,
and we also give it a very small box-shadow
like 0 1rem 4rem for the blur
and then the color
of black with
.25
opacity.
And then what we have to do is to of course
set the initial and the final state
to the normal state.
So scale of one and no box-shadow
and that's very easy, we just use the none keyword,
and at the end it's exactly the same.
Okay, so in the beginning we have
no scale and no box-shadow,
then at 50% we scale it up a little bit, give it a shadow,
and then 100% back to normal.
And now all we have to do is to add
our animation: property.
So animation:
pulsate
one second
but that is actually not enough,
because look at what happens when we do that.
So I'm gonna click now.
And it happened, but it only happened once of course.
I can click again, and then it's gonna happen again,
but I want it to be infinite.
And so all we have to do is
to actually add the word infinite
and so that is going to create an infinite animation
as long as the button is focused of course.
So this only applies in the focused state of course.
But try it now, it should already be working,
and yeah actually it is.
So, great.
So we have that part completed as well.
And now we should probably define a font size
for this parent element as I was saying before,
and we should also vertically align these two elements.
So, moving back up here, we have the location,
ah here it is.
So lets give it a font-size of 1.2rem
and then we want to vertically align the two elements,
the icon and the button.
So of course we use Flexbox,
display: flex;
and vertically align,
center.
So by now you've used it so many times
that I'm sure that it's becoming really familiar.
Okay, now we should just give some space here
to the right side here of this icon
so to create some space between these two.
So actually we need this selector,
(clicking)
so margin-right let's say .5rem,
okay and so now we have this part here completed as well.
So all that's left to do is now this writing part
so let's do that.
So first, it's the background-color
that you noticed to be our primary pink color.
So (--color-primary) then also let's give it a margin
to the right side to create that space
between the location and the rating, so 3rem,
and actually it's not to the right
it's to the left of course.
And also it should have a white color.
So color:
white.
And now just for this text here,
so the average is really big,
so 2.25rem
and then a smaller font-weight
and then the count down there is a lot smaller.
So font-size: .8rem; and also I want it to uppercase.
So let's take a look at that,
and that looks pretty good already,
we just need some padding here on the left and right side.
And of course, this should stretch
the entire height of the parent container right?
So going from up here, all the way down here.
So how do we do that?
Take a moment and think about how we can do that, okay?
So have you figured it out?
Well it's actually the exact same situation
that we had up here with these elements, right?
We also wanted them to stretch all the way
from the top to the bottom,
and so that's what we need to do here.
We do that by setting the align-self: property right?
And we simply set it to stretch,
because remember that all of these elements
are aligned to the center because of this declaration
that we have up here.
And so now we override that here
for this single element called &amp;_rating
and align it to the stretch,
so basically make it stretch
and occupy all the space that it has available for that.
Okay, and now just about the padding
that I was talking about,
so we don't need any padding at top and bottom,
we just need padding at the left and right side, so 2.25rem.
Alright, and now what's left to do
is to center these two both horizontally and vertically
here in this container.
So my favorite tool for that is of course, Flexbox.
So, display:
flex;
and I'm gonna say align-items: to center,
and justify-content: to center as well.
But now you will probably think
that there will be a problem with this,
and that is absolutely true,
because they will now be side by side right?
So the elements are side by side
and no longer on top of each other,
and that's exactly what Flexbox does,
it lays out the flex items in a row.
But remember that we can change that, right?
And so all we have to do is to set flex-direction:
to column
and that's actually it.
So let's see, and here we go.
So in the main axis, the justify content
aligns these elements to the center.
So in that direction they are to the center,
and then along the cross axis which is notice,
align items also centers the elements.
And so that's what we end up with.
Now I just want to slightly decrease
the space between these two, and that's very simple.
So I can simply set a negative margin to the bottom,
so like -3px
and yeah, that looks more consistent.
Looks better.
So let's compare it to our original result
and yeah, it's actually exactly the same, right?
So looks pretty similar, and so yeah,
we're done with this part of the interface.
It looks great, right?
I think it's absolutely fantastic, really beautiful,
and I hope that you think the same
and that you're really proud of all the work
that you have accomplished so far in this section.
So great job, I hope you're learning lots of Flexbox
and I hope you're really enjoying this project.
If you wanna continue with it right now
then let's just move on to the next video.