Let's continue styling our form in this lecture.
So once more we add a new component here,
to a components folder so form.scss
add .form in here, and of course, also included here.
So, form, save it and close it.
Alright, so we have the form and in there
we have the form input,
and of course the form label, at least for now.
And of course we also have the form group,
and let's start with the input actually, okay?
So, font-size of one point five rem,
let's give it a nice padding of one point five in the top,
and bottom it on two on left and right,
And usually we always do it like this on buttons,
and form elements.
We give it a bit more on the sides
because it makes elements look better, actually.
If we just give it one point five it looks a bit strange,
it looks like it's smaller on the sides
than it actually is.
So always a bit more on the sides, okay?
Now a nice border-radius as well,
let's do it on two pixels this time
because the element itself is a lot smaller,
and then we want it to have a background color
where we can look through a bit.
So we use rbga again,
white, and let's say 50 percent opacity.
Also you want to get rid of the border, so 'border: none;'
Alright, let's take a look at that
before we do anything else.
Okay, now the first thing you need to notice
is probably the font family, it's not the same
as you have in the rest of the webpage.
So the font family is not Lato,
and that's a default thing that the browsers do, actually.
So by default they don't give it the font family
that we have for a webpage.
So let's edit, and, well, we could do font-family
and I'll set it to Lato, but we can do something better
with something that we learned,
you don't have to theoretic lectures,
and we can say the font family directly to inherit.
And that's it!
And so now it will automatically inherit
the font family as well.
So you know that usually all elements,
they automatically inherit the font family,
but not the input elements and so we set it manual here,
and then you see it will work now.
So slight difference, but it's clearly visible, okay?
Now let's just give some space here
between these form groups, okay?
So you want a margin bottom,
but we don't want it on the last one.
So, we use our old trick where we start everything
except the last child.
So margin-bottom let's say two rem,
and it will improve things a bit.
Okay, what you also saw here was that
when we selected to (mumbles) the element,
then you saw this blue border here going on,
and that's also something that we don't want to see.
Now this blue border appears on the input elements
when it's focused, so this is the focus state.
And in CSS we can actually style it using
the focus pseudo element, okay?
So let's do that.
So instead of active, or hover,
or something like that, it's simply called focus.
And that blue line that you see is called the outline.
So we used outline before, like in the first section
in the beginning where we have these three images,
and then when we hover, we have this green border
around them that's also an outline, okay?
But this one is an outline
which the browser gives us by default,
and we don't want that so we set it to none.
Now this focus is actually very important
for people who use a webpage without a mouse,
but only with a keyboard, and so when they move around
with a keyboard on the webpage,
they need to know which form elements are actually focused,
and so for accessibility reasons,
we should never just do input focus,
and then set the outline to none and call it a day.
So we should always make the form elements
that are focused visible, alright?
So let's do that and we will do it by giving it a box-shadow
and also give it a border at the bottom.
So box-shadow: zero, one rem in the y direction,
two rem of blur, and then color black with point one.
And then, as I said, a border at the bottom,
of three pixels, then we say it should be solid,
and then we say we want it to be our primary color.
So the border is just a short hand property
for the border width, the border style, and the border color
but it's easy to adjust and specify them all at once here.
So let's take a look at that now,
and so now we have this nice shadow
and the green line as well.
Now what you see here is that when you click this
you will see that this one here moves down a bit,
and that's because of the three pixels that are created here
for the border here that's being added,
and so what we should do is to actually add that border here
in the initial state as well, but reset it to transparent.
Alright, and so it will be invisible in the normal state
and then as soon as we click it, as it's focused,
it becomes the green.
Now another thing that I also want to do
is to give it a width, so 100 percent,
and be sure to (mumbles) add it also display it as a block.
So that's better so that it has its own line here.
Well maybe it's a bit too much here with the 100 percent,
so let's just put it back to 90,
but you see that now this effect that we had going on here
where this one then jumped up and down is now gone, okay?
So let's do that, and another thing that we can do
is to actually style the placeholder here,
so that's also nice you see that in here it's this really
light gray here, and so with that we show
that it's actually only a placeholder,
and as soon as we start typing,
you see that it becomes darker, okay?
So let's do that, put 90 percent here
let us use a brand new pseudo element,
and that one is called webkit-input-placeholder.
So, webkit-input-placeholder,
and this right now will only work on Safari and Chrome,
but hopefully it will get implemented
in the other browsers as well.
So remember that pseudo elements,
they are with these two colons,
and they represent things that are actually on the webpage,
and so a placeholder is, of course,
a pseudo element, and not just a pseudo class,
which stands more for states here like focus.
So let us dial the color for this one here,
and so I guess we now need a new variable,
because this is a new color that we don't have yet.
So, this is another dark gray,
color dark the gray or gray-dark,
and I'm gonna call this one number two,
and so this one really should be number one
but I don't really want to change it now
because then I have to go to the place
where I used this here and change the variable name.
So we should have actually thought about this
right from the beginning,
but, well, that wasn't the case so now we can't use that.
So let's use that color actually.
Ah, here it is.
So we don't need the home anymore,
I will actually call this variable name here,
Alright. Now, another thing that I wanted to show you-
first, check this one here- well, this didn't really change,
well let's check it out again,
and yeah, of course I see why it doesn't work,
it's because this one is of course not on a form,
you see, we are here on the form level,
so right now we're saying form
and then webkit-input-placeholder,
but of course this is on the input.
Right, and so this should of course be in here,
and since we're at that,
this here is also not in the right place,
I mean it works, but we're not using
the power of nesting here, right?
So why I repeat the input should just do it like this.
So now it should work, and yeah here we go.
So now it's this cont and when I start typing,
it becomes dark, and actually it becomes pretty dark
it becomes black, and that's because once again
the font color is not really inherited.
So we have to set this once again to inherit.
So that's something really particular
to these input elements,
they don't inherit basically the font properties.
Now another very cool thing that we can do
is to actually make use of the validation
that Google Chrome has.
So remember that I told you
that here in the email input for example,
we specified the email type and then Google Chrome
will test if we're actually writing
in a valid email address or not,
and if we're not, it will basically be invalid.
And, in CSS, we can actually use that,
because on an input element,
we can actually use the invalid pseudo class, okay?
The invalid, and of course also the valid pseudo class,
and then we can apply specific styles
to when the value is valid, or when it's not valid.
So let me show it to you actually,
so in here we start with this here yellow,
and yellow, or let's say orange,
orange means that the input is not correct.
So let me start writing something here.
So, 'hello', is not really a valid email address.
But now, you saw, as soon as I started writing here
after the 'at' symbol, it turned green.
The same thing here, so we said that it should be required,
but right now there's no text, and so it's not valid.
So right now if I were to submit this form,
and it will say 'please fill out this form'.
But if I now start writing here it becomes green,
if I delete this one here it gets orange again,
and it says 'please fill out this field',
and if I just write something invalid,
it says 'please include an "at" in the email'.
And so we can take advantage of that invalid states.
Now I wanna think, when do we actually want this to happen?
Well, we want it to happen
only when the field is actually focused, right?
And so, we set focus once again,
and then invalid, and that's it.
So when we have an invalid, focused, input element,
then this is the style that we want to apply.
So we want a border that is orange,
and so let me get the color here,
so it's called color-secondary-dark.
Color-secondary-dark, okay,
and that should do the trick, and here it is.
So right now it's invalid,
and now I typed, and now it is valid.
And in here, 'hello at jonas.io',
and so now it's valid, like this it's not valid,
and like this it's also not valid.
Alright, so that works, so now,
before we move on to the radio buttons,
let's do that trick where we make this part here invisible,
and only appear as soon as we write something here
in the input, and so basically
it will then look like that name here,
that text would fly out and come out here down here,
because it's actually the same text.
So, this effect here, you see the full name,
and it moves down like that, okay?
So nice little effect,
but I think it makes all the difference
to have these subtle things on the webpage.
So let's know and actually start
by formatting here this label.
So we give it a pretty small font size of one point two rem,
make it bold with 700 font weight,
and then we give it a margin-left,
with two rem, that's because we want it positioned
exactly on the same position which the text is on top,
and then a margin to the top,
of point seven rem, okay?
And finally we should also display this as a block,
because otherwise you know
we cannot really use these box model properties
here on the element, right?
So let's take a look at that now,
so now you see this is now really aligned here
so that the effect will actually work
that we're looking for.
And now we need to take care of the magic
where this is only shown
as soon as we have some text in here,
and so once again this is really only CSS,
and no Javascript included,
and what allows us to do this is to use
the placeholder shown, pseudo class.
And so the placeholder shown is again here on the input.
Now I'm not going to really place it here,
and I'm gonna explain to you why in a second,
but for now trust me that this is how it has to be done.
So input and then placeholder shown.
So when the placeholder is shown on the input element,
then we can (mumbles) style it.
But it's not the input that we want to style, right?
What we want to style is the label.
We want the label to be hidden and not the input,
and so in here we also have to select the label.
(mumbles) first with like this,
but probably you notice that this is not going to work.
And why is that?
Well, because the label is not a child element of the input.
So we see in the HTML that there are siblings
so they're at the same level,
they're both childs of the form group, okay?
So again, input, and label, they are siblings,
because they are on the same level,
they're both children of this parent element,
but in CSS we have a very powerful selector
and it is called the sibling selector.
And so, this is how it works,
and this one is actually the adjacent sibling.
So what is an adjacent sibling?
Well, it's just a sibling that comes immediately
after the element that we select in the first place.
So we first select input, and then
with the adjacent sibling selector,
we select the first sibling, which is the label.
And so in this case, this works.
But if there was some other element in-between here,
let's say here was another div,
and then there was like some button or something,
so this would totally be possible,
then we could still use a sibling selector,
but we would have to use this one.
So this is the general sibling selector,
so this one works if there are more levels in-between,
but now we can use the adjacent sibling
because the sibling is right next to the first element.
Now one particular thing about the sibling selector
is that the sibling that we have to select,
in this case the label,
always has to be after the first element.
So the input in this case.
So again, the label needs to be after the input,
which is the case here, in order to be selected
with the sibling selector.
So, just as we have it here,
so we have to input, and then we select
the sibling of that element, and a sibling called 'label'.
If the HTML was written the other way around,
so if we had to label before the input, like this,
this wouldn't work, there would be no way of selecting
the label here from the input.
And that's the reason why I wrote the HTML in this order.
Alright, so when you need to use the sibling selector,
then you need to be careful about that.
So, when a placeholder is shown,
meaning that we have written nothing in our input,
we want the label to be hidden, right?
So, opacity zero, and then another thing that we should do
is to set the visibility to hidden.
That's because if we just set the opacity to zero,
then the element will basically still be on the page,
but only invisible, but if we set it to visibility hidden
as well, well, then it's really gone.
So why don't we just use the visibility hidden
without the opacity?
Well, because we cannot animate the visibility, okay?
That's how we use the opacity,
because we actually want to animate this effect,
and actually let me show it to you,
So, setting the transition here to all
in point three seconds,
and then you will already start seeing the effect.
So reload, and so now it's gone,
meaning that right now the placeholder shown, pseudo class,
is active and so right now,
this selector here is working,
so placeholder is shown, but as soon as we start writing,
the placeholder is gone,
and then these styles here will be gone as well.
So that's what happens now.
So you saw the opacity was animated,
and so it faded in, now it faded out,
in, out, in, out, you see?
Now what we want is to happen
is to also move down from here, right?
And so an initial state, it has to be there,
transform, translate, and of course it's in the y direction,
and it's going up and so minus four rem.
Let's actually show it to you how it will look like
still visible so to justify why I used the minus four rem,
so this is where the input is,
in this statement as I start writing it moves down.
Let's make it invisible again,
give it a save,
and now, here we go.
So, really cool right?
In the next lecture, we will then take care
of actually adding these radio buttons here.
So, stay tuned for that next lecture.