Finally, we reach the
last part of our project, and that's the
call to action section with a booking button in it.
And so in this lecture, you will learn
how to make that button because it has
yet another really cool and modern hover effect on it.
So let's get back to work.
So that here is a call to action section
that we're going to code now.
So it has this text here, which is an h2 element,
and then this button that I was talking about.
But let's for now take care of the overall formatting
of the section and of this heading element here.
Okay?
So this here is probably the, well, actually it's not.
So this is the detail.
And so right here is where we have to put
our call to action section.
So a div with the CTA class, short for call to action.
So in here we have the h2,
which I'm going to call cta__book-now,
and then the text that's in here is,
"Good news!
"We have four free rooms for your selected dates!"
So just this.
And then after that, we have our button,
which I'm simply calling btn.
All right.
And now in here, for now I'm just going to put
some text, so only four rooms left,
but we're going to have to change that later,
and I'm going to explain to you why then.
So for now, let's just have format here, or CTA element.
So down here, all the way down here,
and let's get this one here.
So call to action.
And I want to start with a padding of 3.5rem top and bottom.
And also, let's center the text here.
So text align to center, because that will
automatically center the h2 element as well as the button.
Okay.
So let's now format that h2.
So book-now, and that one has a text transform
of uppercase, and actually let's start
with the font size.
So 1.2rem.
And a font weight of 300.
And also margin to the bottom of 2.5.
All right.
Let's check that.
And here we go.
Okay, you'll see that everything is centered,
and well, of course this text here is way too small.
Let's make it 1.5.
And so here we go.
And now we have to style this button here of course.
So how do we do that?
And for that let's take a look here at the example,
so that I can explain you what's actually going on.
So the trick to this here is to
basically design the button like this,
and then put two elements in there,
one that says, "Book Now," okay,
so the text that we have here,
and then another one that says, "Only 4 rooms left."
And as soon as we hover the button,
well, they both slide down a little bit.
And when we then hover out, of course they move back up.
So that's exactly what happens.
So take a look.
So you saw that.
The "Book Now" moves down, and the
other text also moves down.
So you saw that?
And so that's what we have to do.
So again, we have the button outside,
and the in there we have two elements,
one for each part of the text,
which then move down as we hover.
Okay.
So let's do that.
And I'm going to call the first one Button Visible,
and the second one Button Hidden.
So I'm simply using a span element here.
So Button Visible, saying Book Now,
and then Button Invisible, and that's where
this text here goes.
So let's style that, now.
Actually, let's first change the font size here,
because I saw it was still way too small.
Okay.
And okay.
So now the button.
And so now the visible part and
of course the invisible part.
So let's start with the simple stuff.
So the font size of 1.5rem, of course remove the border.
Also set the font weight to 300, and also to uppercase.
And then give it a nice huge border radius.
Okay, so that it's rounded at the sides.
Next I also want to change the background,
and that should be that gradient that you saw, right?
So it was a gradient from our
light primary color to the dark one.
And so of course then your gradient to the right side,
and I don't know why this is always happening.
So this is how it should be.
So going from the light color to the darker one.
All right.
And finally, the color of the button, of course,
should then be white.
All right.
So let's take a first look at that.
So it's starting to look a bit like our real example.
Now, we're ready to start the visible part,
so first of all, since it's a span,
it's an inline element, but we want it
as an inline block, so in order that we can use
padding in there, okay?
So we want the padding at the top and the right side.
So 2rem top and bottom, and then let's put
a huge length for left and right, like 7.5rem.
Okay?
And that's because it's this padding here
that is going to define the size of the button.
Okay, so let's just take a look at that again.
And okay.
So now this here is our visible part, remember?
So Book Now is the visible,
and the hidden part should be that one.
So let's now take care of that.
And remember that this here should basically be
here on top, so that when we hover the button,
it can move down here to the center, okay?
So we will make this a completely different element
that's out of the button in the initial state.
Okay.
So let's do that.
Make it an inline block as well.
And then we're going to use absolute positioning.
Okay?
So that we can really put it outside of our button.
Okay, so from the left, it should be zero.
And from the top, well, what we have to do
is to set it to minus 100%, and what that's going to do
is it's going to move up exactly the size of the element.
So basically if this element is like 50 pixels high,
it will move up 100% of that.
And so 50 pixels.
Okay?
And we also need to give it a padding.
And it should be the same padding as this one here.
So 2rem and 7.5, and that's actually not really accurate,
but I'm going to leave it at this here
so I can show you what happens
if we do it like this, okay?
Now actually what I should also do here
is to give it a height and a width of 100%
so that it has the height and the width
of the parent element once again.
So height, 100%, and width, 100%.
So let's take a look at that now.
And so probably it should be up there somewhere now.
So let's inspect that.
And actually it's somewhere completely different.
And that's because we didn't specify
a position on the parent.
So I don't know where it really is,
but what I know is that it's gone.
And so in here we should now set position
to relative, of course.
Never forget that.
Okay.
And so right now, this is where the invisible element is,
so exactly where we want it to be.
Now you see that actually the word Left is here,
so it comes out of the button,
and that's because it doesn't have enough space, okay?
So if we remove this part here, like set it to zero,
then it should have enough space to fit all the content.
And so that's what I was saying that padding would work,
but that I would explain to you later
why it wouldn't work.
And actually this is not what I have to change, but here.
All right.
So that's better.
And actually you can see it here.
Well, not really, but imagine that I changed the color,
so let's like put it to red,
and then of course you see that the text is here.
Okay?
And so we should probably hide that part.
Right?
So how can we do that?
Well, actually the best way of doing that
is to set overflow to hidden.
Okay?
Because that element is outside of the button,
and so it's an overflow element,
and if we set overflow to hidden here,
then it will simply disappear.
Okay.
And so now it is gone.
So actually we are ready to already
implement the functionality now.
So when we hover the button, what do we want to happen?
Well, we want something to happen
to the visible of course,
and to the invisible.
So what should happen with the invisible element?
Remember that right now it is at top minus 100%.
So what is the position where
it would be completely visible?
Well, it's just top zero, right?
And so that's all we have to do.
Top zero.
Okay?
Then of course we want to have a transition here.
All in .2 seconds.
So let's take a look at that.
And well, not a lot is happening, actually.
So let's take a look at why that is happening.
So let's use here the dev tools and set it to hover.
And so what's happening here with the invisible?
And actually I don't have any hover state here,
so maybe something went wrong.
But actually everything should be correct.
Let's take a look at the converted CSS,
and you'll see that we already have a lot of CSS written,
and here is the selector that we just wrote,
and actually that's completely incorrect.
Okay, so that's not how we can do it.
So let's simply put it in here,
because that's actually the way it should be done.
So that was just a mistake.
Okay, and then the same thing for invisible.
Let's get rid of that.
And of that.
And so top zero.
And let's try that again.
And so now you'll see that it's moving down
right into the middle of the button,
and as we move out, well, it doesn't go away.
Let's reload this.
And yeah, so now it's working.
As we hover out, it goes away again.
Okay.
And so now all we have to do
is to do something similar with the visible.
But in this case, we're not going to use top,
because we actually didn't use
absolute positioning on it.
So instead, we're going to do transform
and simply translate it down.
So translate Y, so in the Y direction,
and 100% of its height.
And actually we didn't define its height,
so we should probably just do the same as this one here.
And then also put a transition.
And I'm seeing here that we have a lot of repeated code,
so let's simply do it like this.
So select all of the child elements,
and then all of this here is repeated,
such as this one here.
So of course you want the transition to happen on both.
So a little refactoring in order to make our code better.
Okay.
So again, what happens here is that this part,
the visible part, will translate 100% of its height down.
Okay?
And so with this, it should already be working pretty well.
And yeah, it is.
So that is the functionality that
we were looking for, right?
Now the only difference to the original
is that we also changed the gradient
from one side to the other.
So let's do that as well.
So let's just put it here.
So it went to the right, and now we can
simply change it to the left.
All right.
And the final thing is the focus.
So remember to focus on the inline button.
Well, here in this button, we're going to do
the exact same thing.
So outline, none, but instead of having that outline,
we have the animation that we already coded,
and it's called pulsate.
We want it to run for one second,
and basically forever, so infinite.
And with that, we should be ready.
So you saw that the gradient changed,
and it's not transitioning, actually,
and that's because transition doesn't work
for background images, and so it also
doesn't work for gradients.
But that doesn't really matter because
with the other animation that we have going on here,
you don't even really notice that.
Okay?
Okay.
And the other thing is to now click it,
and then you see the pulsating animation,
and so it looks like it's really calling you,
"Please click me," okay?
So that's the purpose of this animation.
And this here of course keeps working,
and let's just add a cursor here.
So that's also missing.
So cursor, and pointer.
Okay.
And so with that, we are actually done.
So let's compare it, and it looks the same,
except that the text here is a bit smaller,
but that doesn't really matter, okay?
So great.
We are ready with this project,
at least for the non-responsive part.
So right now if we tried to decrease this,
so let's go here to the mobile.
Then it's not going to do a really good job
to adapt to mobile screens, for example.
Okay, so as we get smaller,
it starts looking like this.
And so that's what we have to fix
over the next couple of lectures.
Okay?
But for now, this is still great.
So congratulations for finishing this project
and for learning everything you learned
about Flex Box in this section.
And actually not only Flex Box,
because I also showed you a couple of other cool tricks
and techniques here in this section,
but of course the main focus was on Flex Box.
And so I hope you really mastered that by now.
So project is finished.
Over the next couple of lectures,
as I was saying, we will take care of
writing some media queries in order to
make everything super responsive here,
and adapted to mobile and tablets.