The first step in moving on in our project
is to actually convert the CSS code
that we've been writing so far to a SASS code.
And so we're gonna set up a couple of variables
and we're also gonna nest selectors where that makes sense.
And so here we are back in our SASS code.
And actually we already have a lot
of variables here going on so mainly with the colors.
But let's see if we can find some more.
So I think for the colors we already
have variables for everything, right.
I don't really see another color going on here.
Oh, actually here it's black.
So why not also having a variable for black?
So color of black.
Again, later down the road we may decide
that the black that we want is not really complete black
but maybe only some really dark gray.
And then we would have to change all of that manually.
And so it's better to always have a variable
so that we can change it very easily and very quickly.
And so now I can replace it here, color black,
and of course the same thing here.
Now again, doing so with the RGBA,
identifying a hexadecimal color in
here only works with SASS.
So in regular CSS we really have to define
the colors here separately for R, G, and B,
with a number ranging between zero and 255
such as we had before.
But now in SASS we can put the hexadecimal,
a number here like we have with the black color,
and then the RGBA function is still going to work.
Alright, and there are no more color variables here.
Now some people like to go really crazy here
and also specify variables for all of this stuff
like family, weight, line height, and all of that,
but I think that's not really necessary because in fact
we're only ever specifying this code once here.
So we're not having this Lato font-family
all over the place it's really just here.
And so in fact we're only defining it in one place
and so there's no need to have a variable, alright.
Now remember that we're still having here in the background
this terminal running where we're still detecting
all the time if we're doing some changes to our SASS code.
And then each time we change anything
it actually reloads the page, right.
And so all of the changes that we did already
should be reflected in here.
And so during the development of this entire project
I will just keep this running in the background
and we don't have to worry about this anymore.
So this is our development setup.
And now that we have a variable setup at least for now
let's take a look at nesting our selectors.
So remember that we're using the BM methodology
so a block element modifier and so we're using
all of these really low specificity selectors.
So we have header, header logo box, header text box
and so on and so forth.
And so when we select its elements we always do
this just with a class selector.
And so all of our selectors they're really
just only one class selector with one class.
So they all have the same specificity,
which is extremely low.
Also, since each and every element actually has a class,
nesting can be a bit difficult here, right.
It looks like there's not much to nest here, right?
It's different from the example that we had
when we first looked at SASS where we did simply nest
all the elements like we had.
Remember, UL, and then in there we had the LI,
and then in there we had the A.
So right now we don't have that kind of structure
because every element has its own class.
But still we can do nesting here.
And I'm gonna show you how.
And this is how we do it.
So remember what ampersand operator does,
it basically, it copies this selector here
that we have up until this point, right.
So actually all of this.
So it's not header, so if we now want to specify this
decoration block here we can actually write it this way.
Logo-box and that's it.
So we copy the coding here and here we go.
So this is now nested inside each other
and the code when compiled will be exactly the same.
Because again, this header here is like it's copied here.
So I imagine that if we copy it
and then we place it here,
and so it looks exactly the way we had before.
Right?
And so instead of having to write header all the time
in each single element that we want to select,
we can just use nesting like this.
So, let's put these all together here,
all of these which have to do with the header.
So it's all of these and then we can just replace
the header with the ampersand operator.
Now here in Visual Studio Code,
when I select something and then hit CMND + D
it will automatically select the
next instance which is the same.
So you see here I have header selected
and you see that already down here
it's becoming with a different color
and now if I hit CMND + D then it also gets selected.
And you see these two cursors here blinking.
So we have multiple cursors now
and if I now write the ampersand it
will replace both of them.
Alright, so again, this is not really a CSS feature
but it's a feature of this text editor.
And I know that Adam does this as well
and probably also brackets.
And I know that sublime text also does it.
And so you can try to figure out how
your text editor does this trick.
It's really handy sometimes to replace
multiple instances of the same text all at the same time.
Alright, and so that's it.
So, I really like this approach with nesting
the selectors like this because you see is like
really all encapsulated all in this big, one header block.
Okay?
So when scanning down our code we can see okay,
this I the header then inside we have these declarations
for the header and then from there we move down
to this element logo box logo and text box.
Okay?
So let's save this and let's actually take a look at the
styles CSS and so here you see that actually
what I explained to you is exactly what is working.
So you have to the header declaration block,
which starts here, ends here.
Then we have the header logo box, the header logo.
So exactly what we had before doing this nesting.
Right?
So we change this into SASS
but it looks exactly the same in the output.
So this is what we wanted.
Now, the next thing here with the heading primary,
so they can do the same here, right.
So let's actually do it.
All we have to do is to basically not that much code.
Whoa, this is really fast.
So cut this one and put it in here.
It goes to this heading Primary Main,
so the system modifier here right.
And so now here such as we have before,
I can replace it with the ampersand.
And that's actually it.
So it will be heading primary--main, and here --sub.
Alright, make sense?
So again it's just nicely encapsulated block,
which now contains all of the code for
the heading primary all at the same time.
And we can now do the same thing here
with the button of course.
So we have button link, visited, hover, active,
so these for sudo classes and then here there's modifier,
and then this sudo element.
And we can wrap them all into one huge block.
Okay?
So how do we do that?
And actually I want you to do it.
So it's a small challenge here so pause the video
and try to nest all of this code into one huge block.
Maybe it's not exactly easy at this point
but it's a nice challenge and so I hope
that you can manage to do it.
Hopefully you manage to do that
so let's go take a look at how I would do it.
So actually let's start by just writing button here
and then start by copying all of that in there.
Okay, and so now we can just remove this here
and let's again replace this with the ampersand operator.
Now we'll start hitting CMND + D to select
all of these button instances, okay.
So button, button, and there's more.
Button, button, okay, that's it.
And so now replace all of these with the ampersand.
Okay, so we have now button linked, button visited,
button hover, button active, button wide,
and button after, and button wide after,
and button hover after, and button animate it.
Okay, but this is still not perfect, right.
Because we can do more.
We can also replace this part here
because it's already here.
Make sense?
So we can just do it like this.
Copy this entire thing in here
and take this out.
Okay, make sense?
So let's try to read that.
So here we have this will translate to
button--wide and then here it
will translate to button--wide,
and then the after sudo class.
Okay?
Does it make sense?
Now we can do the same thing in here.
So let's go to the hover part, which is up there.
And put it here.
Alright, so again this was repeated this part.
Right?
So let me put it back very shortly.
So this was already here, so why write it again?
We can just take it out and replace it
with the ampersand operator here.
And so this gonna translate to button hover after.
And I think that now we're good.
Now everything is nicely nested
and I think it makes a lot more sense like this.
It's easier to read and it's all
encapsulated in the small block that we have.
Now I know that it may take some time to get used to,
to this nesting and to make sense out of it
but you'll see that with practice
and maybe with all the practice that you're gonna take
while we're building this project,
after that it will make sense to you
and you will be so used to it that it's no problem anymore.
Just one last final check,
see if everything is still working and yes it is.
So our button works exactly the same as before.
So all the logic was preserved even
after we changed all of this code here.
Okay?
So that was my goal for this lecture,
so we're now ready to move on.