Two fundamental aspects
of modern responsive design are, without a doubt,
deciding about doing mobile-first or desktop-first
for their website or app, as well as selecting breakpoints
for our project, when writing media queries.
So, in this lecture, that's what we're gonna talk about.
So, let's start right into it.
In the desktop-first approach, we optimize our interfaces
for the large screens.
And therefore, we start by writing CSS code
for these large screens, into our CSS file.
This is what we have been doing all this time
in the Nader's Project. Right?
Now later, when we make the website responsive,
we simply write media queries,
in order to shrink the design to fit the smaller screens.
This is the more traditional way of doing things,
and also the easier way to learn, in my opinion.
The way we do this, is by writing media queries
that test for max-width.
And, if that's confusing to you, no problem.
I'm gonna explain that in the next slide.
But, for now, let's see how the mobile-first
strategy is different.
In mobile-first, we start writing CSS code
for smaller screens, in order to optimize for mobile.
And then, move up to larger screens from there
using media queries.
And, in this case, we do this by writing media queries
that test for min-width.
So, it's basically just the opposite work flow.
Now, even bigger than the technical aspects of mobile-first,
is the philosophy that's behind the strategy.
Which, is that we, the designers really have to think
about the mobile experience, by reducing our websites
or apps to the absolute essentials.
Stripping away everything that's not really necessary,
in order to end up with a smaller and faster final product.
We're gonna discuss this a bit more in a second,
but for now, let's move on to the more technical
and more exciting aspects of responsive design.
So, since we were talking about desktop
and mobile-first strategies, this is an excellent time
to talk about the difference between the type
of media queries that we have to write for each approach:
max-width for desktop-first and min-width for mobile-first.
Maybe you've always been using max-width media queries,
but without really understanding how they work.
And, so that's what I want to clear up right now.
So, as an example, we have here a pixel spectrum
going from zero to infinity, with a couple
of breakpoints in them: 600, 900 and 1200 pixels.
Let's start with desktop-first.
And, remember that we start by writing CSS
for larger screens, and so, our initial code
is on the right side of this spectrum. Right?
Now, in order to adapt our design to smaller screens,
we write max-width media queries, like this one.
So, max-width 600 pixels.
So, what this media query does, is that it basically checks
if the current viewport width is smaller
or equal to 600 pixels.
And, if it is, than all the CSS code
that is in this media query will apply.
And, if not, that specific code will just not apply.
So, what this means, is that the max-width is 600
because that is the maximum width at which
the media query still works; it still applies.
And, after that, it stops working.
Now, in these media queries, what we do
is just override some specific parts of the global CSS code.
Only the parts that we want to change,
because all the rest of the global code
will, of course, still apply.
So, think of media queries as tools,
to overriding specific parts of our CSS
for specific viewport width.
All right, and so the same, of course, works
for the next breakpoint and the next media query,
which is max-width 900 pixels in this case.
So, all of the code that is in this query will work,
as long as the width is less or equal to 900.
In other words, as long as the maximum width is 900 pixels.
But, maybe now you're wondering, what if a phone
has a width of 500 pixels?
Which media query will apply now?
That's an excellent question,
and the answer is pretty simple, actually.
Both queries will apply,
because both conditions are true. Right?
500 is less than 600, but also less than 900 pixels.
And, so the code in both media queries will be applied.
Now, if you have conflicting CSS rules in these queries,
which is usually the case, like defining
the global font size in both media queries,
than the one which appears less in the code
is the one that takes precedence.
Just like you learned in the lecture about the cascade.
Remember that one?
That's because media queries don't add any importance
or specificity to our selectors.
And so, the order of the code matters a lot.
And, that's why we keep our media queries always at the end.
But don't worry, if this sounds overwhelming right now,
because we're gonna apply all of this
over the next couple of lectures.
And, just to complete the example with the last breakpoint,
here is how the media query looks like
for a 1200 pixels.
So, at 1200 pixels is the width at which
we start doing some changes in our media queries.
Above 1200 pixels, we have the desktop version
of our project, outside of any media queries.
Okay, and with this we have the full picture
of this example project, with the desktop-first approach.
So, let's now look at the mobile-first approach,
where our initial CSS code is obviously on the left-side
of the pixel spectrum, where the mobile phone screens are.
So, where before we had max-width media queries,
we now have min-width queries.
Like this min-width 600 pixels,
which basically asks the question,
is the current viewport width larger
or equal to 600 pixels?
If so, than the code applies.
So, it's called min-width query, because 600 pixels
is the minimum width at which the media query
starts to apply.
Now, visually speaking, this translates to a pixel range
starting from 600 pixels covering all the way
until infinity, basically.
So, all screens with the width larger than 600 pixels
will have the code in this media query applied to the page.
Make sense?
Now, we have to use this type of media query
in the mobile-first approach, because basically
we want the queries to stay away
from our smallest screen styles.
So, we want them to work for bigger screens,
and so the max-width approach we had before wouldn't work.
You can see that very nicely, with the arrows in the diagram
and the pixel range that each query covers. Okay?
So, again, in mobile-first with our media queries
we want to stay away from the small screen sizes.
And so, that's why we have to use
min-width media query types.
And so now, for the remaining two breakpoints
the logic is pretty much the same
as for the desktop-first strategy.
So, for the 900 pixel breakpoint,
we have a min-width 900 pixel media query
which is activated if the viewport width
is larger or equal to 900 pixels, of course.
And, the same for 1200 pixels.
So, it's just the same logic as before.
All right? Did you get that?
Now that we know everything about mobile-first
and desktop-first, let's try to decide
what's actually best for you,
depending on your unique situation and project
by looking at the pros and cons of mobile-first design.
So, we already saw that the whole strategy
behind mobile-first, is to narrow down our interfaces,
being it websites or apps, to the bare minimum.
In order to create a small, fast and efficient product
completely optimized for mobile users.
And, this actually makes a ton of sense
in a world that's becoming more and more mobile
with a huge part of the internet traffic
already coming from mobile.
Another big advantage of mobile-first,
is that having all these design constraints
on smaller screens, we automatically prioritize content
over purely aesthetic design.
Which also makes sense, because I'm sure that you've heard
the sentence "content is king." Right?
However, the problem with this strategy
is that we end up with a opposite problem.
Where the large desktop version
might feel overly empty and simplistic.
I mean, why having an advanced system
like a huge desktop computer, if websites don't even use
the device's resources and capabilities? Right?
Also, if you're like me and more used to see a whole lot
of desktop websites, than it may seem a bit weird,
even counter-intuitive and also difficult
to develop mobile-first.
That's simply because a larger canvas,
where we can start designing without so many restrictions,
will give you much more creative freedom.
Which is great, to set your websites apart
from the competition.
Plus, if you're developing websites for clients,
they usually like to see a desktop version
of the site as a prototype,
and not just a super stripped-down mobile version.
So, that's also something you have to consider.
And, finally, users of a particular website
in a certain business niche, might not even use
the mobile internet that much
and prefer to use a normal computer to check out websites.
We always need to consider the purposes of a website
and align it with their users' needs.
So, this is another question you have to ask yourself,
when deciding which strategy to choose.
All right, so this might look
like there are more cons than pros to mobile-first.
But, it's not that simple, of course.
I've seen a lot of designers online saying
that they actually don't build mobile-first at all.
But, of course, there are also people building like this.
Each project is a project, and in each case in the end
it's you who has to decide what's best.
There's just one important piece of advise
that I have to give you, and that I follow myself.
Which, is that no matter what you decide,
always keep both the desktop and mobile versions in mind
and understand that they are both important.
You should never design only for one of the solutions
and just leave the other one as an afterthought.
All right? Does that make sense?
Now, about the Nader's Project that we've been working on.
You have probably already noticed that we're using
a desktop-first approach, simply because
I would find it extremely difficult to teach you
all the concepts that I've taught you so far
on a small screen, with all the restrictions
that we've been talking about.
It just wouldn't be practical, at all.
And so, the media queries we're gonna write next
are all of the type max-width.
But, that's not a problem at all, because in the last slide,
and in this lecture in particular,
I've given you everything you need to know
to start building mobile-first websites for yourself,
if you think that that's the best strategy for you.
It's really not such a big difference
and I do highly encourage you to try it out for yourself.
Again, I did it this way in this course
because it's just easier to teach,
and also to learn, in my opinion.
But, on your next, real-life project
you should totally try it out, if it makes sense for you.
All right, moving on.
We need to also talk about breakpoints.
Remember that breakpoints are the viewport width
at which we want our design to change.
Or, in other words, where we want to put our media queries.
No matter what we decide, about going mobile-first
or desktop first, one thing that is for sure
is that we have to select breakpoints for our design.
And, for me, there are three major ways of doing so:
the bad, the good and the perfect way.
Unfortunately, the bad way is also the most used way
of choosing breakpoints.
And, it consists of simply using the width
of popular devices as the breakpoints.
And, designers really like to use Apple products,
like the iPhone and the iPad, to set breakpoints
for their screen width.
And while this is the easiest way,
it has a couple of problems.
First, you're optimizing for one very specific device,
ignoring all the users of other devices,
which may be even more used than the Apple products.
And, second and even more important I think,
is that this strategy is not future proof at all.
If tomorrow Apple decides to completely change resolutions
on all their devices, do you want to go ahead
and change all your media queries
on all the projects that you've ever built?
I don't think so, right?
We've been talking a lot about
reusable and maintainable code.
In using specific devices as breakpoints,
is completely against all that logic.
Now, of course it's okay to use the strategy
if you're just starting out with responsive design
and just want to learn how it works.
But, if you want to get more serious, it's time to move on
to a better way, which I like to call the good way.
In the good way, we look at all the most-used device width
on the entire internet, try to group them together
in a logical way and then pick our breakpoints from that.
And while it's still not ideal, to use real devices
to figure out breakpoint, it's already a lot better
than the first way.
Because we're using a lot of devices, and we're also using
the most popular device width.
Plus, we're not setting breakpoints at one specific point
but between similar device width.
All right, and now the perfect way to do this
is to ignore devices all together
and only look at your content and your design.
So, ideally, it works like this.
You begin at one size, either mobile or desktop
and then start increasing your screen width
or decreasing for desktop first.
Then, as soon as the design breaks,
which means that the design no longer works,
it no longer looks okay, then you insert a new breakpoint.
And, that's it.
So, again, you just put the breakpoints
wherever your design starts to look weird and out of place,
and don't think about devices, at all.
Now, the thing, is that this approach
can be extremely difficult.
And, that's why not many people are doing it.
Without the constraints of at least a couple
of pre-defined breakpoints, it's hard to find the best ones
and not to end up with really a bunch of them.
And, that's why we're gonna use the second method
I showed you, which I called the good way.
But, you should totally try this perfect way in the future.
Okay? You really should.
It's a great exercise, to design without the constraints
of having pre-defined breakpoints.
Now, with the second approach that I showed you,
we start with the most-used screen size
that we can get from an app called StatCounter.
So, this data is freely available on the internet.
This one is for the range between August 2016
and August 2017.
But, if you're watching this video in 2018, 2019
or even 2020, these stats will probably not
have changed that much.
And, even if they did, you can just use the strategy
with the new screen sizes
and select your breakpoints from there.
Anyway, in this diagram, I just plotted
these most-used screen sizes, that you can see
in the chart down there.
So, from this, you can already see pretty good
how we could group these screen sizes. Right?
So, usually, we'll need one breakpoint for phones,
one for portrait tablets, one for landscape tablets
and one for the desktop.
There can be more, or course, but these are the basics.
So, where do you think these breakpoints should be,
based on this diagram?
And, here is how I would position them.
So, the phone ranging from 0-600 pixels,
from 600-900 the portrait tablets, from 900-1200
the landscape tablet, and from there it's the desktop.
I actually even included a breakpoint for big desktops
starting at 1800 pixels.
But, that one is not really mandatory,
it's just if we want to give users
with these huge screens something special.
Now, this could be different, of course,
it's actually a bit subjective.
But, as long as it makes sense, and it does I think,
than it's great.
Now, just to give you some perspective,
these are the iPhone 8, iPad portrait and landscape
and MacBook Pro 15 inch.
And, yeah, it is totally okay, to call this iPhone,
or iPad or MacBook.
And, in fact, we can and should use these devices
to test our responsive designs.
What we should not do though,
is to just use their width as breakpoints.
But, we already talked about that.
Alright. And that's it for this lecture.
I hope it made a lot of things clearer to you.
And now, all we have to do is to actually implement
these media queries.
So, don't wait and come with me,
straight to the next lecture.
See you there.