Welcome back.
Now before jumping right into Sass Code,
let's first take a look at what Sass actually is.
So this lecture is designed to give you
a very quick overview of what Sass is,
how it works, and what features it includes.
So, putting it in very simple terms,
Sass is a CSS preprocessor, an extension of CSS
that adds a lot of power and elegance
to the basic language.
So basically, we use Sass to fix the problems
that we have with CSS.
CSS gets very messy, very quickly.
For each project, having a single CSS file
with thousands of lines of code
without any reusable pieces, without any logic,
gets completely unmanageable after some time.
And that's why we use Sass which provide us
with a couple of handy features and tools
that CSS simply doesn't have, while at the same time,
not changing the fundamental way that CSS works.
This in particular, makes Sass very easy to learn,
and so I'm sure that you'll be
up to speed with Sass in no time.
The way Sass works is like this.
Instead of writing a CSS file with regular CSS code,
we write Sass code in Sass files.
Then, we run a compiler,
and that compiler converts the Sass code we wrote
into regular CSS code as if all we ever did was write
in regular CSS in the first place.
So, we need to process our Sass code first,
and that's why it's called a CSS preprocessor.
Our website has no idea that the code we wrote
in the beginning was in Sass
because it only ever sees the final output
of the compiler in the form of CSS of course.
Okay?
Does it make sense?
Now there are actually other CSS preprocessors
like Less or Stylus, but Sass is the most popular one
which is why I chose it for this course.
So what are these features that Sass actually gives us?
Let's get a quick overview
before we actually start writing Sass,
so we that we know what we're looking at here.
First, Sass gives us variables which,
just like in normal programming languages,
allow us to have reusable values such as colors,
font sizes, spacing, etc.
Next, we have nesting, in order to nest selectors
inside of one another, allowing us to write less code.
Next up, there are operators
for mathematical operations right inside of CSS.
Then, partials and imports which are one
of the most important and most useful features of Sass,
allowing us to write CSS in different files,
and then importing them all into one single file.
Next, there are mixins,
to write reusable pieces of CSS code.
And also functions, which are quite similar to mixins
with the difference that they produce a value
that can be used later.
Next up, we have extends, which can be used
to make different selectors inherit declarations
that are common to all of them.
And finally, control directives allow developers
to write complex code using conditionals and loops
like in real programming language.
However, we do not cover this topic in this course
because it's nearly not needed in a real world project.
It's more for writing CSS frameworks or something.
So, this was just a very high level overview of Sass.
In the next two lectures,
we're actually gonna start using this,
and everything will make a ton of sense to you.
Now, one other thing before we start writing Sass.
Maybe you have been googling Sass before
and looked at some Sass code, and seen different ways
that the code looks, and that's right.
There are actually two Sass syntaxes
which can be quite confusing,
so we'll have to clear that up.
One syntax, which is actually the original one,
is just called Sass like the language.
The other one is called SCSS which stands for Sassy CSS.
The Sass syntax is indentation sensitive
and doesn't use any curly braces and semicolons
as you see here on the left side.
However, I find this syntax a bit confusing,
and I find it also more difficult to learn,
and also more difficult to convert original CSS projects
to Sass with the syntax.
That's why I prefer the SCSS syntax
which preserves the way that original CSS looks like.
That's why SCSS is what we're gonna use
in the rest of this course.
Now, if for some reason you prefer the Sass syntax,
please feel absolutely free to use that one
because everything should still work the exact same way,
will just look different.
All right, and that's it for the basic Sass intro.
In the next lecture, we're finally gonna dive
right into it, so don't wait,
and hit play on that next video.