Let's start the CSS grid part of the course
by taking a look at what CSS grids actually are,
how they work, and why we need them.
So, what are the CSS grids that everyone
talks about so much these days?
Well, the CSS Grid Layout is a brand new module
that brings a two-dimensional grid system
to CSS for the very first time, and there really
has never been anything like this before in CSS,
so this is a real game-changer,
because it changes everything:
how we think about layout, how we write our CSS,
and even how we write our markup in HTML.
All of that is much easier, and more logical too,
with CSS grids, and so we can now finally design
much more complex layouts, because we now have the tools
to actually build them in our code with CSS Grid,
and that actually also holds true for Flexbox,
which works very well together with CSS grids,
where Flexbox can handle the one-dimensional layouts,
and Grids, the two-dimensional layout parts.
Together, these two new technologies solve all the
layout problems that we could never really solve before,
at least not in a clean and straightforward way.
So, by having native grids now right in our browser,
we can even throw CSS frameworks, like Bootstrap,
out the window, because CSS is now the framework itself.
We don't need to be bound by a simple
and boring 12 column layout anymore,
like Bootstrap and all these other frameworks.
We're free to do whatever we want,
because it's now so simple to implement
without any weird hacks in our CSS, or even HTML code.
So, building a simple two-dimensional layout,
like this one, which we're actually gonna build
in our grid project, by the way, becomes really,
really simple and straightforward with CSS grids.
It all just works a bit different
than the way we've been doing it for so long now
with float layouts and other hacks,
and that's why I say that CSS Grid requires
a whole new mindset, a whole new way
of thinking about design, HTML, and CSS.
These are really exciting times to be a CSS Developer,
and I can't wait to show you how grids actually work,
but before we can jump into code, we need to talk a bit
about the terminology around CSS grids,
and this is a bit similar to the Flexbox terminology,
but actually a lot more complex at the same time.
So, just like we have a flex container in Flexbox,
in CSS grids, we have a grid container,
and we create a new grid container
by setting the display property of an element to grid.
Simple as that.
Then, all the direct children
of the Grid container are the grid items.
We also have axes like in Flexbox, but the difference
that these are called the row axis in the x direction,
and the column axis in the y direction,
and these axes are always the same.
You cannot change where they are like we do with Flexbox,
which makes it a bit simpler actually.
So, row axis and column axis, but there's
actually a lot more we need to know.
So, first the vertical and horizontal lines
that divide up the grid, and separate the columns
and the rows, are called the grid lines,
and they are automatically numbered for the columns
as well as for the rows, starting from one,
all the way to the number of rows plus one,
and the number of columns plus one of course.
Now, the actual space that is between the rows
and columns is called the gutter,
and the row gutter can be different from the column gutter,
so what are the grid rows and columns actually?
Well, the space between two grid lines is called a track,
no matter if it's vertical or horizontal.
If it's horizontal, then it's called a row of course,
and if it's vertical, then it's called a column.
Simple as that. But it gets better, because there is more.
So, the area between two vertical
and two horizontal grid lines is called a grid area,
and if that area is between two adjacent grid lines
and two adjacent column lines,
then that area is just called a grid cell.
Okay, so I know that this is a lot to take in,
so don't worry all too much about it
at this point, because with time,
this will all come naturally to you,
especially the grid lines, gutters,
tracks, rows, and columns, because we actually use
these terms all the time when we start working with grids.
And now just to finish this lecture, this is just
a quick overview of all the CSS Grid related properties
for both the grid container and the grid items.
Now, I will not go into explaining
all of these properties at this point,
because we're going to use them throughout the rest
of the grid part of this course,
and so you will certainly get familiar with all of them.
So, again, this is more intended like a reference,
that maybe you can even print out like I actually did,
because believe me, this comes in very handy
when we first start using grids.
So, whenever you need to get a quick overview
of all these grid properties, here they are.
Alright! So, that's a quick intro to what CSS grids are.
Now let's move on to setting up our tools,
and finally start coding with CSS grids.