With our interface finally completed,
it's now time to write some media queries
to optimize it for smaller screens.
Now, we have learned about
how to do this before in this course,
so it's not really something new at this point.
However, what is new is how easy flex box makes the process
of making our layout completely responsive
with just a small amount of code.
In this lecture, and the next one,
that's what we're gonna do so that I can actually show you
how easy it is and not just tell you.
Now, about the breakpoints,
this time we're gonna use a different strategy.
We're gonna use that strategy
where we basically set the breakpoints
to where the design starts to break, okay?
So that's what I called, back then,
the perfect way of doing stuff.
Now, we're still gonna keep the old breakpoints
that we used in the other project in mind as well,
but only if there is actually something
that breaks at these width.
Okay, so, let's now start taking a look,
and set this here to mobile right?
That we have our responsive layout in this nice view here.
Now, this is what I wanted to reduce, all right!
Let's start decreasing this.
You see we are at 1500 pixels approximately now.
Okay, so now we're at about 1200, okay?
And that's the max-width
that we define for our container here.
Remember that?
So the container here has 120 REMs,
so 1200 pixels basically.
So if it starts decreasing furthermore,
then of course the width becomes 100%
of the available view port width,
because that's exactly what max-width here does, okay?
Now, we want to change something here
which is actually removing this part here from the top,
because that starts to look a bit weird.
So what I'm trying to say is that our first breakpoint
should be at 1200 pixels.
So, as soon as we approach this here,
then we move the container all the way up here to the top,
and so we don't have this pink background color anymore.
Neither at the sides, and nor at the top.
So that is going to be our first breakpoint.
Now about the media queries themselves,
in the last project,
we actually wrote that huge media-query manager,
but right now I wanna keep it simple here, okay?
So, all we're gonna do is just write out
the media queries in the old way.
So, let's go here to our layout,
and to our container,
and so all we have to do
is to now add the media query in here.
So media, only screen,
and then our condition.
Now keep in mind that now, once again,
we are using a desktop-first strategy, right?
So our media queries here will be off to type max-width.
So just like in the other project we did before.
So max-width, and 1200 pixels.
Now two things about that,
first we should have this width here in Ms",
because of the reasons that I explained to you
in the last project,
and second, I actually want this to be variables,
so that I don't have to write out
this number here all the time,
each time that I am going to use it.
So, let's do that in the base CSS.
Now probably, you think that we will do it
as a CSS custom property right?
But the thing is that that doesn't work okay?
So, we cannot declare one of these variables here,
and then use it in a media query here in this place.
That simply doesn't work.
CSS doesn't allow it to work.
So we have to do it with SaaS variables, okay?
So that's absolutely no problem at all.
We can mix CSS custom properties,
and use them for some use cases,
and then use SaaS variables for other stuff.
So, no problem at all.
So, remember this is how we determine SaaS variables.
I'm gonna call it bp for breakpoint.
And then this one is the largest,
and it's 75em, and let me show that to you.
So 1200 divided by 16 is 75,
so 75em, not rem, but em is what I want.
So 1200 pixels just so that we can remember it later
when we use it.
That's he largest breakpoint.
Now, we can actually use this, so let's copy it.
All right, that is our media query for the container.
And what do we actually want to change here?
Well, it's very simple,
all we wanna do is to set the margin to zero, right?
So, before we had 8rem, top and bottom,
and auto on the left and the right side
to center the container inside its parent element.
But right now we don't need that anymore,
because it's already filling the entire view port anyway.
So just margin zero should fix that.
Actually, here it's already working.
So we approach 1200 here, and then, bam,
all the margin disappear.
And up here you also can already see our media query, right?
All right, nothing that's all we have to change,
actually, for this width, so let's now continue
to move down a little bit.
And it starts looking a bit weird down here already,
but let's keeping going just a bit.
And now you see that down here
it's also now moving to a new line,
and so that's not really ideal,
and so what I wanna do is to keep here at 1100,
and change the global font size,
and that will them decrease all the length,
which are measured in rem right?
So, once more that's exactly what we did
with the Nater's Project.
Decreasing the font size, which are sized in rem,
which in turn depends on the global font size.
So, this is our next breakpoint.
So large, and 1100 divided by 16 is 68.75.
All right so, 1100 pixels,
and actually that one is here in the base-file,
so that's just included here.
Select media only for screens and max-width
of bp-large.
All right, so right now our font size is 62.5%,
which makes it so that one rem is 10 pixels.
Now, let's decrease that to eight pixels.
Okay, so eight divided by 16 is, of course, 50%.
So, font size 50%.
And that's actually it, so let's test it out.
And, yeah, that looks better,
but actually we have another problem here now,
which is that the space here is back,
and that's because the 120 rem that we defined for the width
of the container are now no longer 1200 pixels,
But instead, they are, let's calculate that,
so, 120 rem which are now only eight pixels,
and so that's now only 960 pixels, no longer 1200 pixels.
So let's just very quickly fix that,
and saying here, in the layout,
for a container that right now the max-width
should be 100%, and we can also say that
width should be 100% just to be 100% sure.
Now that should be fixed.
Yeah.
So we hit 1110, bam, here we go.
Now we still see some space down here,
let me see where that came from.
So where is that container?
And actually there shouldn't be any space,
but yeah of course if we increase the page here like this,
then it has to show us something right?
So the container it ends here, and it has no margin,
but we still have a part of the page
if our screen is this big,
and to then it will of course show that the background
gray-end that we defined for the body.
So, if we reduce the view port, then it will no longer show,
but if we increase it,
and let me show that to you even more.
Well, actually I cannot.
But, for example, if the view port was like this,
then even more of this pink color here would be created.
But that's not a problem at all,
so let's not worry about that, okay?
The only thing that's not perfect here
is this situation right now,
but let's fix that in another way.
Let me inspect this element here,
and what I'm simply gonna do is to decrease
this margin area a bit more.
So 0.8, 0.9.
So let's put it at-2rem,
and so then that should no longer occur in no width at all.
So, let's come here to our components.
Overview, button, and list.
And so here we are in the recommend.
So let's put this one here at -2rem,
so instead of having to write another media query here.
Okay, so that's fixed now.
Let's keep moving down with our width,
and for now everything still keeps looking great right?
And now we have that problem here again with the images.
So, let's actually add a new media query here at 900.
Because at this point, everything start to look a bit
too narrow here.
Like the side nav is already becoming very narrow,
and so is this column here,
and especially the review column okay?
So we're getting less and less space here,
and that becomes even more dramatic
as we decrease it further down.
So, here at 900 let's make another breakpoint,
and what we're gonna do is to basically put
this navigation here which is now a sidebar,
all the way here on the top.
So spanning from the left to the right.
With all of these four navigation items side-by-side.
So that then, this part down here so the hotel view,
which is all of this here can occupy it
100% of the view port width.
And that will buy us some more space.
So, that shouldn't be all too hard to do.
So, let's just check out which element we're talking about,
and that is the content here, right?
So the content is the element
that has both of these things that we were talking about.
So the sidebar and the hotel view right?
So the content is already set to flex
so it's a flex box container,
because remember we positioned these two elements here
side-by-side using flex box,
and so now all we have to do,
if you wanna put one on top of the other
is to change the flex direction right?
Because right now it's a row,
and so all we have to do is to change it to a column,
so let's do that.
And first let's create another breakpoint here,
or another variable for breakpoint.
So after large comes medium,
and 900 pixels divided by 16 is 65.25.
56 I believe it was.
Just to be sure, so 56.25em
equals 900 pixels.
Okay, so let's come here to our layout again.
Let me actually copy this one
so I don't have to write it out all the time.
And so remember, the one we want to manipulate here
is the content.
So at the medium breakpoint, what we want to change
is the flex direction to column,
and that will put our navigation on top,
and the hotel overview beneath it.
So let's test that as we hit 900 pixels,
and here we go.
So, great.
We have the sidebar here stretching all the way
to the right side, and then down there
the hotel view occupying 100% of the available width.
So, that's great.
Now we're back to having more space down here, all right?
So, next up, let's put these items here side-by-side,
because it doesn't make much sense to be like this right?
And also, I'm gonna get rid of this text here actually,
because we wanna have the navigation,
then right after that we want to start the hotel overview,
and not see any of this text over there okay?
So, let's go to the navigation,
and I think that's a component right here at the beginning.
Yeah, here it is. The side-nav.
So, remember that we want to put the items
all beside each other right?
So all we have to do is to set its parent to a flex, right?
So making off the items, flex items,
which will then automatically be side-by-side.
Now of course we have to do this in a media query.
So let me copy that, and of course this code here
should be in the media query,
and not just out there.
All right, so let's take a look at that.
And all right!
So it's starting to look pretty good already
they are now nicely side-by-side.
Let's just get rid of this margin here.
So margin zero
so that margin-top that we had here,
we don't want that anymore.
And then as I was saying,
let's get rid of the legal text also.
And what I want to copy is actually this media query.
So display: none.
All right, so the legal text will be gone now,
and just to check it,
Okay, so that looks good already.
Now, what we should do here, of course,
is to make of them occupy it 1/4 of the entire width here.
Basically, what we want them to do
is to occupy this entire width.
Let's do that.
Of course, that's not really hard at all.
How are we going to do that?
Well, it's very simple.
We set flex to one, okay?
We give all these four flex items the ability
to grow as much as they can,
and since they all have the same flex value, which is one,
they will all occupy it the same space.
Now, just here, let's remove that margin from the bottom.
Now, we should be pretty much done with it.
Let's actually zoom a bit in here.
75%, and that looks pretty good to me.
Now, maybe we should also center
this content here inside of the box.
Let's do that as well.
It's in the link, right?
Let's put that media query in here.
What do we have to do in order
to horizontally align these items?
Well, all we have do is justify content, center,
as we've been doing so many times.
Now, let's just actually increase the padding as well.
Let's say 2rem, and here we go.
That looks perfect, right?
Now, just some smaller fixes that we should do here as well
is maybe decrease all of this padding that we have here.
All of this excessive white space
that we really don't have space for at this view port width.
Let's get rid of all that.
For that, let's remember that this element here
is the detail.
Here we should definitely decrease the padding
and to say then here for the description
and probably the reviews as well.
Let's do that.
Just copy this media query,
and so let's do that.
Legal: we already changed that.
The overview, and actually this is in the layout, right?
It's actually here in the detail.
We want the padding of 3rem now,
no longer 4.5, okay?
Next, let's check the description.
Here we can actually leave a padding of 2rem, I would say,
it was three, so let's decrease it to two.
Now, the margin-right also needs to change
because remember that this margin-right of 4.5
was the exact same value as the padding here on the detail.
We should probably decrease that one to three as well,
so 3rem.
Now, where is the review?
List, recommend, ah, here we go.
The review, I'm also gonna decrease the padding in here.
Now, the media query is gone, so let's copy it again.
Padding: 2rem, and that's actually okay like that.
Since we're here,
let's also decrease the margin at the bottom to 3rem.
Let's just check if we have something else to change.
I think this section here can also need some less space.
Let's say, 2.5rem and zero down from 3.5.
Let's check that.
Yeah, that looks a bit more natural, I believe.
So without all of this space that we had before.
The same here in the cta section as well.
If you now decrease this here,
we should be good to go for a long time,
for a long range of width.
It still looks good
except this here
and maybe we should find another fix for this here as well.
Let me actually go here to the components
and to the recommend,
so these photos here are this ones.
If you want them to stay always side-by-side,
we can actually achieve that with flex box.
Let's set the container to display flex.
Then these elements, so these flex items,
they will just stay side-by-side all the time.
Yeah, just like this.
That's a very easy fix for that problem.
All right, so we're still good here I believe.
There's no major problems at any point,
so I think that the next breakpoint
could be, for example, here, 600 pixels.
Such as we had in our other project,
so 600, I think, is a pretty good breakpoint.
In this project, it's a good point
to make some more changes in here, in this interface.
I'm actually leaving for the next video.
If you want to do that right now,
then just come with me right to that next lecture.