Welcome back.
Let's now try out Flexbox
for the very first time in practice.
And for now, we're gonna use CodePen again
because what we want right now
is just to write a simple demo, so a simple example,
and for that, CodePen is perfect,
so just head over to codepen dot io,
and then, click here, Create a New Pen.
So we can hide this JavaScript part here,
and then, just HTML and CSS.
So here in the HTML, let's just create a container
with a couple of items in it,
and we can actually use the Emmet syntax here
that I showed you before.
So an element called container,
and then, with items in there.
So class item, and then, five times,
hit Tab, and that's it,
and I'm just gonna put some numbers here
like one, two, three, four, and five,
and that should be enough for our demo.
Now before writing any actual Flexbox code,
let's start by doing our global resets like we usually do,
so margin zero
padding zero, and box sizing
border-box, okay?
Now we can hit Save here as well.
And no, we don't need an account,
so let's remove that as well.
And now just some very quick formatting
for container,
and for the items.
So just a quick background color,
like this gray color, and give it some padding as well
of like 10 pixels, okay, so no flexbox code here at all,
just some initial styling before we start with Flexbox.
Now about the items, let's give them
some background color as well.
And I'm using this pink color, which is f1425d.
Then some padding, let's say 40 pixels.
Some margin as well, like 30 pixels.
A white text color,
and a bigger text as well, so font-size,
let's say 40 pixels as well.
Maybe this is a bit too much, 30, but okay.
So now we're good to go.
So in this lecture, what I want to do is to focus
on the Flexbox properties that we apply on a container.
So basically, the first set of properties
that I showed you in the last lecture.
So the first thing we have to do in order to use Flexbox,
remember, is to set the display property to flex,
and take a look at what happens immediately.
So these flex items here, they're now
automatically side by side, right?
Without using any float, without anything,
all we did was to set the container to flex,
then automatically these type elements
become flex items that are displayed side by side.
All right, now the next thing that I want to show you is
the property called flex direction,
so remember that the default,
so the initial value is the row, so if you say row,
nothing changes right, because that's the default,
but we can also say row-reverse, and what happens then is
that it inverts the direction of the main axis,
so the main axis now goes here,
from the right side to the left side, where before,
it was going from the left side to the right side,
as I showed you in the diagram in the last lecture.
And so with this, we inverted the order,
and so of course, it now starts at one,
two, three, four, five, all right?
Now the next thing that we can try out is the column,
and then we get this result,
and so now, the flex items are stacked
one on top of another, so one, two, three, four, five,
all the way down here, and then the last one
is column-reverse, and you can imagine
what that one will do, exactly.
Now basically, the column starts down here,
which means that the main direction is going from here
down here, up in the direction up here, okay?
So remember, it's always important to know
where the main direction goes, okay?
And now that we have experimented with all of these,
let's just set it back to row, which is the default,
so you can probably imagine that this will be pretty handy,
for example, for responsive designs,
that for example, on a smaller screen,
we can simply set the flex direction to column,
and then, the elements will all be
one on top of another, so that is flex direction.
Next up, I want to show you justify content.
So justify content,
and remember that this property is used
to control how the items should be positioned
along the main axis, right?
So let's start with center, here.
And so you see that automatically
all the items are now all right here
in the center of the container,
so with that very simple property, we immediately centered
the entire content in this container.
Just imagine how difficult it would be
to create this very simple layout
that you see here with a float layout.
It would be much harder, so center puts these items here
right in the middle of the container,
but it doesn't do anything to the space that's between them.
Because the space that we have here is defined
by the margin that we have on the items.
So this margin here defines the space.
Let's actually try to remove it,
okay, and then it would look like this, right?
So all that justify content does
is to put all the items in the center of the flex container.
So let me show you another one here which is space between,
and that one is also very exciting.
Space between, and that's the result.
So what you see now is that the space
is evenly distributed between these flex items,
so this space, and this, this, and this,
it's all the same space,
and Flexbox automatically does
all these calculations for us,
and automatically positions the elements like this,
and of course, if we change the width here of the browser,
then the space that's between these items also adjusts,
so that makes it really easy
to position and align these elements.
Now let me once again get rid of that margin here.
Because now that makes it even more visible
what the space between property here does.
Because there's another one which is actually pretty similar
which is called space around, space-around.
So basically what space-around does here
is that it puts the same amount of space
on both the left side and the right side
of each of the flex items, so what this means is that
this total space between these two flex items
is double the space that's here
on this left side of this item, all right.
Now next up, there's space evenly,
which is also pretty similar to these ones,
so space-evenly, and as you can see what this one does
is that the space is always the same,
so this one is the same as this, and this, and this,
and all of the spaces here between them.
So while space evenly ensures that the space
is always the same between elements
and on the sides of the elements, space around ensures
that the amount of space around each element is the same
on the left and on the right side.
So it's a subtle difference,
but it can make a huge difference sometimes.
So space between, space around, and space evenly.
I also showed you center already,
and so now, what we have left is flex-end,
so when we want them on the right side,
and then flex-start, which is the default.
So these are the options for justify content,
and I will leave it at center here, okay.
And I will also get rid of this margin.
All right, and now the last property
I want to show you on this video is align items.
So remember that justify content defines
how the flex items are aligned along the main axis
and the line items here defines
how the items are aligned along the cross axis.
Now in order for this to work,
we actually need one of them
to be bigger than all the others,
because right now, they are already perfectly aligned
along the cross axis, right?
So along this one here,
but if I make one of them bigger than the others,
then we can experiment with different
alignments across the cross axis.
Let me just put a new class here,
so i2 for item two.
And let's give it some height, like 200 pixels or something.
And all right, so you saw already that
all of them actually growed, not just the i2
on which we defined the height, right?
And that's actually because the initial value
on the line items is stretch,
and with stretch, this is what happens.
So let's just set something else here,
so for example, center.
And now we see what alignment
along the cross axis actually means.
So we have one element that is bigger than all the others,
and with align items set to center,
we basically centered these elements here
relative to this one, which is bigger
in the vertical direction, so in the cross axis.
So now along the cross axis,
they are now all nicely centered
like around this line here, right?
Now if we set this to flex-start,
then they will all be aligned here nicely at the top.
And the same for flex-end,
and they will be aligned here to the end,
and all of that happens, once again, along the cross axis,
so in here, from up to down.
So we saw center, flex-start, flex-end,
and of course, the default is stretch.
So what does stretch do?
Well let's just say it simply stretches
all the other elements to match the height
of the highest flex item, okay?
So that can be very useful as well.
Now there's actually one more,
which is called baseline, and for that,
I'm gonna increase the font size on this one here as well,
or actually, I can do it on another one.
Let's add one class here called i4,
and then, in here as well.
So font size, 70 pixels.
And now if I set this one here to baseline,
then what it will do is to basically align the text
on these flex items along a line,
so if you draw an imaginary line here under these texts,
you will see that they are now completely aligned,
and if I increase this even more, like say to 90,
then they all keep nicely aligned
down here along the text, okay,
so basically, align items to baseline
is to align them to their common text.
Now once again, I'm going with center here,
and of course, I don't want this font size.
So these were three properties
that I wanted to show you in this video here,
so flex-direction, justify-content, and align-items.
Because these three are by far,
the most used Flexbox properties on the flex container.
Now there are also flex wrap and align content,
but I'm gonna leave these for another video.
Now before we finish this one,
I want to show you what happens
with the justify content, and align items
when we change the flex direction.
So let's set this one to a column.
All right, and now the main direction
is no longer going from the left to the right,
but from the top to the bottom, right?
And so, why are these items now here
horizontally centered like this?
Do you know why?
Well, it's because of this
align-items property set to center, right,
because this direction here now, so basically,
the horizontal centering is now in the cross direction,
and remember that align-items is the property
that controls the positioning along the cross axis,
and so this center here is responsible for this,
so let's set it to flex-start.
And so now we see that it's at
the beginning of the cross axis, which remember,
now goes from left to right, so it starts here
and it ends here, and so if we set it to flex-end,
then all of these move to the right side, right?
And so once again, it's really important
to keep track of where the main and the cross axis
are situated in order to use the justify content
and align items properties in the correct way.
And now, just to show you how
the justify content works in this situation,
let's just increase the height of this container
to I don't know, let me experiment here a bit,
500 pixels for example.
No, that's not enough.
So, 1000 pixels even.
Well maybe it should be even more, I guess.
So 1500 pixels, okay, and now,
let's see what happens here.
And so you see that they now start here,
and then, they're basically centered
now in the container, right?
So this space here, down here at the end of the container
is the same as this space here, up here, right?
And once again, why is that?
Well, it's because justify content is set to center,
and so along the main axis,
which is now going from top to the bottom, right,
so along this main axis, they are now centered,
so let's change it to space-between,
and so this is what happens.
So the space is now distributed here
between these items just as I showed you before,
but when I showed it to you the first time,
it was horizontally, so it was in this direction,
but now, if we change it to a column,
it now happens in the vertical direction,
because once again, that is now the main axis.
All right, and I think that was enough
experimentation for one lecture alone,
and I know this is probably very confusing right now,
because I felt exact same thing
when I first started learning of Flexbox.
It was all very confusing in my head,
and so many properties with so many different names,
but believe me that after some time using these,
you will really know how to use them
and when to use which property,
and it will all become really easy for you,
so don't worry if it sounds confusing right now,
because with practice, it becomes really easy and intuitive.
And in the next lecture, we're gonna take care
of the properties related to the flex items themselves,
so we're gonna change some order,
and experiment with the flex grow,
shrink, and flex bases properties.
So keep tuned for that next lecture.