Are you excited to learn something new right now?
Then you're in the right place,
because we're gonna start using SASS variables
and nesting right now.
Once more we're gonna use CodePen here
instead of starting to write SASS right in our code editor.
That's because if we wanted to use SASS
on our local computer right now,
then we would first have to install and configure it
and then compile the SASS code to CSS.
But right now all we really wanna do
is to just learn SASS and start using it,
and not having to worry about all the configuration stuff.
And CodePen allows us to do exactly that.
In order to follow along with this lecture and the next one,
just come here to codepen.io
and then just create a new pen.
Just like this.
In here, we can write our HTML or CSS and JavaScript
and it will render the results down here.
We can also configure a bunch of stuff.
We're not gonna write any JavaScript code,
so let's just close this one.
Then we can set some settings here.
For example, for the CSS our CSS Preprocessor will be SASS.
And remember we have SASS and SCSS,
which actually stand both for SASS,
but with a different syntaxes.
So remember, we are going to use SCSS,
which stands for Sassy CSS in this course.
This is going to be our preprocessor,
and then CodePen will automatically compile
all code that we write here to CSS.
It says here already SCSS now, right?
So we're just gonna build a very small example here
in these two lectures, just to get you familiar with steps.
We're gonna write a small navigation.
Let's start by very quickly marking that up
in the HTML here.
Nav, then in there we have a unordered list
with a class of navigation.
And in there we have a bunch of links.
I'm sure you have done something like this before.
And just an empty link here, okay?
So something like this, About us.
Let's copy this one
and then close it.
We want something different here.
Let's say Pricing and Contact.
Just follow along with me here,
just copy this code, this HTML code,
so that we can then start writing the SASS,
which is what we really want.
So we have this navigation here on this side.
And then we just want two buttons
sitting on the other side of the navigation bar.
You'll see later what I'm trying to do here.
This is just a div that will hold these two buttons,
the button main, pointing to nowhere once again,
and then another one.
Unfortunately, this CodePen doesn't really have
an autocomplete function,
so we have to really type out the entire code,
which is a bit boring.
But that's what we have to do. (chuckles)
And then just close the div and close the nav element.
And that's it.
That's our simple markup.
Now before we do anything else,
let's do a normal reset like we did
on our other project as well.
Let's just say margin: 0 and padding: 0.
Now let's start styling the nav element.
Let's say we want a margin of 30 pixels
and some background color.
Now, colors are a typical use case for SASS variables.
So let me show you how SASS variables actually work.
Now first of all, what is a variable?
A variable is just like a container
where we can store some data,
for example like the name of a color.
Then we can reuse it all over our code.
So we just have to define it once
and then can use it everywhere.
And if, for example, we then wanted to change that color,
we only would have to change it in the variable definition
and it would automatically change all over the code.
So let's define a variable, and this is how it works.
Let's call this one color-primary.
The color I'm giving it is this one, f9ed69.
This is just a yellow color
that I have selected before for this project.
Let me just comment this here.
Actually what you can do in SASS
is to write comments like this.
So instead of having to write like we do in normal CSS,
so just like this and here a comment, then like this,
in SASS, it's actually easier.
We can just do this double slashes.
So just this, and then we can say this is a yellow color.
All we have to do now here is to write color-primary.
Let's see what happens.
Here we go.
Here is our yellow background color.
Again, this is what happened.
We stored this piece of data here,
this piece of text in this case,
in the color-primary variable.
We then used that color variable down here,
and it read the data from our variable definition
which is up here.
And we could now go ahead and use this variable
wherever we wanted.
Now, imagine that we wanted to change it.
Let's cut it here and just write red, for example.
And then it would change to red, right?
That's not what we want, of course,
so let's put our yellow color back here.
And that are variables.
Note that you always have to define a variable name
starting with this dollar sign here.
That is how SASS identifies variables,
always starting with this dollar sign.
Since we're here defining variables,
let's actually add two more colors here already.
So, color-secondary, which is kind of an orange, f08a5d.
All right, and then another color-tertiary,
so the third color, and this is a pink, b83b5e.
Let's now actually style the navigation itself.
But before we do that, we can also save our pen here.
So just hit Save.
Then it will ask you to create a new account here.
But that's not really necessary
because all that matters, it hasn't changed this link here.
So now if you wanna share this with someone,
you just have to copy this link and paste it.
For example, if you have a question with some problem
with your code and if you wanna share it to get some help,
then you can simply go ahead
and copy and paste this URL here.
Now, something else we can do here
is to click here and then see our compiled CSS.
This is the SASS code which is compiled to this CSS code.
This is very simply this code.
So the variables, they of course don't produce any CSS code.
They are just there to store some data for us.
Then here the variable that we had here
for the background color
was simply replaced with the variable that we defined,
so exactly as I showed you.
So you see here, color-primary, this f9ed69.
Now when we see the compiled CSS,
that's exactly what you have here.
That is what the compiler does behind the scenes.
Now, about the navigation,
let's first select it.
The first thing we can say is that we want no list style.
List-style: none, and so these small bullets will disappear.
Now we wanna select these li items here, right?
So these ones.
This is an excellent time to talk about nesting.
How would you usually do it without SASS
if you wanted to select this li item?
Probably you would just write something like this.
Navigation, and then li, and then just select it, like this.
Right?
But with SASS and with nesting,
we can actually do better than that.
All we have to do in order to replace this
is to write li right in here.
And that's it.
So these are nested selectors.
We first select a navigation.
And then inside the navigation, we select li elements.
It's exactly what we have in here.
But SASS allows us to write this in this easier way
so we have to type less code
and it's also better organized, I think.
Again, this selector here basically means
that we want to select the li
which is inside of the navigation.
This is exactly what we have here.
We select a navigation
and then the li is inside the navigation.
So we can write the selector
inside of the navigation selector.
Does it make sense?
We then no longer need this one.
Let's just start by writing some code here
before I can show you actually the compiled CSS
to show you that it works the exact same way.
So display, I'll put them as inline-blocks
so that they are nicely sitting side by side,
just like this exactly,
so the three li elements are these three, right?
You can already see that does this work, right?
We also put a margin-left here of, let's say, 30 pixels.
And again you saw that it worked.
Let's take a look at the uncompiled CSS,
or actually the compiled CSS, sorry.
So yeah, this is the code that I showed you initially.
It is the result of the nesting that we did in SASS.
Great.
This gives us a really cool new tool.
Can actually also increase the space here of these panels
so that we can see the code a bit better.
So yeah, now you know how nesting works in SASS.
But that's not all.
Nesting can be even more powerful than this.
Let's say you wanted to format only the first element here,
only the first li element.
You could very simply use the first child pseudoclass.
I'm sure you're already familiar with that.
What you can do, for example, would be something like this,
li and then last-child.
We can then say that we want no margin in there,
margin: 0.
And so it worked.
Now actually, we want,
sorry, not the last child but the first child.
So it works just as intended, right?
However, we can do better than this
because we are repeating the li here.
So we could actually nest this even deeper.
There's no limit to how far you can nest.
You can put a nested selector inside a nested selector
inside a nested and so on and so forth.
So you could go really deep with your nesting.
But getting back to what we were doing,
what we can do here in order
to avoid the repetition here of this li
is to simply nest this inside here
and remove this li from here, like this,
and then finally replace it with the ampersand.
What does this ampersand symbol here actually do?
Well, what it does is to actually write the selector path
up until this point.
So in this case, this here will be replaced
with navigation li.
Let me actually write it out for you
because I know it can seem a bit complicated.
What we have here in practice is navigation li,
and then first-child.
Right? This is what we have.
Now in here, you didn't need the ampersand symbol
because in the markup, the li is actually
inside the navigation.
So here, this li is inside this ul
with the navigation class.
So you don't need to use the ampersand in here.
But here in this case, this first-child pseudoclass
is actually attached to the li, as you can see here.
So there's no space here.
If you would do it like this, without the ampersand,
then it would do like this.
And you see that it no longer works, then,
here in the code.
Because this is not what we want.
To want it to be like this.
So we have to repeat like this piece of code here,
which is exactly the ampersand.
So again, this ampersand basically writes out the selector
at this current point here.
So in here what we have at this point
is navigation li and then from here, the first-child.
Let's take a look at the compiled code again.
This is exactly what I was telling you.
It converts then to this code,
which is exactly what I showed you and what we want
in order for this to work.
Usually when we have a pseudoclass like this one,
we have to use this ampersand
operator, let's call it like that.
Next up, we want to style the links here.
Now they are inside actually of the li elements.
So where do we put it?
That's right, we put it here, inside this li selector.
This is again in the third level already.
You shouldn't go deeper than this.
In here we have .navigation and then li and then a.
This is gonna translate to this selector here.
So what we're writing in here
will be equivalent to writing this piece of code.
Let's just say that we want text-decoration: none
and text-transform to uppercase.
And you saw that it applied these styles, right?
So really cool.
We can also set a color here.
Since we're talking about colors,
let's actually add another variable.
Let's say we want color-text-dark.
So we're gonna put a dark gray here,
and then in here we say color-text-dark.
Then hopefully our links will turn gray.
And yeah, so here they are.
Actually we should use the link pseudoclass here.
Doesn't make much of a difference but it's just better.
As a next step, let's get these buttons here,
so this button element here,
so that they put the class button
floating to the right side here.
Let's just do that.
Buttons, I can actually call it buttons, float: right.
Let's change it here as well.
Let's call it buttons.
So now they are here.
Now I should also then float this part here to the left.
So navigation, where is it?
And float: left.
Now what's going to happen?
Yeah, that's right.
The background color here disappeared.
That's because all of the child elements
of this container, of this nav container here,
are floating and so the element collapses
and it loses all its height.
We can actually see this in the inspector.
Actually, where is this?
So yeah, here.
Here we can see up there, well, you will see it here.
It says that there's a height of zero pixels.
So again, this happens because all the child elements
of this nav element are currently floated.
What do we have to do here?
We can use the clearfix method.
I'm sure you're already familiar with that one as well.
I showed it to you in my other course.
So every CSS developer which uses floats
also uses clearfix in order to fix this problem.
Do you remember how we used to do that?
We usually created a class called a clearfix
and then added it to that element,
so just like adding class, clearfix, in here.
And we can actually do that right now.
I will then show you another way.
So class clearfix, and then in here,
we create this class as well,
or we select element.
So the clearfix works like this.
The content is empty.
Of course I forgot that what this actually does
is to add a pseudoelement after the collapsed element.
Basically it's this pseudoelement,
this clearfix pseudoelement,
that is then going to clear this float.
It will do so with the clear both property.
Also we should set the display to table.
So here we go.
The clearfix class worked.
It fixed this collapsed element.
Now instead of writing this separate class,
we could simply add it here to the nav.
This would actually be the exact same thing
as writing this.
Because it's to the nav element
that we actually want to attach this pseudoelement
which then clears the float.
We can do even better with this.
Do you already see the solution, what we can do?
That's right, we can put it in here.
We can once again nest the selectors.
And then here, what do we put here?
Exactly, we put the ampersand operator.
And that's it.
It's back to working here.
So this here will be replaced with nav,
and then from there, we add the pseudoelement.
Let's just check that just to make sure.
So here we go.
Again, we have to use this ampersand
because if we wouldn't use it,
then this is what it would look like.
So nav and then the space,
as I was telling you in the beginning,
and then the after.
But that's not what we want.
So we need to attach the ampersand operator in here.
All right, and just to finish this lecture,
let's now very quickly style these two buttons here, as well
so that we can use these other color variables
that we already defined before.
We have two buttons here.
We have the button main and the button hot.
Some of their aspects will actually be pretty similar,
so let's group them together here.
The main button
and the hot button,
both with the link pseudoclass.
All right, we want them to have a padding of 10 pixels.
We want them to be displayed as inline-blocks.
And now you see that their padding is actually
applied here on all the entire element,
not just on the left and right.
So now the box model works on them
as if they were block elements,
as I was explaining you in one of the theory lectures.
We want their text to be centered.
We want a border radius of 100 pixels,
so again a really huge number
just to give them these rounded corners.
Of course we also wanna get rid of the underlining.
So text-decoration: none.
And also to make them uppercase.
We can also set their width.
I think this is a good time to use another variable.
Variables don't just have to be colors, of course.
We can use everything for variables.
Let's create another variable here
and call it width for the button.
Let's say we want 150 pixels here for the width.
If we then later wanted to, for example,
change this design aspect,
then instead of having to go down there to the button,
we could just change the settings here,
this variable setting.
So this variable here could act, like, as a setting.
Our variable name is width-button.
So you saw the effect here.
They are now larger than they were before.
Okay, so these are the main definitions.
Now let's give each of them a different background color.
So button main, and we actually want one background color
on the normal link state,
and then a different one for the hover state.
How could we do that using nesting?
Do you have any idea?
Well, I will give you a hint.
We don't need to write 'em here in the first selector,
so in the beginning of the selector.
We can use nesting for both of these states.
So how are we gonna do that?
We do it like this.
Use again the ampersand and then link.
And that's it.
So it doesn't just work, of course,
for the after pseudoclass or for the
first or last child pseudoclasses.
It works for all of these as well,
like link or hover as well.
So, hover.
This will translate into button main link
and button main hover.
So background-color.
And here let's use our color-secondary.
Let's see it.
Yeah, here it goes, great.
There's a cool trick, a cool thing, I can show you,
which is also part of SASS,
background-color, which is to use a color function.
SASS comes in with a couple of built-in color function
which can make life a fit easier.
Instead of having to calculate another color,
for example imagine we want this button
to become a bit darker as soon as we hover it.
Instead of having to calculate or to figure out
another color for this,
we can simply use one of the built-in color functions,
which is called darken.
So we say darken and then we put our color.
Again, we can use our variable here, so color-secondary.
And now it's already paying off
to having this color stored in a variable,
'cause then we don't have to write it all over again.
Now let's say we wanted to make just 15% darker.
And that's what this does.
Let's now test it.
And yeah, it's a bit darker.
Can put it only 5% darker.
Let's see how that looks like.
Now you see it's only getting slightly darker.
But let's get back to our 15% as we had it.
Let's take again a look at the compiled CSS.
We have the link and the hover state, as we specified.
Then here this is the color that SASS calculated,
which is like 15% darker than this one.
All right, cool.
Now we can just do the same thing here
for the other button as well.
This is very similar so I can just copy the code, so hot.
Then here, the tertiary.
Yep, that's right.
Then copy it here.
And so it gets also darker as we hover it.
Now just to show you another one,
there's also lighten.
As you can imagine, this will do the opposite.
So it will turn the color lighter.
And yeah, so it works.
Maybe that's a bit too much.
We can just put, like, 10%.
And yeah, great.
Now we want also a color in here
for these two buttons.
That's say color.
And actually we want, like,
a white color or something like that.
So let's just define another variable here.
Color-text-light.
We can make it maybe not completely white,
but something similar.
So instead of fff, we can use eee.
Take a look how this looks like.
We call it color-text-light.
Let's see, oh yeah.
It looks good, right?
I think this small example was a great use case
of using variables and nesting for the first time.
I hope that you really grasped these concepts
and that you fully understood them
and that you're now ready to use them
in the real world.
What I want you to do now is to again
take a look at the compile CSS
and carefully compare it with the code that we just wrote.
So just so you make really sure
that you understood what happens here
behind the scenes of SASS,
so what exactly it does with these variables
and with all this nesting.
Okay?
In the next lecture, we're gonna be back to this example
and then I'm gonna introduce you
to mix-ins, functions, and extends.
So keep tuned for that one.