After the Flexbox properties
for the flex container,
now I wanna show you the properties
that we use directly on the flex items.
So this is where we left off after the last lecture.
Now, let me just put this one here
so it aligns item back to center.
Because now the first thing that I wanna show you
is the align-self property.
So you can come here to one of these items,
and then use align-self.
And remember what align-self does.
Well, basically it overrides the align-contents property
for one individual item.
So right now, the align-items is set to center.
And so all these items here
are now centered along the cross axis, right?
So, from top to bottom.
But if you wanna override that for one individual,
let's say the number four here,
we can say align-self.
And put this one, for example, at the end.
So, flex-end.
Now all the flex items except this one here
are aligned to the center,
so along the cross axis here
except for this one, which we set to flex-end.
And we can set it to flex-start, of course.
Can also set it to stretch
and that one is pretty useful.
We're gonna see that one in the course.
So now this one is actually the same height as this one
because it's stretched in order to fill the entire container
which was defined by this element with the number two.
Now the number four here has the same height.
So let's just put it back to the end here,
so flex-end, alright?
So that's the first one that I wanna show you
and next we can play around with the order.
Remember that the initial value of order is zero.
So if you wanna put one of these elements
here at the beginning,
all we need to do is to put the value
which is lower than zero.
So let me show you how.
So, "order: -1"
And now it will go here to the start.
So, why's that?
Well, Flexbox orders all of these elements
according to their order number.
So this one has zero, zero, zero, and zero.
So all of these have zero,
but this one has minus one
and so this is the one that has the lowest order.
Since Flexbox starts ordering from the lowest order number
Well, then of course this one here becomes the first.
Now, if you wanna change this,
and let's put another class here for the third one,
so "i3."
If you want this one here to be the first one,
then we can set this order to minus two, for example.
And now this one will be the one
with the lowest order.
And so it now comes here to the first position.
Now we can also do this the other way around.
So if we set this one to one,
then it's the one with the highest order.
And so it moves here to the end.
And so now we have minus one,
zero, zero, zero, one.
And we can use this even further if you wanna.
For example here, order two,
and now this one would be the last.
So that's how we use order.
And that's actually pretty useful,
once more, for responsive design
in order to change position for some elements
on a smaller or on a bigger screen
depending if we're using a mobile first
or a desktop first strategy.
So that's order and align-self.
Now let's take a look at the last three
which are flex-grow, flex-shrink, and flex-basis.
So the first one that I wanna show you is flex-grow
and remember that flex-grow
is the ability of an element to grow.
And what we do is to specify an integer.
So just a number like we did in the order.
The first thing I wanna do
is to actually set flex on all the items.
And so for that I can use the item class.
So, "flex-grow: 1"
Take a look what happens now.
Alright, so all of them now
occupy the entire space that they can.
Or, in other words, they growed as much as they can.
So they are now occupying all the space they possibly can.
And we can see it even better
if we move this margin here, actually.
Okay, and so now they're actually touching one another
because again, they occupy all the space that they can.
And that's what flex-grow here does.
So it gives items the ability to grow.
Now if we set all of them to a higher number
like two or three or even 23,
it doesn't really matter,
because this number only matters
in relation to other numbers.
So let me actually give you an example of that.
So, I'm going to set these back to one.
Put this margin here back as well.
But now what I'm gonna do with this one here,
is to set flex-grow to two.
And watch what happens now.
You saw that?
This element here is now double the size of these ones.
That's because two is double of one.
So this one has twice the ability to grow
than all the other flex items.
I can show you that even better
by setting this, for example, to three
and now it's three times bigger than the others.
Flex-grow, again, gives the element an ability to grow.
Now, remember that there is also a shorten property
which stands for flex-grow, flex-shrink, and flex-basis.
So saying flex-grow is actually the same thing
as saying "flex: 1"
So, a simple trick to expand a flex item
to occupy as much width as it can
is simply setting its flex property to one.
Let me get rid of this now
and this one here as well.
So let me show you what happens
if I just set this on one of them.
Let's say this one here, the last one.
So, "flex: 1"
Alright, and so now this one occupies
all the space that it can
so all the available white space
and then the remaining flex items here
they just occupy the rest of the space.
So that is flex-grow.
Now next up, I wanna show you flex-basis.
Let's do it on this one here.
And I can actually get rid of this one here.
So flex-basis.
And now remember that with this one
we can set the width of a flex item.
Instead of using the width property on a flex item,
we usually use flex-basis, right?
So let's set it to 20%, for example.
And here we go.
So it's now 20% of the container
than these other elements here
which basically have their flex-basis set to auto
which is the initial value for flex-basis.
So this one here simply occupied
the space that they need
and then all the remaining space
is occupied by this last element here
because its flex set to one.
Another one that's missing is flex-shrink.
And in order to better show that to you,
let's actually change this one here
to a pixel based value.
So let's say 300 pixels.
So now this one here has 300 pixels.
Now take a look at what happens
when I decrease the viewport width.
So, just decreasing this window here.
You saw what happens?
Again, the first thing of course that happens
is that this element here grows smaller and smaller.
That's because it has less and less space
which it can occupy.
So, of course, it becomes smaller, right?
Now, as I further decrease this here,
what start to happen now?
Well, you see, that this element here also decreases, right?
So even if we set its flex-basis to 300 pixels,
so basically we set the width to 300 pixels,
it still starts decreasing
when there's no more available space.
But sometimes that's not exactly what we want.
So we can actually change that
using the flex-shrink property.
Because remember, flex-shrink controls
how an element can shrink.
So, flex-shrink.
Now remember that flex-shrink
has the initial value of one.
So, one means that the element
is basically allowed to shrink.
And that's why we see this behavior here.
Where the element starts getting smaller and smaller
as there is no more available space.
Now if we don't want this to happen,
we simply set it to zero and with that,
the element is no longer allowed to shrink.
So, let's see that.
And you see what happens now?
These last elements simply get clipped
basically from the viewport.
Or actually, the viewport increases its width
in order to fit these remaining elements,
but what doesn't happen
is that this element doesn't change its width
because it's not allowed to shrink.
So that's what you did here with flex-shrink to zero.
Now as I mentioned before,
we should always use the flex property.
Instead of having this,
we just use the shorthand
because that's the best practice.
So flex, and now it's zero for flex-grow
because we don't want this element to grow
as much as it can,
so occupying all the space it can.
Then we also don't want it to shrink
and do want a flex-basis of 300 pixels, for example.
So that's exactly the thing that we had before.
Let's convert this one here as well.
Where is it? Now it's not here anymore.
So I already deleted.
But what we usually want here is actually the one.
So usually we want the elements
to be able to shrink, right?
Because we don't want that situation
where the elements no longer fit the container.
So that's the way it works now.
With that, I showed you all the properties
that we can apply to a flex item.
Now there's a lot more to learn, of course.
Again, we're gonna use all of this later in the project.
By then, you can see how we actually
use all of these properties in real life situations.
This here is just a very small example
just to really show you how the properties work
and that they exist.
But as soon as we start a project
you will use these properties in the real life
and everything will make a lot more sense to you.