Welcome back.
Let's now, finally, get our hands dirty
with CSS Grid for the very first time.
And so here, I already have a brand new
CodePen open in Firefox,
as you can see here.
So we're working, now, in Firefox,
as I was telling you in the last lecture.
And you'll actually see why in a second.
So when we start using the Firefox dev tools,
so let's start by closing JavaScript editor here
because of course we don't need it.
And now for a small example, let's start with some HTML.
So we start with a element called container.
And so we used Emmet throughout the course a lot,
and it actually also works here in CodePen.
And so I'm using that right now to write our markup.
So we want the container element,
which will actually be our grid container,
and then in there we want to have a couple of items.
So let's call them item,
but I also want to give each of them an individual name.
So item one,
and so you see we're using the BEM notation here again
with this dash, dash here.
Now I want this to happen six times,
and so I simply can say times six.
And what this will do is that it will do six times
this part here of the code.
So we will have one container element
with six items in there.
Now the problem with this is that each of these six items
will have the number one here.
But we don't want that, and so we actually can do better.
Because here in Emmet, there's another trick that we can use
and it is to use the dollar sign, basically.
And so now this dollar sign will get replaced
with the current number,
so one, two, three, four, five, and six.
So let me show that to you when I now actually hit tab here.
And so here we go.
So one, two, three, four, five, and six.
So that's a very handy trick in Emmet
that I wanted to show you.
Let's now put some content here into these divs,
and we're gonna put the number from one to six,
and then a color.
And so these divs, they will later have
these different colors.
So orange,
green,
number three, violet,
pink for number four,
and then blue and brown.
And brown, alright.
And let's now actually save this,
so I just hit the save button here and then you see
that this changes here the URL.
And you see that I am actually logged into my account,
and so this CodePen will actually be available
on my public CodePen profile, if you wanna check that out.
So now about the CSS, let's give it some more space
here on the side.
And let's start by writing some simple styles
for the container.
So let's just give it some background color,
background-color,
like #eee.
And a width of 1,000 pixels.
So now we're not really worrying
about using rem and all that stuff,
so we just want to make this work.
We just want this to be like a small demo.
Let's now also center this in the viewport,
and for that we can use our old trick,
zero and auto.
And actually let's put something like 30 pixels in here
so that we get some space between
the top of this window and the container.
Okay, and with that, we're ready to start using grid.
So how do we turn an element into a grid container?
Well, very simple.
Display grid.
And that's it.
So now this is a grid container,
but nothing really changed, right?
And that's because we didn't define any columns or any rows.
So that's what we're gonna do next.
And here is how it works in grid.
So we have a property
called grid-template-rows,
and in here we can define our rows.
So let's say, we want these six elements here
to be divided in two rows and three columns.
So that makes six, two times three makes six.
So we want two rows and three columns.
So what we do here is to define these two rows.
So I say that the first one should be 150 pixels,
and I say that the second one should be 150 pixels as well.
And that's it.
So that's how grid-template-rows works.
We define, basically, the height of our rows.
So the first one should be 150 pixels
and the second as well.
So simple as that.
And now let's do the same thing for the columns.
So grid-template, and you can guess
that this one is called grid-template-columns.
So let's also do 150 pixels for now,
and later we're gonna change all of this,
so this is just a very first approach.
And alright, so we see here
that they're actually now already laid out as a grid here.
That's awesome, right?
Now before we actually go inspect this
here in the dev tools, let's add some colors here
to these items so that we can better see what's going on.
Alright.
So item, and so first of all let's define some global styles
for all of these items.
So let's give them a padding of like 20 pixels,
a font size of 30 pixels,
and font family, and we simply say we want sans-serif.
And we say that the color should be white.
Okay and now the colors of these items,
and actually we can use SASS here again.
So you can see here that this is actually SCSS, alright.
And so we can construct our selectors like we've been using
all the time in the project.
Okay, so this here will mean item one, right.
Let's do this for all of them,
two, three, four, five, and six.
So item two, item three, item four, five and six.
And let's just give them some quick colors.
And my orangered again,
okay so the first one will be orange.
Let's quickly copy this here as well.
This one will be yellowgreen,
blueviolet, so these are just some built-in CSS colors
as you know already.
This one is called palevioletred,
so this kind of weird color.
This one is royalblue, and then goldenrod or something.
Alright so now we can see that our grid is really laid out
in a three per two fashion here,
with these squares which are each 150 per 150 pixels, right.
So just as we defined up here.
And now let's actually inspect this here,
and this works very similarly to Google Chrome,
so we say inspect element,
and let's now actually put this here on the side.
So just hit this button here.
And okay, so we have more space to actually see the grid.
Now here in the markup, as you start hovering
these items here, you see the lines in the page, right.
So this is the grid container here,
and then all of these grid items, right.
But that's actually not the best part
because if we select the container here,
we see here display: grid, right
and when you click this item here,
then you can actually see a nice grid overlay
on the element.
So we can now come here to this layout tab
to see this even better.
So this is our container that we have,
with our six items in there.
And now we can display line numbers here,
which makes it even better.
And so now you see these line numbers.
So remember from the first intro lecture
where I told you that the column lines
and the row lines get automatically numbered.
And so here it is.
One, two, three, and four,
which are three columns, plus one.
And then one, two, three, for the lines.
Okay, and so that makes it a lot easier to build CSS grids
here using the inspector.
You can actually also see the grid lines in here,
like these dashed lines that you can see.
Maybe it's not really visible right now
but you are gonna see it a bit better in a second,
because let's now add another thing to our grid.
So remember that I told you that we can also have
space between the grid items, right?
And that's called the gutter.
So let's add grid-row-gap,
and let's set it to 20 pixels.
And what's gonna happen?
Yeah, here we have the gap now.
Let's make it a bit bigger actually, so 30 pixels.
And so this is the gap.
We can, of course, also put a gap in the columns.
So grid-column-gap, as you can guess.
30 pixels as well.
And alright, once more, the dev tools show us
the gap here, and now you can also see the grid lines
a bit better here, right.
So they're limiting here each of these grid items.
So of course we can also change the column gap
to something else than the row gap.
So remember I mentioned that as well before,
so we can have different gaps for columns and for the rows.
Now if you want to have the same gap for everything,
you can simply use grid-gap, and set it to 30 pixels.
And then it will all be the same.
So let's comment out these ones here,
just so you keep them here in the code.
Okay, and that's it.
That is our very first CSS grid.
You see how easy it was to put these six elements here
in this very simple grid layout?
No floats, no weird HTML tricks here,
because imagine if you wanted to do this very same layout
without grid.
We would have to have just a wrapper
for these three items here, and then a wrapper
for the second three items here.
And that's really not practical at all,
it's so much better laying these items out like this.
So before ending this lecture, let's just very quickly
recap what we did here.
So we first set the display property to grid,
and then we defined our rows,
so the template rows for the grid.
And in this case, we basically said that we want to have
two rows, each of them with 150 pixels.
You could also put the second one to 100 pixels for example,
then of course it would become smaller.
So the first value for the first row,
and the second value for the second row.
And then of course, the same for the columns.
So we said we want three columns,
basically each one with 150 pixels.
And we can actually do a bit better here with this,
but I'm gonna show you that in the next lecture.
For now, I just want you to get the basics really right.
So we defined our grid in terms of rows and columns,
and then we also added some gaps here.
So a row gap, and a column gap, which can be different
but if we want them to be the same, we can simply use
the grid-gap property to set both of them at the same time.
Then we also inspected them here in the dev tools,
and don't forget to check this display line numbers box here
so that you can actually see the line numbers
because we're gonna need that in the next lecture.
And that's it, that's the very fundamentals of CSS grid.
But there's a lot more, of course, a ton more to learn.
And so I'm gonna wait for you right in the next lecture.
See you in a second.