Hey there, so in the last lecture
I gave you a high level overview
about how HTML and CSS are processed in the browser.
Now in this lecture we're going to start to look
at the CSS parsing phase,
because a lot of important stuff happens in this phase.
Now just before we start
let's do a quick review of the official terms
that we can find in a CSS rule
just so that we're all on the same page
in these and the coding videos.
So a rule consists of a selector
and a declaration block.
As you know we use the selector
to select one or more HTML elements that we want to style.
Then in a declaration block
is where we write the actual styles
in order to style elements on our page.
To do so we can write one or more CSS declarations
in each declaration block.
Each declaration consists of a CSS property
and its corresponding value,
which is the value that we assign to a property.
This value we assign to a property
is called the declared value.
All right and that's it, very simple.
So let's now talk about the first step
of the CSS parsing phase.
First off remember that in the parsing phase
the first step is to resolve conflicting CSS declarations
and the second step is to process the final CSS values.
So let's start with step one in this lecture,
which is the cascade and let's define exactly what it is.
So the cascade is the process of combining
different stylesheets and resolving conflicts
between different CSS rules and declarations
when more than one rule applies to a certain element.
Because as you probably already know
a declaration for a certain style property like font size
can appear in several stylesheets
and also several times inside one single stylesheet.
Now CSS can also come from different sources.
The most common one is the CSS that we the developers write.
These declarations that we put in our stylesheets
are called the author declarations.
Another source can be the user declarations,
which is CSS coming from the user.
For instance, when the user changes
the default font size in the browser
then that is user CSS,
and last but not least
there are the default browser declarations.
For instance, if we put an anchor tag in our HTML for a link
and then don't style it at all it will usually
be rendered with blue text and underlined, right.
That's called the user agent CSS,
because it's set by the browser.
So the cascade combines the CSS declarations
coming from all these different sources,
but how does the cascade actually resolve conflicts
when more than one rule applies?
Well what it does is to look at the importance,
at the selector specificity,
and to source order of conflicting declarations
in order to determine which one takes precedence,
and here's how that works.
First off the cascade starts by giving
the conflicting declarations different importance's
based on where they are declared,
so based on their source.
The most important declarations
are user declarations marked with the important keyword.
You already know the important keyword in CSS, right?
If not I'm going to show you an example in a second.
Next the second most important declarations
are the author declarations marked with important.
Third, the normal author declarations,
then the normal user declarations,
and finally the least important ones
are the default browser declarations,
which actually makes a lot of sense
so that we can easily overwrite
these declarations coming by default from the browser,
but we should get a look at an example here, right.
So here we have two rules
which both apply to the button class
and we have two conflicting declarations
about the background color.
These are both author declarations,
but if you look closely in the first rule
the declaration with the blue background color
contains the important keyword
and therefore this declaration is more important
as we can see from our table.
This means that this is the declaration that gets precedence
and so we see that our button is indeed blue.
Great, does it make sense to you?
I'm sure it does
and we'll see a lot more examples later on.
Now a lot of times
we will just have a bunch of conflicting rules
in our author stylesheets without any important keyword.
That is actually the most common scenario
and in this case all the declarations
have the exact same importance.
Now what happens in this case?
What the cascade does if this is the case
is to calculate and compare the specificities
of the declaration selectors,
and this is how it works.
Inline styles have the highest specificity
followed by IDs, then classes,
pseudo classes and attribute selectors,
and finally the least specific
the element and pseudo element selector.
So when we have conflicting declarations
with the same importance as we saw in the last slide
we calculate their selector specificity
based on the priorities I just showed you,
but let's see how we actually calculate specificities
with a small example, that's always best, right.
First off all these declarations have the same importance,
because they're all author declarations.
So let's calculate their selector specificities
in order to find out if the background color
will be either blue, green, purple, or yellow,
and this is how we do it.
The specificity is actually not just one number,
but one number for each of the four categories
I showed you before.
Inline styles, IDs, classes, pseudo elements and attributes,
and finally elements and for each of these
we count the number of occurrences in the selector.
Simple as that.
So here in selector one
we don't have any inline styles of course,
because an inline style has to be written in the HTML,
which is not the case here, so it's a zero.
We also have no IDs here, so it's again a zero,
but we do have one class, the button class.
So for the classes category we have a one,
and finally there's no element selector here
so zero for that one as well,
and that's it.
The selector specificity is
zero, zero, one, zero.
Great, let's now compare it to the others.
The next one is also not an inline style,
so zero for the first one.
Now here we actually have an ID selector
for the nav ID, right,
so it's one for the ID.
We also have two classes pull right and button
so it's a two for the classes category,
and finally there are also two element selectors here.
The nav element and the div element,
which means that it's also two for the elements category.
So finally the specificity to the selector
is zero, one, two, two,
which is actually a highly specific selector.
Selector number three is very simple.
It's just an element selector
and so the specificity is zero, zero, zero, one.
Now the last one, selector number four.
First again we have the nav ID, so it's one for the ID.
Next we have a class, the button class
and also a pseudo class, which is hover,
which makes it two for the classes category in total.
Since there's also one element selector
the final specificity is zero, one, two, one.
Make sense?
Now you're probably wondering
well this is all great,
but how do we actually use these numbers
to find out which of the selectors applies.
We start to look at the numbers from left to right
starting with the most specific category, the inline styles.
If there is a selector with one
it wins against all the other selectors,
because this is the most specific category.
Well this is not the case here,
so let's move on to the IDs.
We see that selector two and four have a one here
while the others have zero
so the ones with zero are out of the game,
because they are less specific then selectors two and four
the ones with the IDs.
Okay?
Now since both selectors have a one in this category
we have to move on and check the classes.
They both have a two in this category
so it's still a tie between them,
and finally in the elements category
the selector two has a two
while the selector four has only one
and so we have a winner here.
The selector number two is the most
specific selector of all
and so it will give our button a green background.
The value of the winning declaration
is called the cascaded value,
because it's the result from the cascade.
So we start with a bunch of declared values
in this case blue, green, purple, and yellow
and one of them wins and becomes the cascaded value,
which is in our example green.
Now imagine sector four also had two elements
then both selectors two and four
would have the exact same specificity, right.
So what happens in this case
and I promise you it's almost over now okay.
Well if there's still a tie at this point
then the last CSS declaration written in the code
is the one that will apply.
So again if everything is equal,
if all the declarations selectors
have the same specificity
then it's simply the last declaration that will be used
to style the selected element, that's it.
Now just before we finish this lecture
let me give you a quick summary and overview
of the most important things we just learned.
This is essentially what you should really retain
from this lecture.
First off we learned that CSS declarations
marked with important keyword have the highest priority
when multiple declarations are in conflict,
but you should only ever use important as a last resource.
If something doesn't work the way you think it should
then look at your selector specificities
and figure out what's going on.
That's always better then just adding important,
which may solve the problem in an easier way,
but will cause you problems in the long run.
Remember the talk about maintainable code
well thinking about specificities
and using important only as the last resource
is one of the things that will make your code
more maintainable for the future.
The next thing to remember
is that inline styles that you write in your HTML
will always have priority over styles
you write in an external stylesheet,
but since using inline styles
isn't such a good practice anyway
this one isn't all too important.
Next a selector that contains even only one ID
is more specific than one with 1,000 classes.
So if you want to be really specific use an ID.
In the same way a selector with one class
is more specific than one with 1,000 elements of course.
One thing that is really important to note
is that the universal selector has no specificity value
and so it's zero, zero, zero, zero,
which means that all other selectors
have a precedence over it.
You will see how and why
when we start coding our project.
Another thing that you should note
is that it's best to always rely on more specificity
than on the order of selectors.
This way if you someday rearrange all your CSS code
you won't have any surprises which could mess up
your entire code.
This again makes your code a lot easier to maintain,
which is hugely important.
Now there's actually one case where you do
need to worry about the order of selectors
and that's when you're using external
third party stylesheets.
Imagine for instance
that you include something like a reset stylesheets,
which defines a couple of styles for common elements.
In this case of course
you want your stylesheets to be able to overwrite
the third party styles if necessary,
and so your own stylesheet
should be the last one to be included in the HTML.
So in this case the order is actually usually important.
All right, that's actually all there is to know
about the cascade and specificity in CSS.
So if you ever wondered what the cascading word
in cascading stylesheets actually means
now you know it.
Great, right?
And the best part is that understanding all of this
will now allow you to write better,
cleaner and more maintainable CSS code.