Welcome back.
Now that we have a working media query manager
that we did in the last lecture,
let's now finally start using it
and write some real media queries for our page.
But before we start doing that,
I wanna actually take a minute
and come back to the order
of the media queries that we write here.
I wanna recap on why this is the order
and not the other way around,
because this is really essential
in understanding responsive web design.
Imagine that we have a width of 700 pixels for the screen.
In this case, of course,
both of these media queries will apply.
So 700 is less than 1,200 and also less than 900.
And what happens then?
Well, since both of the media queries apply,
it will simply be the last declaration that is applied.
So both of these have a font-size declaration, right?
So the last one of these two
is the one that will be applied, so 50%.
And that is, of course, the one we want
because 900 is the one that's closer to this 700.
If it was the other way around, like this,
then at this screen size of 700,
we would have the font size of 56%,
which was actually only supposed to be used
in the range between 900 and 1,200.
So if we did it like this, this would mess up
our entire code, our entire structure of our media queries.
So this is the way that we want it.
Now, if you happen to be writing a mobile-first website,
then it's the complete other way around.
In that case, we have to start with the lower width
and move up to the larger width
because everything is the other way around.
We have min-width media queries.
So then, in that case, we also need to change the order,
starting with the lower ones and then move on
to the larger screen size.
Now that we have that out of the way,
let's move on and start writing our media queries.
This is the order in which I like to do it.
Let me actually write it down for you.
I will do it here in this mix-in.
The order in which I like to do this
is to start with the base and the typography,
then moving on to the more general layout,
like header, footer, navigation and all that stuff.
So general layout, and also the grid.
The grid also needs to be changed.
Then the the more specific page layout.
Then finally changing the components.
In this lecture, we will take care of this part.
We're gonna change some stuff in the base,
in the typography, general layout and grid.
Actually, we don't need that many changes
because once again, this overall font-size here
takes care of most of the changes
that we want to make, actually.
Adjustments that we need to do are pretty minor
in most of the cases.
Let's fire up our typography file here
and then close all of this here.
And I'll take a look at our webpage.
This is it, still here in the device menu.
Notice something really cool that we can do
what I didn't show you in the last lecture,
which is to show actually our media queries.
These are our media queries, these ranges here.
56.25 is the smallest one.
Let me check that out for you.
Where is this mix-in?
56.25 is here.
Let me zoom that out a bit, so 75.
So in here we are now in the 56.25 media queries.
Actually we have a smaller one, which is this one.
But we don't really have one on the page
at this point already
because the only three media queries that we wrote
were the three here.
And the one for the phone is not here.
So dev tools of course cannot know
that we actually plan for one for the phone.
So it's gonna come up here later.
But anyway, this one here is our break point at 900 pixels,
as you can see in here.
Then you can also nicely see which one is applying.
When they become darker means that they are applied.
Then you have this one here as well,
and all you need to do is to click here
and it goes to the break point.
Also you see here that the blue ones
are the max-width media queries.
Then here the orange ones are the min-width.
Google Chrome also does this nice distinction here for us.
Then up here, we have simply the responsive way
where we can decrease and increase our screen here
as we wish, as I showed you.
Then we also have a list of devices here,
basically where we can test.
So like the iPhone
or iPhone 5
or the Nexus or whatever.
But we're mostly gonna use here our responsive.
So we were talking about typography.
What do we have in the typography?
Well, we have the primary heading,
we have secondary heading, tertiary heading and paragraph.
Let's now take a look at what happens with these
as we decrease our page.
You see that they nicely adapt actually.
And they still adapt in here.
And only down here, almost at 600,
this where it starts making some problems.
So imagine that we had a device with 300, let's say,
and then we would no longer see the text here at all.
So we have to fix that.
Another thing that I wanna fix
is to actually get rid of this white border here
on a smaller screen size.
We can do that, I think, here at 900 pixels,
so basically at the tablet portrait mode.
So starting from here,
let's get rid of this white border now.
That is actually in base, I think.
Well, it should be but it's not.
Let's actually copy this one here to base,
'cause there should be,
yeah, there's one for the body
and this is where it should be.
This has nothing to do with typography.
All right, so that's now actually include
for media query here.
I will just copy it from here.
I'm lazy and I don't like to type so much,
so just copy this here.
Now let's get rid of this padding.
Zero.
Let's take a look.
Let's reload, I'm not sure if it did reload automatically.
Here it goes, the padding.
Right here at this break point, now it's gone.
And as soon as we increase it,
then of course it comes back.
That's the media query already doing its work.
Great.
But what we're doing here before was
to actually decrease this entire text here,
starting at 600 pixels,
basically our phone media query.
Let's do that.
Typography and heading-primary.
I'm putting it right here.
Include respond(phone)
and what do we want to happen here?
Well, I think what we should do here
is to actually get rid of all this letter spacing.
Now I see that actually this should probably be in here.
Right?
Because this is where the font size is actually defined
and the letter spacing.
So let's get rid of the letter spacing,
at least in part.
We had 3.5 rem, let's put it back to one rem.
And then the font size, let's decrease it to six rem.
Well, six would be the same, so five rem.
Then down here, let's do the same.
Decrease the letter spacing,
well, not to zero but maybe to five pixels,
so .5 rem, for example.
Let's take a look at that.
And yeah, that looks a bit more natural now.
And yeah.
Actually already now have this last media query
that we were missing.
But now we have one in our actual code
and then here it appears.
So that looks better now.
But what about our H2's?
Well, I think they're probably a bit too big here
at this point, right?
Basically we should probably change them
at the 900 pixel media query.
So, tablet portrait.
Let's do that.
Heading-secondary.
Include respond, and we call it tab-port.
So let's decrease the font size to, like, 2.5 maybe.
And then for the phone we can make it even smaller,
2.5 like this.
And then one for the phone.
Remember, the phone is smaller so it comes after the tablet.
So phone, and then let's say two rem.
Check it out.
And yeah, that looks probably better.
We're not seeing it here on real devices.
But for now it's okay to do it like this.
Usually I always change everything here in the browser
and then I start testing on real devices.
And from there, I usually always see some stuff
that I have to change afterwards.
But essential things, so the first and major changes,
they can be done here in the browser
without any problem usually.
All right.
I think that for the H1 and H2,
this is actually already changed enough.
Maybe it's even a bit too small.
I'm not really sure.
So let's put it to three and then 2.5 or something.
So three and 2.5.
That should be better.
All right, and with that we actually already finished
the part about the typography and the base settings.
Animations here, they don't need any changes.
The utilities also don't need any changes,
at least for now.
Maybe we'll change something here a bit later.
But for now we're good to go here in this folder.
Then here in the abstracts folder,
there are also no changes.
So now let's move on to the layout.
I wanna start with the grid, actually.
So closing the typography, closing the mix-ins here as well.
I'm gonna start with the grid.
Let's take a look at what happens with the grid.
Where do we have one of them?
This is a grid with four columns in it.
You see that they're becoming really small,
so really, really small.
And it doesn't look, like, good at all.
The same thing here.
Where else do we have?
I don't think there's any more than this.
Ah, here also, too.
But here it's no problem.
But here and here, it's definitely not okay like this.
So let's go to our break point.
I think where we should change it is here at 900.
Here it's still kind of okay
and we can later make some adjustments here to this.
Right now it's still okay.
But below this, these columns,
they are definitely too narrow.
So we can't wait until the next break point,
which would be this one.
We cannot have them looking like this.
So we have to change the grid system right here
at the tablet portrait break point.
All right.
And what are we going to do in order to fix this?
Well, we're simply gonna set the width
of all the columns to 100%.
That's the easiest way to do it,
and that's what's usually done on mobile devices.
So all the columns are basically transformed into rows.
So the entire mobile webpage will have
only one single column, basically.
Include respond(tab-port).
So all of the columns should have a width of 100%.
I'm gonna set it to important, actually,
because I wanna make really sure
that these widths here are overwritten.
Now the next thing I have to do is to then, of course,
remove any margin from these columns.
'Cause right now they all have this gutter here.
But since they're no longer side by side now,
we don't need any gutter, right?
So margin-right: 0, very simple.
Next up what we should probably change is this gutter here.
So let's open up the variables.
This gutter is in 80 pixels, or eight rem,
'cause 80 pixels is no longer accurate
on these lower media queries.
So we have eight rem here.
But that's way too much, I believe.
So let's create a new variable here called gutter-vertical
for six rem, called small.
So gutter-vertical-small.
Where is that?
And yeah, here we go.
Again, I'm gonna copy this, and where is it?
Okay, right here.
Notice it's starting to look a bit confusing.
(chuckles) I know.
But I think that's okay
given how much writing our code in this way here,
which may look a bit strange, improves our lives
over just writing original vanilla CSS code.
Even if looks a bit strange with all this nesting going on
that this includes and all of that going on,
you will see that you will become used to it.
So it's not really a problem.
So gutter-vertical-small here,
just to confirm that the name is right.
Then let's take a look at it, actually.
Well, that doesn't look so good for now.
That's because these images here are huge and overlapping.
We're gonna fix that later.
So one column, next column, next column.
But of course this is not ideal at all
because we probably want some margin here
between these columns now, right?
Because the columns there are basically now
no longer columns but just like sub-rows.
So each of these here should probably
have a margin at the bottom.
Now, I also have some space here on the right side.
I'm not really sure why that is happening.
So let's take a look at that.
Ah, it's because of the row.
I'm not sure what's going on.
Let's take a look.
Oh, the row has a margin-right of six rem.
Why is that?
Ah, of course, this should be margin-bottom,
not margin-right.
So margin-bottom, we had it here
and then we changed it with the media query.
Okay, what I was saying is that here,
the columns, they no longer should have a margin-right.
So we change that.
But they should have a margin at the bottom.
I would say it would make sense
to make it gutter-vertical-small as well,
because now it's actually vertically aligned
and no longer horizontal.
Let's take a look at that now.
While it doesn't look ideal for now
because this is way too wide, of course,
the row and the columns itself,
they look better now than they did before.
And the same thing here, of course.
We now have to change some more here about the row,
but the distance between them looks okay for now.
So what we should do here is to also change
this max-width here, okay?
Right now, the row is occupying 100% of the available width
because the view port is smaller than the grid width,
which is, as you see, 114 rem.
So what max-width does is that,
if the width is lower than the grid width,
then it will simply occupy 100% of its available width.
But we should now actually change that to a smaller value.
Let's put it to something like 50 rem or something.
Max-width: 50rem, and it will probably fix this problem.
Yeah.
That looks a lot more natural now.
All right.
That looks kind of good already.
Not perfect, of course, but acceptable.
So let's take a look at how this will look
on an iPad, for example.
Here is a problem, of course.
But we're gonna fix this one
when we start looking at the individual components.
Right now we're still talking about the width
and/or the layout of the page.
But this looks okay.
So I think for the grid, we're good to go for now.
And the smaller, minor things,
we're going to fix them later down the road.
Next up, let's talk about the header.
Well, the only thing that I see really happening here
is maybe this line here.
It's becoming way too, like, way too steep.
So in comparison to this one here which has this slope,
then this one here has a really higher slope.
And it doesn't look really good any more.
This was the initial look we were looking for,
something like this.
But now, as we really decrease the screen,
especially moving on here to the mobile screen,
then it starts looking a bit weird.
So let's change that now for the phone only.
So closing the grid here
and moving on to the header, so right here.
Include respond(phone).
And then so what we have to change
is these clip-path's here.
I'm gonna change them to 90 vh.
That will probably fix that problem.
So here we go.
Well, maybe 90 is even a bit too much.
Let's put it to 85.
The same thing here as well.
And yeah, that looks pretty good.
At 620, it's like this and then, bam!
There it goes.
The next media query, and our change is there.
Now, another thing that we should probably change
is this navigation here.
It looks a bit too much now here
moving into the center of the stage.
Let's put it a bit more here, up in the corner,
in order to make it look more similar here to this image.
Let's do that and open the navigation.
What we have to change here is the button.
Include respond, and then let's actually take a look
at where we want to change this.
I think it starts appearing even before.
Yeah, so I think we should already start it here,
closer to the 900 pixel media query,
because it starts looking off already here at this point.
So, tablet port.
So we have six rem here for both the top and the right.
Let's decrease that by two
and put it to four in these two.
And then the same thing here, for the background.
Well, I don't know what this is doing here.
So let's remove it.
Also decreasing it by two makes it 4.5 and 4.5.
So sorry, double cursors here, .5 on both.
Take a look.
Oh yeah, that's much better.
And for a phone, it's good as well.
So we don't need a new media query here.
Well, actually we could do a new media query.
Why not?
Let's take a look at how it will look
at an iPhone 5, for example.
For now, maybe just ignore that this is happening here.
I'm not really sure why.
I mean this white space here.
Well, it looks like it's because of this element here,
probably moving out of the page.
So this is why this weird white stripe here
is happening on the side.
Anyway, we can see that this is quite
not really good on the phone.
So let's simply add another query for the phone here.
Let's say three, three,
and then the same thing over here.
So yeah, now we're good.
We have to change it to responsive
and then we can click here
in order to move across our view ports.
So navigation looks better now.
Actually, let's open it.
And as you can see, it looks pretty good
without even changing a thing, even on these smaller sizes.
So everything's fine, everything's good.
The header looks good as well now.
So now let's take a look at the footer,
which is the final layout part which we have here.
So we see now that probably we should make these
100% as well, such as the columns,
and then probably center all of this on the page.
We can decrease the space here as well a little bit
and maybe even this padding.
Yeah, so there's a couple of things to change here.
So let's do that.
The first thing that we wanna change
is the padding, as I was saying.
Include respond, and I'm gonna make it
for the tablet in portrait again.
You see that this is probably the most important break point
we've been working on, along with the phone actually.
So this tablet in landscape is not really
such an important break point from my experience.
The most important one is this tablet in portrait,
so 900 pixels, and the phone at 600 pixels.
For the tablet in landscape mode,
well, the most important change, we already did it
by doing this.
In here we basically decreased the entire page.
We zoomed it down.
And that was already enough to make it looking good
for width up until 1,200 pixels, so between 900 and 1,200.
Now, let's change the padding here then
to a bit like eight ram and zero, for example.
Then what we should change next is the navigation.
Because remember, let's just take a look at the HTML
so that we're on the same page here.
The footer_navigation and the footer_copyright
are these two elements that are basically side by side.
So these are the ones we should manipulate right now.
Let's say we want the width of 100% on this one,
and a text-align set to center.
Let's see what that looks like.
And yeah, that's much better already.
But still not quite what we want
because this line should probably not go
all the way until here.
But let's take care of that in a second.
For now, let's change this one here as well.
That is the copyright.
We also want the width to be 80%.
And then we don't want any float here.
So float: none, right?
Okay, and that looks better.
But it's, again, still not perfect.
That is because there is one thing that we should do
and we haven't done up until this point,
which is basically setting a padding for the row.
'Cause remember, these two are in a row, right?
So these two are the columns
and they are inside of this row.
And this row here, it has a width of 50 rem.
That's probably way more than the width here
at this view port size.
And that's why we're simply having 100% of the width.
We can also observe the same thing going on in here.
So we should probably have some padding on this width.
Sorry, on the row.
So a padding on the row is what we should have.
On the left and on the right side.
Let's go back to the grid.
And you'll see that this going a bit back and forth
between different stuff.
But, well, that's just how it goes.
Writing media queries is maybe not the most fun thing to do,
but we still have to do it, of course.
And it's not so bad in my opinion, actually.
So we were saying that we want a padding on the row.
So this here is the place where we should do it.
So padding, top and bottom, is zero.
But we want it on the sides.
Let's put, like, some three rems here
and take a look at that.
All right.
That's better, right?
That's much, much better, actually.
Well, something weird, ah, yeah, okay.
We have this scrolling going on still.
The page is right now larger than the screen
and so there is something that we will have to fix
a bit later once again.
For now let's just continue with our media queries
and then see what's happening a bit later.
We will do that in the next lecture, so stay tuned.