So we talked about layout types.
Now let's actually go build a float layout.
In order to do so,
you will learn how to build your very own simple float grid
that you can use on a small webpage like this.
In this lecture, you're actually gonna learn
a bunch of new stuff.
Firstly, how we should architect and build
a simple grid system.
In order to do that,
you'll learn how the attribute selector works,
how the powerful not pseudo-class works in CSS,
and how the calc function works,
and also what's the difference
between calc and simple Sass mathematical operations.
A lot for one lecture,
so let's get our hands dirty now.
Now before we start, what is a grid actually?
A grid is just a design system
which allows us to build consistent interfaces.
This kind of grid will allow us
to divide our available space
into two equal parts and three equal parts
or in four equal parts or even something like this
with 1/3 on one side and 2/3s on the other side.
This leads to way more consistent designs.
Now it's really become like a standard
in web design, so everyone really uses a grid like this.
You also see that there is a consistent space here
between all of these columns
so we always have this space here.
We just call it the gutter actually.
Once again, the grid is designed
to allow us to build consistent interfaces.
Here you can see all the different elements
that we're gonna have in our very small grid.
So we have one configuration with two columns here,
then we will have a configuration with three columns
like these ones here, and then one configuration
with four columns, okay?
Now if you wanted to do more like five, six, eight,
10, 12, or even more,
then the logic that we use here for these columns
is the same like extending it to even more columns.
But for this example and for this project,
four different columns is more than enough.
Now in the three-column configuration,
we also have this column here
which actually spends over two of the single columns,
so you see, this one here spans over these two, right?
And so we could then put 1/3 on this side
and 2/3s on the other side
if that's a layout that we want to build.
And then for the four-column configuration down here,
we have one column that spans over two of these,
so this one here spans over these two basically
in case you need a layout like that.
For example, one, one, two,
or you could have two, one, and then one again,
so to have a bigger column in the middle like this one.
And then finally, we also have a column
which spans over three of the individual columns here
which is this one.
So these are all different configurations.
Now the columns, they always should be in a container,
and this container is what we call a row.
This one here is a row for these two columns,
then here is a row for these three columns.
This one is a row for these two columns,
and so on and so forth.
So all columns that are, let's say, in a line,
they are in one row always, okay?
So we have to build rows and columns.
Let's now code up this grid system here, okay?
This shouldn't be all too hard.
There's actually a lot of advanced CSS involved here
but I'm sure you're gonna master that, right?
For now, let's see if our page is actually still working,
and you see something is strange here,
so let's check what's wrong.
And as suspected,
it's actually once again here some problem,
and yeah, that's right,
so something here went wrong again.
Let me close this,
and open a new tab, and restart the process, so npm run
compile.css.
I think that's the name of the.
Let's take a look.
Compile.sass, okay.
Then we need to make some change.
Okay.
Now it run.
And okay.
So everything looks normal, okay.
Now before we actually start writing the CSS,
let's start by writing the HTML markup
to have something similar to this, okay?
But this is of course only for testing purposes.
We don't want anything here like this on our webpage, right?
So starting then with the HTML,
let's put it here after the header, okay?
Let's just put a section here
just to test our grid, okay?
Class, grid-test, okay?
Now in here, we're gonna have a couple of rows, of course.
So div class row,
and then these columns.
So the first type of columns,
I'm gonna call it col-1-of-2.
And that's the text I'm gonna put in there
so that we can nicely see what we're actually talking about.
And then the second column.
So these two here will basically become these two
later when we have the CSS in place.
And now let's make this part here.
So as I was saying, these columns are always in a row, okay?
And so these are gonna be called 1-of-3, 1-of-3,
and then of course we're gonna have three as well.
So I was missing this part here.
So col-1-of-3.
And now we also have this one here, right?
So a column two of three,
which spans over these two here.
So another row, of course.
And again, this is just for testing purposes.
We're not gonna have this one here in our design.
So two, and then here, two.
So you see the logic?
This one is a one part of a three-part grid,
and this here is basically two parts
of the three-part grid, okay?
So this one here.
And now finally the last one.
Actually let me copy this one
'cause it's more similar already to what we have.
Just copy this one,
and then I use this trick where I select all the three's
by hitting Command + D.
And four, okay?
And now all we have to do
is to make this line here and this line.
So this is a one of two,
and this is a three of four.
Actually this is two of four.
Of course.
Sorry for the mistake.
So column two of four.
And so one plus one plus two makes the four, right?
And then finally the last one
where we have three.
So one plus three makes the total of four.
So this is our HTML markup
so that we can test our classes.
So we're now ready to go to work with our CSS.
And as you can probably guess,
we are gonna make a whole new Sass file
to build this grid, okay?
And since this is actually a layout part,
so part of the layout,
we will put it in the layout folder.
So we do a new partial here, S-A-S-S,
and then we import it here of course
in the main file.
All right.
So starting with the row.
First off, we need to define a width for the row.
And one of the standards that is used these days
is to make it 1,140-pixels grid, okay?
So width,
1,140 pixels.
Now what's wrong with this?
I'm sure that you guessed it.
That's right.
We want to use rems, not pixels,
and so all we have to do is to divide this number by 10
because we already know
that 10 pixels equals one rem, right?
So 114 rem but it's still not perfect
because what we actually want is not width but max-width.
What's the difference between width and max-width?
Now let me actually show it to you in here.
So the max-width of this is 114 pixels, right?
Now decrease the screen like this,
then you will see that everything starts to adapt
to the width of the screen.
So what max mean.
Oh (laughs) sorry.
So max-width means
is that if we have enough available space,
then it will have the width that we specified
but if there is not enough width,
so basically if the viewport is smaller
than width that we specified here,
so in this case, if the viewport is smaller than 114 rem,
then it will simply fill 100% of the available space
that it has, okay?
Let's actually give it some kind of background color
just so that we can see what's going on.
So background-color.
I'm gonna give it a nice gray here.
Okay.
And the last thing we want to do
is to always center this row in the viewport.
So how do we do that?
And probably you already know the trick, right?
So what we do is margin, zero, and auto.
That's the trick that everyone uses to center block elements
inside of another block element.
So we say that the margin on top and of the bottom is zero,
and left and right is auto.
Why does that actually work?
When we say that we want the margin to be automatically,
this means that the browser, when rendering the page,
will automatically figure out the margin
that we want on the left and on the right side, right?
And since it's both set to auto,
it means that left and right will be the same,
and CSS will automatically calculate the left margin
and the right margin, and they will be the same,
and so of course, the element will be centered,
so that's the simple logic behind this.
And let's now actually ours, our page.
Something is not working again.
Let me check out what's going.
Again, this error here, okay?
So let me run it again.
I should probably change the autosave function
in my code editor.
I'm gonna do that later.
All right.
Now here we go.
So we have our column with this nice width,
and it's also centered in the browser, so perfect.
Let's just inspect it so we can see.
All right.
So up there, you see that's actually 1,140 pixels wide.
Now one last thing that we should also do about these rows
is that we should have some space,
some gutter between these rows.
So imagine we have a layout,
and then we have multiple rows,
and we naturally want some space between them, right?
So let's take care of that.
And so we say
margin-bottom of, let's say, 80 pixels.
Now these values that we're specifying here
like this max-width and these margins,
they are great candidates for specifying a variable
so that we have one place in the variable files
where we can easily change all of these values
by simply changing one variable.
Let's actually do that
by opening this file.
And now starting to organize this a bit.
Let's put some comments here.
So these are colors, okay?
And now down here, we will have variables for our grid.
So let's say grid-width.
So remember, 114 rem.
If one day in the future, we want to change this,
we don't have to search through all the files,
we simply can change it here in the variables file, okay?
And now I will specify a variable called gutter-vertical,
and set it to the 80 pixels that we had before,
which is equivalent to eight rem.
Since we're at it, I can also specify
the horizontal gutter, right?
And I will set this to 60 pixels, so six rem.
And the horizontal gutter is of course,
it's these spaces here in-between the columns.
This is even better to have as a variable
because once we start specifying
these gutters and these columns,
we will use this value over and over again,
and so this is a perfect candidate for a Sass variable.
Okay.
Let's now just go ahead and actually use these.
It's grid-width.
And then here,
it's a gutter-vertical.
All right.
Let's check it out.
Yep.
Here we go.
Actually I'll show you something
because you see, this is the last row here, okay?
So between all these rows, we have a margin,
and then also of course the last one.
Now this doesn't make much sense, okay?
So we want the last one not to have a margin in the bottom,
so let's simply remove that,
and I'm sure you know a good way of doing that.
So what would that way be?
It would simply to use the last child pseudo-class,
and then set the margin-bottom to zero on that one, right?
But we can do even better,
and what I mean is to use the not pseudo selector.
Let me show you how it works.
We can use it on the row.
You already know by now
that you can use the ampersand operator,
and then we set the not pseudo-class.
So we have row, not.
Of course, let me just show it to you again
just to make sure we're on the same page here.
So this is what we have here, right?
So row, not.
Now what we can do here
is to specify another pseudo-class in here.
Let me first show it to you and then explain it.
So last-child.
Now let's duplicate here, okay?
All right.
So what does this not here actually do?
Now without the not,
this would simply select the last child, right?
So if we add this, last-child,
then we would simply select the last child,
so the last row element.
Now what the not does here
is that it simply does the opposite,
so we select everything except the last child.
It's basically just the opposite.
Instead of selecting the last child,
we select everything except the last child, right?
And so what we can do now
is to simply put this margin-bottom in here, and that's it.
So now instead of setting the vertical gutter here,
this 80 pixels on all of these rows,
we put it on all the rows except the last child.
This is what the not here does,
everything except the last child, okay?
Does that make sense?
So another very powerful pseudo-class
that you just learned here.
Let's check it out,
and indeed, it is now gone.
Really cool.
And you see it apply here.
At least you should see.
It should be somewhere here.
It's actually not.
Of course, it's not.
It is in these ones here.
Okay.
So here you have row, not, last-child, margin-bottom.
So these ones, of course, have the margin-bottom,
and then only this last one
does not have that declaration block.
All right.
Cool.
Now we're ready to work on the columns.
Let's start with the very first column
which is the column one of two, okay?
And since we always have these columns inside of rows,
we can actually nest it here
inside of the row selector, right?
So col-1-of-2.
And so this will translate to a column
which is always inside of a row.
Okay.
And so now how do we actually define
the width of this column?
Let's take a look here at the example.
What is the width of this column here?
It is very simply the entire width of this row
minus this gutter, this space here
divided by two.
So again, this entire space here
ranging from the left side
all the way to the right side here is 100%, okay?
If we then subtract this gutter space here,
we end up with the entire space
that these two columns can occupy.
If we then divide that in two parts,
we end up with a width of one of the columns, okay?
That's exactly what we want.
Let's do that in CSS.
Now how do we actually do these calculations?
In CSS, there is an extremely powerful function
which is called calc.
In here, you can do mathematical operations,
and you can actually mix units in here.
That's really important.
It's a huge advantage.
Again, this allows us to make calculations
where we can mix units.
That's a big difference
between doing native CSS calculations or doing them in Sass
because in Sass, we can also do operations of course
but we cannot do them with multiple units,
so we cannot for example
mix rem with pixels, with percentages.
It's actually pretty logical why it is that way.
It is so because we compile our Sass file
while we're developing the page,
so even before the page is served of course to the user
but this kind of calculation all depends on the layout,
so it has to happen while the website is rendered
using the visual formatting model.
That's when these calculations can occur
because it's only then when CSS and when the browser
knows what the percentage is, what the rem is,
and what all of that stuff is, okay?
So we have to do it using the native calc functions.
Let's now translate what we were saying earlier.
So we have 100% of the width.
From that, we subtract the gutter.
So the gutter that we have
is called gutter-horizontal, remember?
And then we simply have to divide all of this into parts.
If you know any math,
we have to put these parentheses here
so that it first does these calculations,
so that it first does this calculation here.
100 minus the gutter, okay?
So we put it into parentheses
so that this operation happens first,
and then the result of that will be divided by two.
Okay.
But that's actually not enough to make this working
because in the calc function of CSS,
if you want to use a Sass variable,
we have to actually do this little thing.
We have to use the hash,
and then wrap it into these curly braces, okay?
And with this, it will actually work.
Okay.
Let's now give this a background color so we can see it.
Let's use orange red here just for exemplification.
Then of course, we also want to actually see
the gutter, right?
So we want the margin on the right side of the column,
which will then be the gutter.
Now remember that there is only one gutter here, right?
So on the case of the one, two column,
it's only in the first one.
So this gutter here will be the right margin
of this first column here.
And then when we do these columns here,
then this gutter will be the right margin of this column,
and this gutter will be the right margin of this column,
and so we always want the right margin
to be on all of the columns except the last one,
and that's exactly what we did with the row before, right?
Let's now do that.
Once again, we can use the not pseudo-class.
Then in here, we can use the last-child.
So margin-right, and gutter-horizontal.
All right.
And so our columns also have a gutter now,
so a margin-right.
Now only one thing left.
Since we're using a float layout here,
of course we need to float these columns.
So we use float, left.
We always float all these columns to the left side.
Like this, we are ready to actually take a look
at our result.
Yeah.
Wow, it's actually working already.
So our first column, our gutter, and our second column.
Let's actually inspect this one.
Here you have the margin-right of six rem,
which is the horizontal gutter that we defined,
and here we saw the selector that we built.
So the column one of two,
which is inside of a row element,
and then not the last child, right?
Okay.
Now just one thing that I want to show you
is that this row here has a zero-pixel height,
and I'm sure you know why that happens,
and it is because all of the child elements
of this row element are floated,
and so the height collapses and becomes zero.
What do we do against that?
That's right.
We use the clearfix hack.
We already did that once actually
in our initial Sass lectures.
Let's do that again.
Remember that by then, we used a Sass mixin, right?
So a reusable piece of code that we could then add here
to this row declaration block.
Let me show you again how it works.
Let's write our first mixin here in the mixins file.
So a mixin always starts with us writing mixin
and the name of the mixin which is clearfix in this case.
Clearfix.
What do we want this clearfix to actually do?
How does a clearfix actually work?
What the clearfix does is to append a pseudo element
after the element which will then clear these floats.
What we can do is to use the ampersand operator
and then after, all right?
We're gonna include this mixin in our grid.
It will then simply copy this code here,
and so this ampersand, if we're writing in a mixin then
will transform to row,
so it will then be something like this
just to show it to you,
after, and then all the code that are in the right.
Let's do that.
How does a clearfix work?
Again, we always need to specify the content property,
otherwise a pseudo element will simply not appear
on the page, and we want it empty
because we don't want to see this element on the page.
Then we also need to display it.
The way it's done is to use the table value in here.
That's simply the standard version of the clearfix,
so display, table,
and then finally the property that actually performs
this clearfix is the clear property.
This would clear both floats,
so float left and float right
so that it's gonna work
no matter if we use float left or float right.
That's actually it.
All right.
Let's now include the mixin in here.
Let me actually put it here before these columns.
Include
clearfix.
That should do the trick.
Let's check it out.
Yeah, I think this looks different.
Yeah, here we go.
So our row now has again a complete height
with 17 pixels in this case.
So we cleared the float.
We already have the one of two columns nicely set up.
Let's now move on to the next type of columns.
All we have to do in order to finish this lecture
is now code up all of these different columns,
which shouldn't be all too hard, okay?
Let's now do that.
Let's start with col-1-of-3.
How is the width going to work this time?
Let us take a look actually, okay?
It's actually pretty similar to what we had before.
So we have 100%, and if we subtract
this gutter and this gutter,
and then divide the result by a three
because now we have three columns,
then we end up with the width of one of the columns, right?
So it's very similar to the one that we had before.
And so let's do that.
So 100%
minus,
and now two times the gutter-horizontal.
And here this part is missing.
And now divide this result by a three because this time,
we have of course three columns, all right?
And now this stuff here is actually the same.
Now of course, I should not simply copy this code here
into this column, right?
Really against the don't repeat yourself practice, okay?
And we're also not gonna do
one of the solutions that I mentioned earlier,
something like a mixin or something like that.
That also doesn't make much sense here.
Instead we want to do
is to basically select all of the columns at the same time,
and then apply these styles to all of these columns.
Let me show that I think is the best way to do that.
For that, we're gonna use the attribute selector, okay?
Let's do that here.
We could of course go ahead and add a new class
to all of these columns.
So we could add something like simply col,
and then select that,
and then have a specific style only for col-1-of-4
but that again would be a bit too much I think.
I prefer to use the selector that I'm gonna show you,
which is the attribute selector.
We start with the brackets.
Select this.
And then in here, we can specify an attribute.
For example, we could put src if we wanted.
Just an example.
Src is an attribute of the image.
Let's see.
For example, this image has the src of img/logo-white.
And so we could now select all of the elements
that have this exact src,
or we could also select by alt.
So we could say something like alt, logo.
Actually let's do that.
So we could do something like this,
and this would basically select all of the elements,
which have this alt attribute equal to logo.
Now in this case, that's not what we want at all obviously.
What we want is to select
based on class.
Now why do we select based on class
if we could simply do it with a dot, right?
But let me show you because what we can do also here
is to not just select equal
but we can do something like this.
For example, this symbol here
means that we want the beginning to be what we set here.
So let's set this one to col dash, and that is it.
What does this do?
It will select all of the elements
in which the class attribute starts,
and that's what this symbol here means.
So where all the class attribute start with col.
That is exactly our case, right?
So we have all the columns starting with col dash,
so col dash one and one,
and you see all of these are selected.
And so this is a nice way to select all of the columns
at the same time.
Again, the magic happens actually here with this symbol.
This allows us to select only the ones
that start with col dash.
Now we can use other symbols here,
so other selectors here as well.
Instead of this, we could have the asterisk,
and what this would mean is that select any classes,
which contain this part col, okay?
But that's not what we want
because this could lead to some mistakes maybe.
We only really want the ones that start with col.
Actually there is another one.
You could put this sign here,
so like the dollar sign,
and then it would mean any class that ends with col dash.
So we can do start with col,
end with col, or simply contain col, okay?
But what we want here is this.
Now there are a lot of applications for this selector here.
For example, we could also select links
based on a specific href attribute,
or we could also select anchor elements,
which have the target attribute set to blank,
so these are the links that open in a new tab
when we click them, and we could then style
these ones differently than the regular links.
And so there is a whole lot of applications
for this kind of selector, so keep this one in mind
when you start building your own pages.
Now what we really wanted to do here
is to actually pass all of this in here, right?
Now all of the classes that we have
will have this float property set to left
so that will be floated to left,
and also they will have their right margins set
to this gutter that we specified
but only all except the last one,
which is what this not does here.
All right.
If we now check out.
Here we go.
Our one of three columns are now also working.
And you see that already it's styled these remaining columns
with the color that we specified
and also with the gutter, right?
So all we have to really do next
is to specify their width, okay?
Now just to show you.
Let me show you for example.
So here is that selector that we just wrote before.
So it selects first the row,
and then in there, all the elements with the class
starting with col dash,
and so you saw that this really worked.
Okay.
Let's continue with the one of four.
And then in the end, we will do the intermediate ones,
two of three and the other ones as well.
How is this one gonna work?
Again, very similar to the other ones.
This time, we have three gutters of course,
and then we simply divide it by four
because we have four columns.
Very simple, right?
And so you see that it's already working in here.
Now we have to do is to specify
this, this, and these remaining columns.
Let's actually copy this.
Two of three.
Now it actually gets a bit more complicated.
What is the width of this kind of column?
Let's check it out here in our example, okay?
What is the width of this column?
Can you see it?
It actually is easy to see it up here.
The width of this column is the width of the normal columns
of the one of three column
plus another of these columns.
So two times this column plus the gutter.
That's actually it.
All we have to do is now translate this to code.
Again, the width of this column
is this one plus this one plus the gutter.
Let's do that.
What we have here already
is actually the width of one of the columns, right?
So let's simply wrap that in parentheses.
All right.
And multiply it by two.
So two times the width of the simple column
plus the gutter width.
That should be it.
Again, we simply multiplied two times the width
of the single one of three column.
So this one here, you multiply it by two,
and then add the gutter width,
which is exactly what we discussed a bit earlier.
Let's take a look.
Something is not really working here.
Let's take a look at what's happening.
Now something is not right.
I see.
Okay.
Of course, I misspelled this word here.
It's not width, it's of course horizontal.
Okay?
Sorry about that one.
Now of course it's working.
So this column plus this column plus this gutter
makes this column here.
Let's do now the same thing for the col-2-of-4
but actually it's the same.
So one of four plus one of four plus this gutter
will make this two of four column.
All right?
Let's do that.
So col-2-of-4.
Let's have two times,
open parenthesis and then close them here.
Always be careful with the parentheses.
And then we simply add the gutter again.
Let's just copy it
so that I don't make the same mistake again.
Yeah, let's check it out.
Here we go.
Everything is working.
Now there is only one left, which is the three of four.
The logic now is actually pretty similar.
The three of four is the same as having this column
plus this one plus this one
plus this gutter and this gutter, okay?
So three times the one of four column
but two times the gutter.
Let's just copy all of this.
Three.
In here, remember we multiplied by three now,
and then two times the gutter.
That's it.
Indeed, it is now working just fine.
With this, we actually already have
our grid system in place,
meaning that we are now ready to use it
in the rest of the project.
Now I know that this math that we did can seem a bit scary
but once you understand it, it's really no problem.
Since you now know how to do it,
you can simply copy it for next time,
so for the next project and then use it.
It's way better to use your own stuff,
at least that's my opinion,
and know exactly how it works and what you're doing
instead of always relying
on some third-party external stuff.
At least that is my opinion.
Now if you think that this gutter
is maybe too large or too small,
then again if you have another project
with some other requirements,
you can very simply come here and change it.
For example, imagine we want a bigger gutter.
All we have to do is to increase it.
Now we see the gutter is really huge.
Or if it's too big, then you can just put it
to something really small like two.
You can come here and you have smaller gutters.
That is the power of CSS variables,
changing one value in one place,
and then it takes effect on the entire page
everywhere where you used this variable, okay?
Our grid system is now in place.
Let's just hide this CSS here from our page
because we don't really want to see this, right?
So HTML comments, they work like this,
and now at the end,
we just close them like this.
That's it.
Now we commented out our code.
So each time that we want to now use one of these columns
or one of these rows with the columns inside,
we can come here and copy them
and just use our grid as we intended.
All right.
This was essentially in order to move on,
and also for you on the way to becoming
a more advanced CSS developer.
Now you really know how grids are configured
and how they work and you could easily build your own.