This is the second part
of building the features section.
This is where we left off after the last lecture.
Now it's time to actually style these icons, this heading,
and the paragraph.
After we're done doing that,
we will then lay them out here in this way.
So the icon here on this side,
and then these two, one after the other, okay?
But let's start by styling these three.
We have the icon, and the text,
and then the heading separately.
So we have features,
and then we have the feature.
This feature component here would, in theory,
be reusable in another page.
So it's completely independent from the features class.
But I still put them in the same file though
because they are closely related.
Having these classes in different files
would make me jump around a lot through the different files.
That would be terrible for recording videos like this.
Basically each of the section now got its own file.
And then there, I have the overall element,
which is like the container of these components.
But again, this feature here would be completely reusable
somewhere else later on the page,
or if I had another page on my website.
Let's style the icon,
and then let's also style the text.
Actually let's start with the text.
Let's set the font size to 1.7 rem.
That's it.
Actually we don't have to do anything else,
just increasing the font size here a bit.
Then as for the icon, let's change the color.
Remember how we do that with SVG icons.
What we have to do is to use the fill property,
and then we use the primary color, color-primary.
That's our golden color here again.
And then finally, let's just size it.
You want a width of 45 pixels or 4.5 rem,
and then the same for the height.
That's usually the same.
Now finally, we also want to style the heading-4.
That's gonna be in the typography file.
Heading-4.
We will then also later have
the heading one, two, three, and four.
Let me actually do all of them here.
Why not?
One,
two,
three, and then four here.
All right.
We want them to have the font family
that I mentioned before, which is this one here.
Sorry.
Now I closed it.
We want the font-display.
It's Josefin Sans.
That's the one that we're gonna use for all of the headings.
It is font-display.
We also want the font-weight to be 400.
Remember, we actually included that font-weight
in the HTML from Google Fonts.
Now we actually want all of these
to have these two properties.
That's a perfect use case for a CSS extend.
We can do like this placeholder
that I showed you a long time ago, I think.
We haven't really used it since then.
But now it's a good time to use it again.
Use this placeholder, which I'm simply gonna call heading.
Then I put this here.
Now all I have to do is to extend all of these
like this.
I say extend and heading.
That's it.
What's gonna happen now
is that basically this heading-1 here is copied
aligned to this place here.
Let's copy this all over the place here.
What's gonna happen now,
it's like as if this heading-1, heading-2, heading-3,
and heading-4 will be copied here to this selector.
It's not a mixin because a mixin works the other way around.
The mixin, this code here will then be paste
into each of the selectors.
An extend works the other way around.
Basically the selectors are copied into a huge selector,
which then makes this code here apply to all of them.
Anyway, we were talking about the heading-4.
Here the font size, we want it to be 1.9 rem.
Now remember that I told you
that we want to use this heading-4
in different situations throughout the page.
We want to use it here on these features,
but also this one is an H4 as well.
You see that this one is white,
and this one is dark.
That's actually do that with a modifier class.
Let's add a modifier class.
One for light.
And the color here is gonna be grey-light-1.
And then we will have dark, and that's gonna be grey-dark-1.
Actually it's here.
All right.
Let's just duplicate this.
This one is for dark.
Now we of course have to add this to the HTML as well.
Let's add multiple cursors here in each of them,
so we don't have to write it once.
Heading-4.
This one is a dark version.
The modifier is with these two dashes.
All right.
Let's check it out in our page.
That already looks quite good.
This icon here has the correct size.
All of this looks just like we have it here.
Now all we have to do is to actually align these elements
like we have it here.
How are we gonna do that?
Once again, we are going to use a CSS grid here.
Because why not?
This is just a small component,
and we actually a two-dimensional layout here.
Let's take a look.
This is actually two dimensions.
We have the row axis and the column axis.
It's really a two-dimensional.
Why not use a CSS grid for doing that?
We will have a two-by-two grid.
Let me show it to you here actually already.
That's not the one.
That's the one.
We're gonna have this two-by-two grid.
And then in there, we will place the three elements.
Does that make sense?
Typography is done for now.
This feature here, which itself is a grid item of course,
will now also become a grid container.
So we have a grid inside a grid inside a grid.
Just like we had in flexbox,
we can really nest the grids really deep.
Display, grid.
Let's start by defining the columns,
grid-template-columns.
What width do we want to have for the first column?
The first column will contain the icon.
We already know the width of the icon, so it's 4.5 rem.
In this column here, we could simply put 4.5 rem as well.
But instead of doing that, we will simply put auto,
or we could use min-content or max-content.
Let's actually use min-content.
Why not?
Because this way,
if we eventually wanted to change
the width here of the icon,
then automatically the width of this column would adjust
without us having to change anything.
And then the rest of the grid.
The second column will simply occupy the rest.
Okay.
Simple as that.
Makes sense?
Now as for the rows,
again we don't really need to specify them
because all we want to happen is them to be the size
of the content.
Once more, we don't really define them.
Probably you start to see this emerging as a trend.
Many times, we don't really define the row,
we just define the columns.
In a real world scenario,
that's actually many times the case.
Many times, we just want the content to define the rows.
In that case, it's not really necessary to define the rows.
We will have other cases where we will define the rows.
You're gonna see that later.
But for now, it's good like this.
It works perfectly fine like this.
Let's check it out.
We'll see that it's actually
not really perfect yet, okay? (laughs)
Let's check out what's happening here.
Let's inspect this.
Here you see all four grid cells.
The first one is actually larger, much larger
than the icon, and that's because right now,
we only have three elements in this grid.
So the third one of course,
because of the auto-placement algorithm,
gets placed here under this icon.
What we could do here
is to place this grid item here in this grid cell.
But actually what's even better
is to make this grid cell here
span all the way here until the end,
so that we end up with this grid area here for this icon
because right now,
this row here is also as high as this icon,
but actually we do not want it to be as large,
as high as this text here.
If we had all of this column here,
these two rows for this icon,
then that would actually happen perfectly fine.
Let me show that to you.
The icon, we want it to have the grid-row property
set to start at number one
all the way to the end, or span two.
In this case, it's really the same.
We could just add minus one,
and then we're sure that it goes all the way until the end.
Automatically now, the text should get placed here
to the end.
For some reason, that didn't really happen.
This is actually a good opportunity
to tell you something important
that I didn't tell you yet, I think.
This minus one here, this means not the end of the grid
but the end of the explicit grid, okay?
This would be the last explicit grid line.
But we didn't really define any grid rows,
so there is not really an explicit grid.
This minus one here doesn't make much sense.
Instead of just minus one, we should simply add span two.
Makes sense?
Again, the minus one only works with an explicit grid,
but we had an implicit grid
because we didn't define the row,
so it didn't work as expected.
Right now it does.
Let's inspect it here as well.
It doesn't really highlight here the spanning going on,
but it doesn't matter because we can see it by ourselves.
Because you see that this icon here
is actually already in this second cell.
This is like all the same cell.
Actually I think if you hover it here, then you will see it.
Not really, but again, that's not a huge problem.
We're almost done here now.
What we need now is of course some spacing here.
Let's add some spacing between the columns and the rows.
That's very simple, of course.
So I'll just add a grid-row-gap.
Let's make it 1.5 rem.
And then again for the column as well, grid-column-gap.
This one is 2.5 rem, okay?
Let's check it out again.
All right.
Here we go.
That looks really good, really good already.
Just a couple of things that we need to change here.
First of all, in our demo project,
these icons here are actually a bit moved to the top.
Basically to center this, the center of the icon
here with the text.
That's just something that we have to do manually.
Let's fix that.
Very simply, you're just gonna translate
the icon a bit to the top.
Transform and translate in the Y direction,
just minus one rem.
That should fix that.
Yeah.
That looks a bit more natural now.
Our second issue is that you see in these two columns
where we only have three lines of text
that the space here is huge.
I mentioned before that I wanted to have different text
in the different elements.
That's because I wanted to show you
how we can fix exactly this issue.
Let's actually inspect it.
We want this one here now.
You can see that this row here
is larger than the row in here and in here.
Why is this happening?
It's happening because this features grid here,
which contains these six grid items,
makes it so that these grid items
that all of the grid items fill the entire cells.
That's because of the align-item's property
that is by default set to stretch.
Remember that?
Align-items is a property that controls the alignment
of grid items along grid cells.
These here are the grid items of this features grid.
Currently, this align-items property is set to stretch.
What do we do if we want all of them here
to start at the top?
Basically move all of this here to the top.
We just have to set the align-items property
on this parent container here to start.
Let's do that.
This here is the grid container.
Align-items, let's set it to start.
If we're back now, that is how it looks like.
We could maybe even give this here like a background color,
but actually that's not even necessary
because even with this inspector here,
we can see that this grid item
is now no longer the exact same of the grid cell
but just the size of its content
moved all the way to the top
just as we specify at the grid container.
Of course, we could also set this to end.
Let me show you how that would look like.
Yeah.
Then it would move these two here,
which are smaller than the other items.
It would move them simply to the end,
so to the bottom of their grid cell.
Or we could try center also.
All right.
Now it's centered but that's still not what we want.
We just want them to be at the start.
It's really important that you are aware
that all of these properties that I showed you
in the first section, so an intersection,
that all of these properties exist,
and what they do and how you can use them to your advantage
to achieve exactly what you need to achieve.
In this case, we really needed the align-items
to move all of this up to the top,
so up the column axis.
All right.
Right now, it actually looks the exact same as our demo.
There is just one small thing to fix
because when you reduce this here,
what you see is then it gets narrow and narrow
and even more narrow.
What we want to do here of course
is what I showed you in the last section,
which is basically to make this responsive
without writing a single line of media query.
That's what happens here.
As you see, at some point, the text gets smaller,
and that's because of media query,
but that's not what I'm talking about.
What happens is that at some point,
you see that it moves down here.
Instead of a three-by-two grid, we now have a two-by-three.
And then as it gets even smaller,
it does basically a one-by-six grid.
That's what we want to achieve.
That's quite simple actually
even without media queries.
Do you remember how we did that?
All we have to change here is these grid-template-columns,
and define some new column tracks,
so grid-template-columns.
Do you remember what the trick here is?
First of all, we need to use the auto-fit keyword in here.
Remember what auto-fit does?
It simply create as many tracks as can fit
based on the width that we define.
This width that we define here
will be with the minmax function.
Minmax, and we say that the width should always stay
between 25 rem and one fractional unit.
That's as simple as it.
Actually I said 25. (laughs)
Okay.
250 pixels, basically.
Again, the width of each of the tracks
should always stay between 250 rem and one fractional unit.
Based on this, CSS will add as many tracks as fit
in the container.
That's exactly what we did in one of the demo examples
in the last section.
Let's check it out if it works.
Where is the container?
Okay.
We start with the 1,120 pixels.
Let's move it down now.
Remember that each column can have up to 250 pixels.
We start decreasing, decreasing,
and then bam, you see?
At this point, it no longer could fit three columns,
so it reduced it to two columns.
Let's check it out here.
You see this feature here is 251,
which is almost the minimum size that it has to have.
You see it now?
Bam.
250.
And a bit last, we'll push it off the edge,
and bring it down to two-column tracks.
That's really amazing.
That's really great and powerful.
Now you see that it's even more important
to use this align-items set to start that I had before.
For example now here,
you have a lot of empty space down here.
It's really important
that you see that if we inspect this here,
so the size of the item is just this.
Without the align-items set to start,
it would look really weird.
This works just the way I explained before,
and everything is working.
Of course we could change this 250 pixels to something else,
but I found that it works really well
in this particular situation.
Okay.
We're actually done with this section.
We used two grids here.
One big grid, which could fit all of these six items here,
so one grid item for each feature.
And then each feature is a grid container itself,
which then itself contains these three grid items,
so the icon, this H4, and this text.
Grid allows us to nest as many grids inside of each other,
and that is very helpful to create
even very small two-dimensional layouts like this one.
We could have used like flexbox for this one here as well
but then we would have to mess with margins.
We would have added a margin to the bottom of this here,
for example, or the top of the text,
and that would have added some extra complexity
that is not really necessary if we can use CSS grid.
Grids don't only work for the big layout parts
like some people say,
but they can also be for very small components
as long as they are two-dimensional,
then it makes a lot of sense using grids for that.
Next up, we're going to build this part here.
Yeah, stay tuned for that.