Let's continue writing our media queries
right now in this video.
So, remember from the last video, where I had this
weird thing going on at the very end of the video
where it scroll, like, to the sides here?
Well, it turns out that it had nothing to do with
the media queries, but it was a bug here in the dev tools,
so all I had to do was to click here to go back to
normal state, then click it again, then everything
was back to normal, okay?
So maybe that happens to you also, and so, that is the fix.
So, just toggle this, remove the state, and then come back.
Okay, so that fixed it for me.
It had nothing to do with the media queries.
Alright.
And actually, we had not yet finished the footer here.
We wanted to decrease the space here, right?
So let's quickly do that here, in the footer.
So, it was here, at the logo box.
So, the margin bottom, let's set it to, like...
4rem only, that should be enough, why not?
Okay, maybe six.
And then we're good to go.
So, save, close, and let's now move on.
So, we took care of all of these now, of all of these
four layout components, so let's now take care
of the page itself.
So, let's take a look, actually, before we do anything.
So, that's looks good now.
And now, let's see.
So I think we have way too much space here in general, okay?
So this is too much space, this is too much,
this is too much.
And so, all of these sections, they have too much padding.
Let me see where that starts.
And yeah, I think already here, at the 900 pixel,
so at the tablet portrait mode, it already starts
to have too much padding.
Okay.
And so, let's actually remove at least part of that, okay?
So, include, respond and tab-port.
So, the section-about has 25rem.
So let's decrease that to 20 0, okay?
And yeah, that's better, okay?
The same thing here, okay.
It's definitely better as well.
And I see we also have too much space here.
So this one here is definitely too much space as well.
But let's take care of that later.
Let's continue for now with the layout of the page.
So, we removed five rem from that padding,
so let's probably do the same thing here in the features.
So, 15 in here.
Then section-tours, 25, 15.
And this is different, so this one is much larger
than this one, simply because of the fact that we have
this non-rectangular shape here, so we have to give it
a bit more space in order to look more natural.
So, let's copy this one, then remove five on each side,
such as we did before.
Okay.
Let's copy it again.
Section-stories.
Okay.
So, 10rem and 0.
And the same thing.
Here, on this one.
Well, it actually doesn't have, okay, sorry,
so this is not off the sections, this is already
part of the booking, okay?
So let's leave that one for later.
Let's take a look now.
And so, we definitely have decreased space now,
and it looks better than before.
We could probably decrease it even a bit more
for the mobile, okay, but, well, we can leave it as well.
So, 900 is this here.
Looks okay on a tablet.
Let's take a look, for example, at the iPad.
And that looks acceptable for me.
Now, iPhone 6, for example.
And...
Looks okay to me as well.
Now, remember what I told you before.
We have to test this on real devices so we have
a real impression of what stuff looks like,
but obviously, in this course, we cannot do that.
But you should definitely try it
when you build your own sites.
Now, as I was telling, let's decrease the space here
that we have there.
So, what's causing this is the...
Let me show it to you.
It's this class, more down.
So it's this margin-button-big, okay?
And it's one of the utilities, and so, of course,
we can add media queries here as well.
So, 8rem currently, so let's change that.
Let's put, like, 5rem or something like that, okay?
And now, since we're at that, let's do the same thing here
for the medium one, okay?
So let's put, like, 3rem in here.
And since these have important,
I'm gonna put it here as well.
And yeah, it's better now, it's definitely
better this way, right?
Okay, so for the layout, that's it.
Right, looks acceptable, as I was saying.
And of course, this is far from perfect,
because I'm not really 100% optimizing this webpage here.
Because it's not a project that is going to a real client,
so if you want this to be 100% real for yourself,
then you should probably go ahead and tweak this even more
and test the hell out of it, so that it becomes
really polished, but I am here just fixing
the major problems, okay?
And, well, the major problem that I see here next
is this one, okay?
So let's now move on to the next component.
Actually, it's the first component that we're working on.
And that is called the composition, okay?
And here we have to do some real major changes,
and let me actually show you how I want this to look
in the final version, so let's do something like this.
Okay, so we have, basically, the images side by side.
This one here is a bit bigger than the other two,
so it, like, scaled, and looking as if it was on the top,
but then I'll configure it in a slightly different way than
we were before, so that they don't occupy so much space.
So, let's do that.
And we need to make a lot of changes here, so starting with
the photo, of course, because that's where the image itself
is, so include respond, and let's actually see
where this starts to look really bad, like this.
And we see, okay, that it's happening...
Again, at the 900-pixel range here,
so at the tablet portrait, okay?
So tab-port, okay?
So what are we going to do with these?
We will float them side-by-side basically.
So, float: left.
And for that to work, we need them to have
a relative position again.
Because, remember up here, we have an absolute positioning,
but we're now getting rid of that, okay?
Also, I want the width to be the same for all,
so 33.33333%,
and then I also want them to have a slightly less
pronounced shadow, let's see.
So, like, only three for the blur, not like this,
and then here, just 20% for the black color, okay?
And then I also have to undo some of this stuff that is here
on each of these elements, so let's do that.
So top, set it to zero.
And then some changes down here as well.
So, top to zero here as well.
And then, what do we have here?
We have left 20%, we don't want anything like that.
Left: 0.
And actually, let me go to top: 0 back here.
Now, remember that we had some of them scale up a bit,
so let's take a look before we start that.
Alright, so now they are nicely sitting side-by-side.
That's a lot better than what we had before already.
But let's now, in order to make this a bit more creative,
let's just slightly scale this one up,
and this one here as well.
Or, actually, all of them, why not?
So, the one in the middle can be the biggest one.
This one slightly smaller than this here.
Even smaller than that.
Now, another thing that we can do is to put some top here.
So, 1rem instead of zero that we had.
So, to move this one down a bit,
and then move this one up a bit.
So, -1rem.
So, take a look at that now.
Well, that doesn't look okay, so looks like transform
didn't really apply.
Transform: translate.
And, of course, that's not what I wanted at all.
I wanted scale.
Stupid mistake, again.
And, no, that looks a bit better than before.
Now, all we have to change is to put this one here
on the top, so let's give it a higher Z index
than the rest of them.
Let's say just 100.
Alright.
And actually, this effect here still works,
but on a touch device, this is not really gonna happen
anyway, so you can just ignore that one, okay?
So, I like this section as it is right now,
so let's move on here to the next one.
And what I would change in here is maybe give it
a bit less padding and decrease this kind of spacing here,
okay, so just small adjustment, and then we should
be good to go as well.
So, composition, and where is this one,
ah, it's a feature box.
And I'm doing it in the same breakpoint again.
So include, respond, tab-port.
So, I'll slide degrees of the padding.
And then here, the margin can be actually set to zero.
Okay, so.
Just a really small adjustment.
And now, well, I think we still have too much space here,
to be honest, so let's decrease the padding that we have
in the section.
So, back to the home here.
Now down here.
So section-features.
Let's put 10 here as well.
And yeah.
I prefer it this way.
Now it looks more symmetric here, so the space between
this one here is now equal, like, the line is right
at the middle of these two sections now.
So, a lot better.
So, we're doing great progress here.
Now what we have to do next is to fix
these next three sections.
So, this one here, the tours, then we can fix
this one here, 'cause this looks really messy right now.
And then, finally, we fix the booking, alright?
But we're gonna leave that for the next lecture
so that you can take a quick break here,
and then come back to coding this last part.