Welcome back.
I hope that the last command line lecture
was not all too bad for you
because in this lecture we're actually
going to put it to use for the first time.
So in this lecture, we're gonna install SASS
on our local computer.
Now there are several ways to do this,
but I found that the easiest one is to just use
an NMP package called Node SASS.
So now you're probably wondering,
what is NMP and what the hell is an NMP package, right?
And that's great.
So let me know introduce you to a whole new world
of front end web development in case you haven't used it
up until this point.
And what I'm talking about is the huge Node JS
and NMP package ecosystem
where you can find all kinds of open source tools
and libraries and frame works needed
for modern web development.
In one of these packages is a package to compile SASS
which we're about to use.
So it all starts with Node JS which is an open source
JavaScript run time that allows developers
to write and run JavaScript application on the server.
Now after some time, developers started using Node
to also write tools like for task automations,
or again to compile SASS to help them
with local web development.
And that's what we're focusing on in this course.
Not the part about writing JavaScript
on the server of course.
Now in order to use and share these packages
we need some kind of tool to install and to manage them.
And that's where the Node package manager, or NMP comes in.
So NMP is basically just a very simple command line
program that allows us to do exactly that.
Plus NMP also allows us to do some automations
of boring tasks.
But more about that later.
Let me just tell you that today every serious
front end web developer in the world uses some kind
of package manager like NMP which is the most popular one
since it comes directly with Node.
So let me teach you the very fundamentals of NMP
throughout this lecture always with the goal of
in this case, installing SASS on a local computer.
All right so the first step to actually get started
with this is to install Node on your computer.
So let's head over to nodejs.org and grab the installer.
So this is nodejs.org
and from here you can grab the installer for Node JS.
So you can just install version six.
It's more than enough for what we're gonna
do in this lecture.
And if you're not finding the right installer
for your platform, you can just go here to downloads
and I'm sure it will be somewhere here.
Now I of course already have it installed
and so I'm not gonna do that.
And so you should probably just pause the video
and wait until you have everything installed.
All right, so I hope your installation was successful.
And so let's now open up the command line.
So terminal
on the Mac and if you're Windows,
remember just open the command prompt by right-clicking
on your start button on Windows.
All right and so the first thing we should here
is to test if it you actually have
Node installed successfully.
And let me just increase the window here slightly.
So that you can see what's going on here on my screen.
All right.
So in order to test if you have Node successfully installed,
you just write the command Node and then dash V.
Which will check for your version basically.
And so if you see anything here,
no matter what version it is,
it doesn't have to be the same as mine.
As long as you see any output here, it means
that Node is successfully installed on your computer.
Now if you're using Visual Studio Code like me,
you can also use the integrated terminal here
so there's a terminal already built
in to Visual Studio Code, okay.
And you can totally do that but in order
to make things more clear and more easier
for you to understand,
I'm not going to use this one, which I used usually,
but I'm gonna stick with the normal terminal here.
So that being said, let's now navigate to our project folder
and remember how we do that.
First let's check where we actually are,
what LS or DIR on Windows
and then I just change directories with CD.
Remember?
So desktop and then from here, I know that the folder
is called one natours.
and so I just write one and then tab, return,
and that's it.
Let's check if everything's there.
And yeah, index, IMG, and CSS.
So it just navigates to your own project folder
so that we can start using NMP right now.
Before installing our first package,
usually the first thing that we always do in a new project
is to create a package.json file.
Which basically will contain the definitions
of our project and where NMP will write the packages
that we use.
And in order to do that, we use the NMP command
so since the program that we installed is called NMP
we simply need to run NMP on the command lines.
NMP and then what we want to do here is init.
So NMP init will open this program here.
And so you see, this utility will walk you through
creating a json.package file.
And so this is basically just a simple helper
which will create the package.json file for us.
So again this is usually the first step that we take
when we start using NMP on a new project.
So we start with the name here.
If we just hit return now it will take this name here
as a default but let's just call it natours.
The version is one, that's absolutely okay.
The description, let's just say
landing page for natours.
You could even leave it empty, it doesn't really matter.
This also is not important.
So we can leave all of this empty.
Here you can put your name if you want, the license.
And now it just asks if this is okay.
And it looks absolutely okay to me so okay.
All right and so here is the package.json file.
So we can just open it and here we go.
So it contains the name that we specify,
the version, description, main, scripts
which we're gonna take a look at later,
author and license.
So nothing really exciting here for now
and so let's move on now.
So what we really wanna do is to now finally install
our SASS compile, right?
So let's do that.
And it's very simple again.
So we use the NMP program then install
and now the name of the package.
And the name is called Node SASS.
So the name of the package that we want to install.
And now we need to specify it one last thing.
And this will make it so that the package.json file
is updated and lists this package as one
of our developer dependencies.
So what does that mean?
It means basically that Node SASS is a tool
that we use to develop our project.
So what we do is to say save
dev, okay, and that's it.
So hit return, and it should now download this package
and install it.
So it's normal that it takes some time.
All right and here we go.
So let's now take a look at the package.json file.
And here we see it.
So this is now listed as a dev dependencies here.
So Node SASS is the one that we just installed
and on version 4.5.3.
And it's listed as a dev dependency.
That's because we specified as I was telling you
where do we have it now?
Here it is.
So here, this save dev option.
So this is like an option that we specify.
And we said save dev and so it's now installed
as a dev dependency.
Now there are all kinds of packages on NMP.
For example imagine that we wanted to use J query
here on this project.
We could just come here
and write NMP install J query.
And now in this case we're not going to put a save dev
option in here because J query
is not a tool for development.
It's a JavaScript file that we want to include
in the project.
Well not in this project of course,
this is just to show you how we could install
other NMP packages.
And if you just hit return it will also install J query
and that's it so let's now take a look.
And now you see that it's nowhere to be found here
in this file.
Now if you wanted it to be here we could also say
NMP install J query.
So just a trick that I didn't tell you,
if you wanna see the commands that you wrote before
you can just hit the up arrow on your keyboard
and it will show you all the commands that you wrote before.
So right now if I move up and it will show me
the last command that I run here.
So if I type now save instead of save dev.
Let me show you what happens then.
It then creates here a field for dependencies.
Not dev dependencies because dependencies are the ones
that we actually need for a project.
So in case of J query in our project
we want to use the functions that it offers us
while in Node SASS it's just a helper,
just a tool for us to be able to use SASS in the project.
Now maybe you've noticed that there's a new folder
in our project right now.
It's this Node modules folder.
Let's open it up and wow there's a lot of folders in here
and they're all because of the packages that we installed.
So here we see the Node SASS package
and this is the code that actually makes it run
but this package here, it needs all of the other packages
in order to work just fine.
And that's why NMP installed all of these
packages here as well.
But we shouldn't really worry about this.
So it just leave all of this in the Node modules folder
and there's no need to ever touch it.
Now maybe you're wondering, well why do we need
this package json file?
Why do we have to worry about writing
these dependencies here and these dev dependencies
here as well?
So imagine that you want to upload your code
so that I can take a look at it if someone
is not working right.
So if you have some kind of bug there.
Then you're not going to share this node modules
package with me because it probably contains
thousands of files.
There's really no need to share these with me.
So if you wanted to share your project,
you will only share everything else,
but not the node modules.
What you will share though is the package.json file
because from that one I can then reproduce,
I can recreate this node modules folder.
So that's just imagine that we don't have it anymore,
we just delete it in fact.
So let's delete it, you should delete it as well.
So this code is now gone so if you wanted to use J query
or Node SASS right now, we couldn't do it anymore
because the packages are gone, the code is gone.
So imagine that we receive this now, this project
and we wanna reinstall these packages.
So we can easily do that because the package.json file
knows which dependencies, so which packages we used.
So all we have to do is to say NMP install.
And it will now take a look at our packages.json file
and download exactly the packages that we specified there.
So you see that now indeed the node modules folder is back
and in here we have all of these folders
and one of them is of course Node SASS
and also J query should be here, yup here exactly.
So this one that we have here as well.
Now in our project we don't really need J query
so we can just uninstall it.
So we say NMP uninstall J query
and then we have to again specify the save fleck.
So the save option so that it removes it also
from the package.json file.
And it's gone.
So you see that it's no longer here.
Well this piece of code here stayed here
but it doesn't matter, it's not important.
You can actually get rid of this right now.
Okay.
So our only dependency, so our only package that we need
for our project is Node SASS.
All right and with that we actually have
everything we need in order to write and compile SASS
in the next lecture.
So let's just quickly recap what we did in this lecture.
So we started by created our package.json file.
So I write clear here.
So we started by writing NMP init
in order to create the package.json file.
Then we installed Node SASS by writing NMP install
Node SASS and then we used save dev
in order to save it as a development dependency
here in our package.json file.
Which means that it's a development tool
that will just help us building our project.
Now the reason we wanted to save this here
in the package.json file is because this was we can share
our project without sharing the entire
Node modules folder here
which doesn't make any sense at all.
And so if someone else receives our project,
they can just do NMP install just like this
and then all of the dependencies
will be automatically installed.
And the same of course applies to yourself.
So imagine you are a building this project on one computer
and then you're continuing it on the next one.
You're also not gonna take the Node modules folder
with you to the other computer, no.
You just do NMP install and that's it.
So this package.json file is really useful
in each project where we have NMP modules
should really have one.
Okay and now with SASS installed on our computer,
let's quickly move to the next lecture where we're actually
gonna use it to compile our very first SASS code.