[Instructor] Big parts of our website are already
100% responsive by now.
But there is one important aspect we haven't
really tackled yet and that is resonsive images.
Now we do have flexible images already.
So our images nicely scale with the view port width
but responsive images take things to a whole new level.
And that's because responsive images are not only
an aspect of responsive design but even more importantly
of web performance.
Remember this diagram we talked about
but in the beginning of the course where I told you
how important performance is?
Here it is again because responsive images
are crucial for web performance.
What are responsive images all about?
The philosophy behind responsive images
is to serve the right image to the right screen size
and device using different techniques in HTML or CSS
so that users don't have to download images
that are way too large for their devices.
For example, let's suppose the image for the zero section
is one megabyte large.
Now it may be absolutely okay to send this
one megabyte image to a desktop computer
but it's not okay to send this one megabyte to a phone,
which may have a slow or expensive data plan
somewhere in the world.
As developers we really have a responsibility here
and responsive images help us solve these problems.
So instead of sending one megabytes to whatever
device is consuming the page,
it makes way more sense to send the one megabyte image
to a device with a large screen that actually
needs the image and a much smaller version of the image
to a device with a small screen that doesn't
need such a large image anyway.
Right?
And that's what we're going to do and it's pretty
exciting to be able to do this in my opinion.
It's really cool.
Let me just tell you that this is pretty advanced stuff
and that not many developers out there know
and take this even seriously.
So once again, knowing this advanced stuff
will really bring you to a complete new level.
Now in which situations should
we actually use responsive images?
There are mainly three use cases where it makes sense.
The first one is called resolution switching.
And all that we do in resolution switching
is to serve up the same image for a smaller screen
but with a smaller resolution.
So basically, just like we saw in the slide before,
same image but a smaller version for a device
that doesn't need such a big image.
Next, there's density switching which is actually
a special case of resolution switching
but where the screen size does not matter
but a screen pixel density does instead.
So what is pixel density?
In simple terms, pixel density is the amount of pixels
found in an inch or a centimeter.
Now what matters to us is that
there are low resolution screens,
and high resolution screens.
Low resolution screens are just typical PC screens,
I would say and they can be called 1x screen
because they use one pixel to display
one pixel of our design.
So if we say an image should be 100 pixels high,
they will actually use 100 physical pixels in the screen
to display these 100 pixels that we specified.
Now high-resolution screens are the ones found
in all modern smart phones and even some computers
already have them, like the MacBooks with retina displays.
These are high-resolution screens
and can be called 2x screens because they actually use
two physical pixels to display one pixel of our design.
So if we say we want an image to be 100 pixels high
it will actually be 200 pixels in a physical screen.
And this all happens automatically of course.
What does all of that mean for our images?
It means that if we want our images to look sharp
on high-resolution displays which use double
the amount of pixels then we actually have to serve
an image with double the resolution of the original image.
And that's what density switching is for,
to serve one image to a high-resolution screen
and another one if the screen is low resolution.
The last use case is called art direction.
Art direction happens when you don't just want
to serve the same image but in smaller resolution,
but a whole different image for a different screen size.
For example, you may want to keep the important details
in an image but remove parts of the image
around these details, just like in this example where
the size of the details doesn't even change
on a small screen, just stays the same.
Or you could also want to load a completely
different image altogether.
And responsive images actually allow you to do that.
In conclusion, resolution and density switching
is when you want to serve the same image
but with different resolutions.
And art directions is when you want to serve
a completely different image.
Now why are we even talking about
these different situations?
We are because it's important to distinguish
between the different use cases
because they require us to use different solutions
in our HTML and CSS code.
So we have to choose accordingly.
Make sense?
And since code is what really matters here,
that's what we're going to do next.
So let's now move on to the next lecture
and start implementing some responsive images in our HTML.