Hello there.
Let's now put some of the stuff
we've been talking about into practice
by going back to our project
and convert all our pixel units to rem,
and I'll explain you why of course.
So in this lecture, you're gonna learn
how and why we use rem units in our project,
and why you should do the same,
and, of course, work flow to convert pixels to rem
in the easiest way.
So this is what we're gonna do in this lecture.
We will change all the absolute pixel units
to relative rem units, okay?
And why are we gonna do that?
Well, it's quite simple actually.
It's because we want an easy way
to change all the measurements on our page
with one simple setting,
for example, when we hit a break point
to display our page on a mobile device.
When that happens we want a way to decrease
all the measurements in our site at the same time,
and instead of writing hundreds of lines of code
and in media queries,
we can just change one global setting,
and that is the global font size.
So let me show you how this awesome technique works.
So you remember how the rem unit is always
in relation to the root font size, right?
So if we now set that root font size,
we can and very easily change
all the other measurements on our page to rem,
so let's do that.
So the root font size is set in the HTML selector, okay?
And so we say font size 10 pixels.
Not the 16 that we had before, but 10.
I'm actually gonna remove this one
by just commenting it out so it stays here for you to see.
And so I changed this so 10 pixels,
but now, why did I change it to 10 pixels?
Well, we do 10 pixels here in order
to make our life easier to be honest.
That's because now we know that 1 rem
equals exactly 10 pixels, right?
Because remember, 1 rem is exactly the root font size,
so if 10 pixels is now the root font size,
then 1 rem is 10 pixels,
and so now it's really easy to replace
all the pixel units with rem,
because all we have to is to divide all the pixels by 10
and that's our rem, right?
Now, if it was 1 rem is 16 pixels,
then we would have to make a lot of calculations,
and we don't want to do that, of course,
so this is a pretty common technique to avoid that, okay?
So with this in mind, let's actually do that.
So we start here at the top and change all,
or let's say most, of our pixel measurements to rem.
So we have a 30 pixel padding,
so just divide it by 10 and you end up with 3 rem,
okay, and that's it.
So let's keep looking, what do we have here?
Oh, another one, 40 pixels, so it's 4 rem, right?
So you don't have to do any calculations,
you just divide it by 10 for rem.
And here, 3.5 rem, it makes sense, right?
And I will actually show you the effect of this in a second.
So here we have percentages, nothing changes,
here, 6 rem.
Here again, 6 rem, and here 3.5 rem.
Font size here should be 2 rem.
Here it's 1.74 rem.
Well that's a bit specific, let's just keep it at 1.7 rem,
or we can say 1.75 rem.
Okay, that looks acceptable.
Now here, we have -10 rem,
here just 1,
and 10, and -1, okay?
So ideally of course, you start by doing this
right in the beginning of the project,
but I didn't want to overwhelm you
and to scare you with all too much theory
right at the beginning of the course,
and so we just started the simple way,
and the way you probably already know
how to do everything which is in simple pixels,
but if you're doing responsive design and modern design,
and modern CSS development,
then it's really good practice
to use relative units like rem.
So here we have 3 rem.
Now of course we could also have used m's instead of rems,
but that's a whole lot of work.
Believe me, I've tried it,
and it's really difficult to make,
because, remember that m's depend not on the root font size
but on the font size of the parent element,
and with that you have to do a lot of calculations
and it becomes really, really difficult to manage.
So I always set everything to rem
and then it's really the best solution.
1.5 rem, 4 rem, and 10 rem of course.
Here, we can also do it here in these box shadows,
and here it's .5,
so whenever you have a point
you don't write out just 0 in CSS, okay?
So of course you can, it works,
but it's just a coding practice
to only put the dot, okay?
It's just a good practice that professionals use.
So 10 rem in here.
Any more pixels here, no, that's it.
Alright, so let's now take a look
and see if everything's still working the same.
Alright, great.
The only thing is, here, the text size here,
because originally we set it to 16 pixels, right?
And so now here we actually have to set the font size.
Here it is.
So if we still want it at 16 pixels,
and this should be really easy, right?
So 16 pixels is 1.6 rem.
So let's go back, and here we go, great.
Now what I want to show you is this.
So if you now go ahead
and just change the overall font size, here it is,
then see how the entire design changes.
I'll go down to 9, and you'll see that everything changes.
Everything became smaller.
Take a look at the padding here outside,
at this padding, and here at this size,
and also the text size as I will decrease it further.
Sorry, this was increasing, so I decrease it further now.
Everything is becoming smaller, right?
And that is amazing once we start writing media queries.
It will make our lives so much easier.
So imagine we had, now, this smaller version,
like on a phone, then this would already take
a lot of work from us.
Instead of writing all the media queries
to make all the font sizes smaller
and to make all of these distances here smaller,
like these 30 pixels,
this now automatically converts to something else.
For example, in this,
wow, this is now really small,
let me check this, where is it?
Yeah, this body, it has now a padding not of 30 pixels,
but of 15 here, as you can see down here.
You see now it's 15 pixels
and not the 30 that it was before,
and that's because we set the font size here to 5, right?
So 5 is half of 10, and so 15 is half of 30, right?
If we put it back like to 8,
then the padding becomes 24 and so forth and so on.
And the same will of course work in the other direction.
So imagine we have a really huge screen or something,
and we want to increase our design,
or someone zooms in the page,
and that's what happens.
So we can also write media queries for larger screens
and then increase the design.
Alright, so that is the trick,
and a huge, huge advantage of using rem.
Now, we can still improve this,
because it's actually a very bad practice
to set the font size to pixels as well,
so up here, this shouldn't really be 10 pixels.
It should be something else.
The problem is that by doing so we actually
override the browser font size setting
that the user can manually change in the settings,
and many people actually do that.
For example, when they have bad sight
and cannot see so good,
then some people actually
increase the default font size of their browser.
Now if we set the font to,
like, the 10 pixels like we did here,
then we remove the ability for these people
to see our website properly,
because they can no longer change the default font size.
Well, they can, but our root font size
will not be affected by that anymore.
It will just be 10 pixels
no matter what the user has as a default font size.
So this is a really bad practice,
and that is why we're going to set
over a font size to a percentage here,
which will translate to a percentage
of the font size given by the browser.
Now the default font size,
if the user doesn't change anything,
which is the initial situation that we want, is 16 pixels,
so that's the absolute default,
and that's a situation that we're counting on here.
So if we put 100% here, this would mean
that the root font size would be 16 pixel
if the user doesn't change anything,
and if the user does change the default font size,
let's say to 18 pixels,
then the root font size will be 18 pixel.
If he changes to 20 pixel,
then it will be 20, and so on and so forth.
Now, but we don't want 16 pixels here, right?
What we want is 10 pixels,
and so it's very simple.
All we have to do is to divide what we want,
which is 10, by 16.
So I'm having a calculator here,
so 10 divided by 16 is 62.5%,
and that is what we're putting here.
62.5%, and that's it, that's the whole technique.
So now, imagine, let's say .625,
so if the default is 16 like we had before,
then this translates to 10 pixels, right,
which is what we want.
But if the user changes to, let's say 20 pixels,
then our default font size will be 12.5 pixels,
so the root font size I was saying,
and if the user does 22, it goes to 13.75 pixels,
and so on and so forth,
and so with this we allow the user
to actually zoom in on the page automatically,
not only to change the font size,
but to also zoom in on the page,
because basically that's what happens.
Not exactly zooming, but increasing
all of the measurements that we have on our page.
So make sure that you understand this technique.
It's really widely used in the CSS developer community
because it's so simple and yet so powerful, as you saw.
Now, one thing that I should probably tell you
is that rems are not supported below Internet Explorer 9,
so if you have to develop a site
for one of these browsers,
so the really old Internet Explorers,
then you cannot use rems because your site
will simply not work at all, okay?
Now, since that applies to almost everything
that I'm gonna show you in this course,
I guess that's not really irrelevant at all,
because if you're interested in taking this modern course
that you're taking right now,
then you're probably not trying to develop
for these old browsers anyway.
Alright, and one more thing we can do
before we finish this lecture
is to use the power of inheritance,
since we already talked about inheritance.
So whenever we can use inheritance,
we should use it instead of using here
something like the universal selector,
and so what I'm going to do now
is to remove this box-sizing from here
and put it here on the body.
So now we set the body to box-sizing border-box,
and then in here what we do
is to say box-sizing and we use the inherit keyword,
and that's it.
So remember how we could use the inherit keyword
to force inheritance.
That's what we're doing here.
So the box-sizing property by itself is not inherited,
but by setting the box-sizing property
on each and every element on the entire page to inherit,
it'll automatically inherit
whatever we put here on border-box.
So this is considered a slightly better practice
by the CSS community
because it makes it a bit easier to change the box-sizing
like in plugins or other components
where we might want to use
a different property for box-sizing.
So it doesn't make a huge difference,
just a slightly better practice
to do the box-sizing border-box like this.
Alright, and since we're at it,
we should actually update this universal reset here,
because we can do slightly better than this,
which is to also select all of the after pseudo-elements
and also all of the before pseudo-elements.
That's because, right now,
only the real elements get this behavior here,
but the after and before pseudo-elements,
they don't get this behavior,
and since we don't want to see
any strange behavior happening,
we will also include these ones here as well.
So you know we already have a after pseudo-element down here
and if we had put a width or a height
and then a padding or a border,
then it wouldn't have behaved the way we expected it,
which we expected because of the box-sizing of border-box,
so actually it's down here.
So it wouldn't have worked the way we expected
because we actually didn't have this part here
in the universal selector in our global reset.
So just another slightly improvement
over our previous code.
Okay, and that's really it for this lecture.
See you in the next video.