So after a quick break,
let's now continue building the home
section that we were working on.
I already mentioned that we were gonna lay out
all of these elements in the cart using a grid.
But how are we actually gonna do that?
And the first thing that comes into my attention here
is that this actually is laid out in two columns, right?
So you see that here we have these two on the left side,
and these two parts here on the right side.
And so what that means is that we have a grid,
which has two columns here, and we can put
these two here on one side, in one column,
and these two in another column.
And all the other elements, just like this button here,
this name, and this image, they can then span
both these columns from one side
to the other side of the grid container.
So let's now quickly do that, and create our two columns.
And as for the rows, we can actually let CSS
take care of that automatically, okay?
So we're just gonna define the columns,
and the rows will be put automatically in there.
Once more, we're using an implicit grid here.
You're probably starting to see that this is a pattern.
Most of the time, we just define the columns,
and then let CSS figure out the rows automatically.
Now that's not always the pattern,
so that's not always how it's gonna work,
but many times that is the best practice, okay?
So very simple in this case.
(keyboard clacking)
Grid template columns, and all we want
is two columns with the same size.
So repeat two, one F-R, right?
Then before that's gonna work,
of course we need to add display grid,
and now we're ready to see how that's gonna look like.
And, alright, it's already doing what it's supposed to do.
So let's now say that we want this image,
this name here, and the button
to span across both the column tracks, okay?
And that shouldn't be all too hard,
All we have to say is grid-column from one, to -1, right?
And I'm gonna copy this one here,
because it also applies to the name and to the button.
Now how are we gonna do this with the button?
Well, we should actually add a class here, I guess,
so besides that class here that it has here already,
let's call it the home button as well,
so home button,
and so let's add that down here as well,
and grid-col, from one, to -1, okay?
And I noticed I called this CTI for some reason,
and CTI means call-to-action, but I think that up here
I called it something else,
and yeah, I called it button actually.
Okay so let's go to all of these,
so I select CTI now, and then I hit command-D,
here in VS code, to select all of them,
and then I just have to paste,
and it's gonna paste it in all of these six places.
And if I check it out now, yeah,
then that looks much better.
So the image is already spanning here,
across the entire container, but for some reason
the button is not, so let's check out why.
I guess I know why, because I only added
this here to the last one,
so of course I need to add this class to all of them.
Okay, and just one more left, and yeah.
Okay so that's much better.
So let's take a look at our grid here
in the dev tools, so this one here, alright?
And where is it actually down here?
Well let's inspect it, and yeah.
So you can see that it's spanning these two grid-columns
then we have this like icon here
which we still have to format.
Then we have the name, such as we specified
it's spanning these two columns as well.
And then all of these four details here,
they are, of course, just one cell, each of them.
Okay, so let's now style this heart,
and position it up here in the corner.
And so how do you think we should do that?
I think that the best way here, is to use overlapping.
So basically placing this grid item
here on top of this image, in this grid cell here.
So right in this grid cell, okay?
That's where I'm gonna place this heart icon.
So from column two to three, and from row two to one.
Homes, and yeah, here we go.
So grid-row, and now I have to specify all of this,
because otherwise the auto-placement algorithm
is just gonna put it in column two, three,
but not in the first row, where I want it to be.
So from grid-line two, to grid-line number three,
just as we said before.
Now let's also do the same as down here,
but make it just a bit bigger, alright?
If we take a look at that now, then here we go.
So this is exactly where we wanted it to be,
the problem is that now the image actually moved down.
That's because the automatic-placement algorithm
doesn't automatically put grid items one on top of another.
So instead it just moves this one here down.
But we don't want that to happen,
we want this also to be in the first row.
So we have to specify that, just as we had
to do for the icon.
So where is it?
Oh, yeah.
So grid-row, from one to two, please.
And that should fix it.
Now just to be sure that this icon here
will always stay on top of this image,
let's just give each of them a z and x.
And so this one, of course, will be higher,
so z-index of let's say one, and the like, a z-index of two.
And it worked even without that,
but just to be 100% sure, and also to show you
that this is how we define which of the elements
should be placed on top of the other.
Now just one more thing here with the like
is this here, so it's not aligned here
to the right side, as we want it to be.
And how do we align grid-items
inside of grid cells horizontally?
We just use the justify-items property, right?
But in this case, we want this
to happen only with this one here.
And so we can use justify-self on this exact item.
So justify-self is going to align
the item inside the grid cell,
and we want it to be all the way to the end.
So, here we go, now it's here all the way to the end.
Now, just one more thing, let's just give it
some margin here, so to push it down and right a little bit.
So margin, one rem, and with that, we should be good to go.
Alright, so that looks much better.
Next up, we have this name of the house.
And so that is how this looks like.
How are we gonna do that?
Well first up, let's style this element,
and take care of placing it afterwards.
So we're talking about this one here, the name,
and so let's start with the font family,
and this one is the display font,
and so I'm using that variable name here.
The font size is 1.6 rem, I want the text to be aligned
at the center, it would have some padding of 1.25 rem,
and the background color of color secondary.
So that's over a dark blue.
Then the color itself is white,
and the font weight, 400.
I'm doing all this very quick and very fast,
without explaining much, because you're
already familiar with all of this,
and that's not really part of the CSS Grid anyway.
So that's the main style, and let's now think
about the more difficult stuff.
Well, for some reason nothing really happened.
Let's see why that is.
And it's probably because of this error here.
So let's give it a save again, and then yeah, here we go.
So how do we now go from looking like this,
to what we have here?
So basically the width of this item here
is not 100%, but just 80%, and all of this here
is centered in the grid cell,
and then it's also moved up a bit.
So let's take care of the first things that I said.
First off, the width is only 80%,
and then it is horizontally aligned
inside of it's grid cell, and that's pretty easy.
Once again, we're going to use justify-self,
and this time, set to center.
So that's really easy, right?
So that's how it looks like right now.
And now all we have to do is to place it here in the middle.
And we have two options for that.
The first one is to move it up from here,
but then that would create this half-empty row here, right?
So basically we would have one row
which would be half-empty, and then half of it
would be occupied by this element.
And I don't think that's really perfect,
so instead, what I'm gonna do is to place
this grid item here, right in this first row,
so basically putting it here into this first row,
so you're on top of the image, using overlapping once again.
I already defined the grid-column,
let's also define the grid-row, one, two,
and let's define a z-index as well,
in order to ensure that it's gonna be on top of the image.
So how does that look like?
And, whoa, it's stretching all the way
from the top to the bottom of this grid cell.
But that's of course not what we want,
and so we have to vertically align it here to the bottom.
We already used justify-self,
and for this one, we're gonna use align-self to the bottom.
So justify-self and align-self are pretty similar,
with the difference that justify
does it horizontally, so in the row-axis,
and align does it vertically, therefore in the column-axis.
Okay, so that should fix that, for some reason it didn't.
And that's because it's not called bottom,
but it's called end instead, okay?
So let's take a look at that in the dev tools,
and alright, so here it is, all the way
to the end of this grid area.
And now it's just very simple,
we just have to move it down with a simple translate.
So transform, translate in the y-direction, 50%.
Because 50% corresponds to 50%
of the height of the element itself.
So it's gonna place it exactly at the center.
And here we go, so that is the result
that we were looking for.
I hope that you understood the reasoning about it,
why I did it the way that I did.
And I thought this was a cool way of showing you
why some of these properties like justify-self,
or align-self, are really important to know all the time,
and have always in mind, whatever situation we face,
when we build our layouts.
Now, of course we need some more space here,
this is actually now overlapping
these icons here, and this row, of course.
Let's just create some space between the rows.
And that is actually pretty easy.
We just need the grid-row gap.
So where is that?
Gap, and we're gonna go with 35 pixels here.
So again this was obtained through experimentation,
and I settled here on this value,
I thought this was the best.
Now this still looks rather strange.
So you see that this space here
between this home name and this row here
is not quite as we want it to be.
That's because we moved this here down,
and so we created this inequality here.
So let's see that a bit better here.
You see that we have these 3.5 rems here, here, and here,
but then we have this overlapping.
It would be amazing if CSS Grid allowed us
to style some of these gaps individually.
What I would like to do now, is to say
that this first gap here, should be 5 or 6 rem,
and the others should be only be 3.5 rem.
But unfortunately, that's just not possible
with CSS Grid at this point.
I don't know if that's gonna change in the future,
but right now, when we specify the gap in the grid,
it will be same for all the rows and for all the columns.
So we cannot style just one gap individually.
We just have to come up with a solution for that,
and the solution that I've found
is to add a small margin to the top of these two items,
the house location, and the house rooms.
If we add a margin to the top of these two,
then that will increase the space
between this name and then this next row.
That is not ideal, it's not perfect,
but we have to come up with solutions like this
from time to time, and in fact it works perfectly fine,
in this situation, doing it like this.
So let's copy this from here,
and add a margin top of 2.5 rem.
And if you check that out now,
then that actually looks a lot better.
And you can see it even better over here.
So that's the best solution that I could
come up with at this point.
Another solution would have been
to say that the second row here
should be a bit higher than the others,
and then move these two here down to the bottom of this row,
but I think that this way is actually better.
It's a bit cleaner, not interfering
with the individual height of these grid-rows.
So we're now actually almost done with this grid,
all we have to do is to apply some simple styles here,
to each of these four characteristics of the homes.
So let's do that, and let's set the font size, at first,
and actually we can do it right here.
So font size 1.5 rem, and then the text
is going to inherit it, and so I don't
even need this selector here.
Next up, I wanna give each of these four details
a margin to the left side of 20 pixels, so 2 rem.
And so that's how it's gonna look like then.
All that's left to do now is to put
these two elements here side-by-side.
And what's the best tool for that job?
Well, I strongly believe that Flexbox is the way to go here.
So Flexbox is really perfect for this really small stuff.
Even if we start using CSS Grid
for almost everything one day,
I think that for this small-alignment stuff,
Flexbox is always gonna be the easiest,
and most straightforward solution,
because it's really as simple as that.
All we have to do is really say display, flex,
and then they will be two, side-by-side, okay?
Even better, what we can do is to say align items,
and center, so we will also vertically center
these two items along the cross-axis, basically vertically.
So that looks even better now.
And all of that with just two very simple lines of code.
Now here on the icon let's give it
some margin to the right side,
in order to separate the icon from the text.
So margin right, one rem, and that's necessary
because in Flexbox there's not something
like the grid-gap that we have in CSS Grid.
In Flexbox we cannot specify gaps like we can with grids.
But actually I read somewhere, I think on Twitter,
that they are thinking about adding gaps to Flexbox as well.
So someday if that becomes available,
then that will be fantastic.
We'll no longer have to deal with margin-rights then,
we could simply add a gap here in the Flex container,
in order to separate the icon from the text here.
But right now that's not available,
but maybe someday in the future
we will be able to do that, so then it's even simpler.
I think that's actually it.
I think that's the design we were going for.
I think that it looks exactly the same in fact.
So that's awesome, that's great progress
from you up until this point.
We're building more and more complex layouts here,
using more and more advanced techniques,
and so we're already mixing CSS Grid with Flexbox,
and using some advanced placement techniques as well.
So I hope that this is really useful for you,
so that you can build your own designs sometime
in the future, using all of these powerful techniques.