Welcome back.
Do you still remember the diagram that I showed you
in the beginning about how CSS works behind the scenes?
This one, right?
So we've been talking a lot about the parsing phase,
but now it's time to move on to the website rendering phase.
So this lecture should give you a pretty good overview
about how the visual formatting model works,
so that you can write your code in a way that makes
more sense to you.
What this lecture will do is maybe not so much give you
new tools, but it will summarize a lot of the CSS
that you actually already know, and put it in a more
meaningful context.
So, the CSS visual formatting model is an algorithm
that calculates boxes and determines the layout
of these boxes for each element in the render tree,
in order to determine the final layout of the page.
This model is one of the fundamental concepts of CSS
which is why I decided to include it in the course.
Now, in order to do this, the algorithm takes into account
factors like dimensions of the boxes, which are calculated
by the box model, the box type, which can be inline,
block or inline-block;
the positioning scheme which includes concepts like
floats and absolute or relative positioning;
stacking context, the other elements that are present
in the render tree such as siblings or parents;
and finally, external information such as the current
viewpoint size, dimensions of images, or other factors.
So, by putting all these factors together,
the browser figures out how the final website will look
for the user.
So let's now look at the first four of these factors
in more detail.
And let's start with the box model.
The box model is without a doubt one of the most fundamental
parts of CSS and it's something you really have to master
in order to lay out a webpage.
The box model is one of the factors that define how elements
are displayed on a webpage and how they are sized.
According to the box model, each and every element
on a webpage can be seen as a rectangle box.
And each box can have a width, a height, a padding, margins
and a border.
But note that they're all optional, so there can be boxes
with no margins or no paddings at all.
Now this image here shows us how the box model works.
So let's break it down.
First, the content of a box is where all the text, images
or other content that we specify go.
We can easily define its height and width using
the corresponding CSS properties, as we're going to see
in the next slide.
Next, the padding is a transparent area around the content,
but still inside of the box.
We use paddings to generate white space inside of a box
and we can define the padding by specifying the padding
property in CSS, as I'm sure you already know.
Next, we can specify a border for a box,
and that border goes around the padding and the content.
Similar to the padding, we have the margin,
but instead of being inside the box,
the margin is white space that's actually outside
the box itself.
So we can think of margin as a space between boxes.
So, for example, if we want some space between two elements,
we will define their margin properties in CSS.
And finally, there's something called the fill area.
Remember how the text content and images go inside
the content box?
The same does actually not apply for background images
or the background color of the box.
These properties will be applied not only to the content box
but to the entire fill area, which also includes the padding
and the border, but not the margin.
Alright, so let's now talk about heights and widths
in the default box model.
As I mentioned, you can specify the height and the width
of an element.
Now, if we choose not to specify the height or width
of a certain element, the visual formatting model
will just use the content of the box to determine its size.
So let's now take a look at how the default box model
calculates height and width of block level boxes.
And more about block level boxes, or elements, later.
So, the width of a box, as we will see in the final layout,
is defined by the right border plus the right padding,
plus the specified width, plus the left padding,
plus the left border.
And the same logic, of course, applies for the height
of the box.
But let's look at a quick example to make this more clear.
Suppose we define the height for element of 100 pixel
and the padding to the top and bottom of 20 pixels.
So the final height as displayed on the website
would be 140 pixels.
This means that whenever we define a width or a height
of a box, the padding and border get added
to what we defined.
But that doesn't sound very practical, right?
So the solution to fix this problem is to use the box-sizing
property with the value of border box.
And I'm sure that many of you already know
and use this trick.
And they also show that in my beginning HTML and CSS course.
But it's still important to remember
how this actually works.
So, if we set box sizing to border box,
the height and the width will be defined for the entire box
including the padding and the border and not just for
the content area.
What this means, at the same time is that the paddings
and borders that we specify, will of course reduce
the inner width of the content area,
instead of adding them to the total height or width
of an element.
Alright.
So, if we look at the height and width calculations now,
in this case, the actual total width of a box is equal
to the specified width.
And the same goes for the height.
So, if we now define some paddings or borders,
they will not get added to the dimensions of the box.
Which makes our lives so much easier.
And if we look at our example now, the final height
will of course be 100 pixels, just as we specified
for the height of the element.
Alright.
So we looked at the box model and how height or width
of boxes are calculated.
But this applies mainly to block-level boxes,
which is one of the different types of boxes in CSS.
So let's now look at the three most common
and most important box types and how different box types
determine how boxes are laid out on a page.
Let's start with a block-level box or element.
We can say both.
Now, first off, the type of a box is always defined
by a display property, which I'm sure you know already.
So in the case of a block-level element,
the display property is usually set to block.
But please, note that the values flags for flags block
layout list item and table also produce block-level boxes.
Now, all HTML elements have a display default property.
And elements such as paragraphs or divs,
which are usually formatted visually as blocks,
have their display property set to block by default.
We can always, of course, change this property manually,
which can be very useful in some cases.
Okay. So being a block-level box, this block will always
occupy as much space as possible, which is usually 100%
of its parent width.
And create line breaks after and before it,
meaning that blocks are formatted vertically
one after another.
Now, about inline boxes, they're basically the opposite
of block-level boxes, because their content is distributed
in lines, meaning that an inline box only occupies
the space that its content actually needs.
Therefore, they also don't cause line breaks after
or in line with them.
But instead, they just sit inside their block-level
parent element.
Now about the box model, things work a bit different
in inline boxes.
First, the height and width property do not apply.
Which means that we cannot use these properties here.
And second, we can only specify horizontal paddings
and margins on inline elements.
So only on the left and on the right side.
That's the way the box model works on inline elements.
So of course this has some serious limitations.
And in order to overcome them, there's another type of box,
and that's the inline block box.
Now, inline block boxes are technically also inline boxes
but which simply work as a block-level box on the inside.
So, since they're technically inline elements,
they also use up only their content space and cause
no line breaks.
But, since they work as a block-level box on the inside,
the box model applies to them just like in the regular
block-level boxes.
All we need to do in order to set an element to an inline
box is to set its display property to inline block,
and that's it.
Very easy.
So it's really important that you understand the difference
between these three types of boxes,
so we can use them as needed in different situations.
Okay.
Next up, we have positioning schemes.
And there are three of them in CSS.
The normal flow, floats and absolute positioning.
And I'm sure you're already familiar with floats
and absolute or relative positioning,
and so this is more to bring all of these properties
together into a bigger context.
So, the normal flow is what happens to an element
if you don't do anything to it at all.
If you don't float it and if you don't use position
absolute on it.
If you use position relative, then the element is still
in a normal flow.
And what the normal flow means, is that the elements
are simply laid out on the page in a natural order
in the code.
The next positioning scheme is when you use floats.
The float property causes an element to be completely taken
out of the normal flow and shifted to the left or right
as far as possible, until it touches the edge
of its containing box, or another floated element.
When this happens, text and inline elements will wrap
around the floated element.
Also, when an element is floated, its container will not
adjust its height to the element,
which sometimes can be problematic.
The usual solution to this is to use clear fixes,
which I am sure you have used when building layouts
using floats, right?
And then finally, there's absolute positioning.
And just like with floats, when you set the position
property to absolute or also to fixed,
the element is taken out of the normal flow.
Now, what's different here is that with absolute
positioning, the element has no impact on surrounding
content or elements at all.
In fact, it can even overlap them.
So if we want to position an absolutely positioned element
on the page, we use the CSS properties top, bottom,
left and right to offset it to its
relatively-positioned container.
Now as I mentioned, an absolutely positioned element
can overlap other elements occupying the same space.
And how do we solve this?
Well, CSS solves it for us, actually, using something
called stacking context.
So there's one piece left in the puzzle of the visual
formatting model: stacking context.
So, stacking contexts are what determine in which order
elements are rendered on the page.
A new stacking context can be created by a different
CSS properties, where the most widely known is Z index.
But there are other properties that also create
new stacking contexts.
Now, stacking contexts are like layers that form a stack.
Layers on the bottom of the stack appear at first,
and elements higher up the stack appear on top,
overlapping the elements below them,
just like you see on the slide.
In this example, we have three stacking contexts
because each element used the Z index property
on an either relatively or absolutely positioned element.
And that's one way of creating a new stacking context.
Now between these elements, the one with the higher z index
appears on the top, and the one with the lowest z index
appears at the bottom.
Now, a common misconception is that only the z index
property creates new stacking contexts,
but that's not the case.
An opacity value different from one,
a transform, a filter or other properties,
will also create new stacking contexts.
That's why sometimes, even with the z index set on
a positioned element, the stacking order doesn't work
as expected.
But as with everything we talked about in this section,
we will see practical applications of all of this
in the coding part of the course.