Often, particularly for authorization,
you will need access to the Authentication object as it
contains the currently logged in user, their credentials,
authorities, such as roles,
the UserDetails object that might contain some custom
fields that you have configured.
Now the Authentication object goes through two transformations.
Prior to authentication, it is an authentication request.
The authentication flag is set to false,
the credentials required for authorization are populated,
and there are no assigned roles or authorities yet.
Once authenticated, it's known as an authenticated principle.
The authentication flag is set to true,
the principle becomes the UserDetails object that was
returned by the UserDetailsService, and the roles and privileges are populated.
The authentication is then stored in the security context,
which in turn is stored in the SecurityContextHolder,
a thread local,
making the authentication available in the current thread of execution.
Now there are many ways to access the Authentication object in your application.
Here we have the AccountController.
The setup-totp requires the username to confirm if the user
has two-factor authentication enabled.
If they don't, it generates a new two- factor authentication QR code.
Now you could simply access the Authentication object from the
SecurityContextHolder by calling the getContext and getAuthentication method.
Then retrieve the UserDetails from the getPrincipal method.
This is messy.
There's a lot of casting here,
and we are accessing the holder through a static method.
We can do better.
Another way to do this more cleanly is to simply add a field of type
principal or anything inheriting principal to your method.
Now Spring MVC will detect that this method parameter is of type principal,
and it will resolve it.
Hence, you can also use an object of type authentication.
You can then access the UserDetails object via the getPrincipal method.
Now this is slightly better,
but you still need to apply a cast to retrieve the principal.
A cleaner approach is to use the AuthenticationPrincipal annotation.
This does the casting for you.
Much cleaner.
Now one issue with this controller is that it checks to see
if the user has two-factor authentication enabled by making
a call to the data store.
Now we can do better here.
Now we can add this property to our custom UserDetails object.
Then in the UserDetailsService, we can populate it.
Now back to the AccountController.
We can now refactor it to use the new property to determine if the
user has two- factor authentication enabled.
Also, if you're not too keen on coupling your application with Spring Security,
you can easily create your own annotation.
Target will be parameter.
Then, you just simply add the @AuthenticationPrincipal annotation.
And now you can replace this new annotation in your controller,
decoupling you from Spring Security annotations.
In case you ever wanted to change in the future, you only need to change the logic within this new annotation.