If you have been following the course,
you're probably now very familiar with the Configuration class.
We have used it extensively.
One thing that's bothering me is it's starting to look very
cluttered and messy and not very readable.
So let's tidy it up.
Abracadabra.
There.
That looks a lot better.
I'm sure you can agree.
Our starting point is the http builder object.
We indent from there,
add our filter and exceptions handling configuration
followed by the login builder.
Everything related to that we indent and group together.
Next, we do the same for the rememberMe and oauth2 builders.
Finally,
we get to the authorizeRequests builder where we can
configure our authorization logic.
Also include the following annotations in comments around this,
formatter:on and formatter:off,
as you don't want your ID to mess everything back
up if you select format source. Now let's get stuck into URL authorization in the next sections.