If you're using JSP, Spring provides a tag library,
which you can add to your JSP pages.
Also, we need the Spring-security-taglibs dependency in our POM file.
This then gives you access to two key tags,
the authorize and authentication tag.
The authorize tag allows you to selectively display parts of the page based
on the user's authorities or the security configuration.
Here on our portfolio page, we have the Admin link,
which links to the admin section that requires the admin role.
Now if the user does not have this role, it throws the AccessDeniedException.
A better approach would be to only display this link to admin users.
We can use the authorize tag to achieve this.
Using the access property to add the Spring expression
like hasRole ADMIN or the URL property to check if the
user has access to the admin URL.
This will check the configuration in our configuration class.
The authentication tag gives you access to the authentication
principal in case you want to display the name or any sort of
details about the principal, properties like email name,
etc.
In this case, we could add the user's name to the top-right corner of the page.
Now I'm actually using Thymeleaf, which is a templating engine.
So my page is an HTML page and not a JSP.
Hence, this won't work for me.
But Thymeleaf gives me access to the security tags.
I just use the security tag within HTML objects.
Okay, let's give this a test.
As you can see, the admin button is no longer present.
However, don't be fooled.
These tags adjust for aesthetics, look and feel.
Don't rely on them for security.
If I simply type in the URL at the top for the admin page,
it will go directly to the admin controller. Next we will look at how you can address this by protecting your URLs.