To enable method-level authorization,
you need to add the @EnableGlobalMethodSecurity annotation.
It has three properties you can set depending on the type your require,
either secured, jsr250, and prePostEnabled.
Now you can use the following annotations on any bean
object in your application context.
Pre and post are the most powerful and most commonly used as they
allow you to take advantage of expressions.
It consists of a PreAuthorize annotation,
which allows you to check the user's role and authentication prior to
executing a method and post authorization that executes after a
method call and gives you the ability to interrogate the return
object prior to returning the method.
The Secured annotations are the original annotations used in Spring Security,
but are more limited than the pre and postAuthorize.
You can use them to verify if a user has one or more roles,
but you cannot perform more complex operations.
Spring also supports jsr250 standard annotations.
However, they are not as powerful as Spring's annotations.
You can basically just match roles, no expression support.
Now once method-level security is enabled,
you can use the PreAuthorize annotation.
Here is the service that returns the portfolio for a user.
Now it is used by two controllers, the MVC and the RestController,
which use different URLs.
We can use the PreAuthorize to enforce the principal must be
authenticated and have the admin role, or they must have the user role,
and the username parameter passed into the method must
match the one in the Authentication object,
basically the same check we performed in the configuration against this URL.
Again,
this is very powerful because two separate URLs were accessing this same method.
So this provides an additional layer of security in case a developer
were to change one of those configurations or simply add a new
controller with a different URL accessing this method that does not
add the appropriate authorization rules.
This will protect against that.
You can also reference other beans in this expression,
like the isPortfolioOwnerOrAdmin, calling the check method on the username field.
Now we can also change it to the postAuthorize,
which will perform the validation after the method is called.
Now in this case, that would not be very efficient.
It is always best to perform validation prior to a method call.
And in my experience,
the PreAuthorization annotation is used a lot more frequently unless
we want to authenticate based on the returnObject.
Now in this case,
we can check if the returnObject username property matches the principal's,
adding that additional layer of protection.
Now the PreFilter evaluates before a method is invoked.
It accepts two properties, the value,
which is the expression that will be evaluated for
each element in the collection.
If the expression returns false for any of the elements,
it will be removed from the collection.
And the option filterTarget element,
it must be of type collection and have a remove method.
If the method has more than one collection parameter,
then we can use the filter target to identify the one we want to filter.
Otherwise, we can just simply omit this.
The reserved name filterObject can be used within the expression
to refer to the current object being evaluated.
Here we have a method, which allows you to save transactions to a portfolio.
Let's restrict it to the principal with the role admin
unless the user owns that portfolio.
You can use the reserved filterObject to reference the
transactions object username property.
Then we compare against the authentication.username
property for the current logged in user.
This will evaluate this expression against every transaction in the list and
remove the ones where the expression evaluates to false.
Hence, unless the principal was an admin,
the user cannot inject transactions with someone else's username.
Now here we have a method that returns support queries.
We can use the filter method to filter out any support queries that do
not belong to the authenticated user and are active.
Now if you're using the same expression frequently or
they start to get very long and complex,
then you can create an annotation.
The target will be method, and add your filter annotation to it.
Then you can simply annotate your methods with it.
Now method-level annotations are very powerful and give you access to the
parameters passed into the method and returned from the method,
but not to any of the domain objects used within your methods.
Now next we'll dive a little deeper and look at authorization at the domain level.