Digest tries to solve the problem of transmitting
credentials in plain text over the network,
making it difficult for someone sniffing network traffic.
It uses md5 checksum hashes so that the credentials are
never transmitted across the wire,
both client and server nonces to defend against replay attacks.
Let's configure digest authentication in our application.
We will mix it up a bit.
For our admin section, we will use digest as it is more secure than basic.
The remainder of the site will continue using basic.
To achieve this, we will need to set up two filter chains.
We need to configure a new configuration class that
extends the WebSecurityConfigurationAdapter.
First we need a digest authentication entry point.
Let's configure a method that returns an instance of 1
and add the realm and key to it.
The realm is the security policy domain.
You can partition parts of your web application into separate
realms with their own security policies.
Hence, we will call this on admin-digest-realm.
The key is used by the entry point to generate a nonce
required in the digest authentication.
It basically is an encoded string used to prevent replay attacks.
The server creates a new nonce for every request and
expects it back in the response.
If the same nonce is detected in multiple requests or some
of the details of the nonce don't add up,
the server can reject it.
to see how Spring generates the nonce, let's drill into the digest entry point.
It uses the expiryTime, which is 300 seconds from the currentTime:,
an md5 hash of the expiryTime,
and the key we added to the authentication provider.
This now forms the signature value.
Finally, it encodes the nonce in base 64.
When the request is sent back to the client,
the expiryTime in the nonce is used to check if the request is still valid,
and the signature ensures that it hasn't been tampered with.
We also need a new UserDetailsService,
the reason being is that the default one generated by Spring
Boot adds a prefix to the password of noop.
The reason it does this is that, by default,
Spring expects the password to be encoded.
And the default encoder in Spring Security 5 is bcrypt.
Hence, if the prefix is in front of the password,
it is stripped, and a noop password encoder is used instead,
which matches the password in plain text.
However, the prefix just doesn't work with the digest authentication filter.
It doesn't strip the noop and, hence, will not authenticate.
In the adapter,
we are going to override the method configure that accepts a
parameter of AuthenticationManagerBuilder and create an
in-memory AuthenticationManager two users,
user and admin.
We also need to expose this UserDetailsService as a bean so that Spring
Boot backs off and doesn't configure the default one.
To do this,
we override the UserDetailsService bean method and expose it as a bean.
Now to get around not having to add the noop prefix,
we will add the noop password encoder as a bean.
This will cause Spring Security to set it as the default encoder.
This is okay for testing your app,
but it is not suitable for production and is why it is depreciated
by Spring as they want to warn you against this.
For now this is fine.
We are going to go over working with credentials securely and correctly.
Next,
we will add a method to the configure that returns an instance of
the DigestAuthenticationFilter and add the new UserDetailsService
and AuthenticationEntryPoint to it.
Finally,
we override the configure method that takes in the HTTP security parameter.
By default, the filter chain matcher is always any.
We want it to only secure the admin site.
So we will add an antMatcher with the admin site URI.
Then add the digest filter and the digest entry
point into the exceptions handler.
Finally,
we indicate that all requests to admin must be
authenticated and have the user role admin.
One last thing.
Because we have two configuration classes that extend the
WebSecurityConfigurerAdapter and override the configure method
that accepts the HttpSecurity object, Spring will configure two filter chains,
and it needs to know the order to evaluate them.
By default, it assigns an order value of 100.
But you cannot have two filter chains with the same order value.
Let's give the admin configuration class an order of
101 by using the Order annotation.
Okay, that's it.
Let's kick off the server and test this.
If we access the admin site, it should be using digest.
However, it seems to still be using basic.
Hmm, let's see what's going on.
If we add a breakpoint and look at the FilterChainProxy,
we can see two expected filter chains.
Basically,
by having two configured classes extending the WebSecurityConfigurerAdapter,
Spring configures two independent filter chains.
The FilterChainProxy will check each filter in order to
see which one matches the request.
The first chain in the list has an anyMatcher and has the
BasicAuthenticationFilter and entry point,
so it will match all requests, including admin.
Hence, the second one will never be evaluated.
One way we can solve this is by changing the matcher to be
more specific and exclude the admin URI.
However, an easier and better way would be to make the digest one evaluate first.
To do this, we can add the order annotation.
We will make the admin configuration that uses digest order 1 and basic order 2.
Let's try to access the admin page again.
Now the chain for admin is evaluated first.
The admin login pop-up now has the admin realm displayed.
And the header returned to the browser indicates
digest authentication is required.
If we log in this time,
the browser adds an authorization property to the header with the
digest details required for authentication,
the username, realm, server, nonce, the URI we want to access,
the hash credentials, quality of protection,
and the nonce count.
The client increments the nonce count each time it
makes a request using the same nonce.
If the server receives the nonce count twice, it could be a replay attack.
In the authorization header value, the key bit is the response property,
which is the encoded credential.
In this instance, our browser selected the qop,
the quality of protection, as auth,
which is defined in the RFC 2617 as the first hash,
which we'll call here HA1, an MD5 of the username:realm:password.
The second hash, which we will HA2 is the method,
example get, post, put:digestURI.
The response is then an MD5 hash of the HA1,
the nonce, the nonceCount, the client nonce,
the qop, and the HA2.
So there is a lot of protection here for your credentials.
The password is encoded and not plain text.
You also have the protection against replay attacks due to
the nonce and the cnonce being included.
It is, however,
susceptible to man-in-the-middle attacks where an
attacker could intercept the request, modify it,
and then forward it on to the server.
There is, however, a version of digest that addresses this.
The qop for that is auth/int,
and it includes the hash of the body in the response.
That way the server can verify that the body wasn't tampered with.
However, it is not widely supported, and Spring also doesn't support it.
The DigestAuthenticationFilter behaves a little
differently to other authentication filters,
like basic.
By default, it doesn't completely authenticate the token.
If we log in again with a breakpoint,
we can see after successfully authenticating the user credentials,
it adds an authentication token to the security context
with a false isAuthenticated flag.
And the credentials are also populated with the password.
Hence,
this is still an authentication request and not an authenticated principal yet.
There are still other pending authentication checks that need to be performed,
like checking the isEnabled or isAccountNotExpired or suspended flags and any
other custom checks defined in the AuthenticationManager.
The digest filter cannot use the AuthenticationManager because it compares
the digest and not just the password for authentication,
and the digest varies between each request.
Hence,
it uses the UserDetailsService instead to retrieve the plain text
password to generate the digest for authentication.
So how did we get access to the site you might ask?
Well the InterceptorFilter will detect that the authentication
token is not yet completely authenticated and will use its
AuthenticationManager to re-authenticate and replace the token
with an authenticate principal,
hence where the password was placed in the token for the digest filter.
This is not ideal as the plain text password is exposed
in the context for a period of time,
which increases the risk of it being exposed.
You can get around this by setting the setCreateAuthenticatedToken
flag to true on the digest authentication filter.
But that would make your authentication limited to
just checking the credentials.
The Spring team actually do not recommend digest as
you can see on their web page,
even though intuitively it might seem that digest is better than basic or form,
even if you use HTTPS.
The Spring team's main concern here is that with digest,
you need to store the password in your identity store in plain text.
Now you can encrypt it and provide a little bit more security.
But the preferred and secure way of storing credentials
is through a one-way hash like bcrypt.
There is way to store part of the credentials in MD5 format for digest,
but it isn't every effective. In the next section, we'll actually show you why.