With Spring Security, you can also enforce security at the domain level.
In our demo application, each user has an instance of a portfolio.
You may want to vary the access to these instances in your application.
Example,
the owner of the instance or an administrator might have full access to view,
update a particular portfolio instance.
But say the owner wants to allow a friend to also view that portfolio,
but not make any changes to it.
Now Spring Security provides the hasPermission
expression just for such a scenario.
And it comes in two flavors.
The first can be used if the instance of the object is available.
It considers the user requesting permission on the instance,
the object instance itself, and the permission required to access it.
The second flavor considers the identifier of the object instance,
example the portfolio ID and the type, which is usually the Java class name.
Now before you can start using these expressions,
you need to provide your implementation of the PermissionEvaluator
interface and implement both flavors of the hasPermission method to
define your domain authorization strategy.
As by default, Spring configures the DenyAllPermissionEvaluator implementation,
which is not very useful as it just denies everything.
Now Spring has an implementation you can configure,
the Spring access control list,
where you can specify Access Control Entries that comprise of the principal,
the domain instance, and a permission like READ,
WRITE into a collection forming an access control list for the domain instance.
To use this implementation, you need to create a number of tables.
Now unfortunately,
this means that you can only use it in a data store
that is a relational database.
Now our demo application uses MongoDB, and as of now,
there is no implementation for Mongo.
Now in the next section,
we'll go over how to create a custom implementation for the demo app.
But to demonstrate Spring ACL,
I have created a separate REST application that uses the H2 embedded database.
You can check the Spring documentation for schemers that
are compatible with your database type.
The first table is the acl_sid table,
or the access control list security identifier table.
It stores the principals and authorities used in our application.
It has an ID field, the principal boolean,
to indicate if it is an authority, like a role,
or a principal, like a user.
Next is the security identifier.
Now if it is a principal, it would be the username.
If it an authority, then it would be a string of type role or authority, etc.
The second table is the acl_class,
and that stores the domain object's fully qualified class names.
The third table,
the acl_object_identity is where we store the instance information
of the domains defined in the acl_class table.
It has an ID, the object_id_class,
which references the class of the instance defined in the acl_class table.
The object_id_identity field is the primary key of the instance.
Example, if this was a portfolio instance,
it would be the portfolio ID, which is the primary key in the portfolio table.
The parent object is if the instance was a child of another instance.
The owner is the identifier of the owner that is defined in the acl_sid table.
The ACL inheriting defines if the acl entries for this
object inherit from the parent object.
The final table is the acl_entry table,
which contains all the access control entries,
which store the individual permission assigned to
each sid on the instance object.
Your application would populate these tables
automatically as users are added and removed,
etc.
For this demo, we will add these with insert statements.
Now don't worry.
It will all make more sense once we start to populate these tables.
Let's set up our security identifiers.
We add our users,
setting the principal to true and their usernames in the sid column,
incrementing the ID for each new user as it's a surrogate key.
Then we add the two roles, admin and user,
setting the principal to false to indicate it's not a principal,
but an authority.
Next we add the portfolio class to the acl_class table.
Then for the instances of our portfolio in the portfolio table,
we add references to them in the acl_object_identity table.
The first field is just a surrogate key, so we increment it for each record.
Next is the class ID of the acl_class table, which is 1, the portfolio.
Then the object_id_identity, which is the primary key of the instance, i.e.
the portfolio identifier from the portfolio table.
For the owner_sid,
we reference the identifier of the principal from the acl_sid table.
And finally,
the access control entry table is where we define the
permissions to the instance object.
First, we give each owner read access to their portfolio.
The first entry is the ID from the acl_object_identity that
we want to add the access control to.
In this case, it's the first instance of the portfolio.
The order is 1 in case you have multiple access control entries for an instance
and want to define the order they will be evaluated against.
Then the sid we want to give access to.
In this case, it is Bob.
The mask is 1 for read access.
You probably would want to give the owner all the access
types for CRUD operations like READ, WRITE,
CREATE, DELETE,
and also the administrator for updating the ACL for that particular entry.
Example,
if you were providing an interface to users to grant
access to their portfolio to other users,
then to make the ACL changes to that instance,
they would have to have an admin ACE entry.
Next, granting is either 0 for denying or 1 for granting, i.e.
to define if the expression gives access on returning false or returning true.
And the audit flags we set to true,
meaning that we want to log all the success and failure events.
Now Bob now has read access, but let's also give Bob read access to instance 2,
which is the portfolio that belongs to James.
Okay, that covers the tables.
Now we have to configure the ACL PermissionEvaluator in our application.
First,
we need to add the spring-security- acl and
spring-boot-starter-cache dependencies.
Next,
we need to create a configuration class that extends the
GlobalMethodSecurityConfiguration so that we can override the
createExpressionHandler method that returns a MethodSecurityExpressionHandler.
The expression handler is responsible for handling
security to method invocations.
Hence,
we return a new DefaultMethodSecurityExpressionHandler and set our
AclPermissionEvaluator and the ACL cache optimizer to it.
The ACL cache optimizer is used to prime the cache with the access control list,
i.e.
the data in the ACL tables we configured.
And the AclPermissionEvaluator will be performing the
permission checks on the domain objects when the expression is
added to method security annotations.
Now both require the AclService,
which is responsible for tasks like translating the ACL data from the database,
etc.
The implementation is a JdbcMutable, which accepts a datasource,
lookupStrategy and a cache.
The lookupStrategy is what performs the lookup of the ACL information.
In this case, it's a JDBC,
which will look up the data in the ACL tables we configured.
AclAuthorizationStrategy represents the strategy to determine if
the sid has permissions to perform admin actions on the ACL
entries of the domain object instances.
The constructor accepts the instance- granted authority that
specifies the role that can perform the admin tasks.
PermissionGrantingStrategy is responsible for checking whether the ACL
grants access to a given sid with a permission value.
And the EH-based cache will contain the mappings of the object identity to
the ACL to reduce the expensive cost of the database.
EH cache is an open source cache and is heavily used in Spring.
Now that was a lot of configuration,
but we now have the PermissionExpressionHandler configured.
So let's use the hasPermission expression to secure some domain objects.
We can use the hasPermission expression with any of
the method-level annotations, like pre and postAuthorize and pre and postFilter.
In our portfolio API application,
we can request the portfolio of different users via a REST call.
The user currently has no restrictions on viewing other users' portfolios.
In our ACL tables,
we configured each owner to have read access and Bob to also
have read access to James's portfolio.
So let's add the PermissionExpression to enforce this.
In our portfolio repository,
we can add the PostAuthorize annotation with the hasPermission expression.
The user must have read access to the portfolio instance being returned.
If we try again, Bob now has access to his and James's portfolios only.
He does not have access to Victoria's or Dave's.
However, Bob still can access their portfolios using the portfolio ID.
So let's fix this.
Let's add the PreAuthorize annotation to the service method, getPortfolio.
This time,
we will use the hasPermission expression that uses
the ID of the portfolio instance.
By using the hash ID,
it will pass in the ID from the method variable into the hasPermission class.
Next,
we supply the qualified class name of the portfolio entity
and state the user must have read access.
If we try again,
Bob no longer has permission to access Victoria's or James's portfolio.
In the controller,
we can use the PostFilter annotation on the method returning all portfolios in
the system and add the hasPermission to indicate we only want to return the
portfolio instances that a user has read access to.
Again, this is useful, but it's not advisable.
It's always more preferable and efficient to add the filtering in your queries.
In your application, you will want to programmatically update the ACL.
The AclService is a mutable ACL service, so you can expose it as a bean.
Then we can use it in our application to create a new access control list,
and you can also update an existing one.
As you can see,
there are a lot of ways we can restrict access to our domain objects now.
You can even add these on controller methods and get access
to objects in the model for interrogation.
Spring ACL can be complex to set up, but is very powerful.
From my experience though, I have rarely seen in used.
In the next section,
we'll create a custom implementation of the hasPermission expression for our portfolio web application.