It's time to test the site's security.
So put on your hacker hoodies, and let's go down to the basement.
The hacker is browsing their portfolio and comes across the following
page with a search text field where you can enter in the crypto symbol
you want to retrieve transactions for.
Now these type of searches should always raise some alarm bells,
and it's worth testing for injection.
By simply submitting a single quote, ouch.
Real back exception handling.
The hacker now knows that there is a database back end and a
definite opportunity for a SQL injection attack.
Now through trial and error and different combinations of input
or perhaps by viewing the source and getting some hints that
this might be a Spring back end,
the hacker tries to use the default table with the following query.
Now this query closes the single quotes and adds a union with three rows of the
typical field names you might use for username and password,
as well as the users table.
The hacker has now all the credentials from the site.
Now there's a number of issues here.
First, the site has poor exception handling.
The exception should definitely not have been presented to the user,
but perhaps may be a default exception page or simply
just returning an empty result set.
Now, of course, the second issue here is the SQL injection vulnerability.
The developer should definitely have used a prepared
statement or used the Spring CrudRepositories.
Again, this is an obvious example.
But again, as a tech lead,
I still see this kind of code from time to time
while performing technical reviews,
particularly when the dev team is under pressure with tight deadlines.
Corners are cut, perhaps with the intention of going back and refactoring it.
But this is often forgotten.
Hence,
it is a good idea to keep credentials in a separate database or data store,
behind an API or a microservice perhaps.
Thirdly,
the password strength is not inline with best practices and is very
susceptible to brute force or dictionary attacks.
And finally, the password is in plain text.
It should be hashed so that it's useless to the hacker.
Now fortunately, Spring Security has support for password hashing, which we'll discuss in the subsequent sections in this module.