Okay, let's have some fun and try to penetrate the site.
So quickly put on your hacker hoodies and head down to the basement again.
As mentioned,
one of the issues with hash- based remember-me cookies
is that if someone gets a hold of it,
they will have access to the site until the cookie expires.
Now, by default, for Spring, that's 2 weeks,
and this could easily happen if the user is using a
public computer or a shared computer.
Here I have Postman.
If I simply try to access the site, it redirects me back to the login page.
But if I copy in the cookie from Chrome into Postman,
you can see I now have access to the user's
portfolio page until the cookie expires.
The user would have to change their password to invalidate the cookie.
Now if the cookie expires,
the cookie could still be used to perform an offline brute force or
dictionary attack to try and reveal the user's password.
The hacker can simply copy and decode the content of the cookie,
which reveals, in this case,
that it's a hash-based remember-me cookie as you can see the three properties,
the username, the expiry, and the MD5 hex.
Now in the MD5 hex is the role password or a one-way hash of the password.
Now it's worth a shot for the hacker to try and crack it as the encoding is MD5.
And there is a chance the password could be in plain text,
could have poor password strength, and the key strength might also be very poor.
Now focusing on the key first, the hacker can register an account for themselves.
Now since they know the password they used,
they will have three pieces of the puzzle,
the username, expiry, and password.
Because it's MD5,
it's quite cheap for the hacker to perform billions of hashes per second.
Here I have a simple app that demonstrates this.
I put in the cookie content.
First, it decodes Base64.
This gives the hacker the username and expiry.
Next we do a sort of dictionary attack with different
combinations of poor secret key choices.
And our poor choice of keys reveals itself very quickly.
The value of the secret key should've been much larger and more random.
It should also not be hard-coded in the code.
Vault would be a great place to put it, which is covered in the previous module.
Now that the hacker has the key,
they could focus on the password in the previous cookie
much the same way as they cracked the key.
Now the major weakness of hash-based Remember me is that if the identity store
is hacked and the username and password hash were exposed,
if the site used bcrypt with an appropriate work factor combined with
strong password rules and additional security pin,
it would be extremely difficult to crack,
even for a single account.
However, the way Remember me hash is configured,
there is a backdoor into the site as the hacker could simply use the
bcrypt hash to generate the remember-me cookie.
All they would have to do is put all their effort in cracking the key,
and that only needs to be done once.
Then all the accounts are exposed to the hacker.
Also,
they don't have to worry about the pin because the pin is
not included in the Remember me hash.
Now only users with two- factor authentication enabled
would be protected in this scenario.
Fortunately,
Spring provides an alternative way of enabling Remember me that addresses
some of the shortcomings of hash-bashed token approach. We will cover this in the next section.