A CAPTCHA,
which stands for completely automated public turing test to tell
computers and humans apart is a computer program or system
intended to distinguish human from machine input typically as a
way of thwarting bot spam.
Now you have probably them seen in many forms on the website you access.
They sometimes can be a little bit annoying, but they do serve a purpose.
Take, for example, our registration page.
It wouldn't take much for someone to create a bot to
spam post user registration requests.
The operation of creating so many users would consume application resources,
particularly in the data store or consume all the storage in the data store,
degragading the performance of the application,
effectively,
a denial of service attack on your users or significantly
increase the cost of running your infrastructure,
particularly if you're using a cloud platform.
Now CAPTCHAs won't completely protect you against this,
but it will make life harder for the bots and will add
another layer of defense on your site.
Now rather than reinventing the wheel and creating our own CAPTCHA,
we can use Google's free reCAPTCHA API.
Now they have some of the very best developers looking at this problem and
are constantly evolving the API using machine learning.
Their slogan is tough on bots, easy on humans.
To set up Google reCAPTCHA,
you first need to create an API key from the admin panel,
select reCAPTCHA.
Now for demo purposes, the domain to add is localhost.
This is because the browser and the code is running on the same PC.
But in production,
you would need to add a domain of your application or it won't work.
Accept the terms.
You will then get the site key and the secret key.
Just like in two-factor authentication with Google Authenticator,
keep your secret key secure.
Now Vault is a great place to put it.
If the key is breached,
then hackers can get past your CAPTCHA security protection.
Google makes adding the CAPTCHA widget very simple.
In the registration HTML page,
we add the following API script and then add the
following div to our login form.
You need to add your site key here.
Now you need a service class to verify the CAPTCHA with Google.
The service will need to make a REST call to Google to verify the code,
so we need a RestTemplate.
In your Configuration class,
expose the RestTemplate as a bean using the RestTemplateBuilder.
Now in the Google reCAPTCHA service class,
you can autowire the RestTemplate for the constructor.
Here I have the secret key hard-coded in the class for demo purposes.
This is not good practice for a production site.
Keep the secret secure.
Pass it in as a property.
Vault is a great place to put it, and we covered that in module 3.
Next we have the Google VERIFY_URL where we pass in the secret,
remoteip and recap response in the query string.
In the verify method, we make a REST call to Google to verify the recap.
Check for success and populate the RecaptchaDto and then return it.
Now we could put the logic to verify the recap in the RegistrationController.
But a better, cleaner, and reusable approach is to create a validator.
You can create a recap validator annotation, Target is TYPE.
Then for the implementation, you need access to the httpRequest object.
So using the SpringBeanAutowiringSupport class,
we can autowire the httpRequest from the thread local each time.
In the isValid method, we check if the g- reaptcha-response parameter is present.
If not,
we fail the validator as there's no point in making an expensive REST call
to Google if the CAPTCHA was not selected by the user.
If it was, then we call our service class to verify the CAPTCHA with Google,
returning if it was successful.
Okay, now all we need to do is add the annotation to the UserDto class,
and the validation will be done for us automatically before
the RegistrationController is called.
Okay, let's test this.
The CAPTCHA now prevents registration if the user did not select it.
If we select it, the user account is created.
Easy peasy.
And we can now reuse this annotation in other pages in our application.
One improvement.
You want to layer your validation for registration by grouping
the validations and executing them in stages.
First,
check the mandatory fields and confirm the passwords and pins
match as this uses the least amount of resources.
Then if that passes, check the reCAPTCHA as that requires a REST call,
which is a little bit more expensive.
Next,
validate the uniqueness of the password as that costs you a data store lookup.
And finally, if everything passes, create the new user and request email verification.