Now what this header does is informs the browser that your site requires HTTPS.
The user browser would then cache this,
and all future subsequent requests will automatically be
defaulted to HTTPS by the browser, even if your user specifies HTTP.
Now this is great for protecting against man-in-the-middle attacks.
It also prevents your user from accepting any
invalid certificate for that domain.
Now in order for the browser to accept the HSTS header,
you need a valid certificate signed by a certificate authority.
Once you have this in place,
the user's browser will accept the HSTS header
provided by Spring Security by default.
Because the current certificate is not signed by a certificate authority,
your users get that scary browser warning.
They then have to add the exception manually and have that
annoying broken handbag in the top-left corner,
which just doesn't look professional.
With Let's Encrypt, you can get a domain validation certificate for free.
So your users don't have to deal with that annoying warning
and can have the confidence that the server they're
connecting to actually owns that domain.
In this demo, I will show you how to generate certificates with Let's Encrypt,
how to configure your Spring Boot application with these certificates,
and how to renew expired certificates.
Let's Encrypt uses automated certificate management
environment protocol to verify that you control the domain
address without any human intervention.
You do this by cloning the source of the certbot from Git.
The certbot runs a small web server behind the scenes to
communicate with Let's Encrypt to verify that you control
that server and own that domain.
It then generates and renews keys for you.
You need to, however,
make sure that port 80 is open for outbound and that
you have Python 2012.7 installed.
Now in order to properly demonstrate this, I need a domain.
So I borrowed one from a site that I'm in the middle of working on,
kasiaphotos, which is not very synonymous with crypto,
but it will do for this demo.
Now if we run the following command, the -w indicates the web root,
and the -d indicates the domain you want to certify.
The keys will then be generated in the following directory where
Let's Encrypt will generate the PEM files.
Now Spring actually doesn't support this format.
It actually supports PKCS 12.
However, we can use OpenSSL to convert between those two formats.
So once we've converted the keystore,
we can now update these Spring properties files
with the new keystore information.
Now there is a vulnerability here.
You can see that the key-store-password is in plain text,
and also there is the location of the key.
Now this make it vulnerable if your server is breached or if a hacker
manages to get the source or the release artifact.
Now many organizations have central Nexus
repositories where everyone has access to,
so anyone can easily download the release artifact,
or they could just fork or clone the Git repository
as in many organizations now, they're promoting an open source culture.
Now I can't recall how many times I've reviewed code with really
great implementations for security only to find these details in
plain text in the properties file.
Now in the next module, you will learn how to secure these details.
For now for the purpose of this demo, this is fine.
Now if we refresh the page, we now have the green lock or,
accordingly to my wife, the green handbag.
The cert is valid for 90 days, and renewing it is very simple.
We just run the renew command on the certbot.
Now the HSTS header should be accepted by the browser.
As you can see, the first HTTP request is now redirected to HTTP.
But notice that the latency was 0.
The browser didn't even send the request out.
It just automatically redirected to HTTPS.
You may have probably noticed that the very first request to your
site from the browser is still vulnerable as the browser will not
have the HSTS header details cached yet.
The HTTP request would be send to the server.
The server will send the HTTP response with the redirect to HTTPS.
And only after the first HTTPS request responds will the
HSTS be enabled for all future requests.
Hence,
the hacker has a small window of opportunity to
perform a man-in-the-middle attack.
There is a solution to this.
You can have your domain included in the browser's preloaded host list.
Now most browsers support this now.
For more information about submitting your domain for inclusion,
go to the following website.
Now one final header worth mentioning is the HTTP public key pinning.
It's an optional header you can configure.
Now public key pinning in another TOFU, trust on first use,
aimed at addressing the issue of a certificate authority being compromised.
You could enable this header and add the public keys
you want to associate with your site,
as well as the period of time it's valid for.
Now in the header filter object, there is a method,
httpPublicKeyPinning, where you can add the Sha256Pins of the public keys.
Now the first time your user's browser receives this header,
it will cache the keys.
Now for all subsequent responses from your domain,
the browser will expect them to be encrypted with the
following keys or their request will be blocked.
However, Chrome has decided to deprecate its support for this header,
and other browsers might probably follow their lead mainly because
it can be used for hackers to ransom your site.
If your server gets hacked and the hacker manages to inject
spoof headers into the responses to your users,
then those users will no longer be able to access
your site for up to 1 year even.
Also, if you lose your keys or want to change them,
you can't do it without a lot of your current users being blocked from your site.