In summary,
you now know how to use Spring Security to integrate an
identity store with Spring Security,
create a registration page and validate user input,
and force password strength policies as recommended by OWASP,
how to use Spring Security's password encoders to
store and treat hash passwords,
how to effectively use bcrypt and why its preferred for password hashing,
and how to securely store your application's secrets with
Spring Cloud Vault using Vault by HashiCorp.
So a key takeaway here is enforce password strength as recommended by OWASP.
Always store your passwords encoded in a hash,
preferably with an algorithm that scales with your hardware,
like bcrypt.
If you're using bcrypt,
ensure the work factor is appropriate to ensure the
application is still performant, but brute force attacks are less effective.
Generally,
the right balance is around 1 second to perform password matching as
the user probably won't notice the difference.
And finally, centralize your secrets.
Ensure they are encrypted, audited,
and clients can only access the bare minimum of function.
That's it for this module.
I hope you will join me in the next module where we will look
at additional layers of authentication, like two-factor authentication, Spring event handling, and Remember me using Spring Security.