Hello and welcome back to the course
on Deep Learning.
Today we're talking about deep autoencoders.
In fact this is a quick tutorial to introduce
deep autoencoders.
So why is this tutorial important?
Because I wanted to point out one thing
that you should be aware of,
stacked autoencoders are not the same thing
as deep autoencoders.
And this will become extremely obvious when you see
the full in picture.
Are you ready for it?
And here we go.
This is a deep autoencoder.
And right away, just because based on the colors
and the way we've structured this course
you can tell that this is a blast from the past.
These are restricted Boltzmann machine.
So stacked pre-trained, layer by layer RBMs,
this is what we have here.
These are, this is our stacked autoencoder.
So basically it's RBMs that are stacked.
Then they're pre-trained layer by layer.
Then they're unrolled.
Then they're fine tuned with back propagation.
So then you do get directionality, and then you,
in your network and then you have back propagation.
But in essence a deep autoencoder,
comes from RBMs.
Stacked autoencoders are just normal autoencoders stacked.
A deep autoencoder is RBMs stacked on top of each other
and then certain things are done with them in order
to achieve a autoencoding mechanism.
There we go.
Just wanted to make sure you're aware of that
and that if you hear one of these terms, or the other,
that you know exactly what is being referenced.
And if you'd like to learn more about deep autoencoders,
a great paper by Geoffrey Hinton and others called,
Reducing the Dimensionality of Data with Neural Networks.
So check it out if you'd like to learn more about
deep autoencoders.
And remember that they're based on RBMs.
And I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then enjoy Deep Learning.