Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial, we defined the init function,
that basically defines the architecture
of our neral network.
And now in this tutorial,
we're gonna make the second function required,
which will not only do the action of encoding
and decoding, but also will apply to different
activation functions inside the full connections.
But also, the main purpose of making this function
is that it will return in the end the vector
of predicted ratings that we will compare
to the vector of real ratings,
that is, the input vector.
So let's do this, it's going to make sense.
So again, we're defining functions starting with def,
then we give the name of the function
which we call forward, like forward propagation,
because that's during the forward propagation
that the encoding and decoding take place.
Then some parenthesis.
And in this function, we have to input two arguments,
one first argument that we have to input
all the time that is self because we're gonna
use our object and so we need self to specify
that the functions we'll use will be applied
from our object.
So self, then comma, and then we a second argument x
which is our input vector,
which you'll that we will transform this input vector x,
that is our input vector features with all the ratings
for the movies in one specific user,
by encoding it twice and then decoding it twice again
to get the final output vector that is the decoded vector
that was reconstructed, okay.
So that's call the second argument x
and now we add a colon
and then we go inside the function.
Okay, so what do we do first?
Well what we have to do first is very simply
the first encoding that takes place,
that is that we are about to encode
our input vector features that is x
into a first shorter vector composed of 20 elements
in our first heading layer.
So here we go.
How are we going to do this?
Well we're going to take our outer encoders
that is self then dot and then we'll use
this activation object that we created here
from the sigmoid class,
because this sigmoid activation function
will activate the neurons
of this first encoded vector of 20 elements.
So let's use the activation function here.
So we add activation and inside activation
we have to input our input vector
that so far is represented by x,
but remember what's we're doing now is the encoding
and to do the encoding we have to apply
the activation function on the first full connection
and the first full connection is represented
by this object here, fc1, so in fact to include
that information of the first full connection
we don't input x directly.
We are gonna input x in this object fc1,
because fc1 is an object of the linear class
so fc1 takes an argument and this argument
is execute a vector at the left of this full connection
and right now since we're in the first full connection,
this vector at the left is the input vector x
and so what we take here is our first full connection
fc1 applied to the vector at the left of the full connection
that is x and since this first full connection
is associated to our object, our encoder,
we have to specify here that we're taking
this first full connection from self
because self represents our object.
All right, and this returns the encoded vector
and actually since this forward function
will return in the end the output vector
that is actually the vector predicted ratings
that will compare to the real rating,
well what we're going to do is modify x
after each encoding or decoding
so since this returns the first encoded vector
in the first hidden layer while this will be the new x
and so I'm gonna add here,
x equals self activation self fc1x.
So to recap, this x here is the input vector features
at the left of the first full connection
and this x here will be
the new first encoded vector resulting
from this first encoding that happens here
with the activation function in the first full connection.
Okay, so that's what's maybe the tough part
but now it's going to be very easy
because basically what we need to do
is do the same for the other full connections
and so this is going to be exactly the same.
We need to copy this line,
paste it below for the second full connection
and now what we only have to do
is to replace fc1 by fc2
because this is the exact same principle,
this x here is the vector of the first hidden layer,
then on this vector in the first hidden layer,
we're making the second full connection
which will encode this vector of 20 elements
into a shorter vector of 10 elements
and at the same time,
we apply the sigmoid activation function
to activate the neurons
and then eventually x becomes this new encoded vector
of 10 elements in this second hidden layer, all right.
And now let's do the same for the third full connection
represented by fc3.
So I'm copying this line,
pasting it below and replacing fc2 by fc3
for the third full connection
and that's the exact same principle
or almost because this time
we're not encoding this input vector x
at the left of the third full connection fc3
into this new vector x at the right of the full connection.
We are now decoding it,
because remember the third full connection fc3
corresponds to the decoding
from an input vector of 10 elements
that is the input vector in the second hidden layer
to a larger output vector
at the right of the full connection
that is composed of 20 elements.
So that's decoding.
The first part of decoding
before getting back our reconstructive input vector
with the original number of features
and the movies.
So that's decoding but that's the same principle.
And then eventually we're getting
to our final output vector
that is at the very right of our auto encoders
and that's of course our reconstructed output vector.
That is the copy of our input vector.
And so this is going to be x then equals,
then we take our object self again then dot
and then try to guess what we have to code next.
While we don't apply the activation function
because this is the final part of the decoding
and therefore we only have
to use our fourth full connection, fc4
without the activation function.
That's the specificity of the auto encoders
when reconstructing our decoded output vector,
we directly use the fourth full connection fc4.
So here we just need to add fc4
and then inside we just need to input the vector
at the right of this fourth full connection fc4
which is of course x.
All right, and actually that's done.
We did first two encodings
of our input vector features and then two decodings
to get our reconstructed output vector in the output layer
and that's exactly what we would like to return
because this is our vector of predicted ratings
and this will be the vector
that will compare to the real ratings
that is actually the input vector of features
and after which we will measure the loss
so that we can then obtain the weight
to eventually reduce this loss.
All right so let's add what we need to add now
which is this final step of the forward function
that is return and x.
So x is our vector of predicted ratings.
So here we go, the class is actually over now.
It was composed of two functions,
the Init function that defines the architecture
of our auto encoders and the forward function
that does the action of establishing
these different full connections
by applying at the same time the activation functions
to activate the right neurons in the network.
All right, so now what we're gonna do
is create an object of this class
which will be our auto encoders.
That's how it works.
You are probably more comfortable with this
because we already created many objects
of different classes before
so remember we have to use non capital letters
for the object and so we're gonna call it SAE as well,
first act auto encoders but that's the object
and now that's when we use the SAE class
with capital letters to create an object
from this SAE class that we chose to define here.
And since we didn't specify any arguments
in the init function of this SAE class
while we have the self argument but it is always here,
you know it's a default argument just to specify the object.
Well, we don't have to input any arguments here
so basically our auto encoders is ready
because it is already defined by this architecture
and we don't have any parameters
in this forward function.
Okay so that creates the object
and now what we're gonna do
is define a criterion which we'll need
for the training afterwards
which will happen in the next tutorial,
so it's gonna be another exciting step.
I can't wait to get there
because that's where the action takes place.
So let's create a new variable
which we're gonna call criterion
and that's basically the criterion for the loss function,
and the loss function is going to be the mean squared error.
And so here we're gonna use the MSE Loss with capital L
and some parenthesis.
And so this MSE Loss is a class,
so criterion will be an object of this class.
Okay, and this will make much more sense to you
in the next tutorial when we use this criterion object.
You will see that we will use it
to measure the mean squared error, all right.
And now one last thing we need to do.
Actually, one last thing that we need is an optimizer.
Of course, exactly like in Keras,
we have to end up with an optimizer,
that will applies to category in descent
to update the different weights
in order to reduce the error at each epoch.
So that's the last variable we need to define here,
so we're going to create a new variable
that we're gonna call optimizer,
and this will be equal to an object of another class.
And actually we have one class for each optimizer,
that is we have a class for the Atom optimizer.
We also have a class for the RMS prop optimizer,
and as I told you I did some experimenting
and I actually tried the two,
I actually tried the Atom class
that is the Atom optimizer
and the RMS prop class for the RMS prop optimizer,
and I got the best results with RMS prop.
So what we're gonna do now,
is create an object optimizer from this RMS prop class.
But don't worry there is still much room for improvement
for you to practice and try to get better results
than the results we will get in the end.
So, now we have to take the RMS prop class.
So parenthesis and actually we're taking these two classes
from different modules.
MSE Loss class is taken from the NN module,
but this RMS prop class is taken from another module
that we imported in the first code section here
and which is as you might have guessed,
the optin module from the Torch library.
So actually, RMS prop is taken from the optin module.
All right, and that's not all unfortunately.
We have to input some arguments in this RMS prop class
and we will actually input three things.
So first, we have to input all the parameters
of our AutoEncoders, that is these parameters here
and the Sigmoid activation function.
Well, all the parameters that define the architecture
of our neural network, and don't worry
we don't have to rewrite all that again.
We have an attribute from our SAE object
which will get us all these parameters.
So to get the attribute we need to get first the object
which is SAE then dot, and this attribute is parameters.
And we add some parenthesis.
So good, we have all the parameters of our AutoEncoders.
And now second input.
The second input is going to be
a learning rate that it's better to specify,
and so the name of the parameter for that is LR equals,
and again I did some experimenting
and a good value I found was 0.01, all right,
but again you're welcome to try some other values.
And then final input which is the decay.
So as a reminder, the decay is used
to reduce the learning rate after every few epochs
and that's in order to regulate the convergence.
So that's a parameter that can improve your model even more
and so we'll add a value for this parameter,
and we'll call it weight_decay,
and based on my experimenting
a good value I found was 0.5.
And here we go, that's actually
the end of the architecture of our neural networks.
Congratulations for following.
We actually took some kind of a more advanced level here,
but that's part of the job of a de-per-ing scientist,
to experiment, do research, and make very robust model,
and you will see that with this one.
We will get great results.
Okay, so now that we're done,
we're going to select all this section
to define our class SAE
and create this object of this class
and besides we're defining a criterion and an optimizer.
So let's do this, let's press command and control
plus enter to execute.
And here we go, the class is now created.
So basically that created our AutoEncoder
and remember that the class,
or the instructions to build the AutoEncoder,
and this line of code creates the AutoEncoder
because it creates an object of this class.
So, that's it for this tutorial
and in the next of tutorial we're gonna make the code
to do the training,
and that will get us closer to the exciting phase
where we see our model learning,
and of course eventually the final results
with the test set performance.
So we'll see all this in the next tutorials
and until then enjoy the learning.