Hello and welcome to
the almost last step of this part two building the RNN,
well at least this is the last step of
the architecture of the neural network.
What's left to do is just to add the outward layer
and that's exactly what we'll do in this tutorial.
And it's going to be very efficient,
it's actually very simple.
We just need to take our regressor,
it's actually exactly the same as for
the ANN and the CNN.
We take our regressor, or classifier,
then dot, then we add,
again the add method from sequential class,
to add this final outward layer of our neural network.
And now the important question is
which class are we gonna use to add this outward layer?
Well since this time we're not adding an LSTM layer,
but a classic fully connected layer,
you know because the outward layer is fully connected
to the previous LSTM layer,
the fourth one that we added here,
well in that case to make a full connection
we need to use the dense class
exactly as we did for ANN and CNN.
So let's do this.
Let's specify in the add method here dense,
the dense class,
and now we have to input one argument,
only one which will correspond to
the number of neurons there needs to be,
you must not choose it there is only one possibility,
there needs to be in this outward layer.
And so since we're predicting a real value
corresponding to the stock price,
well the output has only one dimension
and this one dimension is exactly what we need to input.
And the argument for that is units,
basically units corresponds to
the number of neurons there should be in this outward layer,
and that corresponds exactly to
the dimension of the outward layer, which is one.
Alright, so lets add units equals one,
our stock price,
at time T plus one
which is exactly what we have to predict.
Lets select this line and execute
and there we go, we have our final layer,
the outward layer, of our recurrent neural network.
So congratulations, you are now done
with the architecture of our super robust
LSTM recurrent neural network,
and now we have two remaining steps.
The first one is compiling the RNN
with a powerful optimizer and the right loss,
which will be the mean squared error
because we're doing some regression
and the second step,
and the last step of this part two building the RNN,
is of course to fit this neural network that we make
to our training set.
And our training set is composed of x train,
that's the right data structure
that is expected by the neural networks
so we need to take x train and not training set,
or training set scaled,
and of course we will need to specify the output
when fitting the regressor to our training sets
because the output contains the ground truth
that is the stock price at time T plus one.
We're training the RNN on the truth,
the true stock price that is happening at time T plus one
after the 60 produced stock prices
during the 60 produced financial days
and so that's why we also need to include the ground truth
and therefore y train.
So we will do these last two steps
in the next two tutorials and until then,
enjoy deep learning.