Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
In this one we are going to compile the RNN
with the right optimizer
and the right loss function.
So, we have done this before.
We first start by taking our regressor,
this time regressor because we are
predicting a continuous value
and, we add a dot and then, of course,
we use the compile
method, which is another method
of the sequential class.
And in this compile method
well, this time for our regression problem here,
we need to input two arguments
and these are gonna be of course,
the optimizer and the loss function.
So, let's start with the optimizer,
op-ti-mi-zer like that is the name of the parameter
and this will be equal to
well, here we have a choice.
Because you will see that for rec renewal networks
in general, and especially in the keras documentation,
that an RMS prop optimizer is recommended.
So, if we look at the keras documentation,
which is on the SIMS site as what we looked at
for our input shapes.
Well, let's try and look for it.
We're looking for the optimizer and I think,
that if we scroll down here we will find optimizers.
There we go,
So, as you can see you have all
the optimizers you can use in keras
and here is the RMS prop that I just talked about.
So it is some kind of an advanced
stochastic gradient descent optimizer.
And as you can see here,
this optimizer is usually a good choice
for recurrent neural networks.
So, that's the first option you can try.
Try with an RMS prop.
However, with our implementation
we're not gonna use an RMS prop
and that's for the simple reason that I have experimented
with another optimizer which is
the one you're very familiar with;
it is the Adam optimizer.
The Adam optimizer is always a safe choice.
It's always a good choice because it is very powerful
and it always performs some
relevant updates of the weights.
And therefore, in our implementation we are gonna use
the Adam optimizer.
Which, if you scroll down even more
you should be able to find.
Here we go,
Adam, Adam optimizer.
And you can by the way see the arguments
that you have to input.
If by any chance you are forgetting about them
so there we go, Adam optimizer
and then you can find some other ones like
the Nadam or TFOptimizer.
But the most relevant ones for ANN's are
RMS prop or Adam.
And as far as we're concerned,
with our problem we are going to choose
the Adam optimizer.
So let's go back to python
and let's put here in quotes,
adam, no capital letters, just like that
exactly like before.
Perfect.
So now we have our Adam optimizer
and now we need to input the second argument
of this compile method,
which is the loss.
And the name of the parameter for the loss is
loss; just like that.
And now,
this time things are gonna change.
We're not doing classification anymore.
So the loss is not gonna be binary cross entropy.
This time, we're dealing with a regression problem
because we have to predict a continuous value
and the loss for this kind of problem is
the mean squared error.
Which makes sense because
the error can be measured this time
by the mean of the squared differences
between the predictions and the targets.
And by targets I mean
the real values.
So that's what the loss is for regression
and it is called the mean squared error and very simply
the name that we have to type here
for this loss
is mean
underscore
squared
error.
Just like that.
Mean squared error,
also sometimes called MSE.
Alright perfect so let's execute this.
I'm selecting this and, execute.
Alright perfect.
Now our regressor is compiled with a powerful optimizer
and the right loss function.
And there you go, we are done with compiling the RNN.
Another step done.
And now we're gonna move on to
the final step of this part two;
which will be about of course fitting the RNN
to the training set
which I remind is composed of
X train and Y train.
So that's exactly what we'll do in the next
and final tutorial of part two
and until then, enjoy Deep Learning