Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
Alright so time to create our first RBM object
so this is going to be a very quick and easy tutorial
because basically what we need to create this object
is just call the class RBM with the two parameters
NV and NH because basically when we create
this first RBM object well only the init function
will take action so basically only the parameters
of the object will be created that is initialized.
All the weight in the tensor of weights W
will be initialized, then all the bias of the probabilities
PH given V will also be initialized
as well as the weight of the probabilities PV
given H that will be initialized.
Then the other functions sample H, sample V and train
will be used during the training,
they will not take any action right now
when creating the object but we will use them
when we train our RBM model over several epochs.
And so why only the init function will take action,
well that's because that's the default function.
As soon as you create an object of a class
the init function takes action automatically
and then from the object that will be created
we can use the different functions that are defined
in the class and so that's exactly
what we will do in the training phase.
So let's create our RBM object.
So to create this object we need NV and NH
so NV is a fixed parameter, we already have NV
and that is the number of movies because remember
NV is the number of visible nodes and at the start
the visible nodes are the ratings
of all the movies by a specific user
and so we have one visible node for each movie.
And so now we have several ways of getting
the number of visible nodes, well first
we could say it is equal to NB movies
or the other way and that is a safer way
because we have to make sure
it corresponds to the number of features
in our matrix of features which is a training set
that is actually a tensor of features
and to make sure of that we can define NV as len
training set end brackets
and zero. Why is that? Because training set bracket 0
corresponds to the first line of training set
and len training set bracket zero is the number
of elements in this first line.
That is exactly the number of features we want for NV.
So that's a safer way but you can directly
take NB movies as well.
Alright so NV equals len training set zero
we have our first parameter that we need
for the init function to take action.
Then what we also need is NH, the number of hidden nodes
and that is a parameter we choose.
That's how we want to create the architecture
of our newel network.
So NH equals and here we can choose any number
but let's try to choose a relevant number.
We have 1682 movies so 1682 visible nodes
and so well let's see the hidden nodes correspond
to some features that are going to be detected
by the RBM model and among these features
we're gonna have some jars, some actors, some directors
whether the movie's got an Oscar,
whether the movie's rather old or new.
Well we can detect many features
in all our database of 1682 movies.
So the number of hidden nodes corresponds
to the number of features we want to detect.
So let's say that we want to start by detecting
100 features, maybe that's a good start
and of course then you can practice,
you can try some other models,
create some other RBM objects you know
to test several models and compare them
and so you can try to detect some more features
or even less features, it's actually hard to say right now
what is the optimal number of features
but this NH parameter is totally tunable.
You will definitely improve your model
by trying to tune this number of hidden nodes parameter.
Alright so we have our NH and then what do we need?
Well there is one more parameter
that was not highlighted yet and that is the batch size.
We already mentioned this concept of batch
you know when we created this dimension here, one.
That corresponds to the batch
and that's because when we train our algorithm
we will not update the weights after each observation,
we will update the weights after several observations
that will all go into a a batch
and so the batches will have each one
the same number of observations.
So this additional parameter that we can tune as well
to try to improve the model in the end
is the batch size so right now
I'm just creating a new variable that I'm calling batch size
and again we have to start with something.
We have to start with the batch size so that can be one,
in that case you do online learning because you're updating
the weights after each observation going to the network
but let's get a fast training and to get a fast training
we can take a rather large batch size and so let's start
with 100 but this again is totally tunable.
You will be able to try several batch sizes
and one of them will definitely lead you
to better performance results
but here you can see we have a batch size of 100,
we have 943 observations so the training will go
very fast, which is good to start.
So we're gonna start with that and then you will practice
and tune your model to try to improve it.
Alright and now good news, we are ready to create
our RBM object because basically we have
our two parameters we need that is the two parameters
of the init method, NV and NH.
So now that's very easy there is nothing more easy
to create an object of a class
we actually already did it many times
in the first volume of this course.
For example, remember when we created
our class vary objects from the sequential class?
Well we indeed created an object of a class
but now the difference is that we made our own class
so right now you are about to create the first object
of your class, so congratulations in advance.
Let's do this, so we're gonna call our object
RBM then equals and then we just take our class
RBM with capital letters and then some parenthesis
and as you can see we can already see it,
Python recognized the argument to input,
that's NV and NH because Python recognized
the init method that takes, as inputs, NV and NH.
So here we go, we're all ready now to input NV first
and then NH. Alright and that will create our RBM object.
So let's do it, let's select these four lines here
and execute, here we go, we have our RBM model created
and now we just need to train it
and that's exactly what we'll do in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy the learning.