Hello and welcome,
to the step two of data pre-processing.
So in this step, we will be importing the dataset,
with which we will work in this data pre-processing section.
So, as you understood, the tool we need
to import any data sets is Pandas.
The Pandas library, and so that's exactly
what we're gonna use to import our dataset.
So we're gonna put our dataset, which by the way
is data.csv, into a new variable
that we're gonna call dataset.
And this is now that we use Pandas,
we take our shortcut pd, that we gave here and then dot.
And then we're gonna use one of the functions,
of Pandas, because Pandas is a library
that contains many functions and some classes.
And now we're gonna use on of these functions.
And the function we wanna use,
is the function that imports any datasets,
and this function is called read_csv,
you have it right here.
Read_csv and now we add some parenthesis,
because we have to input some arguments.
And in fact we only need to input one argument
and that is the name of our dataset.
Which we have to put in quotes, like this.
And now what we simply need to write
is the name of the dataset, that is Data.csv.
As simple as that, this will import the dataset.
We can check, if I select this line and execute.
My dataset is well imported, we can check it out
in variable explorer and here it is, that's the dataset.
So, let's quickly explain what this dataset is about.
Well first, this dataset is just an example of
how datasets work in machinery, and so don't pay attention
to the little size of the datasets.
Of course later we will work on much larger datasets,
but this is just to explain how datasets work in machinery.
And so here we have some information of customers,
these informations are the country, the age and the salary.
And based on these informations we would like to predict,
if the customer purchased a certain product.
So the value of the dependent variable purchased is no,
if the customer didn't buy the product,
and yes if the customer bought the product.
So the first thing to understand that is very important,
is that most of the time, we have our features
in columns and our observations in lines.
So here we have 10 observations.
Then the second very important thing to understand is,
the difference between the independent variables
and the dependent variable.
In most datasets, in supervised machinery,
you will have independent variables
and one dependent variable, that you want to predict.
So what is the difference between the two?
Well, the dependent variable is the variable you
want to predict and the independent variables,
are the variables you want to use
to predict the dependent variable.
So in other words, the independent variables
are the predictors and the dependent variable
is the variable to be predicted.
So that's very important to understand.
And now, now that we understand this difference,
well that leads us to the third thing
important to understand.
It's that, in Python we need to separate two arrays,
one array that will contain the independent variables
and one array that will contain the dependent variable.
So that means that for now we have one dataset,
in one same DataFrame, but in Python
we don't work with DataFrames and we work with arrays.
And that's why we had to import the numpy library here.
Because it I with this library,
that we will work with arrays.
So now, what we have to do is to create
the matrix of features, that is the matrix of
independent variables that we will put in one separate array
and we will create another array, a one dimensional array,
which will contain the dependent variable in one vector.
Okay, so let's create these two arrays.
I'm gonna press okay and I'm gonna move onto
the next line, to create these arrays.
So the first array that will contain the features
and we call it the matrix of features, we will call it X.
X equals, and now we need to extract from the dataset
the three first columns, because the three first columns
are the independent variables.
So since we're extracting these columns from the dataset,
we start by taking our dataset, that same variable
that we created here, then dot.
And now we're gonna use another function from Pandas.
That will take the indexes of the columns we want to extract
from the dataset, that is the three first columns.
And this function is iloc.
And so now, in brackets we need to input the indexes
of the columns we want to extract.
And so, what are these indexes?
Well, indexes in Python start at zero, as you can see here.
So this first column here has index zero,
this second column has index one
and the third column has index two,
and this has index three, so basically
we need to take the indexes from zero to two.
And there is a trick to get these indexes faster,
well it's to take all the indexes
of the four columns here, except the last one.
And so, how do we do that?
I'm gonna show you, so in the brackets first
we need to input the lines first.
And we wanna take all the lines,
because we want to take all the observations.
So basically, we'll take the ten observations here.
And to take all the observations we need to input
a column, that will take everything.
And now we want to take all the columns except the last one,
and the trick for that is to use
a column and minus one, why is that?
It's because minus one is the index of the last column
from our dataset, so minus one is the index of this column.
But in ranges in Python, because actually this is a range,
well the upper bound is not included.
So this minus one here that represents the last column,
the dependent variable will not be included,
because this is the upper bound
of this range here, from zero to the last column.
An therefore, a column minus one will take
all the columns except the last one.
Alright and then, to get all the values
in these lines and columns we're extracting.
We need to add here dot values, that's just how it works.
And now, lets extract the dependent variable vector.
So, lets check it our, I'm going to execute, here we go.
X is created, and to have a look at X,
we can enter it in the console, here it is, we have our
10 observations and only the three first columns,
country, age and the salary.
Perfect and now we need to create
the dependent variable vector, that we will also put
in an array and that we will call Y.
Common practice to call it Y, the dependent variable vector
and machinery, so why equals and now that's
exactly the same, we will take the same syntax as for X.
So, I'm going to place that here
and same we're going to take all the lines,
so we use the column here but then
we only wanna take the last column.
And there is another trick to do that,
maybe you guessed what it is.
It's to take on the minus one,
because as I just explained, minus one represents
the index of the last column in an array.
So minus one is the of the dependent variable vector.
So let's check it out, I'm going to select this line
and execute, alright Y is created,
let's actually enter it in the console Y.
Here we go, we get why Y with all the outcomes whether
the customers bought, yes or no, this specific product.
Perfect, so now we did everything we had to do to import
the datasets, we imported the dataset
as a DataFrame with this first line.
We created the matrix of features with this second line
and we created the dependent variable vector
with this third line, perfect.
So now, second step done, we're ready to move
onto the third step, which will be about
taking care of missing data.
So, I'll see you in the next tutorial
and until then enjoy machine learning.