Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial
on Convolutional Neural Network.
So again I have to say congratulations because you've built
your first deep learning model in the previous section,
an artificial neural network.
And as you understood in the Intuition tutorials,
a Convolutional Neural Network is just
an artificial neural network on which you use
this convolution trick to add some Convolutional layers.
And why do we use this convolutional trick?
It's to preserve the facial structure in images
and therefore to be able to classify some images.
So you've got the point.
Convolutional Neural Network are
great deep learning models for computer vision,
to classify some images, some photographs,
or even some images and some videos.
So in this section, we are not going to solve
any business problem as we used to do
in the previous sections, but we are simply going to
solve an image classification problem where our goal
will be to classify some images and tell for
each image the class of the image.
And so we're gonna work on a very simple
image classification problem.
We will have some images of cats and dogs
and we will train a Convolutional Neural Network to predict
if the image is a photo of a dog or of a cat.
So right now some of you might be thinking
that it's not very important to predict
if an image is a photo of a cat or of a dog
but the key thing to understand here is that
we'll have a folder full of images.
These images will be some images of cats and dogs
but once we build our Convolutional Neural Network model
you will simply need to change the images
of cats and dogs in the folder
and replace them by the images you want to work with.
For example, if there are any doctors in this course
well you will be able to replace these cats and dogs images
by some medical images for which you have to predict
the category it belongs to.
So for example, if you are working with brain images
and you have to predict if this brain image
contains a tumor or not, well provided you know
the answers of many observations
like thousands of observations, then you will be able to
train a Convolutional Neural Network to predict
if some new brain image contains a tumor, yes or no.
So, I'm not a doctor here so I hope
I'm not telling you things that don't make sense,
but I know that deep learning is used in medicine
for medical imaging, and I also know they use
Convolutional Neural Networks to accelerate cancer research
as we can see in this article right here.
So that's the point.
We are working with very simple images.
Images of cats and dogs.
But then you will be able to replace them
by whatever images you want if you need to predict
some categories for your images.
Okay so right now what we're going to do is
prepare our work environment for our
Convolutional Neural Network.
Because you're going to see that things are going to change
compared to what we used to work with earlier.
Because remember, so far in this course,
the data set we used to work with were tables.
Tables containing some independent variables
and one dependent variable.
And now we have some images, so we need to do some
image pre-processing to be able to input these images
in our Convolutional Neural Network.
So how can we do that?
Well first, let's set the right folder
in our working directory.
So we need to go to file, explore,
then we go to our Deep Learning A - Z folder.
Right now it is on my desktop, like last time.
So we double click on it.
Right now we're still in Volume 1 - Supervised Deep Learning
so we open it.
And this time we are in
Part 2 - Convolutional Neural Networks.
So let's go inside and after the CNN Intuition lectures
that you had with Kirill
you are now ready to build the CNN
and therefore we want to choose this folder here.
Section 8 - Building the CNN, and here we go
that's the folder we want to set as working directory.
Make sure that you have the data set folder
and I will explain what it is in the next tutorial.
Okay now to set this folder as working directory
we need to click on the tool button here
and then we click on set console working directory.
Here we go, now we are ready to start building
our Convolutional Neural Network.
So let's start doing this in the next tutorial
and until then, enjoy deep learning!