Hello, and welcome back
to the course on deep learning.
Today is a clarity tutorial.
Today we're going to just quickly mention
on why we need to revisit K-Means clustering.
And then, we'll proceed with the course.
So, let's have a look.
Here we've got a image, a screenshot from one of
our previous courses, a course that Hadelin and I created
sometime ago called machine learning A to Zed,
and I know it seems kind of odd you've got
a course inside a course.
So it's like Inception, but the point of this
tutorial is just to mention that
the next video in our current course
is a video from that course on machine learning A to Zed.
We've specifically taken that video to refresh
your knowledge, or even if you haven't learned about
K-Means clustering before,
then to introduce you to K-Means clustering,
because knowing K-Means clustering will be
helpful when you're learning self-organizing maps.
And you'll probably come across this concept
in other places if you decide to study
self-organizing maps in more detail.
The thing I wanted to point out here is that
K-Means clustering is relevant to SOMs.
It's not exactly identical.
It's not going to be your like one-stop shop
and help you understand SOMs all of a sudden instantly,
but it will prepare you for understanding
self-organizing maps.
And specifically there's a couple of things that
I like about the K-Means clustering algorithm
and looking at this video that's coming up,
you will see how this whole process of
jumping around, how, like, pushing and pulling
is happening as those nodes, or
as those centroids are traveling across the map.
At how they're being pulled and pushed around
by the actual data points,
and that kind of similar process is going to
be happening in self-organizing maps.
So you'll get you into, it'll prepare you for
the mood of what's going to be happening in SOMs,
and that's why it's useful.
And also the other thing is that
K-Means clustering is a unsupervised type of algorithm.
Albeit, it's not a neural network.
It's just an unsupervised machine-learning algorithm,
but at the same time, it'll also prepare you
in terms of unsupervised learning.
So there we go.
That's why we need to revisit K-Means clustering,
and I hope you enjoy the next tutorial.
And I'll see you back here after that.
And until then, enjoy deep learning.