Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So, in the previous tutorial we introduced
Convolutional Neural Networks and we set the right folder
as working directory, which is this folder
containing our cnn.py file that we're about to make
and this dataset, that we will explain in great details
and that we will also pre-process in this tutorial.
So, as you can see, this is no longer a CSV file
because of course you cannot create a CSV file
where you have your images separated by some commas,
that wouldn't make any sense.
So, instead of having a CSV, I have a dataset.
I'm not going to open it right now, but basically
what there is in this dataset are all
our images of cats and dogs.
But this dataset has a special structure,
a structure that will make our life easier
and the life of the CNN model easier as well.
Because, let's think about it for a minute,
how can we make a training set and a test set
where the independent variables are now the pixels
distributed in 3D arrays, and therefore not distributed
like in the previous dataset where we had our independent
variables in columns, next to the final column
that contained the dependent variable.
Here, since our dataset no longer has the structure
where the rows are the observations and the columns
are the independent variables
and the dependent variable next to each other,
then we cannot add explicitly the dependent variable
in our dataset because it wouldn't make much sense to add
this dependent variable column along the 3D arrays
representing the images.
And, you know, when we train a machinery model
we always need the dependent variable
to have the real results that are required
to understand the correlations
between the information contained in the
independent variables, and the real result
contained in the dependent variable.
But here, since we cannot add this dependent variable
column in the same table, how can we extract
the info of this dependent variable?
Well, we have several solutions.
A classic solution is to only have a dataset
containing our images, separated in two different folders,
a folder for the training set
and a folder for the test set.
And then since each of the images has a name,
the name of the JPEG or PNG file,
well you know what we can do, and that's the first solution,
is to name each of these images by the category
of the image, that is cat or dog, and add, for example,
a number to differentiate all the images.
So that means, that in each folder the training set
and the test set, we would get, for example, 5,000 images
of cats that we would name Cat One, Cat Two, Cat Three,
Cat Four, Cat Five, up to Cat 5,000.
And then, Dog One, Dog Two, Dog Three,
Dog Four, Dog Five, up to Dog 5,000.
And then, that's where the solution takes place.
We can write some kind of code to extract the label name
Cat or Dog from the name of the image file
to specify to the algorithm whether this image
belongs to the class Cat or belongs to the class Dog.
And in some way, we get the our dependent variable vector,
because we can fill in this dependent variable vector
with the label names that we managed to extract
from the image file names of all our images.
So that's the first solution, but that's
not the one we're gonna use because we have
a better one, and a more efficient one.
And, this better solution comes with Keras,
of course, we're using Keras.
Keras is an amazing library for deep learning
and computer vision, and of course, it contains
some tricks and tools to import some images
in a very efficient way.
And that's the solution we'll use
and you will see, you will be very happy to use it.
Because, basically, to import the images with Keras,
what we only need to do is to prepare
a special structure for our dataset.
But it's a very simple structure
as you are about to see right now.
So what I'm gonna do, is open this dataset
and you're going to find out about this special structure.
So here we go, dataset opened.
Okay, so the first pillar of the structure is to separate
your images into two separate folders, we already said that,
a training set folder and a test set folder.
Alright, but that's not the trick, remember we want
to have a simple way to differentiate the class labels,
that is, differentiate the cat images and the dog images.
And so, basically, the simple trick that we can use here
is to, again, make two different folders
one folder for the cats and one folder for the dogs.
And that's how Keras will understand how to differentiate
the labels of your dependent variable,
that is the real results, whether each
of your images is the image of a dog or the image of a cat.
Because then, if you go into this folder, for example
the dogs folder, well as you can see,
I have some different images of dogs.
This is the first dog, this is a second dog here
and a third dog, fourth dog,
alright, this one is cute.
Well, anyway, I have some images as you know
them because they have the JPEG format.
So that can be any kind of images you have on your computer,
you know you can take some pictures of your friends
and replace these dog's pictures by the pictures
of your friends and then you'll be able
to train an algorithm that will predict,
which friend of yours is in the pictures.
So that can be pretty fun to do, but remember,
you need a lot of images.
Alright, so basically we have pictures of dogs here,
and then if we go back to the other folder
that's the same for the cats folder.
In this folder we have some images of cats, so that's
the first cat, second cat,
third cat and et cetera.
So, this dataset is a very well-known dataset
in computer vision, it can be used as a performance
benchmark, to test your Deep Learning models
on this to simply see if you get some good accuracy
and so it's a very useful dataset.
So, this dataset here is actually a subset
of the whole dataset, that you can find on Kaggle.
Because the original whole dataset contains
25,000 images, but here is just a subset
since we have much less images than that.
So, let's see how many images we have.
Well, it's going to be kind of the same
as the business problem we had in the previous section.
Because remember in the previous section we had,
10,000 observations corresponding to 10,000 customers
of a bank and remembering the data pre-processing part,
we divided these 10,000 customers into
the training set and the test set.
And remember the training set contained 8,000 customers
and the test set contained 2,000 customers.
Well, here it's exactly the same for our cats and dogs
images, we have 10,000 images in total,
then I put 8,000 images of dogs and cats in the training set
and 2,000 images of dogs and cats in the test set.
And then in the training set, I put 4,000 images of dogs
and same for the cats, 4,000 images of cats.
Alright, and that's the same for the test set,
since the test set contains 2,000 images of cats and dogs.
Well, we have here 1,000 images of dogs, you see it's
going from 4,001 to 5,000,
so 1,000 images of dogs and 1,000 images of cats.
Alright, so to summarize, we have 10,000 images
in total in the dataset, 8,000 images in the training set
and 2,000 images in the test set.
So that's an 80% 20% split, then in the training set
we have 4,000 images of dogs and 4,000 images of cats.
And in the test set we have 1,000 images
of dogs and 1,000 images of cats.
And basically, right now we did
the big part of data pre-processing.
I'm talking about the data pre-processing
that we used to do in the first part,
in the previous models.
Because, basically, we already imported the dataset.
Then we don't need to encode any categorical data
because, of course, our independent variables
are in someway the pixels and the three channels.
So, there is no categorical data here and therefore
we don't need to do any encoding.
Then, next section, splitting the datasets into
the training set and the test set,
well, that's the same here,
thanks to the structure of this folder.
Our dataset is already splitted into
a test set and a training set.
So all good here and then, finally, we get to the next
and last section, feature scaling.
And so, do we need to apply feature scaling?
Yes we do, remember what I said from the previous section.
Feature scaling is 100% compulsory in deep learning
and especially computer vision.
But, you know, since this feature scaling section
is associated to this whole data pre-processing part,
and since we're not using this data pre-processing part,
well, we will take care of feature scaling later,
just before we fit our CNN to our images.
And so the conclusion of all this, is that,
there is no part one data pre-processing.
Part one data pre-processing was done manually
and then we just need to to come feature scaling
and image augmentation, so that our deep learning models
can run the most efficiently as possible.
And, therefore, since we won't use this
part one data pre-processing, well,
that means that the the first part
of our CNN model won't be data pre-processing
but directly, and that's the exciting thing about it,
because the data pre-processing part is the boring part,
well, the first part here is building
the Convolutional Neural Network.
And here we go, we are ready to build it
and that's what we'll do in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.