Hello and welcome to this tutorial.
Okay so we are halfway our data preprocessing phase.
We learned how to import the libraries,
to import the data set.
We learned how to take care of missing data
and today we're gonna learn how to encode categorical data.
So the first thing that we're going to do
is that we are going to explain why we need to do this.
In this dataset we can see
that we have two categorical variables.
We have the country variable here and the purchase variable.
These two variables are categorical variables
because simply they contain categories.
Here the country contains three categories.
It's France, Spain and Germany.
And the purchase variable
contains two categories yes and no.
So that's why they're called categorical variables.
And now you can guess that since machine learning models
are based on mathematical equations,
you can intuitively understand
that it would cost some problem
if we keep the text here in the categorical variables
in the equations.
Because we would only want numbers in the equations.
So that's why we need to encode the categorical variables.
That is to encode the text that we have here into numbers.
Okay so in this tutorial we are going to encode
these two variables country and purchase.
So as usual we are going to import a library
that will do the job for us.
And this library is going to be the same library
as we used to take care of missing data,
is the sklearn preprocessing library.
So let's just copy this and paste it here.
But then we're not going to import the imputer,
we're going to import something else which is LabelEncoder.
Alright.
So LabelEncoder is a class
from the sklearn preprocessing library.
So exactly as we did when we took care of missing data,
here we need to create a first object
of the LabelEncoder class.
Okay, so I'm gonna call this object labelencoder.
Okay, so since we're first going to take care of the country
categorical variable here, I'm gonna call this object
labelencoder_X and then what I'm simply going to do
is I'm gonna call the LabelEncoder class.
Okay so we simply need to do this.
We simply need to create an object
of the LabelEncoder class.
And then we're gonna use this object on this column country
here which is our categorical variable.
Okay let's click okay.
Okay so to apply the labelencoder object on our column,
we will type label encoder_X,
so that is our object.
then we're gonna take a method of the labelencoder class
which is the fit_transform method.
And we're going to apply this method on X.
But not the whole matrix X, we just want the first column.
And I'm gonna let you guess what to put next.
We need to put the index of the first column
and we know that indexes in Python start at zero.
So the index of the country column is zero.
So here we're gonna put bracket.
We want the the whole column,
so we here put colon to take all the lines.
Then comma and then we put the index which is zero.
Okay, so what we need to understand here is that by typing
this line of codes we fitted this labelencoder_X object
to the first column country of our matrix X,
and all this returns the first column
country of the Matrix X encoded.
So that means that if I select this and execute,
you can see that the output contains the 10 values
of the first column of our matrix X, but this time encoded.
We no longer have the countries written in text.
We have the encoded values of these countries.
So now all we need to do is to take the first column here
of the Matrix X, put it here, so that the first column
of this matrix X becomes this array
of encoded values of the countries.
Because as you can see if I, if I look at X right now, X.
We can see that the first column
contains the countries in text.
France, Spain Germany et cetera.
And now if I select this line and execute, okay,
and if I type X again.
Okay now the first column of the X matrix
has the encoded values.
you can, we can see that France is zero,
Spain is two, and Germany is one.
Okay, so by doing this we encoded the country column.
However do you suspect any problem that could happen?
I will let you think for 10 seconds of what problem
could happen here, and I will tell you what this is.
Okay so The problem is still the same.
Machine learning models are based on equations,
and that's good that we replaced the text by numbers,
so that we can include the numbers in the equations.
However since one is greater than zero
and two is greater than one, the equations in the model
will think that Spain has a higher value than Germany
and France, and Germany has a higher value than France.
And that's not the case.
These are actually three categories
and there is no relational order between the three.
We cannot compare France, Spain and Germany by saying
that Spain is greater than Germany
or Germany is greater than France.
This wouldn't make any sense.
If we had for example the variable size with the sizes like
small, medium and large, then yes we could express orders
between the values of this variable,
because large is greater than medium
and medium is greater than small.
But here it doesn't make any sense.
So we have to prevent the machine learning equations
from thinking that Germany is greater than France
and Spain is greater than Germany.
And to prevent this, we're gonna use
what are called the dummy variables.
That means that instead of having one column here,
we are gonna have three columns.
We're gonna have a number of columns equal
to the number of categories.
So since we have three categories here,
France, Spain and Germany, we're gonna have three columns.
Each of these three columns will correspond to one country.
We're gonna have the France column,
the Spain column and the Germany column.
And in each column there is gonna be either one or zero.
So for example if we are in the France Column,
it's gonna be one if the country is France
and zero if the country is not France.
So let's do this, let's create those dummy variables.
To create those dummy variables,
we're gonna use another class,
because the labelencoder only encodes the values
without bothering if there is order or not.
So we're gonna use another class here,
which is the OneHotEncoder class,
cool name right?
OneHotEncoder.
Okay.
Okay and as usual we're gonna create
a onehotencoder object.
so I'm going to call it onehotencoder equals,
so that's the object and here we're gonna call the class
OneHotEncoder with the capitals
OneHotEncoder
and parentheses.
Because we're calling the class.
And now let's inspect this class.
So here I just type command and control plus I.
Which means inspect.
And if I put that below we have information
about the OneHotEncoder class.
Let's look at the parameters to see what we have to input.
Okay the first parameter is n_values,
so that's the number of values for feature.
We don't really care about that, but an important parameter
is the second one, categorical features.
Specify what features are treated as categorical.
So basically what this means is that we need to specify
the index of the columns, that is the column
of the categorical variable, which is the country column.
It has index number zero, so here we are gonna input
categorical_features equals,
in bracket zero.
Alright.
So that way we specify which column
we want to one hot encode the categories.
Okay so now our object is ready,
and now we need to fit it to our matrix X.
So let's do this, it's really simple.
It's kind of the same logic every time.
We are gonna type X equals because we want to transform X,
then we use our object onehotencoder.fit_transform
then in parentheses we type X and we don't have to only
take the first column of X because here we specified
the zero index, so that's fine.
And then we just need to add toarray and parentheses.
Okay so that will one hot encode the variable X.
And you will see exactly what it's going to do.
Okay, so now we must not forget to reselect
and execute this line because we imported a new library,
which is the OneHotEncoder so execute.
Okay.
And now let's select these two lines and execute.
Alright.
And now let's have a look at X.
I'm gonna type X here.
Or okay so maybe it's better to look at it from here.
Let's look at it from here, X, alright.
I'm gonna change the format
because I don't want all the decimals.
So three is the number of decimals.
So I'm gonna put zero here to have zero decimals.
Let's click on okay.
And here ait is, we have zero decimals.
Let's open our dataset too.
Okay so as I told you the first column here, country,
was replaced by three columns,
these, this column, this column and this column.
And then we still have our two columns
which is the age and the salary.
So when I was explaining is that,
this first column here corresponds to Frnace.
This second column here corresponds to Germany.
And this third column here corresponds to Spain.
So here for example let's take the first line.
We know that the first line
that has index zero is the country France.
And since the first observation is France,
then that means that this first column here is gonna be one.
because this corresponds to the France column.
Then since the second column is Germany,
then it's gonna be a zero here
because the first observation is France and not Germany.
And same for Spain the third column here is Spain.
And it's a zero because the first observation
is France and not Spain.
And that is how you encode dummy variables,
by making sure that the machine learning models
don't attribute an order into the categorical variables.
Okay so let's click on okay here.
And now let's take care of the second variable
which is the purchase one.
And now be relieved, we won't have to use onehotencoder.
we will just need to use labelencoder
because since this is the dependent variable,
the machine learning model will know
that it's a category and that there is no order
between the two.
So for the purchase column here,
which is the dependent variable we are only going to use
labelencoder and that's what we're going to do.
So we're gonna do it very quickly.
I'm just going to copy this and paste it here.
then we have to create a new object here.
So we're gonna call it labelencoder_y.
We cannot choose this object labelencoder_X
because this was fitted to the X column here.
So that's why we need to create a new object.
And here we just need to replace the first column of X by Y.
and same as here, Y.
and let's not forget to replace X by Y here.
And that's ready.
We created our object of the LabelEncoder class
that will be fitted to Y and that will transform y
into an encoded variable vector.
So let's select these two lines here.
And press command and control enter to execute.
Here it is.
Now let's have a look at Y.
Okay so let's open a dataset first.
You see that in the dataset the purchase column
has the two categories yes and no.
And now if we look at our vector Y,
it is encoded and the LabelEncoder class
attributed zero to no, and one to yes.
Perfect.
We're all good.
We encoded our categorical data and now you know everything
that there is to know about encoding categorical data.
So Congratulations.
I know this was quite a long tutorial,
but we almost did the most difficult part.
We're approaching soon the fun and exciting parts
about making models.
So we are almost there.
Hang on for one or two more tutorials,
and this is gonna get very exciting.
Thank you for watching this tutorial
and I look forward to seeing you in the next tutorial.
Until then enjoy machine learning.