Hello, and welcome back
to the course on deep learning.
Now that we've seen neural networks in action,
it's time for us to find out how they learn.
So, let's dive straight into it.
There are two fundamentally different approaches
to getting a program to do
what you want it to do.
One is hard-coded coding, where you actually
tell the program specific rules and
what outcomes you want, and you just
guide it throughout the whole way,
and you account for all the possible options
that the program has to deal with.
On the other hand, you have neural networks
where you create a
facility for the program to be able to
understand what it is doing on it's own,
so you basically create this neural network
where you provide it inputs,
you tell it which one has outputs,
and then you let it figure everything out on its own.
Two fundamentally different approaches,
and that is something to keep in mind
as we go through these tutorials.
Our goal is to create this network
which then learns on its own.
We're going to avoid
trying to put in the rules.
A good example that I can give you right now is
this will come further in the course, but
it's just a very visual example.
For instance, how do you distinguish
between a dog and a cat?
For on the left side, on the project
that's depicted on the left,
you would program things in like,
the cat's ears have to be like this,
look out for whiskers, look out for this type of nose,
look out for this type of shape of face,
look out for these colors, you describe all these things
and you'd have conditions, like
if the ears are pointy, then cat.
If the ears are slopping down, then possibly dog,
and so on.
On the other hand, for a neural network,
you'd just code the neural network,
so you'd code the architecture,
and then you point the neural network
at a folder of all these cats and dogs
with images of cats and dogs,
which are already categorized,
and you tell it, "Okay.
"I've got some images of cats and dogs.
"Go and learn what a cat is.
"Go and learn what a dog is."
And the neural network will, on its own,
understand everything it needs to understand,
and then, further down, once it's trained up,
when you give it a new image of a cat or dog,
it'll be able to understand what it was.
So, there they are.
Those are the two fundamentally different approaches.
And today, we're going to slowly start
getting into how that second approach works.
Alright, so let's get straight to it.
Here we have a very basic neural network
with one layer.
This is called a single layer feedforward neural network,
and it is also called a perceptron.
Now, before we proceed, one thing that
we do need to adjust is that output value.
Right now, we can see that it's just a y.
We need to put a y hat in there,
and the reason for that is
usually y stands for the actual value,
and that's what we're going to be using.
So, y is going to be the actual value,
which we see in reality.
Output value is the predicted value
by the algorithm, by the neural network.
Y hat is the output value, basically.
That's the denomination for the output value.
And the perceptron was first invented in 1957
by Frank Rosenblatt,
and his whole idea was to create
something that can actually learn, and adjust itself.
And this is what we're going to be looking at now.
So, we've got our perceptron.
Let's see how a perceptron learns.
So, let's say we have some input values
that have been supplied to the perceptron,
and, basically to our neural network,
then the excavation functions apply,
we have an output, and now we're going to
plot the output on a chart.
So, there it is, our output y hat.
Now, what we need to do is
in order to be able to learn,
we need to compare the output value
to the actual value that we want
the neural network to get, right?
And that is the value y.
And so if we plot it here,
you'll see that there's a bit of a difference.
Now, we're going to calculate a function
called the cost function, it's calculated
as one half of the squared difference
between the actual value and the output value.
Now, there are many ways you can
come up for cost function.
There are many different cost functions
that you can use.
This is probably the most commonly
used cost function, and
why it is specifically this function,
you will find out further down,
when we are talking about gradient descent,
but for now, we're just going to agree
that this is the cost function, and basically
what the cost function is telling us is
what is the error that you have in your prediction,
and our goal is to minimize the cost function,
because the lower the cost function,
the closer the y hat is to y.
Okay, so as long as we agree on that, let's proceed.
So, basically, from here, what happens is
there is our cost function,
and from here, what happens is
now we're going to, once we've compared,
now we're going to feed this information
back into the neural network.
So, there we go, there's the information
going back into the neural network,
and it goes to the weights,
and the weights get updated.
Basically, the only thing that we have control of
in this very simple neural network are the weights.
W1, W2, all the way to Wm.
And our goal is to minimize the cost function,
so all we can do is update the weight.
So, we update the weights,
tweak them a little bit,
and how exactly, we'll find out further down,
but for now, we agree that we update the weights,
and then we continue.
But here, I've put up this screenshot
of the data, just to make one point very clear,
that right now, throughout this whole experiment,
everything we're doing right now,
we're dealing with just the one row.
So, we have a denizen of one row,
where we have, for instance,
we're dealing with how long you study,
and the variable that we're predicting is
what results you're gonna get on an exam,
and the independent variables that we have
is how many hours did you study for,
how many hours did you sleep,
and what did you get on the quiz
in the mid-semester?
So, in the middle of the semester,
there's a quiz, what percentage did you get there?
Based on those variables, we're trying to predict
what score you'll get for the exam.
And in an exam, the 93 percent,
that's the actual value, so that's y.
So, we feed these three values into
our neural network again, for the second time now,
and then we're going to be comparing
the result to y.
So, let's see how this works.
We feed these values into the neural network,
everything gets adjusted, and weights get adjusted.
So, as you can see, this is, again.
We're going to feed the values,
again, the point here is that we're
feeding in the same values,
so we only have one row.
We're training on one row.
This is because this is just a very simple, basic example,
then we'll see what happens when there's more rows.
So, again, we feed these rows in,
our cost functions get adjusted,
as you can see everything happens along those lines.
As you can see every time our y hat is changing,
because we've tweaked the weights,
our y hat is changing, our cost function is changing,
let's have a look again.
We feed those in, y hat is changing,
cost function is changing, we get information back,
feed back to the weights, so that
the weights get adjusted again,
we feed in the same values every time,
everything gets adjusted, goes back to the weights.
And one more time.
Feed in, okay.
And another time, so we've adjusted the weights,
we feed in information,
and there we go.
And now, this time, the y hat is equal to y,
cost function is zero.
Usually, you won't get cost function equal to zero,
but this is a very simple example.
So, hopefully, all that made sense.
Every time we feed in exactly that same row,
because, just in this case, we're just
dealing with that one row,
into our neural network, where then,
the values get multiplied by the weights,
the activation function is applied,
we get y hat, y hat is compared to y,
then we see how the cost function is changed.
Feed that information back to the neural network,
and adjust the weights again.
And then we repeat the same process again
with the same exact row.
We're trying to minimize that cost function.
So, up until now, we've been dealing with
just that one row.
Let's see what happens when you have multiple rows.
So, here's the full data set.
We have eight rows of how many hours you slept,
or maybe these are different students
taking the same exam, how many hours they studied,
how many hours they slept before the exam,
what did they get on the quiz,
and their final result on the test.
And as you can see here, on the left,
I've got eight of these perceptrons.
Actually, they are all the same perceptron,
so this is also important to say,
I just multiplied it, or
duplicated eight times, just so that we can
conceptually understand, but the important thing here,
it's the same neural network.
We're going to be feeding these into the
one same neural network, so let's go.
Let's get started.
One epoch, as you'll hear Hadelin mentioning,
one epoch is when we go through a whole data set,
and we train our neural network
on all of these rows.
So, let's go, let's get started.
There's our first row, and there's
y hat for the first row.
There's a second row, there's
y hat for the second row.
So, again, it's being fed into
the same neural network every time.
I just copied them several times,
so we can visually see how this is happening.
Then, again, it's happening again,
that's third row, fourth row,
there's our y hat for the fourth row, and so on, basically.
Then we get the same values for
the remaining four rows, as well.
Every time, we just feed in a row into
our neural network, we get a value.
Then, we compare to the actual value.
So, there are the actual values.
So, for every single row, we have an actual value.
And now, based on all of these
differences between y hat and y,
we can calculate the cost function,
which is the sum of all of those
squared differences between y hat and y and
all that is halved.
And there's a cost function.
And basically now, what we do
after we have the full cost function,
we go back and we update the weights.
We update W1, W2, W3.
And the important thing to remember here is that
all of these
perceptrons, or all of these neural networks
is actually one neural network,
so there's not eight of them, there's just one.
And when we update the weights,
we're going to update the weights
in that one neural network, so basically,
the weights are going to be the same
for all of the rows.
It's not the case that every row
has its own weights, no.
All the rows share the weights.
And so, that's why we looked at the cost function,
which is the sum of the squared differences,
and then we updated the weights.
And now, from here, that was just one iteration.
Next, we're going to run this whole thing again.
We're going to feed every single row
into the neural network, find out our cost function,
and do this whole process again.
Just as we showed previously,
where we had just one row, and we were doing everything
again and again, again, again,
same thing here, but now we're going to be
doing it for eight rows,
or 800 rows, or 8000 rows.
How many rows you have in your data set,
you do this process, and then you
calculate the cost function.
And the goal here is to minimize the cost function
and to get, as soon as you've found
the minimum of the cost function,
that is your final neural network,
that means your weights have been adjusted
and you have found
the optimal weights
for this data set that you're training on,
and you're ready to proceed to the testing phase,
or to the application phase.
And this whole process is called backpropogation.
So, some additional reading that
you might want to do for the cost function,
and, I know we just talked about one,
and there are many different ones,
a good article is located on Cross Validated.
It's called "a list of cost functions used
"in neural networks alongside applications."
So, the URL is there, but you can just
google for that exact search term,
or search phrase, and this one will be
the first one that pops up.
It's actually got some good examples and application,
or use cases for different cost functions,
so if you're interested to learn
more about cost functions, check out this article,
and on that note, I hope you enjoyed today's tutorial.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.