Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial, we imported the data set
and now we're going to prepare the training set
and the test set.
So let's do this.
Let's start with the training set.
So we're first gonna go to File Export
to see what we are going to take.
And as I said in the previous tutorial, we are going to take
the 1000 ratings data set, which is in this folder.
And in fact, what we're seeing here in the ML-100K folder
is five trend test plates of the whole dataset
composed of 100,000 ratings.
So as you can see, we have we have U1 base U1 test,
U2 base U2 test, U3 base U3 test up to U5 base U5 test.
And so each one of those pairs of sets are actually some
separate training set and test it.
So base means training set and test means test it.
So U1 base and U1 test is one train test
plate of the whole dataset composed of 100,000 ratings,
and the other pairs are other training test plates.
And so what's the use of having several train test plates?
Well, that's to perform K for cross validation
manually afterwards, to be able to train our model
on several training set and test it on several test sets
exactly as we did when we performed K for cross validation
with tenfold since indeed we were training
our neural network content training folds
and we were testing it on 10 associated test folds.
And here instead of having 10 train test folds
we actually have five train test folds
and therefore that's to do five fold cross validation.
But we're not going to perform five fold cross validation
in the section because I'd like to focus on the order
and coders themselves.
And therefore we will only take one train test plates
and we will take the first one composed of U1 base
that is the training set and U1 test that is the test set.
So let's import these two sets.
All right so we're gonna start with the training set
which is U1 base and therefore we're gonna
create a new variable training set.
Here we go and now we're going to use the Penals library
still because we want to import U1 base.
But then we will convert this training set into an array
because by importing U1 base with benders,
we will get a data frame.
And remember with Python we would rather work with arrays.
So let's first import it with benders as a data frame
and then let's convert it.
So same we're gonna use the shortcut PD and dot
then the read_CSV function then parenthesis
and for the first argument we need to input the path
that will take U1 base in this ML-100K folder.
So let's do it.
We have to put the best in quotes like before,
and so we start with the folder that contains U1 base
there is a training set and this folder is ML-100K.
So we start by typing ML-100K,
then slash and then simply the name of the training set
which is U1.base.
So U1.base.
And here we go.
That should be okay to import the training set.
However, I pre checked the separator for this U1 based file.
And this time it happens to be
not a double colon, but a tab.
So you can check it out by opening for example U1 base
on the text editor and you'll see that the separator
is a tab and therefore here we need to specify it.
Otherwise, it will think the separator is a comma
because the default separator is a comma.
So we're gonna add the argument delimiter
equals tab and to specify tab we need
to input slash t like this.
And by the way to delimiter tab should rather be taken
with this delimiter argument rather than this set argument.
So it's good to know that.
And actually now I think we're ready
to import the training set.
So let's check it out.
I'm going to select this line and execute.
Here we go.
Yes, the training set is well imported.
Perfect.
Let's have a look in the Variable Explorer and here it is.
So first of all, what is the split?
I mean, what is the proportion of the training set
compared to the whole set?
Well, we can already see that.
Remember, the whole original dataset in this ML100K
folder contains 100,000 ratings.
And since each observation corresponds to one rating,
well since we can see here that we have 80,000 observations,
that means that we have 80,000 ratings.
And therefore, the training set is 80% of the original
dataset composed of the 100,000 ratings.
So that will be an 80%, 20% train test plate.
And I think that's the optimal training test plate
to train a model.
Okay, so now let's open the training set
to see what it looks like.
So remember, that's exactly the same as in this
ratings data set that we imported in the previous tutorial.
The first column corresponds to the users the second column
corresponds to the movies and the third column
corresponds to the ratings and then the fourth column
corresponds to the timestamps.
But that, as we said, we don't care
because this won't be relevant to train the model.
And so here for example, at the fourth index,
that is the fifth observation because it started at zero
well, that corresponds to the user number one
that's rated the movie number seven, and gave it four stars.
Then, if we take another example well,
at the 260 first observation, well, that corresponds
to the user number five that rated the movie
number 373 and gave it three stars.
Okay, so that is the training set.
It is so far imported as data frame and therefore as I just
told you, we have to convert it into an array
because then you'll see that we will use pi touch tensors
and for this we need arrays instead of data frames.
So let's quickly convert this training set into an array.
That's very simple, we need to take our training set
variable again and give it a new value.
And so now basically what we're gonna do is use a function
that will convert a Data Frame into an array.
And this function is of course, a number I function
that is called array.
So we take our shortcut NP because we're taking
this function from number I.
And now we take this function array and parenthesis.
So that's the best way of converting
a data frame into an array.
And now inside this function, we have to input our training
set but the old one, this one that is a data frame.
So training set.
And as a second argument, we will need to specify the type
of this new array that we're creating.
And since we only have user IDs, movie IDs, and ratings
that are all integers, then we will convert this whole array
into an array of integers.
And to do this, we need to use this argument here that you
see D type and that will specify the type of the array.
And so we'll add D type equals and in quote we will specify
the type which is INT for integers.
Perfect.
So as you see if I select this line now we consider
the train set as a data frame of this size.
And if I execute this, the training set is now an array
that means array actually of intergers 64
and of the same size.
So perfect and if we open it well we get the same values
but this time into an array.
Okay so now we're gonna do the same for the test set,
we're going to prepare the test set
and actually this is going to be very easy
because we will use the same techniques to import
and convert our test sets into an array.
So I'm pasting that here, I'm going to replace training set
by test set, same here training set, test set
and here's well and of course after that
we'll need to replace this U1.base by U1.test
because we're taking out the test set which is U1.test.
Here we go, perfect.
And that will take the test set.
The delimiter is also a tab.
So basically, we're already ready to import the test it.
So let's do it step by step, I'm going to select
this line first and execute.
Here we go, test and import it, we can have a quick look.
So that's the test set.
And same this is exactly the same structure.
We have the users in the first column, then the movies
in the second column and the ratings in the third column.
And so what we have to understand is that the training set
and the test set have different ratings, you know,
there is no common rating of a same movie by the same user
between the training set and the test set.
However we have the same users.
Here in deed we start with user one as in the training set.
But for this same user one we won't have the same movies
because the ratings are different.
Okay, so perfect.
That's the test set.
But right now it is as a data frame
and we need to convert it into an array.
So that's what we're gonna do now.
And actually, we don't have anything to do,
the line of code is ready.
So we just have to select it and press command
or control plus Enter To execute.
And here we go.
Now the test set is an array of integers
64 of 20,000 ratings.
That corresponds to 20% of the original data set
composed of the 100,000 ratings.
Perfect.
So that's done for this tutorial.
We prepared correctly the training set and the test set.
And now in the next tutorial, we will get
the maximum number of users and the maximum number
of movies in two separate variables
because then we will need these two variables to prepare
our restricted Boltzmann machines.
So we'll do that in the next tutorial.
And until then, enjoy Deep Learning.