Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So we just initialized our convolutional neural network
as a sequence of layers using the sequential class
and now we're about to add the first layer of our CNN.
But before we add this first layer let's just give us
a quick reminder of the building process
of the convolutional neural network which is
right here on this slide.
So the CNN building process takes four steps.
Step one, Convolution step two, Max Pooling,
step three, Flattening and step four, Full Connection.
And in this tutorial we will take care
of the first step, Convolution.
So let's also give us a quick reminder
of what this convolution step is about.
So we have an input image,
in our case the input image
will be the image of a cat or a dog,
but here on the example of this slide
this is the input image of a smiling face.
We converted this smiling face image
into a table of pixel values
and this is what we got with all the 1 and 0 pixels.
And so this Convolution step consists
of applying several feature detectors on this input image.
So here on this slide the feature detector
is the feature detector of the left side of a smiling mouth
well the right side but left when we look at the person
and for each feature detector that we use,
we slide it all over the input image
and when the feature detector passes over
the part of the face that contains this left side
of the mouth that is smiling,
well we get a high number in this table on the right
and this table is the feature map.
So for each feature detector
that we apply on the input image we get a feature map.
The feature map contains some numbers
and the highest numbers of the feature map
is where the feature detector could detect
a specific feature in the input image.
Alright and that is the Convolution operation.
This operation here between the input image
and the feature detector
that results in the future map,
is the convolution operation.
And so we do this with many feature detectors,
we will choose in this first Convolution step,
the number of feature detectors that we create
and therefore the number of feature maps
because we get as many feature maps
as feature detectors we use
to detect some specific features in the input image.
And therefore eventually we get our first step,
Convolution done,
as soon as we create these many feature maps
that will form our convolutional layer
and that is exactly what we're gonna build here,
the convolutional layer composed of all these feature maps.
So let's do it.
It's actually going to take one line
because we already imported the packet that we're gonna use
to add this convolutional layer
and so this is going to take one line
and we are gonna start this line by taking our classifier
because of course this is an object
and we are going to apply a method on this object
which will be nothing else than the add method
that we already used to add a layer
but it was not a convolutional layer
but a classic layer composed of several nodes
that's what we did in the previous section,
building the A and N,
but here some things are of course going to change.
So let's take our classifier,
here we go, paste and then dot to introduce the method
and here we go, that's the method we wanna use,
add pressing enter and now parentheses
and in these parentheses we will add the parameters
of our convolutional layer.
So now remember when we added the classic layer
in the A and N section,
what we used here was the dense function
but this dense function is used to add
a fully connected layer like in the A and N
and therefore this is not the function
that we're gonna use here.
The function that we're gonna use
you can guess what it is, it is Convolution2D
and we can use these functions
thanks to this import here, Convolution2D.
All right so now new parentheses
and let's see what we need to input here
in this Convolution2D function.
Alright so I'm going to press here
command I to get some info
about this Convolution2D function
and here we go.
So we have several arguments as you can see here,
64, 3, 3 border_mode, input shape.
So let's see where they are.
All right so the first argument is nb_filter,
the number of filters.
So this is exactly the number of feature detectors
that we're going to apply on our input image
to get this same number of feature maps.
So the number of filters that we choose here
is the feature maps that we want to create as well
because there will be one feature map created
for each filter used.
So we need to choose this number of feature detectors
but that's not the only thing that we need to choose here.
As you can see, it says nb_filter, number of filter,
but it also says number of rows in the convolution kernel,
so the convolution kernel is just another name
for feature detector or filter
but anyway we have this number of rows
of our feature detector and also the number of columns
of our feature detector
and so to understand what it is, if we go back on the slide,
well the number of rows is the number of rows
of this feature detector table
that you see in the middle of this slide
and same number of columns is the number of columns
of this feature detector table
that you see in the middle of this slide.
So basically, if we go back to spider,
well the numbers here that you see in the parameters
of the Convolution2D function,
well 64 here is the number of filters you wanna use,
three is the number of rows of each filter,
and this other three here is the number of columns
of our feature detector.
So basically if we choose 64, 3 and 3,
that means that we'll create 64 feature detectors
that are gonna have the dimensions 3 by 3
and that will go through the input image
to create 64 feature maps.
So now what are we gonna choose here for a function?
Well we're not gonna choose 64
because first of all
if you look at most of the CNN architectures,
you will see that the common practice is to start with 32
you know we start with 32 feature detectors
in the first convolutional layer
and then we add other convolutional layers
with more feature detectors like 64 and then 128
and then 256 but here and that's the second reason
we are working on a CPU,
well maybe some of you are working on a GPU and that's great
but if you follow the installation instruction,
we are working on CPU so we wanna start slowly.
But don't worry we'll get some very good results.
At first we'll get some correct results
and then we will improve our CNN and get better results.
All right so we are not going to choose 64 here
we're gonna start with 32 feature detectors
but then we will choose these 3 by 3 dimensions
for our feature detectors
and therefore we will add here 3, and 3.
So that means that we create 32 feature detectors
of three by three dimensions
and therefore our convolutional layer
will be composed of 32 feature maps.
Then next argument, what is the next argument?
This is border_mode.
So border_mode that's not the most important here.
This is just to specify how the feature detectors
will handle the borders of the input image
but most of the time we choose same here
that's the default value.
So that's what we're gonna choose here
and therefore we don't need to input it
since it will automatically take the default value.
And then very important argument,
input_shape.
So what is input_shape?
That's the shape of your input image
on which you are going to apply your feature detectors
through the convolution operation.
And that's a very important argument
because all our images don't have the same size.
They don't have the same format
and therefore we need to force them
in some way having the same format.
That means that we will convert all our images
into one same single format
and therefore one fixed size of the image
and we will do this conversion
during the image pre-processing part,
right after we build our CNN
and just before we fit our CNN to our images.
And therefore in this input_shape argument,
we need to specify what is the expected format
of our input images.
That is the format into which our images will be converted.
And so which format are we going to choose here.
Well first, let's go back to this slide
to give us a quick reminder that input images
are converted into 3D arrays,
if the image is a colored image
and into 2D arrays if the image is a black-and-white image.
So here since we are working with colored images,
well our images will be converted into 3D arrays
during the image pre-processing part
and so what is this 3D array basically?
Well it is composed of three channels,
each channel corresponding to one color,
blue green or red,
and each channel corresponds to one to the array
that contains the pixels of our images.
And therefore if we go back to spider,
well we see that input_shape has three arguments,
three, 256, 256, so as you might have guessed,
three is the number of channels,
so it will only be one
if we're dealing with a black and white image
or three if we are dealing with the colored image
and then 256 and 256 are the dimensions of the 2D array
in each of the channel.
So here that means that we are expecting colored images
of 256 x 256 pixels.
Great but this is not the format that we're gonna use here,
we're gonna use a smaller format
and that is for the same reason that we're using a CPU
and that we don't wanna wait too many hours
before the code finishes to execute.
And therefore here we're gonna choose a small format
which will be three channels
because of course we wanna keep these information
related to the colors,
because you know cats and dogs don't have the same colors
and therefore differentiating them with the colors
can be helpful to classify them.
So we will keep the colors
and therefore we choose three here,
but then we will choose a 64 x 64 formats
because this will be way enough
to get some good accuracy results.
You will see in the end
if you're working on a GPU,
you're welcome to choose a larger format like 128 by 128
or even 256 by 256,
but you either need to use a GPU
or run your code before sleeping for 8 hours.
So let's input this format
but then there is one last thing
that we need to be careful with here.
It's the order of the input_shape parameters here.
As you can see we start with the number of channels
and then the dimensions of the 2D arrays.
But this order of these input shape parameters,
is the order used in Theano back-end.
And here as you can see we're using TensorFlow back-end.
And the order in TensorFlow back-end
is not the same order as in Theano back-end.
This is actually the opposite order we need to start
with the 2D arrays dimensions
and then the number of channels.
And therefore what we need to input here
for our input_shape argument
is input_shape, equals then parentheses,
first the dimensions of our 2D arrays
and therefore 64, 64
and then the number of channels 3
and that is because we're using TensorFlow back-end.
So just be careful with it,
make sure that you're using TensorFlow back-end
if you're using this code,
and if you are using Theano back-end,
well just input three, 64 and 64.
All right and now we just have one last argument to input
which is the activation function,
exactly as we did for our fully connected layers
in the artificial neural network that we built
in the previous section.
Only here we're doing it for a different purpose,
for the A and N we used this activation function
to activate the neurons in the neural network.
Here we are using this activation function which by the way
will also be the rectifier activation function
but just to make sure that we don't have
any negative pixel values in our feature maps.
Depending on the parameters that we use
for our convolution operation,
we can get some negative pixels in the feature map
and we need to remove these negative pixels
in order to have non-linearity
in our convolutional neural network
because of course classifying some images
is a nonlinear problem
and so we need to have non-linearity in our model.
And that's why we use this activation function here,
this rectifier activation function
to make sure we get this non-linearity.
So let's add it,
it's exactly the same as what we did before.
We input this activation parameter here,
then equals and then in quotes,
we input the name of the rectifier function
which is as usual relu.
Perfect, and that's done.
Our convolutional layer is ready to be added
in our convolutional neural network.
So let's select this line and execute.
Here we go, perfect.
Our first convolutional layer was correctly added.
So we are ready to move on to step two,
the Pooling step
and that's what we'll do in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.