Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So today we are going to convert
our training set and our test set
into an array with users in lines
and movies in columns.
So first why do we need to do that?
Well, the reason is that we need to make
a specific structure of data that will correspond
to what the restricted Boltzmann machine expects as inputs.
The restricted Boltzmann machines
are a type of neural network
where you have some input nodes that are the features,
and you have some observations going one by one
into the networks starting with the input nodes.
And so what we have to do is create a structure
that will contain these observations
that will go into the network
and their different features
that are going to be in the input nodes.
And that's exactly what we are about to do
by creating this array with the users in lines
and the movies in columns
because we will have the observations in lines
and the features in columns.
And so basically we're just making
the usual structure of data for neural networks
or even for machine learning in general
that is with the observations in lines
and the features in columns.
That was exactly the same
for the dataset of our journaling problem.
Remember we had the observations in lines
which were the customers,
and the features in columns
which were the information of these customers,
and that's exactly the structure of data
expected by a neural network,
and that's why we are now converting
our data into such a structure.
Okay so now that we understand,
let's convert our data into such a structure.
So since we're gonna do this
for both the training set and the test set,
we're gonna create a function that we will apply then
on the training set and the test set separately.
So let's create this function.
To create a function in Python
we need to start with def for definition,
and then we need to give a name to the function,
and we're gonna call this function convert.
Okay then we need to give some arguments to the function
and actually we only need one argument
because you know we will apply this function
to only a set which will be the training set first
and then the test set.
And so here we only need one argument
that we're gonna call data.
So that's our argument.
And then when we apply the convert function
to our training set and our test set,
we will just need to replace data
by training set and then test set.
Alright, then colon, that's just Python syntax,
and then Enter to go into the function
to give its definition that is
tell the function what we want it to do.
Okay so as you understood we are about to create an array
where the lines are going to be the users
and the columns are going to be the movies.
So I guess what you're thinking about right now
is a two-dimensional NumPy array.
We could do that, however,
and that's just because we're gonna use Torch afterwards,
we won't create a two-dimensional NumPy array,
we will create a list of lists.
So list of lists, what does that mean?
That means that we're gonna have several lists.
One list for each line, that is one list for each user.
And therefore since we have 943 users,
that means that we'll have 943 lists,
and these will be horizontal lists,
so these will correspond to our observations in lines
in this special structure that we've just described.
So it will go like this.
The first list will correspond to the first user,
the second list will correspond to the second user,
and et cetera.
And then what will we get in each list?
Well, of course we will get the ratings of the 1,682 movies
by the user corresponding to the list.
And so we'll get the rating for each of the movie,
and remember if the user didn't rate the movie,
then we'll get a zero for that set.
And that's why the new converted training set and test set
will have the same size because basically
for both the training set and the test set,
we are considering all the users and all the movies,
and we just put a zero when the user didn't rate the movie.
Okay so to recap.
This whole list of lists
will be a list of 943 lists
because we have 943 users,
and each of these 943 lists
will be a list of 1,682 elements
because we have 1,682 movies.
Alright so now let's create this list of lists.
So we're gonna start by giving a name to this list of lists,
and we're gonna call it new_data,
and that will be our final output
that the function will return,
that is it's going to be
our final array with the users in lines
and the movies in columns.
And so since new_data is a list of lists,
we need to initialize it as a list.
And how do we do that in Python?
Well, that's very simple.
We need to initialize it this way
with an equal and then brackets.
That initializes the list.
Okay next step.
Next step is to make a for loop
because we wanna create a list for each user,
the list of all the ratings of the movies by this user,
and therefore we need a for loop
that will get the ratings for each user.
And so here we start with for,
and now we need to introduce a local variable
that will loop over all the users of the data
that is the training set or the test set.
And so we're gonna call this variable id_users,
and this will take the values of all the IDs
of the users in our database.
And then we need to specify a range for these user IDs,
and that will simply going to be all the user IDs
from one to the max that is the total number of users
which we got in this variable here,
and so now you understand
why we got to create this variable.
So for id_users going from one up to nb_users,
but now be careful there is a trick,
the upper bound in a range is excluded,
and therefore nb_users will not be included here.
This will go from one
to the number of users minus one,
that is, 942.
And we want it to go up to 943
because we want to consider all the users.
And therefore what we simply need to do
is to add here plus one so that it goes up to 944,
but 944 will be excluded and therefore
we will go up to 943 which is what we want.
Okay and now we need to introduce a colon
still because of Python syntax,
and we press Enter to go into the loop.
And so now what are we going to do in this loop?
Well, right now what we wanna do is to create
the first list of this new data list.
And what is this first list going to be?
Well, as you understood,
that's going to be the ratings of the first user
because id_users here starts at one,
and so we are starting with the first user,
and so we're starting to add
the list of ratings of the first user,
and we're gonna add it in this list here
which is the whole list.
Okay so now the question is
how can we create the list of all the ratings
of the movies by this first user?
Well, first what we'll do is get all the movies' IDs
of all the movies that were rated by this first user.
And so we're gonna put all these movies' IDs into a variable
which we're gonna call id_movies.
Alright and this will contain the movies' IDs
that were rated by the first user.
So how can we get that now?
Well, we need to take our data,
and you can imagine the data to be the training set
because then we will apply convert to the training set.
And so let's say that data is the training set,
from the training set we wanna take
first the column that contains all the movie IDs,
and that's the second column, that is of index one.
And so that's the first thing we'll do.
We'll get the first index of the training set which is one.
And then we'll take all the observations,
and to do this we use this colon here
and we separate the colon and the one by a comma.
So here so far we're just taking the whole colon
of the movies' IDs in the training set.
So so far we're taking the whole column here,
the whole one with all the users.
Okay but now we just want
the movies' IDs of this first user,
the first user because we are at the beginning of the loop.
So how can we only get the ratings of this first user?
While I'm explaining, try to pause the video
and try to guess the next thing I'm going to code.
So basically what we want is the movies' IDs
going from this one up to this one,
that is basically we want all the movies' IDs
when the first column equals one.
So what we need to do is make some kind of a syntax
that will tell we want the first column of the data,
that is the training set,
such that the first column equals one.
And the trick to do this in Python
is to add a new condition,
and we add it in a new pair of brackets,
and inside this new pair of brackets,
we're gonna put the condition.
And as we said, the condition is that
data, that is the training set,
well, actually the first column of data that has index zero,
and we take all the lines again equals equals.
And so now as we understood we want one,
that one is id_users because id_users starts at one,
and so we put id_users.
And so this will take
all the movies' IDs
of this first user.
Okay perfect, we get our movies' IDs,
and now we're gonna get the same for the ratings,
that is we're gonna get all the ratings
of that same first user.
And so this is going to be very simple
now that we get how it works.
We're just gonna take this line here,
copy it then paste it below.
And here instead of id_movies,
we'll create id_ratings.
And so here that's the same.
We wanna take all the ratings of the training set,
and the ratings in the training set
are in the third column,
that is index two.
So here we need to replace one by two.
So we're taking all the ratings from the training set
such that the first column is equal to one.
And so this will get us all the ratings
given by this first user.
Okay and now we have what we need to create this first list,
that is the list of the ratings of the first user.
But be careful, this is not this one,
because the one we would like to get
is not only the ratings of the movies that the user rated,
but also the zeros when the user didn't rate the movie.
So what we exactly want to create right now
is this list of 1,682 elements
where the elements of this list
corresponds to 1,682 movies.
And for each of the movie,
we get the rating of the movie
if the user rated the movie,
and a zero if the user didn't rate the movie.
So that's what we wanna create right now.
And so far with id_ratings
we only have the ratings of the movies
that the user rated.
So what do we have to do right now?
Well, we have to create this new list of 1,682 elements.
And we are going to initialize it as a list of zeros.
You know we will initialize it as a list of 1,682 zeros.
And then what we're gonna do is that
for the movies that the user rated,
we will replace the zero by the rating for that movie,
the rating of that movie by the user.
So let's do this.
Let's initialize this list of 1,682 movies,
and so we're gonna call this list ratings equals,
and to initialize such a list of 1,682 zeros,
we're gonna use Numpy which has a shortcut np then dot,
and then we're gonna use this very practical function
that is called zeros and parenthesis,
and inside this parenthesis we just need to put
the number of zeros we want to have in that list.
And so what is it?
That is 1,682 and that is nb_movies.
So here we input nb_movies.
Here we go, that's taking shape.
And so now what we have to do is replace the zeros
by the ratings for the movies that the user rated.
So how do we do that?
Well, there is a trick here.
Try to guess what I'm gonna code next.
Well, first of course we need to take our ratings,
and now what do we do?
So we just need to replace
the zeros by the real ratings,
when rating that was.
So we're gonna try to access
the indexes of the ratings that exist.
So I'm gonna add here some brackets,
and inside these brackets,
we will get the indexes
of the movies that were rated.
And so what are these indices?
Well, the good news is that we already have them,
because that's exactly id_movies that we created here.
That's why we had to create id_movies here.
So this id_movies contains all the indexes
of the movies that were rated,
and so that's exactly what we want.
So I'm going to copy these indexes here
and based them in our ratings.
Okay but now there is another trick.
What is the trick?
The trick is that indexes in Python start at zero,
and our movies' IDs start at one.
And so how do we fix this?
Try to guess what I'm about to add?
Well, we basically need the movies' IDs to start
at the same base as the indexes of the ratings,
that is zero and therefore we need to add here a minus one.
That way for example let's say
that the first user rated the first movie,
the first movie has its id_movie equal to one,
but the first movie will be the first element
of this ratings list,
and the first element of this ratings list has index zero,
and therefore the first movie that has movie ID one,
well, to put it in the first position of this ratings list,
well, we need to subtract one so that we get one minus one,
that is zero, and therefore this first movie
will have the index zero in this ratings list,
and therefore will go in first position
and not in second position.
If we didn't have id_movies minus one,
well, id_movies would be equal to one,
and therefore it will go in the second position,
and that wouldn't make sense.
So that's a thing we must be very careful in Python,
but be relieved that's just practice
if it is your first steps in Python.
This will get very obvious soon.
So id_movies minus one,
and then what do we need to do?
Well, now that we managed to get
the indexes of the movies that were rated
in this ratings list of all the movies,
well, for these movies we need to give the real ratings,
that is we need to put the real rating
of these movies in this ratings list.
And so what we need to do is add an equal,
and since this corresponds to the ratings
of the movies that were rated,
then this will be equal to the real ratings,
and what are the real ratings?
Well, double good news,
we also already have them
because they are in id_ratings here.
So here we go.
We just need to add the real ratings
of the movies that were rated,
and that is id_ratings.
Alright perfect, we are almost done.
Now we managed to create for each user
the list of all the ratings
including the zeros for the movies that were not rated.
Perfect, and so now we have only one thing to do left,
and that is to add this list of ratings here
corresponding to one user to this huge list
that will contain all the different lists
for all the different users.
And therefore what we need to do
is to take this whole list,
new_data, underscore data,
and now what we're gonna do is take
another very practical function
that is the append function,
and that will append this list of ratings here for one user,
for the user of the loop, id_users,
to this whole new_data list.
So how do we do that?
Well, we add a dot here,
and then we use the append function,
and inside the parenthesis
we're gonna put this whole list of ratings
for this one particular user.
And to make sure this is a list,
we need to put ratings into the list function
just to make sure it's a list.
Alright because we really need a list of lists,
because that's exactly what Torch expects.
Alright perfect and now we are done.
This function is over.
I hope this was not too hard.
We had a lot of mechanism to understand
especially with the indexes,
but now it's done, congratulations.
Our function is ready and now we are going to apply it
to our training set and our test set.
But before of course we're going to add here
the final line to return what we want,
but that's very simple,
we just need to add return,
and then what we want to return is the list
of all the different lists of ratings,
and that is new_data of course.
So perfect, now the function is really ready.
And so now we are going to apply this function
to the training set and the test set.
And to do this, there is nothing more simple,
we just need to take our training set,
and then we're gonna use the convert function on it,
and what we do need to input?
We'll, that's of course the training set,
the old version of the training set,
that is this version right here.
And this version right here
is going to become this new version
that is an array with the users in the lines
and the movies in the columns.
So here we paste training_set.
And now we're gonna do the same for the test set.
So I'm copying this line and pasting that here.
And we're gonna replace training_set by test_set,
and training_set again by test_set.
Alright here we go, let's do this.
Let's convert our training set and our test set.
So first what I'm gonna do is select the whole function
just to define the function.
And so I'm going to execute, here we go,
and now let's convert the training set
and the test set one by one.
So we're gonna start with the training set,
and just to check what we expect
because we're gonna lose
the old version of the training set,
well, let's check that we will get
the right values for the first list,
that is for the first user.
Well, as you understood,
the first list will contain
the list of ratings of the first user,
that is this user one here,
including the zeros for the movies
that this user didn't rate.
So here we can see that since
the movies' IDs start at two,
well, that means that the user
didn't rate the first movie, of movie ID one.
And therefore the first element
of the first list should be a zero.
And then the second element
will be the rating of the second movie,
and the rating of the second movie is three.
So the second element of the first list should be three.
And then the third element of this first list
will be the rating of movie number three
because the user rated the movie number three,
and the rating of the movie number three is four.
So the third element of this first list should be four.
So let's just check that in the first list,
the three first elements will be zero, three, and four,
and then we'll just trust what happens for the rest.
So I'm gonna press OK here,
and I'm going to select this line,
and here we go, let's hope that it's going to work.
Here we go.
Okay, so first we don't get an error, that's great.
Then as you can see, training_set is a list of 943 lists.
You're gonna see that these 943 elements
are going to be lists,
so that's another good sign.
And so now let's open this training set.
Here it is, and as you can see,
this huge list contains 943 horizontal lists,
so each of these 943 lists
corresponds to each user of our database,
so this first list corresponds
to the ratings of the first user.
And so we check that for the first movie,
the second movie, and the third movie,
the ratings are, as expected, zero, three, and four.
Perfect, we did it.
Alright and then that's the same for the other users.
For each user we get the ratings
of all the movies of the database,
and we get a zero when the movie wasn't rated,
and the real rating when the user rated the movie.
Okay great so that works.
And now we're going to do the same for the test set.
And so we're gonna trust this.
We are going to select this line as well and execute.
And here we go.
We have our new version of the test set
and it's still a list of 943 elements,
and we get the same thing that is a list of lists
with all the ratings inside
including the zeros for the movies
that the users of the test set didn't rate.
Excellent, so I'm going to close this.
And that's it for this tutorial.
Now the next tutorial is going to be much more simple
because basically what we'll do is convert
this list of lists into Torch Tensors
because that's exactly now
that we're starting with Torch.
So I'm super excited to start.
We will create very soon the architecture of our network.
And until then, enjoy deep learning.