Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial we converted
our training set and our test set into these arrays
composed of the users in lines and the movies in columns
and we did this because in this special structure,
that is the usual structure for any deep learning model
or even machine learning model,
well, the lines are going to be
the observations going into the network
and the columns are the features that are going to be
the input nodes in the network.
So for each user we will have its ratings of all the movies,
zeros included,
and these ratings are going to be
the input nodes for this observation going into the network.
And now that's when PyTorch comes into play.
Because very soon we will start creating
the architecture of our neural network.
But we will build this architecture with tensors,
PyTorch tensors.
So what are tensors?
Tensors are simply arrays
that contain elements of a single data type.
So a tensor is a multi-dimensional matrix
but instead of being a NumPy array, this is a PyTorch array.
In fact, we could build a neural network with NumPy arrays,
but that would be much less efficient
and that's why we're using tensors
as what we are about to do with the torch.Tensors.
By the way, with TensorFlow we have exactly the same.
With TensorFlow we work with tensors
that are TensorFlow tensors, so another kind of tensor,
another kind of multi-dimensional matrix,
and so we could also implement our autoencoders from scratch
with TensorFlow.
But I actually did that and it turned out that,
for autoencoders, I preferred PyTorch much more,
because not only I got better results,
and also this was much more simple.
So let's go for PyTorch.
Alright, now all we have to do in this very quick tutorial
is to convert our training set and our test set
that are so far a list of lists, into some torch.Tensors.
So the training set is going to be one torch.Tensor
and the test set is going to be another torch.Tensor.
There are going to be
two, separate multi-dimensional matrices based on PyTorch.
So this is going to be a very quick tutorial
because the conversion is going to be very easy.
We will just use a class from the torch library,
which will do the conversion itself.
So let's do this. We're going to take our training set.
So training underscore set
and we'll give it a new value
which will be this converted training set
into a torch.Tensor
and so first we need to take torch,
so that's the library
and then dot
and now we're going to use the class FloatTensor,
which will create an object of this class.
The subject will be the torch.Tensor itself.
Remember, I told you
that a torch.Tensor is a multi-dimensional matrix
with a single type
and since we're taking the FloatTensor class,
the single type is going to be float.
So let's take the class FloatTensor,
with capitals F and T,
and inside this class we need to take one argument
which has to be a list of lists
and, of course, this is our old version of the training set.
That's why we had to make this conversion here
into a list of lists. That's because
the FloatTensor class expects a list of lists.
So let's input our old training set
and that's basically all.
This will give the exact, same matrix
with the users in lines and the movies in columns,
but instead of being a NumPy array,
this will be a torch.Tensor.
And now we're going to do the same for the test set
so I'm copying this line
pasting it below
and now we're just going to replace training set
by test set.
Test set, here we go,
we are ready to convert our training set and our test set
into torch.Tensors.
Now, I have to warn you,
the training set and the test set in variable explorer
will disappear
and that's because the variable explorer pane in Spyder
doesn't recognize torch.Tensors yet.
Remember that PyTorch is very recent.
It was basically released a few weeks ago
so it won't be recognized yet
in variable explorer in Spyder.
But don't worry. The variable will still exist,
only they will not be displayed in variable explorer.
So let's check it out.
I'm going to select this line
and execute to convert our training set into a torch.Tensor
and as you can see the training set disappeared.
But I guarantee you that it is still here.
And now we're gonna do the same for the test set.
So I'm selecting this line and execute.
And now the test set also disappeared
but it's now converted into a torch.Tensor
and that's what we want.
So, perfect!
Now the common data pre-processing
for recommended system is done
and now it's time to take care of what is specific
to restricted Boltzmann machines.
Remember, with restricted Boltzmann machines,
we're gonna predict if a user likes yes or no a movie.
So now what we have to do as a next step is
to convert all the ratings into binary ratings, zero or one.
Because these are gonna be the inputs
of our restricted Boltzmann machines.
So we'll do that in the next tutorial
and until then, enjoy deep learning.