I'm not going to take you through a huge architecture discussion and show
you a bunch of class diagrams or anything like that,
but I want to take a minute to talk about why Spring
was developed the way that it is.
Spring was developed to make existing tasks easier.
Before Spring came around,
we used some design patterns from the JEE blueprints to help
establish better code and repeatable processes.
These blueprints helped to establish a consistent way of doing things,
but often still made code brittle and untestable.
If you've ever had to, say,
recompile code because you were moving to a different
environment or change things like URLs or connection
strings because of your environment,
then you realize these are the things that we are trying to fix.
This problem is referred to as write once,
run anywhere and is often abbreviated with WORA or pronounced WORA.
These are the problems that we are faced with.
It can be a lot simpler than this too.
You just may want the actual implementation not hard
coded inside your application. This is what Spring's architecture is going to help us with.