Here is a snippet of just the beans namespace definition that
I just copied to the top of our XML file.
I believe that the misunderstanding of namespaces is one of the reasons
that people are afraid of XML and using XML configuration.
Spring has created this namespace that simply acts like a
dictionary for the properties that we can use to create a
bean inside of our application.
Let's talk a little bit more about these properties.
So our XML declaration allows us to define a bean in XML.
This bean is called a CustomerServiceImpl bean,
and it represents where we want to put our business
logic inside of our application.
There's a few other properties to find in this example as well
that we're going to walk through more in detail,
but you can see the pieces that we are creating here.
The beans are essentially just classes.
The XML configuration is composed of beans just like our AppConfig was as well,
and they're just POJOs that we use inside of our application context.
Defining beans can be thought of as replacing the keyword new.
So whether you are in your application or you're saying something
like your _____ CustomerService = CustomerServiceMy,
CustomerService = new ServiceImpl, wherever we're using that keyword new,
that's something that should be thought about being put
in your XML or Java configuration.
Lastly, we always want to define the class,
but use the interface, and I'll show you what I mean by that in our demo that's following this.