What problem is Spring trying to solve?
Whenever I'm going to introduce another framework or tool into my code base,
I want to look and see what it's actually buying me.
These are the big questions I ask, what is this trying to solve for me?
Well, Spring brings to the table quite a few things.
It increases our testability.
It increases our maintainability or the ability to maintain our code.
It also helps us with scalability.
I call these the ables, the testable, maintainable,
scalable-type properties of our code.
It decouples things and makes it so that we can add caching layers,
things like that in there.
There's a little bit beyond the scope of what we're
going to cover in this class,
but these are all focused at Spring and the principles
behind Spring help us deliver on.
It also helps us reduce code complexity.
And lastly, though,
and this is my biggest point that it tries to solve for us is
that it puts the focus on our business.
The business doesn't care what framework I'm using.
They care about what we're getting coded done,
and Spring helps us get complex code done faster,
makes it more maintainable, testable, and helps remove that complexity, and just makes everything a little bit easier for us as a developer.