project structure in place,
we can go ahead and get started adding Java code to our application.
To do this, it's quite easy.
All we want to do is navigate down to our source,
main, java folder that Maven created for us when we created our project,
and right-click and select New, Java Class.
And at first use,
you may not be aware that you can add a package in here
at the time of creating your class.
You do that by fully qualifying the name of the package structure you want.
So I'm going to type in here com.pluralsight .model .Speaker,
and Speaker is a capital S signifying the class name.
When I hit Enter, it'll go ahead and create this object structure for me,
and if you look at your project navigator on the left,
you can see that it created that folder structure modeling the
package structure and the object class name correctly,
and it's also indicated up here on line 1 of our code
with package com.pluralsight .model.
Now we can enter in a couple of member variables in here.
I'm just going to do a private String firstName and a private String lastName.
And once I have those in here,
I'm going to give myself a little extra space and right-click and say Generate,
Getter and Setter, select both of them, and hit OK.
Once I save this, it will compile it into our application, and that's really it.
That's all you need to do to add the model object to your code.
Quite simple.
Again, navigate to source, main, java, right-click,
fully qualify the package name and the class name.
It'll create our speaker object for us,
and then we'll enter our member variables and generate our getters and setters.
Now that this is in place,
let's go ahead and add our repository object to our class structure as well. The next piece of the