To set our application up for setter injection,
we're going to have to define another bean inside of here
just like we did for the SpeakerRepository,
but before we do that, I want to open up our SpeakerServiceImpl.
And inside of our SpeakerServiceImpl,
we're going to get rid of this hard-coded HibernateSpeakerRepository
reference just like we did for our Java configuration.
Then I'm going to go down and give myself a little
extra space and click Generate, Setter, choose SpeakerRepository,
and click OK.
Before I move on though,
I do want to change the name of this from setRepository to setSpeakerRepository.
The name isn't essential,
but it does make it easier especially for autowiring by name,
which we're going to show a demonstration of that later in this course.
I'm going to click save.
And I do like to clean up my imports.
You can see up here on line 4 that we have an unused import.
That's why it's highlighted in gray.
I'm going to do Ctrl+Shift+O on my Mac and remove that import.
You can also do Ctrl+Shift+O on a Windows machine rather than _____ Ctrl option,
and it should clean up those imports for you.
You can also just delete it manually.
I'm going to save this and go back to my applicationContext,
and let's create another bean inside of here.
As I mentioned before, to do this,
we just want to create a bean just like we did for the SpeakerRepository.
So I'm going to give myself a little extra space there.
Make sure you stay inside that closing bean element that
I have on line 12 of my application.
And we'll say bean and give it a name of speakerService.
And notice I'm doing this as variable names exactly like
we would do in the Java configuration.
And I want to define a class,
and the class is going to be com.pluralsight .service .SpeakerServiceImpl.
And instead of doing the forward slash and closing element,
I just want to do a right angle bracket,
and it'll give me that closing bean element separate.
And the reason we want to do this is because we're going to
create a property inside of here now.
And the property name is going to be speakerRepository,
and there's two options inside of here of reference or value.
Since we're referring to another bean, we want to do reference.
If we were just putting a value in there,
say some string or some numerical value,
we would use value.
So we want to do a reference,
and that reference is going to be to the speakerRepository bean.
And then we can close that off with a forward slash,
right angle bracket, and save this.
Now our beans have been defined,
and we can see that we have our SpeakerServiceImpl created with a
property that we're setting from the reference to the bean
speakerRepository that we've defined on line 7.
So we're going to take that bean and inject it in there,
and it's calling the setter on our SpeakerServiceImpl
that we created inside of here.
That's why I wanted to name it setSpeakerRepository.
If we had left it as setRepository,
then our property name would just be lowercase repository,
so it uses the bean naming convention.
Now let's make the changes we need to to our Application.java to load this.
Switching to our Application.java,
we have to do the same thing that we had done
before with our Java configuration,
and that is to create an instance of the
ApplicationContext to Bootstrap our application.
So we'll say ApplicationContext appContext = new ClassPathXmlApplicationContext.
Inside of here, we will give it the name applicationContext.xml,
and then save that.
Now from here,
I'm going to comment this out just so you can see that it was hard coded
before and we've switched it over to our newer style.
We'll say SpeakerService service = appContext.getBean,
and we want to pass in here the name of speakerService,
and we'll pass in the class type so that it can do this without casting.
So we'll say SpeakerService.class, and save this.
And now our application is set up to run.
I'm going to exit fullscreen so I that I can see the build console.
And right-click on main, say Run Application.main.
And you can see that our application loaded.
So let's walk through what just happened here.
In our Application.java, we Bootstrapped our application on line 9,
as you can see here, by loading that applicationContext.xml that we created.
Our applicationContext here is created inside of our source,
main, resources folder, and so that means that Maven,
when compiling, will actually compile it out to our classes directory,
so under target classes, you can see our applicationContext.
So when it goes to run our application,
it's actually copied that down to our target classes directory,
and that's just where our classpath launches from.
And then we created beans inside of here.
We started off with a speakerRepository,
and then we created the speakerService and did a reference to that
speakerRepository into our speakerService that did setter injection,
then we changed our speakerService to accept that setter injection.
And remember, on line 16, we changed that name to setSpeakerRepository,
and that referenced back to our applicationContext where on line 11,
we said that the property name was speakerRepository.
If we hadn't changed that and just left that as repository,
it would've just been property name repository,
lowercase.
And our application is actually all configured now.
The only thing we really had to any different was create this
applicationContext where we had a namespace in here.
We start defining our beans,
and our beans actually look quite similar to what we
did in the Java configuration.
It just may seem a little bit more second nature to do
you to do it in the Java configuration,
but you can see how we are now wiring up our application the same way. We have that same setter injection inside of our application now.