So we already defined our bean to use setter injection.
There's two types of injection just as we did inside
of the Java configuration module.
There's setter and constructor injection.
Setter injection is using exactly what it sounds like,
the getters and setters of our bean,
and constructor injection uses the defined constructors.
Something to keep in mind though is that you can use both
setter and constructor injection together.
We're going to now show you how to use a constructor injection example,
but I just want to point out that I feel that setter
injection is often better for existing code.
We've seen our simple setter injection and what it's like to use that.
Constructor injection guarantees a contract for us.
There's a few nice things about doing that,
but namely it's that we have our code and our contract defined when we
create that object instance because of the constructor.
A positive and a negative though is that I need to have a constructor
defined for each situation that I want to guarantee.
I should also note that you can use constructor and setter injection together.
One other slight difference is that constructor injection is index
based and not named based like setter injection is.
Let's go ahead and add an injection-based example for our
constructor inside of our application now.
Changing our application over to be a constructor injection
example verses setter is actually pretty quite easy.
So I'm going to go into our applicationContext on line 11
and change that to constructor-arg, and instead of name,
constructor arguments are index based, so I want to do index= 0.
They're 0 based, meaning if I have multiple arguments I'm going to pass in,
I have 0, 1, 2, 3, and so on.
So we start with 0.
So I'm going to say constructor-arg index= 0.
Then I need to go to my SpeakerServiceImpl.
If I try to run this right now, it's going to break.
I want to add two constructors inside of here.
I want to add a public SpeakerServiceImpl,
and I'm going to give this the no arguments constructor,
just the default no argument so we don't break any other
examples we're going to do in the future.
Then I'm going to add a second one inside of here
that is public SpeakerServiceImpl.
I'm going to make this one take in an instance of our SpeakerRepository.
And honestly,
I'm just going to go down here and copy this code that we already have created
for our setter because it's going to be very similar to that.
So, paste that in there and save it.
So our two constructors, one on line 12,
the default no arguments,
one on line 16 that is the SpeakerServiceImpl taking an
instance of the SpeakerRepository,
and it's just going to assign those variables to one another,
so we have our this.repository is equal to our repository we're passing in,
and we'll save that.
That's it.
That's all we have to do.
Since we only have one argument, the index for this one is 0.
If we had multiple arguments in there, it would be 0,
1, 2, 3, 4 like in our applicationContext where we just have index 0 on line 11.
Let's go back to our Application.java and run this
now and see what that looks like.
So if we right-click on our main, and say Run Application,
it'll run just like we expected it to almost like we didn't change anything,
although we did.
So now it's constructor injection verses the setter injection.
You can see the code for both there.
All it took to change that in our applicationContext was changing
that one property on line 11 to constructor-arg, and we have it constructor injection based.