The next piece we're going to add to our application is the service tier.
Now we're not talking about web services,
but more so services as in the business logic tier.
So similar to the repository, we're going to go ahead and click on source,
main, java.
Right-click and say New, Class and enter in our package of com.pluralsight.
And this time, we're going to add service on the end of it.
And for a class name, we're going to say SpeakerServiceImpl, and click Enter.
Verify that you have the service package on the left or at the
top of your code and that the name is correct.
And then inside of here, we're going to do a couple of things.
We're going to add a finder method as well in here and say public List Speakers,
and it's going to be a very similar signature to what we
did for the finder in our repository,
but this would enable us to do other things such as swap out
our repository tier and that type of stuff,
so you may be looking at this going,
this seems like a lot of overkill for a basic example,
which it is.
And we want to do our findAll here,
and we're going to utilize the repository that we just created,
but we haven't imported that yet, so for now,
we're going to hard code this,
and this is part of the problem that we're going to solve with Spring.
So we're going to say private,
and we're going to do SpeakerRepository repository =
new HibernateSpeakerRepositoryImpl.
Now this is what your code would like without Spring in it.
We haven't added Spring to our application yet,
so this is pretty accurate, and we would say return repository.findAll.
Now just like we had with the repository,
we don't have an interface for our service yet either.
So let's do the same thing and say right-click,
Refactor, Extract, Interface, and we want to call this the SpeakerService,
and click the Member findAll, and Refactor,
and it will do the same thing.
And you can uncheck these if you don't like the dialogs asking you to
make sure that you're not changing this elsewhere.
We say OK, and we should see our interface here of SpeakerService.
Now we can move on to creating a simple,
main method that will test out all the pieces of the application that we have just written to be used together.