In this module,
we showed how to do the similar configuration we had done in the
Java application using the XML configuration.
We created the applicationContext, which was just like our AppConfig.java file.
We showed what a bean definition looked like,
and the bean definition code is very similar to the
@Bean annotations that we used.
We then demonstrated setter injection and constructor injection.
Then we looked at autowiring and actually compared that to the
autowiring that we did in our Java configuration app.
We showed the various autowiring methods as well by constructor,
byType, and byName,
and showed you how your application can break using one
approach and succeed using another.
Let's look at some of the more advanced Spring configuration concepts in this next module.