One of the reasons I originally updated this course was because Spring
quit offering a direct download for the compile jars.
Sure there were ways to obtain it,
but nothing as simple as just clicking a link on their project page.
With some of my other courses,
people had asked that it just focus on one technology and
not use supporting tools such as Maven.
Well, like it or not, Spring wants you to download their tools using Maven.
It will be simple for this course though and candidly any
project of moderate complexity should be using Maven or
Gradle anyway to manage dependencies.
The Maven repo has the source, Javadocs,
and the binaries all available for download.
And one of the main reason Spring wants you to use Maven is because of their
transitive dependencies that are required to run the projects.
Spring Boot could be used to set up your application as well,
but it's much too complex and a black box for trying to
show you just the basic fundamentals of what Spring needs
to run in order how to set it up.
We will set up a Spring Boot application later
though and compare the differences,
but let's get our app configured and use Maven to download those dependencies and wire up our app.