Let's recap quickly what we learned in this module.
We covered quite a few things, and it was a fairly large module,
and it set up for us all of the upcoming modules that we're going to go through.
We discussed why we'd want to use Spring and what it's
buying us inside of our application.
We went through and looked at the prerequisites that we
had for our application and set those up for what we're
going to do in future modules.
We built a demo app and went through the details of that demo app and
discussed the pain points inside of our demo app and why we want to
use Spring to remove some of these critical pieces that are hard
coded inside of our application.
Then we went ahead and downloaded Spring and
incorporated that inside of our application,
and you saw how quickly and easily it was done using Maven.
The next module that we're going to do is the Java configuration module.
Now I want to caution you.
A lot of people are real quick to want to skip the XML
portion of the configuration of this course,
and we have even restructured it so that you go the Java section first.
I do strongly feel that the XML section,
though,
helps people understand the separation of concerns somewhat
better than doing it in just plain Java,
so let's go through Java first because that's the most popular, and then the XML section might help solidify any questions you may still have.