our application, we want to create a file where we can Bootstrap everything at.
I'm going to close our build section here and navigate over to our source,
main, java directory again, and right-click and do a New Java Class.
This is a very simple class to start with.
We're just going to call this AppConfig.
Now it doesn't need to be named this.
This is kind of a default standard or a norm.
You could call it whatever you like,
but we're going to choose AppConfig just to stay
consistent with what we're doing, and click Enter.
This is it.
This is all we need to start Bootstrapping our application.
If you've used any other versions of Spring where you did XML configuration,
this would be the start of your application context,
so this is where you start configuring the context of your application.
All of your configuration starts at this point and
trickles throughout your application here.
So there's nothing special about it.
You'll notice it's a default public class.
There's no methods.
It's a plain POJO.
We'll go ahead and start adding annotation to this,
but before we do, let's go ahead and talk about what those configured annotations are.