To start the configuration of our application,
we're going to use an @ configuration annotation.
The Java files that have the configuration annotation replace any
XML files that we could've used historically.
Configuration is a class-level annotation and looks something
like the annotation in the snippet above.
In that AppConfig file that we just created in our demo,
we now put an @Configuration annotation at the top of that class.
Methods used in conjunction with the bean annotation are
used to get instances of Spring beans.
Now, we're throwing a couple of topics at you here really quickly,
and there's a short, but steep learning curve.
We're going to explain what a bean is and what a configuration file is as we go.
We just have to show you these two concepts as we dive into it.
We add an @ method level annotation for Bean,
and it looks similar to this where we're saying that what this
method returns is an instance of a bean and that the bean is now
registered inside of Spring and available for us to use inside of
our Spring application.
Classes and method names can be anything.
Spring really doesn't care.
It doesn't have to be named getCustomerRepository or anything specific.
We can call our methods _____ foo just as long as
when it goes to create these beans,
we have them marked as a bean and in a configuration file.
Let's begin by starting to add some of this configuration to
that AppConfig file that we just created.
I've switched back over to our IDE.
I want to go ahead at the class level and say @Configuration.
And you can see that as we're typing it,
it wants to go ahead and suggest what it should be.
We want to choose that second one, the configuration,
not configurable, configuration, and choose it,
and it will automatically import that annotation for us.
Now this signifies that this file is to be used for configuration purposes.
To add a bean, a Spring component down here,
we can start off by just creating a method,
so I want to call this public,
and I want to return an instance of the SpeakerService.
And I'm going to just call this getSpeakerService.
I'm going to use a no arguments method signature.
And I want to return inside of here just a new
instance of that SpeakerServiceImpl.
So I'm going to say return new SpeakerServiceImpl.
And it's even suggesting to return the implementation of it.
So I can save that, and now we have our method signature and structure complete,
but we still need to tell it that this is a bean.
So we want to say @Bean.
And we can optionally, we don't have to, optionally give this a name.
And I'd like to, and I want to call this the speakerService,
and I'm going to do this camel case, just like we would a variable name.
This is it.
We've literally Spring enabled our application.
We've told it to configure this as a Spring app,
and we've created a bean, our speakerService,
and we're going to show you how we transform that out of the application to be in this registry or this configuration that's now a bean.