Setter injection using the Java configuration approach
is really as simple as a method call.
A lot of the mystery of injection just goes away.
A lot of developers I talk to are concerned with the black box fill
of dependency injection or inversion of control.
And with the Java configuration approach,
it's more visible as to what's actually going on.
With XML, there's a lot of wondering what's wired up and what's calling in,
who and how this autowiring is all taking place,
and that just kind of goes away with the Java configuration.
Setter injection is simply a matter of calling a setter on a bean.
We're going to define a bean using the bean annotation
like we did in the previous demo,
and you can see here that we've got our getCustomerService
method that returns a bean of type customerService or a
bean named customerService, and notice, though,
that we have a setter injection in here.
As we're building our beans,
we're going to call this setCustomerRepository method
on our customerService instance.
To do that,
we need to have a method called getCustomerRepository in our
configuration that returns the customerRepository bean.
This is going to wire the CustomerRepository inside of our CustomerService.
Let me say that again.
We're not just going to call an instance we create.
We're going to call and get an instance of the bean
from the Spring configuration file.
So when we define a bean such as our CustomerRepository here
that returns an instance of CustomerRepository,
you can see that those methods now line up.
I'm going to call getCustomerRepository that's registered as a Spring bean,
and that's going to return an instance for our
setCustomerRepository instance on our service instance.
Take note,
Spring is still doing a lot of magic behind the scenes when a
bean is registered such as these beans are all,
by default,
a singleton and will only execute the method the first time it's called.
That's very key point because if I didn't have this set up this way,
it would create a new bean every time we called this.
Since it is in Spring,
it's going to register this as a singleton and only return one instance. Let's implement this in our code now.