We need to do a handful of things to get our application
set up to use autowiring correctly,
and that has more to do with just how we're doing the demos than you
need to do this in every application you've done.
We're trying to show a bunch of different techniques,
and this makes it a little bit more interesting showing some of those.
To start with, let's open up our SpeakerServiceImpl,
and inside of here,
we had gotten rid of our default no args
constructor in one of the previous demos.
Let's add that back in because we're going to need that for our setter
injection demo that we're going to use autowiring on.
And I want to add a couple of log statements just
using simple System.out .println, so we'll say System.out .println,
and inside of here,
we'll say that we are in the SpeakerServiceImpl no args constructor,
and I'm going to go ahead and copy this because we're going to add
some of these to a few different methods here.
Let's go to the next one, and we'll say that this is the repository constructor,
SpeakerServiceImpl repository constructor.
And the last log statement that we'll add is one in the
setter for the SpeakerServiceImpl, and we'll say that we are in the setter,
and just save that, now, pretty straightforward.
All we did was add a no arguments constructor and the
SpeakerServiceImpl log statements and setter log statements.
Let's go back to our AppConfig.
As of right now,
we are still using the constructor injection that we've wired up.
It's really actually not injecting.
It is configuring the bean, but we are just adding that in there.
Let's comment this out,
and I'm going to leave these in here just so you can see as we go
through each instance of these what the configuration was from the
previous to the next and say new SpeakerServiceImpl.
And if we ran this right now, we are not wiring in the repository anywhere.
Since we want to use setter injection to begin with,
let's go back to our SpeakerServiceImpl and go to that
setRepository and say @Autowired.
When I save this,
it's going to automatically inject that SpeakerRepository bean into this setter.
So when we run this code, we should see the no arguments constructor get ran,
and then we should see the log statement for this
SpeakerServiceImpl setter also get ran.
Let's go back to our application code and run this.
And you'll see that we were in the no args constructor,
and then the setter was called,
and then our other log statements from the other stuff we were
doing with our singleton scopes are dumped out.
So, very simply,
our code was changed to do the no arguments constructor
and setter injection inside of here, and then we went to our SpeakerServiceImpl,
added that no args constructor in here,
and just specified that we wanted this method to be
autowired and injected this way.
What if we want to do constructor injection though?
We were using that before, and we have our constructor still in here.
I'm going to show you how to do this where your beans are fully autowired,
not just individual methods because it shows that demonstration,
that example a little bit more concrete.
You'll also notice that we talked about the component scanner before,
but we haven't configured that yet,
and that's because we haven't configured our beans to be fully autowired,
just on individual methods.
Let's talk about a technique called stereotype annotations first so that we can fully autowire our beans up.