To recap what we did in this module,
we learned that instead of an application context that we could
configure our code using the Java AppConfig file.
We use an @Configuration annotation to define files
that contain configuration code.
We can have multiple files that are containing configuration information.
They just need to have that annotation at the top,
and then when we wire up our application wherever
our main method's contained at, pass in those config classes.
We can just define a bean using the bean annotation.
After setting up the configuration of the beans,
we walked through setter and constructor injection
using these configuration types.
I like this approach a lot since, as we mentioned before,
it seems to remove some of the mystery of what's
going on behind the scenes in Spring.
It's literally just writing Java code and wiring those
beans up in that configuration up,
which can sometimes seem like a mystery with some of the other concepts.
We started to dig into some of the more wiring concepts that
are a little bit advanced with Spring,
but let's dive deeper into those because we really
just scratched the surface on those,
and let's go into autowiring deeper in this next module and focus on autowiring and component scanning inside of Spring.