To fully autowire our applications and not just do a
hybrid like we did in the previous demo,
we need to talk about stereotype annotations.
Our last example we had beans still configured in the
AppConfig file and then had some things autowired.
To remove the need for those bean definitions in the AppConfig,
let's discuss the stereotypes.
The first one is @Component.
It is actually the same thing as @Bean.
I referenced component here just so that if you saw it in another example,
you wouldn't wonder what it was and why we hadn't covered it.
We'd already used @Bean, and they are basically the same thing.
The next one is @Repository, and as you might guess,
it's used to denote a class that's being used as a repository object.
Nothing else changes with these.
[00:17: 27.398 ]
They're just nice to label beans as such.
You could technically just label everything as a bean or a component,
but you could use a filter to look for specific types of annotations.
That's beyond the scope of what we're going to talk about here.
The last one is @Service.
This is often confusing to people because a service does
not mean a web service or a microservice.
It rather means where you would put your business logic.
There is actually a fourth annotation that we will cover in the
Spring MVC intro course named controller.
It's out of the scope of what we're covering here,
so I didn't use any real estate to show it,
but this is where you would create web or microservices for your application.
Now that we've seen our stereotype annotations,
let's go ahead and finish wiring up our application the whole way.
In our AppConfig, we want to add our component scanner.
So we're going to import @ComponentScan.
Inside of here,
we want to give it the string syntax for an array of the
package structures that we want to scan,
so we want to do com.pluralsight inside of here.
And this just tells it that this is where we want you to
start scanning for beans to autowire.
Now the other thing we have inside of here is we
still have this hybrid approach.
On line 15, we have a bean defined.
On line 24, we have bean defined.
To fully autowire our application,
we can get rid of these bean definitions inside of here.
Now one thing I didn't mention to you when discussing the
stereotype annotations is that the bean annotation is only
applicable at a method level.
So we've got a method defined on line 17 and a method defined on line 25.
I can use the @Bean annotation here.
I cannot use the bean annotation at a class level.
So to demonstrate this, I'm going to open up our SpeakerService,
and if I come out here and type @Bean, you'll see that I get an error,
and if you hover over the error,
it'll actually tell you that that is not available for that specified type,
where I can come in here and say that we want a component,
and that will work.
That is applicable, but since we're in a service,
I'm going to use the service stereotype annotation,
and I'm going to go ahead and name this here.
So we'll give us our speakerService name that we had before, and save this.
Now the other thing I want to do is I want to autowire this bean,
and right now it's set up for setter injection.
Let's go ahead and leave it that way.
I am going to go back to my AppConfig,
and now I can actually comment out all of this code
for this speakerService bean.
We're actually going to do the same thing for that
speakerRepository here in just a second,
but let's not get ahead of ourselves just yet.
I'll open up my HibernateSpeakerRepository,
and I will note that we are doing this on the implementation,
not on the interface.
Don't make that mistake and open up the interface and try
to do it on there because it won't work.
At the top of our HibernateSpeakerRepositoryImpl,
let's do @Repository, and we'll give this a name as well,
and this will be our speakerRepository, and save that.
So now this bean is set up as a repository using the
repository stereotype annotation.
Our speakerService is set up as a service with the name speakerService,
and then our AppConfig, we can go ahead and finish commenting out all of this.
And right now,
speakerService is set up with that setter injection
for the repository to go into it.
Let's make sure we've done everything right here and go
ahead and try and run our application.
I want to open up our application, right-click on main,
say Run, and you'll see that it called the no arguments constructor.
The setter ran through our code that showed that we had those objects,
printed out the name, and we had the same address.
So we've actually kept that scope the same.
Now, let's not move too fast here.
Let's show you a couple things inside of here really quick.
We just got rid of this bean definition that we had
to go type all that code out for, wire up the whole thing.
This @Scope, if we still want that scope,
I can go back to anywhere we define a bean at the top of the code and say,
well, let's throw Scope in here.
So I can go in my app and still define Scope here if I want.
By default, it's singleton, so there's no reason for me to do that,
but I can define that at the class level.
And we have our autowired setter injection taking place.
If we want to change this to constructor injection,
we can go ahead and move that up to the constructor and autowire it that way,
and let's run our application again and see what it does.
We go inside of our app here, go ahead and click Run,
you'll see that we have now switched over in our log statement to
using the repository constructor injection,
and it's still autowired up.
So I've effectively removed all of this configuration code
inside of AppConfig by just having the component scanner and
defining our beans the right way.
This may not seem like a big thing to you except for I've worked in
applications that have had hundreds of beans,
2, 3, 400 beans.
If I have to go through and define 8 lines of code to
define each bean and then troubleshoot that,
you're talking with 300 beans,
a couple hundred lines of code to get that set up for that application,
and trying to stay on top of that and maintain that,
this really saves you a lot of time and effort,
and it's really actually quite nice in how it wires those things up.
So it's really simple.
You just define the stereotype.
You can still define the scope if you want,
and you can move around the autowiring from constructor to setter if you want to do it based off of which contract you want to enforce.