I want to thank you guys for spending your invaluable time with me, and I know there was a lot of reading
on this course, it's very content heavy and I hope you found a lot of value from it.
You have this course in perpetuity.
So feel free to come back and access this course at any time or if there's a section that you want to
brush up upon at a later point.
Come back to it.
I will be sure to update this section this course accordingly.
Thank you again.
I'm seriously so proud for the work that you guys have put into your profile, and I hope that by the
end of this course, you have a really sharp profile that you feel proud about, that showcases your
skills, your expertise that gets you involved on the platform.
The more involved you are, the more of an investment you make into this platform, the better it will
do for you in the long run.
So be consistent.
Definitely don't come away from this course thinking that if you just spruce up your profile a little
bit, but don't add more people.
Like if you're like, Well, I have 20 connections and then you never post anything ever again, it's
not going to do much for you.
Being an active participant, being a known resource, being a helpful advocate, being somebody who's
involved in the platform who posts often is definitely going to help your chances of success increase
greatly.
Because the more involved you are, the more the algorithm is going to pick you up, the more likely
clients potential clients will see your profile click on your profile.
It's exactly what we want.
So thank you again.
Don't forget to add me on LinkedIn if you haven't already come find me.
Aaron Booth, Virtual Assistant Mentor You'll find me on LinkedIn, and I really look forward to meeting
you to checking out your profiles and seeing what kind of work you guys are doing.
And I'm excited.
Sky's the limit when you really invest in yourself, a lot of great things can happen.
So hopefully by the end of this course, you are already well on your way to finding pitching and attracting
your ideal clients.
LinkedIn can be a game changer.
Just give it time, give it consistency and be persistent.
And I have every faith that this will be a great asset to you and your business.
Thank you guys so much for joining me.
I will see you on the next course and I will certainly see you on LinkedIn.