There are other ways to look for job listings, so if pitching a client like we just went through the
search bar lesson about using key phrases to find people who are hiring VAS, and if that is not your
cup of tea, I got you covered.
Maybe instead of working with a client, you're interested in working as a VA for a company.
That could mean you're hired as a contractor for a company, or maybe they even hire you as a full time
remote employee.
That would be cool, too, because you get benefits.
Anything you choose is fine for your own company, but if a if a job listing or working with a company
sounds intriguing.
Here's what we're going to do.
We're going to navigate at the top of the page over two jobs.
Now see here.
LinkedIn smartly already knows that I am a virtual assistant, and they've recommended jobs for me,
which is cool.
But just in case they don't do that, you can search for virtual assistant at the top bar.
Then, of course, like everything else in LinkedIn, we can drill down into specific locations, even
by state.
Oh my goodness, but I was thinking more country.
So if you're based in the UK, for example, you can search for V jobs that are posted in the UK for
PlayStation.
Oh my god, that is cool.
OK, so a couple more things I want to do.
I want to dial down on recent job postings.
Twenty thousand, I want to select my level.
If your brand new entry level is not about it here, I want to especially pay attention to on site,
remote or hybrid.
So as a VA, you're likely going to want a fully remote job.
So LinkedIn will actually help by completing the jobs that are fully remote and that were recently posted.
So I can see here there's over 1100 jobs for a virtual assistant with companies that I can apply for.
So if you do see something that you're interested in, you're like, Oh, OK, tell talent to fi and
you're looking through here and here.
It aligns with the time zone and you like everything that they're listing out and you're feeling good
about the administrative duties that they're listing for you.
You can go ahead and click Apply.
It really is as simple as that will want to make sure that we have this toggled on.
So make sure again, before you even get to this point in the course that you've really gone through
early on in the course and you've put a banner up there, put a nice profile photo out of the video,
you've got your title down to a really concise and clear tagline and you're about your summary is great,
which I want to make sure that the basics are there so that when we apply your profile, it will be
shared automatically with the recruiter and then we go through the process of actually applying for
the job.
Something else I want to point out, by the way, that if you scroll down and you see basic requirements
or education requirements, I'm going to let you in on a much needed secret that we all frankly need
to be talking about a lot more.
If, for example, you are looking at the requirements and you're like, You know what?
I don't quite fit all the requirements.
Forget about it.
Don't worry about it.
I want you to apply anyway.
I don't want you to tell yourself, no, that you're not qualified for my job.
I want the recruiter to tell you that you might not be qualified for a job.
So if you're interested in a job that you're like, I know I can do this, I might not be able to provide
marketing assistant experience, but everything else I've got, I want you to apply for it anyway.
Worst case scenario, they say, No, you're not qualified.
Best case scenario, they speak to you anyway.
Better case scenario.
They have another job opportunity for you in mind, but it is a great idea to use this job section to
also hone in and kind of package your work as a virtual assistant to so freelance clients are great.
Job listings with companies are great, both are great, and you can find both of those options here
on LinkedIn.
So your homework at the end of this video, which is just about wrapping up, is to look through the
jobs section on your own profile and see if anything sticks out.
See if there's anything that you're interested in.
See if there's anything that you could apply for today, and why not apply for it right now?
What do you have to lose?
Absolutely nothing.