So why is video on LinkedIn so powerful?
Well, by now, you've probably heard that 80 percent of all content consumed online is VIDEO.
And in this video, I'm going to talk a little bit more about native video on LinkedIn and what makes
it such a powerful tool.
Now, besides the fact that 80 percent of people are already interacting with VIDEO More Did you know
that 90 percent are using those videos to make purchasing decisions?
I mean, just think about that for a minute.
I hope your mind was just blown over.
The people who are on LinkedIn, these are CEOs, C-suite level CEOs, VIPs.
These are the decision makers who are in charge of finding and hiring people like you.
They are making purchasing decisions based on a video.
So if you're a virtual assistant and you start setting out weekly videos that educate people about your
your skill set or educate people about something that you're a master in, like if you are masterful
at SEO or web type website design and that's your jam and you're not making videos about how good you
are or you're not making videos about tips or tools or things people should be doing for their own business
and using SEO as a major missed opportunity.
So hopefully now you're ready to upload videos on LinkedIn, and there are two ways that you can go
about doing it.
One.
You can upload a link from YouTube.
So let's say you film a video about your niche and you upload it on YouTube, but then you take that
YouTube link and you put that on LinkedIn with a little blurb about what it is that the person is going
to watch.
That's good.
I mean, that gets a lot of engagement, but you know what's better?
Native VIDEO And what that means is that you're uploading the same video that you put on YouTube.
You just upload it as a native.
VIDEO No link.
You're just uploading it straight up to LinkedIn.
And the reason that works so much better is because social media platforms really like to promote their
own platform the same way that other algorithms work, like on Facebook.
Facebook doesn't like to promote links that take other people away from Facebook, so if you are constantly
linking to other websites, Facebook is not going to promote you as much.
But if you're doing live video that's native to the content if you're doing native videos that you're
uploading straight to Facebook.
Facebook likes that they're going to reward you by promoting you more.
OK, so hopefully by now you guys are like my phone, I'm ready to film and upload it to LinkedIn.
And if you are ready to do that, then my job here is done.