Now that we have our video profile uploaded, there are a couple other interesting things that you might
want to consider doing.
We're going to click on this pencil icon to the right of your name.
Here's where we can fill out first name, last name.
But there are two things that I want to bring your attention to.
The first is pronouns.
You can now add your gender pronouns to LinkedIn.
Personally, I like doing this because you're simply informing people how they can refer to you.
And by doing this, it also allows others not to make assumptions about one's gender.
I think it's a really nice thing to do nowadays, but again, this is completely optional to you.
The second thing you might want to do is add a name pronunciation.
If you have a name that perhaps has unique spelling or it's pronounced or it's pronounced in a way that
people typically get wrong.
You can add your pronunciation simply by clicking on that blue option.
All we'll do now is click and hold on this blue button and you'll say your name.
Slowly, and perhaps several times, so I'll go first.
Aaron Booth.
Hi, my name is Aaron.
Let's stop playing and make sure we like it.
Hit apply and then you'll see that you have an audio recording active hitting the pencil icon allows
you to either delete or record an entirely new one.
I'm going to go back to my profile, oops.
Oh, and of course, hit save now that I'm back on my profile.
You can see next to my name a new microphone icon or a megaphone.
I guess whatever that is, you can see a sound icon.
It's a good indication that you and or somebody else on LinkedIn has added a pronunciation.
And when you want to hear yours, you simply tap on that button and it will play your name.