Let's talk about certifications and skills.
In fact, over the next few lectures, we're going to talk about each of those things individually.
Once again, if you don't have a section that's for certificates or skills, I want you to scroll to
the top of your page.
We're going to add that profile section.
Skills are under your core section.
This means LinkedIn thinks that you should be absolutely no questions asked, including your skills.
In fact, they even say that filling this out will help you get discovered.
So skills is a definite.
And then other the recommended you can do things like add courses.
Perhaps this one, you can add licenses and certifications.
Certificates like this are also given out at the end of this course, of which you can certainly add
to your LinkedIn.
In fact, if you've noticed right off the bat, I have a couple of licenses too that I did years and
years ago under project management.
And if I had additional certifications, then I would also add them here.
I do want to note, by the way, that some of these fields will be irrelevant to you and I as Vas.
That's because certain fields like Credential ID credential, you are ill.
This is from a credentialed school, for example, is different than something like Udemy, like Skillshare.
In fact, all you need is a name of the course or certificate that you've taken, as well as the issuing
organization.
So if you were watching this on Udemy, you could enter the name of this LinkedIn skills.
Twenty two and then you could do Udemy as the issuing organization.
The reason that I think adding certificates like this is so helpful is because it helps give potential
clients a better idea for what kind of work you've done.
This is especially helpful if you're a new VA and you don't yet have any testimonials or a lot of work
to share with them.
They can actually come down to the section where you can direct them to this section and let them know
that you've worked on certain skills, that you've taken online courses for certain niches that basically
that you working on your own and proactively to make sure that you can provide the best services possible
in the next section, we're going to talk about skills, why they matter and even a skills assessment
test.