Now one of the most important features of device software
that AWS offers is over the air updates,
or OTA.
Now on a microcontroller running Amazon FreeRTOS,
we might have a piece of software running that suddenly has a
security vulnerability introduced to it.
Now when this happens,
we might actually write a patch for the vulnerability and
want to apply it to the existing software.
So what we would do is we would write an image for the software so that we can
overwrite the old version and upload that into the AWS cloud.
Once that was done,
we'd actually be able to send it through over to the
microcontroller with Amazon FreeRTOS and essentially schedule an
update for that to replace the existing software.
Now once that process has been scheduled,
it will notify something on the device called the OTA agent,
or the over the air agent, and that will download the new firmware,
which is this software patch, to the device.
But it's going to do this piece by piece over MQTT so that
it can assemble everything and then verify that it is the
software that it expected.
Now importantly, it's going to do a signature verification,
which essentially means it's going to check to make sure that this software is
legitimate software and not just a piece of malicious code that some hacker is
throwing onto this device and hoping to get updated.
After the software has been verified,
the device is actually going to have the over the air agent go
ahead and check that it's the latest version.
And it's also going to run a series of other tests to make sure that the
application with the new image doesn't have any conflicts or errors that
arise in comparison to the old version.
Now once all of those tests are passed,
the old version of the software will actually be deleted
and you'll go ahead and have that new image on the device
be what is loaded from then on.
Now the final part is that this will all eventually be
reflected inside of the AWS cloud,
so you do know that this has happened on each of your devices that require an update, and you can manage and monitor that later on.