Whenever you're interacting with AWS IoT,
connections to the AWS services are going to be handled by the Device Gateway.
So let's go ahead and take a look at what exactly the Device Gateway is.
Well the Device Gateway is a fully managed,
auto-scaled entry point for IoT devices that are connecting to AWS.
Now what this means is that when you have a situation with an IoT device
that is maybe trying to connect over MQTT or Websocket,
and it's going and sending information through to AWS IoT,
that information will go through the auto-scaled,
managed Device Gateway.
Now that information might end up getting routed to the Message Broker
or the Shadow service or maybe the Device Defender.
And any of those different services are also going to rely on Device
Gateway to route the traffic all the way back.
But now what happens if we have a case where we have a bunch more devices,
let's say another million devices get added and we have a lot
more traffic that's going to come through?
Well the nice part about the Device Gateway is that
it will auto-scale up for us.
This means that when we have one device to one billion devices,
the Device Gateway will handle all of that increased
throughput for us and we won't have to do a thing.
We'll just have to pay more for the amount of traffic and time that we're
actually using with all of these different services.
However,
AWS IoT will handle the scaling of infrastructure in the background that
we need to actually process this increased throughput.
So really,
think of Device Gateway as an ever expanding door for whatever traffic requirements you have that's completely handled by AWS.