So now let's take a look at authentication and authorization and
how these two different things can work together to help us
secure our applications and devices.
Now let's briefly take a look at what authentication and authorization are.
When we're talking about authentication, we mean being able to prove how we are.
When we're talking about authorization,
we mean being able to prove what we have permissions to do.
Now when I'm saying we, I don't necessarily always mean us as individuals,
but also devices that might take advantage of these two different concepts.
So let's first start by looking at AWS IoT authentication.
There's going to be multiple forms of authentication and then
there's going to be purposes of that authentication.
So the first form of authentication is X.509 certificates.
There's also identity and access management users,
groups, and roles, which I'll talk about in a moment,
but are another concept inside of the AWS umbrella.
After that, there's Amazon Cognito identities,
which again, is another concept related to AWS.
And federated identities,
which will allow organizations that already have existing federation
and identity solutions to integrate those with IoT.
And finally,
there's also custom authentication strategies that you
could use when you're working with IoT.
So what are the purposes of each of these forms of authentication?
Well X.509 certificates are going to be used on IoT devices so that those
devices can prove they are the device that they say they are.
Now the IAM users, groups,
and roles are going to allow you to use things like the CLI,
the SDKs,
or you could integrate them in web and desktop applications that might
be running with some components in the AWS cloud.
With Amazon Cognito identities,
those will be tied to mobile applications and mobile
devices that use those mobile applications,
and then federated identities will also be used
sometimes for web and desktop applications.
Now with custom authentication strategies,
those could be used for web, desktop, or mobile applications as well.
So in addition to authentication methods,
how can we deal with authorization in IoT?
Well there's two kinds of authorization that we might interact with.
The first is AWS IoT policies, and the second is AWS IAM policies,
or identity and access management policies.
So what do these two different kinds of policies actually allow us to do?
Well let's look at some example authorized actions that we
might get from having one of these policies.
One of the first actions we could potentially take with maybe an
IoT policy would be to publish or subscribe.
Now this would mean we could send or receive messages to MQTT message topics.
We could also do things like management actions inside of the AWS console,
where we might use an IAM policy to do things like manage certificates,
IoT things themselves, rules related to those IoT things,
or other actions of that nature.
Now we could also do AWS integrations, for example,
we might have an IAM policy set up to allow us to
interact with other AWS services.
Now this could be things from storing data inside of Amazon S3 or
maybe integrating with the database like DynamoDb.
Now each of these is just an example of the many different
kinds of actions and the layering and complexity of these
policies that we could get into.
But for right now,
let's actually take a look at how authorization and
authentication are tied together,
specifically what could we attach to an AWS IoT policy versus an AWS IAM policy?
Well when we're working with AWS IoT policies,
we're more likely to attach those to Amazon Cognito
identities or X.509 certificates,
whereas when we're working with AWS IAM policies,
we're going to associate those with users,
with groups, and with roles.
So both of these different kinds of policies will not only
give us different permissions to take actions on IoT related
concepts or AWS related services,
but they'll also frequently be attached to completely separate things, like you see here.