Hello and welcome back.
This is Fernando Medina Corey, and in this video,
we'll be taking a look at how we can enrich and analyze
data that's generated by AWS IoT.
So let's go ahead and jump into it now.
In this overview, we'll review the specific services that we'll cover.
We'll start by looking at IoT Analytics.
We'll see how we can use it to both prepare and analyze our data,
as it flows through IoT Analytics.
Then we'll look at IoT Events and see how they can help us take
complex input sources and then determine when different things
like potential failures and our IoT scenarios might happen and
alert on those kinds of events.
After that,
we'll look at IoT SiteWise and see how we can use AWS
provided hardware and software to integrate on-premises
environments with the AWS cloud.
Finally,
we'll take a look at what's next for us and what we should continue
to explore as we work through our IoT journey. So let's go ahead and get to it in the next video.