Let's take a really quick look at the AWS IoT button.
We'll do this by taking a look at an example workflow using the IoT button.
We'd start with the literal device itself,
which simply would allow you to press a single button
that AWS has shipped to you as a device,
and you can configure that button to do different things.
Now the button will come with a certificate preinstalled on it,
so it can authenticate itself over through Wi-Fi to the AWS IoT Core or
other services that might require that certificate.
And then once it's done that, you'll be able to set up in the background,
whenever that button is pressed,
that something like a lambda function will trigger and
then take some customized actions,
depending on however you configured that button and the lambda function.
For example, you might want to order some tacos or turn a light bulb on or off.
Now this is really just a high level overview,
but you can definitely apply the rest of your knowledge about AWS IoT
if you're deciding to go and use the IoT button and create things like lambda functions and IoT applications.