So what is the Internet of Things?
Well let's get started with a quick definition of the Internet of Things.
The network of traditionally non-networked devices like teapots,
dishwashers, or vehicles,
that contain the hardware and software required to connect
with other devices and exchange data.
Now this will start to get us a little bit of an understanding of what
we're talking about when people use the words IoT.
But let's take a look at a visual to help us get a
look at this a little bit better.
We'll start with some of those IoT devices that we mentioned.
Now these are traditionally non-network things,
so not traditional computers or servers or maybe even cell
phones as we think of them in the modern age,
but maybe something like a door with an internet connected lock or a car
with maybe a speedometer in the long run or other bits of information
that would eventually be sent to a network.
Or maybe some hardware in a factory that we need to construct
different things inside of a manufacturing environment.
Now each of these devices would probably send or receive bits of information,
and because of this they'd need to be networked in some way.
Now these devices might just be networked in a way that's
with a local application or a local device,
so for example, in the instance of the manufacturing equipment,
maybe it doesn't eventually connect to the entire internet,
but it does communicate within the manufacturing environment and
communicate to other local devices or local applications.
However, for many other IoT devices,
they will eventually connect to some sort of application server through the
internet and then maybe be processed in different ways.
So for the example of the locking door for the IoT device,
it might connect to some sort of mobile application that
would allow you to lock or unlock your door.
For the car,
maybe we'd send speedometer information to an application that
allows us to process that for insurance companies.
And this actually happens frequently where if you
sign up and opt into these programs,
you might be eligible for reduced rates if you're a safe driver
and you're driving within the average speed limits of the area
or the required rules for the road.
Now let's take another look at some segments of IoT,
just so we can get a better understanding not only of these
individual devices and how they might work,
but general segments that the entire IoT market might have.
Now the first one that we already discussed a little bit is vehicles.
You'll frequently see these not only in your own cars and the
devices inside of those that send and receive information for
maintenance and other purposes,
but also in things like 16 wheelers that have lots and lots of
information that they send back and forth,
both on the places that the goods that they're carrying go and the
maintenance information on those large vehicles.
In addition, there'll also be IoT used in agriculture or in security,
to do things like monitor the progress of growing plants and also just
to keep track of different locations and try and make sure that no
intruders are coming into those locations.
You'll also frequently see IoT within the medical industry,
and it'll be used within hospitals to monitor the various
devices that are in those hospitals.
Now frequently this will impart a bit of a responsibility on
us when we're using IoT to do it correctly.
And we'll talk more about these risks later on.
Now in addition to medicine,
you'll also see these in buildings and cities and homes.
Now these sorts of integrations could be anything from
traffic lights to just integrations on the door lock in our
home that we talked about earlier.
However,
they'll also frequently be used to try and save on things like electricity
or power that might be used for heating and cooling when there's nobody in
the building or the temperature inside or outside the building is
fluctuating a little bit differently.
Now to kind of lead into our next segment here,
the utilities will also use this information and use IoT devices to help
monitor the progress of their various utility networks.
Now all of these are just a few of the segments that we
might encounter when we're working with IoT.
But I wanted to give you a basic understanding of all these IoT
segments and the fact that there are many more,
to let you see how pervasive IoT currently is and how likely it is that this will continue to be of importance later on.