So now that we have a high level understanding of how IoT
works and some segments that IoT falls within,
let's take a look at some specific terminology that we'll need to
know when we're working with the Internet of Things.
Let's get started by talking about smart and connected devices, or things.
Now this is kind of a more generic term that could apply to
anything from watches to thermostats to dishwashers.
But when I'm talking about things in the context of AWS later on,
specifically AWS IoT things,
I'm not only talking about those devices that we
mentioned that are smart or connected,
but I'm specifically talking about a representation of a
specific device or logical entity.
Now this is taken directly from the AWS developer documentation.
And when we're talking about this,
it could be anything from an application instance,
so not just maybe a thermostat or a dishwasher,
but an actual application that's running somewhere in the cloud or on-premises,
but also things like physical entities that are related
to devices that connect to AWS IoT, but they don't connect themselves.
So if we're thinking about this in the context of that car I mentioned earlier,
this could maybe be an engine inside of the car,
which is a physical entity that's related to the car,
but that engine itself might not actually connect to AWS IoT.
It might send information to the car and that car maybe
would then send information up to AWS IoT.
So now let's fill in a few more missing components of this
larger diagram of how IoT things work.
Now specifically, I talked about those devices,
but let's take a little bit of a step back and start thinking about
different sensors that might exist on those devices and inputs that
might come into those devices themselves.
Now one of the first ones might be things like
thermometers that check different temperatures.
You might also have things like motion sensors,
which determine whether or not some motion is there,
or device inputs that come directly from some physical device.
This could either be things like touch or other device inputs
that maybe come from an ambient environment.
Now another thing I wanted to point out is there could be device states,
such as locked or unlocked,
and different devices might have actuators inside of them,
which essentially allow you to do things with those devices,
and they might report on the state of those actuators inside the devices.
Now these could be things like locks or levers or manufacturing equipment,
and all of these might be things that might feed data into an
environment or might require some input from outside of the
environment to actually change and so stuff with.
So let's go ahead and actually take another closer
look at how these IoT things work.
Specifically,
let's look at these IoT devices and how sensor inputs might come into them.
So inside of these devices,
we might have a lock or a speedometer or maybe a control
attached to manufacturing equipment.
Now each of these different things would then connect to the device
and these devices would then need to use some communication protocol
to actually send information around.
And when we're talking about these communication protocols,
we might be talking about things like Wi-Fi,
but we could also be talking about other protocols like Bluetooth or 3G or 4G,
and there's many others that might come into play because the communication
protocols that we use with IoT can be substantially more varied than the ones
we're used to just when we're using our laptops,
for example.
Those might all be tuned to Wi-Fi,
whereas these other devices might have other protocols for the various
situations that might come up to leverage those more effectively.
So after these protocols get involved,
the ones that are going to connect to the internet eventually
would probably do so and then be sent over to maybe a cloud
provider to send that information that's generated up there or
retrieve information from it.
There might also be information that's send over the
internet to an on-premises environment.
However, again, like the example we mentioned earlier,
it could just be that that device is kept within the on-premises
environment and never really sent out through the open internet.
So now that you understand there's this
communications protocol layer in between,
let's take a quick look at some different protocols that we might interact with.
Now this will be really quick so we don't have to
dive into too much detail here,
but the language will be important for you to use later on.
Now the first one, which you may already be familiar with,
is 2G or 3G, which has long range and takes a relatively high amount of power.
There's also Wi-Fi, which you should also be familiar with,
which is relatively medium range and medium power usage.
But when you're trying to do things that save power,
you might use protocols like Bluetooth,
which have a smaller range and lower power usage,
or even things like near-field communications,
or NFC,
which has a very small range and low power usage because when you're using
near-field communications and also thinking of things like RFID,
these things are going to be activated by some other scanner or
power that's actually being brought next to them.
So that's why it's not actually using any power until it's activated.
So in addition to these transport protocols where
we're transporting information,
there's also data protocols that kind of fit underneath that.
And I won't dive into all the specifics here,
but the terminology, again, is important to just be aware of.
The first one of these protocols is MQTT,
which is a lightweight publish and subscribe messaging model.
Now this will allow us to do things like see what different messages are
coming from different channels and subscribe to those and also send messages
out to channels so other devices and other people could subscribe to those
bits of information for their applications.
There's also Websocket,
which is going to enable bi-directional web communications.
Now this is going to allow you not only to send
information from one point to another,
but it's also going to allow you to send information from
that endpoint back to the original device and do that at the
same time in an efficient manner.
There's also HTTP,
which you'll frequently see when you're working with web applications,
and it's the traditional web application protocol that many of us are used to.
Now these are just a few of the data protocols as well,
but the main reason I'm including these,
as well as the transport protocols,
is because there's a lot of variety when it comes to protocols and IoT.
You're not just getting the exact same stack that you're
used to seeing in web applications.
There's a lot of differences that are happening underneath the hood
here when you're working with all these devices.
So now that we have a better understanding of all of that terminology,
let's actually move on in the next video to start taking a
look at the purposes of IoT things and how we can use them for the benefit of our organizations.