Let's take a look at the Message Broker.
The AWS IoT Message Broker is a publish/subscribe broker service that enables
the sending and receiving of messages to and from AWS IoT.
Let's go ahead and visualize the IoT Message Broker now.
We'll start with some IoT things,
in this case just two devices that we want to connect to the Message Broker.
Once we're going to do that,
we'll need to have a Message Broker topic inside of there.
In this case,
our light bulb is going to establish an MQTT connection to our topic.
Now this will create something called the persistent session.
I'll talk about that more in just a moment.
But in addition to being able to connect with MQTT,
we could also connect with HTTP,
and we could also connect with MQTT over the WebSocket protocol.
Now each of these different methods would allow us
to connect to the Message Broker.
Though technically with HTTP, we can only publish to the topic,
we can't actually subscribe from it.
So after we've established some kind of connection
and we want to send information in,
we could send a message through the connection we've created to the topic.
Now, when we do this,
we'll likely have some sort of subscribe to this topic that
we'll want to receive this information.
In this case, we have an IoT thing which is an application, not a device.
As I mentioned previously, IoT things can be devices,
but they can also be applications that want to interact with the
Message Broker and other parts of the IoT Core.
In this case,
this application has created an MQTT persistent session that is going to
receive the messages from that topic and then process them inside of the
application and do something with them later on.
So it can go ahead and get these messages,
but it will be relying on some sort of connection to
the Message Broker to do this, usually over Wi-Fi or something else.
Now this would continue to work effectively if we sent in other
messages over any sort of protocol into a topic that was subscribed
to by the IoT thing that is the application.
It would continue to receive the messages from those
topics that it's subscribed to.
But what were to happen if we actually had a connection go down and it's
unable temporarily to connect to the Message Broker?
Well in this case, we fortunately have the MQTT persistent session.
Now the persistent session will store some metadata about which
subscriptions it had before it disconnected.
So because we have the session,
we know that two of these topics were subscribed to by the IoT application.
Now this means that when additional messages start to come through,
they'll start to pile up,
up to about an hour before that persistent session is finally
removed and those messages go to the trash.
Now in this case, all of those messages,
once the connection is reestablished,
will be sent over to that IoT application because of that
MQTT persistent session and the subscriptions that it had
inside of the Message Broker.
So this is one massive benefit that the Message Broker gives us.
It's going to allow us to continue to tolerate failed connections and
intermittent connections and it's going to be able to use those
persistent sessions to eventually deliver messages that maybe were
delayed because of disconnections.
So let's really quickly recap what we can do with some
of these Message Broker protocols.
Let's start with MQTT,
and we can use this to publish and subscribe to AWS IoT Message Broker topics.
Now we also have HTTP, which we'll only be able to use to publish to a topic,
and finally we have MQTT over the WebSocket protocol.
Now this will allow us to do both publishing and subscribing to topics.
So let's take a look at some examples of topics,
so we have a clearer understanding of how they work.
We'll start with two light bulbs and we'll say that the
first light bulb has a topic called bulb/1.
The second light bulb has a topic of bulb/2.
Now if we have an application that wants to get information
from both of these two different topics and receive any
updates that are made to these topics, then we could subscribe it to bulb/#.
Now technically we could instead subscribe this to
bulb/1 and subscribe it to bulb/2,
but because we used this wildcard character of #,
this will actually allow us to subscribe it simultaneously
to any other bulbs that get added later,
like bulb/3 or maybe we just have a completely different kind of bulb,
like bulb/new.
Now any of those topics will be subscribed to when we use this format.
So now this application could receive any updates from these bulbs
and also interact with a mobile application to support changing
and working with those bulbs as well.
But we'll dive into that later when we're talking about device shadows.
So let's take a look at another example.
Let's pretend we have a series of factories,
and in factory 1 we have either one or multiple machine arms
that are doing some work for us and publishing data to the
topic of data/factory1/arms.
Now in the other factory we have,
we're publishing information to data/factory2/arms.
So what if we wanted to subscribe to all the arms in these different factories,
but we didn't want to subscribe to all the other devices?
Maybe we had other levers and actuators inside of our
factory and we only wanted to get these arms.
Now because we situated our topics in a way where we have
the factory before the actual device type,
if we replaced factory 1 or factor 2 with the pound symbol,
we actually wouldn't be able to delineate between the arms and other devices.
So here's what we would use instead.
We'd match just the single component inside of the topic,
so we'd have data/, and then the plus symbol,
another slash, and arms.
Now this would match us anything in between those slashes.
So it would match the data/factory1 and the data/factory2,
both of those ending with arms.
Now this would allow us to then integrate with some sort of application that
subscribes to this particular topic with the wildcard,
and then it would be able to send that information on to a
database or do whatever else it needs to.
So hopefully this gives you a good start on what
topics are and how we can use them, and we'll take a closer look at them in future videos.