Let's take a look at the Device Shadow service.
Now before we do, we'll need to know what device shadows themselves are,
and their JSON documents that are used to store and retrieve
current state information for a device.
So it kind of follows that the Device Shadow service is a service that
maintains the shadows for each device that you connect to AWS IoT.
So let's try and visualize this a little bit.
Let's first imagine that we have device shadows and
they're in the Device Shadow service.
So we have lots of these, we have one for maybe our construction arm,
one for a microprocessor, and another one for a connected light bulb.
And each of these are connected to AWS IoT.
But let's dive in this a little bit more and let's take a
closer look just at our light bulb here.
Now like any other AWS IoT device,
this light bulb is going to have a shadow document associated with it.
Now the shadow document in this case might have
part of it be including the state.
Now there's more involved in the shadow document than just this,
including things like versioning and other parts of the shadow document,
but in this particular case,
let's just pretend it's simplified down to the state Now
the state in this particular case says it's reported and
the color of the state is white.
So this means that currently our light is just emitting white light.
But what happens if we want to connect, say,
a mobile application to change the color of the light?
Well in that case,
we'd need an application that actually goes and interacts with the
shadow document from that mobile device and then it actually
retrieves the reported state of the light.
Now this might make that available inside of our mobile application,
but with shadow documents, we can do more than just retrieve the current state.
What we could actually do is we could say we want a new desired state
and then our application could go and it could set both a desired
state and a reported state for the light.
So in this case,
it would see that the state currently desired is the color purple now
after the application updated that in our shadow document,
and then our light could subscribe to the topics for the shadow
service that tell us when this document is changed and it could
see that there is a difference between the desired and reported
states and once it does this,
it can take an action on the device itself and then change the state of the
device to the color that was requested in the application.
Now after that happens,
the shadow document itself will once again be updated and the
application can check for changes in that state,
and then once that has been updated,
can re-report that to the mobile device and let it know that the new
state of the light is indeed purple like it requested.
Now this is definitely a little bit of an over simplification.
There's a few other components involved when you're
working with the Device Shadow service,
including some MQTT topics that would actually manage some of
the interaction between the device itself,
the shadow document,
and the mobile application that's involved with the shadow document as well.
There's also different parts of those topics that let you get the document,
update it, determine whether or not the update is accepted or rejected,
and some complications there.
But this general overview gives you an idea of part of the workflow that would happen when you're using device shadows in AWS IoT.