So now that we have a lot of context about IoT generally,
let's take a look at how AWS specifically fits in with our IoT needs.
Now first let's ask the question, what does IoT require?
Now we talked about this a little bit before,
but we think it really starts with these devices.
But on top of these devices, we need some sort of device software.
Now this device software will allow us to interface with these devices and to
do different things from the data that they're generating.
Now in addition to this device software,
we might need some management services to help us do things like
secure those devices and also verify that the incoming information is
from those specific devices authentically,
and then doing things like integrating them into workflows and
monitoring them both for security vulnerabilities and also just to
make sure they're functioning as expected.
Now in addition to these management services,
we also have other things we'll want to do to analyze
and act on the data that is generated.
So these three different categories are what we'll be
looking at later on this in course,
specifically related to AWS services that enable all of these areas.
But let's take a look at some specific components of IoT so that we
know exactly why we need these different services.
First,
we already have the devices and AWS isn't currently going to help us out
there by providing us our own devices unless we're using things like an
Amazon Dot or Alexa or things like that.
Now in addition to these devices, we need the software that we just talked about.
Then we might also need certificates to verify these devices
to some sort of authorization provider so we know these
devices are who they say they are.
Now in order to do that,
we might need network connectivity to actually go in and
connect to some authentication system.
Now this authentication would then verify those certificates
and then maybe pass them on in terms of the information that
they're sending to a public cloud, a local device,
or an on-premises server.
Now each of these different things might also require us to have some
certificate management system so that we can verify other local
devices or just the ones that we're using now.
Now in addition to certificate management,
we might need permissions so that we know which devices that
are sending information in are allowed to send it to the
public cloud or local devices as well.
We don't want every device to have all the permissions or it might
exploit those later on if it ever gets hacked.
Now in addition to permissions,
we want to make sure we can store some of the data that's coming in,
so we'd need some data stores.
We might also want to integrate devices or the data that's coming
in with other applications or third party APIs.
In addition to that,
we might want to do backups of the data that's coming in or
the devices and the states that they're in.
We might also want to monitor and log our devices to see if
there's anything unusual happening and also just to graph the
variances in our device fleets.
In addition,
we might have workflows that we want to integrate into our
systems so that if something happens on a device,
we can then trigger other things to happen down the line.
Now in addition to workflows,
maybe we have lots and lots of devices and we want to be
able to group them into logical categories.
This is another feature that we might have to build
ourselves if we were doing this all on our own.
So this should give you a decent idea of what the kinds of
things are that we would actually need in order to start
working with devices in IoT effectively.
So now let's take a look at how AWS starts to solve some of these problems.
First let's take a look at device software.
Now AWS offers many different tools and one of them is Amazon FreeRTOS.
This is an IoT device operating system.
Now it's going to be installed on IoT devices themselves to
allow you to interface more effectively.
This is an open source piece of software that you can integrate with
your devices to allow them to be used more effectively.
In addition to this operating system that Amazon provides that's very
lightweight and is meant to be installed on IoT devices,
it also offers the AWS IoT device SDK.
Now this comes in multiple languages and provides SDKs for programming with
IoT devices that need to interact with the AWS cloud.
Now in addition to the AWS device SDK, which can be used on those IoT devices,
we also have AWS IoT Greengrass.
Now this allows you to extend AWS services down into your own devices.
So rather than having all of your devices need to connect up into the cloud,
you can extend the functionality of AWS services down into your own hardware
in your own maybe manufacturing environment or other locations that need some
sort of ability to use things like AWS services,
but don't always get to connect to the internet.
So this can really expand the amount of things that
you can do with those devices.
Now in addition to device software, there's also AWS Management Services.
Now some of these are not specific to IoT,
but they're all useful for IoT itself.
One of the first ones is the Thing Registry.
And this going to allow you to register all the IoT things that
you have so that you can keep track of them,
use certificates for them,
and do a bunch of other things specifically related to those things,
like grouping them and adding metadata.
In addition to the Thing Registry,
there's also features for security and identity verification.
Now these are going to allow you to assign certificates
to different things in the registry, create certificates that you might need,
and otherwise control permissions and things along
those certificates and authentications.
There's also the AWS IoT Device Defender.
Now Device Defender is going to help you by auditing your fleets of IoT
devices and making sure that you're configuring them with best practices
and otherwise notifying you if you're not.
Now in addition to Device Defender, there's also the Message Broker,
which will allow you to send and receive messages from IoT devices effectively
and then take actions off of those messages down the line.
We'll also be talking about the IoT Thing Graph,
which will allow you to help keep track of the various IoT
things underneath your organization's umbrella.
And finally, there's on other point,
which is one of the ones that is less related specifically to IoT,
but more to AWS in general, which is Identity and Access Management.
If you're unfamiliar with AWS,
you can essentially think of this as the overlying system
that is helping keep everything secure and properly
authenticated when you're working with AWS.
It manages everything from granting users
permissions to do things on AWS services,
to also making sure that any applications that you're
running inside of the AWS cloud have permissions
appropriately to act on other services.
So in addition to these management services,
the final kind of building block here is the analysis and action section.
And AWS has many different services to help you do this,
ranging from AWS IoT Analytics to help you analyze the data
that's coming into your IoT environment,
and then develop meaningful insights from it,
and also AWS IoT SiteWise,
which is going to help people in manufacturing environments actually
keep track of the equipment that's on their locations.
There's also AWS IoT Events,
which will help you act on different things that are coming into the IoT
environment and the trigger other reactions from that.
And finally,
there's other AWS integrations even outside of all of these specific services.
You can integrate with a vast variety of different services that
AWS already has inside of their services suite.
So now that you have an understanding of all of these different services,
I hope that'll get you ready for future sections where we'll dive
into many of these different services themselves and help you understand the specifics of what each of them do.