Now that you know what external or third party libraries and modules are and how to install them, let's
take a step back.
Why?
Because there are still a lot of built in Python modules that we haven't explored yet, and it's really
worth doing.
So we're going to see some very interesting, super useful modules and some of them will be your companions
for the rest of your career.
You're going to learn about collections.
We're going to see a bit more about the OSS module, which we saw when we learned how to work with files,
shuttle and daytime.
So you can work with dates and times a bit more about math and old acquaintance of the course time it,
which will surprise you and regular expressions.
And lastly, we're going to see how to compress and decompress files with the zip file module.
With all that in your pocket, you will, by the end of the day, be programming a serial number finder.
This program, which you are about to create yourself, will be able to go through a series of folders
and files and find within each file all the text fractions that meet a certain condition.
But that's going to happen at the end of the day.
So now it's time to learn everything you need to know.
Snap your fingers and we'll see you in the first lecture of the day next.