We've got into day 16 a day we must not forget, because you are going to learn one of Python's main
applications Web development today.
You're going to learn how to create websites with Python, and we're going to meet Django for that.
Django is a framework for web development.
When we say that it is a framework, we are saying that it is not only an application that we incorporate
to Python, but it is a whole framework to develop websites.
Django allows us to manage both the front end, which as we have already learned, is the part of the
website that is visible to the user as well as the back end, which is the back end site, the data
and the calculations the user does not see.
In the next lecture we are going to learn what visual environments are in order to create our site.
Virtual environments are super useful tools to work on our computer with different packages that are
separate so that they don't clash with each other.
And the project that you are going to do today is the creation of your first website.
You're going to create a web application that helps manage a to do list.
On this site.
Users will be able to create a user account log in created to do list, edit tasks, delete them, mark
them as completed and search for tasks by keywords.
First, we will create the structure and functionality of the site through Django and HTML and then
we will apply style styling through some CSS codes that your site changes from looking something like
this to something like that.
Super professional with an intuitive, modern, visual language.
This is going to be a long day.
So let's jump into action by clicking on the following video right now.