New Day and new project.
Today, you will end the day creating something that will surprise you.
Forget Siri and Alexa today.
You are going to create your own virtual assistant, a program that you can talk to.
Yes, talk, not write.
And that you can ask to assist you in many tasks.
You will be able to talk to your assistant and prepare it to be able to do whatever you want.
The great thing is that you can not only make it capable of performing the tasks we will see today,
but you can also add as many features as your imagination is capable of developing.
To learn how to do this, let's get to know some new libraries, such as P, sx3, which is a module
that allows Python to talk to us.
Speech recognition.
The library that allows us to translate the sound of the human voice into text web browser, which enables
us to manipulate a web browser.
Pi What kit?
A tool to connect your code to many websites like YouTube, Wikipedia and more.
Yahoo Finance to search for information on the stock market.
Pi jokes a database of jokes so your assistant will never be boring and wikipedia for everything.
This project is going to take you one step higher.
So let's start right now.