It's amazing to start a new day of study together again, along with some warm coffee, tea, whatever
you're drinking, and all the energy that we need to face our problems.
Today, we have a challenge.
One of those that you will remember for a while today, we are going to create a hangman game.
You remember Hangman.
The one where someone thinks of a word shows you how many letters it has, and you have to guess the
letter, the word letter by letter until you discover the hidden word.
But if you make a mistake, the poor little hangman is formed.
And if you complete him before guessing the word, you lose.
Do you think you can program this right now?
Well, probably not right this moment, but after learning everything I offer you today, you'll be
able to do it together.
Today we are going to dedicate the whole day to learn a single topic in depth functions.
Functions will allow you to take a big step in your career.
And I think that if we measure your learning curve so far, this is the point where your skills will
take a big leap because functions allow you to solve much more complex problems than we have seen so
far.
So when you master functions, your limitations as a programmer will be greatly reduced.
So functions and everything related to them is this fifth day of study.
I won't take any more of your time because you're going to need it.
See you in the next video.