Welcome to Day ten.
It's a very special one because as of today, your beginner stage is over.
Considering everything you have learned so far, we can say you have learned all the basics of Python
programming.
So we can also say you already know how to program.
And what you need to know now is to practice and expand your knowledge to know how to apply what you
have learned in different applications that Python has in the real world.
From now on, you have to apply the knowledge you already have in different uses programming games with
graphical interfaces, data science, artificial intelligence, machine learning, web development,
interactive graphics, integration to social networks, blockchain, facial recognition, and much,
much more.
All of that starts today.
Also, since you are no longer a beginner, we are going to change our work methodology from today.
Our lectures will be more dynamic and we will develop together the project of the day as we learn new
concepts.
Today, we are going to start with one of the most requested topics.
You are going to program this game in Python learning how to work with a very special library called
Pi.
Game through PI Game, you will learn to create a game screen and characters assign them images and
movements.
Program What happens when the elements come in contact?
For example, when a shot hits an enemy, you will also learn to calculate the score, to define the
background, to program the end of the game, and even to add sounds.
And since we are going to exclusively dedicate this day to program the game with PI game, we are not
going to focus too much on the principles of the OP.
For instance, characters are not going to be in separate classes, nor are we going to apply inheritance,
which we could do.
But in order to concentrate on PI game, we are going to write a rather simple code.
I'm sure you're anxious and excited to get started, so I'm not going to take up any more of your time.
We'll see you inside Pi Charm.