Welcome to the sixth day of this intensive Python training.
I'm ready to start full of energy and enjoy what learning and growing brings us in life.
Today is another day you will not waste because in a couple of hours you will have so many new skills
that you will be able to create a program that yesterday you would have found impossible.
Today you are going to create a recipe box.
That is, you are going to be able to write a code capable of managing a collection of files containing
recipes.
And this program is going to be able to read those recipes, create new ones, delete them, create
and delete categories and so on.
This means that you will have to learn how to manage files and folders on your computer from Python.
So today your code created in pie charm will not only show you things in the console, but will also
cause real modifications to files and folders on your computer.
Can you feel how your capabilities are growing?
Your next programs will be able to access your computers, directories and do all sorts of things with
them.
Throughout this day, you will learn how to open and manipulate files, create new files, write or
overwrite text files, navigate between directories and create or delete folders.
Learn a couple of super useful tools like Path, Lib and Path and so much more.
No matter how your day is going so far, this is the time to focus on Python.
I'm so excited to have you here, so let's get going.