Now that we understand how to handle errors and exceptions and pythons with the try, accept and final
blocks, we are going to talk about two libraries that allow you to test our code as our program starts
to expand into larger multi file projects or you start working with a team, it becomes really important
to test the program as you or your teammates make changes or updates to the code.
It is imperative to run your test files to make sure that the code still executes as expected.
Well, there are several testing tools out there, but we're going to focus on two pilot and unit test.
Pilot is a library that analyzes your code and reports potential problems.
It can identify style problems or maybe some invalid code.
On the other hand, we have unit test, which is a built in Python library that allows you to test your
own programs and then verify if you are getting the desired results.
We'll start by showing you how to use pile int to check your code for possible style errors.
And if you're wondering what I mean by style.
Python has a set of style convention rules known as Pep eight, which we'll also look at next.
Finally, we'll explore how to test our code with the built in unit test lab testing library.
Let's go over to the computer and see how this works.
In this lesson, we'll use pilot to check for errors that our file might have.
So first, we'll need to install pilot on our computer.
So go to command line or terminal.
If you use Mac or Linux and call PIP install and then call pilot.
So I've already installed it and that's why I get this message.
If you don't have this tool, the interface will start operating until it is installed, then the cursor
will be back here.
So we had pilot installed on our computer.
So now I'll create a file containing an intentional error in day eight and you can create it wherever
you like.
What matters is that you know how to access your file from command line.
Later, this new file will be named file one dot P and it will only contain two things a variable named
number one, which will be equal to 500, and a line that will print this variable.
But I'll type this name with an uppercase.
That's the error.
So of course Python will complain.
It will turn a blind eye on it and leave it.
So I have a file with an error.
Now I want to use Pylon to check my file and look for errors or style issues, which is what Pylon does.
So I'll go back to command line so as to check my file using pilot.
I can find some error that prevents my file from executing, which I will as well as style issues will
also be present.
So I'll search through my system from within command line until I find my file.
It is located in desktop and I'll go to the python folder where I've saved all the files created for
this course.
Then I'll go to date eight where the current folder is located since I know I'll get an error instead
of executing it directly.
Typing file one point p, I'll use pilot and then I'll enter file one dot P and in order for this to
be executed the way I want, I'll type minus R, which stands for Report Space and y which stands for
yes.
So the syntax to verify if your file contains errors is written like this.
Pilot file name minus r y.
If you're using an older version of pilot that you already had installed, then you don't need to enter.
The minus are and y.
If you installed it for this course, do it like I told you to.
So I'll press enter and I'll get some kind of extensive report.
Notice that it contains several lines and tables.
So let's go to the beginning so as to analyze what this is.
We've received an automatic report, including important details about our code.
So firstly, there is a summary of all the problems in our code.
These three lines.
The first items which starts with C are style issues.
They don't prevent our code from executing.
They are issues that don't meet Python's writing standards.
So we've lost points here, starting with E!
That's an error.
Notice that it reads undefined variable number one, and we know what this is about.
So we can also see that there's a missing module docstring and that the software has found a constant
that is not regarded as a variable since we didn't execute it because it doesn't come.
Firm to uppercase naming style.
This is due to the fact that Python interprets the number of one as a constant when it's actually a
variable.
All right.
Let's see what's next.
This is a summary of the most important issues of our code, and there are some analyses as well.
Here we have statistics sorted by name so we can find how many modules, class methods and functions
we have.
We only have one module here.
Then we have some raw metrics.
For instance, we can see if there are comments on our code and when working with somebody else.
We can also check here if there's a comment on each module.
Then we can check whether there are duplicated lines or not.
In this case, there are none.
So message is sorted by category.
We have two conventional messages which are about style issues, and we also have one error message.
Next, we have more details about these messages, such as which category they're included in.
We can see the error message is linked to an undefined variable and we can see what the convention messages
are about.
And we have the most important thing at the end.
There's information concerning the whole code.
In our case, it's gruesome, meaning that our code contains errors and it doesn't meet writing standards.
So we're going to clean it a bit so as to improve it and get a better score.
However, do not try to get ten out of ten because it will put you on a high stress.
Sometimes the only way to get a ten is to write a code that can only be read by a computer and not a
human being.
So strive towards a seven at least.
So let's go back to our code.
We'll add some things it should have.
First, we're expected to add triple quotes and an explanation about this module so I can type this
module prints something.
This won't prevent our code from executing, but it has to be included.
Our code is also expected to be always inside a function, so that is not an isolated text without purpose.
So we'll create a function named function and add colon.
Then we'll add proper indentation and correct our error by typing PN in lowercase so that our variable
can be called correctly.
So notice that Python highlights style issues.
If we position ourselves on this brand line in our function, it will display a message that reads P
Pep eight, which is the style guide for Python code expected to blank lines and it found one.
So it expects two blank lines before a function and we'll add them.
That message is gone now and we'll also call our function down here.
So function.
And now we have another problem.
We'll position ourselves here to see that.
Python tells us it's expected to blank lines after the function.
So the code shouldn't end with this line of code.
It should end with a blank line.
Python stopped complaining and this has gotten better.
So let's try it again here once again.
Type pilot file one P minus R, space y and press enter.
We'll now get a new report and a much better one since we got seven and a half out of ten.
If we check what's missing, we'll see that there's a docstring missing.
We'll know more about this soon.
So taking into account what we've already know, this is the best score we can get.
Actually, pilot would be really useful when we work with other people.
You'll hardly use it when working alone because you can manage your own ID, which points out the errors.
Sometimes when working alone style issues may not be very serious.
However, it's important that you know how to use Python because it will come in handy when working
with others.
So this was pilot and in the next lecture we're going to see how we can work with the unit test in order
to test our code.