So this choice complements the previous one in which we had managed to create a link that takes us to
this site for creating new tasks which has the title tasks form, but which does not yet have a form.
That's what we're going to do in this lesson.
We're going to go to task from HTML where we only have a header and we're going to add a tag to add
a form.
This tag is called form.
We're going to set up the form here before we close the opening tag.
We need to give it a parameter called method, which can have two different values.
The one we're going to use now is the value post.
The other value that we can go in method is get.
We use that option when we want to create a form to obtain or retrieve information, for example, a
form to query a database.
But as in this case, we want to create a form to publish something, to deliver information, not to
get it.
And that's why in this case, we use the post.
Another parameter we're going to need is action.
And this is to determine to which URL we want to send this information.
As in this case, it will be stored and published on this site.
We don't need to put anything here and we can leave it empty.
The first visual element we're going to add to our form is going to be the send button.
We do this with an input tag just as we use input in Python to ask the user for information.
Here we use input to create element labels where the user has to do something.
The input in this case is going to have a type because there are different types of input tools.
The one we want to use here is submit.
We want an input of type submit.
If I create a submit button, look, we're actually going to put it and we're going to put the text
with a value equal to send.
If I come to the form and I refresh it.
Here's my submit button.
See, it's in that default form.
If I had put another type here instead of submit to, let's say, email, well, what would we see?
We'd see a button that has a different shape.
It's more elongated.
It's for putting an email address.
Well, that's not what we want.
We want a submit so we can undo it and we put submit.
So we've got a button as we want it.
And then the site is ready with its button, but it doesn't have the form yet.
That's what we're going to add up here.
The form is actually already there because it's been created automatically and we just need to load
it into our HTML here.
We have to put the fields.
It's as simple as adding an element with the double square brackets that says form inside.
With this, we should now have the form.
If I refresh it, we see this, which is not at all attractive, of course, but the form is there.
So how do we rearrange it?
We have three ways to display the form.
If we put form dot as table, it's displayed as a table and that is what we're looking at now.
This is the default, but it's not the one we like the most.
We can show it as UL, and if we see it like that, we're going to see some kind of list.
UL is user list.
So here you have these dots before each field, but the one I want to choose is as P for paragraph because
if we've refresh now, it looks a little bit better.
Of course it's still like style.
Don't worry, we're just working on the hard code.
The visual style, colours, shapes are all a matter for the end.
I always insist on that.
And now let's create a task to see how this works.
The user is going to be wind ten.
The title can be made up task.
Here we put any description and send it and we get an error.
It tells me.
See SRF verification failed.
What does this mean?
Well, let's solve it first and then I'll explain it to you.
So we're going to add here, first of all, a square bracket and the percent signs to put inside the
expression CSF token.
And what is this?
CSF tokens prevent a common security hole in web applications known as cross-site request forgery.
Basically, what they are preventing here is a security attack that allows a malicious person to modify
the state of the server by impersonating a user.
If we did not put this, the website would trust that user, but the request would not.
Be real and will be spoofed by the attacker.
As the website trusts the user, by default, it performs the requested operations and processes them
as if it were a real user.
This CSF token prevents it and is necessary to put it.
Otherwise it will not allow us to move forward.
So let's go back to our site and let's create a new task.
Let's put made up task again.
Put anything inside, say it's completed, send it and we get an error.
Okay, let's look at this.
It says no reverse match at create task.
Okay.
So this message tells us that it hasn't found the site we want to send the user to.
After creating the new task.
So we should go back to tasks, but it's not finding any site called tasks.
I honestly don't understand why, as the original site should be called tasks.
So if we go to views, we see that we've spelt it right.
Reverse lazy is pointing to tasks as it should be.
And let's see if the URL is correct.
No, it's not right.
The name we've given to this URL is pending and it should be tasks.
That's the explanation.
So I've been assuming the home was called tasks, but it was called pending.
Sorry about that.
I could have edited this so that in the video you don't see my mistakes.
But I think it's important that you also see the reasoning we use when we get an error so that we can
get to the cause of it.
In fact, I think it's best to leave tasks as the name of the home.
So we come back here and note that although we have received an error, this happened when the site
wanted to redirect us to the home after having created the new task.
This means that the task was actually created successfully.
It was the following process that failed.
So if we come back here, made up task already exists.
So that part works fine.
Now let's check if we've solved the sending us to the home.
So let's create another task.
Let's put another task and let's put anything here.
Let's send.
And now?
Yes.
After creating the task, it sends us back to the pending list.
It already has the original tasks, plus the ones we've just created.
Well, so that you don't get confused about what we did in this lesson, let's briefly review what we
have done.
First, we generated a form in which, although we didn't load any fields, these fields were automatically
assigned.
Why?
Because inside views.
We have created a class which inherits from Create View, which provides us with a type of view that
allows us to create elements to this class.
We've given a model which is task, and then we have asked it that the fields of this create view are
all those that exist within the task model.
And we have also told it that when it finishes creating a task, it should send us back to tasks.
So here it is important to note that the fields all attribute is the one that made our form know which
fields to show.
So that's what we've done so far.
But we're going to do in the next lesson is add the ability for the user to modify tasks that have already
been created because people sometimes make mistakes or change their minds and they want to modify what
they've created.
So we're going to make it possible for our user to do that in the next lesson.