Attention.
Drive your attention from this lecture on, you are going to be taking a very significant step in your
programming career.
We are going to teach you code that makes decisions, which is the seed for artificial intelligence.
What you are going to learn today is called control flow.
It basically consists of making it so that depending on whether a condition is met or not, Python executes
one code or another.
For example, if you're programming a video game, control flow will be used to say, if player one
defeats the enemy, take that player to the next level and if they've not defeated their enemy, execute
the code that subtracts a life and restarts that player at the current level.
For another example, if it's a program that manages a database, control flow will be used to say if
the searched record is found, display its data on the screen and if not, display an error message.
The three key words that we need to control the flow of our programs are if if such a thing happens
ELIF, which is a combination of else.
And if that means if something doesn't happen, see if another thing happens and else which means if
not, the following would be a typical example of if Elif and else in Python, if a condition is met,
execute this code.
This is the most basic.
If the condition is met, it executes and goes on.
But if it is not met, it skips the code without executing it and goes on with the rest of the program
as if there was nothing there.
But you can also tell it, if not else, execute this other code here.
Python will execute one of the two codes.
If the condition is met, it will execute the first one and if not the second one.
But you can also introduce in the middle some more checks thanks to Elif, which stands for LS.
If, as we've learned, that is to say if the condition is not fulfilled, see if the other one is fulfilled.
You can put as many LPs as you want.
Python will check your conditions from top to bottom, and when it finds one that is met, it will execute
its code and leave the rest of the tree.
Note that whenever you write an if, an ELIF or an LS, you must put a colon at the end of the line.
And something to pay close attention to in Python is that the syntax of the control flow?
Because although its writing is simpler than other languages, it is much, much stricter with the tabulation.
That is, the white spaces that denote the priority and the order of its logical sequence.
The good thing is that this makes it very easy to read, as you will see pretty soon.
And in fact, let's see it now on our beloved black screen.
Welcome to the black screen.
And we're going to start here with a file called Decision Maker, where we're going to start with something
very simple.
We're going to check if ten is greater than nine.
So remember, we put the code on at the end when we hit enter py charm immediately understands that
we need the tabulation here so it puts the cursor where it should be.
Keep in mind that if you delete it and start writing here, you'll be able to do it, but then you will
get an error.
It is essential that after the colon comes the tabulation and here is where you're going to give the
order of what to execute, but only in case the verification is correct.
We're going to ask it to print.
It is correct and we're going to execute it.
Run and we choose decisions maker.
And here we see that it prints is correct because indeed ten is greater than nine.
That is to say that the condition is fulfilled.
So the only thing that if is checking is the true or false value that we find here.
And actually, if I go straight and put something like if true, it will print, it is correct.
The thing is, if there is a value here that says true or some comparison that means true, then the
next code is executed.
And if it says false, then it is not.
So let's try it with a variable.
Let's suppose I have a variable x that has the value.
True.
And here I check if x and we print it and it tells me is correct because you can see it x is true.
And now let's see what happens if the condition is not met.
If I have here and if that says if five is equal to two and the last time I checked five is not equal
to two, then what would happen in this case that we don't execute anything?
There is no line to execute python.
Did the check saw that this is not true and didn't print anything because it couldn't go into the part
of the code.
It didn't even read it well.
But then we have the option to decide what to do in case the condition is not fulfilled.
We may want that some other thing happened.
If the condition is not met.
Well, at the same indentation level of the if we put else statement, which is the same to say if not
and when we hit enter, we must continue with this same indentation line to say what is going to happen
if the verification is not correct.
Well, we're going to ask that it declares it is not correct.
And now if we run, we have the phrase it is not correct.
Now, this code wasn't even read because it just read the second part.
It only read a particular block of code if the condition allows the computer to read it.
Do you follow me this far?
Well, now let's see another example.
Let's delete all this and let's put in Pat.
And let's say that pet equals dog and let's do the same checking with this if pet equals cat.
So this is going to be false.
And we put the code on here and we ask it to print.
Well, you have a cat.
Great.
Okay.
If this isn't so, we're going to say print.
I don't know what animal you have.
Perfect.
Since there's actually a dog.
Well, it's going to say here is I don't know what animal you have so far.
We've already understood this, but we're going to make it a little more complex by adding options for
different questions.
So, okay, if you don't have a cat in that case, we're going to check with Elif with a new comparison
and we're going to see if actually pet is equal to this time dog.
And in case it is, we're going to print you have a dog.
Now, since we have a dog, we're going to verify the logical sequence here.
That was Python checked if we have a cat and as we don't have one, it didn't enter the execution line.
Then it went to a lifeline and made another verification.
Then it found a true value here because pet does equal dog.
So Python said, Hey, I'm allowed to read this code here and executed this line.
And once it finished, it left the code.
It didn't stay to continue reading the remaining code.
So keep in mind that you can keep adding as many glyphs as you want.
For example, here I could create another one that says Elif pet is equal to fish.
And in that case, we would say, of course, after the colon print and you have a fish and this here,
it doesn't see any fish because pet is dog.
But if our pet were a fish in that case executes that you have a fish.
And finally, if there was a pet that is not in any of the options, like, for example, a rabbit,
I looked at this one, this one, this one, and none of them is rabbit.
So the campaign later reached this else because none of the options open the door for it.
And it had to enter in this room and print the last line.
Examples like these, you're going to see a lot and we're going to do one a little bit different.
So you can see also how you can nest if conditions.
We're going to say that the age of a person is 16 and we're going to set an F here to see if this person
is an adult or a minor.
Then we check if age is less than 18 and if this is so, we are dealing with a minor.
This number, it may vary in our country in case the condition is met.
So we say you are a minor and if not we're going to say print.
You are an adult.
Perfect.
We already have an approach to see if a person is a minor.
But imagine that once I know that he is a minor, I also want to know his school grade.
Let's say in this case, it's nine.
That's enough to approve or fail the school year.
Okay, let's go underneath the print for a second.
If you can put an F inside an F, as long as you respect the indentation hierarchy.
And here we can see if school grade is equal or greater than seven.
In my country to approve, you need a grade greater or equal to seven.
So we put the code on and then we press enter.
Notice now that we now have a new indentation level, we're now not at this place, but at this.
And this is where we print.
What's going to happen if you meet this condition?
Well, let's say past congratulations.
So we're going to put an enter in here.
We're going to create an elf situation in case our person hasn't approved.
And we will print failed.
Oh, this will happen.
Remember, only in the case that our person is a minor.
If he is an adult, we will never reach the considerations about his grades.
So we test it.
Approved.
Perfect.
So what happened here is that the if statement entered this condition because its met then printed the
execution and then did a second check.
Notice these helpful lines here.
This is pie chart helping us understand the decision tree and it came out with a string related to his
grades.
So once Python finishes this tree, well, it either continues with whatever is in our code, if there's
anything there or exits the program.
These are just a few examples, and I assure you that we are going to see decision making and control
flow issues throughout the course because this is one of the most frequent aspects to find in almost
any programming code in the world.
So you're going to get used to seeing it.
Now you're going to reinforce this knowledge with the practices coming up next.
And then we're going to the next lecture to continue learning.
Cool stuff.
See you there.