So now that we know how to print the details of all the books contained in a page, we're going to convert
this to a list so as to analyze each of its elements and get to the rating.
So we're going to convert this, which is a print so far to a variable named books, because it will
contain all the books since there will be all the class product.
If we print books.
Well we obtain the same but in list format.
So let's take the first element and create an example which will be equal to books and it's index zero.
So we obtain the first of its elements.
Let's print example and here we have the first book and all the information corresponding to each of
its elements which are in class product pod.
But what do we need to know here?
We need to check if this book has the number of stars that we want.
So we're going to make a selection.
We're going to make example select class star rating three.
Since this book is rated three, stars will enter that name to see if we obtain the information we need.
So let's execute.
And here's the element we need.
So this is how we make a selection that verifies whether the list contains an element or not.
If we searched for a four star book, we'd get an empty list.
Therefore, if we get an empty list, we don't want the title.
And if that list contains an element, then we will take the title.
So let's figure out how to obtain the title of this book.
Let's print books again so as to have all the books on the screen and see where we're going to find
that title.
So it pops up several times.
The title appears on the first tag, the one corresponding to the cover of the book.
And if we go back to the website, we'll see the book and this image that contains some data in its
code, which includes a reference to the title.
Well, we don't exactly want this, but if we scroll down, we have this H three tag followed by A and
the title which is in title.
That's what we want to reach.
So how do we get that?
Let's go back to our selection and instead of selecting star rating for the stars, we're going to look
for the attack and we have to begin there.
So let's type print example and execute this.
So we obtain the list containing the A element and it contains a comma and another a element.
So it has two a tags which correspond to the cover and the title.
We want the latter.
So we're going to ask for index one, which is the second element.
Let's execute this once more and here we have our precious tag.
Now we have to look for our title so as to obtain a light in the Attic, which is the first book.
So remember that we can use these objects, the tag type ones as dictionaries, so we can call the keyword
title and execute it and we'll see that title on the screen.
That's how we get to the title.
To sum up, we now know how to identify the rating of a book and how to take its title.
So now that we're able to obtain those features, we only need to combine them in a full loop that iterates
over all the pages, check all the books of each page verifies if those books are rated four or five
stars, which is our special rule and if the condition is met, takes the title of those books.
So let's do that in our next lesson.