So far we've created our characters and we can see them on the screen, and yet we have this pretty
boring background color which we choose when we begin to set up our game.
This was just a demo of choosing a background color, and I'd actually prefer a more impressive background
image, like an outer space image.
Something interesting.
We'll need to look for a new image.
Then I'm attaching the one I'm going to be using so you can download it if you want.
In order for you to learn how to look for an image, I'll do almost the same as before.
There are several websites where we can look for images.
I used free pick where I can choose between free and paid resources.
You can use other images or illustration sites like Pixabay Pixels, Google Images, among others.
But what's the catch here?
Well, finding an image in exactly the size that you need is a bit difficult.
For example, we need an 800 by 600 image here.
So I'm fond of this one and that's the image that I want.
If I click to download it, I'll probably get an image whose resolution is not the one that I need.
So I advise you to download the image and then open it with an image editor so as to configure the image
size.
I'm using Photoshop, but you can use whichever you prefer.
So I've created a new 800 by 600 image.
I use this image which was much bigger, and I set up the size I needed.
So once I export this image, it will be just as I need it.
This is not a course on image addition.
I could explain what I did in full detail, but it was basically what we needed to do.
If you want to know more about Image Addition, we have a course on Photoshop usage and many others
on Image Addition.
You can take advantage of them whenever you like.
So I saved my image as background JPEG and now it is located in the folder where I save all the resources
for this course and I can use it inside pie charm.
And here it is.
So I'm leaving this image in the resources section of the course in case you want to use it.
So let's see how we can use this as a background image in our pie game screen.
We'll go to the section where we stored some images in variables and let's create a new one that can
be named background, which is equal to pie game image load here and we'll upload background JPEG,
which I saved in this directory.
So once we create our variable, let's go to the game loop where we can set up the background so we
won't use a background color, but a background image.
And so screen won't be created with the fill method, but with the blip method which we use to add an
image to our screen.
Remember, it requires two parameters an image which is stored in the background variable and a location.
So since we want this image to cover the whole background, we have to start at coordinate zero, comma,
zero.
That should do it.
We'll execute our window again and we'll see the image that we chose.
And it looks great.
But you may notice that both our rocket and our enemy are moving a little slower.
So why is that?
Let me explain.
The image is being loaded through the game loop, which means that it is being loaded in each iteration.
This makes the iterations run slower because our loop is carrying out several tasks.
It loads the image, places it, and so on.
So the iterations that control the character's movements take more time to execute.
And we can appreciate this when opening our game.
To solve this, we have to make all the movements take up more space.
0.3 pixels is a very low value now, so let's change it to one.
We'll modify it here inside the if that checks the key down event, we'll change that here to where
we check that our enemy stays inside the lines.
And we'll also change it here where we see it reads 0.3.
Now it is one.
So this will speed up the movement.
Perfect.
This is a suitable speed for our game.
If you want it to run slower or faster, you can modify it like we just did.
So we're one step closer to finishing our game.
We have to program the attacks as well as the score we get when killing an enemy.
Then we have to learn how to kill those enemies and so on.
So let's go to our next lesson and keep on programming our game.