You already know what object oriented programming is.
You know how to create a class and how to assign attributes to a class and its objects.
Now let's learn how to create methods for a class.
Actually, we have already created a class method by accident because technically in it is a method.
It is just a special method that is already built into all classes by default.
Next, we are going to see how to define methods that give some interesting functionality to our class.
This is going to be easy for you and probably remind you of how we created functions because it's basically
the same thing.
Let's continue with the bird class example.
Let's write def inside the class so that python knows that we are going to create a function.
Then we write the name of the method, which in this case would be chirp.
We use the same naming rules that we use with functions, and then we write some parentheses where we
pass arguments and then a colon.
What differentiates classes from variables is that inside the former, we're always going to pass at
least one mandatory argument, which is the word self, and it refers to each instance or object of
this class.
What follows is putting inside the function, whatever it takes for our object to do something.
In this case, it can be only to ask that it prints peep so that our bird chirps.
If we want to create a method that asks for arguments, we can do it this way.
We create the method fly and besides self, which is mandatory, we ask for another parameter that can
be the amount of meters or feet that our bird must fly.
Next, we are going to use that argument in the code so that the action that our bird is going to execute
includes the information that has been passed to it.
So this is how we create methods for our classes.
How do we execute them?
We're going to show you that right now in Pi Charm.
We'll keep on taking the bird classes, an example in which we can have some class and instance attributes.
Now we'll add some methods to our class.
So let's create two methods.
One will be named Chirp.
And as we said in the example, this will allow our bird to say something or sing like tweet.
So we type chirp and look at what python will do when I enter brackets.
It adds self automatically.
So why does it do this?
Because self is a mandatory attribute.
So pie charm saves me the trouble.
Now I have to create code lines in order to execute something such as an action that our method is going
to perform.
So we'll just make our bird tweet, and that's all our method needs.
We'll create another one.
But for this second method, it's going to require parameters.
For example, if I want to create a method named Fly, I'll need more information besides self such
as the feat, which is the altitude our bird will be flying at every time we execute this method.
To simplify, this will type only one string literal that says the bird flies an amount of feet that
we will get from our feet parameter and then we'll complete the sentence with the words feet high.
Now we have created two methods and added them to our class.
So notice that if I close the class, everything I've typed will be enclosed in the bird class.
So now we get out of the class and let's create an instance for our bird, which can be named Tweety.
This instance will be a bird and will need to parameters.
One will be color and it will be yellow, and the other is species which will be canary.
Now Tweety exists.
So if I type a dot after Tweety, not only will I have parameters or attributes that I did before,
like color, species and wings, but I'll have the methods chirp and fly.
This is how I execute them.
I call chirp, which doesn't ask for any parameters, and if I execute our file it will show tweet,
which is what Tweety has to do every time we call the method chirp.
And if I call fly instead of chirp, remember, it requires me to pass the parameter feet.
So I'll say the bird will fly 164 feet high.
We execute it and it says the bird flies 164 feet high.
I can also add features like the values of our attributes to our methods.
Suppose we want our bird to say its color besides tweeting.
So let's type tweet.
I am.
Let's open a call and then outside the string we type dot format in order to call the value corresponding
to color.
However, there can be an error that is quite common for a beginner.
You'd say, well, if I need to pass color as a value, then I should type color.
And that's it.
Well, it won't work.
In fact, we have to pass the color of the instance which will execute this method.
So we have to complete the process with self color and the software will stop detecting the error.
So if we execute the method chirp, our bird says Tweet, I am yellow.
It works because we've added self.
This is very important and every time you build a method that calls an attribute inside a class, you
must relate that attribute to the element that receives it.
The attribute belongs to the object or the instance that's calling the method.
So in this case, self will correctly relate the method to the color that corresponds to the instance.
So this is an essential feature of methods.
This has been easier to understand since we learned about functions two days ago, and class methods
are basically functions that are linked with our particular class.
So let's keep moving forward.
Object orientated programming has a lot to offer us, so let's learn some more in the next lecture.