So up to now, Hazel knows how to do four things.
This wouldn't be a very useful assistant, only knowing how to do four things.
So we're going to add a few more so you can see everything she can do later.
It's up to you and your creativity to continue adding more functions.
So let's make another ELIF that this time is listening for the expression Do a Wikipedia search for
if this expression is heard within my request.
What it will do now is speak to tell us.
I'm looking for it.
I'm perfect.
Just like that.
Now we need to clean the expression that my request will receive to know what it is we must search for
in Wikipedia.
And remember that my request will contain a very long phrase.
And we need to eliminate the words that aren't specific to the search.
For example, if we say Do a Wikipedia search for Amsterdam, we don't want it to go to Wikipedia and
search for do a Wikipedia search for Amsterdam.
We want it to search only Amsterdam.
So at this point in the code, my request will be equal to my request.
But applying the method replace and what I'm going to replace is the expression do a Wikipedia search
for and I'm going to replace it with nothing for an empty string.
In this way, it leaves only the term we want to search.
Then we're going to create a variable called answer that will perform the search on Wikipedia and store.
The result answer will be equal to the object Wikipedia with the method summary, which asks for two
parameters.
First, it needs to know what we want to search for.
So we put my request.
Then it will ask how many sentences of the response we'd like it to show.
For this, we put sentences equal to one so that it reads only the first sentence of the found article.
So once we have the response, we call speak so that it tells us something like according to Wikipedia,
and then we call speak again.
But this time I'm only going to pronounce the contents of answer we put, continue and execute.
Hello.
I am Hazel.
How can I help you do a Wikipedia search for David Bowie?
I am looking for it.
According to Wikipedia, David Robert Jones, the 8th of January 1947, the 10th of January 2006, known
professionally as David Bowie, was an English singer, songwriter and actor, but had a significant
impact on popular music.
Okay, so I've advanced a little to save time.
Don't miss out on looking up David Bowie to know more about that legend.
So this has been searched in Wikipedia.
We can also add a function that searches for something on the Internet.
Let's put Elif again and if Hazel is listening, the expression, search the Internet for inside my
request.
So it's going to tell us, of course, right now.
And so we call P what kit, which is for searching things on the Internet.
We use the method search and it's going to search for my request.
Once it is searched for it, it will you speak to tell us.
This is what I found.
So let's try it out.
Hello.
I am Hazel.
How can I help you?
Search the Internet for Breaking Bad.
Of course.
Right now, this is what I found.
Okay, so, in fact, it searched the Internet for the expression search the Internet for Breaking Bad.
But I only wanted it to search for Breaking Bad like we did with Wikipedia.
Let's go to this part.
After telling us it's going to take care of it to rewrite my request and that it's equal to my request.
Replace the same as we did before.
And now we replace.
Search the internet for.
And we change it for an empty string and we execute.
Hello.
I am Hazel.
How can I help you?
Search the Internet for Breaking Bad.
Of course.
Right now, this is what I found.
And now, as you see, it searched exclusively Breaking Bad.
Not the other words which had affected my result.
So let's stop Hazel one more time.
So she stops working, and we're going to enjoy ourselves a little more.
We won't try what follows one by one.
Instead, we're going to write the new functions, and later we can try them all together.
So let's make it so.
If it finds the word play inside my request, it will understand that I'm asking to play a video on
YouTube.
So speak and Hazel will hear this and say something like, Oh, what a great idea.
I'll play it right now.
So after telling me this, it will call pie what kit again and invoke a method called play on white,
which means play on YouTube and it will search for my request on YouTube and reproduce it.
So you put continue and I suppose that's enough, but we should try it in just a second.
Let's make it so it hears the word joke within my request.
Why?
Because like this, we can make it execute pee jokes.
So we call speak.
So it tells us what's found in pee jokes.
And we're going to call the method, get joke, continue, and we've got it.
So let's make it give us information on the stock market.
What do you think?
Now Elif will check if it hears a say something like stock price.
If it hears this within my request, it must generate a variable called share.
And which share do we want to search for?
This will be decided within my request.
If we apply, split, it will divide it into two words.
And let's take the index minus two.
Why?
Because if I say I want to know the price of Google shares, the word shares will be the index minus
one because it's the last and the word Google will be in the index minus two.
Finally, let's add the method strip so we can eliminate any prospective space in white.
To clarify, this means when we pronounce the request in this way, that the title of share the interest
will be in this position.
So I'm sure you're saying that the user could pronounce their request in many distinct ways, effectively
so.
And this is a test, so you can understand how this works.
If you want to contemplate all the possible alternatives, you would have to use logical operators to
add other possibilities in order to implement certain ways to resolve the problem.
So as you understand, we can't encompass all of this in video classes, and it wouldn't make much sense
either.
The most important is that you learn how to do it so that later you can get creative as to contemplate
the alternatives of the real world.
So returning to our project, we already have the name share that interests us stored within variable
share.
Now let's create the variable portfolio so that we have a dictionary where we can associate a stock
with the ticker that corresponds.
The ticker is the official initial that which will search for a determined company in the stock market.
So, for example, let's put Apple stocks.
If Hazel hears this word, we want her to to relate that a p p l is the name of the ticker of Apple.
Another example is if she has Amazon that she relates with a m z n.
So let's put one more example that can be Google whose initials are g0ol.
You can try out as many as you want.
I've only used these as an example, so as this could end up giving us an error, let's make it so.
The following is all inside an error handling block.
Let's create the variable search stock that's going to be equal to what is in portfolio within the index
share.
That is what it will receive when we talk.
So once this variable is created, we're going to overwrite it so that it is equal to the object.
Yahoo finance which we gave the abbreviation y, f, and here we will put ticker and within brackets
the search stock.
And thanks to the Library of Yahoo!
Finance, this will search for our ticker within the dictionary.
Let's save the response of this search inside a variable that can be called price.
So later it gives us this information.
Price will be equal to search stock info and as info will return a type of dictionary with lots of information.
We're going to search only for the key, which is called regular market price.
This key exists inside the dictionary that was created by Yahoo finance and will contain the search
price.
So up to now we have everything saved in variables.
Now we need our assistant to inform us of this through speak with a literal string which can say I found
it the price of and from here we call the variable share, which contains nothing more than the name
and then we complement the phrase with is and finally called the variable which contains price.
With this we shall have our answer.
We just need to add a continue and we can leave try to go to accept.
So in case there was an error which can happen, we want to receive a calm message like I am sorry but
I didn't find it.
We closed with a continue and well we have added many functions today and you can see the versatility
of everything you can do with this virtual assistant in the next class.
We'll put it to the test to see how it works and how it looks beyond this.
It's up to you to add everything else you want.