In the previous lecture, we saw the first part of how to create an how to invoke functions.
We saw that this is the typical function syntax, but we have left a part unexplained so that we can
see it all step by step.
In this example, we made the internal code of the function print something on the screen.
But normally what we want is that the functions return something as a result.
So although this function is well written, we usually include the keyword return to return the result
of the function instead of printing something on the screen.
If we use return, we can take advantage of what the function returns to store it in a variable.
Let's see it with a very simple example.
Here we have a function called sum which asks for two numbers as parameters.
What this function does is return the results of the sum of those two numbers.
This is great because although this function does not print anything on the screen, that is to say
visually it does nothing.
It does return a value that we could store in a variable.
This opens the door to many more applications that you can imagine right now.
And Federico is waiting for you in pitch time to put it into practice.
And now we're going to put into practice the functions using the return keyword.
We're going to use a similar example, the one that Phil showed you in the previous video.
We create a function with the word death.
We're going to name it multiply because that is my function is going to do and it is going to ask the
user to pass two parameters.
The first one will be number one, and the second, number two, we put the colon and we're in the proper
indentation to start writing the contents of my function.
This time I'm not going to put a print function.
Instead, I'm going to write the return, which is the most normal thing that you find in all functions.
A word return in some place of its code generally at the end.
And what this function is going to return is the result of multiplying number one times number two.
And with this, we already have our function finished.
So if I execute this, we're going to see, as we saw in the previous lecture, that because we did
not invoke this function, we have only declared it.
There is nothing to show in screen.
But now pay attention to this.
Even if I invoke it calling, multiply and pass it to values, for example, five and ten and then execute
it.
We are not going to have anything on the screen either.
Why?
Because this function does not have any code that shows something on the screen.
It only has a return that what it does is to return some information, as we have not done anything
with that information.
It is not seen on the screen.
But if, for example, what I would do with this is to print this declaration of the function and execute
it.
Now we see the result on screen because multiply returns a value that I'm passing it to a print statement.
But this is not the most common use of functions either.
Normally what we do with a function is to store it in a variable so that we can do whatever we want
with it later.
So this could be called result, and now a result is in a variable and I can print result.
And then we are going to see on the screen 50 is the consequence of having printed the variable that
contains my function to which I've passed the numbers five and ten in this case, as I could have passed
five and 200, and it will continue working because this function is prepared to work with any value
that I pass in my parameters.
Sometimes you will also see that the functions, instead of having only the return, can have the operation
or all of its code inside internal variables.
So let's suppose here the variable total, that total is the one that stores the multiplication and
then what the function returns is total and it will work exactly the same.
So this lecture complements the previous one where we learn the structure, the syntax of a function.
But now we're also working with return, which although it is not a technical requirement that has to
be there, it is the most common actually.
That is what functions are for to make a process and obtain a result.
The result is return.
So many students ask, what is the difference between printing inside a function or putting return?
Well, print is only going to show something on the screen to the user, but then that information dies.
This is not possible to use it anymore.
It is only on the screen.
It is not stored anywhere.
On the other hand, return when returning.
As a result, any type of result like a string, a float, an integer or a dictionary, whatever.
We can use that information as we want.
We can print it, for example, or store it in a variable, use it in future operations, in future
functions, and so on.
I also want you to know that it's not common, but if you want to use it also in addition to return,
you can also print something on the screen.
You can just say in here also print total.
And now even if I don't print the result of my function as inside the function, there is a print command.
The result will be printed and also stored.
This is technically possible, but it is not common to see.
Perhaps the beginners usually do it to be able to go checking as they construct their code.
So what is happening here and be able to see its result?
But the typical thing is that functions only return something.
There is a problem that we are going to solve later is that this function does not establish what type
of data I need the user to enter.
My function is set up to work with integers and floats because I can multiply those data types.
But what if the user, instead of giving me a five or any of the number, he gave me a string.
Let's do that with 202 and I run this.
I get an error because it tells me that they cannot multiply sequences of elements that are not integers
like strings.
So here I have a problem.
I'm trusting that the user is going to know what to do, so I'm allowing him to do what he wants and
if he does what he wants, the program is going to crash.
So right now, let's keep this in mind because we're going to learn how to solve it later, how to handle
that these variables or parameters set.
What types of data I need in here?
We will see it later.
So I thank you very much for joining us.
Step by step in this process of learning the functions, there is still a lot to find out.
So after the practices, we'll see you in the next lecture.