So we're finally fit to write our whole code due to the fact that we're able to implement all the strategies
necessary to find the elements we need to use in this loop, which will be more complex than everything
we've done so far.
So let's remove this and leave basic URL there.
Since we're going to use it here, we'll clarify that this is intended to create a URL without page
number.
This way we know what's inside our code.
Then we'll create an empty list in which we'll add all the title as we find them.
So let's type list of four or five star titles, and it will be named high rated titles and we'll be
equal to an empty list.
Okay, let's start our loop.
We need a loop that iterates over all the pages so that we can later check and select elements on each
page.
So we can type iterate pages for each page in a range from 1 to 50.
So we type 51.
What will happen?
We'll create a soup for each of these pages, so a different soup will be generated for each iteration.
So we enter create soup on each page.
We indent once again and then we create a new variable named URL page, which will be equal to basic
URL format so as to change the page number in each case.
In each loop, the number we put here will be equal to page.
Because remember that page is a number included in a range that is from 1 to 50.
So page will be our first number.
We now have the URL of all the pages, so let's create a new request and a variable named result which
stores requests dot get which will contain anything that's inside the URL page, the one we just created.
So we have the correct requests.
Now we're going to create a soup with that two requests that is equal to BS for beautiful soup.
Now it's time to add two fundamental elements which are results dot text and the HTML pass method.
We have our soup and once we have it, we need to select all the books from each page.
So we'll create a new variable that can select inside the soup all the data of the books.
So here we select data of books.
The variable will be books and will be equal to soup dot select.
And remember that the books are inside a class named Product Pod and that's why we enter a dot.
That class contains the data of all the books.
So now that we have this variable, we can create a loop that can iterate over the books.
That is each book of each page.
So for each book in books, this loop will check if those books are rated four or five stars.
So let's clarify by saying check if they are four or five star books and let's indent once more since
we're going to check if the names Star Rating four or Star Rating five are present and we'll automatically
store that search in a list.
So let's verify the length of that list.
If the list has a length of zero, it means there is neither four nor five star ratings.
So we check if length of books select in the search of class DOT staff rating four, which is the first
case is different from zero.
If that's the case, it means we're talking about a four star book.
We're also going to type R so as to take into account the five star books.
So we copy and paste and replace four with five.
So whether we're looking at a four or a five star book, it's irrelevant to us.
In any case, we'll be able to access the code if the number of elements is different from zero.
That is, there's at least one element.
If it is different from zero, it means it is a four or five star book.
If this condition is met, we will access the code which will store the title of the book in a variable.
So store title in variable.
Let's indent and now let's call book title which will be equal to book select.
Remember that book in this element of the loop which represents all the elements we'll iterate over.
So now we select the a tag in its index, one because we're going to receive to a tags.
But we need the second one that is the one in index one.
We want to take title from that tag so as to store the title of the book inside this variable.
So now that we have a variable containing the title of a book, we can add book to list.
That's why we created this list up here.
The one named high rated titles.
So we invoke it and apply the append method in order to add the book title.
So now we should be able to access each page, access each book of those pages, and verify if those
are four or five star books.
If that's the case, we should then store the title of those books in a variable which we can add to
the list up here.
If I executed this, a list would be generated, but I wouldn't see it on the screen.
So outside of these loops, we're going to create a code that can show four and five star books in console.
And this is an extra line of code that can help us check if everything went well.
So how can we see all of these books?
We'll ask that for each be in high rated titles, BE is printed and displayed on the screen.
So how did we do?
I think we did great.
Let's execute this and see what happens.
So we have lots of books here.
Look at this long list.
Seems like there are several high rated books.
And to verify if this list is correct, we'll check the first three books Sharp Objects, Sapiens and
the Dirty Little Secrets.
Let's go to our website to see which are the first three high rated books.
The first one has three.
The second one has one and the third has one.
So the first four star book is Sharp Objects.
That's right.
The following is Sapiens, which has five stars.
And this is followed by Requiem, which wasn't displayed.
And The Dirty Little Secrets, which has four stars.
So I reckon we did a pretty good job because we got four and five star books like we wanted.
So this works properly and you can check if you want.
So we managed to satisfy two specific conditions through web scraping.
So let me emphasize that there are no formulas for you to scrape websites.
This task will vary depending on the websites you want to work with.
Remember to always obey copyright and privacy laws.
In fact, your access may be restricted if you scrape websites excessively, so most websites are prepared
to fight web scraping back.
Nevertheless, I'm very happy with everything we've achieved so far.
So let's rest and get ready for more exciting lessons.