So now it's time for us to make our rockets shoot bullets so as to kill its enemies.
So what do we have to think about here?
If we execute this, we can see our rocket moving around and we want the bullets to come out of the
rocket regardless of its position on the screen.
If the rockets hear, the bullet has to come out of here and if the rockets hear, the bullet has to
come out of here and so on.
Another fact we have to take into account is that the bullet should go off in a specific direction.
That is, if the bullet comes out when the rockets here, it should keep moving in that direction and
not mimic the movements of the rocket.
So we have to make the bullets go off in a specific direction from beginning to end, and that is when
reaching the top of the screen or hitting an enemy.
These are the major aspects we have to think about.
So I already have a bullet image which I found in Flat Icon.
You can look for yours in any site you prefer.
So just like we have the player and the enemy variables, we should have the bullet variables.
So let's copy this and type bullet variables.
Bullet image.
And because we need a variable to store it in, will copy the word bullet so as to paste it in this
file which is named bullet p and g.
We'll have Bullet X Bullet.
Why?
Bullet X change and Bullet Y change.
So what values do we have to change here?
Bullet X won't be a random integer anymore, but it will be zero.
This doesn't do anything special because the coordinate x should change according to the rocket's position.
Bullet Y is the place where the bullet will come.
Out of that is the rocket.
And our rocket is set at a level of 500 pixels.
So that's the value we're going to enter.
Bullet X change is not the value we're going to employ because our bullets shouldn't move on the x axis,
so we'll leave it at zero for now.
We actually won't need this variable, but we include it so as to have a more complete code.
So bullet.
Why change would be the speed of the bullet because it represents the number of pixels the bullet will
move across.
In each iteration we'll enter a low number such as one, so as to be able to actually see that bullet
depending on whether the bullet has been shot or not.
We want it to be visible or invisible.
We shouldn't be able to see it before it is shot.
So we'll add one more variable.
This variable will be named visible bullet and it can be true or false that is visible or invisible.
This will initialize as false since the bullet won't be visible as soon as the game starts.
So we have the variable storing the information on where the bullet will be displayed when shot to shoot
it.
We'll need a function in charge of that.
So besides, the player and the enemy functions will create the shoot bullet function.
So that will be its name and it will receive two parameters a position in X and Y.
We should be able to see a bullet going off upwards so its value in y should decrease.
Now we have to access the visible bullet variable from this function.
To do so, we need to make this variable be global.
So we enter global visible bullet and now we can access that variable.
Now when calling the shoot bullet function, the visible bullet function will change the true and so
the bullet will be visible.
We still have to write the code that makes our bullet visible.
So when we place our bullet in the screen by using screen bullet, which requires two values in the
first place, we have to enter an image which is bullet image, and in the second place we have to enter
a tuple along with its coordinates which are x and y, which will be the values we're going to pass
to it when calling this functions, since those values are the same as the ones in rocket because the
bullet will come out of it.
We need to stress a difference so that the bullet comes out of the middle of the rocket.
Therefore, we add plus 16 here and plus ten here.
We have the function in charge of creating the bullet.
Then we need to call this function so that the bullet occupies a different space as it moves upwards
in each iteration.
So let's go to the game loop to enter this call.
This will be the result of an event.
Such events will take place when the user presses the space bar.
So let's go to the press arrow keys, which should be named Press Keys event.
Let's make it check if the space bar has been pressed.
We write it like this and we'll check if event dot key is equal to pi.
Game dot k underscore space.
The name of the space bar.
When someone presses it, we'll call the shoot bullet function.
So what values will we pass to it?
Note that I will enter some things so as not to get the expected result.
This is so I can show you how this works.
Then we'll correct it.
We need an x value first, so let's enter the same value as in Rocket.
So we'll enter player x and the height will be bullet y.
It should appear in the right place, but we'll soon see what's the problem here.
We'll execute this for now in order to see what happens.
So our rocket's here, we move it, and then we press the space bar and nothing happens.
Why?
Because the bullet appears once in the same place.
And then nothing happens.
It disappears as there is no iteration that makes the bullet linger.
We should constantly press the space bar in order to see the bullet.
And that's not the idea.
So let's go to the code section where we manipulate the movements and we're going to add bullet movement
so that our bullet keeps appearing in each iteration and we can see it moving upwards.
So how do we do that?
Well, we'll type if it's true that bullet is visible.
In that case, we'll call shoot bullet.
Every time we iterate once again, we're going to enter player X as position in X and bullet y as position
in Y.
And we're going to do something else.
We'll make our bullet move upwards.
So the value of bullet y will change in each iteration.
Bullet Y will be equal to minus equals the value of bullet y change.
You may remember we entered one.
Here it is.
This means it will be lose a pixel in each iteration.
And that's how it's going to move upwards.
So let's see if we manage to make this possible.
Here's our rocket.
Let's position ourselves and shoot.
The bullet goes up and up.
Great.
So there is a problem.
I can't shoot another bullet, and I should be able to.
And another problem is, look at this.
If I shoot and move, the bullet mimics the movement of the rocket.
And that's not the idea either.
This bullet shouldn't change its direction.
Well, we're going to solve these problems in our next lesson, so don't miss out.