Welcome to this new lesson here.
We'll learn how to calculate costs, totals and subtitles in cost panel.
All those calculations should be entered as we click on Total, so we'll manage to make the costs of
everything the customer has bought magically appear right here.
But before that, let's solve one problem.
I noticed as soon as we finished the last lesson.
Although our checkboxes work properly, since we can type numbers in here, what was entered in the
previous checkbox disappears when another checkbox is activated.
In other words, if I enter three here and one here and now I activate pudding.
What I enter before has gone.
It's something we can fix quite quickly.
So let's go to the review check function.
Here we have this line reading food box in position x delete, which is in charge of deleting everything
that's inside of it.
It deletes absolutely everything without checking it first.
So if we have any number, it will delete it since it's in a loop, which means iterates over all the
checks and deletes them.
So that's not the idea.
Instead of deleting everything encounters, let's make it wonder if food box in its position x is equal
to zero and only in that specific case will it delete whatever there is in food box.
Then let's copy this two lines and paste them in drink box.
But replacing food with drink, of course.
Let's do the same with dessert box delete, but making sure that both names read dessert.
Now if we execute this and if we select chicken type one, select soda and type three, the previous
number shouldn't disappear.
All right, now we can move forwards.
Let's assign a function to the total button.
We want this button to have a function named total calculation.
And in order to call that function, we'll need to go to our button's definitions.
Right here.
Here we have a list named buttons, and the buttons are created in this loop, but we have to assign
a command to it.
As we already know, we cannot assign different commands from a loop.
If we did it, we'd have to assign the same command to each button.
And that's not what we want.
Therefore, we'll have to create a new list that can be named created buttons, and it will store all
the buttons that are created in our loop.
As a result, we can call all those buttons after they're created and assign the command we need to
them to do so.
Let's position ourselves inside the loop and once the buttons are created, we have to call created
buttons using a pen, and then we add each button.
So when the loop ends, when we get out of it, we already have our created buttons list and our four
corresponding buttons here we'll call created buttons and it's index zero, which is the total button
and we'll assign a config to it so as to enter a command that's equal to total calculation.
It's the name of a function that doesn't exist.
So we're going to create it right away.
Let's go to the part of our code where all the functions are here.
We define it as total calculation and we want our code to make plenty of calculations.
When the user clicks on total, the code has to add up the values of everything bought by the customers.
Then it has to multiply that by the cost of such products and get a subtotal for food, another one
for drink, and another one for dessert.
After that, the code will get a subtotal adding up those three sub totals and it's also going to calculate
the taxes and overall total.
So if we have to multiply the number of products by their costs, we'll need to take those prices from
somewhere up here.
We'll create three more variables, which will be lists of prices in order not to take up the whole
video type in the costs.
I've already had them here in this text file.
I'll copy and paste it in a second.
So if you want it, I'll leave this file in resources so that you can copy and paste them too.
As you may know, these prices are made up.
So we have three lists which are named food prices, drink prices and dessert prices.
Now we'll be able to make our calculations.
So let's go to the total calculation function and create a variable named Food Subtotal, which will
initialize as zero and it will increase as we loop through everything.
For each unit in food text, which is the list containing the text values of each food box will make.
Food subtotal will be equal to whatever there is in food subtotal plus what's in unit, but unit is
a string type variable and so we have to obtain its value using get and we'll obtain an integer.
And this the number of units has to be multiplied by the corresponding price.
The food prices are in food price, but we need to know the index as food price is a list, we haven't
entered a value for the index, so we'll do that up here in a p variable initializing at zero.
So the specific price is the one in index P, which will be the index corresponding to each price.
We also need to take into account that food price has float type values and unit get has an integer.
So we're going to convert unit to float.
So it has to multiply it.
Since we have many symbols here, we'll make sure that multiplication and addition are carried out separately.
The only thing left now is to make p increase its value in each iteration, and we do so by putting
P plus equals one.
Is that okay?
So we've just done this with food, but let's review it.
We'll select one chicken and two kebabs and now let's get the total.
Well, we can't see it on the screen, of course, as we haven't configured that yet.
So let's create a print for now.
Print food, subtotal to see if it's working.
And once again, we pick one chicken and two salmons total.
And here we have the total, which is the result of those two multiplications.
We have to repeat this process in each category.
So we paste one and one more.
So this one's for drinks.
So we select several times so as to type drink.
And here we type dessert.
I think that's all right.
Since we entered three prints, we'll be able to see three subtitles on the screen.
So for now, let's select one chicken, one soda, and one ice cream.
And let's click on Total and we see three subtitles in the console.
These sums correspond to each category.
So let's delete the prints as we don't need them anymore.
Now we have to use these subtitles to calculate overall subtotal taxes and overall total.
Let's do that.
Let's go back inside the function and calculate the subtotal first.
We'll create a new variable named My Subtotal that's equal to food subtotal plus drink subtotal plus
dessert subtotal.
And we have a variable containing the sum of the three categories.
Let's create another variable named My Taxes.
Suppose we're eating at a restaurant where we're charged an 11% vat, so multiply my subtotal by 0.11.
So that's the tax value.
And my total would be equal to my subtotal plus my taxes.
We now have all the variables, but they haven't been assigned a box in cost panel.
So where do we put them?
Look, when we created cost labels and input fields some time ago, we said the text boxes would get
their text assigned to the text variable named food cost var in the case of food.
Next one is drink cost of a then dessert cost of.
Then we had subtotal bar.
This was followed by taxes bar and total bar.
So we have to assign the calculations we have just made to those variables in order to show them on
our system display.
So let's begin with food cost bar.
We'll create its contents using the set method and we'll create a string literal containing a currency,
a space and a total.
So how do we build this?
We call food subtotal.
But bear in mind that these won't be round numbers, since we're going to make multiple calculations,
even percentages.
It's very likely that we come up with lots of decimals.
So let's type round, add only two decimals and close it right here.
We'll copy this once to enter drink cost bar, which will be equal to the subtotal drink rounding.
And we'll paste it once more to do the same with dessert.
And we adjust it now.
Subtotal var and let's make sure to have my subtotal rounding.
That's the variable containing that value.
Now tax is var and where we round my taxes and the last one is total var which will contain my total
rounding.
So let's execute our application once more.
Let's say these customers had one chicken, two salmon, three juice, and one had pudding.
All right, let's click on Total.
And here we have each input field with its price so we can say our total button is working perfectly.
So let's continue with our next lesson so as to create the invoice function.