So far, the user can create new tasks he or she can view.
The tasks he or she has created can edit the tasks, and we need to give the user the possibility to
delete them too.
For that, we're going to add a class called Delete View that does two things.
First, it asks you if you're sure you want to delete them.
This would be a form that simply asks you a question on the screen, and once you confirm it, it will
delete the task from the list.
So let's go to Pie Charm where we're going to go to the task list file.
We're going to add a new item, a new cell, and we're going to put it after this one that says edit.
This one's going to say, delete the URL for now.
We're going to leave it empty.
Once we set it up, we'll come back here to add it.
Let's go back to our page and we're going to refresh it.
And here it says delete.
But I'm not clicking on it yet because it's not going to take us anywhere for now.
Let's go back to chart and continue with what's missing.
Let's create the view.
What do we have to do here?
We import the class which is also inside edit and it's called delete view.
We're going to create a class for this, which is going to be very similar to what we're doing so far.
A classic called Delete Task that inherits from Delete View, and we're going to assign it as we did
before, a model that's the same as task and as in the first classes in which we had the context object
name.
We want that here.
Also, the elements are not referenced as object, but this tab.
And finally we put a success URL because we want it to take us back to the home of our site once the
task is successfully deleted.
Now we need to generate the template to establish what is going to be shown when we choose delete.
So here in base, we're going to create a new file which we're going to call task, confirm delete dot
HTML as before.
We're giving it the name that the system will look for by default.
Then we'll rename it to our liking.
But for now we're going to leave it as task, which is the name of our list and then confirm delete,
which is the template that will search for delete view when we click on those links.
Well, in this HTML, we're going to put a form we're going to protect it as before with the bracket
and then the percent sign and then CSF token and it's protected.
So we're going to set this form to have the method post as the previous one, because although we're
not going to publish anything here, but on the contrary, we're going to be able to delete something.
We're uploading new information to the database.
We are not asking for anything back.
It's not a query.
So I hope this doesn't confuse you.
But keep in mind that post is not only publishing something but also sending a piece of information
to make something happen as this is the case.
So inside our form, we're going to create a paragraph so we can show something on the screen that tells
the user, you are going to delete this task colon and here you're going to put the name task with quotes.
And this is going to be a variable.
We will put it between two brackets task.
So let's go to the next line and here what we need is the delete button to appear.
Remember that we do this with an input is going to be type submit and this is going to have a value
the text delete and with this we have it.
We only need to add at the beginning, even before the form a link so that we can go back in case the
user enters delete but then doesn't want to do it.
And we put a tag A that says back and that tag takes us to the ref equal to inverted commas, bracket
percentage u r l tasks and we'd be ready.
This is already becoming routine because we already know what are the steps to generate each of the
links.
What we need to do here is to go to URLs and import the view that we have just generated, which is
delete task.
To which we are also going to generate a path.
So here we put the comma, add a path, and this is not going to be the edit task, but delete task
and we're going to leave the integer so you can choose which task is the one you want to delete here
instead of edit task.
It will also be delete task and the name will also be delete task.
So the only thing left to do now is to complete what we had left blank in task list here this link without
completing it.
So where should this take us?
Now that we have a name, we open the bracket and we open the percentage and we tell it.
We want to go to the URL, delete task, and we put task ID so that it knows which task to go to specifically.
So now we're done and we're going to our side.
So we're going to refresh here and we're going to delete the last two tasks that we created.
The first one is going to be made up task.
We're going to delete and it shows us the warning message, but it doesn't properly show us the name
of task.
So let's see what happened here, because it's supposed to say task.
So we go to views to see if the name is right.
And here's the error.
It says tasks plural.
The context object name should be task singular.
So let's go back to our site and let's take the opportunity to test the back link and it works fine.
So let's try again for the delete made up task and now it shows the complete message.
I click delete and it's gone.
It's no longer here.
So we go to delete other task and we see the message again.
Delete.
And now I only have the original three tasks left.
At this point, we have the basic functionality of our site completed and working properly.
In the next lesson, we're going to take some time to solve something very important.
In any site that handles sensitive information, we're going to generate a functionality so that the
user can log in and out so that this information can only be seen by someone who has proven their identity.
So we will see this in the next lesson.