One of the advantages of Python about variables is that you can store any kind of data in them.
For example, the variable my data can contain an integer, then replace it with a float, then change
it to a string and it would always be able to store whatever you put inside.
In most other programming languages, when you declare a variable, you have to give it a name and assign
it a specific data type, for example, integer.
From then on, that variable will only hold integers.
So that's what's great about variables and Python.
They only get a name and you can store any kind of data type inside them.
On the other hand, there may be situations where you need to convert the contents of a variable to
a different data type.
As we saw in the previous lecture, when we wanted to take a user input, which is a string data type
by default, and treat it as an integer in order to perform a mathematical operation on it.
The process of converting a specific data type into another is called casting, and there are two types
of conversions implicit and explicit.
Implicit conversion is done automatically by Python.
It happens when we perform certain operations with two different types, and Python solves it by transforming
the data type without us noticing.
In contrast, explicit conversion is when we expressly ask through the code for a data type to be converted
to another data type.
And how do we do it?
By expressing that we want to put a certain type of data into another.
For example, if I have a variable called my value that contains an integer, let's say the number one,
I can reassign it to another variable with a different data type, for example, a string.
Now if I print this variable, I will see the same value one.
But this time is no longer an integer, it is a string.
So now I can do other things like concatenate it with other strings.
Let's go over to Pi Charm and Federico is going to show all of this in action.
Thank you, Phil.
And let's see how these conversions behave within this file that I just created called conversions within
the data.
You can do the same and let's start learning how to make implicit conversions.
Which are those that Python does automatically when it's possible without having to express.
I want to make a conversion.
Let's see it with an example.
We're going to create the variable that is going to be called number one, and I'm going to give it
a value of 20 initially.
That is to say that it is an integer.
I'm also going to create another variable called NUM two and it will have a value of 30.5.
So known to as a float.
And in fact, if I print the type of number one and then print type of number two, and now I run this.
Wrong again.
And we go to conversions.
And there it is.
It tells me that the first variable is an integer and that the second variable is a float.
That's perfect.
So far, no surprises.
What I'm going to do now is here in the middle, before the data type is printed, I will do a rewrite
of no one.
I'm going to ask that now.
No one is equal to the value of the one, i.e. 20 plus the value of number two, i.e. 30.5.
So now no one is going to be 50.5.
So let's run this.
And now the funny thing is that the result of printing the two types of number one and number two is
now a float for each one.
Because in number one, when you did an addition that would now give you a value of 50.8 and how to
automatically transform or convert to a float.
Number one, stop the being in intake.
It became a float at the moment of printing the data types.
We already had to float.
This is an implicit conversion because we didn't ask Python.
Please convert and move on to a variable that we can support.
Float.
No Python automatically did it for us and saved some work for us.
There are situations where we have to explicitly ask for it.
Those are the explicit conversions and that's what we're going to look at next.
Let's declare a variable, a type of float, for example, let's name it number one.
And this variable is going to have a value of 5.8.
We're going to print number one and we're going also to print the type of data that corresponds to number
one.
It's going to tell us that 5.8 is number one and that is a type of float.
Perfect.
We already knew that.
But if I now want to transform this 5.8 value into an integer value, the way I have to do it is this.
Well, we're going to launch it in a variable name, for example.
Number two, and we're going to say that number to it is equal to the intrigue of number one.
So we want to want it to be transformed into an entire and in brackets of no one.
The reading of this would basically be I want them to to be equal to an intake confirmed by the number
one value.
If I want to print this, let me copy this first and paste it here.
But I change it to number two and we execute it.
It tells us first 5.8 float.
It is what corresponds to the lines two and three of the code.
Then we have created the NUM two and we have made the conversion.
We see that the printing of number two is a five.
What it did was necessarily to eliminate the decimals because number two only admits integers and notes
that what it did was not round it because if it had rounded, it would have taken it to six.
Since 5.8 is close to six.
What it did was eliminating all the decimal points and it left nothing but the intake.
Here we can see that the data type of number two is integer.
So here I've done a conversion.
I've transformed the value 5.8, which was lodged in number one into an intake using this approach,
which is the first data type that you have that you want to have and then in brackets the value that
you're going to transform into the data type.
So now let's try to do what we wanted to do before with the variable age.
Let's create that variable.
We're going to say that it is going to be equal to an input with the prompt.
Tell me your age.
We're going to do it in the same way as before.
But this time to be possible to succeed.
We're going to say that the value of age, which comes in a string, because that's the value of the
user enters, we're going to convert it as an intake of age.
So now age is an Antigua and I can make operations with that.
Then I want this variable new age.
The one that I used before to try to do some unsuccessfully in the previous lecture.
I want this to be equal to one plus eight.
And now you can see that I'm not getting any errors in the code.
It is allowing me to do it.
And now if I print New Age and run the code, it says, Tell me your age.
30 and 31 is the result of adding a value to age because age is now an integer.
Thanks to this conversion we've done up here and actually to make this more interesting, we're going
to put here after the user has given his answer, we're going to print the age type and we're going
to copy this line and we're going to print it again after we've done the conversion.
Notice how the program behaves now aged 30.
It tells me it's a string and it converted it into an intake.
And here we have our 31.
Yes.
The problem that we would have here is if what I want to do is to create the string in this, because
it tells me the new age is a sentence.
Because if I tried to do it.
If I want to include in a sentence that say something like Your new age is going to be.
Hey, we're going to leave the space.
And I want to concatenate it with New Age, which is the value that I already have.
Will this work?
Will it not work?
Let's see.
Let's executed.
My age is 30.
It's a string.
It says in Tiger and it tells me that there is an error here.
What kind of error?
It says that I can only concatenate strings, but not an integer with a string.
Of course, now that I transformed age into an integer, New Age is also an integer.
As you know already, I can't concatenate the string with an integer because this plus doesn't know
whether to concatenate or add.
And it can't really do either, because it has two different data types.
What would we have to do?
Do we have to transform New Age into a string now?
Well, we could, but it's not the most practical thing to go back and forth with data types doing transformations
all the time.
So in the next lecture, we're going to learn something that is going to help us solve this, which
is the print strings with values of any type by formatting the strings.
So let's go to the next lecture.