The Pavilion module is an important component of the Python standard library that allows us to manipulate
file system paths quickly on any operating system.
In the first part of the day, we learn how to work with without path lib because it is a relatively
new module and you are going to encounter a lot of code built in the old way.
And it is important that in this course you learn to read all kinds of code you come across.
But now we're going to incorporate this new feature to make file manipulation a lot easier.
Let's see it in the code to know all the possibilities.
Path Lib officers will start where we left off.
We have this variable named folder that contains a path created with the path object which we imported
properly.
We created this path with forward slashes and we were able to put everything together, the path and
the name of the file we want to open.
So I imagine that I want to open a file.
We already know how to do this, but we used to do it with the open function.
In this case I'll print folder which we have here, but folder is not an object like we used to have
before, which used functions for files or paths.
When we type a dot will see some different methods because folder is now a path object and path contains
other methods.
So to read a file we use read text which is similar to read the one we used in the first lecture of
the day.
If we execute this run, then run and click on path lib will see the contents of this test file.
It says Welcome.
So something's missing here, right?
Do you remember that we needed to do something that we're not doing now?
Exactly.
We neither have to open nor close our file.
We don't use open and close, but we just use these two lines containing the variable and the print
function in order to see what we're reading.
So Path Lib allows us to carry out several tasks more efficiently using less lines.
Actually, we're going to test another methods inside this print such as name.
The name method, which, as you can see, doesn't have brackets, will send us back the name of the
file.
Test dot txt text.
This method extracted the name from the path object.
So another method we have here is suffix, which is actually a function, which is why it doesn't have
brackets.
Suffix refers to the file extension.
That is the type of file.
So suffix will send us back the type of our file, which is a text file.
Text.
And if we look for another function, for instance, STEM, it will send us back the file name without
its extension.
Here we have test as a basic element.
So there's a lot of methods.
Try them on your own and see what they can do.
You can divide your path or file without opening and closing them, and you'll see that it's much faster.
There is also a method that allows you to check if this file exists, and we'll do that using IFF in
order to know what to do depending if it exists or not.
So let's see if not folder dot exists, which is the method that will return true or false since it
is a bowling.
If the folder doesn't exist, will print something like this file doesn't exist and else that is if
the file exists, will type print.
Yes, it exists.
And that's the message.
And we execute it.
Here it says the file exists because test is in my folder.
So now let's type tests to call a file that doesn't exist.
And now the system will say that the file doesn't exist.
So you have many more elements to manipulate, find and divide your files.
We also have a very nice method which will import.
Besides, path will import one method called pure windows path.
This method converts any path you have to a Windows path because this one here runs on Mac.
But if you wanted to convert this path to a Windows path, you'd have to import it just like I did.
And then you would create a new object named Windows Path.
That's equal to pure Windows Path and what's inside folder.
Now, we'll close all this and we'll print Windows Path, execute it, and we'll have the same path
we see here, but with back slashes.
So it'll adapt to the Windows format.
So we've barely glanced at all the possibilities.
Path live offices.
It is another great option to manipulate files and directories.
I advise you take a close look at this and check all the methods you can use the course and the documents.
So thanks for being here with us and see you in the next lecture.