You've already learned how to use pile in to identify style problems or serious bugs in your code.
In this lecture, we are going to learn how to use the built in unit test library, which we use to
see if our code is working as we expect it to work.
Unit test is a built in library, so we don't need to install anything here.
We just need to import it.
Generally, unit test dynamics are very simple.
On one side, you have a code that you want to test, say my file.
PY And on the other side a new module that we are going to use just to do our test first.
Like we said, I import unit test, then I import the module I want to test.
Then we are going to create a new class that inherits the test case method from unit test.
And inside the class we can create as many tests as we need.
How do you write those tests?
Come over to py charm and we're going to show you how they know what to show you how unit test works.
I'll create two new modules in day eight so you don't need to devise the same structure, create the
file wherever you like.
So my first file will be named change text dot P of course, and the second one will be test dot p y.
So change text will contain the text I want to test and test will be in charge of verifying if everything's
okay in change text I'll create a simple function named All Capital, which will receive the variable
text and return that text applying the string method upper to it.
And that's all.
So this is the function I want to test in order to see if it works as expected.
With unit test, we want to verify if a function returns what we expected to return.
It will verify if I created the function correctly.
And in this case we have a very simple function, but unit test is very useful when creating more complex
functions too.
So what do we need to do in order to use unit test?
For starters, we don't need to install anything since it is a python built in library.
We installed it when installing Python at the beginning of the course, so we just need to import it
by typing unit test here and that's it.
So we will also import the method change text which contains the function we want to test.
So import change text and we have it here.
Now we'll create a new class in this module.
We can give this class any name we want, so I'll name it.
Test change text.
This class will be responsible for checking if change text works and it will inherit from unit test.
Test.
Case.
Colon.
Okay.
We're inheriting all the methods contained in test case so as to use them in this class.
So now we're going to create a function in charge of verifying all of this.
So there's something fundamental about functions which do these tests.
Their names must start with the word test.
Otherwise, the software won't find your test.
So this will be named test uppercase.
Then you can give any name you want, but make sure it starts with test.
It will have self as argument and we'll look at three aspects.
First, I'll enter any word in order to see what happens with the function I've created in change text.
This can be wird, equal to study.
Now.
I'll check if my function returns this word uppercase.
Result is another variable that I'll create here and it will contain the outcome of applying the function.
That is the method all capital which I have in changed text which was applied to my test word.
So I'll call change text dot all capital here and I'll pass the word as parameter to it.
The same word I created up here, which is study in this case.
So now we have those two variables.
Now we'll call self assert equal, which is a method of test case in charge of checking to arguments,
result and the expected answer.
What I as a programmer think should be the result, which is study uppercase.
So I'll type study in uppercase between quotes.
So what will assert equal do?
It will check if result which contains this method is equal to study, which I typed manually so as
to verify that both words are exactly the same.
And if they are, it means that my method all capital is working properly so I could execute this.
But in order for this case to be executed as expected, I need to do something that may seem a little
bit confusing, but I'll explain it soon.
So let's type if underscore, underscore, name, underscore, underscore, equal to underscore, underscore,
main underscore, underscore.
Once again, let's close quotes add colon, enter and if name equals main, then we will call unit test
dot main and add brackets.
Well, I'm sure you don't know what all this is for, and I won't explain it in detail since it's quite
boring.
I'll leave detailed notes so that you can download and read them.
But I'll explain this plainly.
Most programming languages have a class named Main.
It is the entry point to start the execution of any program.
Still, Python doesn't work like that.
Main is a way to tell the system which function to execute and which to not.
It is a way to protect that code.
So I won't keep on taking up time with this.
So the notes are available for you to download.
Then you'll understand why we typed if name equals main in order to call unit test.
So since we have completed our code will execute it.
However, we won't execute change text but test as to check if change text works properly.
So we'll click on Run and Run Again.
Here we'll execute test and we'll notice that the test quickly reveals its result, which is okay,
meaning there was no problem.
Now we'll do it wrong.
Let's suppose that instead of returning all capital letters, we want the software to return study with
capital S only if we execute it, it will return an error because it didn't work as we expected.
Here.
It says assertion error.
It means that study, which is typed in capital letters, the result is not equal to study, which starts
with capital S and is the result I was expecting.
This lets me know that the method I use didn't return what I had expected because if I want this as
a result, I should use another method and in this case I should use title instead of upper.
Since it is a string method that returns a number starting with a capital letter, so let's execute
it and now we can see the test result is OC.
That's why we use unit test.
We don't use it to check if there are structure errors or style issues like when we learn about pilot
unit test helps us to check if our code returns what we expect.
This code didn't return any kind of error, but it could have malfunctioned.
So we used unit test.
This is quite useful, mainly when dealing with more complex functions than this one.
So I advise you to read the documents regarding unit test because it has a lot to offer and there are
many more methods besides assert equal.
However, it is a very important method for us.
So for more details, read all the documents and lock it up online and obviously use our Q&amp;A section.
So let's go to the next lesson.