So next stop in our Great Adventure is to program the invoice button so that when clicked, it generates
an invoice inside this blank square search.
Invoice should include in detail everything that China has had.
So let's get to it.
Go back to our code and take into account that we're going to import some tools for this.
One of them being random since we won't be entering real check numbers, but random ones.
Another tool will be using is date time because our check should include date and time of issue.
So let's go to our buttons.
And here they are.
And here we have a function that corresponds to the total button.
So let's create an index one of created buttons, a function that will be assigned to our check issue.
It can be named create invoice.
Let's go back up where we have created our functions and let's define a new one.
So the F and this will be named create invoice as well.
So let's begin.
We have to start typing lines inside the element we have there, which is a text element.
This element is titled Invoice Text.
Remember, we had created it when we added elements inside that panel.
Since we may have issued a check before invoice, text will be in charge of deleting everything before
we begin to issue a new check.
So we'll enter delete from 1.0 up to end, and this is how we make sure that our check is entirely blank
when we start to issue a new one.
We'll start by showing the check number.
So let's create a variable named invoice number, which will be equal to a string literal containing
MN, hashtag, space, hyphen and a random number.
Let's create a call to random dot random, and that number can range from 1000 to 9999.
So it's always a four digit number and it doesn't affect our check structure.
Now we have to add a date.
So let's create a variable named my date, which is equal to date time, date time.
Now, as you know, this will enter today's date.
So now that we have stored today's date, we will set the date format so as to show it in the invoice.
Let's enter invoice date, which will be equal to a string literal containing a month.
So my date month.
Then we concatenate using a forward slash so as to separate this from a call to my date dot day, another
slash and my date year and we have our date.
Then we'll use a hyphen and enter my date dot our and now we'll enter colon and my date minutes and
our variable containing the date form that we want is complete.
So let's enter it in invoice by calling invoice, text insert and at the end we'll enter a string literal
reading something like information, colon, invoice number and invoice date.
Let's write some tabs with backslash and T and here we insert invoice number.
Then we add two tabs and insert invoice date.
Would you like to see how it's going?
So let's execute it then and create a basic check.
We click on Total and here we have information, random number, date and time.
Let's separate the elements in our invoice text with some rows of asterisks.
So Invoice Text will receive another insert which will be in charge of inserting a row of asterisks
at the end of everything we wrote.
We add an F with asterisks.
We'll multiply this by 47, and as you already know, this number didn't appear out of the blue.
We've made some calculations, so I know which number to use.
So let's do a line break so as to always type into the line below.
Actually, I forgot to do a line break on the previous line.
All right, let's execute this and let's make a calculation.
And here we have a row of asterisks that looks great.
So let's continue.
Now we'll add the invoice head so as to detail the items and the costs.
So we'll keep on inserting features in invoice text from the end and will enter a string containing
the word items.
Then two tabs.
Then we add quantity, another tab and items cost.
Let's do a line break and move on to the next line so as to enter another separator line.
But this one won't be like the row of asterisks.
We'll insert an end and include a string literal containing hyphens which will multiply by 54.
And now we'll concatenate it with another line break.
Let's execute it and let's issue a check.
And we have items, quantity and items cost.
Everything the diner has had should be listed here.
So now it comes apart.
Quite difficult to program and yet it's fundamental.
We have to look for each food that has been marked as consumed.
Then we need to know the portions that have been consumed and obtain the total cost.
We need to create a loop that contains an x counter so as to constantly change registers.
So for each f in food, text will check if f dot get is different from zero.
If that register is different from zero, it means at least one portion was consumed.
Otherwise, if the check box isn't selected, it should be at zero.
Hence it shouldn't be included on the check.
So if it's different from zero, we'll insert at the end of invoice text a string literal containing
the food that has been consumed.
We find this inside food list in index x.
If it was the first iteration, this would return the string chicken and so on.
So then we'll concatenate this with two tabs as well as the check head, and we'll try to obtain quantity.
So how do we do that?
We just use F dot get and this will tell us the portions the diner has had.
Then we insert another tab so as to move on to the next column, which contains the costs.
So we have to show the currency and then we have to multiply so as to calculate the integer in food
dot get.
Let's press enter so as to see the complete line on the screen.
It's too long.
So we have the quantity and we multiply it by whatever is in the food prices list in index x.
After that, we do a line break to move on to the next line to make sure that our loop starts again
and again.
We'll add x plus equals one right at the same level of if x will increase a value in each iteration
that way.
So far, everything we've done corresponds to food.
So let's see if it works.
Let's pick chicken and two salmons and we click on Total Invoice.
And here we have chicken one and its cost, then salmon two.
And it's cost.
Well, well done.
Let's repeat the process with each category.
First drink.
Here we enter D and we type drink here.
Let's just everything.
Okay.
Now desert.
And let's copy and adjust everything again for desert.
Perfect.
Now, before each loop we make x reset its value to zero so it can iterate correctly.
That's right.
I believe there are no mistakes.
So let's execute this.
We pick two chicken, three juice and five puddings.
Let's click on total and go to invoice.
And here we have our items, quantity and cost.
It works.
Our invoice is almost ready.
Now we have to provide it with the subtitles.
I have to do another separator line and we'll use this one.
We don't need to write it again.
We'll put it there.
Now we'll insert a head inside invoice, text, insert end, and it'll be followed by string, literal
reading, food, subtotal, colon, space and three tabs.
We don't have to take into account the previous columns anymore, so we call the food cost variable,
the one containing the calculation we made in our previous lesson.
Surely we have to use the get method to obtain that value and we do another line break before finishing
the string.
Let's copy this so as to do the same with drink and dessert.
We replace the corresponding words and variables.
We'll enter another separator line so as to move on to the final calculations.
So we'll do that by copying these three lines as we can put subtotal here, taxes here and total here.
Now we have to modify the variables containing the information.
This will be subtotal var and this will be taxes var and this total var.
So I think we're ready.
Let's test it again.
We'll pick lamb, one juice and one pudding.
Total invoice.
And look at this.
Everything's fine.
Besides the items and the costs, we also have cost of each category subtotal taxes and overall total
to be paid.
We need to finish this check by using another string.
We'll use the one with the asterisks once more.
This should include a farewell message.
So invoice text, insert end.
And here we should include a message reading something like.
See you soon.
What a nice check.
It should be ready.
Let's test it once more and pick one chicken, two wine and four cheesecake.
Let's click on Total Invoice.
And here we can see an overall total, followed by a row of asterisks and a farewell message.
So after several hours of hard work, we managed to create an invoice.
We should save this project as text file using the save button, shouldn't we?
So let's configure that in our next lesson.