Did you think that what you've seen so far was going to be the highlight of the day?
If so, then you've missed the entire point because loops are another cornerstone of programming code.
And what is a loop?
Well, as you may know, a loop means to make something happen again and again.
For example, when you like a music track so much that you activate this function to play it over and
over again, well, that's a loop in programming.
It is when you want a block of code to run more than once.
In these situations, loops are great because if you have to make something happen, say, 100 times,
you don't need to write that block of code 100 times.
You just put that block inside a loop that is programmed to repeat 100 times.
You can also put your code in the loop that repeats an indefinite amount of times until a certain condition
is met.
For example, make the player in your game, run the code fire missiles non-stop until the condition
number of projectiles equals zero is met.
Before moving on to the next lecture, I want to teach you a concept that is closely related to loops,
and that is the iterable concept.
In programming, there are some objects that are iterable.
This means that you can iterate or go through their internal elements one at a time.
For example, a list.
Any list has a specific number of elements, let's say five, then a list is iterable, because you
can execute a loop that does a repetition for each element of the list.
You can create a code that prints the objects in a list, one at a time until the list is exhausted.
We will see how this is implemented.
But the most important thing for now is that you understand that all objects that have a number of elements
that you can iterate on, such as list dictionaries or strings, are iterable objects, and we will
see this in more depth.
To sum up loops repeat a block of code as many times as necessary, and there are two different types
of loops those that repeat for a defined number of iterations and those that repeat for an indefinite
number of iterations.
In the next two lectures, we are going to look at both types, starting with the for loop, which belongs
to the first group, and then the wild loop which belongs to the second.
You don't want to miss them.
So jump to the next lecture right now.