Now that we have on screen the way to see if the user is logged in or logged out, let's create the
forms so that the user can do this dynamically.
So on the views, we're going to create a view for this.
We're going to have to import something else.
We're going to import from Django contrib fourth dot views and from here we're going to import log in
view.
And now that we have imported, we're going to create a class.
It makes sense that we create this class at the top of the list because it's the gateway to all the
other classes.
So we're going to put this class here, which is going to be called log in.
It's going to inherit from log in view colon and inside it we're going to set up some parameters.
First template name.
This template doesn't exist yet.
So let's define its name now.
And then we must remember to give it this name.
It's going to be reached through bass, which is the name of the application slash login page HTML.
Let's remember that to name our template afterwards.
What fields will it have?
Well as this form comes in the login view, then it comes with several fields.
We want to use them all, but we do what we did before.
Inverted commas, double underscore all and close.
We're also going to set up a parameter called redirect authenticated user, which is a Boolean parameter
that determines whether or not we're going to redirect the user when they're authenticated.
So we want this to be true.
And finally through a function, we're going to rewrite the method.
Get success.
Your URL.
It would be the site that the user goes to once they've logged in.
We put self here and what we're going to return is a reverse lazy.
It takes us to tasks.
So what does this mean?
This is going to mean that when the user has successfully logged in, the system is going to automatically
take them to the tasks page so that they can see the content of that page and therefore they're going
to be able to access all the tasks.
So this is how we configure login view.
Now we have to configure the URLs to get there accordingly.
We also need to import this view that we just created, which is called log in and we need to give it
a path.
We're going to put it up here since it's central and we're going to make a path that takes us to log
in.
And remember, that's the name we're going to give to the page.
Then we're going to call login as view as we already know so that it can be seen as a view.
What name are we going to call this?
It's going to be name, same as logging, being consistent in always giving the same names.
So we've just created the login view URL.
Now we want to create that file here.
So we come to base, which is where we said we're going to get this file.
So new file and here we put log in HTML.
This name has to be the same as the one we put in views.
Otherwise there will be problems.
So let's create this form.
We do it first with ah1 tag, make a header and we're going to put log in.
This is what you're going to see at the top.
And we're going to create a form with the tags that open and close.
We're going to configure it to have a method equal to post.
As you know, this is because we're going to provide information and not to receive it or to search
for it.
And now inside the phone, we're going to protect it, as we've already learned to do with CE srf token
so that the pirates don't come and we're going to call form DOT as P and remember that this is so that
it is organized with a paragraph format.
This makes the form elements line up on top of each other.
The system will then automatically understand that form belongs to login view and we're also going to
put a button so that the user can send the information once he or she has completed all the fields.
So we create the buttons with the tag input whose type is going to be submit and its value is going
to be log in.
This is how the user is going to log in.
Close this input and now we have the form created.
We can set the destination of the link.
Remember that here in task list.
We have left these two links without completing them.
Well, now we can complete the one that corresponds to the log in, which is the one we need in case
the user is not authenticated.
Here we simply put the bracket.
The percentage you are l log in, which is the name of our page and close with the same sign and the
bracket.
And there we have it configured.
If we now come to our site, refresh and go to log in.
Now it takes me to the form that is already created.
In this case, it automatically loaded my data, username and password and I click on login.
I go back to the home, but this time I'm already logged in.
And now that we have this configured so that the user can log in from the site, we have to configure
the logging out to.
Here.
We're going to use the form provided by Django Directory.
We don't need to create our own view.
We come to you, Earls, and we're going to import the logout view by typing from django dot contrib
dot auth dot views import logout view.
We're going to create a path to this as well, of course, which is going to take us to log out slash
and we put log out view dot as view.
And finally the name, which is going to be consistent.
So it's going to be log out.
And now what I need to do is to set the value of the perimeter, which is next page, which is the attribute
that determines where the user is going to be sent once successfully logged out.
So imagine the user logs out, clicks on, log out.
And where is the system going to send them?
You should send them to the login page so that he or she can then log in again if they want to.
So we set this in the as view.
And here we set the parameter next page to be equal to log in, which is the name of the login page.
And now that we have a destination after clicking on logout we can come to task list HTML.
Because here we miss the define the destination of this log out and now we have that destination created.
We want our ETF takers to bracket sign.
You are l log out percentage and bracket again.
Now everything is set up.
Now that I am now logged in and I'm going to log out and I'm logged out.
And it takes me directly to the login form.
I can log in again and I'm now logged in.
Log out again and I'm logged out.
If I enter the page manually through the address bar skipping this login and it allows me to enter the
same.
Of course, this is not desirable.
The user should not be able to do what I just did, which is to enter this pending list without being
logged in.
And that is what we'll do in the next lesson.
We're going to restrict the user from seeing certain content if they're not logged in.
So let's do it.