Last lesson, we learned how to issue a check, taking into account everything the diners had.
And we also learned how to do it using the invoice button.
Now we're going to learn how to use the save button so as to save our invoice as a text file.
This won't be as hard as you may think, because we'll just have to follow three simple steps.
First, we need to configure this button accordingly.
Let's go to this button located in index two and we'll assign a command to it.
This is a call to a function we haven't created yet, which will be named save invoice.
And our software complains, of course.
Now we'll go to our function so as to create the new one save invoice.
And once again we'll need to import some elements we don't have yet.
From TK Enter will import an element named file dialog and another one named Message Box.
In our function we'll take all the text from invoice and we're going to store it in a variable.
It will be named invoice info which will be equal to invoice text, the variable in which we entered
all the inserts during our last lesson.
So let's call the get method in order to obtain its contents and we'll get whatever there is from the
beginning with 1.0 up to the end with end.
Now we have stored all the invoice information in a variable.
We'll create a file.
Now it can be named my file and it will be equal to a file dialog element.
Don't ask save as file.
I think it's pretty obvious title inside it's brackets will have to enter two things.
First, a mode which will be w the right mode and second default extension which will be equal to text.
Therefore, our file will have a text extension by default.
So my file is the variable that will contain this file.
Let's call my file.
Right and here we'll type invoice info and that's it.
Now we have to close it.
So let's use close.
And once the file is saved, will inform the user about it.
So let's call message box with the show info method which will ask for a message header.
Let's put notification and then your invoice has been saved and that's all.
So let's try it.
Let's pick one chicken, one kebab.
Two COLAs and two brownies.
Now that we're full, we'll ask for a total and invoice.
And now we're going to save it.
When we click on this button, we have to choose a location.
I'll save it with the rest of today's files.
Name it.
Invoice one and save it.
And now I see the message.
All right, we accept.
And if we go to the folder, we'll come across our invoice one.
If we open it, we can see all the information regarding my purchases.
This is huge.
Now for the final touch will generate code for the reset button, which resets everything to zero so
that we can assist another customer.