And it is time for the math module whose name says it all.
Math is another integrated Python module and we only have to import it to be able to use all of its
resources.
Basically, this module contains the complete kit of resources to work with numbers and python, from
simple mathematics to trigonometry passing through different types of routings.
Today, I want to show you some of them so you can learn how to use this resource.
However, you can check the documentation to know more about this resource, the dozens of operations
it allows you to do.
If numbers are your thing, this is the chest you should learn to open.
Let's go over to Pi Charm.
And as Phillips said, math is a goldmine.
Though it's pretty basic and easy to use, we simply import math and now we can see what methods are
inside the math object.
So let's create a variable called result that is equal to math dot.
And here we have dozens and dozens of methods that allow us to do all kinds of calculations.
Let's try some of them, for example, floor, which means round numbers down towards the floor.
And if here I put any number of type float to go round it and then we print to see the result in screen,
what is it going to show us when executing it is 89.
It rounded down the number.
If I use the SEAL method for sealing, which rounds up this value here would have been 90.
Another element that you will find inside the math module is the letter PI.
Well, this is actually not a method, but a value that if we print it, will give us 3.141516, etc..
PI is an absolute value that exists and that you can use for your operations like calculating radius,
etc..
We also have some trigonometry.
For example, we can create a math log, which is a logarithm that if we pass a number and a base allows
us to create, how many times we have to multiply that base to get the number.
So let's see an example.
If I have 100 and then I have five.
What this math log is going to give me as a result is how many times I should multiply it.
Five so that it gives me a value as 100.
And if we execute it, it is 2.8, six, one, etc..
So we're going to do it with an easy number.
If we put 25 and we execute it so that five exposed to another number x returns 25 but number X should
be two because five times five is 25.
We also have ten, which is the tangent.
If you work with these kind of values, you know that you put here any number and the tangent of that
number will be returned.
We can also get the cosine of a given number with the cost method.
Well, the truth is that this is a module that should investigate according to your interest, because
there are dozens and dozens of methods that allow you to make calculations.
And as I told you, there are they are from basic to more advanced mathematics, trigonometry, etc..
And in fact, although it's very complete, math has its limitations, because if you work with numbers
and you do very advanced things with them, maybe you need other modules that don't come with Python,
such as NumPy.
If you look for it in pi p or in Google, you will find that numpy has many more options to work with
numbers.
If you really like numbers, that's where you'll get them.
In fact, later in the course, we're going to look at NumPy a little bit more.
So you have these two options, math for the average human beings and numpy for the geniuses.
And for now, I'll let you play with this module for you to get familiar with some alternatives.
And I am off to the next lesson.