Finally, we have to activate the reset button.
This one here.
Then our program will be ready when we finish programming.
This button will delete everything in the text boxes and deactivate them.
In addition, this button will delete the updated checkboxes.
Empty these boxes here and delete the invoice we have just issued in order to start issuing a new one.
It's not complicated, actually, so let's do it.
We just have to add one more command to this last button, which is in index three, and this function
will be named reset all.
Of course, the software is complaining as we haven't created that function yet.
So let's scroll up to the function section and let's create reset.
All of function doesn't receive any parameters.
It should start by deleting the check and we'll do that by writing one single line of code invoice,
text delete.
And this will delete everything from beginning to end.
We delete the check with this?
So let's try it.
We just pick one chicken and we issue the check.
Click on Reset and the check is gone.
Now this button will delete the text inside the food boxes.
So we'll start a four loop so that for each text in the food text list, it will make text set B equal
to zero.
We'll repeat this in drink and dessert.
So we type drink here and dessert here.
Let's test it.
In order to fix any problem we might find.
We pick one chicken, one juice, one ice cream, and we issue a check and we reset.
Now, every box was reset to zero.
Now we'll make the boxes remain deactivated.
Do so we'll start another loop for each box in the food box list.
We will configure each box dot config that there states change to disabled and when we repeat this process
so that it also works for drink and dessert.
Replace the words and that's it.
Let's test it again by doing the same as before.
Now invoice.
And when we click on Reset, the boxes are deactivated.
Now we need another loop to deactivate the checkboxes.
This time we will iterate over each var found in food variables.
Remember that food variables is where the check button value is stored.
It can be zero or one.
In var will add a set starting at zero, which means it is deactivated.
Let's copy this loop so as to use it in drinks and desserts.
Let's run a new test to check if it's working.
And let's click on Reset now.
And the checkboxes are deactivated, too.
Now, these boxes need to be deleted as well.
We'll have to do them one by one.
Let's make food cost.
Var have a set in an empty string.
Let's copy this variable and paste it five times as there are six boxes.
One for drink cost.
Another one for dessert cost via another one for subtotal via another one for taxes var and the last
one for total var.
We're almost done but test by selecting more elements this time we'll have a lot of things.
Since it's our last try, let's pick for kebab.
Five beers.
Three COLAs, and now let's execute it.
We issue a check and when we click on Reset, everything is reset to zero so that we can issue a new
check.
Our invoice system is ready.
Congratulations on getting so far.
It was quite intense, wasn't it?
So let's get some rest and tomorrow is going to be unforgettable.