We often need to write a string that also contains other variables.
For example, if I have the information about the color of a car and its license plate number and I
want to print a sentence containing both values.
As far as we know now, I would have to resort to casting to transform some of those values.
And I would also have to do a lot of concatenation that may become too long, impractical or difficult
to read.
That's why we're going to learn how to format strings in this lecture so that we can solve this in a
more practical way.
In Python, there are two ways to do it.
The first one is using the format function.
It's syntax is very simple.
You write the phrase in a single string without concatenation or anything, but you replace the values
that are contained in variables with two empty braces.
After the closing quotes, you add dot format and then in brackets and ordered the variables containing
the values to be replaced, separated by commas.
Here, it doesn't matter if the content of those variables is string, integer, float, or whatever
format will display them as strings without the need to cast and change the data type of your variables.
This solved a lot of problems when it was incorporated into Python because it's very handy, although
it has a big disadvantage if not very readable.
To understand this sentence, the human eye has to go back and forth to make sense of it.
That's why version 3.6 of Python incorporated the so called literal strings, which gives a twist to
this format doing it in this way.
When constructing your string, you add the letter F before the first quotation mark.
This tells Python that this is going to be a literal string and then you put the braces to replace the
variable values.
Only this time you put the variable name inside the braces.
Isn't it cool?
Issue solved now.
Formatting strings is practical and readable at the same time.
You might say okay, fail, but if the second approach is so great, why don't we just learn that one
and that's it?
Well, because there are many people who use both ways.
And in your career as a programmer, you're going to find a lot of code written like this, and it's
important that you know how to interpret it.
Now let's go to pie charts and put this into practice.
So let's put into practice these two types of formatting strings.
We're going to do it in this new file that I've created called Formatting Strings.
Let's start by creating two variables that we want to be incorporated into our string.
These two variables will be X equals ten and Y equals five.
I've already have two variables with two values to integrals, and I want to create a statement that
says, My numbers are this one and that one.
So what I do in the traditional way would be to say, print my numbers.
And with the old way, I would have to leave a space here, concatenate.
Then I would have to put the value of X.
But I could not do it because x is an integer and I want to transform it into a string.
So I would have to say s t to convert it.
As we have just learned.
And then a space.
Concatenate this with a string created with the value of y.
And I believe that here we would already have it.
In fact, let's see if we run it.
Run, run, formatting strings.
And we did it.
It says, My numbers are ten and five.
I have achieved it.
But as you may have noticed, using a lot of conversions in concatenation and this is not practical
at all.
So let's delete all of this.
And if I want to do it with this, the format function, we directly say my numbers are.
And here we write some braces to occupy the value of the first number and other more braces to occupy
the value of the second number.
We close the quotation marks and then we write format so that this method is applied, which is going
to ask me to enter inside the brackets the values that are going to occupy these braces in the correct
order.
So we're going to put X, comma, Y, separated by commas, and you can continue adding values if you
have more keys.
And now if I run this, it says my numbers are ten and five, but it's created in a much more practical
way.
I didn't have to do any concatenation nor transformation.
Notice that if I change the order of the numbers here and put the Y first and the X.
After.
When I print it out again, it will tell me my numbers are five and ten.
It has flipped them around and I didn't have to do that much.
I could actually do operations as well.
Look, we're going to change this whole sentence and we're going to put it.
That what it says here is the sum of and we're going to put the first number and we put the second number
is equal to and here we put one more set of braces.
And what we're going to do is put in format first Y, then X, and we're still missing one more value
for the third set of braces, which is going to be the sum of Y plus X.
So I do the operation here in this third space that I've reserved inside of format to occupy this key.
So we're going to run it.
And it tells me that the sum of five and ten equals 15.
We we're able to solve the operation even without the need to create a variable here that we would have
called Z and that it would be equal to X plus Y, which would have worked in the same way I would have
replaced this operation here with Z and printed it out, and it would have given me exactly the same
thing.
I just solved it in a different way.
So this is one more way to format your strings.
It's efficient.
It's practical because you don't have to do concatenation.
And it was solved in a very easy way.
But it is not quite readable, we could say.
So let's try also the second way to do it.
Let's start from scratch now to be able to work with strings and with integers.
So we're going to delete all of this and we're going to create first a variable called color, and its
content is going to be red.
And we're going to create one more variable that's called license plate, referring to a car, obviously.
And the license plate is going to be a number.
Let's say 541926.
Well, what are we going to print here?
We're going to say print.
We open the brackets and we're going to use the other way of doing it, which is with something called
literal strings.
And as Phil told you, the first thing you have to do is put the F before the quotes.
This tells Python, Hey, Python, pay attention.
This is going to be a literal string and we're going to compose it like this.
The car, as we write the braces here and inside the braces, we put the content, which is in this
case, the variable color and it's license plate IDs and we open keys and here we put license plate,
which is the next value.
Then the key is closed.
We don't need to put format or anything because the values are already in there.
If we run it, we get the car is red and its license plate is 541926.
That is to say that it works perfectly.
And this way I believe that it is superior approach because it is not only practical as the format function,
but it is also readable.
The car is color and the license plate is license plate.
It doesn't get any easier than that.
So this is the best way, I think.
But you have to learn all of them and use them, one that you are most comfortable with.
None of them is wrong.
They're all valid.
So now you know how to do it.
So I invite you to the next lecture where we have something amazing to teach you.