Now we know how to make it so that only registered users can access this site.
But for now, all the users who successfully log in will see the same information.
Be it win ten, be it Peter, Mark, or whoever.
And that's not the idea.
In this lesson, we're going to see that the system only shows each user his own information, the task
he or she is created, and not those of others, but as we have not yet created, a form that allows
you to create new users from the site.
We will learn how to do this in the next lesson.
For now, we're going to create a new user through the admin panel.
So let's go to admin and come to users and go to add.
And the name this new user has is Alex.
And assign him his own password.
We save it and we already have a new user.
Alex, So we can close here now.
And now if I log out as 110 and log in as Alex with my own password.
I can see for now the tasks that win ten has created, and this would be a huge security flaw.
Alex can see the items in the Win ten list, but Win ten is supposed to be the owner of these tasks
and therefore only win ten should be able to see them.
This limitation that we want to set should be coded in views because as we're seeing here, when we
display the pending list, what the program does is return it to everything in the model.
It looks for all the objects which in this context are called tasks and displays them all.
So we're going to modify this using a method called get context data, which will allow us to receive
only certain data depending on the context.
This way, if the context is Alex, we will only receive data from Alex and not from Wind ten or any
other user.
So let's override this method so that it behaves as we want it to.
Inside the pending list class, we will generate the function putting death and the name of the method,
which is get context data and we're going to remove almost all of its parameters.
We only want to leave self and quads.
And these are the two elements that this method is going to need so that we can overwrite it.
So let's set the context value.
So I say that context is going to be equal to super, which means super instance.
And to that super we're going to apply the get context data method, meaning that we're going to make
sure it's inherits from the original element and as an argument, we're going to tell it that we want
all the cogs that it owns.
So here we're going to start setting the values.
And by default, we want it to return some context information.
We want it to return the context.
In a moment, we're going to configure what the context is.
But now we've established where it's coming from and what it's going to return for.
Now as it is, it would return everything.
So let me show you this with an example.
Let's put in here before return a determination that context in its argument city to make something
up is equal to London.
And leave it at that.
Now let's go to our task list.
And under the heading pending list, which is the one we have here in each one.
Let's add the argument city.
So if we come to the site now and we refresh, we're going to see pending list London.
So what did we do here?
We pass in a context which is city.
I'm going to delete this, which we assign a value to.
And we did it here in views.
And that value is the one that was applied and could be displayed in the form.
This, but in a more complex way, is what we're going to do next.
In fact, we're going to set the context.
We want to set in tasks.
And what are we going to do?
We're going to make the context equal to context.
So far, we're not saying anything.
It's a redundancy.
But follow me on this and it will make sense.
So the context task is going to be the same as the context task, but with a filter applied so that
we can filter it to show only what corresponds to the user self.
Dot request.
Dot user.
Do you remember this expression?
Request user.
We used it in the task list in the form here where it showed request user in this paragraph.
So it could show Alex or Win ten or whatever name it is because this is where we filtered it out.
Well, this same expression is the one we use to apply a filter so that it only allows the tasks of
the currently logged in user.
And one more thing we want to do here, and this may seem a little confusing, but it's very necessary
to be able to see the tasks we want to see.
Is that also inside the context count?
Let's set it to be the same as context tasks, but now filtering by another of the fields that we have
in our form, which is completed, we're going to filter only those where completed is equal to false,
i.e. those that are not complete.
And to do this, we're going to apply the count method.
The reason why we do this is to be able to see only the tasks not completed and not absolutely all the
tasks of the user that is registered at the moment.
If we come now to our form being Alex, we refresh and it informs us that there are no tasks.
This is correct.
Alex doesn't have any items in his list yet.
And as you remember, we've established that when the loop results in no tasks, it has to show this
message.
And that's what it does.
Because Alex has no tasks of his own.
Now, has win ten lost all its previous tasks?
No.
We're just not seeing them because we are the registered user is now Alex.
So if I log out and log in is within ten here, I can see my tasks.
But let's go back to Alex because that's where we're testing things.
Okay.
Here we are.
And let's create a task of our own for Alex from here.
Well, first of all, I don't want this field to appear anymore because this allows you to choose the
user to load the task.
And that's not the idea.
We're going to remove it in a moment.
But for now, let's create a task such as park the car.
This is a task for Alex.
We save it and we're not seeing it.
And the reason is that we've not haven't chosen the user.
So it doesn't show me anything.
I need to override the method called form valid.
So the new tasks are assigned to this user automatically and so he can see them as now I don't apply
inside the form to whom it was assigned.
The system understands that this task is not from Alex.
So we go back to pie chart.
We go back to views and look for the class called Create Task.
This is the one we want to modify.
We're going to overwrite with a function the form valid method.
And this already includes self and form.
How are we going to configure this override of the form valid method we're going to call form, dot
instance, dot user.
And what we want is that from now on, this instance, user in our form will be equal to self.
Dot request.
Dot user.
This means that it will automatically assign the value of this instance to the logged in user.
The system itself will figure it out.
It's going to say, okay, if Alex is logged in, then the author of this task is Alex.
And what this method has to return is super with the attributes, create, task and self.
And to this we're going to apply form valid, which is going to receive the form as an argument.
So with this I should have achieved that.
The new tasks are automatically assigned to the registered user.
But in addition to this, I want to make it so that the user field is no longer visible in the task
form because it no longer makes sense to have it there.
So here, where it says Fields equals all, we don't want to see all fields anymore.
We want to create now is a list called fields that has the fields that we want to show which are going
to be title description and completed.
So we're going to copy these three fields and paste them also inside the edit task class because we
want that when we edit tasks, we can't see the user field either.
And now we go to the site and this time we create again a task for Alex and we don't see the user field
anymore.
I rewrite the task called Park the car we send.
And now Alex has parked the car pending.
If we go to win ten and create a new task such as bake the bread.
I send it and now Win ten has a new task to accomplish.
But if we go back to Alex, this task is not going to be found there.
We see that Alex still has only one task created by him.
So this is how we make the created tasks visible only to their authors.
We have now made it so that each author can only see his or her information.
In the next lesson, we're going to learn how to make it possible to register new users from the site.
So I'm onto the next lesson and I'll be waiting for you there.