So welcome to today's final lesson.
And we'll be creating code to control the end of the game, to have some peace of quiet and work properly.
I've turned off the music by deactivating this block of code.
We'll activate it again soon.
Don't worry.
So what we have to do now is to make our game end.
As soon as the enemies get to the rocket that is at the 500 pixel level, we'll try to code the event
that's going to take place when our enemies have a value higher than 500 in their y axis.
So note that in order to test this, I'll set a limit of 250 so that we don't always have to wait until
the enemies reach the bottom of the screen.
Okay.
Where are we going to do this code?
We should go to the block where we've programmed the enemy movements over here, modify enemy location,
and here we have a loop that checks if each iteration for each enemy.
So at the beginning of this block will verify an enemy has reached this point and we'll write end of
game.
Now we ask if an enemy Y has reached a height greater than 500 pixels.
As I already told you, that's the correct number, but we're going to use 250 OC.
If an enemy reaches this point, we have to remove all the enemies from the screen.
To do so will create another loop for each K in the range corresponding to number of enemies, which
means it will go over each one and this loop will assign each of them a new position on their y axis.
We'll remove them from the screen by dragging them down, and so we will create the illusion that they
disappear.
So the enemy y value of each k element that is each enemy will be equal to 1000.
That number is more than enough to make our enemies disappear as our screen is only 600 pixels high.
So following this loop and still inside the if clause, we'll call a new function if the previous condition
is met.
This function is final text, so we haven't defined it yet.
We'll do that soon and remember this name so as to write it exactly like that later.
So now let's enter the break command so as to terminate this loop.
So this is the code intended to verify if an enemy has gotten to where the rocket is thus ending the
game.
So where can we code the end of the game?
Let's scroll up because we have to do two things.
First, we have to create the function we called earlier, and second, we have to create the game over
message.
So we'll create an end of game text and we'll create the variable named end font containing PI game
just like before with font font capital F now just like we did on line 54, we have to set a font type,
so let's choose the same fast test TBTF and IT size will be 40 this time.
The font we needed is ready, so now we need the function.
We said it would be named final text colon and now we'll implement it.
We have to call another variable here which can be similar.
So we'll name it my final font and it will be equal to end font, but we'll make some changes and font
dot render will contain an uppercase text reading game over grade.
And here we have to add true, which is one of the parameters it requires.
The other one is color, so let's choose white again.
So we enter 255 and this variable is ready.
Now we have to display this variable on the screen.
So screen dot blip.
Lets enter my final font and the location with an x and y tuple which will contain value 202 hundred.
So where do these numbers come from?
I was testing this when I found out it was the best option to make our message appear in the center
of the screen.
So if you want to change this, you can try different numbers until you're satisfied.
So let's execute this.
And the game has started.
And when they reached the point we wanted game over, they all disappeared.
A message reading game over popped up where I wanted and the game was ended.
So now we can activate both music and sounds again.
Let's replace this with 500.
So the game ends when the enemies reach our rocket and we finish programming our game.
If you think about it, we started from scratch and thanks to PI game, we were able to create a new
playable game and that's that's huge.
Do you remember when you started this course you could barely print and do a couple of things more.
So you've gotten really far in just a few days.
Tomorrow we'll be pretty cool.
So have some rest and.
I'll see you there.