In this lesson, we're going to learn how to create a page containing a registration for new users so
that new accounts can be created directly from the application.
As you already know, the procedure to create a new view with a new form.
I remind you that the steps we're going to follow are first to create the link, then the form, then
the view, then the URL.
First, we're going to create a link here under the login button.
This link is going to say if you don't have an account, register here.
So let's go to Punjab and let's go to log in.
And here we're going to add below the form a paragraph that says, don't have an account and then a
link.
That has a h r f a link that we don't know yet what it is because we haven't created it yet.
But for now we're going to leave this set up with the text register here.
So if we refresh here, we see our text and this link doesn't take me anywhere yet.
Now let's create the form that we would see if we go to register here.
Then in pie charm, we go to base and create a new file called Register dot HTML.
And what are we going to put in here?
We're going to put the same thing that we have in login.
We're going to copy all of this and we're going to paste it and adapt it inside register.
So what would we have to change here?
That here above instead of log in, it says sign up.
This other thing would leave it almost the same.
The value of the button.
Instead of saying log in, it will say, sign up, and here it will say, Do you already have an account?
And in that case, in this part it will say, log in and it will take us to with the brackets and percentage
URL and log in.
Then we have the form that we should see when we log in to the register site.
Now we need to create a view for this.
So let's go to views.
Django doesn't have a specific view for registrations, but there is a generic form view that we can
tailor to our needs.
And here we can incorporate inside the generic form view of form for registration, which does exist
in Django and will import it.
So within edit, we're going to add a form view here.
And we also want to import this method that I mentioned which is called user creation form and we're
going to incorporate it from Django dot contrib auth form and we're going to import it into user creation
form.
We're also going to need a method called login.
We load it with from django dot contrib auth import login and that's all we need to start building a
class that we're going to put underneath the class.
That's called login here.
We're going to create a new class that's going to be called Register Page, that's going to inherit
from form, view and its contents.
We're going to assign a value to some attributes.
The first one is template name, which is going to be based slash registered HTML.
And this is to define what to write in the address bar.
Foam class will be equal to user creation form.
And also redirect authenticated user.
Remember that we have already used this before and it will be equal to true.
We also need a success URL so that after successful registration it will be redirected with reverse
lazy to tasks.
So we have a class and now we're going to create the URL.
We're going to import what we've just created, which is register page, and we're going to create a
path down here that is equal to register slash and we have to put register pages, view this you already
know how to do almost by heart.
And then the name that we are going to give to this page, being consistent, it's going to be register
and we already have the path.
And now we're going to complete the link.
Remember that in login we had left a link here.
The link starts with brackets and percentage and we'll refer to the URL register.
We close everything and that's it to build the link.
So let's go to the site.
Let's click on register here and notice that we arrive here at a form that we have not designed, but
that has been generated automatically because all this information is already incorporated in the user
creation forms.
So what I want to do here before going any further is to make sure that once the user has submitted
this registration with the registered button and the relevant data, they are already logged in to continue
using the application because for now this would only create a user, but then they would have to log
in and this would be a redundant task.
We would like you to be logged in already.
We come back to Pie Charm and now we're going to go inside views where we were working and we're going
to overwrite something here inside the register page class.
We're going to set up a function called Form Valid.
We've used it before and this is going to require a self and a form.
And this form valid is going to return the super which has the name of the view register page and the
self.
And to this we apply the method form valid pointing to the form so that it returns to us what is in
the upper instance with all that information.
But now we have to establish before the return what we want to modify here.
We want the user to be equal to the form save.
That is to say to what has been saved in the form to obtain the value of our user and also check if
user is not none.
If so, apply the login method loaded with self, request and user.
So those are the values you need to log in the user.
If we now come to registration, we can create a new user, for example, fill and create a password
for him and repeat it.
Now we send and fill is now a new user and at the same time he is logged in as we expected.
He has no task because Phil is new here.
We're going to create a new task for him which can be feed the dog, we send it.
And this is Phil's new task.
Now, also, since we had this thing about redirecting the authenticated user, he's not supposed to
be able to access the register page anymore.
So I'm going to try to do it.
And yes, I've been able to log in.
This doesn't work as expected.
We should be prevented from accessing this page if we are already registered.
So let's see what happened here in views.
We have this redirect unauthenticated user set to true, which is what should block us from this page.
But for some reason this attribute isn't working as we wanted it to.
So I'm going to override it.
We're going to need to impart on the shortcuts also to redirect.
And with redirect we can go back to this same class and get get is going to ask us for itself and then
args and quarks.
We're going to tell it that if self dot request user dot is authenticated in that case, if it is authenticated
to return us a redirection to tasks, then if the user wants to enter this view, the system will ask
him or her if it is authenticated and it will not let them go any further because it will send them
to tasks and if they are not, then he or she will be able to see the registration form returning a
super with the parameters register page and self.
From this it's going to get all the arguments and logs that exist.
So now it's not supposed to let us log in.
We are fresh again, and since I'm already registered, it won't let me see the registration page.
Now, yes, our site has the possibility to register users directly from this view.
Well, in the next lesson, we're going to learn how to do searches.
And if you want to know what this is, what you need to know, you'll find out in the next lesson.