In this lesson, we're going to add a search element to our application.
We're going to create here above elements a text box where the user can put a word and then press a
search button.
So the only the tasks that contain that word or that fragment of a word are shown.
So let's imagine you have 50 or 100 tasks.
Well, you could use a search engine.
And in order to test this, let's create another task containing the word bread so that when we search
for that word, two tasks will appear.
We can put something like buy a bread basket.
And with this we have five tasks, two of which contain the expression breadth.
Now let's go to pie chart to add inside task list, a new form.
And with this form it's going to have a method which is not going to be equal to post as we have done
until now, but it's going to be a method of type get.
This is because now we're not creating new information or posting something.
We are requesting information.
And inside this form we're going to create two inputs, the first one for the text box.
So I put input that is of type equal to text no longer submit.
Like when we create buttons, then this text box will need a name which will be search area and we close
the input.
Later we're going to add a value so that something will be displayed once the user has entered something.
But for now we're going to leave it empty because we need to generate some things first.
The second input we want to create here is a button.
So the type is going to be submit and its value is going to be the text search.
And with this we close this input and we already have our two elements.
And if we come to the form and refresh here, we already can see and I can put any word here and here
we will search for it.
But this doesn't have any logic programmed into it yet, so it doesn't do anything.
We're going to program it now, but inside views.
So we're going to find the view that corresponds to pending list.
And we see that here.
We already have some filters because this page shows us only those tasks that belong to the user that
is logged in.
And of those tasks it only shows the ones that are not completed.
And now we want to add another filter.
We want to only show the tasks that the user has searched for in the text box.
So we do this in the following way.
First we create a variable which can be called search value, and we're going to say that search value
is equal to self.
Request to get.
Then the get method again.
But with lowercase this time and here we're going to pass whatever is in search area.
So if someone puts bread there, then bread is going to be the search value.
And before showing the tasks, that is before returning the context this view is going to set if search
value that is, if it is true, which is the same as saying if it is not empty in that case, it is
going to determine that from now on the context of tasks will be the same as the context of task again,
but this time with a filter, and we'll only take those whose title double underscore contains that
value.
We write this as I contains with the I before contains.
This means that it will show all those whose title contains the search value.
And now we need to add here that in the definition of search value, we also have to take into account
that this box can be empty.
In that case, we put all on the empty, inverted commas so that we can see all the tasks in case there
is nothing entered in the search box.
With this.
We're supposed to have everything ready so that we can put, for example, bread and search for it.
It filters them and only shows us the two texts that include that word.
What I would like to change here is that when I click on search, that word doesn't disappear from the
text box.
And we do this by going back to views.
And here we're going to add after we've left here and after we've done the logic test, that the context
which now corresponds to search value is equal to search value.
And this is then going to make it be the value of the context.
And therefore in task list where we have this input, the text box, we're going to add a value that
is going to be equal to what we have in the variable search value.
So now if I search for any word, for example, bread, then I press the button.
It doesn't disappear from here.
So we're going to delete and we're going to search back so that we can they can all appear.
Let's put here, Mindy.
We put search, and it only shows us this task.
And in the text box, we see the searched word.
Our application is practically complete in terms of functionality, in terms of logic, and in terms
of the elements it has.
What was missing and maybe what you've been waiting to do for a long time is to add a style to it,
make it attractive, because for now, our site, if there is one thing it doesn't have, is an attractive
look.
It's just text on a blank screen.
So we're going to style it in the next lesson.