From this lecture on all object types we have yet to learn are coming and we are going to start learning
about lists right away.
A list is an ordered sequence of objects.
Lists can be assigned to a variable, and there elements can be strings, integers, floats, or any
type of object that we will learn about soon.
A list can even be composed of objects of different data types.
Lists are written in square brackets and their elements must be separated by commas.
It is also possible to nest lists what is nesting.
The same way we can have a list of integers or strings.
We can also have a list of lists, just like strings.
We can index and split lists because strings actually work almost like a list of characters.
Similarly, lists also have methods that allow us to manipulate and parse them.
And unlike strings, lists are not immutable so we can modify or rearrange their contents.
There is a lot to learn about lists, so let's put our fingers to work in Pi charm right now.
Exactly.
Fill our fingers are ready to start typing everything related to lists.
So here we are in a new file that I've prepared that's called lists and it is inside day three.
And we're going to start creating a list.
We're going to assign it to a variable called My List.
And we're going to say that my list is equal to a list composed of data that we're going to put in square
brackets.
In this case, they're going to be a list of strings.
They're going to be in quotation marks, and they're going to be the letter A, then the letter B,
and finally the letter C.
That is to say that this list is going to have only three elements.
First, I'm going to show you what the data type of a list looks like.
So let's print the type that corresponds to my list.
Then we're going to run this by going to run and within run choosing lists.
And here we have that.
This object belongs to the list class.
I also want to show you that we can create lists, as I explained before, that have different types
of data.
We're going to create another list and we're going to say that it is equal, for example, to a string
that says, hello, this is the first object.
The second object is a number 55.
The third object can be a float, for example.
And as you see, this does not throw an error and it allows us to continue with our code because lists
in Python, unlike most languages, can contain objects of different data types.
Let's remove this.
That's it.
I want to show you that we can apply here the length property because the same as with strings.
We could also know the length of a list.
We can know how many elements a list contains.
Then I'm going to say that result is a variable that is equal to Len.
That is to say the length of my list.
And here instead of type, we're going to print result so we can see what it contains.
And it tells us that my list has three elements.
Amazing.
You can also extract the value of one of those elements using index.
We can index list as well.
So I'm going to say that the result is equal to my list at its zero index.
And if I run this, I'm going to see the letter A, which is the element that it has at index zero of
my list.
Just like strings indexes in lists start at zero one, two and so on.
Everything we've seen about indexes on strings applies to lists.
If I also want to search, for example, the indexes that go from 0 to 1, in this case zero, colon
one.
We have here only one object because remember that it goes up to one but does not include it.
But if I put two here, in that case I can see element zero.
An element or element one.
Element two is not included.
If I leave this empty, I can see from the beginning to the end all the elements, the same as with
the strings.
We can also apply what would be the concatenation of lists.
We have seen it with the strings.
So if I create my list too, and I say that this list is equal to, let's say D, E and F, now we have
three more elements in a separate list.
But if instead of results now I print my list plus my list too, we're going to get a concatenation
that gives us a single list that is a, B, C, D, E, F, and has joined them all together.
But remember, the original two lists still exist.
If I print just my list here and then also print my list too and run it, the two original lists will
still exist.
What I have done before was to print them together.
If I wanted the two to exist in a single list so that I could use what I would have to do is create
a third list.
This is going to be my list three and it's going to be equal.
To my list, plus my list, too.
And here we're going to print just my list three, which is the one I just created.
Let's see what it looks like.
Well, same as before.
But now I have a variable.
That is my list three that contains the concatenation.
Well, this would be the basics about lists, and it applies to almost everything that we have seen
about strings, because the strings in some way are a list of characters, although this technically
does not apply to all of the sense, but they work quite similar.
Now there are things that strings can't do that lists can like alternating their elements.
And we're going to see that next.
We're going to allow this my list three to continue existing, which is the one that has six elements.
And we are going to eliminate this line with the result and we're going to do what we've wanted to do
with the strings before.
And it gave us an error.
We're going to say that in my list three in its index zero.
We're going to overwrite it only to that index.
And we're going to say that now instead of a it is alpha and we're going to go to print minus three.
Observe what we have now.
We have alpha b, c, d, e, f with strings.
I could not do this, but with the lists I can overwrite any of its elements.
And we also have methods to do many things with the lists.
Notice if I put the point after my list, we can see all the methods that correspond to the lists coming.
And we're going to look for this one that is called append.
As its name suggests, append is used to add an element to our already created list.
Let's add G, which would be the one that follows alphabetically and let's execute my list three to
see how it looks.
Okay, now we have a, b, c, d, e, f and g.
If you're wondering why I no longer have alpha, note that I deleted the line that did the operation
and rerun a new instance of all of this.
So it cleared up why I did before.
But now we have then not six but seven elements because lists.
When you add an element, this will not be a concatenation.
This is adding something to the original list.
So I didn't have to create a new variable as I have necessarily done with the strings if I want to modify
them here.
The source list was modified and just as I have a method that allows me to add items, I also have methods
that allow me to remove items.
We are going to invoke again my list three and this time we're going to apply a method that is called
pop.
And through it we're going to remove one of the items from our list.
What pop does, if you leave it without parameters inside these parentheses, is to interpret that you
want to remove the last of its elements.
Then we're going to eliminate this G so that we have our original list from A to F, C, and now we're
going to eliminate the last element that is F we execute it and A, B, C, D, E, and the F is no
longer here.
I was telling you that Pop automatically interprets that you want to delete the last item unless you
specify here which index you want to delete.
If I set it to be index zero, then let's run it again.
This time it deleted the first element and I start with b, c, d, e f.
There is also a way to store what that element that you delete in a variable in case you want to manipulate
it or use it.
We're going to repeat this operation, but storing the pop element in a variable called deleted and
what we're going to print now is not only my list, but we're also going to print deleted.
Let's see what it looks like.
So we have the list without the initial element already removed.
The pop element here in the index is zero and a part we have printed the variable deleted which contains
the element that we have removed.
That is to say that you can also remove them and reserve them to use them in the future.
As you have seen, there are many methods to use with the lists.
We're going to learn some of the most important.
Now let's get to know one that allows us to sort the lists.
Suppose I have a list here that is equal to alphabetical elements, but out of order we're going to
do the G, we're going to do the Oh and we're going to do a B, we can do an M and we can do a C.
These are elements that are out of order.
Now I'm going to call list.
I'm going to apply a method called sort, and we're going to leave these parameters empty and we're
going to print this list.
Now, let's see what this looks like.
Our G, O, B, M and C are now B, C, GM and O.
That is to say that they are all in alphabetical order.
And the same thing would have happened if I'd put numbers out of order, or if I'd put people's names.
It sorts them alphabetically.
What you do have to keep in mind is that sort is a method that works in place, that is it reorders
the list itself, but it's not a method that returns anything.
Many times a beginner might think, Well, there, I can do this.
I can store my list and a new list and it's equal to the sorted list.
And then I will print a new list.
And this is going to.
Give me my sorted list.
If we follow our intuition, we would think that this would work.
But run it.
And our list is not there.
It's not even sorted or unordered.
It tells us none.
And this is where it's important to understand the logic of this, actually, to help you understand
it better.
I'm going to type type here to find out what type this new list object that we have here is.
And Python says that it's a non type class.
That's the data type that contains new list which we've supposedly assigned our sorted list to.
But instead of my list we have this non type and non type is the data type of a non object.
Let's see it in basic English.
We could say that Python created the non type object to indicate an object that has no value, which
is not the same as having a zero value.
Zero is something that is not the same as having no value at all.
In a nutshell, none is the result of an object that does not return anything.
The important thing to understand here that salt is a method that performs in action, which is to sort
the elements but does not return anything and therefore we cannot assign that non return to a variable,
which is what we wanted to do in this case.
Maybe this is a little confusing for you now, but the important thing to understand is that there are
methods that simply do something but do not return information that you can store elsewhere.
So if I want to see my sorted list, I simply perform the execution and then I can see my list that
has now changed and is sorted and I can see it this way.
If I wanted to store it somewhere, I have to do it separately.
I stole my modified list in list two.
Now I print here list too.
But this would basically be a redundancy because now I have two lists that are the same.
Finally, one more method that I want you to know is the opposite to this method that allows us to sort
alphabetically.
This one will sort it backwards.
We have a method called reverse.
Let's look for it here.
List, point, reverse.
Here it is.
And what reverse does is it reverses the order.
It puts the last thing first and so on.
In fact, if we print it out, we can see that now.
Our list is in alphabetical order, but it goes from Z to A and that's what reverse does done like.
So to reverse does not return anything.
It transforms it in place.
And we can't store it directly in another variable because it will give us a non object.
Well, this is the most important thing to know about lists, so be sure to download the notes, to
have everything organized and visually accessible to you, and be sure to do the practical exercises
that follow and then move on to learn the next type of data that are dictionary.
So I'll be waiting for you there.