A long time ago, we learned that we can easily search for text fragments within a larger string.
If I want to search for the word python in this text, I just have to ask if word is found in text and
the result will be true because in this case it is found.
But things will be complicated.
If I want to know how many times it appears, or if I have to consider plurals, numeric values, spaces,
etc..
So here come the regular expressions which allow us to make searches with higher levels of abstraction.
For example, if I want to find an email address within a text, I can use them to search for expressions
that respect this format so that they are accepted or to validate if the user entered an appropriate
email.
In short, what regular expressions allow us to do is build a certain pattern to check if it exists.
In another context.
We can access these tools through the E library, which stands for Regular Expressions.
Let's review the basic syntax of regular expressions.
Suppose we want to check if a given user input respects a phone number pattern.
It should have three digits for the area code, a hyphen, and then seven more digits divided into two
groups of three and four digits separated by a hyphen.
One way to structure this pattern with regular expressions would be this the letter R and the quotes
to tell Python not to treat this string as a normal string, but to process it as a regular expression.
So Python will say, okay, some things are going to happen here and I have to treat them differently.
Then comes this expression, which is riddled with characters preceded by a backslash.
These characters would be something like placeholders representing a value that meets some condition.
In this case, D stands for Digit.
So here we have a pattern that says three digits at the beginning, although we don't know which ones
yet, they can be any digits, then a hyphen, then three more digits, another hyphen and four more
digits.
Any string that respects this pattern, for example, any of these will be detected as a valid phone
number by this regular expression.
There are other ways to express the same thing.
For example, by grouping the digits and indicating how many digits are in each group, the special
characters for constructing patterns are as follows Backslash and lowercase dx.
It means a numeric digit.
It can be any number from 0 to 9.
If you write a pattern that says GN Backslash.
DX Dot Backslash dx backslash dx backslash dx this pattern will find a match in any of these examples.
Backslash and w lowercase.
It means any alphanumeric character.
It can be a letter, a numeric digit or a symbol.
For example, this expression will match any of these examples you see on the screen, the backslash
with the lowercase s.
It means white space.
If I created this pattern, I would find matches with any of these examples.
The next three characters are the same ones that we have seen, but in uppercase, if they are capitalized,
it means they have the opposite effect.
The first one is backslash d uppercase, which means it is not a digit.
So a pattern like this is going to match any of these options.
The backslash with a w uppercase means that it is not alphanumeric, it only accepts signs.
So this could be the example you're seeing on the screen right now.
And finally, the backslash with the SE uppercase means it's not a blank space.
This pattern is going to match any group of four characteristics that don't have blanks between them,
but that's not all.
In addition to special characters, we also have quantifier characters as we saw in the phone number.
Example, Quantifier is allow us not to have to repeat special characters all the time.
In Python qualifiers are the plus sign, which means that a special character appears one or more times.
The number of times can be variables, so this validates any of these.
A number in square brackets means that a character is repeated exactly that number of times.
So if you write this, any of these examples will be accepted.
All of them must have exactly four numeric digits after the hyphen.
If we put two numeric digits separated by commas inside the brackets instead, the number of repetitions
can be.
Between those limits.
If we write this, all these examples can be accepted.
And if in the square brackets, we put a number with the comma and then we do not put a second digit.
This means that the number of characters can go upwards from that number as a minimum without limits.
For a pattern like this.
All these examples would be valid.
The asterisk means zero or more.
That is to say, it serves as an indeterminate number of repetitions, which includes the possibility
that it does not even appear.
So if we create a pattern like this, it allows that space to exist one many or no times at all.
And finally, the question mark.
This sign is used for a character to appear once or none.
What is the most common use of this quantifier?
When a word is either singular or plural, placing the question mark after the TSS allows that letter
to appear or not.
And this is used to validate words that we do not know if they will appear in singular or plural form.
Whew.
A lot of information, isn't it?
Don't try to memorize it.
Let's avoid learning overload.
I just want you to be aware that these resources exist and that you look up this information and use
it whenever you need those resources.
Maybe you will remember it over time.
Maybe not.
The important thing is not that you have a library in your head, but you know where to look.
Shall we go over to pie chart to see how this works in code?
Let's do it.
Let's start with this text I wrote earlier.
It's a variable that stores the sentence.
If you need help, call this number any time for online help.
Now have a look at how we would do a search with what we have so far.
I can have a variable called word that stores the result.
That tells us if the word help is in the text, that is help in text.
We already knew how to do this.
If I print the result of word, it will tell me it is true.
The word help is in this text.
So how will we do it with regular expressions?
First, let's make some space so we can import our E for regular expressions and rewrite all this to
create a variable called pattern.
This variable will have a very simple value.
I type in a word that is not in the phrase, it's just pencil.
And then we're going to create the search through a variable called search, which is equal to our e
dot search.
So what do we search?
Well, we do a search using two arguments, the pattern.
And now we look for the text.
Now we print our search and it will tell us that the word pencil is not found in the text.
So the object returned is none a non object.
If I search for the word help which does exist, we get that there's an object r e dot match which gives
us some more data.
It tells us that the span goes from index 12 to index 16 and it also tells us that match is equal to
help.
This has been very simple, using a pattern as easy as searching for a word.
So note that search is a type of regular expression object.
So if we put Dot here, we have a few more things to find.
So if, for example, we search for span, what we're going to see is just the location of the word
found.
If instead of span, we apply the START method, it returns the location of the beginning.
And if we search for end logically, it will give us the location of the end.
But notice that our text has the word help twice.
First here and then here.
But when I search for this word, I found only the first occurrence of help.
If I want to find more than one instead of search, what we're going to search for is find all so that
what we get now is a list with the two occurrences of the word help.
And this indeed is a list.
If I want to know the length of this list, I can do it with the method Len of search.
And it will tell me that the list has two elements.
If I want to access each of these findings, instead of printing the length of search, what I would
do the following for each finding in our e dot find ETA and the argument that find ETA asks for are
the pattern and the text.
And with each one that it finds what it prints finding span which was the location.
What we should delete here is this since we no longer need it and we execute it and we have the two
locations of the two elements of our list which was iterated until it found the word help twice so far.
These are the basics to use a pattern.
But now we'll see how to build special or more abstract patterns.
To start with, let's write here only a text that says Call two and any number that has a telephone
number format.
And we finish the phrase with right now, and this is the text where we're going to search for if a
number exists.
So now we ask for the pattern to not be simply a word or a specific number, but any number that meets
this format, three digits, hyphen three digits, hyphen four digits.
And how do we construct it?
First, we let our program know with the letter R that what follows now is a special string.
It is not a normal string, nor is it a string literal, and that the characters you find here should
be treated as the characters of a regular expression pattern.
So what we're going to look for is three digits.
We do it with backslash and the letter D, three times A hyphen backslash and D three more times and
another hyphen and four more times.
The backslash with D.
And now it's time to construct a search in the result variable that is equal to our search.
And what we search for here is the pattern that we have constructed within the text that we have written.
We print the result so we can see it on screen, and once we run it, it tells us that it has found
an element that matches this pattern, which goes from position 8 to 20, and that is this number that
we have here.
Observe something interesting.
If I change the number, let's put here another different number I run and it still finds them because
what it looks for is not a particular number, but any number that respects this format.
And if I change, for example, the amount of numbers and here in the middle I put one more digit.
Now it will not find anything because this number does not follow this format that asks for three digits
in the middle.
So let's leave it as before.
And another interesting aspect is that if we put DOT Group, which is another method, what we get is
the phone number that this search gave us as a result.
We can search for quantifies, as you've seen in the introductory video.
So instead of repeating three, ten or 100 times the special characters, we can quantify them.
If instead of putting it three times, we put a bracket that says that this digit has to appear three
times.
And this has to appear also three times.
And that this has to appear four times.
And surprise.
This will also give a positive result because quantifies allow us to make this line shorter and simpler.
We can also ask this pattern to be compiled by transforming an object or recompile.
And I enclose each of these groups.
I enclose in parentheses.
There should be three groups of three, three and four digits.
Now, when I print it this way, looking for the group of results, I get the same.
So far this does not tell you anything.
But if instead of empty group, we pass the argument to, for example, I will see the second of the
groups, which is the one that has these numbers.
If I had asked for the first of the groups, I would have seen these ones and thus I could obtain.
The different groups are constructed through a regular expression variable which is compiled.
Note that here the search indexes start at one and not at zero.
As usual in Python.
Any practical use for all of this?
There are many.
For example, your user is going to generate a password and you want to check if the password meets
some conditions.
For example, that the password starts with a letter instead of a number and has eight characters.
Well, let's create a variable password that is equal to the user's input and which asks the user for
something simple.
Password.
Colon.
After that, we create a pattern that is going to control what format the user's password should have.
First we want to put the R letter in order to indicate that this is going to be a pattern which should
start with a letter, not a number.
We're going to put a backslash and capital D, which is what assures us that it is not a digit.
But since we want it to only check this taking into account the first datum, we're going to put a bracket
and one to give the order that it should repeat the progress just once.
Plus, it is going to have seven more numbers because there are eight characters.
So we're going to put Backslash and W, which is an alphanumeric character and set this process.
So it repeats itself exactly seven times and that's it.
We already have the password that the user will generate and the pattern to control it.
What follows is the variable check, which should be equal to our search, and we should look for pattern
in password, and then we print it and run it.
And finally, we're asked for the password.
First.
Let's do it the wrong way.
We start with a number and then we type in the right number of letters.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven is going to tell us that there are no match because even
though the password has the number of letters we asked for one and seven, it doesn't start with the
letter.
We will try again, but this time we're going to start with a letter.
The E.
However, we will introduce less letters than we are asked for.
I press enter and no matches again.
Okay, let's execute it one more time.
And now we start with a letter.
We can add letters and numbers seven more times.
I will add three numbers and four letters.
This does work since it finds a match which is returned so that I can see it.
This is one way of checking if a user's input meets certain conditions.
And just as we have special characters and quantifies, we also have special operators.
Let's take a look at some of them.
So delete this and please and write a text that reads the following message Saturday and Sunday.
This door is closed.
So here we're going to search if our search can be found and pay attention to this.
We build a pattern with the letter R and we're going to check if here we can find the word Sunday or
the word Monday observed.
If I put this vertical bar, which means or the option option or this or that, and which indicates
that either Sunday or Monday can be searched.
So where are they going to be searched?
In text, of course.
To begin with, we create a print of search and see what happens here and it tells me that there is
a match.
Sun has been found in this location.
If the text said Monday it would still work because it looks for Sunday or Monday either one.
But if it says Tuesday this time there is no match the special operator or allows you to look for different
words in your searches.
It can also be used when you have to search for plurals.
For example, here you can introduce house or houses without any problems.
We also have the wildcard.
So let's change this here.
And for example, look for the word lose and lose is inside closed.
So if we print it, it finds the lose fragment in that location.
But then we have the wildcard letters which appear with a dot.
So if I type in a dot here, I will also include whatever letter number, sign or space that has been
previously included.
It shows me close now and if I put three more dots here, I will get the expression is close and if
I add a dot after an execute, I'm going to get is closed.
So let's look at some special operators.
We also have the circumflex accent, which is a sort of little arrow pointing up, which you probably
have above the six on your keyboard.
This will allow us to verify whether a pattern is at the beginning of the string.
So if we put here a backslash and a capital D to indicate that it does not have to be a digit and we
execute this, the s which is not a digit is found.
If our tech started with the number four and we run it, there wouldn't be any matches because a non
digit would not be found at the beginning of our string.
We delete it and a sign similar to this in terms of its function.
Is this currency sign that we type after the special character.
This sign will check what is before the sign will check if there is not a digit at the end of our string.
If we execute it, there will be a match the letter D and if we put a six here and we execute it, no
matches will be found because the six is a digit which does not fulfil the condition of the pattern.
And finally, one more special character.
These are the straight braces with the circumflex accent inside.
Whatever we include here means that the pattern must exclude it.
So for example, let's put the backslash with the SE which stands for empty spaces.
Then instead of search, we enter find all which is going to find the ones that exclude an empty character,
an empty space.
And if we run it here, we have all the characters that are not empty spaces.
It has excluded them all.
I will show you one more alternative, which is to put at the end the plus sign, which serves to indicate
one or more times.
Then it will look for all the characters, regardless of how many times they are repeated.
And it will build a list of words this time, because every time it finds an empty space, it will separate
the elements of the group.
And here we have all the words.
And if at the end, when I print it, instead of putting search, I apply the string strategy, which
is to put two quotation marks and join so that everything there is and what is found in search is joined.
And we print it.
And here we have a text again, but this time without the empty spaces.
So there is a lot you can do.
Please check out the documentation.
Regular expressions are very useful and you will find that you need them sooner or later.
I strongly recommend you go over them, or at least have them in mind so that when you need them you
can use them to your advantage.
See you in the next lesson.