In this lecture, I want to reinforce your learning of functions with a practical application.
Example of a function.
We are going to put a four loop inside our function and we're going to make it take care of unpacking
tuples without further introduction.
Let's see it in p charm.
Now we're going to start with this example by analyzing how a system to impact tuples works, which
we have already covered before.
Suppose we have a list entitled Coffee Prices with a list of tuples inside, so each element on the
list is a tuple.
For example, the first one is cappuccino and it's going to have the price of a cappuccino, £1.50.
Then we'd close the tuple in parenthesis.
Let's create another tuple.
In this case espresso, which has the value of 120.
We close the tuple and a third tuple would be mocha, which costs 190 and so far so good.
We close the last tuple and we start a for loop.
I don't know whether you remember that a four loop enables you to go through every element in our list.
So element in coffee prices.
And what are we going to do every time we go through an element?
We will print it and we're able to execute this, which is a line of code, very simple.
And we will have three elements, each with its two own elements because they are tuples.
If I wanted to print only the coffee but not the price here, I could have split it into two variables.
For example, coffee, comma, price, and then print only coffee.
So there I would be unpacking the tuple and choosing one of its elements.
Finally, cappuccino, espresso and mocha are printed.
Great.
Now we have a system that lets us do so without the functions.
If, in fact, I wanted to continue manipulating this element and calculated not the price, but the
cost of the coffee, which I know is 45% out of its sale value.
Then you could say that here I want to print only price multiplied by 0.45, which would tell me the
cost of each of the coffees and well, I could go on like this.
However, if I want to know which coffee is the most expensive, a function will be very helpful because
I can set up a system which goes through each element retaining that of the highest price.
It could be done in the following way.
Let's first create a function that is def called most expensive coffee.
To be as clear as possible, and most expensive coffee will need a parameter that we pass a list of
prices to it.
So list of prices is the name of the variable we need here.
In order to retain the coffee with the highest price, its name as well as its cost.
I will need two variables one called highest price, which will keep the highest price.
It will be again at zero.
And another variable entitled Most Expensive Coffee with an empty string.
This function will carry out as a series of tasks, but what we actually want from it is the most expensive
coffee and the highest price, all of it in one tuple.
That's why return is enclosed in parentheses, because I will get two variables and I want them in one
single tuple.
Okay.
In the middle we will proceed with a for loop which will go through coffee and price of each element
within the price list.
We will pass to the function colon.
And what is it going to do with each element?
It's going to check whether the price of the element we are looking at is higher than what is stalled
in highest price, which is our variable beginning at zero.
If this is so now, I want the highest price variable to be overwritten and have the content in price.
Price will be the new value in the highest price variable, which started at zero.
This will happen every time a price is higher than most expensive, so highest price and most expensive
coffee will be overwritten.
So I hope you can follow me, because now most expensive coffee has to have as value whatever is in
coffee.
Which coffee?
This one.
Which is the first element of each tuple we're going through.
And so far we have the if.
And now we also need to create an else that says pass.
This is our whole function.
And return is doing exactly what we want to.
They're sending us back these two variables, just as they are.
To verify this, let's print on the screen outside of the function.
The most expensive copy function.
And we're going to pass coffee prices as a list of prices to it, which is the list we have at the very
beginning up here.
When we print it, we'll see that mocha is the most expensive coffee.
And it is indeed.
What happened here is not that the last loop got printed, so we're going to increase the cost of espresso
up to 250.
We execute it.
And now espresso is the most expensive coffee.
So another way could be to store this result in a variable.
And in fact, I could do so in two variables generating the coffee and price variables this time out
of the function.
Plus we want these two variables to be equal to the result of the most expensive coffee function with
price list as list.
So bear in mind the following what it will return here when executing this function will be stored in
these two variables.
Well, first, we need to generate a print so that we can see it on the screen and we do it with a little
string.
We're going to say here that the most expensive coffee is then we call coffee, which is the variable
that contains the first element of this result, whose price is and now we call the price variable,
which we have thanks to the return of our function.
It shows error in the price list because sure, it's true because price list is the internal variable
of the function which goes from here to here.
What we have to pass is out here is not price list because out of that function that name does not exist.
But coffee prices, which is in the list of prices that contains our prices since the beginning.
Now, if we execute it, it reads The most expensive coffee is espresso.
Whose price is 250?
All in all, this has been an example for you to understand how functions work in real life and the
potential they have.
I think together we've done a good job.
Don't forget that we have our Q&amp;A section and in the meantime, let's move forward with functions in
the next lesson.