For starters, I want to introduce you to the starring role, which is pie game.
This tool is very powerful and allows us to create any games that we want and we can find it at pi p
dot org.
Here we have the instructions to install PI game in our computer.
This is the newest pi game version.
However, it's likely that a newer version will exist by the time you watch this video.
Hey, we can see some descriptions that help us know more about PI Game.
And there's an access to its documents which I advise you to read.
Remember that nobody reads all the documents before starting to work.
People only read the most important characteristics in order to use a program.
Then when you need help, you can come back here and broaden your knowledge.
So in today's lecture, I'm going to teach you how to use it in order to create the basic game.
From then on, you can keep on researching.
Well, let's install this program.
And as you already know, we use pip install pi game and I've already got it.
So I won't be seeing the same things on our screens and you'll see the installation process.
We can close this and go to Pi Charm, where we can begin with a new file.
I've created one named Main and now I'm going to import PI game in order to access it.
So first things first.
I have to run PI game inside my program, so I'll call PI Game Dot so as to see all its resources,
methods and properties and I'll call in it, which allows me to run it.
By doing this, we can use every PI game tool.
And in this lesson, we'll set up our screen resolution and we'll learn how to show the screen to the
user.
To do so, we'll create a variable named screen which will store pi game dot display dot set mode.
Here we're basically saying, well, I want the screen to be equal to set mode of PI game.
So what is my screen resolution?
Here we have to add a value that represents the resolution.
We'll add height and width, but we have to add them to a tuple.
So we'll type brackets in order to create one.
And it requires two integers, one for height and another for width.
So I want height to be 800 pixels and width to be 600 pixels.
This is for the game I want to create.
I know it's the right size, so when you create games, you'll choose the size you want.
We could execute this program to see what happens because I've created a screen that should be visible.
So we execute this and the screen appears and disappears.
I don't know if you could see it, but let's do it again.
So the screen comes and goes.
Why is this happening?
Because that's what it has to do.
Display itself.
Since we don't have code down here, the process ends and we no longer have our screen, which depends
on the execution of this code.
So in order to keep on seeing our screen, we need our code to keep on executing itself.
So to show the solution, I'm going to do something I shouldn't, which is to create an infinite while
loop.
So true pass.
This is like poison to programs because we're talking about a loop that never ends.
I only do this in order to teach you some things, and I want you to see what happens now.
So I'll execute this program and the screen appears and stays there.
But I can't do anything.
If I positioned myself here, I can't move it either.
The program is not responding and we can tell that by looking at the mouse.
So that's why I have my task manager at hand and it allows me to access Python and end this task.
So I was able to stop the execution.
But that's not the way we want to see our screen.
Now we're going to start a loop that allows us to display our screen.
This loop will wait for some event to happen.
But what events?
Well, anything that occurs in the PI game screen is an event.
So when you click or press your keyboard, when a character from a game does something or when an object
crashes into another, all of these are events, and as a programmer, you can decide what's going to
happen at code level.
So we'll program whatever happens when the quick event occurs.
Quit is the event in which a user clicks on X in order to close the PI game screen.
So let's create a variable here before the loop named is running, which will be equal to true.
So our loop will say while is running and what will happen inside our loop.
It will iterate over all the events taking place inside pi game.
If we bump.
Into the quit event will make it is running be false.
So remember that quit happens when someone clicks on x.
That's when we get out of the loop and finish our code.
So for each event in pi game dot, event dot get what is going to happen.
Well, if that event contains a type that's equal to PI game dot quit capital Q otherwise it won't work
is running will have false as value and that's how we'll be able to get out of the loop safely.
So I'll explain it once more.
We have a loop which will access once it is displayed on the screen and this loop will repeat itself.
As long as is running is true.
This loop will verify each event taking place inside the PI game naming.
If it's a quit type event, which is the one that occurs when someone clicks on x, the is running variable
will change to false and we'll be able to get out of the loop after that.
Our program will close and that's when the screen will disappear, when we want it to disappear.
So let's execute this in order to see it better.
Here we have our screen which is now responding and I can move it.
That's it.
It's working properly.
Well, I can execute the quit event, which is this one, and I'll get out of the loop and the code
will end and the screen will disappear.
So this is how we can install and run PI game.
We were able to create a screen with a specific resolution and we could also create a loop that verifies
events and allows us to close our screen whenever we want to.
So soon we'll delve deeper into events because every event happening in our game will also happen inside
a loop, which will always verify if any preset event is being executed.
And as a result we'll be able to use the code we created for each event.
So this is all for now.
So I'll see you later.