I propose you to start the day with a very easy lecture that will serve mainly to warm up some of your
engines, that brain of yours, but also to see in detail the logical operators that I showed you yesterday.
The logical operators, which are these that I have with me right now are the comparison signs that
we can use to precisely compare to values and to see if that comparison is true or not.
That is to say, if it's true or false.
So whenever you use comparison operators, you are going to obtain as an answer one of these two values,
true or false?
That is to say that you are going to get a Boolean value.
There are some details that we can learn a little bit more in depth.
So let's head over to py charm to do that.
And now from Python we're going to look at these details about the comparison values.
I already have a folder called day four along with a file created for this occasion.
And we're going to start by looking at the difference between the single equals sign and the double
equals sign.
When we use the single equals sign, what we're doing is assigning a value to something.
We are giving Python a piece of information.
I'm saying, for example, my variable, which is going to be the name of the variable is going to be
equal to I don't know, hello world.
So here, it's not a comparison.
It's a kind of command python.
I want from now on my variable to have as content as value.
Hello world.
Sometimes you assign it to things like I want this button to be this color, etc..
So we use only one equal sign to assign value.
Now, if I want to make a comparison, what I have to do is use two equal signs, for example, to say
I want to compare if ten is equal to 25.
I use two signs and here we already have a question, not an order.
And look at this.
Now we can store it inside a variable.
For example, my bool.
And here we did that with one equal sign.
In this single line have both approaches two equals to make a comparison and one equal sign to store
that comparison inside a variable.
This comparison, as you can imagine, is false because ten is not equal to 25, and therefore my ball
is now going to have false as value.
It is not going to have as content.
Ten is equal to 25.
So if I want to print my bool now, let's run it and let's go to run and let's choose comparison operators,
which is the name of my file.
Then it says false.
It doesn't say ten equal equals 25.
On the other hand, if I wanted to get a true answer here, I would have to put ten equals ten.
Run it and get true.
Also I can compare, for example, operations that result in a certain number.
Instead of this ten, I can say five plus five, and instead of the second ten, I can ask for 18 minus
eight.
So the two operations result in ten.
So if I run it, it will still tell me that this is true.
Because the important thing is not how the operation looks like five plus five.
It doesn't look as 18 minus eight.
But the result of both operations is the same.
Yes.
Do you follow me?
Now we can also compare strings.
So I can say white is equal to black.
They are two different strings and therefore I receive that that comparison is false.
They are not equal.
If I wanted them to be equal, I would say white is equal to white and I will get true.
In fact, keep in mind that the comparison between strings is case sensitive.
Therefore, if this white had a capital W, now, even though they are the same word, the comparison
will give me false.
But like operations, the important thing is the result and not the content itself.
So if I want to put here that the second white, the one with the capital letter will get the lower
method.
And now I can compare both values again that will tell me that it's true.
It says that white written in a lowercase is equal to this white with the capital letter but processed
by the lower method.
So I insist.
The important thing is the result and not how each of the factors involved in the comparison looks.
So we also compare some values of different types.
For example, if I want to say the string 100 is equal to the integer 100.
Python distinguishes that this is not the same as a string and will tell me that the comparison is false,
although they look relatively the same.
So I can also compare an integer with a float and if the value is the same.
So 100.0 is equal to 100.
It will give me true because it is the same result even though they are different types.
Can you follow me this far?
I hope so.
Well, this is about all for the equality comparison sign, but we can also compare the opposite, the
difference.
And this is written with the exclamation point and the equal sign.
This asks if this is different from this, and here they're going to get the opposite result of equality.
Here it's going to tell me that it's false because 100 is not different from 100.
So if I wanted to check 100 against 99, then now the difference is going to give me true because I'm
comparing whether they are different and it's true that they're different.
Well, of course, you know the classical major and minor symbols.
So if I want to know if 100 is greater than 99, I'm going to get true because that's the way it is.
If you compare the reverse with a minus sign, you would get false.
And remember that you can also use greater than or equal to or less than or equal to.
If I say that five is greater than five.
Of course I'm going to get false as return.
But if I ask you if it's greater than or equal to, Python is going to tell me it's true because it's
one of the two things greater than or equal to.
And in fact, it's neither is going to tell me it's false.
Very good.
Well, so far, so much for the comparison values.
But there is one more thing to know.
What happens if I want to make more than two comparisons?
For example, I want to know five is greater than six and also if it is less than eight.
Well, here I have to combine these comparison operations and what I will need are logical operations
to make these aggregates.
And we will see this in the next lecture.
So meet me and fill their.