Today we are going to start talking about a super important topic, which are Python modules and packages.
And for that we are going to talk about something called Pi, pi and pip install.
So far, all the code we have used is code that we already have because it was installed at the same
time we installed Python on our computer.
This means we have used code libraries that come internally installed in Python and these are known
as standard or built in libraries.
At one point we had imported some extra modules like random or path, and still we were able to import
those modules because we already had them installed on our computer.
Those these standard libraries are very complete.
You will regularly need other extra resources.
And what you will discover in this lecture is that there are thousands and thousands of open source
libraries for almost anything you want to do.
They have been created by other programmers to make your life easier.
Do you want a code to create graphs?
Do you want to control Excel from Python or send and receive emails?
Do you want code to control a robot remotely?
Do you want code to do facial recognition?
All of this and much more already exists.
And all you have to do is find it, install it, and import it in order to use it in your programs.
All of this is free and you just have to know how to do it.
This is where Pi Pi comes in, which is a repository of third party open source python packages.
To install these packages we are going to use the command prompt window applying the pip install command.
This is a command you already have on your computer from the time you installed Python or your computer
at the beginning of the course and is an easy way to download packages directly from the pi pi repository
to find a library in pi pi.
We usually do it by searching in Google and the links that appear first usually lead to pi pi the page
with the package or its documentation.
In a little while, Federico is going to show you what a typical search looks like.
But first, we are going to show you how to download and install external packages from the command
prompt on windows or from the terminal on Mac or Linux.
So let's get to it.
And where would we start our search if not on Google?
Do not feel bad for going there because it doesn't matter if you're an expert or a beginner.
Everybody uses Google, so we'll think like an expert who's trying to solve a problem.
They need a code to change the console text color.
Since Python doesn't allow us to do that using its built in libraries.
We need to find out the appropriate package.
Well, no one knows every existing package.
And when I say nobody, I mean it.
So online searches are fundamental in a programmer's life.
So how do we search for a package that allows us to change the console text color?
Well, we type it directly into the Google search box.
You want to always start with Python in order to provide the search with context.
Then type packages.
And this should be followed by a reason why you're looking for a package.
So in this case, I want to change the console font type.
So I'll type for console text colors enter.
And here I have some options which I can choose, so it's likely they'll show me an archive or a package.
So I'm quite interested in this option.
Reading Colored Pie P Because it's located in pie P dot org, which is the official website of pie archive
that Phil recommended to you in the introduction.
So this is safe and I know I'm going to find the most of the best options here.
So let's click on this link.
So where is it taking us?
Well, to pie p dot org site which contains official documents, tutorials and all the information I
need to know how to manage and learn about packages.
So here we have some links that take us to release history, download files and the maintainer python
upgrades are also visible and so on.
So we can also see this text and let's be honest, it isn't necessary for us to read the whole of it,
but some important parts.
There are some very large documents and you have to know what to look for.
So you'll learn as you do it.
First, I have to find the word colored, which is the name of my package and the name I have to use
when installing it.
In fact, here I have the command I have to use in the console in order to install the package pip installed
colored.
So let's do that.
So go to command line.
I have this because I work with Windows.
So if you work with Linux or Mac, you'll use terminal, which you will follow the same steps afterwards.
So what do we have to type here?
First we need to enter this command to.
Install coloured which is pip install and then coloured, which is the name of our package.
So in my case, when I press enter, the system will let me know this requirement is already satisfied
because I've been practising in order to teach you.
In your case, the software will start operating until the program is installed and then you'll be back
here.
So now we'll go back to Python, but we'll use it from the console.
Here we are.
See Colon and its location are no longer visible, but these three symbols.
And now I'll import the package from Python.
You already know that when we have to work with a library that it's not built in, we have to import
it.
So as I've already read the document, I know that from colored I have to import FG, BG and a TTR.
These are foreground background and attributes.
So don't worry.
I don't mean to teach you how to use this package.
That's not what the class is about.
I want to teach you how to install and use packages in general, so I'm going to use it so as to show
you how I already have it.
And because it is something, it's something fun to see.
So I'll create a variable named color and set it up with an fg number one, which is red plus a BG number
15, which is white.
Now I have defined a color variable, so I'll print that color plus a text reading hello world.
And this I know because I read the document atr0 so that it restarts itself and stops writing in the
colors I've created.
So once I press enter Hello world will be written in the colors I choose.
And now I repeat, I'm not teaching you how to use colored, but only demonstrating it.
If you want to use it, you can download it and read the document.
The gist of this lesson is that you learn how to search for, install and use any package that you download.
So let's illustrate this with another example.
So go back to Google and suppose that you want to look for a Python package that allows you to manage
Excel.
Okay, so first we type Python packages for Excel and here we have the first option from Python Excel
dot org.
So let's open it and notice that this site isn't a pi pi yet.
And it reads Working with Excel files in Python here it says This site contains pointers to the best
information available about working with Excel files in the Python programming language.
So here we have a category titled Reading and Writing Excel files and it contains several options.
Then we have writing Excel add ins along with its options and some other stuff we don't need.
So let's go back up and suppose we want a package that allows me to read and write Excel files.
Well, the first one here is Open P Excel.
I don't know if it's better or worse than the others, but I've been researching it a bit and I know
I can go to the documents through this link and it'll take me to the official document.
Open P Excel and I can also go straight to the download.
So this takes me to a similar site to the previous one.
Now I'm in pi pi dot org.
Let's see how to install this.
We have to type pip install open p excel if you want.
You can read the whole document inside this link which shows everything.
So let's go back to command line and we install this with pip install open p excel enter here.
It will happen the same as the previous case when we installed colored.
So now I can go to python and type from open p excel import.
All that is an asterisks so I'll press enter and won't get an error so I'm ready to use whatever open
P Excel contains in order to manage Excel files.
So this is how you can use pip install in python and you can find out what external packages are better
for you.
So we're not using any package for now.
I just wanted you to know how to search for and use whatever package you may need in the future.
In fact, we're likely to need to install some packages in order to do some things.
I want to teach you in some of the next lessons, so I hope this was useful to you.
If you have any doubt, please leave it in the Q&amp;A section because next we're going to learn how to
create our own modules and packages using Python.
So see you later.