In order to use some of today's tools, we will need to install an extra resource, which is the C compiler,
so that we're going to visit the Visual Studio site.
Of course, I'll leave the link in the lesson resources and once there you'll install the community
version which you're seeing here on the screen during the installation process, which we are going
to do by yourself as it is quite intuitive.
At some point you're going to come across this window where you can select some options.
It is very important that you include this add on called desktop development with C++.
Once installed, we can go back to pie chart.
Now we need to install some libraries that are necessary to do facial recognition, but this time we're
not going to do it through the console as we have done so far.
Because I want to show you another way to load Python libraries direct from pie charm without leaving
here.
So what we do is come to file and to settings and then this window is going to open here and we're going
to go to project.
Here we are.
We're going to choose Python interpreter.
And here this system is going to show you all the libraries that you already have installed.
The ones you see here are mine.
Yours may be different.
To install a new library, click on the plus sign, which is here and this box will open and show you
all the existing libraries.
And you're going to look for one of the ones we're interested in, which is C make.
And here it's going to appear for you to choose it.
Here you see a description informing what this library does.
The latest version that exists, the author and the version.
If you don't want the latest version, you can click here and choose another version.
But generally, you'll always be fine with the latest unless you find there are some bugs in it or it's
not compatible with something.
And then you can go back to another version.
Finally, you will click on install package as I have already installed it.
I'm not going to do that.
So once you do that, you're going to see that there's going to be a bar that's going to fill up down
here until the library is complete.
And once you're done with CMH, you're going to go on to four more libraries.
One is the library, and you install that as well.
Then we do the same with the most important one face middle hyphen recognition.
And you will find this one here.
Then we're going to need NumPy to do some calculations that we're going to need.
So let's delete here and put numpy.
This library is also very important for operations with numbers, which we'll see later in the course.
And finally, open CV, middle hyphen python.
This is another important one which you are also going to install.
And once you have these five libraries installed, we're going to import two of them for now to start
working.
The first one is Open CV, which is actually imported in the following way.
Import CV two and the other library that we're going to install in this first practical lesson is face
recognition.
We do it with import face underscore recognition.
Note that here it should be written with underscore, not the middle one.
And a trick that is also important to know when we have a library with such a long name like face recognition
that you have to write it many times or it takes a lot of screen space.
We can shorten our code by giving it a nickname.
So then when importing it, we put at the end as f r.
By doing it this way, we are giving it a nickname.
From now on I can call face recognition just by typing f r.
Then if I put a dot, I can see all the methods that correspond to face recognition without having to
write the whole thing.
So now we have what we need to start working.
So let's get down to work in the next lesson.