Welcome to this new lesson here.
We're going to get to know Google Code Labs.
And for that, I'm currently inside my drive where I've created a folder called My Collapse.
And from here, I'm going to show you how to create and then how to use a co lab document.
We create it by right clicking anywhere in our folder.
We go to more and just as we create any Google document, what we're going to create here is a Google
Collaboratory.
This is where our environment is opened.
This is an ideal tool because it not only serves to practice and improve our knowledge in techniques
and tools of data science, but also for the development of applications of machine learning and deep
learning without having to invest a penny in programs, storage, etc..
Well, with CoLab you can write Python code just as we do in Python or in any other IDE, but it is
especially useful in this case to be able to share and export our code, just as if it were any other
drive document, as if it were a text file or spreadsheet.
Well, you can share these co labs just like those because they are stored in the cloud.
But the main difference you'll see with any other ID like Pi charm, the one we've been using so far,
is that with other IDs, we work with the sheet type code that is a large document in a single file
where you can write one line under the other, and then when you run it, it runs in the order you've
written it.
The CoLab notebooks, on the other hand, store the code in separate cells, and this changes some of
the issues we're going to look at in practice.
So let's start here with the first cell, which is ready for us to start writing here.
I'm going to write any order.
I'm going to create a variable name and I'm going to designate a value to it that can be Frederico.
This is the content of the variable.
So if I press enter, I will appear in the next line where I can continue writing more code.
For example, age, another variable equal to 45.
So if I press enter, I will continue adding lines.
But in order to exit this cell, I will press shift and enter here.
I have exited the cell and the cell is currently executing.
Execute here is different than we have seen in Python here.
Execute means that it is loaded into the system and the system now knows that name is equal to Federico
and the age is equal to 45.
If in this other cell I write a line that refers to one of these variables, for example, print name
and execute it by clicking here we see that the output is Federico because this cell looks for this
value which was already loaded in the previous cell.
But it doesn't end here.
I'm going to go to a new cell.
I can do this here, going to plus code and this creates a new cell.
Or I can go down here where it also says plus code and this will create another cell to.
Well, the point is that from here I'm going to rewrite or override the name variable and I'm going
to make it equal to fill.
Note that I didn't execute this cell yet because I didn't press the shift enter combination, nor did
I click here on this play icon.
So I'm going to go back to the cell containing print name and remember that this other cell hasn't been
executed yet.
So I go back to this cell and print name returns to type Federica.
So why did that happen?
Because this cell has not yet been loaded into the system.
So if I run it now and then rerun this print and now it does say fill, even though this cell is before
this cell, if we were to follow the logic of Python, we would say that the first name is Federico
and then I print Federico, then I change the variable fill.
But when this print was executed, there was still Federico.
But in co labs.
On the other hand, if I re execute this cell and now I re execute this print, now Federico is again
the value contained in the variable name.
So this ordering may be confusing to you, but it's important to know that when you execute a cell,
the compiler updates and has this new value loaded cells can be reordered.
So if I want this cell that has the print to go underneath it, I move it and then I have the print
underneath it and I can keep repositioning them.
So I rerun Federico, I rerun fill and I rerun the print and now fill is loaded.
Do you follow me so I can also create cells that are text?
Only I can come here to plus text or stop here and create this cell, which the only thing is going
to do is type text.
That's not going to be executable, but it's going to appear on the screen.
So if I want, for example, to write a notebook that has some instructions, some descriptions, etc.,
then here I say the following is a function.
I can do that, and this is just text.
I can make it all bold and I can put images and I can put paragraphs and even emojis.
So once I get out of here, it's just a decorative text that's useful for organizing a notebook or communicating
something.
But if I run the whole thing, it doesn't modify the compiler and let's write a function to see how
this part of the code works as well.
So I'm going to define it with Def Show Name and we're going to pass it as a parameter person and we
continue writing inside the same cell to write the content of our function.
And we're going to do print hello a space.
And after the quotes we concatenate to person.
So now I execute this cell with shift plus enter so I can get out of here and let the compiler read
it.
Now the function already exists in the compiler and now I'm going to invoke this function putting show
name.
And you can see that here too.
If I stop the context sensitive help appears just like in picture and I can press tab to make it complete
and let's pass it a name as a parameter.
I try Alex and if I execute this cell, the result is Hello Alex.
Everything works perfectly and look what's going to happen now if I change hello to goodbye and I don't
execute it.
I just exit with the cursor and I execute the call again.
It still says hello, although the visible code says goodbye.
Nothing has been changed inside the compiler and until I execute this cell, the compiler doesn't realize
that there has been a change here.
Now, if I call show name, I get goodbye Alex, which is the greeting we have.
So that's the basics of Google CoLab for now.
And on this day we're going to use this environment because as we said, it is ideal for carrying out
data science applications, graphical representations of big data, graphical visualizations and exploratory
data analysis.
It is especially perfect for sharing code files and for working collaboratively just as we share any
Google document.
So let's move on to the next lesson.