The time to introduce the core concept of Python programming has come.
So let's talk about object oriented programming, Opie.
Opie is a programming concept that allows us to organize code in a way that closely resembles how we
think in real life designing digital objects that we can create, manipulate or destroy.
In OP, we call class to the code that defines an object.
Classes allow us to group a set of variables and functions so that our objects have life.
Anything you can imagine from everyday life that you want to represent in a program can be represented
in a class such as a chair, a building, a light, a backdrop, or a bird.
Let's take the bird as an example.
If you create a class to define the concept of bird, you will define different characteristics for
it.
What do you think?
Such as the color, habitat, age, size?
We call these characteristics attributes.
On the other hand, classes have a set of functionalities or things they can do.
In the case of the bird, it could fly, it could eat, it could make noise and chirp.
We call these functionalities methods.
Finally, we can create many types of birds.
Each bird is a different bird that in your program is going to be created from a bird class.
We can have a bird named Twitty or a parrot named Pepe.
We will call these different birds objects.
That is the abstract concept of bird is the class.
But Twitty or Pepe or any specific bird itself will be an object.
Each instance of the bird class will be considered that object.
In this section, you will learn how to create a class, how to define its attributes and methods in
order to create objects or instances of that class.
So I insist.
OP is a concept of programming and not all programming languages support OP.
Of course Python does.
That's why we're learning it.
And in the next few lectures we will learn in depth all about OP.
Object oriented programming is based on six basic principles or pillars inheritance, polymorphism,
cohesion, abstraction, coupling, and encapsulation.
Don't worry about memorizing these right now because very soon we are going to learn each one of these
concepts one by one, and why they are so important as the pillars of OP.
So why did object oriented programming come about?
Before it existed, only functions were used to program events, which you just learned in the previous
few days.
And as you know, they allow grouping blocks of code under a certain name to do a specific task.
This was very useful because it allowed us to reuse certain modules or functions without having to copy
the code over and over, but just call it out every time we needed it.
So functions are very useful, but they were not able to satisfy all programmers needs.
One of the problems is that functions only perform some operations on input data to deliver an output,
and yet they don't care too much about keeping that data or maintaining some kind of state unless a
value is returned in the function call and assign to a variable as we've done.
If we don't do it this way, everything that happens inside the function is forgotten and this tends
to be a problem.
Let's imagine we have a game where you fight off zombies moving around the screen.
Each zombie will have parameters like their position, size, direction, speed, damage, resistance
among others.
If we didn't use classes to store that data as attributes of each object, we would need to have a variable
for each data we want to store.
The problem comes if we have 20 or more zombies, since we would end up managing a very high number
of variables.
Your code would be complete chaos in response to this issue.
Object oriented programming was born.
It's a perfect tool that allows us to solve certain types of problems in a much simpler and organized
way with less code.
In addition, we can group a set of variables, attributes and methods into a class and make it reusable.
Reusable features that not only are easy to maintain and update, but are flexible for different uses.
In the next lecture, we are going to learn how to create classes.
It's not something you want to miss.
So we're going to be waiting for you there right now.