In this lesson, we are going to see something different because we are going to start working with
documents and folders on your computer.
This means that we are going to learn how to manipulate files from Python in a very basic way.
We call this IO, which stands for input and output, and we're going to start by looking at how to
do fundamental tasks related to text files like opening, reading, writing and closing text files from
Python code.
For that, your main friends are going to be methods like open, read, write and close.
Basically, we are going to open files and place them inside variables on which we will apply these
methods and many more so that our reach as programmers continues to expand.
In this first lecture, we will learn how to open, close and read files, and we will perform some
basic manipulations on what we display on the screen.
In the next lecture, we will move on to creating and writing files from Python.
Let's go to PY Charm so Federico can show you right away how we do it.
Before we start, I'll introduce you to the starring role of this lecture, which is the basic text
file called Test Text that contains three lines, each one claiming to be the first, second and third
line.
This file is stored on my computer, of course, and in the same folder as all the picture files I'm
working with.
It's fundamental that you save the file we work with in the same folder where you're storing all the
python files.
So if you want, you can download this very same file.
I'll leave it as an attachment, or you can create your own file.
So later on we'll learn how to open files located in any other folder in your computer.
But for now we'll work without specifying a folder path.
That's why you have to save your files in the same folders.
So let's go back to Pie Charm and we'll start by learning how to open a file we already know exists.
So we'll store that file in a variable.
Variables not only can contain elements we've already seen, they can also contain many more elements,
such as a text file.
I'll call this variable my file and there I'll save my open method to which I have to pass a data set.
Look, file mode buffering among others.
We'll keep this simple and pass only the file name between quotation marks so as to create a string.
I already know my file is called test text since my file is stored in the same place as all the python
files.
Like I told you, I don't need to provide a path because that place would be the default path.
Let's execute this to see what happens.
You may be asking yourself what we're going to see.
Well, we don't see anything.
Why?
Because we only transferred the contents of test text to my file.
This command doesn't execute anything in the console.
Okay.
So let's go on.
If I want to show you on the screen the contents inside my file.
We know I'll do this with print.
What would happen if I showed my file on the screen?
Let's execute it.
We have something strange here.
It's showing me some data that are useless to the user.
Here it says we're executing the IO library with the test IO wrapper method.
It says the name of the file is test text.
It says it's in R mode.
You'll find out what this is in the next lecture, but it basically means read mode and it also says
it's encrypted with this code.
This isn't telling you anything that's useful for you, but I want you to see that what's inside my
file?
If you open it this way, we're just opening and showing it.
So I also want to show you this, since my file is a variable containing a text file.
It has a series of methods associated with that type of file.
So if I type a dot here, you'll see I can use read, read line, close read lines, plural, etc.,
etc..
So let's start working with this and open the read method which will enter brackets automatically.
If I execute this, I won't see anything because I just opened it and then read it.
These are internal features that make my file read what's inside the file we entered, but we're not
showing anything on the screen yet.
So you may ask, when will I be able to see what's inside the file?
Well, once I've read the file, I can print this act of reading.
We enter print closed brackets at the end.
And if I print this, the contents inside test will be displayed.
So here we were able to open, read and show what's inside a basic text file.
Before moving on.
I want you to listen to this.
Every time you work and open a file, you must close it to.
So my file dot close, which is a method to close a file and allows you to back up your progress.
Sometimes you will work with large files, open more than one file at a time, or open the same file
many times.
So it's very convenient to always close when you're done.
Look, I'll drag it down here so it doesn't bother us.
But as long as we have this here, the file will always close after we're done executing it.
In the same way I've read the file, I can use a similar method called read line singular notice.
There are two of them.
Read line and read lines.
We'll use the singular one for now.
This method reads one line, so only the first line will be printed here.
Actually, another option is to store inside a variable named one line.
My file dot read line and then print the variable execute and it's the same.
We have the first line printed, so you may ask how can I see the other two lines?
If I try print again, I won't be able to see them because I'm not trying to print the variable containing
the first line.
Now, this is interesting.
If we copy this same variable and store it in one line, which is the same variable, but we rewrite
it again and again before printing it, then we will obtain the three lines.
Why?
By reading with read line.
The software saves the last time it read something and then when you make it, do it again.
With Red Line, the software resumes where it left off.
That's why we could apply one line to the second and third lines.
As you may have seen, each line is separated with another intermediate line because every time a file
is created, let's see, each line includes a line break.
That's because I typed Enter after each line.
If I hadn't, I wouldn't have been able to go to the next line.
Therefore, each line includes a line break that's there, although we can't see it.
Python recognizes line breaks and so it displays them.
But if you don't want them to be displayed, use the method one line dot ers trip.
This will remove line breaks and show the results without them.
That's why we see these two lines together.
In case you need this method, here you have it.
Let's execute it as it was and keep going.
So in addition, it's important that you take into account that this is a group of strings, i.e. you
can use all the strings methods in this variable named one line.
For instance, if I type a dot and then right upper, I'll be able to convert the first line to uppercase.
As a result, the first line is uppercase and the rest is lowercase.
I also want you to see that you can iterate over the lines of a file.
So let's delete everything and create a for loop that for each line or l inside my file.
Since my file is actually a group of lines, it prints something like here it says Colon.
And then we concatenate with L.
If we print this, we'll see here it says and then the text from the first line and so on.
Well, we were able to iterate by looping through each line and control every cycle of our loop.
Imagine all the possibilities.
So another option would be the method read lines, plural.
Look, let's start my file.
Read lines in a variable called all.
So the difference here is that when I print it, look at what happens when printing oil.
We obtain a list containing three elements.
The first one is the first line and so on.
So now we can use the list methods.
I can type all is equal to all dot pop.
So when we execute, it all will have only the third line, which is the one we excluded from the list.
Keep in mind that you have to restrict the red lines method to small files because every time you use
it, the whole file will be opened.
If you employ the same method many times with the same code, the whole file will be opened according
to each time you use that method.
And if the files you're working with a large, you'll overload your system and you may run out of space.
So this explains the basics of opening, reading, showing and manipulating elements.
However, take into account that we're modifying the contents of the variable.
My file.
We're not modifying the original text file.
So even if I close after executing all of this, when I open it again, we'll see that the last line
hasn't been removed.
It is still there because we've been manipulating what we showed on the screen inside Petrom.
So in the next lecture, we're going to learn how to create, write and modify the original file in
order to finish explaining how to work with input and output on basic files with Python.
So see you in the next lecture.