Let's start to create our app by importing dt k into.
We have to import everything from it.
So we do so by adding an asterisk and now we can use all its tools.
Let's clarify everything that we do.
Let's initialize T.K. into through a variable and let's name it application and it will be equal to
T, k, capital, t and brackets.
If we put application and a dot, we can see all the t k into methods and properties.
So now after initializing the t k into window, it must stay open.
And remember that when a program closes, when its code stops executing, we lose everything we were
doing.
Therefore, here will type prevent window from closing and it will include a call to application dot
main loop.
This creates a kind of loop that is constantly executing itself.
Hence our code doesn't stop executing and our window remains open.
So we haven't set up anything regarding our window yet.
And if we want to see it, here it is.
It's very small and we can see t k up here.
We can maximize it and close it.
Now we'll begin to configure different features according to our needs.
First, we want to set up a specific size.
So we'll add window size.
We'll call application and call the geometry method, which requires the window size and location parameters.
First, we'll set the window size up, always in quotes.
In this case, it will be 1020 by 630.
So where does this number come from?
So I ran some tests while designing the application, so I came up with this nice size.
It's likely that you don't remember the number of pixels by heart when setting up a window.
You'll figure it out as you add or remove elements, and then you'll be like, okay, this.
This is the size I want.
After entering 1020 pixels in width and 630 pixels in height put plus so as to configure where you want
your window to appear.
I want it to appear in zero on the x and y axis.
In other words, my window will appear on the top left corner of my screen.
We'll see that after executing, however, the user will be able to maximize it and that will ruin everything
we do.
So we have to make sure that the user can't maximize the window.
We'll type prevent from maximizing through application dot resizable and we'll enter values that the
size cannot be changed.
Let's execute this once again.
The maximized button has gone and if we position ourselves on the edge, we won't be able to expand
or contract our window.
That's great.
Let's now set a window title which appears up here.
So far it says TK.
We set it through application dot title and remember that if you want to change things that I didn't
teach you in this lesson, you have to do your own research.
So add a dot and check if there's anything that can help you do what you want to do.
Right now we need a title, so we put one that we like in brackets.
I'm going to put my restaurant invoicing system.
Let's execute again and perfect.
My restaurant invoicing system looks nice.
Finally, I want to set a background color because I'm not quite keen on this pale gray.
So window background color, application config.
And this lets us manipulate a lot of our attributes, but we just need BG for now, which stands for
background.
If you enter a specific color in quotes, your window will have that color.
So we can put colors like blue, orange, white, among others.
But those colors are pretty basic.
As you know, there are many gradients, so I advise that you do two things.
Use the RTB system which we have learned about how to use before, or add the lists of colors that I've
left in the resources.
These are all the colors available in TK Enter.
They include the IGP and hexadecimal numbers in order to use them.
So if I want to use this one named Burley Wood, I can type it here.
Burley Wood Now I execute it.
And so I added salmon, which goes.
Well with the other colors, I want to add.
And that's what I plan on doing.
So this is all concerning our window configuration.
For our next lesson, we're going to add elements like panels, buttons, text boxes and so on.
So let's keep on moving forward then.