To do web scraping with Python, we must first understand the basics of how a website works when you
access a website from your browser.
What you see on the screen is what's called the front end of the website.
That is the graphical interface for the user to view and interact with the site.
In order to do web scraping, what you really need to understand is how the front end of a website delivers
information to your browser, and it basically does this with three elements HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
But to do web scraping, you don't need to know these concepts in depth.
You just need to know enough to be able to understand how your browser manages to display what it displays.
Let's see an example.
When a browser loads a website like a YouTube video, the user can see what is known as the front end
of that website.
Let's say you have a link to a YouTube video, you enter it into your browser, and then YouTube sends
information back to your browser and your browser displays it in front so that you can see it.
This is a human readable format, but what YouTube is returning is actually a code, a code that is
primarily in HTML language, but also contains CSS and JavaScript components.
And this is special code that your browser can read and understand to translate it into something that
looks good to the human eye.
So what we're going to be able to do with web scraping is prepare our python code to read the HTML,
CSS and JavaScript code that YouTube is sending us.
Maybe we can grab the YouTube logo or the video title or the number of views it has.
So we're going to use our python code to look into this HTML code and find where that information is.
So you can take images and information from this document and turn it into a python object.
Do you understand everything so far?
If you do, then we need to understand a couple of things to be able to do.
Web scraping effectively.
The first one is not really technical.
It's the rules of web scraping.
What you are going to do is extract information from someone else's website, so you should always try
it to get permission before extracting.
If you make too many attempts or requests, your IP address may be blocked, which means you won't even
be able to visit that website again in a normal browser.
Now, if it's a website that gets millions of visitors like Wikipedia or YouTube and you're only going
to log in a couple of times to get information, then it's not really a problem because that website
gets a lot of traffic all of the time.
But keep in mind that some sites automatically block web scraping software, so you should always make
sure and check the permissions or the rules or the terms and conditions of a particular website you
are going to try to scan.
And you should also try to check the laws of whatever country you're operating in and see if it's legal
to extract web content.
The second topic I want to talk about is also not really technical, and that is web scraping limitations.
Every website is unique, which means that unfortunately every web scraping code must be unique as well.
Therefore, you can't just take a python web scraping code and apply it to any website without looking
at it, because the HTML code for each website will be unique to that website.
In addition, take into account that any small change or update to a website can completely ruin your
website web scraping code, which will already be rendered useless to those changes if you don't adjust
it.
This is something that's a bit annoying in web scraping, as well as the fact that if you plan to have
a long term web scraping project, it is very likely that you will have to make adjustments over time.
So our goal in this section of the course is to be able to learn General Python Web scraping skills
so that you can apply them to any unique website.
Okay, now let's talk about the main components of the front end of a website.
These are the three main components of a website's front end.
These are the three things your browser receives.
But your browser is not going to show you all the source code.
It's going to use it to show you something that is readable to human eyes.
HTML is used to create the basic structure and content of a web page, so HTML actually contains the
information that is displayed on the website, such as written words in a paragraph.
CSS, which stands for Cascading Style Sheets, is used for the layout and styling of a web page.
Then it will take whatever is in the HTML code and display it according to some kind of style like font
size, color or positioning on the website.
So to put it very simply, HTML.
Now brings the information to be displayed and CSIS decide the style in which to display it.
Finally, there is JavaScript which is used to define the interactive elements of a web page.
However, we won't have to worry so much about JavaScript in our web scraping jobs.
Actually, what we'll be looking to into most is the HTML and we can use the CSS to help us find it.
And don't worry about fully understanding this.
Now we're going to see lots of examples when we're web scraping in Python.
Let's look at a small example of these components.
This would be a totally elementary HTML code.
The top line usually says something like doc type HTML, which basically tells the browser, Hello,
this is an HTML file, and then we have a various tags or elements.
Notice that all the tags that are open have a closing tag and this tag is always denoted with a backslash
before its name.
So we have this HTML tag first and then we have the head tag at the top, which means header.
This part basically contains high level information about the web page itself, such as the title that
will be seen in the browser tab.
And then we have the body component.
Body contains most of the information the website will display, such as headings which are more important
text or paragraphs of text.
The main aspect to understand here is that there are tags in which we can search for things.
So if for some reason we want to get some paragraph from this document, we'll use Python to search
through the P tags which stand for paragraph tags.
This is the main thing you need to know.
The fact that there is an opening tag and a closing tag for everything and that we can search for information
between those tags.
CSS, as we learned, stands for cascading style sheets.
CSS Styles a website, and it also uses tags to define which HTML elements to style.
Again, this is an extremely simple HTML file to which we have added CSS.
The first change you'll notice is that inside the head section we've included a link to a CSS file.
We put in this link tag that says, okay, this relationship will be a style sheet and also says this
will be a CSS file and the h ref, which is the references for the actual file telling this HTML document
where to find the CSS file, which has things like descriptions about font sizes, position, color,
and so on.
And now CSS works in a way that once it's linked to the CSS file, as many things like IDs and classes,
there's actually more CSS elements to this.
But we only need to know about IDs and classes for our purposes.
See right here inside this paragraph tag that has text.
Now inside the opening tag, I have this that says ID est one.
EST one is a callout that I have inside the CSS document.
That means that this paragraph tag is going to go look for the ID called EST one inside my CSS file
in order to style the text it contains.
What does the CSS file look like?
Here's an example.
Essentially, it will have this hash tag symbol with the name EST one and this thing that pretty much
looks like a dictionary containing a property color and a value green.
This means that anything that has est one in this tag will look a certain way when displayed on a browser.
The hash tag symbol basically determines that this is an ID.
Normally IDs are only used once per HTML document.
If instead of ID we saw a call to class in the HTML document with whatever value afterwards it would
look like this in the CSS document, it would start with a dot and the name we give to the class, unlike
hash tag, which means ID and can be used only once.
The DOT means class, which implies that it can be used many times.
Therefore, classes are generally used when you want to add the same style to several elements in each
HTML file.
In this case, the class says the style is going to be blue and arial font.
So a much larger CSS file might look something like this.
It could have PE, which stands for all the paragraph elements in an HTML file, and they'll have a
certain color, a specific font and particular font size.
Or you can have a class with its specifications or an ID, which will affect an element within the HTML
file.
So I know I've been giving you a lot of information right now, but don't worry about memorizing this.
We'll build on it step by step throughout the day.
And you're going to see how it connects to web scraping and Python.
The main thing I want you to take away from this lecture is that your browser receives code that contains.
HTML complements it with hard information on the site and see us as complements that by offering a visual
style to the information that comes in the HTML.
I want you to remember that all this information is organized inside opening and closing tags.
So if we want to search for information about a website through Python, we must learn how to point
to the right tags to find it.
And what we are going to learn next is how to do web scraping from Python and how to use the libraries
called Beautiful Soup LLC's ML and request to do it as these are external libraries, I ask you to install
them on your computer.
You already know how to do it, so we have them ready before we get started with the next lecture,
which is coming right now in total Python.
See you inside.