For
mathematics, everyone's favorite subject at school in programming, numerical operations are very important,
and that's why you're going to learn how to do some basic and not so basic operations in Python.
In this lecture, as you can imagine, in order to add, subtract, multiply and divide, we use our
old and familiar basic operation signs.
But there's much more than that.
And you're going to learn it right now in pie term.
Okay, let's put these operations into practice inside this operate this file that I've just created.
You can do the same.
And let's start with basic operations like addition, subtraction, division and multiplication.
We're going to create some very simple variables.
X will have the value of six and Y with a two.
We will do some operations with them.
And since we learn how to make literal strings, we're going to do that in that way.
I'm going to print it.
Remember to use the F to warn Python that it is a literal string and I want to enunciate an operation
with its result.
For example, x plus y is equal to whatever.
So I open the braces to put inside x.
That is to say that the value of x is going to be to be printed, which is this case six.
Plus, I open the case to write y that we know values two equals.
And here I open the case and put the operation.
That would be X plus Y.
And now, if I run this, I'm going to go to run and run again.
And we pick operators.
We get six plus two equals eight.
That's right.
Now we're going to copy this line and we're going to paste it three times to do the subtraction here
as well.
We're going to say that X minus Y equals X, minus Y.
We use the minus symbol to do subtraction.
Down here we say X times Y equals x times Y using the asterisk.
And down here in the last line, let's say X divided by Y equals x slash Y.
The slash is the division symbol.
If we run this, we have four lines saying six plus two equals eight.
Six minus two equals four and six times two equals 12, and six divided by two equals 3.0.
Notice that the division returns a float value.
Well, let's move on to something a little more complex.
Let's add one more variable called Z.
We're going to feed a seven into this one.
And the first thing I'm going to do is show you what's called a flow division.
And what is a flow division from a division is an operation that divides two numbers and rounds the
results down to the nearest integral.
So it'll be the same than doing a regular division.
But if the result is a floating number, it deletes any decimal number and leaves only the integer.
For example, seven divided by two should be 3.5.
But if we do a fraud division, we get three, because the point five will be eliminated.
So let's try it.
We're going to do a print statement.
Let's make it a literal string.
And we're going to say Z divided to the floor of Y equals and how we write throw a division Z slash
slash.
Why?
This is different than a regular division.
Here we would use only one slash and when we run it, we get seven divided to the floor of two equal
three.
Not 3.5, which would be the exact outcome of seven divided by two, which is the division to the floor.
Now let's learn the modulo or mod operator.
The modulo returns back to the reminder of a division.
In other words, if you do a division and after you get the result here, there is a reminder that is
the modulo.
For example, six divided by three equals two and there is nothing left over.
So the modulo of six divided by three is zero.
But if we do seven divided by two, how many times does the two fit completely inside?
Seven.
If it's three times an even when we have a reminder, we cannot include two for a fourth time.
Right.
So that reminder is the modular modulo.
Then in this case we can say that one is the modulo of seven divided by two.
So let's say in execution, we're going to print it also with the literal string.
We're going to open the quotation marks and we're going to say That's Z, modulo Y, which is two in
this case, is equal to.
And how do we write it?
Well, we use the percentage symbol.
So in this case, it would be Z percentage Y, that's Z mode y.
Let's run it to check that seven modulo of two is equal to one.
As we calculated, this type of division is also never done in real life, but we use it a lot in programming
to detect what a number is, even because if we try any number mod two and its result is zero, it means
that there is nothing left over.
That is to say it is even.
So it's a clever way to discover odd numbers.
So let's look at the powers now.
Let's copy this over here.
And let's drop X to the power of Y.
Is equal to X and we put twice the asterisk symbol and then y.
These two asterisks is what tells Python that we are going to power a number to another factor which
can be two, three, four, ten or whatever you want.
So if we run this, we get six to the power of two is equal to 36 because of course, six times six
is 36.
And let's check this another way.
Let's copy it and let's power something.
But this time, to the power of three.
We're going to say the X to the power of three.
I don't have a variable for three, so let's just write three in here.
Is equal to x.
Three and we run that and it's going to tell us that six to the power of three is equal to 216.
Great.
And finally, let's learn the square root.
We're going to print one more line here and we're going to say that the square root of we're going to
delete everything that follows.
We open up a set of keys and let's say I want to know the square root of six, for example.
So I put the X, the word is.
And then I should write the operation for the square root, which is first the value you want to take
its root 0.5.
The results of an operation where you have some value to asterisks and 0.5 is going to give you the
square root.
And if we run this here, we have the square root of six is 2.4, four, nine, and so on.
And in fact, this result gives us the basis for what we're going to learn in the next lecture, which
is how to round numbers.
So don't miss it.
Feloni Waiting for you in the next lecture.