How
did you make it?
Did you have any complications?
Did something give you more trouble than you expected?
Well, if you made it, congratulations.
And if not, don't worry about it.
It is normal to encounter difficulties when we are left alone in front of the code.
And next, we're going to create our solution from scratch.
And when I say from scratch, I mean from scratch of the file.
So let's open a column again so we can select our folder, which in this case is called Python, remember?
And I've saved it on my desktop here.
I right click to choose a new file.
And this is going to give us the opportunity to create the name of the file, which I'm going to name
Brewery, because it's to create the brand of my beer.
And I don't have to forget to put the dot p y so the system knows it's a python code.
So we press enter, our file is created and here we're looking at the inside of the python folder.
This file we're seeing is already open here so we can start writing code directly into this file.
We're going to choose the column to see a little bit better.
Now, my way of solving this is going to be to start by expressing what it is that I want to be printed
on the screen.
And the prompt that gets printed on the screen is the name of your beer is and then the name of the
beer.
So let's do that.
So print is the command for something to be displayed on the screen.
I'm going to put it as I expect it to be displayed.
So we open the quotation marks and we say, for example, the name of your beer is and then comes the
name.
But since we don't know it, we're going to put, for example, word one and word two all in a row.
Now remember that we want these two words, the name of the bear to appear in quotation marks, so we
select it completely and put single quotation marks.
So that appears.
Just like that.
Well, we already have what we need to be displayed.
Now let's design the structure of how we want it to be displayed.
We want to display first the complete string that says the name of your bear is that leaves this space
and shows this first quotation mark.
And up to here, we know what we have beyond that.
No, because we don't know the words yet.
So here we're going to close this string with double quotation marks.
Notice now that I'm getting the following as an error, let's leave a space to put the plus, which
means concatenate with well, with word one, which we don't know yet.
After word one, we're going to need a space to separate both words.
So we're going to concatenate here with a space between quotes.
It will be a string containing the only a space.
But we're going to put another plus sign to concatenate with word two.
And then we need this last single quotation mark to appear.
And for that, we need to transform it into a string that's going to be concatenated.
And here we can see it all very well.
So we zoom in and you can see maybe this is a little confusing, but what we have here is a double quote,
a single quote and a double quote to generate a string that contains only one single quote.
So as you can see, if I get out of this form of this line, the system is understanding everything,
just just fine, except for word one and work two, which gives me an error because Python says, what
is this?
I don't know where to get this word.
One word to.
If it were in quotes, Python would know that it's a string, but it's not.
So where do we have this?
Well, we're going to create it.
And now we're going to replace these words.
So we need two inputs.
A first input, ASIM.
Something for the user to say, a random word, which is going to be the first part of the Bear brand.
And then we need to ask him a question that we can answer with, for example, the name of a city.
And we're going to say, what city would you like to visit?
So we closed the question, put a colon and leave a space.
That would be the first input we need to replace word one for word two, another input asking him,
for example, something something that he can answer with a color.
And it would be something like, What is your favorite color?
Hey, you can get a little bit creative, generate as many questions as you want.
The answers can be funny.
This this is an exercise.
You have to have fun.
So to get creative, well, we already have the two pieces of code we need to replace these words,
and we.
We can do it.
I'll select the first one.
I'll cut it with Control X and then we're going to replace it here with Control V and we're going to
do the same thing with the second input that's going to go here in place of word to.
And now we have the complete sentence.
Another thing I'd like to do here is to add a line spacing so that they answered.
That looks to be on many different lines.
For now, we're going to run it to see what it looks like.
Note If I now want to run this with shift F10 that will be executed.
It is not a file called Brewery, but this file is called First Project, which is what we've been working
on throughout this whole day.
And probably if you're following my steps, you also have here first project.
So we can't use this triangle to run it, nor can we use shift F10 as you see here in the shortcut because
that would execute this other first project.
So we'd want to change it to brewery, but if we open here, it's not loaded yet.
There's the main and then there's the first project.
The way to add brewery here for a run option would be to come, to run.
And instead of going as we were always going to the first one, which is shift F10, we're going to
do this other role which is with alt shift and F10.
When we execute this one, it's going to give us a choice of which files that exist in this project
are the ones that we want to execute.
And in this case it is brewery.
That is going to be executed as soon as we selected.
And in fact, here we have it.
So before advancing, I want you to see that now Brewery appears in this dropdown and we can choose
it to make the execution from now on with shift and F10.
Well, let's come to the code.
And here it says.
What city would you like to visit?
Well, look, the truth is that I'm dying to visit Barcelona, so let's put this.
And what?
What's your favorite color?
Let's say it's purple.
Now.
Yes, it tells me that the name of my beer is Barcelona and Purple Grape.
I have my answer.
So the next step in the challenge to add a bit of complication was to have the separated into two different
lines.
So how can we do that?
On one hand, we could do it with different print lines.
But if we want to do it all at once, I'm going to make use of the backslash and which stands for New
Line.
As we learned throughout this day.
So after it says the name of your bear, we're going to put here instead of a space backslash with an
end, this tells it to jump lines.
So the second line is going to say is and the full name and we're going to make it so that after this
line with the quotation mark ends, it will generate a backslash.
N That is a new line and it will say, I don't know, congratulations or whatever.
With this we would already have three lines so we run it through shift f10.
Now yes we can do it.
What city would you like to visit?
Well, I've changed my mind.
Now I want to visit London and it tells me that my favourite colour is Let's put yellow.
It's not.
But we put it for a change.
And on three different lines we have.
The name of your beer is London Yellow.
Congratulations.
And that is how we've done it.
If you've made it before watching this lecture, congratulations.
And if you've achieved it by watching this lecture, it is equally valid because it is a way to learn
and see how someone else has solved it.
The code may seem very simple up to this point, but when we get on our own and we are left without
the instructor, we get our books burned and sometimes we need a little help.
So it's perfect.
You're here, and I congratulate you for being here, finishing your first day.
If you did it in a different way.
That's valid, too.
And of course it is because in programming there are many ways to achieve the same result.
And then, of course, some may be more efficient than others, more economical than others, more elegant.
But the point is, at this stage of the course is that you have been able to do it.
So I thank you for following me throughout the solution of this project, and I recommend that you don't
miss the next lecture, which is a very special lecture series.
I'll see you there.