As you may already know, a compressed file is a file or set of files that have undergone a compression
process to make them lighter and easier to transfer from one place to another.
In Python, we can compress and decompress files programmatically.
That is using only code and we can make use of two modules integrated to Python, such as the zip file
module and our old and beloved shuttle module.
Let's go to PY Charm to show you how to use them in order to do what we're going to do.
First, I want to show you that inside the day nine folder.
Python desktop, which I've already shown you on a couple of times.
I have the Python files that I've been working with today and I also have two text files, my text A
and my text B, which I can show you open here.
They have a lot of text in Latin.
They are just examples.
I will leave them next to this option in case you want to download them to use them later.
Or you can use any other file that you have or that you create yourself.
And these two are the files that will learn how to compress and decompress.
And as Phil told you in the introductory video, there are two ways to do it.
To start with, you can use the zip file module, which we import, as you know, and then we create
a variable called My Zip.
This variable is the one that is going to contain the zip file object dot zip file.
Observe that the second time we put zip file, the letters Z and F should be capitalized.
Zip file will require two parameters.
The first will be the name of the file we want to create.
That is the file containing what we want to compress.
This would be like the folder of the dot zip file.
So let's name it with quotation marks of course file underscore compressed dot zip and the opening mode
is going to be w so that we can modify it.
That is to say to write in it.
Actually, it is not that we are going to write, but to introduce the file to be compressed inside
this zip folder, I will execute this first line, although it does not do much yet, but we can compress
the console doesn't show anything, but in the folder de nine where I have my text A and my text B,
I also have this new file which is a compressed file dot zip and which if we open it has nothing, we
delete it because before this code finishes executing, I want to add to it the files that I want to
compress.
Now we call this object whose name is my zip and apply the right method to it.
So what are we going to write in it?
Well, the name of the file we want to compress and we want to put inside.
We're going to write the first one, which is called My Text.
A dot text.
That's the name of the file that I will compress.
And just as I did with this one, which when executed, it will be put inside my zip.
I can also do the same by copying and pasting with my text.
B text.
Once we're done with this, let's call my zip again.
But this time to close it with the closed method.
So what happens if I run this now?
Well, we won't see anything in the console, but in the folder we have this compressed file, which,
if I click on it, I will find inside my text day and my text be compressed into one file.
In fact, I can delete these original files to unzip them so that they appear in my folder again.
To do so, we delete all of this.
So to not generate the compressed file again and generate another variable which you can name open zip
and which will be equal to zip file dot zip file.
It will require us to specify which is the file we want to decompress.
After that we write file compressed.
Then the name it was given dot zip.
And once I find it, it will open it in a read only mode.
So for now, what we have done with this line is simply to create a variable that contains this zip
file, which is called file compressed dot zip.
Well, what's next?
Now we call open zip, which we just created and apply the extract method.
And I want you to observe that we have two options extract to extract one file at a time or extract
all to extract all together.
Do we have to put parameters here?
Actually, it is not necessary.
So we run it and we go back to our folder and here we have our unzipped files here which were not before.
So delete compressed file again.
And we have here are two files compressed and I want to show you another way to do compress files,
this time with another module that is not zip file, but the old and well-known shuttle, which we have
already used earlier today.
Shuttle will allow us in a more practical way to compress all the files founded in a certain folder.
Remember that shuttle lets us go through folders directory trees.
It seems to be the appropriate one.
We have to generate a new variable called source folder.
This variable will contain the path of the file we want to compress.
So let's go back to the desktop.
Do you remember our top folder, the one we used when we dealt with shuttle today and in which we have
this folder structure?
Well, we're going to take advantage of this to see how shuttle can make the compressed file containing
everything inside the top folder.
First we create the path which is equal to C colon, double slash users, double slash when ten double
slash desktop, double slash and finally top folder.
We have to write it exactly like it is using uppercase and lowercase letters, everything.
Note that in your case this will be different.
You can work with any folder you want, choose one you want to compress or with several files and folders
inside, and create the path that allows you to get to that folder.
Because this path here only gets to mine.
We need another variable which is going to be the destination file.
This variable will contain the name of the folder generated.
When we compress everything inside top folder, we can call it all compressed and finally we call shuttle
dot makefile.
And this will require some parameters.
First, the base name, which is a string with which we name the destination file.
This is why we created our variable destination file.
Then it will ask us for a format, a zip one in quotes, and finally it will need the path or directory
that we want to compress.
Well, for that reason we created source folder which will call from here.
So these are the three parameters that shuttle Makefile needs to create a compress file.
So let's see what happens when we run it.
Can't see anything in desktop.
However, we will go to Python Day nine because this is where I'm working.
Since I didn't put a full path here in destination file, it was created where I'm working with Python.
If I had put a different path, this compressed file would have been created somewhere else.
Here we have all compressed.
We click on it and we see that it has the folder structure that corresponds.
And when you open it there you will find three files which have been used and then are all compressed
file exists.
So we still need to see how the decompress using shuttle, which is quite easy to do.
Now we delete everything we have done so as not to generate the compressed file.
Again, we call shuttle unpack and here is unpack file, which serves to unpack a file.
Furthermore, it will ask for the name of the file, which is a string.
Then between quotation marks we put all compressed, which is the name of the file that we have created.
Dot zip.
The second parameter we need is the name we want to give to the folder which will be generated once
we unpack everything.
We want this to be stored in extraction.
Finished.
So remember that here you can put not only the name of a folder, but a complete path if you want it
to be saved somewhere other than the folder we are working on.
So if you type nothing but a folder name, it will assume that the path is the place where we are working
now.
And finally, the format which will be zip.
If I run what we have here, we will see that on day nine, extraction finished has been generated containing
nothing but the files we were expecting.
Shuttle is a much more practical way to do file compression and decompression.
You can also do it with zip file as you like it.
The important thing here is that you have learned to compress and decompress files.
So congratulations and keep up the good work.