To understand what the dictionary type objects are in Python.
Let's think about real life dictionaries.
Open a dictionary at home and you'll find a collection of unique concepts.
For example, all the English words.
Next to each concept there is a definition.
So ultimately what you have is a bunch of pairs which are composed of a concept or keyword and a value
associated with that key.
In Python, it is more or less the same.
A dictionary is a collection of pairs and each of those pairs has a key and a value associated to that
key.
Moreover, keys, just like in real world dictionaries cannot be repeated.
They are unique.
How do you write a dictionary in Python?
Between braces and each pair of elements is going to be separated from each other by commas and within
pairs.
The key and its value are separated by colons.
Unlike lists, dictionaries do not have a specific order.
They do not have an index.
Therefore, even when you create them by writing them in a certain order, that order will be irrelevant
for Python.
Dictionaries could well be written the other way around since you cannot look up a value based on its
index as we did with lists, you can look up values based on its key.
So when is it convenient to use lists and dictionaries for dictionaries?
We said order does not matter.
So you cannot sort with the sort or reverse methods.
But the relationship between a key and its contents does matter.
So a good occasion to use a dictionary is when you want to store values that you can access without
knowing the exact location.
But the relation with another concept.
For example, when you want to store the characteristics of a person which you can then access by consulting
their weight, size name regardless of the order they are stored in.
In order to better understand this, let's see it in action.
And we put ourselves in action right now to see these dictionaries in Python.
We're going to begin declaring our variable.
As always, that is the one that is going to contain our dictionary.
Our variable is going to be called my dictionary.
And remember, the dictionaries are written between braces.
And what we do here is to declare first a key and then a value.
For the first key, I'm going to say see one.
Now, as I've chosen a string name, I have to put it in quotes.
Then a colon to associate it to a value.
And in this case, let's keep it simple with value one.
And I also want to put this in quotes, because it is a string value.
This is the first element of my dictionary, and this could be a complete dictionary.
But let's add another one.
We're going to add another key this time called See two, and we're going to associate this with an
element called value one.
So this is my first dictionary.
Now let's print out the data type that corresponds to my dictionary.
We're going to go up to run and run again.
We choose the file dictionaries and it tells me that this dictionary element is a data type dict, which
remember is short for dictionary.
So, all right, we have a dictionary, but now we're going to print it out to see its contents, not
its type.
So we delete type and we run it again and we see all its contents.
We see between braces there has c one with value, value one and C two with value one.
I repeated it.
I wanted this to be value to.
By the way, I take this opportunity to show you that although the keys can not be repeated, they have
to be unique.
Otherwise it would be complicated.
And when you want to find a key that is written twice, the values can be repeated as you just saw.
The values can be all the same if you want, or they can be two or three that are the same.
That is indistinct.
The keys are the ones that can't be repeated.
All right, let's move on.
Now, let's see how we can query what's in one of those keys.
Let's suppose that I need to fetch the contents of key one.
In that case, let's create a variable called the result to store our dictionary for only whatever there
is in C one.
I'm no longer invoking an index number here.
I'm invoking a key.
And what this brings me, if I now print result is value one, which is the content of C one.
If I had searched here for the contents of C two, what I get is value two.
And that's how you do your searches.
Now let's focus on some kind of real life case.
Suppose I have a variable called customer and I want to store it in a dictionary with all the characteristics
or categories that I have about this customer.
Then a key could be a name, and a name is going to be associated to a value that can be John.
We're going to have a second element that can be last name, but well written, that is and we are going
to associate this to last name.
John can be Lennon and we're going to give it more categories.
We're also going to give it a weight.
And a weight can easily be a value of or type of integer because dictionaries can have all kinds of
data.
So we're going to give it an integer.
And here we don't need quotation marks.
We're going to add one more value and we're going to put height here.
This is allows us to incorporate a float value.
Let's say 1.76 OC.
Here we have a dictionary called customer and now I want to make a query.
Let's make a variable called query, which contains a value that I want to look up.
So I want to know the last name of my customer.
So what I put here is customer in the location of whatever it is in the key.
Last name.
And then that's what I'm going to print.
I'm going to print query.
Let's look at it.
Here we have Lenin.
Perfect.
When I ask the query, whatever is in the key.
Last name I received Lenin.
And if I'd asked to tell me whatever it is in the height key, I would have received 1.76, which is
my client's height.
Well, as you can see, dictionaries contain different types of data, not only in their keys, but
also in their values.
And they cannot be integral strings or float, but also all the data types that we have learned and
that we have yet to learn.
A dictionary can contain lists or it can contain dictionaries inside the dictionary.
Let's create a new dictionary.
We're going to call it Dick, and we're going to put a little bit of everything in it.
The first Q will be one, and it will contain the integer 55.
Then we're going to put a list.
The key two is going to be equal to a list that has the numbers ten, 20 and 30 in it and it supports
it.
There's nothing wrong.
Comma to come up with a third value.
There actually will be another group of elements.
It will have the key three.
And we're going to write a dictionary here.
So we make the dictionary keys.
That is one that has the value 100 and a key as to that has the value of 200.
And this dictionary is the value of the third key, which is a dictionary with two values in it.
That's perfect.
What a mess.
When we want to query this, let's see how it would work.
If I want to print my dictionary, but only what's in the key to which is a list.
Key to is a list.
Well, if we print it, we get the list.
And let's suppose I want to query only what's in index one of this list.
Then I have to add after I close the braces of the key, another bracket in which I'm going to put index
one, which is the one I'm interested in searching.
So here I'm saying please python print whatever it is in the dictionary in its key to and within that
key to whatever is in an index one because I know it's a list, so if I print it, I only get 20.
So my searches can be very specific.
And now I want to search for what is in key three, which is a dictionary.
Let's delete this key.
We're going to obtain the dictionary that is inside my dictionary, which is this one that has two keys.
And if I want to look for what is in the key as to then I add a bracket.
I put S-2 here and I print it and have 200.
That is, I can look up what is in the dictionary within any of the dictionary.
Well, this would allow us to do an exercise.
Here I have this dictionary prepared so you don't have to waste time watching me type.
We're going to paste it in here.
We have a dictionary that has a key one, which is a list A, B, C and a second key, which is key
too, which has another list D, e, f.
What I'm going to ask you now is that you try to make in a single line of code a command that allows
the letter E to be printed on the screen but capitalized.
So take your time, pause the video if you need to, and try to do it.
If not, don't worry.
We'll do it together.
Well, if you're able to do it, congratulations.
And if not, don't worry.
Things can get messed up easily when you're learning something new.
And we're going to do it together now.
We're going to do it in steps so we can think it through easily.
First, we're going to print our dictionary directly through the key.
That's the one with the E.
We said it's key, too.
So we're going to print out key to.
Okay.
Let's go through the steps.
So now we already have the list that contains the E.
Now I want to print E.
So I add a bracket that looks for the index that corresponds to E, which in this case is one because
D is zero and E is one within this list.
So we put one here.
If we print it now, we get the E, and now I want it to be capitalized.
Well, this is the part that may have cost you a little bit.
Remember that the E is in a string.
So we have a method to make a string become uppercase.
So once we've built this whole statement, then we put the dot because we have a string and here comes
the string methods.
And what is the method that we use?
Well, it's upper.
Remember, it has to go with its own parenthesis.
And if we run it here it is our uppercase.
It was easy, but of course, knowing how to do it is what may cost you a little bit.
If I wanted to print the uppercase A well, I would just choose key one and within key one, index zero.
And then I print it here.
I have my capital A here.
Well, let's learn a few more things.
I want you to learn how to add items to a dictionary that's already been created.
So let's create a dictionary, and we're going to fill it with something simple.
A key one with value A and then a key with value B.
Okay.
So we have a dictionary here with two elements.
We're going to print it out and we have our two elements.
Now I want to add key three that has a value of C.
I simply invoke dictionary.
I invoke here a key that doesn't really exist, but I create it at this moment.
It's going to be three.
And since it doesn't exist, what I put here in equals is what's going to be added as a value and what
it's value to be.
C.
So now I go back to print to our dictionary and we are going to obtain that.
Now we have one A to B and three C.
A dictionary has been able to be modified in situ that is in place.
We've not had to create a new variable to contain our modified dictionary, but the disk itself is now
the one that has its modification.
This like lists means that it is possible to modify them.
Unlike strings, I can also overwrite a value that already exists.
Suppose I now want my letter B to be uppercase.
Well, the way to overwrite it is to invoke a key within the dictionary.
In this case, the key of B, which is to.
And what I do here is to assign it to a new value, which would be in this case, be as this key to
already exists.
This is not going to create a new key inside my dictionary, but it's going to overwrite the one that
So we're going to create a print to be able to see this third instance of my dictionary.
We run it and we have here one A to B and three C, that's the way to override.
So a couple of other dictionary methods you might be interested in learning.
Suppose you want to know all the keys that are in a certain dictionary?
Well, let's print out our odyssey.
Let's press Dot to bring up its methods.
And the keys method is the one that is going to bring us all the keys that it has if we print it.
We see here that dict keys is one, two and three.
It did not bring us the values, only the keys.
So if I wanted to know the values, then I print the.
I see values.
So here we get them ticked values A, capital B and C.
These are the actual values in my dictionary.
Now, if I want to know everything that is in a dictionary, then print thick dot items and this is
going to bring everything that is here.
Then dict items is in parentheses, one A in parentheses to B and in parentheses.
Three C.
The fact that they are in parenthesis gives us a guideline that what is inside the dictionaries is something
that is called tuples.
And tuples is what we are going to learn in the next lecture, or I'll wait for you after you've done
the practical exercises that come next.
So let's go to the next lecture.