Now that you understand about loops and iterations, you will have notice that to establish how many
iterations my loop will have, we often need to create a list with a number of elements equal to the
iterations we need.
For example, if we need a block of code to repeat four times so far we need to create a list with the
numbers 1 to 4 in order to iterate over its elements.
Well, actually, there is a more efficient way to do it, and that is using the keyword range.
A range is a function that allows you to set a range of numbers without creating a list or even creating
a variable.
Let's go over to PY charm to learn how range works and then let's go on with ranges in Python.
Up to the moment we said that if we wanted to create a loop that would be repeated, for example, four
times on a list, you had to create a list that had, for example, the numbers one, two, three and
four.
And now I can create a for loop that goes for each number in the list and do something.
For example, print the number.
So if I run this, let's open it in run.
We have one, two, three and four, four lines.
Well, this way it's effective, but it's not the most efficient, because if we have the range function,
we can do it in a much more practical way.
So let's eliminate this list and we will not need it.
We can write our loop.
And here, instead of appealing to an external list, we're going to appeal to a range that we are going
to create at this moment and in this place and range.
As you see, it has some parentheses so that we can put parameters here.
Well, I want a range that goes up to five.
With only this.
I already have the possibility of iterating through all the numbers that go in this case from 0 to 5,
because the range starts by default at zero.
So if we execute, we have zero one, two, three, four, but five is not included.
So the second argument that is not too inclusive, it is where the range is going to stop.
If I wanted to start from one, I can put the one first, the comma and the five, because these two
range parameters say the first is where it will begin and the second is, which will be the first number
that will be out of the range.
So in this case, it's going to give us one, two, three and four, which is what we had before.
So I can set any range I can put from 20 to 30, and it will give us all of those numbers if I want
it to include 30, I actually put it up to 31.
And here I'm going to have from 20 to 30 inclusive.
And not only this but range can also take a third parameter that if you don't use it, nothing happens.
But if you include it after a comma, you can establish the steps that the range is going to take to
skip numbers.
So if I set it to be every two steps, then we will have 20, 22, 24, 26 and so on.
I could set it to every three or whatever number I want as long as it's an integer range does not receive
float in any of its parameters.
Keep that in mind then this is range and thus it serves as to use inside loops and makes them much more
efficient.
But also we can use it outside the loops in which cases.
So imagine you have created a list that goes from 1 to 100.
So what you have to do with this list equals 1 to 3 and so on up to 100.
No, that's impossible.
We're not going to do it in that way.
What we would do in this case would be to create a list that is equal to a range.
But we're going to do it in a casting and we're going to put it inside a list.
And here we put let's say we want the numbers from 1 to 100.
You can even try with large numbers.
Well, it would be from one comma to 101 to include the 100.
And here we already have it.
So let's ask it to print here and to show us our list while we run it.
And here we have one, two, three and four.
And so it goes off the screen until we get to 100.
So range is a very simple and very useful function that can save you a lot of time and code.
So thanks for joining us in this lecture and we're waiting for you in the next one.