Let's talk a little more about inheritance.
Just because you inherit your father's eyes or way of walking doesn't mean you are the same as him in
everything else.
The same is true for inheritance in Python and object oriented programming, for instance, when one
class inherits its methods from another.
Not everything is necessarily going to be the same.
The child class can have three types of methods inherited methods identical to those of the parent class.
Inherited methods that are modified or completely new.
Methods that did not exist in the parent class.
We will see all this in the code in a moment.
The same goes for attributes.
The child class can simply keep the inherited attributes or it can also have its own extra attributes.
This can be done in two ways in the code, and we will also see this in just a moment.
Finally, in this lecture, we are going to talk about the multiple inheritance.
What is this?
While going back to the example of Brian, who inherited Kevin's, his father's eyes.
He may have also inherited Michelle's, knows his mom.
So it is also possible for a class to inherit from many classes at the same time.
And not only that, if Brian has a child, he can pass on the eyes and nose to be inherited from his
parents.
In Python code, it is also possible for the inheritance to be passed through several generations of
classes downwards.
This is great because inheritance is extended and multiplied, but this also will lead to another problem.
If the animal class has a method called TOK and the bird class has modified that method in a third class
called Canary inherits that from bird.
Which talk method?
Is it going to inherit the animals or the birds?
What if bird inherits from animal and living being, which is another class and both have a different
born method?
Which type of birth method is going to be applied to the bird when born is being executed?
There are ways to figure this out in programs and we are going to show you how to code it as well.
So this is going to be a loaded lecture.
So let's head over to py charm right now.
So since there's a lot to cover, we'll start by analyzing the classes from the previous lesson.
We have the animal class that contains two attributes age and color, and we have the born method which
simply says The animal has been born and we have the talk method, the one we just added, which says
This animal makes a sound as the bird class, the one we created down here inherits from animal.
It's supposed it contains all the attributes and methods from animal.
And we've instantiated our first bird object here, which is Tweetie, which is a three year old yellow
bird.
So we said that bird, which inherits from animal, can have three types of methods.
There are the ones inherited from the father class, the ones that we already have.
And if I apply one of these methods to Tweetie, such as Born and execute this code, the software says
this animal has been born.
That's an inherited method without any changes.
Yet we can also have inherited methods that have been modified.
So in our class animal we have a talk method which says this animal makes a sound.
So if we create a new talk method here that is using the same name as the method this inherits from,
and we put something different such as chirp.
What will happen when we execute this method?
Will it execute the method that says Chirp or the one that says This animal makes a sound?
So let's find out.
And it said Chirp, which means this class did inherit a method, but it overrode it so as not to say
this animal makes a sound.
Instead it said chirp.
That method was inherited, yet modified.
Our class can also have new methods which don't exist in the father class.
So bearing in mind that birds fly, we can have a fly method here which says the altitude, which is
the same way we saw the last lesson.
It's a string literal and this bird flies and we can call feet so as to complete the sentence.
So if I call the method that belongs to Tweetie, which is fly, it will require me to type a number
of feet.
So let's put the 328.
And so it will say the bird flies 328 feet.
This was another type of method applied to inheritance, a method that doesn't exist in the father class,
and it's completely new in the child class.
So this was all as regards to methods, but what about the attributes?
So we already know that Tweetie inherits an age and a color.
That's why when creating Tweetie, we had to add the attributes required to the animal class, which
is the one in charge of the inheritance.
But in this case, birds have attributes that other animals don't, such as the altitude they fly at.
This attribute would apply only to birds.
Well, there are two ways of adding attributes to a subclass or a child class.
One is to create its own init method.
We'll do that now and we have to add the same attributes it had before.
Besides self, we have age and color, so here we can add the new one which is altitude will declare
everything again.
Self is equal to age and self color is equal to color.
Then we'll enter the new attribute that's typical of bird's self at altitude, which is equal to altitude.
So this is one way to do it.
And due to the fact that we did it like this, Tweetie now needs a third attribute that is not in animal.
So we'll add to the altitude.
It flies out.
Let's suppose that Tweetie flies at 196 feet high.
So that's it.
No more complaint.
If we create an animal named my animal, which is equal to animal class and not bird, it will only
require age and color.
Altitude is not included because only birds have that attribute.
So let's suppose it is five years old and black and that's it.
This animal doesn't require anything else.
So let's verify something.
If we want my animal to execute, some method will notice that the fly method is not an option since
my animal is not a bird.
So if we try to call that method, we get an error because it doesn't exist.
So we can only add that method to instances of a bird object.
That's why we're allowed to add it to Tweetie.
So this is one way to add attributes to a child class.
The other way is to leave the init method as it is without retyping all the attributes we already have
in the animal class.
Instead, we can use a keyword that is super.
Let's add brackets and a dot so as to use its methods and properties.
And here we have in it, which, as you can see, contains age and color.
So if we call this init method and just type age and color, we no longer need to type self.
Age equals age and self.
Color equals color.
That structure is already inherited.
Notice that there are no complaints and everything works just fine.
So this comes in handy when you have a lot of parameters and don't want to type like 15 new lines to
add all the features you have here by means of super, you can add all the inherited properties and
just type the new ones.
So now let's delete this because we're going to let birds and animals rest for a little while and we're
going to see what multiple inheritance is about.
Let's create three classes, a further class, a child class that will inherit from father and a grandchild
which.
Inherit from child.
They're all empty.
So as you can see, there are no errors because characteristics are passed down indefinitely from generation
to generation.
Grandchild inherits everything from father, though not directly, because it inherits from child,
which does inherit from father.
So now let's imagine that father has a method.
Let's create the talk method which doesn't receive parameters.
It only says hello.
So when father needs to talk, it says hello.
So let's create an instance of the grandchild class which will be named my grandchild and will be equal
to grandchild.
Let's make my grandchild use the talk method and remember it belongs to father and if we execute, this
grandchild is able to talk and say hello, though it doesn't inherit directly from father but from child.
Let's complicate this a bit.
Besides Father, there will be another class named Mother.
And look at this.
It will have a method of its own, which is laugh.
Mother knows how to laugh and it says Haha, piece of cake.
We want it to be a class capable of inheriting properties from father and mother.
So here we'll add comma.
Mother and child will inherit from both of therefore grandchild which inherits from child will have
all the methods and attributes of mother and father.
Then if we want grandchild to be able to laugh, which is very healthy and I recommend you always do
it so we'll have to execute it.
And grandchild says ha ha since it inherited from mother.
And this doesn't mean that grandchild can't inherit methods from father as well.
Grandchild is capable of talking and laughing.
So multiple inheritance is very interesting.
You can inherit from several classes at once and you could add if there were more classes aunts, grandfathers,
anything you want.
So let's complicate this some more.
What if mother besides laugh has its own talk method?
So let's create another talk method for mother.
That method doesn't receive parameters.
So Mother talks, but it says, How are you instead of Hello?
All right.
What's going to happen?
So child inherits from mother and father.
Meaning it inherits the talk method that says hello.
And the other method that says, How are you?
So what will happen if grandchild wants to talk since it inherits from child, father and mother?
So let's make grandchild stop laughing and talk instead.
So what do you think it will do?
Will it say hello or how are you?
So let's execute it.
And it said hello.
So why so?
Because first inherited from father and then from mother.
So let's do the opposite.
Let's put mother and then father execute.
And instead of saying hello, it will say, How are you?
Which is a method of mother.
So this is because elements are searched for in ascending order.
We'll check this out by deleting this talk method and we'll print the grandchild class using one of
the special methods.
So remember, all methods containing double underscore are known as special methods.
So I want to use MRO, which stands for Method Resolution Order.
It is the order in which Python looks for a method in hierarchy of classes.
So what happens if I print the marrow of grandchild?
This is quite riveting.
So I want you to notice it.
Let's make some space here, and we'll see how grandchild searches for things as we ask for them.
For instance, the talk method.
I'll look for it in the grandchild class itself.
That is, if grandchild had a method named talk that says good morning instead of hello and how are
you?
It would print good morning since it would be the first place in which it would look for the talk method.
And if grandchild doesn't find that method there, it will try to find it in child.
That's the method resolution or the grandchild has.
It will go to child.
And if child has the talk method, it will be executed.
If not, grandchild will go up to the mother class.
Why?
Because mother inherits before father.
So that's where grandchild will look for the talk method.
If it finds the method there, it will print.
How are you?
And if grandchild didn't find the method there, it will continue with the father class, which is the
next in its hierarchy and print.
Hello.
And if it didn't find the method in that class it will go to class object which is there even if we
don't see it.
Class object is a class that organizes all classes below.
So notice that we have grandchild, child, mother and father.
And if we change this putting father first and then mother and we executed Maro.
We have grandchild, child, father and mother, thereby changing the hierarchical order.
So I find this captivating.
So as I told you earlier, this will help you reduce the need to type repetitive code, making your
programs lighter and more coherent.
In addition, you can do numerous things you wouldn't be able to do without inheritance.
So inheritance is one of the core concepts of object orientated programming.
We'll get to cover and develop the other concepts, but this is all for now.
So let's solve some exercises and see each other in the next lesson.