As you know, floats can have a lot of digits after the dot, and that's very useful when you need to
be very precise.
But it's a bit much when you want to be clear.
For example, if six friends and I spent $90 on a meal and they asked me to calculate how much each
one of us should pay, it would not be very practical for me to ask them for $12 and $8.
Trillion
571,482,571,429
of a set.
They're never going to invite me again.
That's why we use rounding.
And Python has a method called round, which allows me to remove as many decimal places as I want so
I can visualize and communicate my numbers much better.
The rounding syntax is as simple as telling Python.
Please round this number or round.
And then in brackets two parameters.
First, the number we want round here we can put a number in operation or even a variable.
And as we will see later, also a function that is the first parameter, the number that we want to
round.
The second parameter which goes after the comma is the number of decibel digits we want our result to
have.
If you don't put anything here, Python will consider that you don't want any decimal numbers after
the point by default.
Please note that round can round up or round down depending on which number is the closest.
So 5.3 will be rounded down because 5.3 is closer to five than six.
5.8 will be rounded up because it's closer to six.
5.5 is also going to round up.
That's the tipping point.
Let's take a look at this in practice in pie terms so we can really fully understand that and put it
into practice.
Let's see how this rounding thing behaves in Python.
Let's start by trying to print this operation that we just talked about in the example, dividing 90
books by seven people.
And if I run this choosing the round module, we will get 12.85, seven one, etc..
This is not really a number that we can socialize among our friends.
So let's try to write our value inside the round function.
So we open the brackets close to the end of the value and run it.
And now we're going to get 13 because 12.8 is rounded up because it's close to 13 and 12.
And the approach here was to apply the rounding function inside the print statement.
But what if we do it differently?
We also can we can store this value in a variable, for example, result.
And let's say it's value, it's around 90 divided by seven.
And inside the print statement, we only set result.
And what we are going to get is exactly the same.
Then we can do the rounding inside the variable or the printing time as we just saw.
Or we can also generate another new variable that's called rounding and it's equal to round result.
Well, there are a lot of ways to do it.
As long as somewhere in your round operation it's getting the value that it has to round.
It's going to work and it's going to be valid.
And now let's look at a different example.
We're going to eliminate all of this and we're going to write a new decimal number.
We're going to put it inside a variable called value.
And we're going to give it a content of 95.66, six, six, six, etc. a huge amount of stick.
And now I want to round this value, but not to the point of losing all my decimal values.
Let's say I want to see only two decimals.
Well, for that, the round function allows us to pass an argument to ask for that.
Let's type around.
Let's open and close the brackets.
And as Phil was telling you in the introduction of this lecture, round accepts two parameters.
The first one is mandatory is the value we want to round.
And the second one is optional.
We can add after the comma the number of decimal places that we want to get in our result.
If I say two and now I print it, we run it and it tells me 95.67.
Rounded up the second six.
If I put in here that I wanted three decimal places, it would show me three and so on.
That is round.
Always allows us not only to remove the decimals but also to choose how many you want to show.
Let's see something more.
Let's remove the number of decimals we're going to print again so that we can see only nine six is shown.
And now I'm going to print not only the value, but also the type of data that belongs to the value.
So what do you think?
I'm printing without any decimals, so it's going to show me something that looks as in entrega.
It will show 96.
Do you think that 96 is an integer or a float?
Let's see.
Let's run it.
And to your surprise, it's an intel.
If we do it the way we did it.
Notice I've created a variable that the content of the variable is the rounded number.
This makes it therefore an integer because it doesn't have any decimal places in it.
But now I'm going to do it differently.
Now I'm going to remove the round from the value variable.
Now the value of the value variable is in its number and I'm going to round it inside print.
So here I write round.
We're going to open the brackets and we're going to do it here.
So let's run this.
And now notice the result is the same as before 96 because we've rounded it in the print.
This time it also looks as an integer, but data type is no longer an integer.
It's a float.
Why is that?
Because when we do the rounding inside the variable, we're modifying the value itself, we're transforming
it into an integer inside the variable.
But when we do it outside the variable, like here where we are doing it at the same time of printing,
we are not modifying the value itself, we are just modifying the way it looks.
But we haven't changed the data type, which is still going to be a float because we've rounded it only
in the print instance.
How do you figure this out?
Because if I print it here again, we're going to print back the value.
But this time without rounding it is still appears to me is a number of type float but that if I ask
you again to give me the type of value you notice, it is still a float.
It never became an integer.
It would only be an integer if I round it inside the declaration of the variable.
I hope this helps you understand the dynamics in programming.
Thank you very much for joining us and we look forward to the next lecture.