I'm not going to say the solution to this challenge is complicated, but it is long.
There is a lot to write and I think it's better if we show it to you.
Broken down into steps.
In this first video, we are going to build the skeleton, the basic and linear structure that our code
should follow.
This way we will be able to better see what functions we need to build out to make the code flow as
expected.
So let's go over to pie term to start.
Start by generating the structure of our code in a non executable way simply to understand what our
functions and our executable code have to do later.
Let's say that our code will need a start menu from which the user can choose an option.
So we'll first show start menu.
And this is a function that will be in charge of organizing everything.
Here the user is going to choose something and we'll create a provisional variable which could be called
menu, where we will store the users choice and we will start the variable at zero, which is not an
option since the user can choose between one and six as said before.
Perfect.
So let's make a decision tree so that the system knows what to do according to the user's choice.
So let's say the F menu is equal to option one, which serves to read a recipe.
So what does the code have to do?
It has to have a function that first shows all the categories that exist.
After that, it has to have a second function to ask the user to choose a category.
The user will choose a category and another function is required that shows all recipes within that
category.
And then another function that lets them choose one of those recipes.
Finally, one last function responsible for reading the recipe chosen by the user.
And now the program should offer the user to go back to the start menu.
Go back to menu.
This is one more function you will need to create.
So why do we have to create all of these functions?
Because as some of these functions have to repeat themselves throughout different options, it works
better to have an executable code that we can call in different situations without having to type it
again and again.
Great.
Now we have option one from the menu and here we will type pass simply for Python to stop complaining.
So we can see that if the menu chosen by the user is option two, the one necessary to create a new
recipe something similar to what happened with option one will occur.
So let's show the categories and make the user choose one category and then add another variable to
create a new recipe.
And now again, go back to menu.
This way we can move on to the third option.
So what happens if the user chooses option three?
Option three serves for the user to create a new category.
Here.
There's no need for the user to see the categories and stuff.
We will simply begin with a function to create a category and that's it.
Also, we add go back to menu variable and move on to the next option.
So this is the option that activates if the user picks number four.
This option serves to eliminate recipes and here we will copy a lot from the beginning because this
option will be in charge of showing the categories, then choosing the categories, showing the recipes,
and finally choosing them.
Right.
Everything is almost the same.
So I will copy and paste.
The only thing that changes is read recipe to eliminate recipe.
Various methods or functions similar to those of option one will go here with the exception of the elemental
one, which is eliminate recipe we add path.
Then we have option five from the menu, which would be the one responsible to eliminate a category.
And this is also similar but just up to the beginning.
So it will need to show the categories and choose a category to then eliminate the category.
Then this go back to the beginning and we type pass to do so.
Finally, we have the last function which activates if the user chooses option six.
Its job is to end the program.
So here we type end program and we add pass here to avoid any complaints.
Very good.
So this is the structure of our code.
All we have to do now is to create functions that replace these blue lines so as to have an executable
code.
This is important whenever you type something whose tree would be hard to keep in your mind all the
time.
So working in this way is very organized and practical, and I think that if you continue working like
this, it will help you a lot.
So far, so good.
Now it's time to go to the following lesson where you will learn to create the initial code of our program
and the start menu.
I'll see you there.