In today's solution, Federico will show you first how to unzip the file with the instructions from
Python, and then how we have solved the instructions we found inside.
Let's go to it right now.
To succeed in today's challenge, first, we're going to work with a module to decompress the file.
That's all this module does.
And then once we have the instructions, we can work with the module Project nine, where I will write
the whole code to be able to deal with the instructions.
Well, inside the folder where I'm working with Python, I have already downloaded this zip file called
Project de nine, which I will unzip.
You can use either shuttle or zip file.
Both ways are valid.
I'm going to use shuttle so I type shuttle, unpack archive and here we have to put the name of the
file.
This one is called Project de nine dot Zip.
Keep in mind the capitalization of each word, otherwise it will not work.
Then we decide on the path where we want to download this file.
In my case, I'm going to download it in my home directory that is users and then Windows ten and then
desktop to leave it in my desktop, you can leave it wherever you want.
And of course this path will be different in each particular case.
Finally, we add zip, which is the file name that I will work with to decompress.
So let's run this.
And it doesn't show anything on the console, of course, but if I come to my desktop, there should
be a folder here called My Big Directory.
This came inside the zip and also a file called Instructions.
We open the file and read everything it asks us to do.
First of all, you will have to look for a serial number.
So let's do that.
Inside Project de nine or however you want to call this module, we're going to need almost everything
we've learned today.
We will start with the case inputs, which are E for regular expressions and we import OS to work with
files.
We will import time so we can measure how long the execution of the program lasted.
Following the instructions, we're also going to import date time, which will let us know today's date.
And from puff lib we rescue an old friend that is path to be able to create roots.
It will be very useful.
And finally, we import math to round up the execution time.
All these friends we have met today in addition to some older who are going to be incorporated into
our code.
So let's start with the variables.
We first write a path variable so that we don't have to write it later in the middle of the functions.
This is the path that should take us to the folder.
My big directory.
In my case I have it in my local disk, then in users, then in window ten.
I have it in desktop as well.
And finally it is called my big directory, all in capital letters.
This will be the path I'm going to work with.
I'm going to create the pattern we have to look for, which, according to the instructions, should
first have a letter N, then it should have three characters that are not numbers.
Thus we have to add a backslash and the letter D capitalized to indicate that it is a non numeric character.
This will give us letters and we're going to quantify these non numeric characters in three.
After that, a hyphen is required and then we will have to type in five numeric characters.
Now the D is going to be lowercase and we can't quantized it to five.
This is the pattern we need to check.
Still, we have to generate another variable called today.
This would be a date time date.
And here we have today.
Whatever day you are doing this exercise, when the program is executed, this variable will tell you
what day is, the day you're on.
So let's create two variables more which are the lists, which will store the serial numbers that we
find and the files that contain those numbers.
So the first list, one is going to be called numbers found equal to an empty list, and the second
is called files found.
These are also going to be an empty list for now.
And now we can start creating our functions.
The first function will be in charge of finding these serial numbers in a given file.
So it's going to be called find number to which a file should be passed, where the search will be carried
out.
Besides, a pattern will be needed for the function to know what pattern to look for.
As this function has to open the file, we have to create a variable that can be called this file,
which is equal to open.
And what are we going to open?
The file that we passed to it in the parameters of the function, and we'll open it with our mode so
that it is read only.
Then we need another variable which contains what is in the text.
Thus you can call it text equal to this file dot read, which is the read method.
And once we have the contents of this file inside text, we check if the regular expression search of
the pattern that we pass searched in the text we just extracted.
What do we concentrate on if it is true?
If so, that is if the pattern appears in a text will receive that pattern.
We will copy this.
And so we will receive whatever it is found.
And if not, we are going to ask for an empty string.
And why do we do this?
Because otherwise this will return a non object and our list will be filled with non objects.
This is an easier way to clean up our list and this was the first function we need.
The second one, which is complementary to this one, is in charge of creating the lists with the serial
numbers it finds and with the names of the files containing those serial numbers so we can name this
function create lists, which does not need parameters.
What it does need is a for loop that goes through all the folders, subfolders and files through the
walk method, which allows us to traverse all the folders in my great directory.
Then I'm going to go through all the folders, the subfolders and the function will check the files
it finds in OS walk and here we pass the path in brackets.
That's why we put it in a variable so that we don't have to write everything here and now.
What this loop is going to do for every file founded Colon is to store in a variable called result whatever
the find number function returns.
Now we call the function find number.
Just as we learned recently, we can call a function inside another one and store whatever is returned
in a variable in this case result.
Well, fine number asks for a file and the pattern.
What we will pass to it is a path composed by folder and by a.
This means that this path will be composed of the folder address.
Remember that folder stores a path and the name of the file in each case.
Here we have the file where for it to look for that number.
And we are still missing the pattern, which will be my pattern and the one I've created up here, which
will look for the serial number just like we want.
The results of this search for each file will be stored in the result.
Remember that this result or an empty string will be stored.
Once we receive that result, we will check if.
The result is different to an empty string.
So that's how we can clean up the results that we're not interested in.
Then only if that result is other than empty.
I mean, it contains a serial number.
We can call the list of numbers found append in order to add the result, but it won't store the result
just as it appears.
Because remember that that construction, which contains a lot of data, has from where to where the
result goes and it tells us what is an object.
No, we just want it to give us the group found in that result.
We also add the add the name of the file containing this result so that to create the other list we
call the list that we defined at the beginning files found and we add to it with point append and then
we add here is of the file, the title.
In doing so, we have achieved that.
When the execution of this function finishes, we have to complete lists, numbers found and files found.
With all the findings this function has done.
Finally, we need one more to show the results on the screen and organize the contents of these lists
within our tables.
We're going to format this with the function show, all which does not need parameters.
Create an index starting at zero.
A variable that will be a counter to go through our lists, indexes and print their contents.
Start printing.
And first we print a dashed line to create a kind of separator which you should repeat about 50 times.
Print out the date of this search and we can create a string literal that reads Date of search.
A colon.
A space.
What comes next is a construction.
Observe this for now.
I just put today inside a call.
We can call the show all function to see the whole process.
Run and run Project nine.
Here we have the 50 dashes, then date of search and it shows us the date time format, which is year,
month and day.
But I prefer month slash day slash year.
How do we do that?
We call today month and we add a slash and then another call to today day.
We put one more slash and finally we call today year.
And now this will display the way I want.
Date of search and today's date in the format I chose.
So let's move on.
We need a line break here to separate things slash RN and we can print the headers of our table.
We type in print and here we write in capital letters file.
So we're going to make some tabulations so that each title is separated from each other.
I can confirm that these three tabs will be enough.
You can try on your own to find out how many you need.
And now we write serial number.
Down here, we have to print some separators, just as you saw in the example on the instructions.
The separators will have as many dashes as letters.
We also have three tabs here.
And then we add dashes until we complete the length of serial number.
So this is the end of the header.
If we print it out, we already see file and the serial number.
What follows is to show the list of the results that we have found.
So how do we print them?
Well, make a four loop that iterates each of the elements in the list file's found.
We can say that for each a in file's found colon.
And what we do now is to print a line containing inside a string literal the contents of a which is
the title of the file.
And here we tabulate to jump to the next column, which is the serial number column, where we do a
call to what the numbers found, which is the list containing all the numbers.
But here, since we are not using the numbers found as indicator for the iteration, we will have to
put the index we are in at the moment.
So we've completed the line we need.
But before we exit the loop, we have to make the index add a value.
So the next loop shows index one and so on.
So if I print this, we won't see anything on the screen because neither create lists nor find numbers
have been executed yet.
So far, our format is empty.
It doesn't show anything, but we will close this by making a line break once all the records are displayed.
And then, according to the instructions, we should show all the numbers we have found and the time
it took.
We then print all the numbers found with a string literal that says numbers found colon.
And where do we get the value to know how many numbers were found?
It can be either numbers found or files found, as we should do with this.
With numbers found, we call the length of numbers found.
And this will give us, as a result, the number of findings we had.
Since we couldn't execute our functions yet.
It's going to tell us zero for now.
Then we have to give a count of how long this work took.
To do so, we make at the top before our whole program starts running a variable called START, which
is going to contain the timestamp of time, dot time so that we can evaluate later, closing the time
how long the work took us.
We go all the way back down here.
And before we report.
Here.
We have to cut the timestamp.
So let's create the variable end, which should be equal to time, time.
And then we have to calculate this with a variable that can be called duration, which is equal to end
minus start.
And this is what will give us the result, the time of how long our program lasted.
Print it as a string literal that says duration of the search colon space and here we call duration.
I want you to pay attention to one thing.
If I execute duration just as it is, it's going to tell us that the duration of the search is 0.04.
Now, this duration is quite short because we haven't executed the most time consuming functions yet.
But here I want you to focus on, as in the instructions rounding up in order to round duration up,
I have to put it in parentheses to be the argument of the call to math dot seal, which stands for rounding
up.
Even so, we still have zero because it doesn't have any value yet.
But now when we do absolutely everything we will get a different number.
We could add the word seconds here for the sentence to make more sense and we can finish with another
dashed line.
So let's see how this looks.
That's great.
Now we just need to call in order the functions that should be executed.
First we call create lists, which will store the two lists, allowing us to use them in show all,
which is the function that runs our program.
Has it worked as we expected?
Here we have date of search today's date.
Then we have files with the serial numbers we have found in that file.
And we can also see the amount 11 files.
See that?
Now, it did round up and told us that the search took one second.
We did it.
I also like this project because it really implies using almost everything we've learned today.
You've been able to put a lot of things into practice, so we're almost done with another day.
I really productive one.
It's time to have a break and relax to to think about today's achievements.
Congratulations.