We already have the base.
So now let's transform all of that into executable code.
In this second part of the solution to the Recipe Book Project, we will import the extra modules to
have all the necessary tools.
We will create the most important variable of this program, which is the path.
And finally, we will create two very important functions one that serves to count the recipes and the
recipes folder, and another to run the start menu, which is the backbone of our program.
Let's go over to Pie Charm to move forward with this project.
And now let's start with the second part of the creation of our program, whose skeleton we already
have and write the essential issues we need to move forward first.
The modules we have to export, we will need to import OS, which as you know is a useful module to
navigate through our files.
We're going to import from path lib the object path which is essential to create forgive the redundancy
paths.
Also from OS we're going to specifically import system, the one that allows us to clean the screen
and to eliminate everything we wrote previously.
Every time our menu restarts, it is a visual detail that I think is worth incorporating when programming.
So we're already to create the START menu and we will store it within a function, but we still need
to have a think what the start menu has to do.
It has to welcome, as we said, and then inform that the fire where the files are located, how many
recipes we have, and finally show the menu.
So we will need to build this star menu a variable that contains the path where the files are.
That's paramount.
So my path, this is the name of the variable is going to have a path inside which is composed of the
path home, which is to say the whole path that goes to the parent directory, which may vary from one
computer to another.
And the receipts folder where all the recipes are created are stored.
So I recommend that you should already have them in the parent folder, which is win ten.
In my case here I have the folder recipes with four categories we talked about earlier, each one containing
the two recipes that correspond to each category.
So there's no need for you to write all this content as if it were a real recipe in each of them.
I wrote, This is the recipe and that's it.
Just in an example to verify whether they are being read when we execute them.
So make sure to build that so that everything works properly when you start testing.
I have the variable my path.
Another thing the start menu will need is to show how many recipes there are, and I want to store it
within a different function.
Two, which is the first I'm going to create.
So this is going to be called count recipes and count recipes needs a parameter, which is a path,
and we will put inside this function a counter because if we want to count the recipes and we have a
record of them, a counter variable would be great.
So the counter variable will keep a record of everything we find using a for loop.
So for each text or each file you want to put here found in the path corresponding to the pathway of
pass to it, this loop will verify and look for all the files ending in text by means of the glob method.
Do you remember it?
And remember that the formula here is to type two asterisks and a slash before asterisks dot text so
that it searches not only within the recipes folder, but also in all the folders that I find inside
recipes.
So we type colon and what it's going to do every time it finds a text file, the counter will simply
increase a number in order to, at the end send us back through or return whatever this counter contains.
This way.
Every time I execute count recipes, I will be able to know the number of recipes my folder has.
This number will vary because our program creates or eliminates recipes.
Consequently, it's not a fixed number, so we're all ready to create our start menu.
And this will take time because it requires some visual stuff and there's a lot to write here, so let's
name it start.
So it doesn't need us to pass any parameter to it because it's the first thing executing in our program.
This has to clean the screen first because it's going to execute several times and every time the user
makes a choice or performs an action, this menu will go back to the beginning and when it happens,
we want the screen to be clean.
Thus here we type system and then in quotation marks.
Kels, because I'm working with Windows.
If you use Linux or any other system, you have to type clear instead.
So after that, I would like to print something on the screen.
Let's write something like Welcome to the recipe administrator.
So far, so good.
But for it to be more visible, we're going to add up here.
A divider made up of a chain of asterisks.
50 is enough.
And we will add some more down here to make it look a little bit better.
So see how everything looks on the screen.
And now we execute my recipes, which of course doesn't show anything because I haven't called start
yet.
If I do not call a function, the file's content will never execute.
So now it's okay.
Welcome to the recipe administrator.
So we need for the clear to work better.
So here it shows a little square because we haven't yet configured what inside the bug edit configurations
and here we choose emulate terminal in output console.
We executed again and now we clean this and see that a new banner has formed, which we will complete
by adding first and asterisks multiplied by five concatenating the welcome greeting and at the end also
concatenating with five more Asterix to make it even.
Let's see there OC perfect.
We still need a space before and after welcome.
But look how good our greeting looks.
We can do so much with so little.
Now we're going to do a little line break and tell the user where the files are.
To do so.
We'll create a string literal that says the recipes are in and we add a call that connects the user
to my path.
We will also tell them the number of recipes our folder has by means of another string literal that
reads something like Total Recipes, Colon Space, and then a call to the count recipes.
So we can invoke it from here and pass the my path variable as a parameter so that it can look for the
total number of recipes within my path.
So let's see if it works properly.
The recipes are in the location and total recipes.
Eight.
So since we have shown all the initial information, our next step consists of showing the options menu
and asking the user to select an option.
But since this menu has to show us itself repeatedly till the user chooses correctly, we will put inside
a wild loop.
We will say that while what we want doesn't happen, this will have to keep on repeating itself and
to know whether what we want is occurring or not.
We will create a variable that contains the information we need so the user will make a choice, so
we will store it in the menu.
Choice variable the value x, y x because an incorrect choice it is an option the user cannot use.
In this way.
We make sure the first time the program is executed we can enter the while loop and show the menu.
As long as the user's choice does not meet the conditions we need, it will continue repeating itself
till the user chooses.
Right.
So let's set up the wild loop by creating a condition that checks whether or not the user has chosen
a letter because we expect them to pick a number.
Therefore we say while not menu choice through the is numeric method which serves to check whether the
content is a number though it is in a string.
This is one of the methods you have to discover on your own, maybe other ways to solve it, but I think
it is the most practical.
So another aspect to verify is if the user has picked a number between one and six.
That's why we also add or because two are the conditions to be met.
Keep in mind that menu choice is not within a range that goes from 1 to 7 because the last number is
not inclusive.
And by putting a seven, we make sure that it goes up to six.
These are the options.
But as the user will pass through a string, the menu choice we have to cast it into an int and this
is how it should look like.
We will close the console so that you can see better.
And we add coal on here and this is the condition we have to ask for the loop to keep repeating itself
over and over.
What the loop is going to do is to show the menu.
So we print in here, choose an option colon and now we jump into the part where we print the menu print
and we type three quotation marks to do line breaks here and write everything down here.
The first option is read recipe.
The second one is create new recipe.
And afterward the third option comes, which is create new category.
The fourth option, eliminate recipe option five, eliminate category.
And finally, option number six, leave the program.
So I think everything is okay once it finishes showing us all the options.
What is still missing is the user's input.
Now is when we have to overwrite the content of menu choice, the same variable like the one above with
the user's input.
And we get out of the loop only if the user enters what is right.
And lastly, we put return menu choice.
If we execute it, we will see the options.
And I could intentionally choose something wrong.
For example.
Ah, I see.
All again I choose eight and again.
And if I choose one the program is over because I chose an option.
That was correct.
We could stop here and go to the next lesson to work with the functions we still need to complete our
code.
We have the beginning and the receipt counter, so see you in the next lesson.