Another small, yet very useful function is the enumerator, which in Python we call enumerate its function
is to make our life easier when we need to access the indexes of a collection.
For instance, if we are writing a for loop in which we need to access both the object and a list and
their index numbers, then the enumerator will come in handy.
While we already are able to access the indexes of a list or a string with the knowledge we already
have.
Enumerate will simplify this process significantly.
Let us demonstrate it for you in Petrom.
Right, let's start by creating a loop in which we need to access the indexes of the elements of a list
with the elements we have so far.
We would do it in the following way.
We will first create a list, for example, one that has the letters A, B and C, and then we would
need to create another variable that is called, for example, index with a value of zero.
And now we go into the for loop and we say for each item in list, for example, print index, which
right now is going to be zero.
And the item itself, which is going to be each of the items in our list.
And we should also make sure, of course, that each iteration of our loop index gets added one more
value at a time.
So it's changing along the whole for loop.
So we run this, we come to run where we're going to see enumerator and here we have zero A, one B
and two C.
Perfect.
We've been able to access both the index and the item, but this is not the best way to do it in Python
because we have to learn how to use enumerator or enumerate.
We're going to be able to do it in a much more elegant way.
What we would have to do here is to remove the index.
We don't need it.
And let's say that instead of accessing list here, what it accesses, let's put this in parenthesis
is an object of type enumerate.
This contains list and then we don't need this last line either and we don't need to put the index here.
So we're going to print each one of the complete items so that you can see what the numerator contains
when we put our list inside of it.
So we've run it and it has a series of tables that each contain first the index and then the object.
So here we have where to extract the information we want.
If we want it to print a certain element of these tables, as we saw before, we can separate here into
two variables so that the first one contains the index comma and then the item.
And here we also print index and print item.
And what we see now is zero A, one B to C the way we had it before.
But look at the code.
It's much more synthetic and therefore much more efficient.
With enumerate, you can not only work with strings or lists, you can also work with integers.
If you want to create here, for example, instead of a list, a range from 50 to 55.
Look what happens if we print this.
We have index zero for 50, index one for 51, and so on.
We have created our collection automatically enumerate super handy and we not only use this in loops,
we can also use it outside of a loop.
If we want.
You can use it so that the list contains A, B, and C is transformed in a list of tables instead of
a list of strings.
A list of tables that contains in each table the object and the index.
Well, it's all very simple.
So let's go step by step.
The enumerate would have list inside, but we have to make a casting with all of this so it is transformed
into a list.
So we put it all in the parentheses and at the beginning we put list and now we have our tables in a
list, but we are going to store it in a variable that we can print.
We're going to store it in my tables, and then we're going to print my tables and we're going to see
it on the screen.
And here we have the our list.
ABC became a list that has three tables, zero A, one B to C.
We already know how to unpack these tables if we want to access them.
If, for example, I want to get to find index one here, I would have to go inside my table's access
index one, which is where this table is located.
And after that access index zero, which is where the first element of my table is located.
I run it and here I have the one and we have managed to extract.
We can get to any element in this way.
So when you want to access the indexes of an iterable object, consider enumerate as it does in a simple
and inexpensive way.
Thanks again and see you in the next lecture.