In this last part of the solution for the DE Six project, we are going to put the finishing touches.
We are going to create the most specific functions such as those for deleting or creating files.
And then we are going to organize the startup of our program so that it functions as we want it to.
I'll see you in Pie Charm.
And in this part of the video we're going to complete what would be the most specific functions, the
read recipe, create recipe, delete recipe functions and so on.
And we're going to start creating a function that allows us to read a recipe.
And here we're going to start using all the methods that we have learned.
This one is very simple read recipe.
We're going to have to pass it just the recipe so that it can take the element and read it.
And the only line here is a screen print of a path to which we apply the red text method, the one to
read a file, and inside the parentheses we pass the recipe that has been passed to this function.
This is all that this function needs and it is ready.
So we replace it here with read recipe.
Then we'll pass my recipe, which is what has already been chosen in the previous one.
And this is the only place where this function exists.
So let's make it collapse.
And now go to option number two, the assets to create a new recipe.
So we need to create a function for this create recipe.
Create recipe will require us to pass it a path to know where a recipe has been created.
The path is the one that we're going to have in my category for having generated it.
When we typed chose category to create recipe, we first check if the recipe we're creating already
exists because we could be repeating something that already exists.
So we create the variable called exist, which is equal to false, which is what will let us make a
loop until we can create a new name.
And here comes a loop that says While it doesn't exist, this is the condition that allows it to keep
returning to this loop.
Until we create a new name Colon, we print something on the screen for the user to know what to do.
We type right the name of your recipe, colon space and below we save recipe name and this variable
which will contain the input of the user in which we shouldn't put anything since we already put it
above in the print.
Then we concatenate the input with dot text to complete the name.
Then we print something else.
We're going to ask the user to write the recipe.
Write your new recipe, colon and space.
We're going to store this in recipe content.
This is another variable equal to another input that we leave like this.
We already have two elements to build the new recipe that the user is going to generate.
And finally, we create a new path to create this new recipe that will be equal to a path which is the
route we had, which reaches the category and which is going to be concatenated with recipe name to
build the complete route that includes our new recipe.
So now we have to check if it doesn't exist, then we apply the exist method from OS, but using the
not to do the negation then if not os dot path dot exists and we open brackets inside there.
We need to check if the new path exists, which we have just created, and then if it does not exist,
call the object path and apply the method right text which is a method of path that although we did
not see it specifically in the course for path, we did see it, but without using this object anyway,
you could have discovered it among the methods of path which was part of this instruction.
What this method is going to do is to write a new text made up of a path that is new path and a second
parameter that is the information there has to be a string and that this recipe content, these are
the two variables that we have generated and we print it so the user can see it, otherwise they will
not know what it is they have already created.
And it is going to say here your recipe, then we name the name of the recipe has been created and we
have our recipe.
Now we're going to make the condition of the variable exist change so it is not looped.
Again, we change it to true and in case it does exist we tell the user with a print sorry, that recipe
already exists and the loop will initiate again.
So far I'm done with this function because this function doesn't have to return anything.
It simply has to create the new recipe.
And then we type create recipe here, create recipe to which we have to pass my category so that the
software knows in which category it is going to generate it.
The next one is very similar function.
We need a.
Function that creates a category and the function is so similar that we just copy it and readapt it.
This is a much easier way of working.
So this will be called create category, which needs a path we will let exist be false initially.
As long as it doesn't exist, it's going to enter the loop and say the new category.
And we put here a category name where we start an input to which we don't have to add text.
In this case, we don't need a second variable here because the category does not have any content.
Now let's create a variable called New Path that has the path to category name so as to use such path
right here.
This if we'll check whether this new path exists, then through the path it is going to call another
path method which is called MK Dear, which stands for Make Directory because we want to create a new
category, a new folder.
So what will be in the new folder?
The one stored in new path?
And what are we going to print?
A phrase that says your new category and we right here, the name of the category that is stored in
the variable category name that has been created exist becomes true.
And in case it already exists, we're going to say sorry, that category already exists.
So we have another important function and we put it here replacing create category and as a parameter
it needs that we pass it a path, which is another thing in my path, starting almost from zero and
we're nearly finished now.
We need the function in charge of deleting a recipe.
Let's create it up here.
This will not cause much difficulty either, because we're going to call it delete recipe.
This function, of course, needs to know which recipe we want to delete, so we're going to pass it
a parameter called recipe.
We're going to make that through path.
That is what takes the element that between parentheses it says recipe, the one we pass, it is going
to apply the method unlink the one used to eliminate the file.
I think this is going to be enough.
It's already eliminated and we still need to tell the user that we have done it.
We will put a print that says with a string literal the recipe.
We pass the name of the recipe recipe name so that it only puts the name and not the whole path has
been deleted.
By doing so, we finish with this other function.
It doesn't have to return anything.
Just print that on the screen and here we can pass the call to the function delete recipe which needs
to know what recipe we're going to pass.
Which is my recipe, the one that has been generated with all the functions that we have allowed the
user to choose a recipe.
So we still need another function that can delete a category.
And we're going to come down here and let's put death delete category.
This function needs us to pass it what category we want to remove.
So we pass it a parameter category and we take a path element that has the category that we have passed
to it, to which we have to apply a path method that is called MDR, which means remove directory and
which we have seen throughout the videos.
So we've removed that category and we still have to tell the user with a string literal the category
and we put a call to category name.
Again, this is very similar to what we've done before has been removed.
Well, this is taking a lot of time, but we're getting to the end now because this is the last specific
category we need to include here.
So let's type here, delete category.
That's the call and we feed it with the category chosen in the previous function.
So my category means that we're done with this.
We only need a function that allows us, in all cases to return to the beginning and something to finish
the program.
So we'll do it very quickly.
So going back to the beginning is going to be a function that is simply called return to the beginning,
and it doesn't need parameters, of course.
And what it does is ask the user to press a key, for example, B So since the user could enter another
letter or a number and we don't want that to happen, let's make a variable named return choice which
is going to be initialized as X and then we'll start a wild loop that says as long as return choice
apply lower so that whatever the user enters is valid.
So as long as it's different from the value that is b, the loop will keep on repeating non stop and
here inside the loop.
In order for the user to enter a good value, we'll call the variable return choice to rewrite it with
an input provided by the user.
Here, we should be clear that what we need is that after a line break they press B to return to the
menu.
A colon and a space for the user to type.
And this is the whole function we put it here.
We call it back to the beginning.
Here to.
Also here.
I'm finally here.
And in this last one.
And then to finish the program, we don't need a function.
Just write it.
Because the only thing to do here is to generate a variable that has a true value.
For example, finish program.
This one does not yet exist yet, but we can declare it as true.
This is the only thing that will happen when the user chooses six.
We should remove all these paths and they are no longer needed and not part of the program.
They served for, if not to complain when we had nothing.
So, look, we're almost done now.
We have to do some things first.
Here, we have to initialize the program properly.
Let's first set this variable that we just created.
Finish program is going to be equal to false.
To make sure that we always enter the loop that we're about to generate so that all this can repeat
over and over again.
And here comes the loop, which tells us that as long as end program is not true and we leave it like
that now we select all of this and press tab to tab selecting it and pressing tab once to tab, and
now everything is inside the loop.
Well, what's going to happen inside this loop?
First, this menu that we have created, which is to store the user's choice, is not going to be equal
to zero, but equal to start, which is the function that starts the whole game.
This calls the menu and asks for a number.
We use a pixel number and it's going to ask you to choose a number triggering all this stuff we have
here.
I would say the program is ready.
It looks unbelievable.
We've worked a lot on this video has been quite long.
So I invite you to go to the next video to prove if the program works.
Correct, if there is anything wrong that we need to be corrected and congratulate ourselves for the
hard work.
So I look forward to seeing you in the next video.