We already understood the theoretical concept of object oriented programming and what a class is.
Now we are going to see how we use object oriented programming in Python.
The first thing is to create a class and we will use the bird as an example for this.
Classes are defined with the keyword class in lowercase and then the name we want to give the class
in our case bird.
Then a colon by convention.
The name of the class begins with a capital letter.
And if it is composed by many words, let's suppose it was called Element Bird.
The blank spaces are omitted, joining directly all the words and capitalizing the first letter of each
word.
Then we'll write its internal code, starting with a tabulation.
And if I put pass inside, we already have a minimal class created.
This would be an empty class without much practical use.
But it is the minimum class that we can create.
I only put pass so that it does not give me an error.
Now that we have the class, although it is empty, we can create an object of the bird class.
We can do it as if it were a normal variable.
So we write the name of the variable, for example, my bird equal to the class with parentheses.
In this case, the parentheses are empty.
But later on we will see that the class may require arguments to be created and we will load them inside
the parentheses.
But for now, we're going to leave them empty.
Join Federico and Pi Charm to create together your very first basic class.
So we'll start by declaring a super basic class, which starts with the key word class that tells Python.
Well, what we're going to type next is a class.
So then we'll give it a name conventionally.
It'll start with uppercase and it'll be named Bird.
So let's type Colon and begin with today's class.
So since we don't know what to do inside a class yet, we'll just type pass so we don't receive an error
message.
What you see here is a class bird is just the definition of an abstract concept.
Now we can create bird type objects which don't do anything.
They don't chirp, fly or lay eggs, and they don't have features like color or height.
This is just an existing entity.
So if I want to create the bird type object that is a class instance, I'll do it with a variable such
as my bird.
And my bird will be equal to a bird type object.
Here will type brackets as to indicate this as a bird type instance.
So I don't have just a class now, but an instance named my bird.
And I want you to ruminate on the following.
So far, we've been using variables for storing base python data, such as strings, floats, dictionaries,
lists, and others because they are Python built in objects.
This means they're contained in Python standard library.
However, we're creating new objects now, and they are also types of data.
In fact, my bird contains a type of data that is not a string or an integer, but a bird.
You have declared it.
So what if I want to execute this code?
Well, I won't have anything at first because there's no executable line here.
There's just a class declaration and instantiation.
Nothing will be executed on the screen.
So let's print my bird in order to see it on the screen.
And we'll see.
There is a bird, which is an object that's located here.
But what happens if I print a bird data type?
This is what I was talking about.
So we'll print the type of my bird.
So what will be shown on screen?
The software will tell us.
The data type of My Bird is a class main bird.
We'll find out what main bird means soon.
So bear in mind, there is no string dictionary or integer but a bird, which is a data type I've just
created.
Right.
Let's move on.
So I declared a variable that contains a bird here.
And so there's a bird in my program context.
Let's create another bird, shall we?
I can create all the birds I want, and each of them will be a different object.
This will be named another bird and it will be equal to bird.
And it's brackets.
So we'll print another bird and delete the bird type, since we don't want to keep saying it.
And we'll see how these two birds we've created from the same class look like.
So we have two bird type objects.
One is located here and the other is located here.
Here.
We can see they are two different entities with the same bird class.
So do you want to keep on watching birds create Tweety?
Donald Duck.
Penguin.
The ones you like.
They will all be different objects.
If we had a more challenging task, we could make them interact with one another.
So far we've created two birds and we'll create an empty abstract base class to which we'll start adding
attributes in the next lecture.
So don't be late.
I'll see you there.