So you already know how to open a screen in which your game can be executed.
Next step is learning how to customize such screen.
In this lesson, we'll change the by game default icon.
This title and the background color.
This code will be long and contains several compliments.
Therefore we'll leave comments so as to always remember the task carried out by every block of code.
This is used to initialize PI game and this line is used to create the screen and this is the game loop.
So let's move forward with our code.
Always clarifying the intended function of each block.
Remember that this is really useful.
We'll adjust the title and icon settings before the loop.
So here we'll type title and icon.
Now let's call PI Game and you'll notice that every time we change something regarding our PI game,
library will need to start by calling PI Game dot, followed by something else in this case display.
Now we'll call set caption which will give us the window title that will appear here.
This will be named Space Invasion.
You can pick any name you want and if we execute this, we can read space invasion up there.
This needs a proper icon now, which we can find on the internet.
Of course I use flat icon, but you can use any of the page to search for PNG and other types of images.
I'm not related to flat coin, it's just a page I use.
As you can see, I'm searching for UFOs and I'll choose this one.
And if I click on this image, I can download it in different sizes.
I'll choose 32 pixels, which is the right size when using icons, not big drawings.
So now I click here and this downloads the image in my computer.
I'll save the image in the same folder I'm working with in Python.
So I'm going to drag the image right to the folder containing the main program and notice that in pie
charm we can see that besides main in day ten I also have UFO, which means I can use it.
Its name is UFO, P and G.
So let's store this image in a variable so as to use it.
From there the variable will be named icon and will be equal to pi game dot image, dot load.
And that's how we store the image in the icon variable.
And how can we change this image into an icon for our window like this pie game, dot display call set
icon and pass icon to it, which is the name of the variable containing the image.
And if I execute it, I can see the little alien beside the title space invasion.
So what I want to do now is to change the default background color, which is black.
So let's position ourselves inside the for loop because everything that will be updated in our game
has to be inside the game loop.
And let's call the screen variable, the one we created before and the fill method fill will require
us to enter a combination of colors in our GB format.
So in case you're not familiar with this, our GB stands for Red, Green and blue.
Here you have a web page in which you can learn how to use it.
Just add values to red, green and blue, and this will make all possible colors.
If we enter zero here, we make black.
For instance, if we enter the highest number in green, which is 255, will create vivid green.
And if we want to use blue instead of green, we just enter 150 and that's it.
So if we add 150 in red, we make violet, and that's how we can create colors.
So let's create the tuple containing three values inside screenshot fill where we can enter our GB.
I'll pick a color I really like and it's a kind of violet.
You can choose any color you want, of course.
So we're likely to change colors as we move forward anyway, and that way we'll be able to combine them
better with the rest of the elements.
All right.
If I execute this, my color doesn't appear.
That's why I typed it inside the loop.
It's a command that requires the screen to be updated in order to change this green color.
So after establishing this green color will call PI game display update.
And we'll use this method after choosing the background color to update our screen.
And here we can see our screen with the color I picked.
Now this looks better.
Our program is getting better.
You don't want to.
Ms..
What's next?
So I'll see you in the next lesson.