It's time to set up our application structure, which, as you can see, will be divided in three big
sections top panel, left panel and right panel.
The top panel will only contain the main title, and that's all in the left panel.
We're going to put two submenus.
The one above will include lists of food, drinks and desserts, and the one below will include costs
in the right panel.
We're going to add three sections.
Top section will be a calculator.
The middle section will be the printed check and the bottom section will be a couple of buttons with
which we can use our app.
So let's begin with the top panel of our app.
We'll type top panel and create a variable named top panel which will be equal to frame, which is a
t k into class, used to create frames in which we can add more elements.
Now we have to add some settings inside its brackets.
So let's start with location, which will be application.
It will have a very thin edge.
Ed, let's put one because I'm I'm fond of minimalism and will add a relief which contains five options
flat raised, sunken groove and Ridge.
So this lets you configure the 3D effects on the edges of the panel.
You should try all of them and see which ones you like the most.
I prefer flat since it's the minimalist one.
So now that I've decided how my panel will look, I'll put it inside my application.
So I call top panel pack and I'll input in the brackets where I want to place my panel side equals top
and let's execute it.
And the top panel is not visible.
Why so?
Because we haven't set up any size and we haven't added any element.
So here it is.
It's just a tiny white pixel that you may not see.
But don't worry, we'll make it visible soon.
So what are we going to add to our panel?
The title, which will be inside a title tag.
And let's create the title tag variable which will be equal to another t k enter element, which is
label and we'll set it up.
So where are we going to put our title in top panel?
Then what text will it contain?
Well, text equals invoicing system.
So what about font colour?
Will define this with FG, that's foreground and I'll choose Azure four, which is one of the options
from the table of colours that you can use in TK Enter.
So I'm going to press enter so as not to exit the screen.
As long as we are inside the brackets, we won't move to the next line.
So let's choose a font type with the font property and now we open brackets to define this.
I'm going to choose Dosis and you can pick whatever font type you like.
So the size will be 58 and this will be the title fund.
So it has to be big.
The background BG will be the same as before Burley Wood and now we need the tag width, which will
be 27.
So I got this number after running some tests as well.
All right.
I've designed the tag so I can call title tag, dot grid, and we can create a kind of grid inside the
top panel.
Then we can choose which row and column a tag will be in, since our tag will be the only element inside
the panel will simply put zero in row and column.
So this may be a little confusing, but as soon as we configure the other panels, you'll understand
the role played by rows and columns.
So we have a title tag ready.
Will we be able to see something on the screen there?
It is awesome.
We have the top panel and it's nice edges.
So far so good font and background go well together too.
Okay, let's keep on creating elements.
Now it's time to create the menu, which is the left panel.
Let's type left panel here.
And this panel will have its own variable so as to create another frame like we did before.
And let's set the left panel up so as to add to it application, because this panel will be outside
the top panel.
The left panel will have the same edges and relief as the top panel.
And now we have to place it somewhere by typing left panel pack.
And the side of this panel will be left, since it has to be on the left side of the screen.
So if we printed it now, we'd see a tiny white spot again.
So let's continue with our configuration.
So here should go the cost panel, which contains subtitles and all that.
So Cost panel will be a variable named cost panel that is equal to a frame which will go inside left
panel.
The edges of this frame will also be equal to one and its relief will be equal to flat as well.
So let's place it somewhere on the screen by putting cost panel pack and.
This time it will be on the bottom side of our left panel.
Now, let's continue with food panel, which, as you can see, should be on the top left corner of
the left panel.
So food panel has a variable named food panel, which is equal to a label frame element.
It's neither a label nor a frame, but a label frame.
We're talking about a frame which contains a built in tag.
So we'll place it on the left panel and the tag will contain a text reading food.
So let's choose a font by using font, which will be equal to doses in brackets.
Its size is 19 and it's in bold, comma and enter.
Its edge will be equal to one.
And relief will be equal to flat.
Foreground will be equal to zero four.
And food panel is ready.
So let's call the food panel pack so as to place it.
This panel will be inside the left side of left panel, and that's it.
The following one is the drink panel, which will be quite similar.
So let's copy and paste.
I'll pass on a handy tip to replace food with drink, so I have to position myself at the end of one
of them.
Press alt and without releasing click on the end of each food and I have several cursors.
Then I can delete and type drink.
And I just did that once, but I could change all the words I selected if I wanted to.
This is a label frame that goes on the left panel and it should say drink, starting with a capital
letter.
Its characteristics should be exactly the same as before, and it should go to the left, too, because
this panel was placed on the left.
This other panel will be further to the left.
So now we have to create the dessert panel.
Copy and paste.
Select delete and type dessert.
The rest is just the same except for this, which just starts with a capital letter.
So in case you're wondering how this looks like, we can execute it.
And here we have our tiny little spot containing all the panels.
Soon we'll be able to see them.
The time has come for us to create the right panel.
So let's open a call to right panel containing a variable named right panel.
And let's add a frame which will be stored in application.
Its edges will be equal to one and its relief will be equal to flat.
So let's type right panel pack so as to place it on side equals.
Right.
And that's it.
Keep in mind that right panel contains three elements a calculator, a check, and some buttons.
So let's create the calculator panel first and its variable calculator panel.
This element will be equal to a frame whose location is right panel.
Its edge is equal to one and its relief is equal to flat.
We also want its background to be the same as the one we've used before, which is Burley Wood.
Now we have to place it, so calculate the panel pack, but we don't have to type anything here.
Why?
Because this panel will be placed on the top section by default.
Let's copy, calculate the panel and create a last two panels.
Let's make several selections so as to type in voice panel, which is the middle one.
So this is a frame of the right panel.
Its edge background and location are the same as before.
Since the top section has been used, this will be placed automatically.
And now our last panel, let's make multiple selections and type button panel and let's leave the rest
as it is and let's check if it works.
Here we have a window which doesn't show anything we've done so far, regardless of all our hard work.
But don't get upset.
Everything that we've created is ready to be displayed in the following lesson.
Only the final touches are missing.