Welcome to the lesson on NumPy.
This is one of the cornerstones of data science.
If you want to work with python applied to data science, you will need to know NumPy, which is the
standard library for performing large scale numerical operations.
NumPy is very powerful.
It has a lot of methods and properties to work with operations and numbers.
It has some elements that we have not known so far, which we are going to go into right now.
First of all, I'm going to emphasize that you should visit the official numpy documentation.
I'll leave you a link in the resources.
And it's very important to know it and to know how to navigate it, because numpy is so huge that we
could never cover it in a course no matter how many 100 hours we give it.
Here you will have everything you need to know how to get the most out of this powerful tool for data
science.
So what you're seeing on the screen is a notebook that I have written, especially for you to get to
know NumPy.
You will be able to connect to this notebook through the link that I will leave in the resources to
access it.
It is in a drive document and you will be able to have it at your fingertips, but you will not be able
to edit it because if all the students edited it, it will be destroyed in half a day.
So you're going to have to have a copy.
So you'll be able to click on the button here which says copy to drive.
And from then on you'll be able to go to write on a copy of this document that you'll have stored on
your own device.
Here, below the instructions.
Let's start by importing into NumPy and we'll do that using the nickname so we can refer to NumPy as
NP.
So we type import numpy as NP.
Now we can call numpy just by typing NP and remember that this import is not implemented until we run
this cell.
Well, let's get to know one of the most important elements in numpy, which are arrays.
An array is an array of data organized in different dimensions.
This will start out as something similar to lists, but you'll see that as it gets more complex, you'll
notice the difference clearly.
So let's write our first array.
We're going to call it a1d array because it's going to be a one dimensional array.
And for that reason, we can say that this array is going to be very similar to a list.
So this variable is going to contain an object and p dot array.
And in brackets, we're going to create a list that has the numbers one, two, three, four and five
in it.
This is an array that has only one dimension.
What do we mean by one dimension?
It has one length, which is five units.
And that's the only dimension it has.
We will see what the other dimensions of an array can be.
If we want to create the two dimensional array, we will create another array called array two DX and
it will be the same as an NP of type array, which will contain a list that contains in turn two lists.
Then we put brackets again to write the first of these two lists, which is going to contain one, two
and three.
This is the first element of this two dimensional array, but it's missing its second dimension.
So after the brackets that enclose this first element, we're going to put a comma.
If you want, you can press enter to visualize it a little bit better.
And here we will write the second list, of course, in square brackets, which will contain four,
five and six.
You're already looking at a two dimensional array here.
I'm declaring it, but we're not yet seeing how it's going to look on screen.
But I want you to have the notion that the two dimensions are the two lists that we have inside our
array.
The dimension that array has is two by three because it is like a table that is too high.
The two rows and three wide because it has three columns.
But we can also create arrays of three dimensions.
We can write array three D, which is going to be equal to an NP array.
And this first is going to have a set of square brackets to wrap all the content and the whole array.
Then come the square brackets that serve to enclose the first table like this one above, which is a
two by three table.
In fact, let's copy that table so we don't have to write it all over again.
So I copy and paste it here.
After this second bracket, we put a comma because our second table is coming up.
Here we open the brackets for the second table, and now we open the square bracket.
It's for the first line of that table, which is going to have the numbers seven, eight and nine.
So after closing this bracket, we put comma to write the second line of this second table.
I hope you're not getting dizzy.
And here we're going to put the numbers that follow, which would be ten, 11 and 12.
So as you can see here, I have slightly more complex drawing.
But if you analyze where each of the brackets open and close, you will see that we have two tables,
each contained with six numbers.
And each of these tables is too high by three wide.
In total, our three D array has 12 elements organized in a two by two by three layout, i.e. two tables
of two rows and three columns.
Okay, let's run it.
So all this exists in the compiler.
Now I want you to see this statement that says that for each of these arrays, we can get its properties,
such as its shape, its number of dimensions, the data type and the size.
Let's see how we can get this information for each of these arrays.
We do this with properties, for example, with array one D and we use DOT to call its properties.
We're going to ask it to show us the shape property, then to do the same array.
We're going to ask it to show us its number of dimensions with the property n dim.
We're also going to ask it to show us its data type through D type, and we're also going to ask it
to show us its size.
And we can add one more, which is the type of array one D.
If we run this, we get the following first its shape, which is five wide and nothing more.
It has no other dimensions.
Then after the comma there is nothing.
It's a single element tuple that tells us that the shape of this array is five elements along, but
it has no height or depth.
Then the number of dimensions tells us that it has one, as we already know, and the type of data that
our array has are integer values.
The size is five because it has five elements and the type of this array is a numpy and the array.
So that's what we get when we ask for its attributes.
So let's do the same for the 2D and 3D arrays.
Changing here, the variable names, there are quite a lot of them and we run it and here we have that
shape is two in height and three in width.
First report the height.
It has two dimensions.
It has the same data types.
It has six elements.
And it's the same data type.
So now let's switch to 3D, but with multiple cursors.
I'm perfect.
We run it and it's going to show us that the shape is too deep, i.e. it has to tables by too high and
three long.
It has three dimensions.
They are also integers and it has 12 elements and it is also the same data type.
So now we're going to import PANDAS.
Just to give you a glimpse so that you can see what pandas is.
Pandas complements Python very well.
It's another library for manipulating analysing data in Python.
It is built on top of NumPy, so a lot of functionality is similar.
And we're going to use pandas to work with structured data sheets, structured data sheets, organized
information in rows and columns, but no longer in an imaginary way, as we do with a raise in NumPy,
we actually in a kind of spreadsheet.
In fact, if you are familiar with Excel, we can say that PANDAS is the Excel of Python.
So now let's import Pandas with import pandas as PD as nickname.
And we're going to create a variable called data that contains a PANDAS data frame.
Let's create a structure dataframe from our to the array and let's see what gets formed here.
So we call data so that it can be printed.
We will not sell and look what we get back.
Now it is clear that PANDAS is the excel of NumPy because it organized our array which had these six
elements in two dimensions of height and width.
This time in columns and rows, putting in its headers and index, which always starts from zero of
the rows and columns.
In the next lesson, we're going to know more about pandas.
But I wanted to show it to you just so you can see what it does.
So now let's create an array of size four by three.
And made up of only ones.
We could write all of those ones manually, one by one.
But we're going to do it in a simpler way.
We're going to create a variable called ones containing a numpy dot ones to which in brackets we're
going to put a tuple where we put its dimensions, which, as we said, will be four high and three
wide.
So we call ones run our cell and we get an array that's automatically created containing a four by three
table with all our ones in there.
If we wanted it to be zero and it was three dimensions two wide, four high and three long, we would
do it like this.
We would say zero is equal to an NP dot zeros and in parentheses we put the dimensions in a tuple two
wide for high and three long.
We call zeros so we can see it.
And here we have our two dimensional array, the front table and the back table, and both four by three,
all with pure zeros.
And now let's see how we can create an array of numbers that goes from 0 to 100, but jumps from 5 to
5.
There are methods to do that, too.
So we're going to create an array that we're going to call array one, which is going to be equal to
numpy arrange that has the following information in parentheses from 0 to 100 and that jumps from 5
to 5.
So we call array one and here we have a one dimensional array which goes from 0 to 95 because 100 is
not included.
If we put one one now, we would find the 100 at the end of our array.
We also create an array of integer random numbers between zero and ten with two dimensions two by five.
And we don't need to import random because numpy includes a whole module of random numbers.
So we create an array too, which is equal to NP random, which is already built in random to have random
integers and we're going to make them between zero and ten.
And the third value or parameter is a tuple with the dimensions of our array which is going to be too
high and five long.
We call a rate to execute our cell.
And we find this array of random numbers.
The funny thing is that if we run this cell again, every time we run it, we're going to get different
numbers because they're random numbers.
We can also create an array of decimal random numbers ranging from 0 to 1 of size three by five.
So how do we do this?
Just like with the random library, we can create an array three which is equal to NP random, but this
time we don't call random what we call random.
So if you remember, random brings numbers between zero and one but decimal.
And the parameters we need here are just the dimensions.
Three high by five long.
So we call a ray three to see it.
And we have here our three by five array with these numbers that keep changing if I run it again and
again.
So one thing to consider is that the random numbers are not real random, but generate an illusion of
randomness because it changes what is called the seed that says where the selection of numbers starts
from.
And in fact, we can set the seed to a fixed number.
So let's actually do that by setting that NTP dot random dot seed.
And we set it to 27.
Now I'm going to create the next random, which is going to be in an array of random integers between
zero and ten with dimensions of three by five.
So we already know how to do this.
We create array four, which is equal to np random dot random.
And we're going to ask it for numbers ranging from 0 to 10 and it's going to be a three by five table.
And we run array for.
And look at this array.
We've got those numbers in there, so write them down.
And if we run it again, we have the same numbers.
This is because we have set the seed to the same number and seemingly random numbers stopped appearing.
So what happens when we run the last seed again?
Well, this is different from the previous ones because now our seed is stuck in one place.
So this is the first part of NumPy and we have much more to see.
So I propose that we take a break, have a coffee, and we'll see you in the next part of NumPy in the
next lesson.