Welcome to a lecture on variables, one of the most important concepts in programming in general.
And to explain what a variable is, I want you to think of a box, a simple box.
This box is a space that allows us to put things inside.
Now, let's name this box, for example, my favorite book.
Now, this box exists for me to store in it.
The book I like the most.
So I do it.
And now my box has content.
It has a value.
But let's imagine I read another book the next month and I like this new book so much it becomes my
new favorite book.
So I replaced the content of my box with the new book.
Basically, my box is a variable.
It is a space that I have created to store something and that something can change.
It can vary.
That is why it is called a variable.
In programming, a variable is a memory space to which you give a name and it is reserve so that you
can store it in any content or value that you want.
You can even leave it empty if you want.
And still a variable.
Let's dive deeper into variables right now in pie chart.
Thanks, Bill.
But before we start writing data code, let's get a little bit of order in these folders because up
to now, we've just been mindlessly adding files inside this vote root fo the python.
But I'd like to be able to save this in folders so we can organize it and have everything easier to
find, because at some point we're going to have hundreds of files.
So we right click in Python, we create a new directory, and this creates a folder that we're going
to give a name.
It can be they won and they will put inside everything we learned yesterday.
Then I select the four files that were created yesterday and we put them in day one.
It's going to ask us to refactor because we have to relocate those files to the new path.
So we refactor.
Everything is now saved in day one and we can see it like this.
So we're now going to create a new directory that this time is going to be called data.
And data is going to contain for now only a new file to which we're going to name as variables.
And remember to make it dot p so it understands the python code.
So we close.
These are the files from yesterday.
We can also close our column here and now we can only see data.
Well, we said that we're going to learn variables and the variables are boxes that contain a value
and that value can be changed.
So let's create our first box, which is going to be called name.
We declare it this way directly with the word that we want to use as title for that variable, and then
we're going to assign a content to it.
This is to say that it's going to be equal to something.
This time I'm going to give it a name.
For example, John.
John is the content of the variable called name.
So if I want to print, for example, the variable name, I should print on the screen, not the word
name, which is not a string.
It doesn't have quotes, but the content of the variable.
And let's execute it.
Let's come here to execute.
Oh, well, we still have the brewery here, so we'll need to find a new way, a new file.
We're going to do that through Run, Run again.
And we choose variables this time.
Okay, it's run.
And now it shows as John instead of name, it shows the content of that variable, which is John.
While we're at it, let's adjust the console so it doesn't show down here.
This isn't comfortable for me.
So let's click on this icon here to choose.
Move to the upper right corner and now we can see our console next to our code.
It looks much more comfortable to me.
All right.
As we said, variables are just variables because they vary.
So we can assign another value to the variable code name.
For that, I simply declare it again and I say that it's new content.
Is Laura another different name?
What do you think will happen if I now print name again?
Notice that it is the same command I gave before.
They're not different in any way and it is another point in the code.
Take a second to imagine what is going to be printed on the console.
Well, let's print it out and see what it looks like.
First you see John and then Laura.
And this is because although we printed both times the same variable at this point of the code in line
to the variable still had as value.
John And that's why it printed the word John.
We then assigned a new value to it, then we asked it to print again, but this time it printed with
its new value, which is Laura.
And this is what makes variables interesting.
You can make them dynamically change their content.
So regarding the names we give to the variables, I named it as name.
I could have named it as anything.
It could be called.
X x x x x x.
And if I asked it to print x x x, it would work exactly the same.
The important thing is that not in the name of the variable but its content and that you then invoke
it correctly.
There are, however, some conventions and good practices to name your variables and we are going to
see that in the next lecture.
For now, let's continue learning.
And let's see what we can.
Also assign a numeric content to variables, for example integer.
If my variable is called age, it can have a value that is, for example, 30.
And if I then print age, we're going to see exactly that.
We're going to see the value 30.
Variables can also be added together if they are numbers.
For example, let's have another variable called age two and age two will be equal to 15.
And if I print age plus age two, we run it.
And it prints the sum, which is 45.
I've added two values that were assigned to two variables, and it worked exactly like a mathematical
operation.
So is also interesting that you can use the input function that we have used so far to actually use
it to tell us something.
For example, tell me your name, which would be something that we ask the user.
We're going to do it inside the input function.
We can ask them to tell us his name.
But what if this time, instead of printing it directly, we assign this user input to a variable called
name name.
It says Here is the same as whatever is entered when we ask.
Tell me your name.
So now I can print a concatenation that says your name is then a space.
Then I concatenate and set the variable name.
So let's see what happens when we run this.
They asked me to tell it my name.
My name is Federico.
Your name is Federico.
I already knew that.
But it's nice that I was able to do it this way by storing my value inside a variable.
So now I can.
Well, I don't even need to print this.
We're going to delete the print box.
We run it.
It's going to ask me for the name.
I say Federico, and you can then come up with their zip code and never print the user's input or use
it for any of the purposes.
But the good thing is that now you can store this information in a variable and manipulate it later
as you wish.
You can also concatenate variables.
If your variable has a string value, for example, it will say hello.
We leave a space and the other one will be called name too.
And it will have the content.
Python.
Well, let's now create a variable called phrase.
That will be equal to the concatenated content of name one plus name two.
And if I print now directly phrase, what I'm going to get on the screen is going to be an error.
Oh, yes.
Because the first valuable was name, not name one.
Sorry.
So now we run it again and I get hello python because phrase has now not only one word is content but
two variables that each has a content name is hello name two is Python and phrase is hello python.
And if we do it with numbers, we can also add them together.
Let's suppose the first variable is going to be called age and it is going to have the value of 30.
The second one is going to be called age two and it is going to have the value of 50 and phrase, well,
let's leave phrase as as the name will contain age plus age two and we print phrase.
What we will have on the screen, it will be 80 the sum.
Now, what this variable did was to contain a sum composed by two variables.
It worked exactly the same.
So this is enough to begin to see the use of variable.
Will expand on this much more throughout the course.
So thank you again for joining us in this lecture and see you in the next one.