In Python sets are collections of elements just like lists, but with some key differences that make
them very particular sets can be declared in two ways using the set keyword and then putting your elements
in parentheses or directly using the keys without using the set keyword.
Although the braces are the same ones that we use to declare dictionaries, Python will recognize that
it is a set because its content will be different from the one used in dictionaries.
So to write its elements, which let's say is what this is right here.
Pay attention, because there are two ways to do it.
If you created your set using the set word and parentheses, the set will only take a single argument.
So you must put all your elements inside braces.
They can be parentheses, square brackets or curly braces.
It doesn't matter, but they have to be enclosed so that python reads them as a single element.
If you created your set directly with the set word and with curly braces, then you can put all your
elements directly.
The most important feature of sets is that they support single elements in a set.
Elements are not repeated.
And what happens if you do add repeated elements?
Python simply discards the duplicates without asking you and leaves unique values.
Another feature is that set elements are not sorted into indexes, just like dictionaries.
While you see the elements displayed in a particular sequence, you cannot index them, rearrange them,
or anything related to their internal position.
And another issue is that elements are also immutable.
All of these characteristics imply that although you can store elements of different data types in sets,
you cannot include lists in dictionaries.
So keep this in mind.
I think it's time to see this in action and other details about sets over in Pi charm.
And now from Python.
We're going to learn how to use the sets and all its alternatives.
First, we're going to declare our variable, my set, which is going to contain a set that we're going
to declare using the first approach.
The fill explained to you in the initial video, which is with the set word, then the parenthesis that
opens and closes.
And inside here we put our values inside some other set of braces.
We're going to do it in this case with the brackets, and we're going to create one, two, three,
four and five.
This is already a set and the check it we're going to print the type of my set and we're also going
to print my set right now to see everything together.
We're going to run this from the second run and we're going to choose sets and here it comes first.
This class is a set, and our set looks like this with curly braces and one, two, three, four and
five.
As I told you, we could have done this with other kinds of braces.
It's going to work exactly the same.
We could have done it with another pair of parentheses, and it's going to work the same because the
idea is that within a set you should include a single argument.
So look, what happens if I write it without any parentheses, brace or anything.
When I want to execute it, it tells me.
Hey, type error sets expected at most.
One argument got five then it doesn't want five arguments, it wants only one.
For that reason, we're going to pass it with some type of braces and now py charms.
Stop screaming.
Well, this is one way to compose it.
The other one.
And we're going to do it with another variable that's called other set is without doing it with the
set word, but directly with the braces where we write one, two and three.
We're going to leave it like that.
We're also going to print it so you can see the type of other set, and we're going to print also other
set so we can see what it looks like.
And here we're going to see this to a set that is one, two, three, four, five, and another set
that is 1 to 3.
So it is indistinct and you can create it as you like.
So we're going to eliminate this second one to continue working with the first one.
And as we've said, this collection called Set does not have an internal order.
So let's see what happens.
If we want to look for another element through a print statement, I will show my set, but only whatever
is in the index.
Zero.
Well, we want to run it and it's going to tell me type error set objects are not subscript double that
is to say that you cannot make this type of trick.
Neither can you, for example, modify some of its elements saying My set in position zero, I want
it now to be equal to five.
You will not want to do it, but it will also tell you that the set objects do not support item assignment.
So you cannot do this with sets.
So what can we do with sets?
Let's see.
I told you that it sets a unique elements.
Therefore they cannot have repetitions.
For I've created a collection here that does not repeat.
It's all right.
But if I add elements that repeat, for example, let's put more ones or a pair of twos and so on.
Let's see what happens when we execute it.
Notice it doesn't give me an error.
It keeps telling me that this is a set.
No matter how many repeats, it has no problem.
But Python has removed all the repetitions.
It discarded them and told me that this set only has one, two, three, four and five.
And it doesn't matter how many times you want to add some repetitions.
That's why I can put integers here.
I can put floats and I can put strings.
But what I cannot put are, for example, lists.
So watch this if I want to change this.
Five And instead of being a five to be a list with two and one.
So we're going to execute it and it's going to tell me that there is a type of error.
The list type cannot be mixed within a set.
Therefore, this list element is not supported in sets.
It will be the same with dictionaries, but it is going to support tables.
Actually, we're going to create one here and we're going to create a table that has one, two and three.
So the object that's here in this place, all of this is a table.
And if we run it, my set includes one to the three, the four, and then the table.
You may wonder how it supports tables and not lists or dictionaries because tables are immutable.
That is, they are an unordered and the set requires that its elements are unordered and immutable.
Therefore, lists and dictionaries cannot be included.
Is this understood?
Well, let's simplify this a little bit.
We've got a lot of stuff here, so we're going to leave it at one, two, three, four and five.
We're going to print it out so that it cleans up what we have.
And I'm going to show you that you can also do things here, like use the Len function that we have
had before to know the length of a collection.
So we can say, Len, and we're going to put in the parentheses my set we're going to print and it's
going to tell us that we have a set of five elements it has been able to calculate them.
So you can also make queries like we did with strings, remember?
Now I can find, for example, if two is in my set by asking it to print, if two is in my set and this
should work by giving me a value that is true because it is true that two is in my set.
We didn't really see this before, but you can do this with both tables and with lists, dictionaries
as well.
As long as what you're looking for in the dictionaries are the keys.
Let's reset all of this to look at a couple more things.
Please learn a way to do set joining.
Let's say I have a set that court that's called SW one and to keep it simple it has one, two and three.
Then we have a set called SW two that has three, four and at five.
I intentionally put a repeated number.
Now we're going to create a third set.
This is going to be called SW three and it's going to be equal to SW one.
But we're going to write a point to bring a method that is called Union.
And inside we're going to put what we want to join it with.
Well, we're going to join it with SW two and we're going to print SW three, which is one the one that
contains the union.
We execute it and now we have a set with one, two, three, four and five.
Maybe you should have expected this to have a set with six elements because there are two sets of three
each, but as one of them is repeated, Python removed it and we have five elements.
Do you follow me?
Well, let's get to know a little bit more about the set methods.
So here, let's leave the first one, which is SW one, and let's try the add method.
So here we write the line that says SW one dot ad, and inside we want to put what element we need to
add.
Let's say I want two out of four because I have one, two and three.
Well, we execute it and now we have one, two, three, four in our set.
It can also happen that you want to add an element that you already have.
Let's add a to let's see what's going to happen here.
Is it going to give me an error?
What is it going to do?
No.
It simply runs the code and also allows me to do it.
It doesn't give me an error and at the same time it doesn't add it because it already exists.
So what can we do as well?
If we can add, we can also delete.
So it's this set that has one, two and three.
We're going to apply the remove method.
So what are we going to remove three, which is the last one.
Now it's going to remove and we have one and two.
What happens if I set it to remove an element that it does not have?
We're going to ask it to eliminate six.
Well, it will give me an error because six is not there.
It cannot be eliminated.
For that, we also have another very similar method called discard.
That is not the same as remove.
Well, it works exactly the same as remove.
The only difference is that if I ask it to discard an element that doesn't exist, it will not give
me an error.
It will simply go ahead as if there was no problem here because there is not actually discarding is
not the same as deleting as it cannot discard.
Six Well, we move on one more method.
One that we have already met when we've talked about strings is the pop method.
Do you remember this method?
If we leave empty in the parameters inside the method, it will remove one of its elements.
But since here in sets we don't have any order.
Remember, we are saying the more that in capricious sequence, pop is going to eliminate a random element
in this case.
So pop can be very dangerous.
But hey, sometimes it can be used to do a sort of draw because you can contain the removed element
inside a variable, for example, draw.
Let's make it like that and we're going to print draw.
Well, we executed and we get number one, but we could have got any other because it has a random element.
The last method that I'm going to show you, so let's put this one again, is clear.
What does clear do?
Well, what it does is if we leave it empty here, is it empty is our set.
So now our set has absolutely nothing.
Well, there are many more methods that actually are not so frequent to use.
They're quite specific, but if you want to know them, I will provide them in the downloadable PDF
that you have next to this lecture.
There is a file within the notes and there you will find the other methods so you can try them for yourself.
And if you have any questions, please leave them in the Q&amp;A area because we are here to help you.
So this has been all about the sets and please do the practical exercises that follow.
And let's go on to the next lecture.
We have one more element left.
Another type of data that is not really a collection like the ones we have been seeing so far, but
they are the booleans and you want to know them because they're very important within programming.
So see you in the next lecture.