Congratulations.
You've finished learning all the content of day two, and now you're able to create a slightly more
complex program.
You already know how to do things like mathematical operations, data type conversions, string formatting
and rounding.
So let's celebrate with a new challenge.
The situation is this You work in a company where salespeople receive 13% commissions on their total
sales, and your boss wants you to help the salespeople calculate their commissions by creating a program
that asks them their name and how much they've sold this month.
Your program will answer them with a sentence that includes their name and the amount of commissions
they are entitled to.
Now, this is not a complex program, but that's okay.
You're still learning, even though what you have learned so far is very simple.
Putting it all together in one program can make your new skills get a little bit messy.
A couple of guidelines.
This program should start by asking the user for things.
So you're going to need to use input to receive user input, and you should use variables to store that
input.
Remember that user inputs are stored as strings, so you should convert one of those inputs to float
to be able to do operations on it.
And what operation do you need to do?
Well, calculate 13% of the number that the user has entered.
That is, multiply the number by 13, then divide by 100.
It would be good to print the result on the screen, so make sure this information has no more than
two decimals.
So it is going to be easy to read and then organize all that in a string that you would format.
Remember, we learned two ways to do it and any of them is valid.
All right, go on.
Try to solve it.
And if it gets complicated, Federico will do it with you in the next lesson.
Go ahead and good luck.