All right.
That was a lot of work.
Hopefully you were able to do it yourself.
Otherwise, we're going to go through it right now.
Let's get to it.
In the first exercise, you had to create a function called return different values, a function able
to receive three numbers and return a different value according to the sum of those numbers.
If the sum of the three numbers is higher than 15, our function will return a number higher than the
ones we entered.
If the total is less than ten, it will return the lowest of the three numbers, and if the total is
between ten and 15, it will return a number of an intermediate value.
So how do we solve this using the code?
Well, first of all, we have to create a function.
That's the easy part.
Def will be named return different values and it will need three arguments or parameters.
So we'll name them A, B and C, we type colon and now we're inside the function.
I think we first need to have a variable in which the sum of those three values is solved, that we
can then verify everything.
So some will be equal to A, plus B plus C.
So it'll be very useful to have a variable named list containing a list of those three values.
So what for?
Because this would allow us to order our code, thereby finding which is the intermediate value.
We already know how to find the highest and lowest values using integer methods.
We have the variables.
Now we're going to use flow control so as to see what type of value we have and what we need to do.
So we'll find out if the total is higher than 15, which was the first condition.
If so, this function must return the highest value.
So we'll make return.
Send us back to the highest value on list and eventually we will get the highest value that was passed
to list.
However, it wasn't the case and the sum wasn't higher than 15.
We would use Elif to know whether the return is lower than ten colon and now we know we have to return
the lowest of the values that were entered.
So we type return of list and we can say that this was a piece of cake.
What may have been difficult for you at this part.
Else since we already know is neither higher than 15 nor lower than ten, and whose value will be between
ten and 15?
We need to know the intermediate value, which is not the lowest or the highest.
Here's one way to solve this.
First, we want to order our list because the user hasn't necessarily passed those values from lowest
to highest.
So we will call, list and use the source method, which doesn't require parameters.
We're going to move it to the next line.
Now, our list comprises all the values from lowest to highest, and we can ask it to return the value
that's in list in index number one since zero one and two are its three indexes.
So one, it's the intermediate value.
And now we have created our function.
Now we'll type the call for this function outside of it.
We will ask return different values to apply itself to numbers 25 and seven.
Of course, this song will be equal to a number higher than 15.
But we're going to have to print this in order to see it on the screen.
This is one way to solve it.
So let's type print here and we'll execute this exercise one.
Since the sum of these values is higher than 15, it returns a higher value, which is 20.
It worked.
Now let's test the sum whose total is lower than ten.
It can be done with three, two and four.
This will be equal to nine, thereby meeting the condition that it returns the lowest number, which
is two.
The information returned is correct.
Now we'll select three values whose sum is equal to a number between ten and 15, I believe seven two
and four will be all right.
This sum will be equal to 13, so it will return the immediate value, which is four according to its
values.
We're not talking about the order in which we were passed, but we would have solved it easily by asking
it to return.
B And that's it.
We're talking about the element that's higher than the intermediate value, which is full.
Notice that if the intermediate value had been different e.g. three here and a higher number such is
seven here, so that the total was higher than ten, it would have returned three, which is index zero.
That is to say the index doesn't matter, but the intermediate value.
This was the first exercise.
So let's move on to the second one.
In Exercise two, you were asked to type a function that could have any name you wanted.
That function will receive a word and return it to the user, the letters that form the word without
repeating them in alphabetical order.
So here we have entertained as an example.
This word should be returned more or less like this.
Let's go to Pi Cham to prepare this code.
So what do we need?
First, a function, of course, and we can call it repeated letters.
That could be a good name.
The only argument that will require is word.
So we'll type that and colon.
And now let's start typing the code.
If we want the letters to be repeated, the easiest thing is to store everything in set.
Remember that sets are groups of unrelated elements.
It doesn't matter if you repeat elements, set is going to ignore them and leave only the repeated ones.
A variable called my set would be great to start with.
For now, we have to leave empty, even though an error isn't returned.
It would be wrong if you tried to create the variable this way because what it's being created is an
empty dictionary.
If you want to create an empty set, you have to do the way sets are declared, which is using the word
set and brackets.
Now Python will understand you're referring to an empty set.
So let's keep going.
Now we're going to start a loop that for each letter in word colon will have to provide our set with
all of those letters.
Thus we're going to use the ad method from my set and we're going to type my set dot ad, which is a
common method.
And what will it add?
It will add letter.
So if there are any repeated words, it won't be a problem set.
Won't add them.
So we have our set already built.
Now we have to order it alphabetically.
However, there is a problem.
Sets are not organized groups, so before showing an organizing, it will need to cast it within a list.
We're going to create another variable named my list, which will be the same as a list from my set.
Once the set has been transformed, will make my list employ the sort method, which is typical of lists
and allows us to order the values in a list alphabetically or ascending order.
Now that we've organized our list, we'll be able to say, Please return my list so we can see it.
This is the function.
We'll put this into practice by calling on repeated letters and passing the word entertained.
In order to see this on the screen will need to print it or save it in a variable and then print that
variable.
It's the same.
So we'll run Exercise two and see only the unique letters in entertained, organized in alphabetical
order.
So let's try another word.
I don't know.
Pineapple.
It has a lot of repeated letters.
If we run it, we get a e, i, l, n and p.
This is how this exercise works.
Difficulty levels will raise, so let's continue with the next exercise.
It's likely that the third exercise was difficult to you, since it doesn't have a definite number of
arguments, meaning that you have to work with asterisk args.
Hence it's a challenge.
ARGs is a bit more advanced than basic iterable objects, so we'll create a function named Rose since
we're looking for zeros that are next to each other and we'll pass an indefinite number of arguments
with asterisks args to it colon and we have our function.
Due to the fact that I'm going to iterate over a group of elements and I need to constantly see their
indexes.
I'll need a counter so we can name it counter.
And this will show me a number of increasing one by one, allowing me to determine which is the index
I'll be examining inside my object collection and here it comes, the loop that tells us that for each
end or number inside ARGs that we have to do here is determine if args in the counter index, which
will be zero in the beginning is equal to zero.
So this is not enough though, because if that's the case, then we will also need to know the condition
of the next number.
So we put and so that the two conditions are met no matter what.
If args in the counter index plus one which in the first case will be one in the first iteration and
will be increasing afterwards.
And this is also equal to zero.
If these two conditions are met, I can return the information in which it says that it's true.
Our two conditions are fulfilled, so we're done with this part.
So something had to be done to those conditions that weren't fulfilled.
Yes, we should make our counter increase a number with the symbols plus and equals one.
And this will allow us to check different values on each for repetition, since during the second iteration
it will determine if the element in index one is equal to zero, and if the element in index one plus
one, i.e. two, is also equal to zero.
This will go on until finishing our object collection.
Once the looping is done, if it hasn't found anything, we want it to return.
Return false.
Remember that return is an element that stop the loops.
So if a coincidence appears somewhere around the iterations, this element will stop the search, get
out of the loop and continue with the rest of the code.
If it never stops because it never finds two zeros together, then it will finish doing all the iterations
and before getting out of the function, it will return the false value.
And now we will be done with our whole code.
Now that we have our function defined, let's put it into practice and print something.
We'll print a call to the neighboring zeros function and we'll pass a lot of numbers.
Zero will not be included yet, but I've passed lots of numbers.
Okay, let's run this to see if it returns false, which is what it should return.
That's correct.
There aren't neither neighboring zeros nor zeros at all.
And if I put just one zero somewhere, even then it will return false, because there should be two
zeros, one after the other.
So let's try one more thing.
If I put another zero, we'll have two zeros in our group.
But they won't be neighbors.
Therefore, we still get false.
And now if this and this are neighbors, we will get true.
There's one more situation we need to check.
Suppose we no longer have neighboring zeros, but one on each end and separated.
And we run this.
Notice that I get an error that says tuple index out of range.
So why do I get this error?
Because it went through all the arguments of my args, got to the end and checked if the argument in
the last counter was or wasn't zero but couldn't check the next index because there are no more arguments
for this counter plus one.
Therefore, we inevitably get an error and we can't go on with the program anymore.
This, however, can easily be solved before entering our if we carry out a previous check to see if
counter plus one that is the next index each iteration corresponds to is equal to the len of the args.
If so, then we shouldn't go on with the iterations because the counter plus one index won't exist.
Therefore we're going to ask it to return a false value through return.
Now our if becomes ELIF since we'll run it only if this condition isn't met, and only then would it
begin the whole process and let us get to the end to discover that this is false.
So this would be the ultimate solution to exercise.
Three.
Let's continue with Exercise four
and now we'll check the solution to Exercise four, in which I'm sure you were at your wit's end.
You may not have been able to solve it even, but no worries.
It would be normal because even though it's not a very complicated code, it does require you to work
it out.
So let's see how I did it.
In this exercise, we have to create a function named count prime numbers, which requires you to only
enter numeric arguments.
This function will show on the screen how many prime numbers there are between zero and the number we've
passed as argument, including it.
And then it will turn the total of prime numbers it finds take into account that on one hand I said
show on the screen all the prime numbers it finds, and on the other hand, return the total of prime
numbers it finds.
These are two different things one means to show on the screen and the other means to return.
Remember that we use the keyword return to return things and print to show on the screen.
Please note that although zero and one are technically prime numbers, they're not considered like so
they're exceptions.
So let's start then in pie chart.
We're going to create the named count prime numbers, add a number variable and then add colon.
Now we'll create a list named Prime Numbers.
Why do we create a list?
Because if our function has to group all the prime numbers it finds, then it has to comprise them in
a list.
Oddly enough, we can start our list with number two already included.
Why is that?
Because two, it's a prime number.
So if the user chooses a number lower than two, the prime number count will stop there.
We're going to set it up soon with an if.
Therefore, every time we make a list, we're going to have to start with to take that for granted so
we can start checking straight from number three.
And for that, I'll create a variable named iteration.
Which will contain the number that will be checked from zero to the value we have to reach.
So we'll start with three, since we already know that two is a prime number while zero and one are
not.
First we'll use that block code to get out of the program if the user entered a number lower than two.
So if number is lower than two, return zero.
Thanks to that, we know that there's no prime number.
Thus we don't need to make things harder for it.
But if the number is two or higher, will loop through each number from three to the one we choose and
then check if iteration is lower or equal to number.
And in that case it will carry out the checking.
Of course, we'll soon make iteration increase its value.
As a result, the loop will stop when we reach the number we chose.
Inside this loop, we'll start another one.
But this time it will be for a for loop that will check every RN from three the minimum to iteration,
which is the number that we have in this case in twos.
Why do we do this?
Because if we know that even numbers are not prime numbers except for two, our checking can skip all
of the even numbers since there's no need to check them.
Thus our program will run faster.
So we'll jump from 3 to 5 then to seven and so on.
So here we put a colon.
Now what is going to happen with each number between three and the number we chose?
Let's check it if in this particular iteration calculated by the end module is equal to zero.
This part may get a little complicated, but remember, this is the correct formula to know whether
a number is not prime checking if it is divisible by another number.
We go through all the previous numbers to see if one division is not equal to zero.
Otherwise, it would mean that it is not a prime number since it is divisible by another.
If we don't have a prime number, then we add plus equals two to the value of iteration so as to count
by twos and type break.
To break out of the for loop iteration and go back to while loop in order to continue with the next
case.
But before that inside the for loop will add an else that applies to the other case.
Which one is that?
The case where a number is not divisible by any number.
If this were to happen, it would mean our number is prime, since it would be divided by all the previous
numbers without resulting in a whole number without decimals.
If it is a prime number, then we will add iteration to the prime numbers list so as to give substance
to such list which started comprising whatever it found.
For this.
We also need to add two more numbers to iteration so that it can keep on using while loop until it finds
all the prime numbers, not just this one.
Now we're ready to break out of the wild loop and type the whole list of prime numbers on the screen
with a print so that the user can see it.
So this exercise also required a function which could return the size or length of the list.
So we'll type, return and not print the length of the prime numbers.
Now we have our function to test it.
We'll print it to see all the prime numbers as well as the total.
So we'll print it, then we'll type count prime numbers and choose number 50 and we'll see how it looks
on the screen.
We choose exercise four and here it showed numbers two, three, five, seven and so on.
All prime numbers.
See for yourself a total of 15.
If I put another number like 150, I'd have many more prime numbers.
We'd need to make a bigger screen.
They'd go up to 149 and there's a total of 35 numbers.
If I put number one, it would return zero.
There are no prime numbers.
There's nothing to show on the screen.
So this is how I solved it.
Again, it's okay if it was hard for you.
I hope this way of solving it has helped you broaden your skill of thinking like a programmer.
And now we'll go to the next challenge where you'll be creating your own program.
In the next lesson, Phil will explain the activity.
You don't want to miss it.