Personally, I love simple but useful functions, and that's the case of the min and max functions,
which, as you may imagine, refer to minimum and maximum and serve to detect the lowest and highest
values of a collection.
They work with both numeric and alphabetic values, and there's no reason to put delaying them into
action.
Let's do it.
And now that we're in Python, we can see that the syntax of Min and Max is very simple.
It's just the keyword like min or max.
Let's begin with Min and then in parenthesis we're going to put a series of values in which we're going
to look for the minimum value.
It can be either a series of values like put, for example, 58, 96, 72, 64, 35.
I have here a collection of five numbers.
It could also be a list or any other intermodal.
We're going to start with this way and we're going to store this value inside a variable that's called
minor.
And now we're going to print minor.
So we're going to run and we're going to look for our minimum and maximum file.
And it's going to tell us that the least of these numbers is 35.
If I were to look for the maximum, we can copy this to have the same collection of numbers, but this
time it would be stored inside major.
And the key word here is Max.
Let's print this major variable and we're going to get that.
The largest number is 96, and that's correct.
So this is one way to do it.
Another way to do it, we're going to eliminate all of this is to work directly with a list that we
may have stored in a variable, for example, list.
And let's say that list is equal to these same numbers, but in a list.
So now we can ask to print the maximum of list and it's going to work exactly the same.
Or we can even set up a little string with F and we're going to write here the least is and we call
the minimum of list.
Then we continue with the sentence saying comma space and the greatest is and here we call the maximum
of list and we print this out.
So we have a nice sentence that says the least is 35 and the greatest is 96.
So you can interact with this in many ways.
Remember, inside minimum and maximum, you can put a variable that appeals to a collectible, just
like a list, like a dictionary, or like a table.
Also, you can put the collectible directly in here or directly a series of numbers, as we did at the
beginning.
So we're going to see also that we can work with strings, really, strings organized around minimum
and maximum values.
Yes.
You know that strings are sortable alphabetically, so you can do that, too.
So let's write a list of names.
We're going to be our friend, John, and it's going to be our friend Paul.
We can incorporate our friend Alice.
And finally, our dear friend Charles.
There they all are.
And I want you to know that this is a first in alphabetical order.
So what I want to do is print the minimum of names.
And this will bring me that.
That is Alicia, of course.
And what if I instead of working with a list of names, I work only with a single string like Carlos.
What happens if I ask for the minimum or maximum of a string?
Well, remember that strings are technically a collection, too.
They're a string of characters.
So it's going to look for some characters, and it's going to tell me that the lowest is C, and here
you'll be saying this is wrong fitting the lowest character here is A.
Well, actually, Men and Max will look first for the uppercase letters and then the lowercase letters.
So if we actually take out the uppercase C and put it as lowercase, it's going to change everything.
And it's going to tell us that the min is now equal to a notice.
If we put this O as a capital letter, for example, now it will tell me that the min is O, because
it goes first for the uppercase and then the lowercase.
If you don't want any confusion, you should look for the minimum of the dot lower name.
That's what we have this method for.
And now, even if the O is uppercase, it will tell me that the A is the minimum letter.
In this case.
That's for the strings.
And what if we see how it behaves with dictionaries?
And here there is also some things to consider.
So we have a dictionary that has a key one that has a value of 45.
And let's add a second key.
Key to it has a value of 11.
Then notice this key one will be lower than key two, alphabetically speaking, but the lowest value
is that of key two because 11 is lower than 45.
So let's see what Python is going to look for if I ask it to print to the minimum dictionary the key
or the value.
Place your bets before I hit print.
Here I go.
And what it brought me is a key one, meaning it defaulted to the key that has the lowest value alphabetically.
But if I wanted to return the lower value instead of the lower key, remember that we can ask here through
the values method that what it brings is not the complete dictionary, but its values.
And in that case, it will be the minimum value of this search.
So I hope this lecture has helped you to know this method, that they're very simple.
It has the variations, and it can be really useful when we have to manipulate information.
As always, thanks for joining us and don't skip the practices.
We'll be waiting for you in the next lecture.