From this point on, when the daily projects aren't simple exercises, it is paramount that you try
to draw a graph or a diagram of the type of problem you have and how you would divide it into small
parts.
All this before writing all the entire code.
In this case, I'm going to show you how I've represented it.
But you can do it whatever way you want.
Once the game starts, we need the code to call a function that takes care of picking a random word.
Then we need to show the player a hyphenated representation of how many letters our word has.
Then we need to ask the user to choose a letter.
We then need to check if that letter is valid.
Make sure it's not a number.
And if it is a letter, make sure no more than one letter has been entered.
If the user's entry is not valid, we must ask the user to enter a letter again.
If the input is valid, then the next code block will check to see if the letter is in the word.
If the letter is not found, it will add that letter to the list of incorrect letters and show you how
many wrong letters you have chosen.
It will deduct one life and show you how many lives you have left, and then it will check to see if
you have run out of lives.
If there are no more lives left, the game is over and the player has lost.
But if not, it will ask for the next letter and repeat the cycle again.
If the letter is correct, the code will replace the corresponding dashes with the letter guest and
it will check if the complete word has been guessed.
If not, it will ask you to choose another letter to continue the cycle.
But if there are no more letters left to guess, it will declare that the game is over and that you
are the win there.
Whew.
Quite a job to do all this.
You are going to need to refresh a lot of things that we've learned from the course.
For example, we are going to need some functions that return something via return, but also some that
simply display information like this one, which asks for a list to be passed as an argument and then
displays that list via the print statement.
Remember that you're also going to need to create functions that receive user input and check whether
that input is correct or not before returning it with the return.
I'd like to refresh that.
Suppose we want the user to enter a letter, but we only want them to enter A, B or C to ask for a
user input.
We use the input statement and store that input in a variable.
If we want this line to be placed inside a function, we must put the name of the variable next to return
so that when it finishes executing, the function will return the value entered by the user to verify
if the input is valid.
For example, if they've entered only A, B or C, first, we can establish an incorrect value for the
input and then a while loop that is going to continue executing while the input is incorrect.
This way we make sure that the request is repeated over and over until the user enters a value.
Valid value.
The last recommendation.
Be patient.
Expect to be wrong at least 100 times.
Have fun solving the problems you will encounter along the way and do not regret the hours you will
spend putting this all together and trying.
Don't forget, play some good music.
Grab something nice to drink.
Good luck.
And we'll see you on the other side.