Did you make it?
Yeah.
Not yet.
Oh, that's okay.
Did you have fun, at least?
Well, we did a lot.
And although the part of designing and solving the challenge for you is the part that takes the longest.
It's also the part we should enjoy the most.
And I hope you do, too.
Join Federico over on Pi Charm to show you how we solved this challenge ourselves.
So get ready because we're going to program hangman.
First, we need to import from random a method called choice.
This will allow us to choose a random object from a list of objects.
So what object are we going to choose?
A word.
We're going to have a group of words in a list called words.
And there we'll put words like counsellor and dinosaur and you can pick any words you like.
I'll put heliport as well as breakfast and entrepreneur.
Okay.
This is a complex program that contains a lot of elements.
So let's type everything in lowercase so as not to worry about anything else.
We'll also create other variables that our program will need, such as one that can count all the correct
letters the user finds.
So correct letters is a good name for this variable, which will start with an empty list, since it
will start without any information.
Incorrect letters is another variable we'll need in order to count the letters the user has chosen and
that don't appear in the word since the user will have six tries before losing will count the tries
with a variable starting with six, and we'll also have a variable that counts the right answers in
order to know when they win.
Let's start with zero and then we'll be comparing this with all the letters used in the word the user
has to guess.
So we'll also need a variable to tell when the game is over.
So game over.
This will start as false since the game isn't over yet.
We already have our crucial variables.
Now we have to create functions that will make our game work.
The first one will make the system choose a random word from the list.
So our function will be called Def Choose Word.
That's a good name and it will need first to pass a parameter to it.
Which one?
The list of words from which it will choose.
So list of words is an accurate way of saying that a variable contains a list that will be necessary.
This function will choose a word and will save it on chosen word.
This is an internal variable of the function which will derive from applying the choice method to choose
randomly to the list of words that we pass as a parameter by using it as a function.
You'll be able to create a different list to pass another one to it because functions adapt to anything
you pass as a parameter.
So chosen word is the first variable of our function, and the other one will be different letters.
What will different letters do?
It will store all information about how many letters which don't repeat themselves.
There are in our word, so we can then compare it to the users, write answers and know whether they
want to know how many different letters are worth, has will have to store chosen word in a set, and
this will create a set that contains a number of elements corresponding to the number of different letters
in our word.
And we'll lock this variable in Len to know the length of the set containing all the different letters.
We now have a word to start our game and we know how many different letters there are.
Once we have all of this, we can put it in return.
And when we call the function, we'll get that information, the chosen word and the number of different
letters.
Okay.
This function is ready.
And we can call it whenever we want.
Now, however, we'll keep on creating more functions.
So we'll need a function that asks the user to choose a letter.
And this function will be called as many times as necessary until the user wins or loses.
Therefore, the function will be named ask letter and it won't need parameters since it doesn't require
any extra data to work.
So here we're going to create variables from which we'll get some data.
First, what will be the letter chosen by the user?
We'll create the variable chosen letter, which is the one the user will choose and which will start
as an empty string.
Then we'll need to check if the entered letter is correct.
What if the user enters a number or word?
We need a variable called it's valid, which will be false because what we have here isn't valid until
the user chooses a letter.
In addition, we'll need a place to check if the entered character is a letter.
To do so, we can use the alphabet and we'll create it right now by entering all the letters in the
alphabet.
They were almost there.
X, Y and Z.
Done.
This will allow us to check if the letter the user has chosen is here, thereby being valid.
Now we'll start a loop and ask the user to enter a letter and we use a loop so that the process repeats
itself as many times as the end of the letter is invalid.
That is, the user won't get out of the loop until they enter a valid letter.
So as long as the variable it's valid isn't true.
An input asking the user please choose a letter will keep repeating itself and we have to store this
input in the chosen letter variable that we've already created.
Whatever the user enters will be stored here.
Once the user enters, something will first need to know if that chosen letter is inside the alphabet.
But we also need to check if the user has entered a single character and nothing else.
So we add one more condition with and which will check if the length of chosen letter is equal to one.
That is to say it has one character.
If both conditions are met, not just one, but both, then it will be valid and true.
Once we get this value, we'll get out of the loop.
If this doesn't happen, we'll show a message on the screen that says you haven't chosen a correct letter
and the loop will repeat itself again and again until the user enters a letter.
So once a correct value is sent back in the loop stops we can return the chosen letter from the function,
since it's confirmed that it is a valid letter.
Then we can close the function.
So far we have two functions ready, so let's go to the third one.
The third function will be in charge of showing the game board on the screen.
That is the hidden word by replacing each letter with a dash so that the user has to guess which which
letter goes on each dash.
That's hangman.
So this function will be called show new board.
And I say new board because remember that this function will show every time the user has to choose
a letter, it will refresh and then the new board will appear with a letter or just as it was, and
so on until the word is completed.
So what parameter will this need?
It will need chosen word in order to work with those data.
So when we call this method, we'll need to pass it to the word chosen by the software with the choose
word method.
This way it will be able to use the necessary dashes every time this new board is reproduced.
We need to show a string that has the revealed letters and a number of blank spaces representing the
missing letters we need to find.
So each time it is called, this method will rebuild the current state of the hidden word.
So to do so, we'll use a list called Hidden List that will start empty and check letter by letter if
it is to show a revealed letter or dash.
So for each letter contained in the chosen word, we need to check if that letter is among the correct
letters.
To do this, we have this empty variable we've already created, which will store all the revealed letters
as the game continues.
If that letter is incorrect letters, then hidden list, which is the one we're creating now.
We receive that particular letter, and if the letter is not incorrect letters, then else will also
add something to hidden list.
But what a dash which we put as a string so as to build and shown the screen our hidden list containing
the revealed letters and the blank spaces.
So once this loop has gone through each letter in chosen word, it has to show on the screen how Hidden
List has ended up.
The list should contain as many elements, letters or dashes as in chosen word.
So now we'll print it on the screen and print.
But what are we going to show?
We'd like to show the word by separating its elements with some space between its letters so as not
to leave everything heaped up.
So let's create a blank space and apply the join method to it, which, as you may remember, is a string
method that allows us to join all the elements comprised in Hidden List, but separated with a space.
As a result, we have a function that doesn't actually return anything, but it prints the game progress.
The board will be refreshed and displayed.
So let's close all this and create a fourth function.
Why?
This is a lot, though.
This might be the most fundamental or complex function because it is one we'll use to check if the letter
the user entered matches with the hidden word.
And every time the function checks, it will complete the list of correct and incorrect words.
This function will also check if the user has one try or less.
If a letter matches the hidden word.
And if the user won or lost.
That is to say, we have a lot to do and we're going to need several parameters.
We'll need to know the chosen letter picked by the user in order to work with that.
So within this function, we need to know what the hidden word is.
We also need to know how many tries are left and how many matches there are so far.
Remember that I'm choosing these words as parameters.
They can be any words.
They're internal variables.
I use specific names in order to work inside the function.
Then in return, when it returns something to the code, I'll use the variables that need to be properly
completed while these things change.
Okay.
Let's refresh the game.
Progress with a variable named end.
As long as it's false, it means the game is not over.
If we enter here, it's because we're still playing.
And what happens during the game will determine whether the game ends or not.
So we'll check if the chosen letter matches the hidden word.
And if it does, our correct letters list will receive a new element.
Append What will the list receive?
Well, the chosen letter, of course.
In addition, if we get a letter right, we also need to increase the number of matches to plus equals
one unit.
That is to say, its previous value plus one.
The match is variable comes from these parameters because it's a value that we're going to pass to it
when calling check letter.
Then when calling, it will pass the right answers as matches to check letter, and we'll see that as
we move forward.
Okay, but what would happen if the user guessed wrong then?
Else the list of incorrect letters will also receive a new element through append and it will also receive
the chosen letter.
In other words, that chosen letter will wind up incorrect letters or incorrect letters, depending
whether it appears in the word or not.
If the letter goes to incorrect letters, the user may have one try less.
So for every iteration, Tris will be minus equals one unit.
This is not everything.
The function is in charge of, mind you.
It also has to verify, after verifying if the letter is in the word, whether the user runs out of
tries or whether their guesses are right, thereby winning the game.
So we're going to use IFF to verify whether the number of tries has gone down to zero.
If so, the value of end which we have up here and it's still false will change to true.
And we won't enter it as it is.
But we'll call the lose method, which we haven't created yet.
That's why it's underlined and it's going to return the true value as well as carry out other tasks.
So we'll leave it here for now.
If the user still has tries left, we'll use Elif.
To verify if the value of matches is equal to that of unique letters.
Because if the user's number of correct answers coincides with the number of different letters contained
in our system and will change to true via win a method we're going to devise in a minute when we'll
need the hidden word, as it will show us once more how the board is at the end.
It is still underlined, but not for long, I promise.
So we'll end this function by returning lots of information to the code so that it can use it.
We'll create a return that sends back how the tries are at the end, the state of end, if it is changed
to true as a result of having won or lost the game, or if it is still false because in fact nothing
happened yet and matches that is how they are having tested these right or wrong answers with this method.
So I'll leave this function open so that you can see how these errors PI charm is notifying are deleted.
Let's create the last two functions which are quite easy.
One of them is lose, which is this one we're calling here and which is no longer underlined.
However, it is still asking for return.
That's why it's in yellow.
We'll give return to it once we've completed it.
Inside Lou's, we're going to first print a message that will tell the user you don't have any tris
left, and below it we'll print the correct word was.
So the hidden word was we type a space here and concatenate with word so that the user knows the word
they couldn't guess.
Word is also underlined since we haven't created this variable yet.
We'll do it right now.
When we call choose word up here, we will return a chosen word.
Well, this is the one we're going to convert to word.
Finally, Luiz only has to return.
True so that the game can end later.
Now lose is no longer underlined.
So what follows now is to create the last function, which is win.
So when here is no longer in the line, it asks for a hidden word which is in the parameter we have
to pass it to as to show how the game will end.
Hidden word can be revealed.
Word.
Remember that this is a variable I'm creating in which will eventually store elements.
When will show how the board is at the end of the game.
So we start by calling show new board, which is the function we created earlier.
It needs for us to pass word to it, so we're going to pass whatever variable is included in Revealed
World.
Another task when will carry out is to print a congratulations message print congratulations.
You've guessed the word or something like that.
Lots of exclamation marks and everyone's happy.
We'll also make it return the true value so that the game can end.
So let's close this.
And now Python's pointing out only two errors.
Which are these?
Now that we've finished creating functions, that comes the most dynamic part because we haven't yet
created something to execute the game.
So far the functions have been created, yet not called.
So if we execute this, nothing will actually happen.
What follows can be created quite quickly and easily.
Since we already have all the code inside the functions, we have to join them.
First, we need the system to choose one of the words so we call choose word.
And remember that it asks for a list.
And the list we have here is words.
Of course we have to store in variables whatever choose, word returns.
And what will that be?
We'll open that function to find out and look.
It returns the chosen word and the different letters that make up that word.
So we'll store that by typing first two variable names.
Four chosen words will type word and will store different letters in the unique letters.
We type the equals symbol and the underline goes away.
Okay.
As regards the game dynamics, the system already has a word in order to start the game.
Now we'll ask the user to choose a letter by calling the ask letter function.
Since this step has to be repeated as many times as necessary until the player loses A wins, we'll
have to lock this command in a while loop.
So that repeats itself until the game ends.
So while game over is not true, we're going to first execute print with some decoration so that the
user tries are displayed separately on the screen.
To do so, we can type a series of asterisks to make a line to separate the tries.
Then we can do a line break which will concatenate with an asterisks between quotation marks, and we'll
multiply it by 20 so that it appears several times.
And we'll concatenate this with another line break.
Great.
So we have the decorative part done.
Next, we're going to show how the board looks like so far.
If it is the first turn, there will only be dashes.
So we call Chau new board, which is ready and we only need to enter the word.
And that's it.
Then we'll print another line break so as to have everything organized.
This is kind of a simple graphical interface, and here's where things actually get interesting.
So what else can we enter here?
Some data we can point out how many incorrect letters there are so far.
At the beginning, they'll be zero.
And we concatenate with a list of letters which is inside the incorrect letters list.
We can also separate those letters from one another with dashes or dots so that they are not too close.
Thanks to the joint method, which allows us to enter incorrect letters.
This will be the first data to process.
We can also point out how many tries there are left by typing a string literal that says tries colon
space.
And then we call tries and that's it.
So what else can we do?
We can copy another separator line here, and we can now ask the user to enter a letter.
So we'll call a function we created to do this ask letter.
This doesn't need parameters, so we enter it just as it is.
And remember, however, that ask letter will send us back the letter the user has entered, so we'll
store it in variable to use later.
We have the hidden word which we showed with dashes, and we also have the user's letter.
Now comes the most important part, which is the function check letter.
So we're going to call it check letter.
We need to pass lots of information to it.
We need chosen letter.
Hidden word tries and matches.
We have letter as chosen letter.
That's why we created it here.
The second parameter is hidden word, and that would be word which was created here when the software
chose its word.
We can give it to the program so it does its job.
Tries whether we have them, we have them up here in tries.
There are six tries.
So in order for the software to control the number of tries, we're going to enter tries and that's
it.
Finally, the last parameter is right answers, which corresponds with the users right answers.
So tries is the information this parameter needs.
So now our function will return lots of information.
It will return the number of tries.
It will tell us if the game is over and it will send back the matches how they are after being processed.
We'll store all this in variables.
We'll create three variables here.
The first one will be tries.
The second one will be over, which will control if the game's over or not and right answers.
So this part of the game will return all this information.
And the last part, we're almost done, believe me, which is game over, will now return the information
it has in over so as to know whether the game has to end or not.
So that's it, whether the loop repeats itself or not.
Now we have finished our game and we can try it.
So get ready.
So we execute our file and it displays the separator line and the word the system is chosen.
Looks like we have to guess a long word.
It has like 12 letters.
Incorrect letters.
There are none yet.
Tris, there are six left since we've just started.
And here, there's another separator line.
The game's asking me to choose a letter.
I'll answer wrong.
On purpose.
I'll go with a number that's telling me I haven't chosen.
Right.
I'll choose wrong again and enter two letters instead of one.
New error.
Now I'll enter one letter.
Such as s.
All right.
Seems like S doesn't match our secret word.
So the system added it to incorrect letters.
Okay, now it's telling me I have five tries left, and it's still showing me dashes without any letters.
So let's try with a that can't go wrong.
Well, A is also wrong.
I have four tries left now.
S and a R here.
So I'll try with p.
Good.
P is right.
So the software replace the corresponding dashes.
This means it is doing its job very well.
I have four more tries yet the incorrect letters are the same.
So let's try with EA.
It appears like four times.
I think I know which word it is.
So I complete it with n t r and you.
After I do this, the game congratulates me.
Now let's execute it to see what happens if we lose.
Let's enter.
Q Many times look, the number of tries decreases and the Q's are listed here.
I have one try left.
Oh, no, I've lost it.
Now the game tells me I have no choice left.
And it shows me what the hidden word was.
Well, this was tough.
I hope all these steps helped you.
It's not easy, but don't worry.
It's okay if you couldn't do it.
Congratulations.
If you haven't done it, at least you could do it with me.
It's really important to see first hand how this works so I won't keep you any longer since we're pretty
tired.
So I'll let you get some rest and I'll see you in the next lectures.