In this lecture, we are not only going to learn how to generate random numbers programmatically and
in a very easy way, but we are also going to see for the very first time how to import methods into
Python.
In this case, we're going to need a method called random, which stands for Random Integer, and this
is a method for Python to return, obviously a random integer.
But the problem is that random, it is a method that belongs to a python library called random, and
the random methods are not loaded directly.
That is to say they are not available to be used unless you import them manually to import a method
from a library we already have.
We need to talk to Python like this, this library, import this method.
In the case of the random method, which is the random library, we say from random import random.
And in case you need a lot of methods from a certain library, you can save time by directly replacing
a method name with an asterisk, which means all.
Now when you go to PY charm, you are going to meet five random methods which are rand int uniform,
random choice and shuffle.
I promise that you're going to have fun with this one, so let's go to the code.
Fill is right.
We will have fun in this one.
As you probably might imagine, all of the random functions.
We're going to have a lot of application in the gaming world, especially in many applications where
we need the system to pick something at random.
Well, we said that one of the methods that we wanted to use was called random, which would mean something
like random integer.
If we say random here, you'll see that the system does not recognize it.
It marks it in red.
So far, Python does not know what I'm talking about because it is a method that corresponds to the
random library and we have to import it manually.
So it's not like Max or Min that we have just used that we already have incorporated in the Python library.
So let's write up here that for random, which is the name of the library import.
And here notice that if you press control in the space bar and pie charm, it will pop up a list with
all the methods that you can import from random.
Here.
We're going to look for the one that we want, which is redundant.
Here it is.
And I press the tab key on my keyboard and thus we already have it.
So it's grayed out because pie charm is flagging a supposed error here.
Thing is that we've imported a method, but we're not using it.
Pie charm gets a little bit anxious, as you can see.
Until we don't use it, it's going to be shouting at us from there.
Wait.
PY charm.
I've just imported it.
Give me a minute.
Okay, now we're going to use it.
We're going to say here that we want a variable called my random.
And this variable is going to contain a random integer, that is to say a random.
And we have to pass here some parameters related to the range in which the system should choose a random
integer.
And let's suppose that we want some random number between one and 50, and let's see what happened here.
So we print my random and we run it and we go to the random file and here comes this number.
But pay attention now if I run it again, here it is.
Now it throws me a different number.
If I run it again, and now I get another one and another one, and so on.
In each execution, in each instance of your code, the system will throw a different number.
Can you imagine doing a draw, for example?
You would certainly need random for that.
So let's look at one more method now.
Let's look at the uniform method, which we also need to import.
But look what we're going to do now instead of importing one by one the methods we need.
As in this lecture, we're going to look at many of these methods.
Then we press asterisks.
And by this means, please python from the random library imports everything inside.
So now everything is at our disposal.
Well, let's now transform my random into a value equal to uniform.
And what does uniform do?
It is going to throw is also a random value, but this time a decimal value within the range that we
choose.
I ask for a value between one and five.
So my random now when I print it, has this floating value with a very long decimal.
Normally I prefer to have much less decimals so I can enclose this in round.
That is a solution where at the end I can put a comma and say that I want, for example, only one decimal
number and now if I print it, it will give me back a floating number again, but pretty short this
time, and the same for every execution that I do.
Always a random number.
Now we're going to look at a third method, which is called simply random.
Yes, the same number as the library.
Random.
This method doesn't need any parameters.
You can't type anything in here.
It goes empty.
And what random does is automatically choosing a float number between zero and one.
So every time you run it, you're going to get zero point something.
So let's do it again and again.
And so this is always going to have that fraction of an integer.
It's very handy when you need to be working with percentages or fractions.
Okay.
So far we have three methods in.
Let me delete all of this.
And now let's look at the fourth one, which is choice.
And this is great because it allows you to work with a random selection within the elements of a list.
So if I have, for example, a variable called colors and I give it a blue color, a red green will
be there too.
And yellow, no matter how long your list is.
And below, let's say that my random is equal to choice from the list colors.
Of course we can do this with a list or any other collectible.
So let's print my random now and see that in this instance it chose a random color from my list, and
if I run it again, we will get a different one and so on.
So this way, strings are also liable to be subjected to the system.
And finally, let's get to know a slightly different method, but one that also works with randomness,
which is shuffle.
So this would be useful, for example, in card games, don't you think?
So again, we're going to delete all of this and we're going to say we have a list called numbers and
we're going to build it differently.
What we're going to do is build it casting a range into list.
So list of a range between five and 50.
Also, we can now ask to jump every five places.
So let's see what this list looks like.
So there's no doubt in your mind.
So we're going to print numbers and we're going to have a list that goes from 5 to 55, ten, 15, 20,
and so on, up to 50.
Remember, the last number is not inclusive.
Well, this is our list.
But if I remember for applying the shuffle method, it is written like this.
Now I say that I want to shuffle numbers and this will shuffle it randomly.
And now we get a completely different order inside my list of numbers.
And if we run it again, another setup and so on.
So this would surely come in handy in card games.
Surely it would.
So well, remember, that shuffle is a method that you can't store in a list.
It's like all these methods that we've seen that generate an in-place modification on the spot.
It's actually changing the list.
So shuffle, we can't use the strings because strings are immutable.
So these have been the main methods that exist for the random class wrapping up this day.
It only left one more lecture before we move on to the challenge.
So let's keep going.
I'll see you there.