Welcome to this extra lesson that we're going to do to correct a little bug that our program has.
Maybe you've already played the game and you haven't found any problem, or maybe you've found it as
I did.
Jesuit David Bolivar, a very attentive student who said, Hey, fatty, here's a problem.
So let's run our game to see what Jez will.
I hope I'm pronouncing the name right has discovered.
We notice that something strange happens if we choose more than once a correct letter.
Look, let's try E, right?
This word has an E in it, so let's keep entering E!
One more time.
And of course, it doesn't improve our performance because it keeps showing the same hits and it doesn't
add anything and it doesn't subtract lives.
But look what happens if I keep putting the E as many times as there are letters in our word.
So it gets to a point where it tells me congratulations, but this is not correct.
It is a bug because I did not find the word.
So the explanation is that the match marker keeps increasing as I enter a letter that I've already found
before.
So how do we correct this?
Well, luckily, Jessel not only spotted the problem, but he offered me a solution that I'm going to
take because it's a very smart solution.
He realized that within the check letter function, we check to see if chosen letter is in hidden word
and nothing else.
And this causes us to make decisions that caused this error to occur.
What he proposes is that in addition to checking if two chosen letter is in hidden word, we also add
one more condition that is to say and.
And we check if chosen word is not in correct letters and this solves it.
So why so?
Because it will not only check that the letter is in hidden word, as we see here, but it will also
check that it is not been previously added to the correct letters list.
And so it would also not allow us to enter this block of code that would add chosen letter into correct
letters and that would increase the number of matches.
So this is the solution offered by well and it was totally correct.
But let's add one more element, because this solution generates a new problem.
In fact, it makes that when we put a letter that we already have, have we also lose a try?
Because when not entering here it is going to enter this ls that deducts a try.
Then after the if we're going to create an ELIF that checks both things, it will check if chosen letter
is in hidden word and it will also check if chosen letter is incorrect letters.
If it is found in both lists, it means that a letter that has already been found before is being repeated.
And here, instead of subtracting tries or increasing matches, we will simply print a warning that
tells the player, You have already found that letter, try with another one and with this we have solved
it.
So notice that if we now run our program and intentionally make the same mistake, let's try with the
E.
No matter how many times I put the E, I get the warning message, and even if I do it many times,
it will never declare me the winner ahead of time.
So thank you very much, Jess.
Will students like you help the course progress?
So see you in the next lesson.