The next step in our game is to add the player, a spaceship or rocket that will be located down here
and which will shoot to the invaders.
To download, this image will follow the same steps as before.
So go to flat icon or any page you want and pick the one you like the most.
So I pick this one.
I'll choose 64 pixels here and remember that I chose 32 before because I thought it was the right size
for an icon and I think 64 pixels will work just fine in this case.
So once again, I'll drag this image to the folder containing all my files and let's go back to Python
where we'll see that rocket is inside our project ready to be used.
So keep in mind, this is an 800 by 600 pixel screen resolution and this is valuable information to
set the screen size and locate objects.
Imagine this is a coordinates map in which each pixel contains information about height and width.
The first pixel, located in the top left corner is the pixel located at the origin point of the x and
y axis.
Therefore, if you position yourself here, you're at x 400, which is the width y 300, which is the
height.
These would be the midpoints.
So you need to take all of this into consideration when deciding where to locate your images, characters
and or objects.
So let's see an example.
We'll create our player down here and name it player.
Let's store the image we downloaded in a variable named IMG Player, which will be equal to PI game
image load like before.
Now we're going to type rocket dot png and that's it.
Now we're going to create two more variables.
One, to tell the player's location in the x axis and another to tell their position in the Y axis.
This one will be named Player X and will be equal to zero so that it's located in the top left corner
and this will be player y, which will also be equal to zero.
So I've created a very strange location which is up here.
Now we'll join these data in a function that shows the player's location.
This function will be named player and it won't require parameters and it will call screen dot blip.
We'll pass two elements to it.
First, our player's image, which is IMG player, and then a two pool consisting of the coordinates
at which we want to locate our player.
So we enter player X and player Y.
Now, where will we call this function from?
If we need our player to change positions at any moment, we'll need the location data to be constantly
updated.
Therefore, this has to be inside the game loop and before the update, let's put it here.
And this means we'll first see the background color and then we'll see the player.
If it was the opposite case, first the player and then the colour, our game would go wrong because
the player would be overlapped by the background color and that's not what we want.
Therefore, we have to make sure that we have the background color at the beginning of the loop.
That way the screen won't overlap anything.
And here we'll enter the job of our screen.
Okay, now we'll open the call to player, and that's it.
We should be able to see it.
So let's see what happens.
If we execute it.
We can see the color.
And then our player who's located at zero zero.
These are not the coordinates I want.
I want my player to be down here in the middle.
So if I located the player exactly in the middle, it wouldn't work that well because the half of 800
is 400.
So if I located it in the middle, my player would be located the right side of the screen actually.
So since my player is 64 pixels wide, I have to divide 800.
Once I get the result, I have to subtract the half of the player from that result.
Half of 64 is 32.
So 400 -32 is 368.
And those should be the coordinates at which my player is to be located.
So let's add 368 and execute this.
Now we can tell the player is located exactly in the middle of the screen.
And I also want the player to be located down here in this very spot.
If my player is 64 pixels high and my screen is 600 pixels high, then I need to subtract 64 from 600,
which is 536.
This way I'll be able to locate it where I wanted.
So I hope you're following me here.
So we'll add 536 to the Y axis.
Let's execute it.
And now we can tell our player is exactly where we want.
And in the next lesson, we'll make the game move a little.
So don't miss it.
I'll see you there.