In this short lecture, we are not going to learn a new concept, but a new way to do something we already
know more efficiently.
And by that I mean by using less code.
List comprehension is a dynamic way to build lists.
If you ever find yourself in a situation where you have to build a list through a loop that passes several
times through the append method to add its elements.
That's the moment where this list comprehension will be a good ally.
Let's see it over in Petrom and let's start by doing this with what we know so far.
Let's say I have a variable that's called word that contains the word python and I want to generate
a list of each of the elements of my string.
Then I create a list, an empty list, and I'm going to feed it through a loop for where I say for each
letter in words colon we call list dot append, which is the method that adds a value to a list.
And for this case, we'll append all the letters iteration by iteration that it finds in word.
When we then print our list should be able to see here.
pyth0n.
Perfect.
Now I have lists filled with all those elements as I wanted, but this is taking me all of these lines
to accomplish something that maybe would be much simpler if I do it with list comprehension.
The first thing I do is eliminate from colon to this whole second line.
I'm not going to need it anymore.
Now I add the word letter before the false statement.
Now I have letter for each letter within word.
I take all of this, cut it and paste it inside the empty list and you'll say, this is a kind this
is kind of strange.
And yes, it looks hard to read, but I think it's very readable because we're here telling Python I
want the variable list to be equal to a composite list.
Each element is going to be a letter of every letter that's in words.
So we run it and we get exactly that.
The reading would be then that one letter for every letter that's in word.
And here actually the word letter is the internal variable that we use, but it could have been x x
and it would work just the same or whatever we put in there.
F f for f f and it's going to work fine as long as it's the same internal variable that we're using.
It would also be the same if instead of putting a variable here that has the content python directly
here, put Python because I'm replacing the variable usage.
And now with just one line, I've already built my list.
I'm printing it for you to see.
But this one line is the only line that I need to build it thanks to the list comprehension.
If this is a little more complex for you to read, it's fine to go back to the previous method and use
the full.
No problem.
That is if it's comfortable for you.
We can also work with numeric values here.
Suppose I want my list to store one number for each number we have within a range that goes from zero
to but not including 21.
We can even choose to advance in pairs.
So finally it will be the even numbers there are from 0 to 20.
So if I run it, my list now has 0 to 4, six, eight, ten and so on, so it run perfectly.
Another thing we can do is modify those numbers.
If I, for example, want my list to be made up of every number but divided by two for every number
in this range.
Now, these numbers that we have here, I'm going to have them altered because they're going to be a
division that's going to transform them into different numbers.
Of course, this could have been end times two or n square root, whatever you want.
I can also the number before I include it within my list.
Other things I can do.
I can incorporate an F to decide on every number if it will incorporate that number or not.
Let me show you.
At the beginning we left only this regular N without any modification.
So we're saying add a number for every number that you find in this range.
As long as the number multiplied by two is greater than ten.
So not just any number is going to meet my condition here.
And when we do this, see, not everybody enters here.
We only have six, eight and ten Y.
So the first number in this range is zero.
If I multiply it by two, it's not greater than ten, it's zero.
So that one didn't go in and so on.
And if I want, I can add else.
So we can have an alternative for the numbers that didn't meet the condition.
I can do something else in those cases.
Well, we're going to do this in two steps.
I'm going to add the L's here, and I'm going to say that if the number is not greater than ten, then
print the word no.
But as you're saying, this is throwing me some errors here because once you incorporate the else,
this doesn't go here anymore.
So we're going to select it from the if.
All the way to the end.
And we're going to cut it and we're going to paste it after the first end.
So now the reading looks a little bit less readable.
In fact, it's less readable, but it's logical.
It says that here where it will incorporate N as long as n times two is greater than ten.
And if that's not the case, we'll put the word no for every NW that's in the range that we have here.
And if I print it out, we have no, no, no.
For the first ones they didn't meet the F condition and then six, eight, ten and so on.
So I insist.
The more complex this is and the more we economize in terms of code, the more efficient it becomes.
But many times the cost is the readability.
It's not easy to come here and read this and understand it when we can say that that's one of the most
important values in Python readability.
So if you're not comfortable with this, remember, you can always go back to the for approach.
So let's look at a more practical example of real life usage.
Suppose I have a list of measures in FTS.
You know, it's a measure that it's not used in all countries, but in some.
So I have a list with ten feet 20, 30, 40 and 50.
Also suppose that I want to create a list that contains values in meters.
So let's call it meters.
It's an empty list.
Finally, suppose that I want this meter's list to contain the same measures that we have in feet,
but transformed into its equivalent in meters.
So I do this by having to transform each number, by multiplying it by 3.281.
That's the way we do it.
Now try to think about it for a moment.
Pause the video if you want and try to do it by yourself.
Just using list comprehension.
Let me show you how I would do it.
What I want to have here is a list composed of F four feet multiplied by 0.3048 for each foot that I
find in the feet list.
And with that, I should now have my list of meters equivalent to the feet in my first list.
So let's print it out so we can see it on the screen.
What we print out here is meters, of course.
And if we run it, we have the measurements that we wanted that match the feet in the first list.
And we actually made a loop, but on a single line very handy and so far a little bit readable.
The day is coming to an end now, and we've seen everything we needed to learn in order to meet the
challenge for the next lecture.
So I'll be waiting for you there and we can talk about it and you can start thinking about our next
program.
See you there.