Well, then, given that my application is going to be a system to manage pending tasks, what are we
going to need to have is a database that stores all the tasks created by the user.
This database will have to contain a record for each task that is created and it must be structured,
taking into account several columns in order to assign different attributes to the tasks such as the
user who created it.
It's title if it is complete or pending the creation date, etc. well then our website needs to have
a table for the tasks and the tables must be created inside this model's P file models are basically
for building tables in Django, and for each table you want to create, you must create a class that
represents a table inside the models dot p file.
Basically, each class that we are going to create inside models is going to be a table and its attributes
would be like its columns or its fields.
So let's create our first model or table, creating a class called Task.
For this to be a model, we must pass it the following in its parenthesis Models dot model with a capital
letter and now we enter the class with this clarification.
Python will understand that this is a model and now we're going to create some attributes and then we're
going to assign value to them.
The first attribute is going to be user, which is going to be equal to and this is going to be left
empty for now.
It's also going to have a title, a description, an attribute called completed to assign a value of
true or false so that each record contains that information about the task.
And another attribute is going to be created to hold the date and time that the task were created.
Okay.
These are the fields or columns that are going to contain all the records that we load in the task table.
So let's start defining how each of these data will be stored.
The user field exists because we want tasks to be assigned to specific users by default.
So we're going to need to import a module built into Django, which is used to handle users.
Don't forget that Django is a library specialized in designing websites, so it has many tools that
will automate many tasks.
One of them is for managing users.
So we're going to import it from Django, dot, contrib, dot or dot models, and we're going to import
the user element.
So now we can have this table provided by Django.
Well, a user can create many tasks.
Federico would be one of the users and there could be another user called Fill and so on.
And each of the users is going to have the possibility of creating many tasks.
So in database logic, this is what we could call a one to many relationship.
This means that a single item in the list of users can have many tasks that correspond to that user.
So here inside user, we're going to say that is going to be equal to model's dot foreign key.
So what does foreign key mean that when different records appear in the task table with the same user,
we will be able to associate them with each other because the field user will be considered a field
key.
A field in which many records can belong to the same element, in this case, to the same user.
So if three tasks appear with the user name Federico, a table will know that they are not three different
Federico, but the same one.
And if at some point we ask to see the tasks of the user, Federico will be able to see a link to them
because the field user is a field that contains the foreign key.
So each different user will generate the new key and the repeated users will be associated to the key
that has already been generated for that user.
So now let's get some user parameters.
User is going to respond to user with a capital letter, which is this library that we have just incorporated.
So now we're going to define an attribute called on delete.
So whatever we put as a value here is what's going to happen if the user is deleted.
Let's say Peter created three tasks and then for some reason we delete the user.
Peter.
What's going to happen to the tasks that Peter created?
Let's put here models dot cascade, which means that when a user is deleted, his tasks will also be
deleted.
So the next attribute that we're going to define in user is the attribute to NULL.
If we set true, this means that the value user can be empty.
The attribute blank is also going to be true.
And this means that if we make a form that asks for a record, this record can be blank.
And if we set it to false, it would not allow it.
These are ways of configuring how the field is going to behave within this table.
The next field is title and we're going to tell it to respond to whatever is inside model's dot char
field.
This also has a number of attributes that we can specify.
The only one we're going to specify here is going to be max length, which determines the maximum number
of characters the title can have.
And we're going to set it to 200.
Now let's set description.
This is going to be a text that the user can add when creating a task to explain what the task is about.
Well, this is going to respond to model's text field.
It's similar to Char field, but it has some extra attributes.
And the only thing we're going to copy here is null and blank, because this field can also be empty.
So now let's go to complete it.
Our task can be complete or incomplete.
The user is going to report this through models dot boolean field, and we're going to establish that
by default the value of each of the tasks that we create is false.
And that is to say that at the moment of being created, our tasks will be incomplete.
This makes sense.
Finally created is going to answer to model's date time field because we said that this field has to
define on what date and at what time each of the tasks has been created.
And we're going to set auto now add to true so that by default when a task is created it will be automatically
assigned the date and time of that moment.
So this field will not be filled manually by the user.
And to close this.
In this class, we need to define an STR value.
Let's see if you remember this.
If at some point we want to print a task object, we're going to need to have configured what is going
to be printed.
That's what we're going to set now.
A string that represents textually a task.
So def double underscore str and double underscore.
Again, we're going to ask for self and what this is going to give us through return is going to be
self title.
That is to say that if at some point we ask a task to be printed that will be printed is what is in
the title.
And finally, we're going to define a class matter inside our class task that establishes an ordering.
That is to say how the tasks are going to be ordered inside our table.
We're going to establish that the order of the tasks in our table is determined by the completed field.
Why?
So the tasks that are already completed can be sent to the bottom of the list.
And now we need to do something else with this.
Once we've already created our table, we have to do something called migration, which means that we're
going to send this table to the database of our site.
And there are two things we have to do to migrate our database.
One is to create the file.
So we're going to come to the console and we're going to call Python Manage dot P and we're going to
call the command make migrations.
We run it.
And this has generated a new folder inside our application, which is this migrations folder which if
we open it up, has a file called 0001 initial dot p y and if I open it up, I see that it contains
all the fields from our task table which has already been migrated and so already exists inside our
file.
Now we're going to migrate it to our site and for that we're going to call Python, manage P and call
migrate.
Notice that when I hit enter one more migration is generated and remember that we did the initial migration
when we created our project.
If you remember at that time, it migrated a bunch of tables that Django already had preconfigured to
use anywhere.
Well, what just happened now is that one more table was migrated, which is the one we just created,
which we saved in the 0001 initial file.
And that's the one that just migrated to our site in order to see how this is reflected on our site.
Let's run the server again.
You know, Python managed API run server and this allows us to go to our site.
But now we're going to go to admin.
And here you should see that the table that we just created, but you can't see it yet because it still
needs to be registered.
So let's go back to pie chart.
Let's open the file admin p y where we register our models.
And how do we register it?
First we import it from dot models.
Import task.
And here we're going to ask it to look inside admin site register.
And then we pass it to task in brackets, which is the table we want to register.
Once we've done that, we go back to our site, refresh it and to.
Here's a table called tasks.
This is not yet visible on the site, but only inside our admin page.
So if we click here, we see that our base is empty.
But we can add new tasks.
So let's add one here.
User is going to be wind ten, which is the automatic one, and this has been added thanks to importing
it into user.
Let's give this task a title.
It can be mowing the lawn and let's put a description on the backyard.
Let's put that.
It is now complete and this has been generated.
Notice with the way we have built our fields.
There are different ways here.
When we put in user, it generated this list.
When we put title with a char field, it generated this box for 200 characters.
And when we put in the text field, it generated this space to write the description.
And when we put in a boolean field for the completed field, it generated this checkbox.
Since we set the date and time to be automatically created, there is nothing here for the user to complete.
So I'm going to save this task that I just generated.
My first task, which is mowing the lawn, is now displayed.
We're going to generate two more all for my wind ten user.
The second one is going to be milking the cow.
Here, let's clarify that.
We have to fill two buckets and leave it incomplete and save.
And let's create a third task also for Win ten and the title can be By Tomatoes.
And here, make sure they are red and you can see how this works.
So we leave it incomplete and save it.
Here we have our three tasks.
So this has been the way we've created a database to run backstage on our site.
Now let's see what the next lesson has in store for us.
I'll see you there.