So in the previous lecture we learned how to extract a paragraph from a website.
We use this code to do so.
In today's lesson, we'll learn how to extract a whole class.
In short, what we learned before can be applied to all the elements we want to extract, but we need
to master the syntax used in web scraping.
So that's why you'll find this chart attached to the lessons.
You'll see different special characters that allow us to identify different elements in HTML or CSS
code.
We use quotes to write the names of specific tag.
So if we put super select and we add in quotes and brackets, the word div will be able to extract all
the elements containing the div tag.
We use hash tag to inform the python syntax that we want to look for an ID.
So if we add hash tag and an ID name between quotes will obtain all the elements containing the same
ID as the text we wrote.
If we add a dot instead of hash tag would be looking for a class, and so we'd receive all the elements
containing a class with a specific name.
If we use space to separate two words inside quotes followed by the word div as first word like the
example in the chart and span, a second word will receive all the elements named span that are inside
a div element.
If we use the greater than symbol, it means we want all the elements named span that are inside a development
without anything in between.
These are the symbols that you'll learn to use in order to extract whatever you want to extract.
So let's go back to the site.
And for example, if I want to extract all the elements of the section, learn creative skills, which
contains some texts.
First I need to inspect so as to recognize this element.
So here's the inspection.
If I post myself on the code blocks, I'm able to check which element each code block corresponds to.
There are single paragraphs which are titles of type H five, but if I scroll up, I get to the block
that corresponds to this section.
It seems like the name of this class is Fusion Text, Fusion Dash Text Dash one.
So let's try to extract this class back in py charm.
I already have got this website stored in the result variable and result text has been stored in the
soup variable which contains a beautiful soup element.
Here's why I have to start working.
The variable I'm about to create won't be my underscore P anymore, but central underscore block.
Central underscore block will be equal to soup dot select and will begin to use the syntax we just learned.
If we want to obtain a whole class, the special character we have to use is the dot.
If my memory serves me right.
The name of the class containing all the texts is fusion dash text, dot fusion dash text, dash one.
Let's use this then.
So if we print central block, we should obtain everything that's inside that block.
Will it work?
Let's see.
We execute.
And here we have all this information which is needed inside that block.
It can be text, images and so on.
Why?
This is marvelous.
According to the chart, if we want to find all the elements that are inside another element, we should
use the space in order to separate the block name from the element type.
In this case, it is H five, which is the title that's inside our block.
So if we look for this and execute it, we'll get a list of all the five titles that are present in
our block.
All right.
So remember, this is a list.
Therefore, if we want to find each element of the list, like the index, zero will only receive what's
in the first element and that would be unlimited access, etc..
So let's go back to the site where here it is and the element we have extracted.
And yet we don't want this one element.
We want all of them.
So in order to extract them all, we'll need a loop.
So let's delete this print and create a loop that for each h in central underscore block, it will only
print h four now.
And if we execute it, both elements are printed.
And even though they're not inside a list, they still have tags and style instructions.
However, we want only text.
So in that case, instead of showing H, we have to make it show each dot get text which we previously
learn to use in order to delete tags.
So if we execute, it will receive nothing more than text unlimited access and then learn video.
So this is how we traverse a class and obtain exactly what we want.
These are just examples.
And for our next lesson, we'll continue to illustrate since we're going to learn how to extract images.
And that will be fascinating.
So stay tuned for more of this.