Our application contains a list of all the products and their chat buttons.
Now we have to add an input box beside each product name so that the user can specify how many items
the customers bought.
So we need to add a third column to each list and we're going to do it with loops and create food.
Items will create two more lists because we'll need a series of variables which store text boxes and
another variable which stores the text of those text boxes.
So Food Box will have an empty list for text boxes and food text will also have an empty list, but
for text created inside the text boxes, then we'll enter our loop again.
Keeping in mind that we need two blocks of text that are separated, the first one is to create check
buttons and the second one goes before counter and will be to create input boxes.
That way everything is neatly arranged.
Instead of having this mess of properties and attributes, we're going to arrange them vertically like
columns.
As a result, we'll be able to display what's inside of each element more clearly.
I think this is way much better.
So now let's begin with our input boxes.
Let's create an element for food box, dot, append, and we're going to add an empty element just so
that it exists.
Now let's create a variable for food text using append so that we can call it later.
Now it's time to call Food Box along with its index counter, which will be different according to each
loop iteration and this will be equal to input box.
So what do you call this element inside TK into?
It's called entry.
Consequently, each element of the list will be an input box.
And what will our input box have?
It will have a location.
It will be in food panel.
Then it will have a font equal to Dosis, which is the one we're using.
This time the size will be 18 and it will be in bold.
The edge will be equal to one like the one we've done so far.
Width equals six and finally its state will be equal to disabled.
Therefore this box will be deactivated so that we're not able to enter an amount until the checkbox
is activated.
There's one fundamental attribute missing that would be text variable.
In this way, we can associate it with a text variable, which in this case will be food text with its
index counter.
So the text in this box will be linked to the corresponding text variable and we've created our input
box.
Now we have to place it inside the panel that contains all our elements.
It must always be next to each checkbox on the same row.
So instead of putting it in column zero like checkboxes, we're going to put them in column one, which
is the one on the right.
So food box index counter grid will be equal to row, equal to the number of counter so that the value
decreases as we move forward.
The column will be the same for all the input boxes and it will be column one this time.
So this should be enough in order to have input boxes for each food, let's execute it.
And here we have chicken and its input box deactivated.
We can't type anything there.
Then there's the rest of the plates and their text boxes.
Now we have to do the same with drink and dessert.
I'm sure you already know how to do it.
It's basically the same as we've done so far.
So let's copy these two variables and paste them on drink and type drink.
We're also going to paste them on dessert and change these words.
Then we have to re-establish the structure of food, will copy, create check buttons and add drink
to it.
So we'll create some line breaks in these properties so that they look more attractive.
If you already got the hang of this, you can do this without watching or listening to me.
It will be better for you.
So let's copy this block in order to create input boxes and paste it on drink.
Replace food with drink and that's it.
Now we have to do the same with dessert.
Let's organize these properties in Python.
Readability is paramount.
The better you can read your code, the faster you will be as a programmer.
So we'll create the input boxes here by pasting the same block and will replace each food with dessert.
Excellent.
Now we execute it and we'll see that all of our products have input boxes a complete success.
Congratulations.
So let's go to the next lesson so as to take the next step.