Finally, it's time to start writing, and we're going to start by learning how to use print one of
the most basic and common statements in Python.
When we say print in Python, we don't mean print like on paper using a printer.
We mean print on the screen.
So print actually means to show to display on the screen.
And as I told you before, Python is a very simple language to understand.
So if we want Python to display or print on a screen a sentence like Hello World, for example, we
just say print Hello World.
As you can see, the print structure is very simple.
The key word, print.
And then we put in parentheses whatever we want to print.
If it is text, it will go between quotation marks and there can be double or single quotation marks.
It doesn't matter if they are numbers or other functions, and we do it without quotation marks.
But don't worry about that because we are going to deal with this later.
For now, let's go to pie chart with Federico so that we can learn together how to use the word print
to write your first text.
And so it's time to write our first line of code.
We are empire charm.
We have a space here to write.
We're going to enlarge it by clicking here in project so that this column folds out and we can see more
clearly.
Space to write code.
We're going to begin to use the statement print so we write it directly after typing print.
Here you can see that we get a help that tells us that print is followed by the bracket signs and inside
we can put values.
These helpers are very useful.
It shows them for pi charm all the time.
If you come to the points and click, you will see that you can sort by name.
But the most important thing is that you have a quick documentation or a quick definition, and these
are very useful when you're working with code that is starting to get a little bit complicated.
But for now, let's stick with print.
We're going to open the brackets.
And we said that we're going to write the text.
We're going to write with quotation marks, whatever is inside.
And what we are going to put here is the expression Hello world.
With this, it would be enough so that when we execute it, we can see that Hello World is printed on
the screen.
But first I want you to notice the colors.
As you can see, print is written in blue because it is a key word.
Then the brackets appear in a different color.
So you can easily identify when the content of print begins and ends.
And the content, the text we have entered is in green.
Then what follows is to run this program to see what appears in console, to run it.
We're going to come here to run.
And it gives us a choice whether which file we want to run.
Main was the file that appeared at the beginning, which is generated automatically.
It is not the one we want to run.
The one we want to run is first project.
So once we choose it, the console appears here and it shows us the path of this file.
Then the result of the execution of our program that shows us Hello World.
And here it simply says the IS has finished executing the code so as already exited the execution is
very simple.
It only has one command.
It says Hello world.
So I want you to notice what happens if I change something was with respect to the quotation marks.
Let's say I remove the last quotation mark.
In that case, you can see now that everything is green and it marks a serious error.
This time it is in red because not having told Python when the text ended, I thought that the brackets
were part of the text and included it.
So there it is, marking in error.
It is normal that this can happen frequently or that you forget the brackets, for example.
It will also warn you and that you would be the most common of errors for this type of text.
In fact, if we want to execute it without the quotation marks, let's suppose that we have not seen
the error that announces it and we go to execute.
This time we can do it from here because first project has already been loaded and we can click here
on Run.
Well, the result now is no longer.
Hello world is a syntax error.
This is how you are going to read the errors when they appear.
You're going to see what kind of error you have.
And we can actually see in the example of a text that is marking is here that this error where the error
is apparently located.
So part time is quite clever helping us solve our code problems.
So we return the quotes and now a code is back to normal.
Note that in print you can write whatever you want and some considerations if you wanted to write something
with quotes.
For example Hello world I say hello.
And I want to put it like that with quotes.
Well, what problem I'm going to have here that when I want a quotation mark to appear in my text,
unfortunately, Python is going to misinterpret these quotation marks and it's going to think that I'm
ending the text here and I start again here.
And this hello doesn't understand it.
It marks it as an error.
It's not a word that Python understands.
So when you want to put quotation marks inside your text, we can use single quotation marks and Python
will differentiate from the double quotation marks and understand that they are simply part of the text.
You can also do the other way around, put single quotes outside and double quotes inside.
For text interpretation purposes, it is the same thing.
So if I run this now, you'll see that it says Hello world.
I say hello.
Print.
As I explained in print, not only text but also numbers.
And here I can put 100 if I run it.
What will come out here is the number 100.
And the numbers do not need quotation marks.
It will print them as they are.
You can also actually print operations.
If I put in 100 plus 50 and run this, that's going to come out here as 150.
If I wanted the operation to show, I could have put quotation marks at the beginning, quotation marks
at the end show it's a text and then we see 100 plus 50 and not the result.
When you put numbers without the quotation marks directly, what print does is to execute the operation
that it finds inside.
This is all to start with working with print.
So I thank you again for joining us in this lecture and we will learn a little bit more about this in
the next.