In this lesson, we're going to start getting to know the second pillar of data science, which is the
PANDAS Library, with which from Python, we can work with our data in a more elaborate way than with
NumPy.
In fact, pandas, as we already said, is built on top of numpy.
And as we also said before, it is a kind of python excel.
So here you have to read a little introduction in this booklet, which I will also leave for you to
connect from your own drive and from the link that I will leave you in this lesson.
Here you have the official documentation of pandas and don't forget to visit it.
It will be your ally.
These libraries are so immense that we cannot go through them all in their richness.
But I'm going to show you how to get to know them so you'll be able to start using them as soon as you
finish this lesson.
The first thing we do, like any of the library we need to incorporate into our code, is to import
it.
We put import pandas and by custom we import it as PD so that we can then run it under that abbreviated
name.
So first, let's see, what are the series Inside Pandas?
PANDAS has some data devices, mainly series and data frames.
Let's start by looking at what a series is.
So we're going to create a series of numbers in this case, and we're going to find it's mean we're
going to create numbers, which is going to be the same as P, the Object Point series.
And here we're going to create a series inside the brackets.
But as a list, we're going to put one, two, three, five, 67, 35, 235 and 62.
Then inside the same cell, we're going to call numbers and we're going to apply a method called Mean.
This method is going to give us the mean of this series.
So by executing, we can know that the mean of this series of numbers is 51.25.
For now, we're not discovering anything that we can't do in other ways.
But now we're going to try to find the sum of all the numbers that we have in our series.
We do this by calling numbers again and applying a different method, which is called Sum.
We execute and the sum is 410.
These series objects have many more methods and parameters that you can discover by playing around,
you know, by putting the dart and seeing what it has or by going to the documentation.
So now let's create a different series, a series that doesn't have numbers but strings.
We're going to call it colors, and it's going to be the same as a panda object of type series.
And it's going to have a list of strings which are going to be red, yellow and green.
We're going to leave it with three elements.
So we've run this and now colors already exists.
So we're going to display this list, we call it.
And here's the list.
See how it looks.
It no longer looks like a string of elements, one next to the other, but they appear in this little
table or mini table, which is sorted with the index number, then shows the value and finally tells
us that the data type is object.
Now we're going to create a different but similar series that is going to contain types of cars.
We're going to call it cars, and it's going to be the same as a panda object that has a series that
contains a list with, for example, sedan, SUV and pickup.
We call it execute.
And we have here another table with the same format, but with different content.
And here comes the interesting part.
I told you that PANDAS has, on the one hand the series, but it also has the data frames.
A data frame is a set or a structure of organized data.
And here we're going to create it by combining the two series that we have created so far, which were
colors and cars, and how do we create it?
We set another name, which can be car table, which is going to be the same as a panda object, which
this time is not going to be a series but a dataframe.
So inside the parentheses, we're going to create a dictionary.
So we call the braces to put the key, which in this turn is going to be the one that is going to appear
as the header of the column, which is going to be called car type.
We'll put a colon as in any dictionary, and the value that this key is going to contain is going to
be the variable cars that we have created above.
So we put a comma to go to the next element of our dictionary whose key is going to be called color.
And this is also going to be the header of the column, and the content is going to be whatever is in
the variable colors.
So we already have a car table to which we're going to call to be able to visualize.
We execute it.
And look what we have here.
It's the double entry table that has rows ranging from 0 to 2 and also some headers which are the keys
of our dictionary and the content organized in a single table.
Data frames are very powerful, but not so powerful if they're construction depends on so much manual
data entry.
So far, we can't do anything in a more practical way than in Excel.
So why is it useful to work with pandas?
Well, to work with much larger databases, which you can directly import and analyze in a way that
other programs do not allow us to do.
So here we're going to move on to the second part, and which we're going to see how to connect to this
notebook that we have here with our drive disk so that we can take any file that we have from there
and we can bring it here.
So we're going to leave that for the next lesson, where we're going to learn how to connect our notebooks
to our drive files.