In this lesson, we're going to do step three, which is to compare the faces and then measure the distance
or difference between the two faces.
So let's place ourselves before show images to move on to the next step.
And here we're going to perform comparison.
So in a variable called result, we're going to store the result of this comparison.
The result is going to be equal to the face recognition object that contains the compare faces method.
And this method asks for a list of images to be compared with the original image.
But as we in this example, don't have a list of images but only one image, we still have to put it
between braces because it has to be an object of type list.
Even if it only has one element.
Then the picture that we're going to put inside this list is coded Face A, which is the one we use
as a base.
And the next element is the photo with which we are going to compare it, which is also a single photo,
and we put coded face B, this is what the comparison is going to be made with so that we can see on
the screen what the result of this comparison is.
We go to print result and we execute it.
And here we have again received the two photos with their rectangles and everything.
And now we see in the console that the result of the comparison is true.
This means that it is true that these two people are the same person.
And how does Python reach this conclusion that it is true because it has established a point of comparison
or distance between both faces.
The system evaluates a series of factors between the two photos, calculates them according to metrics
it has established for this purpose, and comes up with a number that represents the distance between
the two faces.
If that distance is less than 0.6, it means that both people are the same person.
So we're going to look a little bit more in depth at this limit, and we will even learn how to modify
it.
What we're going to do now is to take Picture A, which is the picture that we have loaded as controlled
picture.
But this time we're going to compare it with picture, see, which is the picture of Brad Pitt.
This will allow us to reach new and painful conclusions.
So let's see.
Here come the two pictures.
And now we see my friend Brad and me both with the rectangle where our faces are recognized.
But the result is false.
This is very bad news for Brad.
I'm so sorry, Brad.
You officially don't look like me.
But maybe if you grow a beard, you might stand a chance.
Anyway, you can put different pictures.
Pictures of your family members, pictures of friends, pictures of people you know, and check to see
if it recognizes different people or not.
It is interesting to play with different photos of the same person in different positions, in different
environments, with different lighting, etc. to see if the face recognition can properly identify if
it is the same person.
So in the next lesson, there is something great about face recognition that will fascinate you.
And we're on our way.