So we've succeeded in getting the assistant to understand what we say and they can transform it into
text.
So all of this we can program in this function which I can make smaller as to not occupy so much space.
But before we do this, transform the voice into text, the code doesn't have any instructions about
what to do with our request.
So for now, it doesn't do anything.
It simply prints it on the screen.
So before we continue making our assistant do something with our request, we must also achieve the
opposite process.
We must succeed in transforming the response which our program is going to give us as a text so it can
return this response with the sound of a human voice.
So here we're going to delete this call, which was only to test if everything worked okay.
And now we're going to write a function that the assistant can be heard.
And we should define it as speed and it needs a parameter, which is the text it has to say.
So we call message in the parameter, and now we will need two or three lines of code.
The first will be and listen to this for Start Engine.
You would be saying what engine?
So the engine of ptsx3.
The tool needed by default so that we started.
So we can name this variable engine.
It's going to be the same as P T6 three and it starts with the method in it and then comes the code
for deliver message.
The engine is going to say our message.
Then engine is going to implement the method.
Run and wait.
So these two lines are in charge of what is said, that it is executed and that it waits.
So let's call, speak, and we're going to give it a phrase that could be our famous hello world.
If we execute it, it should say.
Hello world.
Did you hear it?
Marvelous.
I'm going to execute it again because I love it.
Hello, world.
Okay, so the voice you heard there is the voice I've programmed on my computer.
Every time I execute a program of text to voice, my computer's programmed to use the voice in English.
You must check that you have your computer configured to a voice in your language.
There are certain interesting considerations to remember when dealing with language.
And in the next lesson, we're going to see how to make this voice sound exactly how we want.