Bugs are definitely going to happen.
I don't want to be a prophet of doom, but nobody is perfect and bugs are definitely going to happen,
especially when the user ends up using your code in an unexpected way.
Although we cannot avoid errors, we can anticipate what the most common errors might be and prepare
our code so that it does not break every time there is an error.
On top of that, we can also pre establish how our program should behave when an unexpected error occurs.
So far, every time an error occurs in your code, for example, you try to add an integer and a string.
The program there is an error message and stops completely.
Thanks to error handling, we can make the code continue executing the rest of the code without stopping.
Error handling can be done thanks to three key words which are try exception.
And finally we use try to tell Python.
Try running the following code to see if it flows smoothly or if any problems occur.
Then we use except to tell Python if an error occurs instead of interrupting the code and displaying
your ugly red messages, please run this code.
Which is the same thing as saying Python.
Let me take care of informing the user about the problem and you go on with the rest of the code and
then we can use finally to say it doesn't matter if there is an error or not.
Whatever happens, always run this.
Let's jump into the computer and see what this looks like in real life so it will understand error handling
better will start by committing errors.
So let's create a very simple function named addition which will print something like ten plus ten.
Nothing can go wrong once the numbers were added up will print.
Thanks for adding quite simple.
Then we call it execute it and things couldn't get easier.
It reads 20 and thanks for adding and the code has ended.
This program contains no errors.
However, we'll let the user decide which numbers to enter.
So instead of typing, print ten plus ten will make the variable n one be equal to an input integer
from the user which will be asked for the first number and we'll also create the variable and two that's
equal to an input integer from the user who will be asked for the second number.
So let's keep it simple.
After this, we'll print n one plus n two and this can go wrong so everything is ready to be executed.
We do it and now the user enter the number, say 15.
But imagine that instead of entering number ten, they make a mistake and type ten with words.
So what's going to happen?
Well, that is obviously an error.
It's a value error, which basically means that the software cannot convert our value to integer since
it is not compatible with any number.
So this is not possible.
The software stopped processing and it didn't execute our line reading.
Thanks for adding.
Therefore it would be useful to have means for covering the possibilities of errors in programs where
we depend on the user doing the right thing.
So the structure try accept.
And finally that Phil showed you in the video is written as follows first type try and colon then press
enter and you'll go to the next line which is already indented, and then you'll enter the code you
want to check.
Secondly, type.
Except in order to type the code that will be executed if there's an error.
And third type, finally, which is the code that will be executed anyway.
And there's one more word we can use here, which is else you can type it after, except because if
you enter else, you'll be saying, this is the code I want to try.
This is the code that will be executed if there's an error.
And this is the code that will be executed if there's no error.
So this means you can add extra code to try, since if there is no error, the try code will be executed.
Then you can add extra code in case everything went fine.
So in the case of addition, first will delete this call and open it inside.
Try.
I want this to be tested by the code.
So we'll call addition here.
And if our addition doesn't work, will want a print that says something went wrong.
So we're not being very specific.
We're just pointing out that something went wrong.
So then else, what happens if the addition works just fine?
Besides showing the result and giving thanks, the software could also show a message saying something
like, You did great.
That'd be nice.
And finally, we'll be executed regardless of what happens.
It won't matter whether there's an error or not.
We can type something like that all to know that we've gotten to that point in our code.
Well, we have everything ready to be tested, so let's execute this and we'll make an error intentionally
by typing 13 first, then letter D, and we'll press enter.
So something went wrong, that's all.
In other words, our software tried to do this, and since there was an error, it printed accept and
finally leaving else out.
So let's do it again without errors.
I'll type 23 and 12 and so it says 35.
Thanks for adding.
You did great.
Else was executed because there wasn't any exception.
And that's all which is the finally was executed regardless of the result.
So in fact, when checking for errors you'll surely use try and accept but else and finally are not
that necessary.
You can even use one of them.
You're most likely to use else more than finally, which is rarely applied, since it's not common that
someone wants to write a code without taking its result into account.
So I also want you to see that there are several types of exceptions that you can create.
Let's comment out this so it's not executed.
And now let's call addition and execute it.
And if we enter a letter, we get a value error, which is a type of error.
Now imagine that we want to concatenate this with an integer such as n one.
We already know we'll get an error, so I'll execute and type something like 12 plus 12 and I'll get
an error anyway because I cannot concatenate the string with an integer like this.
Now I get a type error, which is another type of error.
There are several types of them.
So if you go to the documents and look for built in exceptions, you'll find large list of specific
exceptions along with their descriptions.
For instance, you can find type error and value error.
So preparing your code so that it can handle several types of errors is something you can do easily.
So let's delete this addition and uncomment this block of code.
This is how you can prepare your code in.
Except if you get the type error such as when concatenating incorrectly, you can type a message that
reads you are trying to concatenate different types.
And why would we add a second?
Except because we want to handle a value error, which is the one we got when trying to convert a string
to an integer without the proper value so we can return another message such as this is not a number
and those are different messages.
So let's execute this without errors.
Let's type 12 and 15.
We couldn't concatenate and we got a more specific message.
It tells us we cannot concatenate different types.
The software handled a specific error and returned a message according to that error.
But if we make another error, such as entering 34 and then hello, it tells us that this is not a number
because this is a value error and our code has been prepared to return a message according to value
errors.
So in this way, you can prepare your code so that it can handle each of the errors on the long list.
And as you can see, our code can be prepared for any unexpected event.
Now that we know how to do this, we can make sure the user has entered a number and nothing more without
typing so much code.
So let's create a function named ask number which won't require parameters.
It will only require that the user enters a number through an input.
So we used to do it using while, which iterated over several things and then we had to use break and
continue.
And type a lot of text.
So now we can make this long story short.
So let's type while true and be sure to enter some command to make this loop stop.
This loop will verify if number is equal to the integer of the user's input.
When we require the user to enter a number, we'll now create an except we don't have to point out the
specific error.
So let's keep it simple.
This accept will be accompanied by a print that says that is not a number and we'll also create an else.
If the user enters a number, the software will print a string literal that says you have entered number
and it will return that number using the number variable.
So we mustn't forget that after the user has answered correctly, we need to add a break and remember
that break stops the loop.
So it would be the only way to get out of there.
In order to check if we're getting out correctly, we'll create a print outside the loop that says thanks.
Then we call the function ask number and execute it.
So it's asking for a number.
So I'll try to commit all kinds of errors.
I'll enter feed.
That is not the number.
Enter a number.
So the loop started again.
I'll enter Q W The same happens, I'll enter at It's not possible.
Now I'm going to answer correctly by entering five and it says you have entered number five.
Well, this was a way to take advantage of error handling.
We can make sure the user enters what is expected and that we do not commit errors which can make our
program crash.
So that's all for now.
And thanks so much for being here and we'll see you in the next lesson.