Now it's time to work with images.
Let's click on photography so as to get to this site, which contains several images we can extract.
So the goal of this lesson is to try to extract all the images on this site.
At the same time, we don't want to extract extra images like this logo here.
We just want the images of the courses that will be our mission.
So images are often stored in a site that we can access through a URL link which can contain the extensions
JPEG or PNG.
This is not always the case though.
For example, if we want to inspect this image, we just access the code and we'll find the tag that
begins with IMG.
There are some properties and a class element which is preceded by CRC for Source.
It is precisely where we'll find our image if we enter this very site.
So let's click on the link and there's a window that shows the image from the website which is displayed
thanks to the URL link in source.
So if we want to extract images from a website, we have to look for the IMG tag and find the source
so as to get the URL link.
So we're able to download this image now.
Do you take into account that you can only extract images from websites which grant you permission or
websites whose images are copyright free?
Since this website belongs to Phil, you're free to download its images in order to practice.
Okay, we want to extract all the images of the courses from this site.
So let's go back to the code we're working with and let's delete all this to begin again.
Let's change the URL since we've changed websites and we copy and paste this link here.
So that result stores a requests which corresponds to the site we're interested in and then sends the
link to soup.
So now we need to figure out how we're going to find those images.
Every time you scrape a web, you have to carefully observe the site and find out which elements will
help you with your task.
In this case, the first thing we can notice is that the images are inside an IMG tag, so we'll start
to scrape there.
Then let's create a variable named images which will be equal to a soup object that will select all
the IMG tags.
Now let's see what happens.
We'll print images.
And there's a list that starts with square bracket and contains several elements which are hard to read
as they're really close to one another.
So we'll create a loop in order to see this better.
So for each item in images I will print.
I am.
Let's execute and our elements have been rearranged.
There's one on top of the other.
So what do we have here?
A list of various elements that begin with IMG tag.
We have to verify if these are the images we want.
So note that each element says IMG and then alt, which means alternate text.
That is a kind of description of the image and class is present in all the images.
Okay.
Let's see.
The first image appears to be the site logo, the one that's up here.
We're not interested in that one.
On both the second and the third image correspond to the logo.
And so the fourth is one of the images we're looking for.
In order to identify the ones that we want, we have to spot some difference.
It's likely that the class tag contains that information, so note that the class tags of the logo image
say fusion dash standard dash logo, and that the class tags of the images of the courses say img dash
responsive.
So that's the pattern in all the images corresponding to the courses, the class tag, and we should
keep an eye on that.
The images we're going to extract are the ones containing that tag.
So let's go back here and replace IMG tags with classes.
So we put dot and img dash responsive.
If we print this, we'll only obtain the images corresponding to the courses.
So we've kind of isolated the images that we wanted in the first place.
Now we need to find a way to download them on our computers.
So since this is a list, instead of creating a loop to see the elements, we can ask for the index.
Zero of this soup and print images.
Note that this element contains an IMG tag, a class, some image measurements and the source which
is the link to the image.
That's the link.
We need to download that image on our computer.
So let's add RC here at the end so as to look for the object source.
As regards to the object in index one will obtain the image url.
Perfect.
We're getting there.
So how do we download the URL on our computer?
Look at this because it's a nail biter.
Let's make a new request that can be image one and we'll just store the image.
The first image.
Then we can make a loop in order to do the same with all the images.
Now we'll type requests, dot get and call the URL that we found in images.
So let's type images.
And if we print image one, what do we obtain?
We simply obtain response to 200 not interested in this.
In order to extract whatever we want, we need to call the element content.
And if we print this will receive a very long file, which is impossible for us to interpret as it is
a binary file.
This is how computers read, decodes and stores in image.
With this, we can tell our computer, you need to convert this code into an image and store it.
So how do we do that?
We delete this print and remember we're going to use content.
So let's create a new file named F that will be equal to open.
We can put a file name like my underscore.
Image jpeg.
Try to use the same extension as the original file.
And the opening method we're going to use is not just W which we employed to write, it will be WB,
which stands for write binary.
So far, we're creating an empty file.
Now we're going to type in it.
Let's put f dot.
Right.
And what are we going to write?
Image one dot content.
So all of this text we have here, the way in which our computer reads an image is going to be stored
in the file we've created, which is my underscore image dot jpeg.
So let's make sure to close it with F close.
And if we execute it, we won't see anything on the screen, just the previous print.
But if we go to the DE 11 where we save our projects, we'll find my image, which is on the computer.
So if you want to save it in a different place, remember to go to your files name here and add colon
and a path in order to add a new folder.
So if we put this inside a loop, we'll be able to download all the images that we find on the website
we're working with.
And this has been quite demanding yet amazing.
You've got a valuable resource that lets you scrape websites in order to extract all the images you
want.
Always make sure to have the website's permission.
And let's go to the next lesson.