We already know how to make comparisons between two values.
Now we are going to go up one level and learn how to compare more than two values at the same time.
For example, I have three variables that contain numbers, and I want to know if A is greater than
B and at the same time, if it's less than C, that is.
I want to know if it meets both conditions.
Or maybe I want to know if A is greater than B or if it's greater than C.
That is.
I want to know if it meets even one of these conditions.
While to do these and other combinations, I'm going to need how to use logical operators.
The three logical operators are the first one is and you know, to say, I want a strawberry and vanilla
ice cream, which means that both conditions must be met.
Then the second value is, or as when you say, buy me a strawberry or vanilla ice cream, which means
that if one of those two conditions is met, it's all right.
Finally, the third one is not as when we say we want an ice cream.
That is not chocolate.
I know you want to see this in action.
So let's go over to the code.
So let's understand this thing about making combinations between comparison operators and logical operators.
Suppose that I have only one variable to store the result of two comparisons.
I want to compare whether four is less than five and at the same time I want to compare with a five
is less than six.
But as I said, I want a single variable to store the true or false value for these two comparisons.
I don't want two variables.
Well, one way to do it would be for me to have a variable here that is called my bool and it has to
check if four is less than five and if it is less than six.
This would be a direct comparison where I put the three values and actually if I print it, let's print
my bool and it's going to tell me, let's run logical operators and it's going to tell me that this
is true, because here I actually compare four, less than five and immediately the next operator compares
five with six.
And it works.
But this is not always going to work well for me.
I can also do this comparison changing this and it's going to give me false because four is less than
five and five is not greater than six.
Well, but there is a way to make this much more readable, first of all, and to adapt it to absolutely
all situations.
And this is through the logical operators, which, as we saw are and or and not.
And the way we're going to do it here is with the following.
So we have my ball that checks if four is less than five and also checks if five is greater than six
the word and then it turns red as you see, because it is a key word and allows us to evaluate that
this is false.
So why?
Because although four is less than five, five is not greater than six.
And when the two conditions are not met, the value of my bool is false.
For it to be true, the two conditions must be met.
The keyword is here to be sure that both conditions are met.
Then if the second comparison were that five is equal to two plus three, we print it.
It will say true because now we have two operations that are true.
For readability reasons, you will often find that this is very practical to put the operations in parentheses.
Notice now how much clearer it is to see what I'm doing here and you can use them or not.
The compiler will accept them either way, but sometimes it is convenient to make it easier to read.
Well, we can also make two comparisons that are of different types.
On one side, I check if 55 is equal to 55, and on the other side I check with strings if dog is equal
to dog.
And this will also give me that it is true because it does not matter that the operations that I'm comparing
are one of the other nature.
But now let's look at the operator that's called or.
Let's erase all of this.
And now I want to check if ten equals ten or if three equals three.
This is going to tell me true, because both comparisons are true.
But the interesting thing about this all is that if the first comparison were not true, let's say one
equals ten, which is false.
I printed out and it still tells me true because it doesn't care that both are true.
It only needs one to be true.
It wants to know of this one or this one is true.
So since this is this one is true because three equals three is going to tell me that it's true.
The only way for an or to give you false is for example.
The second comparison is also false.
Now, since neither is true, it can't be true in any way.
So now let's try it with a text.
Let's write some text here that is equal.
This is a variable, of course, to the sentence is short.
Very good.
And now we're going to give my ball the value of a word search.
I want to know if the word sentence is found in text.
And since the word sentence is in text, it's going to tell me that it's true.
But it can also search for two words at once.
So let's enclose this in parenthesis and say that I also want to know if the word short is in text.
And since these two comparisons are true, it's going to tell me that this is true.
If I had searched here for another word, for example, Python, which is not in the text, it would
tell me that it's false because the two conditions are not met unless I had put an or comparison value
here that allows me to make only one of them true.
So these are.
And and or the two logical values that most frequently used.
Now let's look at the not value and how does this work?
So we don't need our text anymore.
And we're going to look at a much simpler boolean that looks at whether A is equal to A and since it
is, of course we'll have a value of true a can prefix the comparison with the expression not as is
painted red.
It is a keyword and that will give me false.
Why?
Because it checks.
If it is not true that this comparison is correct, that we have a kind of double comparison.
First, it checks if the comparison is true or false, and then it returns the information.
If it is not, then here as this one is true, it returns that it is false.
And if this, for example, had been different, the comparison now we would receive a true because
it is a double negation a is not different from A, therefore this comparison is false.
But since we want to know the opposite of whatever has this information, it is going to tell us that
this is true here.
It can get a little complicated because we start with the double negations, negations, affirmations,
etc. Logic can get complicated for common sense.
And you may be saying, Well, but why don't I just use the opposite sign to the one I had if I want
to see if it is equal, I look for different.
If it was greater, I put smaller, but you will see that in some programming flows.
It will be much more practical to have a logical operator such as not, it serves to negate the original
comparison.
And we're going to see this very soon, I promise you, throughout this course, which continues in
the next lecture where Fill is already waiting for you.