And now we have our first tasks and we want to display them as a list on our website.
So let's create our first view.
We're going to come to views p y where we created the function earlier.
And here we're going to change a few things because this was just to show you how we could get a HTTP
response to display something on the screen.
We're going to remove this import and we're not going to use it anymore.
We're also going to remove this function, which is not going to be needed.
And we're going to rephrase this a bit.
Now we're going to import from Django dot views, dot generic dot list.
And from here, we're going to import list view.
And you might be wondering what is list view?
Well, List View is a type of page that represents a list of objects.
So while this view is running, it's going to display a list of objects that this view is operating
on.
And generally, these objects are going to be the result of a query, because generally we don't show
a complete database, but filtered by search criteria.
So in this way, the objects shown in our list view can change according to what we want to show.
Moreover, we cannot set a hard list of items to be displayed because our tasks can be deleted or new
ones can appear.
So we can use the list view not only to show a complete list, but also a list filtered by some search
criteria.
So what are we going to create here is not a function, but a class called Pending List.
And this class inherits from list view.
And what does list view require to work?
It requires a model that is a complete list of objects and the query set that will be a filtered query
which establishes which objects of that model are the ones we want to show.
We will see the latter later.
For now, let's assign a model which is going to be equal to the complete list, which is task.
And of course, it gives us an error because we haven't imported it into this file yet.
Our task list is inside models.
Dot py.
Here you see it.
It's a class.
So in views we're also going to import from dot models import task and now you're going to stop complaining
and we can set our model as a task.
And since this is a view, I want to use it in a different way inside the base URLs module I have here.
Remember this one that we use to display the URLs patterns?
Well, here we're also going to remove these views that we've imported and now we're going to import
it differently.
We're going to put from dot views, import pending list.
And now we have to correct this views that we have inside calling pending list because this URL patterns
cannot show classes.
We're going to apply a method that is as view.
By placing it like this, it will be able to display our class pending list as a view.
This would technically be ready because we have already connected the URL to our view.
So when we refresh our URL in the browser, it should already know that it has to point to our list.
But we are still missing a detail because the URL knows what it has to show, but it doesn't know how
to show it because we haven't configured that yet.
So we still have to set up our template.
If I refresh this, we're going to get an error that tells us that it didn't exist in our template.
It says Inside Base.
It looks for the HTML file, but it doesn't find anything there.
So that's what we need to set up.
So let's create this template that Django looks for by default in this place.
And let's copy that name.
There are different ways to store this template, and I'm going to do it this way.
We're going to come here in our list of folders and files and on the base.
I'm going to create a new directory, which is going to be called templates.
And it's important that you name it just like that.
Now, I already have templates inside base and inside templates.
I'm going to create another directory that is going to seem strange to you, but it's going to have
the name base two.
Because here we're going to have a different templates and the one we want for now is for base, even
though it repeats the name of our project.
And here in bass, we're going to create a new file which is going to have the name we just copied with
the ending HTML.
And here we have a different file to the ones we've been using so far because it's going to receive
HTML code.
Now we're going to write the code for the content of our view, and now it's going to be pure content
without any styling.
Note this there's going to be no colors, no shapes, no fonts, none of that.
We'll do that later.
For now, we're going to create the pure structure of our content.
So remember when we watched Web scraping a couple of days ago when we learned the difference between
HTML and CSS?
That's what it's all about.
Well, let's start by creating a title here with a tag called H1.
And inside this tag we're going to write Pending List.
And here we've already given some information to our code.
So remember that HTML is written inside tags that open and close h one is telling it that this is a
main Title eight, a type one title.
Let's go back to our site and let's refresh now and see what happens.
And it tells us it can't find it either.
Well, the reason it doesn't find it is because it's looking for it at this address where it should
go all the way to templates base and find this HTML file.
And of course, the problem is that we have not yet configured within the project the settings file
where we have assigned the applications we've installed.
So notice that if we go further down, we have templates here.
It says where our application should look for the templates needed to configure its views.
Well, here we have to update drives and put the location where we have this file which is in templates.
The templates are located in this folder.
So we're going to copy its path here and we're going to copy the full name.
We're going to paste it here between these brackets and we're going to put in quotes.
And we're also going to transform the back slashes into double back slashes so that it interprets it
accordingly and not generate special characters here and here.
So we've already told that where where to look for the templates.
And it's in this address in templates which points to this folder where you find the folder with the
name of the application and in here a task list which has just this header.
So the assumption is that if we refresh again now that it knows where to look, it knows to show us
this header which says pending list.
Next, we want some information to be printed in our view, information that's going to be different
each time because when we display the items in the list, those items are going to change.
So how do we pass them to Django?
By default, Django calls this list of objects that we already have, and first I want it to display
it here in a table.
So I go back to this HTML file and the next element or tag that I want to have is a table.
And here we have a space to create a table.
The first element that our table is going to have is a table row.
This is put in with the label TR, which stands for Table Row.
And here we're going to put a header with the label H for table header.
And here, let's just put the word items here.
It's a good header.
Once this TR ends, we want a four loop to start iterating through all the items in our list.
So how do we write a for loop inside Django?
We do it with the square brackets with the percent sign, and then we put for each task that we find
in this object list.
This is a default name that points properly and we're going to close with the percent sign and the square
brackets again.
Here goes the body of our for loop.
And while we're down there, we mark the closing of the loop with the same signs and here we put end
four.
This is a bit different than what we're used to.
Then we want for that each task that it finds inside the list.
What it does is to show it in a table.
So for each record, that's going to be a table row where there is going to be a T d, which is a table
data cell where we're going to put with two square brackets that open and close task dot title.
So where does this come from?
If we go to our model, we find the inside task, we have the element title, and that it is an element
that is going to show for each of the tasks.
With this, we already have a loop that goes through each element of the list objects and that will
show the title of each task in case our list becomes empty.
At some point we're going to put a conditional here, which is put again with the same symbology as
before, where we put empty.
We close this and inside we put a title that can be H three, which is a title of a lower category than
H one, where it says something like, There are no items in this list.
To familiarize yourself with writing in Django, its Python style code with a few variations.
For example, you write your functions in square brackets with percentages, and the double brackets
are to accommodate variables, in this case, the title of each of our tasks.
So we go back to our site and we go to refresh and we get an error.
It tells us that there is an invalid block tag on this line number which is empty.
So let's see, let's see what it means.
Let's check that line.
And yes, here we have the empty and the problem that is is outside the loop.
So this should be inside so that it can consider this condition before the end of our loop.
Now.
Yes, we refresh again and we have a pending list with the header element, which is items and then
our three tasks that we wrote earlier.
And finally, before we finish this lesson, I want to customise this name object list that we've used
here in the search.
That's a generic name.
So I want to customise it so that it's easier to read.
So I'm going to go to our views file and I'm going to add here that in addition to a model, let's have
a context object name.
Basically, this serves to contextualize the name of the objects that it is called according to the
elements of our environment.
In our context, the name I would like it to have is tasks to make it more meaningful.
So I go back to our HTML file and here instead of object list, we're going to put tasks.
And now here we can read for every task in tasks and this is more readable and it should still work
the same way we refresh it.
Perfect.
It's still pointing where it belongs.
This is all about how to build an elementary view, because in this case it is not styled or anything.
But in the next lesson, we're going to move on to the detail view, which is the next step.
So I'll wait for you there.