We already know how to create classes and because of it, we know how to create individual objects that
are instances of those classes.
Still, our objects are all the same and are all empty because we have not yet learned how to assign
attributes to them when designing the class.
First of all, it is important to distinguish that there are two types of attributes.
On the one hand, there are the class attributes.
These are attributes that belong to the class and therefore will be the same for all objects that are
going to be creating created in that class.
For example, if our class has the attribute wings equal to true, this means that all the bird objects
that we create will have this attribute.
They will all have wings.
On the other hand, there are the instance attributes.
They belong to the instance of the class or object.
There are particular, specific attributes that can be different in each instance.
In our case, for each bird, for example, the color attribute will have a different value for each
bird that we are going to create, maybe black, brown mixture and so on.
Right now in Pie Charm, we are going to learn how to create instance attributes first and then class
attributes.
Let's start by creating instance attributes.
We'll declare our bird class once again and this time will store something inside.
How do we define attributes of a class?
We first use the key word def, the one we use when creating functions.
What we're going to create now, which is the bird class constructor, is technically a method and we'll
create it using def.
Now we have to type two underscores then the word in it and another two underscores.
We'll add brackets and complete this declaration with the keyword self.
All will be explained soon.
And then we'll add some attributes we want to our bird, for example.
Color is an attribute of a bird we have.
We'll type colon enter and now we're inside the definition which is inside the class.
Now we call the keyword self dot.
Choose the word color, which will define this attribute and we enter color as a value.
You may wonder what all this is.
It seems quite confusing.
I promise you'll understand it now.
So let's deal with this little by little.
So we've created our class and define the method that we will assign attributes to our bird.
For this method, we've also passed two parameters in brackets.
The first one is the keyword self, which is mandatory, and the other one is the attribute we're going
to add to our parameter, which is color.
Next, we can call self again and what is self?
There's basically the instance of the objects that are about to be created, the birds.
It will assign the parameter color to its attributes.
Color.
For now, we'll type it like this and execute it one so I can explain it in detail later.
If you haven't fully understood this, don't worry because it will start making sense soon.
What's important here is that I got out of the bird class because I went back to the beginning of the
code line.
So now I'll create an instance of Bird.
It will be named my bird.
It will be equal to bird.
And I'll enter brackets and I'll leave this empty because I want you to see what happens if I execute
our file.
So I got an error message.
Why so?
Because Bird demands that we pass an argument.
The color argument.
And here it says that in it, which is the constructor, is missing one required positional argument,
which is color.
So every time you want to create an object of a class that requires parameters, you must pass those
parameters or else you won't be able to continue.
So we'll a silent value such as black, and if I execute it, I won't get an error.
Actually, I haven't done anything to show on the console, but we don't have error messages.
So now keep in mind the following.
We'll create another variable named wird, which will store a string that says hello as value.
If I type word and enter a dot, then we'll see.
That word contains methods and attributes that are typical of strings because it is a string.
Here we can see and use any of them.
This also works with the classes we have created.
If I call my bird, which is the instance of a bird.
And at a dot we'll see.
It contains the color attribute, among other attributes that are typical of classes.
It's the same one I created here.
So I'm creating an object and passing parameters that are mandatory to it.
Our object has that attribute now.
So if I choose it and print it, let's go to the beginning and type print.
And the software will show that the color attribute of my bird is black.
Now that we've seen how this works and how we can look for the properties of our objects, I want us
to try to understand this structure in it is a method.
It is what we call the class constructor.
Every time we create a class Python will automatically call its constructor to see what requirements
that class has.
That is to say what attributes it will need to build the object correctly.
In it is where we establish the attributes which we want to be assigned to an instance that is created
from this class.
That's why we had to pass this value when creating an instance of Bird, because the software used in
it to see what was being required.
So Python demands that we always enter this explicitly.
In fact, we could use any word however we use self because it is a standard word and it will allow
other programmers to read our code more easily.
If I enter self you will know it refers to each of the instances of a class.
So let's see the name of our attribute.
Here it is in the first attribute I created, which is color, the fact that we have to type it three
times may be confusing to you, but we have this color in brackets then self color and this is equal
to color, which is the value of self dot color.
So in order for you to understand this, I'll do something I shouldn't do.
Suppose that instead of color, I enter my color.
Look what happens.
This color is perfect, so I'll leave it as it is.
But this color is underlined in red now and the software doesn't recognize it.
If I move the cursor here, it says it is an unresolved reference to a word that doesn't exist.
This means I should also type my color here.
So these two expressions are the same and this one is different.
This is telling us what is each element?
We're working with two different colors or categories.
If I was creating my bird, I don't enter anything here.
The software expect a parameter.
I'll move the cursor here and notice that it's asking me to enter the my color parameter.
It's not asking me to enter the color this one, but to enter my color, which is this one.
So now we'll break down what is going on here.
This color here is the attribute and this one is the parameter.
If I enter different names here, I could enter my attribute and this one was my parameter.
Now we'll see that this is underlined.
So we should type parameter and it will stop underlining things.
Okay.
Color here doesn't exist anymore because now it's dot my attribute look, it's the first one.
So we're creating a definition that says what attributes the object of my bird class will need.
It will need the self attribute to store a parameter and we'll pass that parameter here.
Could we use different words?
Yes, we could, because the software will allow it.
It won't return an error if I type black or anything else to define the parameter of my attribute.
This won't return an error if I execute it.
It says black again.
What you have to understand is that we are passing to each place.
Let's enter all the keywords again.
So a parameter named color.
Then the color attribute needs to be equal to the color parameter, which is the one we're going to
pass when creating the instance of our object.
So I get that this can be difficult, but at the same time it's logical.
It'll start making sense as you use it.
And as I was saying, we could use different words to differentiate attributes from parameters, but
conventionally we use the same name for both.
It may be confusing, but once you start practicing, you will understand the logic and see that it
is a more organized way to define all of this because you don't need so many names.
So another interesting fact is that we can pass any attributes we want to our bird.
So let's add some such as species.
We also have to add self species, which will be the equal to species.
And this is no longer underlined.
The declaration of the variable.
My bird is highlighted here as if the constructor was saying, Hey, you're missing something.
We've entered the color parameter, but the species parameter hasn't been filled in.
So we'll say that our bird is a toucan and the underline is gone.
So if I print my bird color, the console will say it's black.
But if I print my bird dot, notice that we have to choose color and species will say choose species.
And if I print this, the console will say it's a toucan.
I can create a string literal that says My bird is a we call my bird species and it is and we call my
bird color.
So let's print this and we'll see.
My bird is a toucan and it is black.
It worked.
We were able to work with the attributes that we assigned to each of the parameters of the constructor
of Bird.
This is what we call an instance attribute.
It is an attribute in which each object can have a different value.
My bird, one can be black, my bird too can be red, and the other one can be white, and so on.
There can be toucans, canaries, falcons, etc. etc. However, there are class attributes as well.
Just like Phil told you before, class attributes are the same for all the bird objects you create so
we can define them more easily.
Suppose I say the wings attribute is true.
This means all the birds have wings and don't have to do anything more complex than that.
If I want to see the wings attribute of the bird class, I don't even have to create an instance because
all of the objects will have the same value.
So I can see this by printing bird uppercase this time dot and here we have wings.
And if I print bird wings I will get the true value because it is what all the birds have.
I didn't have to use my bird but bird.
However, if I want to see the value of the my bird object, I can do it too because it's a bird and
it will have the same class attributes my bird wings and we can see it is also true.
All the objects share the same class attributes, so this time we could create undefined aptitudes for
our classes.
So after doing some activities, we'll go to our next lecture to see how we can create methods for our
objects.
See you there.