So we already know how to detect if there's a match.
And we also know how to measure the distance between the people in two different images.
So now we're going to make these two values both result and distance appear in test picture here at
the top so that the user can see how the comparison has turned out, because so far we can only see
it in the console.
So that's what we're going to do in this lesson.
So first, I'm going to delete this value that we've set because it's too flexible.
And if we don't set anything, the system will revert to the default limit.
We're going to take this block called Show Images and we're going to take it further down.
So it's going to show after everything we have to do here.
We're going to remove these prints, which were just for the purposes of you being able to see the results
in the console.
And we're going to show the images at the bottom.
So they're only going to be shown once.
All the modifications that we're going to do now have been applied, not only the rectangles that we
have created above, but also the visualization of the results that we're going to do next.
So we're going to write a clarification that says we're going to show results, and it's going to consist
of calling CV to remember that this library allows us to manipulate how any image looks.
For example, we've used it to put the rectangle and we're going to call its put text method.
Which is going to ask us for several parameters here.
We're looking at them.
We're going to start by setting the image on which we want to put the text, which is going to be test
picture.
Then we're going to set the text, which is the text that is going to be displayed on the picture.
It's not going to be a fixed text.
It's going to be a dynamic text which is going to be built when we get the results.
So we're going to write it with a little string that calls result containing true or false.
Then we leave a space and we're going to call distance to show what the distance is between the two
images.
But as this is a value that has many decimals, we're going to apply the round method to make it easier
to visualize.
And inside the brackets, we're going to set it to show two figures after the point.
Then we're going to set the location of the text.
It asks for the coordinates of the left corner of the string in the image.
So let's put in a tuple that says 50 and 50.
This distance will be enough for it to appear at the left 50 pixels from each edge.
So now we're going to add the font that we're going to use for that we call CV two font, and you can
choose the one you want, and I'm going to choose Font Hershey Complex.
And we're going to set the scale that this font is going to have and we leave it at one.
The color, if you want, you can make the color red or green, depending on the result.
So we can set an if here to be green if the value is true or red if it is false.
For this example, I'm going to keep it simple and make it always green with the value.
Zero 255.
Zero.
And finally, I'm going to set the thickness to two and the other values will be left as they are by
default.
So if we now execute this modification, which is going to show us an additional value to see that Brad
arrives here and he says that it's false and that the distance between me and him is 0.85.
So if I go back to my picture B where I do appear and run it, we're supposed to see in the new picture
the result is true and the distance is now 0.42.
But we have learned one more element in this face recognition training and the next lesson we're going
to start developing today's project, which, thanks to what we have learned so far, we're going to
be able to make a program that sees a person on the webcam and can define whether or not that person
exists in a database.
Our program is going to be a program that registers the attendance of the employees of a company who,
upon arriving at work, are shown on camera and the system stores in a file.
The information about who arrived and at what time.
This is going to be a great lesson and it won't take too long.
So let's get started.