Now it's time to configure the detailed view.
So what is this?
It is a page in our application, which opens when the user selects an item from the list.
So let's say I click on buy tomatoes.
In that case, it should open a page showing us all the details of this task and all the information
that corresponds to this list item.
So we're going to have to create a view for this detail page.
We're going to go to our view files and we're going to copy all this input that we did from the list
view and paste it in and do something very similar because we're going to change list the detail.
And what we're going to import is the detailed view.
We're going to create a class for this element.
I'm going to name it task detail.
And this class is going to inherit from detail view.
Inside it.
We're going to start to create the content we're going to do as before, and we're going to make it
a model that is going to have task as its content.
And this is going to be the model for this class.
Now we're going to create another HTML file to use as a template so that we can see these elements.
So new file and we're going to name it task detail because that's the name that's going to be automatically
generated for this file.
Then we'll see how to rename it.
But just as the previous one came task list, this one will take task as its name and add detail to
it because that's the default name for the detail view.
So don't worry.
We'll see later how we can reassign it to a name of our choice.
So here we have this new HTML and we're going to create a template for it to display our content.
We're going to recreate a header with H one, which is a tag that is going to contain for now the word
task colon.
And then we're going to assign a content to it.
For now, I want you to see what it looks like.
In order to display it on the page, we need to come to the URL's file, which is on the base in addition
to importing into the pending list.
We're also going to import into task detail so we can see it on the site.
So we're going to copy this whole path because we also need to have a path for this URL.
We're going to add a second element and we're going to put in another path, but this one now needs
to be adapted to lead to the detail page.
Well, when the browser looks for the detail page, it's going to look for a path that contains a primary
key, which is in our context is task.
So this here, instead of being empty, will contain the keyword task.
That is to say that after the URL of our site will come a slash with the word task.
For now, of course, this doesn't show anything, but if we add that, it's going to be able to get
to the tasks and then we'll come back here to set it up and we put task and a slash for the number of
the task.
It's about as we can't put the number here because it can be one, two, three, etc. depending on how
many tasks we have, we're going to tell it that it's going to be an integer colon.
And here the acronym peak for primary key.
So as we said, task is the primary key and it's going to take an integer to peak.
And with this, we're going to be able to build routes that look like this.
First, the original URL.
Then slash task.
And then slash with the number of corresponding task.
When you see it in action, this is going to be very easy to understand.
And what we also need to do here is to replace pending list as view by task, detail as view.
And we're also going to change the name of this page so that instead of pending, it is task.
Then we already have the URL to get to our detail views and we already have the view inside views,
which takes us to the template of detail view.
Then we can test it.
So we're going to come here and we're going to type in, slash task, slash one.
And here we have a page that says task and a colon.
And remember that we are looking at this template that we have here and it doesn't have any special
content right now.
If we look for task one or two or whatever, it's always going to show us the same thing.
So far, we've only configured how to get there and we still need to configure what should be displayed
there.
So now let's see how to pass information to it.
Let's go to the task detail HTML file and we'll ask it to show us a variable after task and the colon.
Remember that in Django we passed them with double brackets and the word object, which is also a default
word.
We'll learn how to customize this name.
Once we put this in.
We just have to refresh and we have the text two is milking the cow.
If we put in task one, we will get mowing the lawn and if we put in task three by tomatoes.
So this would be the link to get us to each of the tasks.
And of course we still need to make it possible for the user to get there in a more direct way through
a link that he can click on in the task list and get to the details of each one of them.
So now let's customize this name object, which we have here to represent what we want.
Let's come to views and let's come to our class and let's add a context object name, as we did before,
which is this case is going to be task.
The previous one you can see here was tasks for pending list, but this one is singular task.
So now in the HTML we can change objects to task and it still works the same, but this time with a
custom name chosen by us, which makes the code easier to read.
And finally, what I want to do before finishing this lesson is to overwrite my template so that it
looks for a name of my choice and not for this task detail that was generated by default.
I'm going to rename this file through refactor rename it, and I want it to be called simply task.
This is so that when you want to create your pages, you can give them any meaningful name you choose.
With this, we refactor them and it already has a different name.
And now, of course, if the code goes looking for it, it won't find it because the name has changed.
In fact, I'm going to prove it to you.
Let's refresh.
And it tells us that it doesn't exist because it's looking for task detail, but the file is no longer
called that.
So we're going to change the name it's looking for by going to views again.
Here it is.
And we're going to add another parameter which is going to be template name and it's going to be equal
to base slash task HTML.
That is whatever name I assign to my file.
So if I come back here and refresh now, it's going to search for it by the name I've chosen.
So now we know how to generate our detailed views.
And we're going to go to the next lesson to continue working on developing links that will take us to
the Views page from the task table.
See you in the next lesson.