So far, we have a rocket that's capable of moving along the x axis, and yet it can go through the
edges of our screen and disappear.
That's not what we want.
We want this rocket to move up to this point without exiting the window.
To achieve this, we'll do something quite easy that will allow us to restrict these movements.
But before our system gets out of control, will notice again, point out the function of each block
of code.
Here, we'll point out that this is the player function and here will clarify that these are the player
variables.
So let's leave some space.
And here inside the loop we have the events iteration.
Let's also clarify that the first event will be iterating over is the one that closes the program closing
event.
This is the event that checks if an arrow key has been pressed, so it'll be named press arrow key event.
Then we have this other event which checks if an arrow key has been released.
So to be named release key event.
And finally, we have these lines that will modify our character's location so it will be named modify
location.
And this is the one we use to update.
It is paramount that you take your time to clarify everything, especially in programs where you have
too much code.
Actually, we must do that with all of our programs, but we tend not to do it when a program is rather
basic.
Anyway, always clarify and explain the function of each block of code.
You won't have any problems when maintaining, updating, modifying, or sharing your program.
Okay, so we want to set limits and prevent our rocket from escaping our window.
How do we do that?
Let's position ourselves here and before the call.
That is, once we've changed our player's location as regards the x axis, but without calling it,
we'll create a little block of code named keep inside screen.
This will make sure that our rocket doesn't have a value lower than zero in the x axis.
That's because if our rocket is touching the edge, it means it is at zero.
But if it is at minus one, it's already gone.
Therefore, once we've changed, our characters position will verify if player X is equal or lower than
zero.
If so, will restore that value to zero in player x and we'll do the same on the right.
But it will be a different calculation.
We have to make sure our rocket doesn't go past the other edge.
This edge is at 800.
And our rocket is 64 pixels wide.
So we have to subtract 64 from 800.
This is equal to 736.
And our rocket can't go past that point.
So here we'll add lf player x is equal or higher than 736.
We're not going to allow that by always restoring its position to 736.
As a result, our rocket won't be able to go past that point.
Thanks to this little change we can make, our rockets stay inside the screen.
And if we execute this and go to the right, we'll reach the edge and it won't go past.
And if we go to the other edge, the rocket can't go past it.
And it's like it hits the zero wall and that's it.
So notice that there are some pixels on the edges of our rocket, and that's why we can see some space
between the rocket and the edges.
I like it that way.
We could modify it by entering minus one or minus two, and then we could see where our rocket ends.
But I like that there's some space in between.
This is all for now.
And we have this rocket that can move to the right or to the left.
But it's been left alone in the vast universe.
It needs some purpose.
In the next lecture, we're going to create some enemies that our rocket can defeat.
Don't miss it.