So it's time for us to start focusing on our next project and to take into account everything we've
learned in order to carry out the web scraping on a real website.
Because so far we've just learned how to extract one single element from one single site.
For our next lesson, we're going to learn how to extract different elements from different sections
of the same website.
To do so, we're going to use this website named to scrape dotcom.
You can find the link to this website in the resources.
This is a website that lets us put into practice web scraping freely since all the images and texts
are copyright free.
We can take whatever we want and do anything with it.
To scrape, Dotcom has two sections books and quotes.
We're going to use books, which is fictional online bookstore that contains many examples, such as
books, product details and more.
If we click on any book, we'll go to a site containing details such as reviews, cost, title, image,
description and other related products.
It indeed resembles a real online bookstore.
So we're going to use this website to put everything into practice.
So let's establish a goal.
As web scrapers, we have to obtain titles of all four or five star books.
To accomplish this goal, we'll use everything we know, plus a few more things, because not all the
books are listed on the same page.
And that's the challenge.
Note that there are thousands of results and we're shown one out of 20.
If we want to see the rest of the books, we'll have to enter one page at a time.
So we must find out a way to programmatically browse each page and extract information from all the
books.
Another challenge is that not all of them are five star books, and we want the titles of those books
containing four or five stars.
Therefore, we shouldn't download this book, this or this, but we should download this as it has five
stars.
As a result, our program will have to ensure that one part of the HTML code is the condition to be
met in order to download another part of that code.
So don't worry.
I'll soon tell you which part of the code is in charge of that.
Anyway, these are today's challenges.
We'll learn new things in order to respond to those challenges.
And at the end of the day, we'll have sharpened our web scraper skills.
So let's get to the next lesson and find that solution.