Now we're going to program our assistance so we're able to tell what day it is today.
So delete this call and close this function.
And here I put voice language options.
And now I will create a new function which will work to inform day of the week.
We can call this function ask day and it won't need any parameters.
And here inside let's create a variable with today's information.
Now we can create a variable called day, which will be equal to date today, and let's print this day
and inside the same function.
Let's also create a variable for the day of the week, because in today we need only to separate the
day of the week, which is what we want her to say.
So weekday will be equal to day dot weekday, which is whether she tells us it's Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday or whatever.
Then we're going to print this to see it on the screen.
So let's see how it looks.
And here below, if I call ask day and then we can execute it here.
Return the day in which I'm recording this and the day of the week has a number y.
So because the corresponding index for today is a list that contains the name of seven days, it is
to say that this number corresponds to a day of the week.
But I don't want my system to say a number.
For example, today is for I want them to tell me today is Monday or today is Tuesday.
So I'm going to need to create a dictionary within my function which contains the names of days.
And in this way my assistant has a word to pronounce.
So let's call calendar to this variable which will have a dictionary whose first element will be the
key zero and have a value of Monday and they'll speed up the video so all this doesn't bore you.
Okay, so once I've finished to make this dictionary, we must have seven elements that go from 0 to
6.
This dictionary allows the assistant to associate the numerical value with each day.
So the last thing that we're missing is that our assistant can say the day of the week.
In order to say it correctly, let's call the function, speak from inside the function, ask day.
And the message that it will pass will be a literal string confirmed for today is and a call to calendar.
So which index of calendar are we going to pass it?
The one which is in weekday, which is the numerical value from 1 to 7.
So let's execute again, but it's given as an error.
So what happened here?
It tells us name error with the function speak because here it says name ID five is not defined.
So let's review the function speak and what seems to be the problem here.
We requested ID five, but it doesn't recognize it.
Probably because this has to be before the call to the function.
So let's put these variables above everything and now it's okay.
So now we can call, speak and it should recognize them.
So to remember you can't call something that doesn't exist in the codes logic we execute again.
Today's Friday.
Did you hear that?
So one more time.
Today is Friday.
I love it.
Perfect.
Thank you very much.
Assistant So now we know how to request the date and the next lesson.
We're going to ask the time.