So the time has come for this lonely rocket to have enemies to fight against.
So I've downloaded and stored an image named enemy dot png in my folder.
You can either search for one on the internet or use mine, which I attached to this lesson for you
to download.
This is how I want my enemies to look.
Very well.
Now we have to generate code for my enemy to appear on the screen.
Then we'll make it move.
So let's copy all the players variables we have here, because what we're going to do is is quite similar.
In this case, there will be enemy variables.
The image variable will be named enemy image.
And the name of the file containing the image will be named enemy PNG.
Here we'll type enemy X and the following will be enemy Y.
And finally, this one will be enemy x change.
Here we have a different group of variables for our enemy.
We'll also copy and modify the player function or change it to enemy function, and the rest will remain
the same.
The only difference will be the enemy image.
Everything seems fine.
There are no complaints.
The last thing we need to do is go to our player.
Call where we will call our enemy so we type enemy.
The first variable is enemy X and the second one is enemy Y.
Taking into account how we've done this, the enemy should have the same characteristics as our rocket.
However, if we execute this, the enemy overlaps the rocket because they are created in exactly the
same way.
They are both located in the same place because both have the same coordinates.
So let's give the enemy other coordinates.
As regards the y axis, we'll enter 200, execute it, and our enemy will appear here.
But our enemy will not be controlled by the user.
Its movements won't be controlled from the keyboard, the enemy will be controlled by the computer.
So we also want our enemy to appear randomly.
So like we did before, we'll import our random method which allows us to set a random value.
So enemy x will be equal to random dot round.
So it is in a random integer.
Regarding the screen width, values will go from 0 to 736 because our enemy is also 64 pixels wide as
in the case of our rocket.
We'll do the same with the y axis so that our enemy appears randomly.
We'll enter random rand dent here and the maximum height will be 50 and the minimum will be 200.
If we execute our screen, we'll see that our enemy appears randomly.
And if I close it and execute it again, the enemy will appear randomly once again.
Every time I close the window and execute it again, our enemy will appear in different places.
So that's how we make our enemy appear.
So far, we're facing one enemy who doesn't do much.
It's a bit boring, but this will begin to move and attack soon.
So see you in the next lesson.