The daytime module is built into Python and we can import it.
Well, you already know how daytime allows us to manipulate time.
Don't get excited.
It's not like you imagine, but you will be able to store data about date and time and variables and
do calculations between time periods and display them in different ways.
It is a module that all programmers should have in their toolbox, so lets get to know it in Pi Charm.
In order to start working with date and time, we need to import this module name date time.
Here we have it.
Let's create a variable named my time which will store a time value.
My time will be a date time object.
Add a dot and you'll see several options.
We can choose date time in order to have both values, or we can choose either date or time in order
to have the corresponding value.
We'll choose time and pass the arguments it requires.
To begin with, we have to input an integer that represents our an hour.
We should use the 24 hour clock for this.
So let's enter 17 comma.
And the next thing we have to do is input an integer that represents the minutes.
So let's type 35.
We could also add seconds, microseconds and the time zone, but if we only complete up to a certain
argument, the rest will be automatically assigned values of zero.
So now we're going to print the type of data we're working with in my time.
Let's execute it.
And the software tells us that we have an object of the class datetime time.
Perfect.
However, I also want what value my time contains if I execute it.
The software returns 17 colon, 35 colon and 0 seconds, and it doesn't return microseconds because
I didn't enter a value.
So this is how the time looks when I print it.
I can also print more specific elements.
So if I type my time and a dot, I can choose hours or minutes.
And if I choose to see the minutes, the software will return 35 minutes.
If I had chosen hour, it would have returned 17.
That's the way we can print specific elements in order to manipulate them if we need to.
So we can keep on adding information.
And if we type 50 seconds here and 1500 microseconds here and we print my time, the software will return
all the information we entered.
Moreover, we can use dates, so we'll create a date time which will return a date and let's change
its name to my day date.
Time date requires year, month and day.
So let's type 20, 25, ten and 17.
This would be October the 17th, 2025.
If we print my day, we'll see the next format.
2025.
Hyphen ten, hyphen 17.
Always in descending order.
Year month.
Date.
This date object only contains dates, not time.
We can also print specific elements.
We just want to see the year we execute it in order to see 2025.
We can show this information using a different format as well.
If we choose see time, the software will show a different time format which shows day.
Friday, October the 17th time, which is empty because it's a date object, not a date time object.
And finally year.
So there's something else I want to show you.
My day is a type of date object.
So if I want to see today instead of the information it contains, the software will turn this the exact
date I'm recording this.
When you execute it, you'll see a different date, obviously.
So keep in mind that today contains information that is independent of that contained in my day today
only requires that my day or the variable you have be a type of date or date time object.
So let's go on.
Now I want to combine date and time.
So I import from date time, import date time.
So this may sound strange and redundant, but this is a way to execute this.
It is an object contained inside date time and it has the same name.
So we'll use my date once again and it will be equal to date time.
We don't have to specify if the date or time.
And we can pass all the information here.
Year 2025, month five, day 15, then our 22 minutes, 10 seconds, 15 and microseconds 2500.
Let's print my date in order to see how it looks on the screen.
And voila, here we have the complete information we needed.
Date and time.
If I wanted to change something, I could retype my date.
And make it be equal to my date using the replace method.
We don't need to retype anything.
We'll just specify which element we want to change.
Suppose that we change our mind and don't want to be made.
We want to make month B equal to another specific month, say November.
Then we can print my date, which was modified with replace.
The software will return 2025 November 15.
The rest remains the same.
So besides showing date and time information, we can also calculate the time elapsed between two moments,
whether they are dates or hours.
To do so will input date and as an example, will enter a person's time of birth and death so as to
calculate how much time they lived.
Birth will be equal to date, which can be 1995, March and Day five.
So let's also add death, which will be equal to another type of date object.
This person will have lived for a long time, say 100 years.
Now let's enter 2095 and say they died in the sixth month on the 19th.
All right.
Now we can calculate the difference by creating a new variable named life.
That's a nice name for a variable.
We'll make that variable be equal to the time elapsed by subtracting death minus birth.
This will tell us how long this person lived.
Let's print life and it will tell us that the person lived for 36,631 days.
We didn't pass a parameter to time, so it has a variable of zero.
And if we want to see the days, we can enter dot days.
And that's what we will see.
And if we want to calculate the hours, we won't be able to do it without providing the software with
information about days.
Time requires a date in order to calculate hours accurately.
So we'll import date time once again, and now we'll calculate how long a person has been awoken since
they woke up until they went to bed.
We'll create a variable named woke up and then we'll use a date time object to state the following in
2022.
In the 10th month, on the fifth day, this person woke up at 7 hours, 30 minutes.
Now let's create a variable named went to sleep and we'll use a datetime object as well.
This person went to sleep the same year.
On the same day.
That is October day five, and they went to sleep at 2345.
Okay, now we can create a variable named wakefulness, which will be the result of went to sleep minus
woke up.
If we print wakefulness, we find out that our friend stayed awake for 16 hours and 15 minutes on this
day.
I can calculate seconds too.
I just have to apply seconds here.
And this person stayed awake for 58000 seconds.
Interesting.
That's the approximate amount of time we stay awake every day, which isn't little.
During those 58000 seconds, we get to live, love, cry, conquer, learn, and more.
And on top of it, each second is an opportunity.
This is the amount of time we have each day to seize new opportunities, just like you're doing right
now.
Your studying and learning in order to be a better person full of new chances.
Congratulations on that.
And see you in the next lecture.