In this lesson, we're going to generate a method for the user to create new list items, i.e. new tasks
directly from the page.
We're going to make a link here that will take him to the form to create a new task.
Back to page charm.
And the truth is that we have a lot of things to open here.
So let's start closing settings, models, all these things that we are not going to use.
So we're going to leave views and we're going to leave URLs and we're going to work well with this.
So we're going to go to views and here we're going to add one more import.
We're going to do that from Django View's generic and edit here in edit, we're going to be able to
import a class called Create View.
Create view is just a class that gives us the possibility to give tools to the user so that he or she
can create new items in the list.
So let's create a new class, of course, as we have done so far.
We can call this one create task.
And this class is going to inherit from create view.
This class is going to have a little bit more complex logic because we have to send a request for the
system to create a new element and return the new element created and incorporated in our list.
So for that, we're also going to need to have a new XHTML site like the ones we have here.
So let's create it now, new file and it's going to be called task form.
HTML.
So why do I give it this name?
Because it is the name that the system will automatically search for.
As before, we will be able to change it to another name later.
But by default, the system wants to find task, which is the name of our list, and then from which
is the element associated with the create view class.
So we generate this new document, which for now we're just going to put the header with each one that
says tasks form and we leave it like that.
This is just a check that we are heading in the desired page.
So we go back to views which is shouting error because it needs us to load more information.
We set model back to task.
This is being repetitive, but it has to be like this for each one of the classes.
By default, the create view class gives us a model form for us to add items to our lists.
Basically, that class is going to take our model.
Look, let's open models here.
And I was saying it's going to take this model from the task class and it's going to create a form based
on these fields for us.
All we have to do is specify the fields we want.
That is which of these fields we want our form to have.
So let's close models and we go back to views and we put fields and here we can make a list where we
can put each of our fields.
We can do this in different ways.
One is to put the names like title description and so on.
That's one way to do it and the other way to do it, since we're really interested in loading all the
fields, is to put single quotes, double underscore and then all.
And this is a way of asking, please enter all.
So I've already designed the structure of the form.
The system already knows that it has to create a form for me which has all the fields that are in my
list.
And also I want to make sure that the user has successfully submitted this form.
The site automatically redirects the user to a different page, and I want this so that they have don't
have to manually navigate to another place, but the system takes them somewhere else.
So we need to add this to our create view as well.
Let's import one more tool from Django URLs import.
And from here, we're going to import this tool called reverse lazy.
And what does Reverse Lazy do?
It opens a specific page.
When a certain event occurs.
What event will reverse lazy be triggered by when the user successfully submits a new task?
So let's load the attribute success URL here, which is going to be the same as reverse lazy with the
URL of tasks.
This means that after submitting a new task, the user will appear on the home page of our site.
With this we will be fine.
And now here, new URLs.
We need to add a new path because we now have a new page within our site.
Here we're going to ask that when the user wants to create a task instead of being directed to task
integer, it will take him to create task.
That is going to be the name in the link of our site.
So let's not forget, though, that we first have to import from views to this new class that we have
just created, which is create task.
So why do I do this import so that here we can go to the create task as new page and don't forget this
method so it can show the class as a view.
And here we put the name that being consistent is going to be create task and I don't want to forget.
So here I forget to add after create task the forward slash.
Never forget when you create a URL, you always need the forward slash at the end of the name.
I already have the URL and I'm going to go to the site manually because I don't have a link to get there.
So we're going to put a slash create task.
It's going to say tasks form.
All right, now that we've done that, let's see how to get here, but not manually by typing the address
in the bar, but by going from the home with a link to add a link here, we're going to go to the task
list dot, HTML form and under pending list.
We're going to add another tag this time a tag to a link.
Remember the A is the tag to add a link.
The name we give it is create new task and we can already see it on the site.
There it is.
But this link still doesn't lead anywhere because we have to set the h ref parameter inside the tag
so that it takes us somewhere.
Where to?
We put opening and closing brackets.
We put opening and closing percent signs and in the middle we specify that we want to go to the URL
of our site and from there to create task.
And with that we've got it.
We refresh this, create new task, transforms into a link and if we click on it, it takes us to the
tasks form.
So we can't yet test something we've programmed.
But once we get the form here, fill it in and submit it.
The system will take us back to the home of the site and we'll check that later.
Now let's get on to the next lesson to learn how to put our form here.