Our invoice system is missing only one feature now a calculator.
And this is the last step in the appearance process.
As you can see here, our calculator is basically a grid with four columns and five rows.
The first row would be the display, which occupies the four columns.
Numbers and mathematical symbols will appear there as we use them.
Basically, we have numbers and mathematical symbols which are aligned in the right column and the bottom
row.
We have the C button to get the total, the delete button and the zero button which is missing.
This is what we're going to build right now on pie chart.
So let's add another section to our code calculator.
Quite long.
Our code, isn't it?
Let's build the display first by creating a variable named calculator display which will be equal to
entry.
So we've done this before.
Now it's time for us to customise it.
Firstly, let's decide on a place which is calculator panel.
Secondly, we decide on a font which is doses size 16 and bold.
Then we add the width, which is 32, so as to occupy the total width of our calculator.
The edges will be one as usual, and that's everything regarding the display.
Now we have to locate it on the panel.
So calculate the display grid.
And since it will be at the top, it has to be in row zero, in column zero, and for it to span across
the four columns will add the column span property, which will be equal to four.
If we execute this, we'll see the calculator display ready just above the check space.
Now time to create the buttons.
We'll create them using a loop.
Otherwise we'd have to write like a mile of code lines.
There are 16 buttons, so we need to create a loop in order not to write code for 16 buttons.
We're going to make a list with the names of our buttons.
So Calculator Buttons is a list containing everything we're seeing here, and we'll enter the numbers
from top to bottom and from left to right.
So we type seven, eight, nine and plus sign.
Remember to include quotes.
And next line, four, five, six, and the minus sign.
Now, one, two, three.
And multiplication sign, which is lowercase x.
Now, for the last row, we add the total button, which is c, e, then delete zero and the division
sign, which is the forward slash.
Well, we have the elements representing the buttons.
Now it's time to create our loop.
But before doing that, I will add some variables necessary to place the buttons in rows and columns.
One variable will be my row and will initialize with one because row zero it's already taken up by the
display.
Another variable we will be my column which will initialize with zero because we're going to create
columns zero, one, two and three.
All right, let's start our loop.
For each button in the calculator buttons list, we have to make button be equal to a button element
from t k into uppercase.
So how are we going to set up our button?
Each button we create with our loop will be located in calculator panel.
Each of them will contain a different text because they need to contain whatever there is in the calculator
buttons list.
That's where we store their names.
So just like before we call button title so as to add the name of each button as text font will be dose
size 16 bold foreground will be white.
This is the font color background will be as your four.
So there are two features left.
We want the edges to be equal to one and width to be equal to eight so as to occupy our panel's total
width.
This loop creates 16 buttons since it will iterate over each of these elements.
However, we then have to replace them and this could get a bit tricky.
Button up grid.
And now we have to make them place themselves in their corresponding rows and columns.
So row will be equal to my row.
The variable we created before and column will be equal to my column.
But we're going to manipulate these values in each loop because the first loop will work just fine.
The first button will be placed in row one and column zero.
Perfect.
Now how do we place the rest of them?
Well, since we'll make these variables increase the value as the loop iterates, we'll check if my
column is equal to three.
If so, it will go on to a fourth column which shouldn't exist.
So in that case, we're going to make my row B equal to plus equals.
One will be increasing values in my row so that it decreases every time it reaches the third column.
But we also have to make sure not to expand our columns more than what's necessary.
So first we'll expand them by entering my column plus equals one.
And once my column has been expanded, we need to ask ourselves if my column is equal to four, that
means it reached a value we cannot accept.
All right.
In that case, my column will reset its value to zero.
That should do it in case we did everything right.
Our buttons should appear on the screen, occupying the panel.
Each of them is in the right place and you can check for yourself.
Our invoice system panel is ready.
So what follows now is the most interesting part.
We have to program it to carry out its functions just the way we want.
What a challenge.
See you soon.