In this lesson, we're going to configure another important detail for our assistant, which is a greeting
to us every time we start to work.
So our code will have this section to create initial greeting and the function this has will call initial
greeting and it won't need any parameters.
And the first thing we're going to do is make our function, say, a greeting.
This is as straightforward as calling the function speak.
And we put something like, Hello, I am Hazel or whatever name you'd like to give your assistant,
your personal assistant, and they could greet you with your name if you like.
So later we can make them say, How can I help you?
Now we can make the call to initial greeting and they say to us, Hello, I am Hazel, how can I help
you?
And it's that easy.
A quick lesson is never a bad thing.
So we will leave it here for now.
And in the next three lessons, we shall make our assistant do a little bit of everything.
So don't go anywhere.