I mentioned earlier that I'm a huge fan of infrastructure as code,
but so far in this course,
we've mostly been setting up CodePipeline using the AWS console.
While this is a good skill to have,
in this video we're going to look at setting up
CodePipeline using a CloudFormation template.
As a refresher,
using CloudFormation is a best practice for a few reasons
It's easy to reproduce your infrastructure.
This comes in handy if you have to move regions,
move accounts, or recover after some catastrophic failure.
You're also able to track changes as they occur,
as long as you're CloudFormation templates are stored in source control.
And finally, you can easily tear down resources all at once.
This is very handy when it's needed.
I've already created a CloudFormation template that recreates
the pipeline that we created in this course.
Templates can be pretty arduous to create,
so I just wanted to take a look at a few of the more unique
aspects of a completed pipeline template.
The template is in the demo code in the .aws folder with
the file name hbfl‑pipeline.template.
On line 12 is the actual pipeline resource declaration.
You'll see on line 17 you have to explicitly declare the
artifact store with CloudFormation, something the wizard did for you.
On line 20 is when the stage and action declaration begins.
This is the real meat of the pipeline resource.
Each stage has one or more actions.
Each action has parameters about the type of action,
any artifacts, the action configuration,
and which order it should run in.
If you want to have two actions run in parallel, give them the same run order.
Otherwise, to run serially, just have different run orders in ascending order.
And there's plenty more in this template,
but I think that's all we need to look at for now.
You can run this template in your command line by running this command.
This will create a brand‑new pipeline that will pull from
your hbfl source control repository and deploy to your
existing Elastic Beanstalk application.
When the CloudFormation template is done creating, the pipeline will
execute automatically for the first time on its own,
so you can check to see that everything is working. And that's really
about it for CloudFormation. Feel free to use this template to create
pipelines for projects at work or just for fun.
Now let's take a quick look at what we went over in this module.
We started by reviewing Emma's story and the HBFL project.
Then we took a bird's eye view of CodePipeline, touching
on pipelines, stages, and actions.
Next we set up our CodeCommit repository and our first pipeline to pull from it.
Then we added some actions such as deploy and test to
make our pipeline even more useful.
Adding a manual approval action before deploying is
another good idea that we implemented.
And finally, I went through a CloudFormation template that
recreates everything we built by hand in this module.
In the next module,
we're going to build on the foundation we developed and extend our
pipeline by adding Lambda invocation actions,
CloudWatch Events, and notifications. See you in the next module.