Welcome the step of the course where we'll discuss your go to market strategy which means how you will
reach your customers meaning.
How do you distribute your products and or services in terms of the what why and how of Step 8 are kicked
off of the what.
What are we going to learn.
Well if a pluggable to your business model will talk about what our direct to consumer strategy is and
what that means is do we talk to the customer directly when we sell to them.
Meaning there is no middleman.
We will also discuss our indirect distribution strategy meaning if we sell the wholesale and then others
sell our products or service for us meaning that there is a middleman.
And also if a placable is always going to discuss our online sales distribution strategy our online
distribution strategy and other distribution topics.
Let's move on to why.
Why are we dedicating an entire section to the distribution of our product and or service because you
might realize that you might want to increase your revenue by selling through third parties instead
of through your own sales force distribution.
And please note that we will discuss how your sales force is if a clickable is set up in Step nine when
we talk about sales and marketing.
Lastly how how are we going to complete.
Step number eight.
Meaning the go to market distribution part of our business plan will answer questions here in the inputs
and analysis tap Were you will notice that I included this large green shaded box here so I can humbly
challenge you to expand your thought process about how to distribute your product.
And as with the other steps when you click on the output outputs button you will see the completed go
to market strategy part of your business plan.
Thanks.