Welcome to step three of the course in terms though what why and how of step three.
I'll kick it off with the what.
What are we going to learn.
We're going to learn how to make an incredible executive summary which is basically a short summary
section of the important highlights from your entire business plan.
Now we're going to answer a lot of high level brief questions together in the inputs and analysis part
of step 3 about your business model including really important details on who the customer is.
What is the size and growth of the market.
Who is the competition.
What is the problem with the industry that we are in and the solution.
Meaning your product or service.
We will also discuss your exit strategy meaning an IPO etc. if applicable.
Moving on to why why are we answering the aforementioned questions in the executive summary.
Part of the course and not much much later in the business plan because many people that will read your
business plan might not read the rest of your business plan.
If they don't have time or if they don't think that our executive summary is amazing now our answers
will be brief as we will discuss in much more detail.
The concepts that we're going to cover in step three when we do Steps Four through 13.
OK lastly how how are we going to learn about these executive summary concepts together.
We will answer the many questions together in the inputs and analysis section and then what we'll do
is in the outputs part here in step 3 our executive summary will automatically be created for us.
Now please note that I created checkboxes like these ones here.
If you want to turn off certain parts the executive summary output if they're not applicable like the
inclusion of a board a recent milestone and a mock up or a real image of your product as these details
might not be applicable to all business plans.
Thanks.