Welcome to step 7 in terms of what why and how of Sept. 7.
I'll kick it off the what.
What are we going to learn.
We will analyze and document the description strengths and weaknesses and much more of our top three
to five competitors.
We will also discuss our strengths and our weaknesses with our business model compared to the competition
as well as how our management team compares to the competition.
We'll also compare our pricing policy pricing policy to the competition as well.
In addition we will discuss other optional things to consider like when we go to our competitors websites
for example.
What areas do they post jobs for and what.
And this is actually important.
That may actually signal what they're looking to do in the future from a product strategy or service
strategy perspective.
We'll also look at weaknesses or risks that are mentioned if applicable in our competitors annual reports
which are all free to access online.
If our competition is trade on a stock market we also look at who your competitors follow on Twitter
meaning who their customers are because all people that use Twitter that have really big customers they
follow their customers over Twitter.
This could signal something.
I'll talk about that more detail soon.
We're also a look at what other people are saying about our competition.
If a couple like what employees are saying about their management team on Glassdoor dot com if applicable.
Also you can look at Yelp and you can go to the Better Business Bureau Web site of course if applicable
and you can learn a lot about your competitor from online ratings like teachers for example on me might
look at my terrible 1 2 and 3 star reviews in my courses so they can make better versions of my courses.
OK let's move on to why why are we spending so much time addressing the competition.
Because the beauty of today's online documentation digital reality is that we can make a better product
and a better service by simply analyzing what customers have to say about our competition which it's
feedback.
That's almost in real time.
It's really cool.
Lastly how how are we going to complete Step 7.
Well we're going to answer a lot of questions in the inputs and analysis tab and you'll notice they
include a lot of optional things to think about when answering the questions in Step 7 per this green
shaded cell here.
Now on the step 7 competition outputs tabs here I included a checkboxes.
So you have the option to turn off topics that are just not relevant or of interest to you including
the omission of competitors 4 and 5.
Meaning only if you want to discuss three competitors.
Thanks.