This is my favorite part of the Course as it's a crescendo collection an amalgamation of all 13 steps
in terms of what why and how of creating your final business plan output I'll kick it off for the what.
What are we going to learn.
We're going to learn how to use the answers to the many questions that we answered in steps 1 through
13 and we're going to assemble your incredible business plan.
Let's move on to why now if we click on the final outputs business plan button here we see a massive
amount of information.
Why is everything that we have created for our business plan on this one tab and in a modular meaning
grouped fashion.
Well because I want to show you from a high level perspective all of your hard work in one location
as this will help us to create our final content for our Microsoft Word business plan.
So how are we going to create our final business plan together.
Well I want you to think of the green shaded items you see here as being your heading ones and your
blue shaded items here as being your heading twos and threes for your table of contents.
And if that doesn't make a lot of sense you don't worry because it will in a second.
Okay.
So what will happen is these will automatically link to our table of contents on the appropriate pages
in the Microsoft Word template that you selected that you want to use back in step 2.
And don't worry as we will break this process down in this part of the course and make it really easy
and fun to complete together.
Thanks.