If you're creating slides as well then please click this button here presentation slides.
And when you're finished this click this Ill say 100 percent complete.
Since this is optional it has no impact at all on the final total here.
But here's what you need to so the best way to create a slide deck is to make 10 slides that are simple.
Less is more.
And I've listed them here.
These are my 10 samples here.
BlueShield like usual.
And this is just a guideline and I have the slide numbers.
OK so it's very simplistic.
I've got the title slide which is just the name of the company and the slogan.
And if you did that if you enter all that stuff will automatically flow through here.
The second slide is a picture of the product.
If you don't have this picture push the price you can delete the slide and make your slide presentation
only nine slots and I'll show you where.
Download the predations act the template your management and board advisor slide can look something
like this.
Three employees two advisors less or more whatever you want to do.
And I had this automatically flow through to hear if you do that if mission for slide is the industry
problem.
And if you wrote the answer you probably will show up here.
And then the fifth is Inchy solution which basically says why your product or services based company
fixes the problem and it will flow through right here.
If you did that then we have in the future milestone is the next slide.
And then the seventh slide is a total just one market sentence.
And this just pulls directly from earlier in the course.
This might be a bit too long though and so I'll leave it up to you if you want to make this shorter.
OK but I'll have this sentence appear here automatically.
OK.
And you can always click these blue hyperlinks to go directly to the source other than the second Slide
8 is financials.
And this is blank only because I'm using directly from your financial model I don't have one for me
here and this will just pull information from here directly and I'll show you how to get all this information
is it.
Then we have a slide on the competition.
And basically I wrote this here and I've actually created one for you here.
It will pull in all the information for you but I'll get to that in a second.
So I think a lot more sense as I can make this as simple as possible.
Then I've got contact details and I'll just put in your contact details.
If you have them.
And so as you scroll up here and I can show you where to get the template and if you click here this
will go to your company name if you click here this will go to your company description or service product
description.
If you click here it'll take you to what goes here which is the picture of your product.
If you entered that show click here and because there's no picture in this sample here it'll link to
nothing which is right here but it tells us look it let's go back here to.
And so if we click here it'll take us to where you wrote about your management team.
If you click here it'll take you to where the problem is.
And Step Six click there and it will go there in a second there's a lot of detail in the spreadsheet.
OK.
Right here.
And it's tagged.
Let's go back to the same thing can be said about the entry solution.
If you click on it here.
Future milestone.
Click here we'll take you there.
Total just market same thing will take you there and then financials.
I'm going to show you how it is.
And second cat and then competition I wrote a sentence for you automatically and you can click there
to go back to that slide here.
Or if you want you can scroll over here to see what I wrote for you here.
OK.
Both ways work in this make more sense than act and then just contact details and you can click Bisson
it goes directly to where your contact details are if you'd entered in a phone number and also the e-mail
address.
It will automatically be populated here for you.
It's the code there of the code for the formula.
OK.
Now I want to show you how to complete this so what you can do is click here to go to my Web site and
you can download a number of different templates whichever one you think looks nice just for your company.
There are 10 blank slides and there's a bunch of them.
Can you can also see it attached to this lecture as well.
And here's how it's going to work once you download the template you want to use and I've got a sample
one here.
It's 10 slides first one is a cover page.
And as I run through them you could see here there's a description telling you how to complete each
slide and it's pretty simplistic.
And I think if you can't see this then just click down here to make sure that you see that bottom part.
And you may even have to go to View and show the bottom the notes in the bottom.
See here.
So what you're going to do is just like you did with the business plan template that you completed.
What you'll do is you can just copy this or copy this to go get the details on your company name so
I'll show you here.
I'm sure you've already seen it but just in case you're you've jumped forward to look at this Lesher
before anything else in the course of Russia.
So I paste that there and that will take you directly to where your company name is.
If you want copy it from there or you can just go here and then just copy the entire slide and then
paste special here and then change around the information.
Your call but I think it makes more sense to actually grab each one of these independently.
And if you have a logo grab that and throw in there as well.
And then the next slide here is a picture of the product.
If you have a picture of the product and the picture the product is is going to be if you click here
it'll take you directly there your product or service image can actually put that down here your product
or service image it will show you to your product.
Or service image.
And if you don't have this product or service image all then you can skip the slide and delete it and
you'll have nine slides only.
But if I went up here and I pasted that in the next you go to a blank cell pasted this in here it'll
take me directly to your product or service which is which is black.
But if you put it there it would show up there.
OK great.
Back here this is for your management and board advisers and completely optional might you want to set
this up.
But I did the Olympic ring process of three employees two advisers.
And they're right here.
That's employee one two three.
And then you visors he just copy to go directly there so your first name last name obviously you just
remember what that is but you can copy paste it in if you want.
Your job title copy that's pasted here.
And you can go and get it.
Whoops I'm sorry about that.
I pasted in a line there.
There you go.
It'll take you directly to where your job title is right here.
If you wrote it I wrote CEO and founder in that example.
But whatever is here will be picked up and you'll go here and you'll copy and then you'll whether your
job copy was you're going to go here and just paste special.
You know and change the formatting.
You can if you want.
And for these images here you can go and get your image which you might have pasted in the course and
I want to show you how to make the images look cool and round like that's real easy.
It's kind of fun to backspace.
Make sure I just don't have any trailing spaces at the end.
OK so if you add an image there.
And I'll just get my image here.
If you paste it there it will show up and you copy and bring it over.
But let me just get my amateur.
So we got the from linked in as we discussed earlier in the course.
And so if I paste this and I want to get a circle what I can do is I can go up here first of all and
paint brush and then circle that or I can do is I can go up here to picture forment
and then crop to shape make it circle triangle whatever you want.
I guess that's how you do it.
OK.
And then you can add a little shadow if you want as well by going to quick styles and then you can add
a shadow like that if you want it to your call completely your call completely.
And the images you'll grab here if you put them in the course earlier on.
If you put them in your template you just paste.
Let's get on that image for a second sorry about that
spot.
OK.
And then you just paste here.
Get rid of the showing space.
Her paragraph mark and then it's going to pick it up here if you're interested.
There are other issues just like this copy and paste them and bring it over.
OK.
And rinse lather repeat with these board advisers if you want in every single presentation is different.
We have our own styles so you know this is just a presentation template sample.
You can download the other ones that look a lot nicer.
Again by going up to the top of the presentation slide section and then you can click here to go to
my website to download the presentation templates to use.
Or you can get it from the course attached to this Lesher.
OK.
Moving on what's your industry problem and what's the industry's solution.
And you can go here and get the details.
If it was brought forward here I just couldn't hear industry problems and you can just kind of copy
that or you can click here to go directly to the industry problem and then copy what's in here you go.
Copy and then you pay special over top of the problem here.
Just so you don't I say pay special is it because I don't want you to mess up or change the formatting
but keep text on your column.
Same thing in a solution future product milestone same thing if you had your future milestone written
in.
Can copy this.
Paste it here again make sure that there's no trailing space and it'll take you exactly in the course
where you wrote down.
If you wrote that down your future product or a mouse.
Here you copy and paste special.
So let's say I copy that.
Pretend that's us.
And then what I would do is I would highlight here pay special as text was a text like this and then
you might want to just prettied up move it over whenever a lead up to you and then what you do is the
same thing with the total just market.
And then I've got just 30 more seconds here and what you do is you're going to copy this.
These two here and it will pick up those two areas.
I'll show you what is going to look like actually the final output is going to look like this.
So right here these are two different sections.
This in this so one of two books like this.
And copy and then you're going to paste it as an image
and then you can make this bigger if you want.
And then I wrote at the bottom there you might want a crop.
And so if on the outside you got these lines here you're going to crop this by selecting crop right
here.
And then you're going to crop it and then do the exact same thing with this one here because you're
going to copy and paste this one here.
We're almost done here.
OK.
And then you're going to copy this here and then right here you're going to pay special again as a picture
make it the same size.
If you want just to make it a little bit bigger
and then you just want to make it roughly the same size so it lines up nicely like that.
And again you can crop it if you see those outside those lines in the outside like this.
It's a little finicky sometimes you have to zoom way way in to get it done.
OK.
Hold on try it again.
I think we're going to get here.
We do it all.
We we're so close.
OK.
And will widen it a bit.
There you go.
That's good.
That's good enough.
That looks great.
It's fun.
And these are just simplistic data points here so you can highlight both and drag them down.
That if you want at the bottom I wrote we're happy to provide you with detail financials.
Upon request please see our contact page on the last page here you'll do competition.
So what I did here is just highlight that paste up here and I'll take you helps take you back to make
sure that that's based there and he'll take you right here.
And if you want you can just copy this or copy what Tom Mackley put there for you and then you'll pay
special.
And because there's nothing written in for your stuff yet nothing will appear there.
You can even copy it from there if you want.
But here's what mine looks like just a bunch of fields so they'll copy yours not mine.
And then what you can do is go here and then you can pay special on top of here.
I'll show you that it looks like
it looks something like that's obviously you want to produce up.
Change the formatting around a lot if you want and then drag it up make the font smaller if you want
looks good.
I am a control zere controls that is I think.
And that's that's what it look like.
And then here you just put in your contact details make this a little bit higher up.
And so use whatever template you want.
And again you can take what you've done here and put all of these slides as I explained before in the
appendix parts if you want your final business plan if you have any questions about this please let
me know.
Thanks.