Please click on this button here.
Inputs and analysis.
Now this is a very short step it's really easy to do.
The first question is have you created a logo for your company.
Just select yes or no or not a playable.
And then when you get your logo you can paste it here.
And actually what I'll do is I'll show you actually how I got my logo done in more detail.
All you got to do is just click on this link here and I'll show you how I I had this done I use five
or dot com and these are the four logos that the person I used over five or dot com that's five 5 we
are with another our comp and I selected to use this one for my sample company and you can paste your
logo here if you want to if it's applicable.
And then just entering your cover page date here and then illegal disclosure in every country is different
but select for legal disclosure we want or select not to put a legal disclosure so I'll just like the
first one for example and everything that we do on this slab will be reflected in the next slide as
well so I can select this one here and you see how shark virtual reality is used here is because I mentioned
in my name if you went to your name as well you're coming company I mean it should appear again.
So after you've answered those those questions a short one.
You can click this to mark this as a 100 percent done.
Or you can actually answer the questions and it will automatically update here to be done or not.
There's only two questions that you have to answer here.
And that's why it says 50 percent done because there's only four questions right.
So this one we answered.
And if you were to answer this one too it would appear so let's just say.
No September 1st 2019 and so this here will then change to 100 percent.
You can always use manual override but this button to say 100 percent as well.
And you'll see here that this needle has moved in the whole course.
We're now down 14 percent of the course.
OK great.
So listen now click on the output and see what our output looks like.
So if you enter in your information here business name Kate the company in it and if you entered in
here your product or service subscription then it would appear here just like mine.
And we just entered the date together over that which did that.
So that appears here.
What sort of accident that appears down here and then your name and then if you entered in a web address
the issue up here and your post addressed as well just you can enter this information here just in this
part.
Here is Kobuk.
Step 1 do it.
And if you're always curious where a field came from you can always just copy it and then paste it in
here.
I'll show you.
So what you do is go here.
There hit enter and then it'll take you directly back.
Right here see where we created that field.
Can your Internet address.
Okay great.
So let's go back now to your cover page and so based on what you entered in you have your cover page
done here and this here is my sample and this is yours.
OK.
I always have sample in the middle of shark virtual reality the pretend company and then yours is on
the right here.
And what you do is if you scroll down see every cover page is numbered right page 5 cover page 6 whatever
it is all the way down to her page 50.
This is a big document.
So select whatever cover page that you want to use for your final output here.
And it will feed through later and you'll see why in a second.
So if we're to select.
Cover Page number one for example.
Then we would take a note of this because later on when we create our business plan the final output
if we click here it'll say right here blow you blow you'll find your final business plan content.
Since you selected page 1 in step 2 which we just did then download the Microsoft Word business plan
template called business plan template.
One you can download this by going to the course or you can just click here to go to my Web site and
download it.
And so when he downloaded it looked like this here business plan template one.
And here's all the fields.
OK.
But we'll talk about completing this in much more detail and a lot of this stuff is optional.
But I want to be very thorough.
So again what we'll talk about this later on in the course when we actually create your final output
here in the step here.
So we're now done with with Step 2.
So please make sure that it says 100 percent done.
You can answer the questions here or you can click here to manually override and it will say 100 percent.
So now we are 14 percent of the way done through the course.
Thanks.