Please click on Step 11 other miscellaneous inputs and analysis and this section here is for other stuff
we haven't talked about yet.
And I went through a really long list of things to add to a business plan and where I didn't know or
I wasn't sure where it where to include these that would be relevant for everybody and so I put in a
lot of risks here.
OK.
And so one of them here is one of the is the risk of future technology developments and it doesn't matter
if you're running a tech company or not.
Technology developments in the future will have an impact on the industry whether it's I don't know
maybe you're in the taxi industry a decade ago and you kind of foresaw that there would be some sort
of online a lift or Uber type platform longer term you want to document this because it allows the reader
to understand how long term focused you are.
It's it's really important to know what can destroy your industry so you can get ahead of it and disrupt
yourself.
And I'll give you an example.
So there's Reed Hastings brilliant man who also lives pretty close to here.
He loves education as well.
He's the founder and CEO of Netflix of course.
And he disrupted his business model.
And investors were upset for a while but he didn't care.
He's such a brilliant man.
But Netflix used to be DVD only and then he went to streaming longer term because the writing was on
the wall that that online distribution would disrupt his business model longer term.
So I want you to think like like Reid did please.
HASTINGS.
And just think about what can disrupt your business model longer term from a technology development
perspective and just comment on it and it could always be preempted every battles while enforcement
fought.
Another quote there from Sun said the art of war.
OK next up we've got risks of future competition emerging case so let's say there was a large company
in your industry or a similar industry to yours.
That's not in your market yet.
If they were to enter the industry what would that mean.
What would that mean for your company.
This one here is just risk of future macroeconomic developments and so if the economy goes into a significant
recession you know how you react and if you go to the annual reports of all your competition if applicable.
We did that earlier in Step seven when we went to apples to apples and your reports have said for the
past X years when every many years you'll see that all of these new reports mention some sort of economic
risk that could emerge.
And just talk about it here briefly if you can.
And I think that the best business models are the ones that are founded during recessions because they're
lean and mean and they can come out in and really scaler business when the economy picks up and business
is always cyclical no matter what anybody tells you.
If anybody says this time is different it never is.
But just kind of right down here how future macher macroeconomic decline could impact your business.
OK.
Next up we've got future other developments.
If I haven't listed a risk yet than just had it here please.
You want to cover every angle so that there are no questions basically from from from whoever is reading
this business plan that can be really impressed with you when it's done.
And I wrote here.
Disaster recovery and I made this one mandatory as well.
You know what your disaster recovery plan if if there's if there's a fire or if you lose all of your
data.
That sort of thing it just shows that you're very thoughtful with your long term approach to creating
your business plan.
And and the reader the business plan will love that.
This one is optional but I love it.
I love it.
OK.
This one here.
When I used to work in the hedge fund industry I would whenever I met with a CEO of a company I was
considering investing in or vice versa I would always ask that person this question which is this was
the most mis understood aspect of your business plan by investors or by business partners or by whatever
is it.
It really shows again that you're very thoughtful in your approach and you've thought of everything
to include But it's a little bit esoteric So it's optional.
So when you're done with all the questions here this will update to 100 percent or you can click here
to override it and this will automatically update to 100 percent.
So we're making a lot of progress.
Now we're done with Step 11 inputs.
Now there's miscellaneous documents you might have that you want to include here in the appendix and
don't worry we'll cover that in a lot of detail later on when we discuss what to include in the appendix
or I clicked on the image there.
But I will see you in the next Lesher where we cover the outputs.
First step 11.
Thanks.