What we're going to do is we're going to talk about sales and marketing.
OK.
And so the first question here is optional which is what is your sales force structure and you can talk
about how your sales team is is set up you know who's in charge of of selling to to certain geographies
except cetera.
Do you have a name to count strategy which basically means that you have a handful of employees assigned
to huge accounts and they will have a couple of accounts each and sort them out to make it better for
you.
But if you want to learn how to get customers you can go to my Web site and download my networking book
for free.
It's it's you just go to that Web site Harroun Ventris dot com.
So our time at this because we can all see it and then it'll help you get a meeting with literally anybody.
And what I also did actually is if if you're interested.
I created a couple of videos that can help you out a lot when it comes to networking.
And I'll go down here through them.
Basically what you do is if you want to meet any CEO in the world literally any CEO this will help you
a lot.
When you're selling or you're trying to sell your product or service it's so frustrating when you deal
with people in a company they're not the decision makers because very bureaucratic and I always recommend
going right to the top and I know that might you know might might upset some people whenever but I don't
like to mess around.
I want to be successful.
And then if you want you can go through these as well just to kind of understand how to get free publicity.
This one actually is really helpful from a sales perspective.
I recommend watching it.
I RECORDED IN MY KITCHEN.
But basically what Marc Benioff did who is the founder of the largest company here in San Francisco
the biggest employer called sales force is he made friends and networked with 50 of the top tech and
finance journalists in the world.
And he met with them and that was his marketing and sales strategy.
He was brilliant.
And now I really understand why sales and marketing are always grouped together.
But but check those out if you want if you want to see how to create a great logo or how some of the
bigger brands think about their logos.
You can watch this as well.
There's other other stuff here as well.
But it's not for everybody saw a move on now.
So just talk about your cell structure here.
If you want.
And then here just document what your sales force incentive structure is like how do people get bonuses.
Do they get commission.
Some of the bigger software companies have accelerators which means if you pass and hit your goal of
commissions in a certain month by selling a certain stuff then you get a larger percent of everything
incremental you sell on top of that.
So anyway just just another idea for you to think about.
This is all optional though because a lot of a lot of startups won't even have these these new sales
structure set up initially when they get up and running.
Another one here is sales force registration.
You need to get a license in some industries you do like to sell healthcare products sometimes and financial
services to answer those questions there if you want.
Again they are optional.
Next up and this here is quite a I've got a couple of large columns here.
Rose I should say just to help you out and you can minimize this here if you want a little bit more
more real estate here in your screen.
But these are questions and comments and suggestions to really help you to write your marketing or social
media portion of your business plan.
So what I recommend is to check out how the more established competitors in your industry are leveraging
social media Instagram YouTube etc. and YouTube is a big deal because YouTube is now the second biggest
search engine in the in the world obviously after Google.
And so if you're curious about how to record online and make online videos and whatnot you can always
go to my blog just to hear whatever.
And I made a video on not on how to log in I've made so many mistakes doing what I do but I want to
help you so you can work smarter not harder.
And then there's also something called repurposing content.
So if you write on LinkedIn you can take a quote from the article you wrote for your social media strategy
and put it on Twitter Instagram and actually I have to go here.
I'm sorry but.
But I I wrote this one here how to write a book and give it to potential customers and it costing you
next to nothing and it's easy to do and anybody can do it.
And I think that should be part if you want of your marketing strategy as well.
I want it to be thought of as a leader from a sales and marketing perspective in your industry and I
want people to to think about you as understanding more about the industry than anybody else and I want
you to write a lot if you can online on LinkedIn and and make online videos too because it's free.
It's Here's another example of how to do it.
It's free to do it.
It'll help you get customers over time.
But you've got to be really long term focused if you're going to do this sort of thing because it's
it's tough to quantify what your return on investment is from sales and marketing.
But but it is their longer term when you market.
This one's really good.
I'm proudest when here this is called How to write great online articles and so this one here I really
recommend that you watch.
It's I did it in about two years ago and I used to have my own artist or my own column in Ink magazine
and my editor taught me how to write like a professional journalist.
It's 40 minutes long.
It will really help you understand how to write.
Hope I don't.
Hopefully I don't look too much older than that.
Anyway that's it's there and it's networking goldmine as well.
KOC and I want to create content online daily OK.
Again I want to be a thought leader and you've got to collect email addresses if you're allowed to and
obviously be mindful of GPDA.
I think it's called and always have the opportunity for your for your people in your email address to
unsubscribe at the bottom.
OK.
But it is there's no better distribution channel.
I know it sounds old school but email is the best way.
At this point you can use MailChimp which I mention before or something a little bit more advanced which
I use called active campaign and I mention writing a book and you can watch the video on it if you care
you know give as much as you can to your customers as much as you can you know help them out.
Help them get customers.
And you'll find that when it comes to when it comes to business and this took me years to realize you
know relationships are always more important than product knowledge.
And the more you give the more you get in return longer term it's karma whatever.
I like helping people it's just it is it is it is OK.
And to make sure in your emails you have links obviously to you know Twitter Facebook whatever it is
at the bottom Instagram's a big one.
It's getting more popular I'm having some issues understanding how to use it properly I've started.
But anyway it's just an idea.
All right and here are some more.
And these are more suggestions not really questions that are going to help you from a marketing social
media part.
A portion of your business plan which is important.
It's important.
And if you find that doing social media is tough for you because you have to or you have to do so many
different things when you when you create your content.
Like I'll show you actually mean over here.
So let me close this and I'll show you why I'm closing it.
So if I open up my browser what I do is for my daily flogs I repurpose them everywhere so I upload it
daily YouTube video here and this automatically goes to a new draft page in Linked-In where I upload
reference of of that video.
And then I just upload the logfile cover here for my weekly email and then Twitter.
This is for me to tweet the blog.
This is for me to send it out I'm on Facebook.
And this here is just to put it up on on my website as well and you can always go there and read the
blogs if it's helpful to you OK what topics are OK.
But if it's really overwhelming for you instead of doing what I do we're six tabs open automatically
within within my browser you can go to HootSuite dot com which is kind of like a portal.
It lets you sell all of your social media stuff or distribute.
I should say one platform she write once read many cut and now make sure that the Linked In profile
of yourself and all your employees is amazing.
You can copy and paste this if you want this old and it teaches you based on lecture I gave on line
on how to how to create an amazing LinkedIn LinkedIn profile and you also want to use Google Alerts
just to find out about the branding of your customer in any way that that sort of thing.
And then this one's kind of out there.
But if all of the social media stuff is complicated hire somebody that's an intern maybe somebody that
gets it.
I find that my kids get social media a lot better than I do my kids don't watch TV.
They watch YouTube whatever.
I find that millennials too are amazing because I was clueless when I first started in the stuff and
I still kind of am.
OK.
And then if you want to make a professional looking brochure you can go to 5 or dot com.
OK go here and get somebody to make it for you for next to nothing.
And that's right.
My book covers done and my logos and we talked about my logos here.
Here in the cover page here.
And there's the video actually if you click right here which I show you how I created these logos on
fiber which literally cost me five bucks to get all these made.
And the turnaround time was was really fast.
Now only go back here to step nine and put yourselves Mark OK again.
All right.
So Fiver's a great resource.
And there's other ones online too that will help you out a lot as well.
If you want to Subha of log or create YouTube videos this is a 40 40 minute vlog I create a YouTube
video one day on how to set up a blog from scratch.
What equipment to use and all that stuff.
Now when it comes to web sites I personally use Squarespace for mine.
But you can use Wordpress as well which I think has some free options but but in Squarespace Let me
show you here actually.
And you can skip if you want to here in this lecture.
If you don't care about this.
But but I created my web sites here on Squarespace.
It's really really easy to do.
I don't want to learn about your new home and you but you just create new pages there's no coding at
all.
They help you design it is well and you pay a minimal fee as well.
And anyway I have my entire web presence here.
So and I blog and put my blog stuff on here directly in my here to market my stuff.
So let me go back to your story.
OK.
And you can create from scratch a great looking web site using Squarespace and have all these wonderful
templates with images.
It's fun too.
OK.
And then oh for business cards.
I don't want to use a place like Vistaprint where which is where I got some of my brochure stuff something
I actually want you to go to this Web site here.
I'm going to show you.
It's called Move as an account to dot com ads your business card is kind of old school in some countries.
People still use a lot not as much in the Bay Area but these are wonderful business cards that are that
are that are thick and they're really creative as well.
And Air B and B whatever a lot of other great companies you use them.
It's a little bit little bit pricey so obviously just do a search on the word coupon and then Miew and
then you can get these for a lot cheaper.
It's a little pricey sometimes it can cost you 20 cents just to to use one whatever.
So I use them sparingly if at all.
And then here you want to write on your social media strategy so all these these little pieces of advice
humbly for what it's worth here in these two rows.
You can use this for the content of some of these questions you answer here so this one here.
Talk about your social media strategy here.
And I tag it as your social media strategy in case you always want to know where it is in this entire
spreadsheet.
And then what your lead generation strategy So here you're going to talk about your email marketing
campaign or lead generation campaign and how you get customers from online sources.
If it's pleasurable which it should be and then hear your off line media strategy and if you is like
old school stuff like radio TV newspaper trade shows etc. you want to mention that here and you can
always look at how your competition does that sort of thing as well.
Obviously it's getting a lot cheaper to advertise on you know radio whatever in other places because
you know Nazmi people are using that and you can even consider looking into creating a podcast longer
term.
But the bottom line is you want to repurpose your content you write once read many.
So if you create a blog daily or whatever then maybe a little video snippet can be used on Instagram.
And there's a guy named Gary Vaynerchuk and do a search on him Gary V.
That's what people call him and see his campaign.
He does a really really good job on this and he is a thought leader he's very vocal as well so let me
see Gary V if I search here will take us his Web site of course it does.
And so he does a really good job.
He's edgy but he gets his point across.
OK.
So you can understand what his social media strategy is just by going to his Web site here.
He's whatever he is.
The thing is if you don't remind people of your success a lot of times people don't know about it.
I know that sounds a little bit out there and uncomfortable for a Canadian to say whatever.
But anyway you get the idea.
But but use his as a model if you want to because I think he he gets it and he has gotten and he understands
it better than I think anybody out there.
So Gary and you can listen to his podcast as well.
It's weekly and it's engaging.
And so once you're done with all this your score will score your status we'll update here as well as
here as in all cases or you can just go here to override what I did there and if you want to come back
to this social media stuff later you can always you know click here like I've mentioned before and flag
these flag appear down there so that those that fly a couple of them whatever and then come back to
it later.
And to your comments on the right there if you want but we are now done with Step Nine where we're almost
two thirds done.
Our price is 64 percent.
Great job.
And I will see you in the next lecture where we will talk about sales and marketing outputs.
Thanks.