That what we can do is we can get some pretty cool images.
I'm very visual and I love the visual process when we create these are these documents so that when
we show who are our board is I don't I didn't go to Harvard Law or work at those companies but just
an example.
And this guy Gates William I'll show you down here.
It look like that.
And for our final business plan output will be there as well.
And even for the presentation slides if you care and you want to create a presentation and you can always
put the presentation in the in the appendix section which I'll talk about later.
But you can even put them on this one slide so that you have a slide that looks like this is like Olympic
rings right and it's got you know three people here that work at the company.
And then these are maybe two of the advisors you throw here and it just helps to assuage any concerns
your investors or readers of the business plan might have a boat do your background or any gaps etc.
which is why we talked about gaps in a lot of detail there in the previous question so let me go back
here to inputs for managements.
Okay great.
And you can go and just get a bunch of Logos as well if you want.
So let's say that person worked at these companies here you can go here and you'll see different different
logos so you can copy this logo if you want to copy the image and then just do the same thing I did
which was shoes and these weird this was just what I do pasted here.
Oh there it is there.
Sorry.
I think it's going to work came through.
All right fine.
And you can make it smaller to whatever dimension you want to use so let's just go here just to tidy
it up and use this as a faster faster.
Drag it over and go one one.
There you go.
And then I can just kind of drag this over there again that's an easier way to do it.
Hold it there.
OK.
And then you can add all those images here if you want to.
And I can use the same methodology used here so let's see what size they I point 3:8.
OK so we'll do that again.
So I'll go here.
Zero point three OK and that will format the same size.
Just keep it consistent and I recommend throwing in two or three logos.
You don't want in a date your reader of the business plan or the presentation slides to me logo's you
get the ideas put in there.
All right.
And then he writes if you want with the strengths of that board member and just right here a little
bit about them as well.
This will go into our business plan mash output part here I'll show you in a future election coming
up.
You can just write a little bit of I don't know a summary here like this guy here has a Ph.D. which
stands for plumbing heating and dishwashing where he was a Rhodes Scholar research scholar.
Sorry Dad I'm trying to be funny.
Working.
I know.
All right.
So anyway just write all that stuff and then just scroll down and do the same thing for the second board
advisor if you want a second board adviser and a third one.
Say I don't have enough marking experience on my business plan.
There's this guy Seth Godin his real name going south and north.
He worked at gamble and Procter.
That's the real logo.
And maybe he worked at this company here all made up obviously.
See I don't have a market experience so I can get somebody using LinkedIn using the methodology I showed
you has something with me that will meet with me and we'll be a board adviser.
OK.
It's just copy and paste in the picture and that's Seth Jones actual picture there from a from from
from LinkedIn.
And every time you copy images from LinkedIn I know they look around initially but you copy and paste
and they actually end up looking square.
So you can get.
I mean anybody say we go here to this guy here who apparently looks a lot like Brad Pitt or George Clooney.
I've been told.
Just kidding.
But when you copy and it's probably work for mine.
That is me.
But whatever you copy anyone's name and image I should say what you'll see is it will appear Square.
So let's go here.
Let's say this person here.
OK.
I met her actually she used to chew you to me.
She's cool.
I met her down in Brazil.
So you click here and then you would right click.
And then if you were to paste it.
It would appear rectangular.
Right.
So you paste it and then we use the same.
What happens there takes awhile I guess.
And then what you do is you click it and then you'd go you know 1.7 five by 1.7 five and then you just
kind of drag that all the way over here for all your images.
And I know it's a little bit arduous it's kind of fun too but when I would just I recommend doing it
and you'll see exactly where we're going to put this in our in our business plan I shall take you there
now.
OK.
So our management team part.
Ill go right here and then we'll copy and paste it there.
Actually let me show you what's going look like so let's grab this and we say we're putting in this
person here as an advisor.
That would actually go in the advisor section on management put it down here right.
So he's the second adviser outpaced that there.
I would get the bio and paste it there as well as the the name of the person.
And then what we'll do later is I'll show you when we're formatting this in this part of the Course
here when we're formatting this rock what we'll do is we'll actually get rid of all those those lines
those borders as well.
It all look really clean and nice as well and you'll see what these fields mean as wanted to kind of
visualize and show you why we're doing all this stuff so we just back out of that.
OK.
OK so you'd enter in all your born advisors if you want to have them at all and you can just skip this
too if you want.
And I just put dummy data in here for all the advisors.
OK.
Then you write your own bio.
OK and so this is all just made up Tony shark is whatever this is his background.
Let's see.
That's the image of that person.
And in a couple of these images I showed you how to get them directly from from Linked In.
And of course you have to ask these people to if you're really going to put it on an official business
plan.
And that's actually really who works for me correct guy OK.
And we just go down here and you'll find that you click on this and we'll go back to the name of the
person earlier on.
OK so Ryan Reynolds it clicked that will go back to where we we documented that earlier in the course.
I'll call you quickly here.
So if we click here on this person's name you can change that person's name right here as well.
All right let's go back to Step Four crates.
And again the reason I clicked this instead of clicking up here is whenever you click on these buttons
it jumps to the very top of each of these tabs.
Nice one to save us time.
OK so.
So you you would.
Put the image of all of your employees here and I'll tell exactly when to put them in and then paste
some logos as well like the three logos I showed you above.
Rinse lather repeat this for all employees if you care to answer them in and for all board advisors
if you want as well.
And so I give you the option enter up to 10 employees and I think three board advisors.
Yeah.
So this is all the same thing all the scroll down I've dummy data here.
And if you have any questions about this please let me know as well.
OK.
We're done tenth tenth person done.
And again if you don't have data in here this will look different these these fields.
OK.
It'll basically it'll it'll tell you to skip or scroll down and skip over this one.
There we go.
We're almost done here.
OK.
And this one here is optional but if you want you can enter in more details like who you're looking
to hire and what in what sectors etc. or what kind of employees.
And if you if you document and weaknesses earlier on and I didn't and I did not in this example but
they would appear here care of the weaknesses of every employee.
So you know what kind of person you want to hire and you documented here.
OK.
We're here actually in the white part in that blue parts for for example.
All the weeks's will come through.
If you can.
OK.
And if you want you can write down or just kind of think about who's in charge of all of these and these
are the major functions that are roles in most companies.
Right you can just kind of right down here just you know who is who's in charge of what.
As you think about putting together your management team sector can.
And then as I mentioned I like to run a really lean company and I like to outsource a lot of stuff and
so if you get people that you outsource stuff to and I gave you the option enter in five of them.
OK.
So I didn't include an image.
There's no point in cleaning which is people that were just kind of outsourcing things here and they
will look like this here outsource partners here and say I've got five of them and then we'll just vanish
I'll show you how to put in just the name in the bio.
That's it.
But you can answer them here.
So I made the same person for all five is just an example.
But you have different people.
And again this is optional because it has a word optional here.
OK.
So the name of the person entering the company and everything is tagged so that it is pulled forward
later in the document when we create the final business plan and I'll show you in the letter after this
one what the output looks like as well.
It's pretty cool.
All right.
So you write the bio of the first outsource partner second outsource partner type their name here if
applicable where they work.
I know I not the same person just dummy data.
Their title and then a bio.
And when you write the BIOS for people that are on your board of advisors and and these other outsource
partners bios just think about what the gaps are in the skill set and the weaknesses of all of your
employees because you want to give a more cohesive high level overview of your entire management team
including people that work there meaning in your company and maybe it's just use to just include one
include up to 10 people here and then board advisors as well.
And then your outsource partners and you can see here where the other stuff is going to feed into and
it is extraordinarily thorough.
OK.
And by the way after you complete all of this stuff later on the course and I'll explain exactly when.
When you right click this and you click Update field the right names of the right people will show up
here automatically.
OK.
And the page numbers as well.
I didn't change these yet.
That's why they appear unchanged.
So this document the blank verse in this document is 62 pages.
It is very thorough.
OK.
And I didn't want to leave any stone unturned.
And a lot of the stuff you may not use so we'll just delete them later.
And there's just a ton more stuff that's in order of course like milestones financial success or a bell
make much more sense as we progressed through this course.
OK.
So a lot of this is optional optional optional.
It's a lot of questions but there's a lot of optional stuff too right.
OK.
And and that's it.
And so everything that you documented here will be used on the next output part as well as the complete
outport output I should say amalgamation portion as well.
And we'll get to that much much later.
But let me let me go back here now and this will take me to the top of that tab.
That's OK because we've And she had all the information hypothetically speaking.
And then as you answer the questions for the questions that are required.
Ill keep track and tell you what percent you've done of this and after you've updated all of this this
will change here to 100 percent done which will be shown here and the flags as well if you have any.
And a lot of the times you'll want to flag these things say you reach out to some people that you want
to put on your board or you're not sure about it yet or you might consider it.
So I would go over here and just flag some of these entries here.
OK so you just go here come back to this question and you can always filter it based on the ones you
want to come back to later right.
This is pretty comprehensive but you'll see a flag is created here.
Just like with the other tabs you'll see that we have a flag right here.
So when you're done with this tab you can click this as well which will override in 300 hundred percent
up there if you want to if you want to.
And then updates the course.
And it now shows that you are almost a third done between 9 percent and if you answered your name it
would you would read a little message there for you and try to personalize it for you.
There's the update and that is it.
And so what I'll do is in the next lecture I'll go through the outputs part of the mansion section meaning
everything we just typed in here will we pulled into here and I'll explain what it means and how to
customize it even more.