Okay now that we're down with units or number of hours billed and you can read that comment there if
you want to but I'm setting this up so that services based business models can use this financial model
and product based as well.
Okay good.
So now that we got the number of units we have to enter in how much it's going to cost to buy a single
unit or how much we're selling each one for which is called The average selling price or people on Wall
Street called the HSP and if you're doing a services model you would enter in here the hourly rate charged
and kime And if you're doing the services model you're allowed to have half numbers here if you want
like you my bill a half an hour whatever.
Ok so here you'll enter in how much you going to bill for.
So let's say that the the goggles or product or whatever it is you're selling.
Let's say you sell each unit for $99.
OK.
So and let's just keep that constant for the first year whatever it is you're selling it's nine bucks
and they're not going to pay just the value here so you can go to space special and then you like values
and do that because if you're using a Mac this is what it looks like.
OK good.
And let's say that the average selling price goes lower after the first year let's say that we figured
out how to produce this thing on a much cheaper basis or for some reason your bill your hourly rate
at a lower rate.
So let's say that we dropped by 5 percent lower.
So I'll just take this time.
Point eight point nine five for a 5 percent drop.
See what that gets to that amount.
They're not around number but it's 5 percent drop just for fun.
So I'm gonna to copy this now.
And then I'm going to paste it just for the rest of this year.
And this is just dummy data but I think this will help you understand or use this and how to model financially
okay.
And then you can just paste special the value and can do that the value.
Okay great.
And then what we can do is let's say that by the third year that's the pricing point drops to.
I'm just going to make a number up here seventy nine dollars.
Okay we're getting more efficient competitors.
And for the industry and we charge a lower pricing points.
So I'm going to go here and enter this amount here.
Right click and I'm just going to pay special just about you get good.
And then let's say that the pricing point drops to $69 here for whatever reason.
K and I get a copy this and I can pay special just about X I don't mess up the formatting like the borders
in different places and stuff.
Right click and pay special that done.
And then we see hold on a second and you'll see it the spark lines are up in there.
And then let's say here that the pricing point drops to $54 for whatever reason you could change on
a monthly basis as well I just want to have a dummy date in here so I can show you trends and the fun
part about financial modeling in general is you look for high level trends.
It's so fun like accounting isn't is a science.
It has to be precise.
But finance when you're predicting the future is a bit more of an art.
It's fun.
And a lot of these answers might be based on what you entered in for milestones for example earlier
in the course or when you plan to release products that sort of thing and so I'm not going to enter
in the rest of the data here hear I'm saying leave that empty for now.
So now that we have the average selling price or the hourly billing rate depending what kind of business
you have.
And now we have the number of units sold.
So if we sold 100 units in January of 2013 for example at 9 bucks each that our revenue is obviously
going to be 100 times 99 which will be reflected up here.
So 100 times 9 9 9 thousand nine hundred Now I did not put curtseys here on purpose.
I didn't put Yahn in front of it or a pound or whatever but all the currency stuff will be reflected
for you if I click here.
See here it says revenue and net income forecasts are in Canadian dollars.
And if you were to change this back here and I'm happy to see my beloved Canadian flag appear here on
the Windows version.
But if we were to change it say leave the country like that for now.
But this has changed.
I'm going to pick a random currency ready going to go here.
Boom boom boom.
That one whatever currency that is there appears here.
And if you want you can click here to get an update on that currency if you want a more recent version
of it.
OK.
So that's why I'm so ignorant.
I don't even know where that is first.
I'm so eager and I'm going to change it.
Please don't give me negative rating if you're from there.
So I only go to Gibralter pants.
OK.
So that's the exchange rate for Jabalpur pants.
And it updates here at your Balter pants.
And the reason I say that is because if we go back here to financials and just click it there then we
go here at all.
You'll see that it updates here.
The revenue net income aren't Gibralter pounds and you'll see that revenue appears because I've engine
in revenue I haven't answered any expenses yet.
Okay.
And I'll explain this more detail soon.
That's why net incomes are the same as the revenue which we're in the rabbit and cat.
And but you see revenue here and I just entered in the first five years.
Right.
So you see steady growth then for some reason it plateaus there.
And if I click here on the home and I scroll down you can see that that data is starting to populate
through here on your 1 pager as well.
Here at the okay it's not accurate yet because I have Tenterden expenses and other items but I just
wanted to show you that it appears here.
And also here it says Gibralter pounds at this rate and again and you can update that rate if you want
to by going to here.
And then just clicking directly one on that that thing there.
Okay.
Let's go back now to financials.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm going to make this a bit wider for us so we can read the numbers
there is getting bigger in the second.
Okay.
So he can just go here and DoubleClick My take a second or two for it to open up.
But there you go.
Good.
And if you want you can get rid of decimals as well by going here highlight all the items and get rid
decimal system make it smaller if you want and every currency is difference.
It looks like this made a little bit too high that's fine.
But for now we're going to do and this is optional as you can enter in the number of returns you had
or hour or hours that were refunded if it's a services model.
OK.
I don't leave this blank for now but if you want you can do that actual and say hey we had a big product
recall that we see in a proxy we have shipped over here to put into a disaster scenario for a couple
of months over here.
We had a big product recall here.
And let's say that 100 units were returned.
And you're going to see the chaos this creates.
And for those of you that are creating a product.
Please be careful with inventory inventory can destroy a company for those as old as I am.
I remember when I was a kid in the 80s and Atari big video and company released this video game for
E.T. and it was the worst video game ever and they actually had to literally bury the Barry E.T. video
games bury the inventory in the deserts.
And it's interesting a lot of them are now big collectors and there it is that's what it looks like.
And I mention this I know it's a little bit off topic and nostalgic for me.
There's the box along with starburst.
I'm hungry for starburst but I'm showing this because inventory can destroy a company and I want to
impress upon you the fact that please be careful when it comes to inventory and only build stuff.
The second before you want to sell it.
And if you buy books from Amazon like paperbacks look on the last page of the paperback because it will
show the day that it was printed which is usually a day or two after you ordered it anyway.
So I will include just a disaster scenario here for a couple of a couple of months just for fun and
you'll see what that does to revenue and the company it could actually own almost bankrupted.
OK we're going to stop every 20 minutes.
All right.
Great.
So let's scroll down now.
And I provided another revenue line item for you Kate in case you wanted to add another revenue line
it totally up to you.
But I want to name this now.
Whatever product is you're selling.
So all right here just's VR goggles and that will get reflected everywhere as well.
Case It says here.
Now if your Go-Go's sees now the spark line it's all done for it's pretty cool.
And you can call it consulting hours if you want depending on kind of business you have.
And then right here this is an optional revenue line item and in here there's no math behind it if you
want you can creates insert a couple of rows whenever or just scroll them in the of the spreadsheet
and insert a couple of more calculations.
Let's say that we had a a services business model like a lot of software companies sell the product.
And then there's a services or maintenance line item sales code maintenance and then a lot of the time
it's 20 percent of revenue.
I'm just going to go up here actually and make it 20 percent of whatever I sold here I know it's not
perfect don't do it up here because it will create a circular reference because or don't do I should
say at the top here it will create a circular reference because it's is going to be this plus this next
revenue line every day.
But I'm going to make my maintenance 20 percent of my goggles revenue.
OK it's not perfect but a lot of business balls are like that.
OK so let's go up here and see you at my goggles revenue.
So 20 percent of $9900 is is this here Khalilah so I'll just do that or copy this formula all the way
across.
It's not perfect but I just want to basically appeal to everybody that's taken this course that would
also be a little bit different.
And I'm just going to highlight all these guys here.
Bear with me for a second.
Here
over here
and then here
cut and paste here the formula
great.
All right.
And that's this year is just December 2022 it's 20 percent of revenue line item 1 which in this hypothetical
example is this dude here which is the goggles 20 percent of that amount.
Is that all right let's go back here we're now done with revenue completely.
OK.
And then we have to discuss the costs of revenue.
Now if you double click on any cell you can see what the math or logic is.
So this year total revenue is just that revenue line item one plus this revenue line item I'll get there
in a second I'm trying to scroll line item 2 down there.
That's all it is.
So I've got to have line as most you might have one and if you have one and not to then you can completely
ignore the second line item here by clicking that to hide it.
If you want but I don't include it so I'm going to unhide it now as well.
OK good.
All right.
Great.
We're now done with revenue and what I'll do is actually in the next lecture I'll talk about the cost
of revenue meaning how much it costs us to Bill one hour of our time meaning how much are you going
to pay your employees or how much it costs to make one of these products that we're selling for 9 bucks.
OK so and this will feed into our margin structure which I'll explain from scratch starting in the next
lecture.
Thanks.