This question here it's just informational.
It's optional as you can see it basically says.
Have you thought about attending local free meetup events in your country.
This is a great way to network in your industry to understand more about your customers.
Maybe your competition and business partners so if you were to go here to meet up dotcom this works
for every country in every industry and every city on the planet.
This is awesome.
So you just do a search here of what your industry is and you can attend meet ups.
This course is not going to be tech focused only but here's a number of tech little meetings you can
go to locally here in the Bay Area.
OK moving on let's go back here.
OK.
Here you write down what your company's mission statement is.
For example I wrote down Google's mission statement which is to organize the world's information and
make it universally accessible and useful.
If you want what you can do is just make this the exact same thing of what you wrote above here in step
one point three which is your little 15 word tagline or you can you know write something a little bit
more elaborate if you want completely your call.
As always you can see the example of what I wrote for that section in that question here so I wrote
here to make all visual media content ever created powered by shark virtual reality and it make virtual
reality universally accessible cap.
All right.
Next up I want you to list and this will really help you a lot to later on in the business plan a way
to write down what's your number one strength compared to the competition then your number two strength.
And number three.
OK and so here I wrote we are the lowest cost producer that's my number one strength.
Number two I wrote we own a patent it quickly renders all movies and video game content into 3D.
And then here I wrote that we have an exclusive contract all pretend of course with Marvel Studios to
render all Marvel Studios movies into 3D using our patented virtual reality software so just write down
whatever your three strengths are there and I made those required and then here these are optional if
you have four or five strings to one list.
Then I want you to also list your three biggest weaknesses because I'm going to challenge you in a nice
swift chorusing and challenge us to really think about weaknesses of our company and address them and
so here are three weaknesses that I wrote down Caye weakness one weakness to weakness three.
Number one I don't have a large cash balance.
Then below it I ask how do I decrease the risk with number one.
Okay.
And I wrote here to raise capital by creating an incredible business plan.
My second weakness is I don't have any presence overseas.
How do I address this week.
Number two I wrote here by raising capital and using part of the proceeds raised to open an overseas
office.
And lastly for Week Number three how do I address weak December 3 which is I don't have the same experience
as the CEOs do or senior management teams do.
Of my competition and they wrote here we intend to create a fantastic board of advisers which will assuage
any Curran's any concerns of our relative lack of manager experience.
And I'm going to teach you in the management section in a lot of detail how to create a board of advisers
from scratch so you can have amazing people on your board for free which will make your business plan
and your presentation slides.
If you have slides much much better when investors or whoever the reader is of your business plan or
your presentation looks at your materials OK and number four and five I made optional a can this one
here is optional.
Why did you choose to locate your company where it is.
And I wrote down my sample answer there.
And you can see I have a typo here.
Don't worry if your grammar spelling is not is not perfect ok because later on when we go into Microsoft
Word together and we update our template from scratch and this is all going automatically up to the
table formats it's going to love it.
But you're going to see all of your spelling mistakes here automatically underlined and grammatical
errors as well which will be in green.
That sort of thing if you forgot a comma.
More on that later.
OK.
It's this last one here I wrote.
It's optional but I really recommend doing it.
If you're serious about taking this business to the next level and I go here have you set up a one hour
consultation with a tax lawyer where you live.
And you know tax lawyers charge a bunch.
It's a pain in the neck but they can save you a fortune later on if you read your copy of the right
way.
Initially again I'm not a lawyer.
Please seek legal advice.
If you want to do this optional step here.
And if you're in the United States whenever you can go to legalzoom.com and set up a one on one meeting
for for half an hour with any kind of lawyer for 30 minutes.
If it's a business lawyer meeting or $15 for 30 minutes if it's a personal lawyer meeting again just
check it out Legal's dot com if you want and they'll even help you register your patents trademarks
and copyrights overseas using what is called the Madrid protocol which is a little bit off topic but
if you're curious about the Madrid protocol and registering your trademark or copyright or whatever
in different countries it doesn't matter where you're located you can watch this lecture right here
which is just going to if you click on it's going to open up a new YouTube window.
Again it is completely optional.
OK so once you're done with this and I didn't answer all the questions here for you I did just a couple.
And I've only asked it and it's 17 percent but this once you answer all the non optional questions.
OK.
Like like these ones here you'll see that that will that will increase from 17:2 to a higher number
and you can always just override that completely by selecting this option here so I've got 22 percent
done for step 1 and 2 percent the whole course.
But if I click this and make it go from 22 percent to 100 now or 7 percent done the course and the needle
has moved here on the total course progress you can always minimize this as well if you want more space
which I explained here in the get more space in this spreadsheet button here.
It takes a second or two for it to minimize the first time.
And I want to make this universally accessible to everybody regardless of if you're using Windows or
Mac with Excel and based on whatever screen size you have.
And again to get a black back you can click there or you can click here and take you to the home screen
as well.
OK.
But I'll just open this up.
So we're now officially done with step one of the course.
If you have any questions at all please let me know what you can do is you can always scroll over to
the right side and enter in comments.
Takes a little while to enter in comments for for every single question that you've entered.
If you want and then later on you can come back and you can filter based on comments that you've entered.
Again it's completely optional hence the word optional but because it's in white it means you can feel
free pleased to answer those those answers.
OK if you have any questions about this please let me know.
If not I will see you in step 2 where we talk about the cover page.
Thanks.