OK now it's time to do Step 12 we're almost done men were making great progress here.
Ok cool.
So next step what we're going to do is make sure you're here directly on row 5:58.
And if you don't know how to get there or you're somewhere else you can always highlight this.
And then just paste in here it doesn't matter where you are.
So say you're lost anywhere in the spreadsheet.
If you paste this in here it'll automatically take you boom over here.
And I recommend doing that actually no matter what.
Even if you're right here with me I still want you to do that and I'll show you what I want to copy
this.
You'll see why in a second.
Paste it in here.
Enter because it's going to highlight exactly what we're going to pull over and this is a little technical
I don't care.
But there's white cells here on purpose just ignore them just so I could get a nice looking copy and
paste for you.
So make sure before you hit copy.
If you don't see these rows and columns and by the way your numbers will be different.
If you started in year one and you called year one year one or 2000 9000 or whatever your numbers look
different from my cat and your your y axis here will differ from mine to number wise if you have different
numbers in your model so for mine I went up to I think $800000 in revenue and 34000 in revenue in the
fourth year which is 2012.
Your numbers are look for me.
If you can't see any access at all that make sure that all these Step 12 tabs often and make sure to
hit the two or three.
And make sure everything is open up.
But I don't think anyone can have that.
OK.
And I only have five years worth of day I only put five years worth of dummy data in and not the rest.
That's why this appears like that.
So here's where you.
Yeah.
So after you pasted that in there now you get hit copy Control-C or Right-Click.
Copy and paste it here.
If it doesn't look good you can always pay special if you wanted to as well.
So sometimes Microsoft Office works really well allowing you to pay stuff between documents.
If it doesn't then you select Paste Special K so when I use it when I use Windows sometimes and I pay
special it doesn't work.
So now I just paste it as is and it's smart enough to grab the data directly so try pasting special
if it doesn't work then just try pasting as is in case it should work.
OK great so that's done.
Next up we have got this financial ratios and piu we did in the last the last step there so I'm going
to copy this and put it like this.
Copy over here.
The reason they got smaller.
Right.
Paste here just to tell me exactly what to copy and paste in case it's highly good.
This is page 2 right click copy and then get rid of this here and I paste on top.
This just hit paste doesn't seem to work out that well so what I can do in this case is pay special
one to or just drag that down there and it pulls all the data over and it's got those nice blue looking
charts there at Trape specials for fun.
Pases picture doesn't work.
All right.
So when you use it on Windows it works a little bit better.
So in this case just paste it as is.
OK.
I've tried this on Windows as well.
And then you can just kind of drag it down and make a little bit nicer there.
Sometimes you need a lot of manual work as well as kind of back that up.
It's going to have to you have to delete that cellar Pena.
All right.
See I just cut cut this out here.
Cut and I don't think I'll run of the same issues I'm having here.
But if you do then just do what I'm doing here.
Get the axe and you can even make an.
Lips.
That's good.
OK great.
That's done their Feitel ratios.
All right.
And then we're going to do financial ratios too.
You'll notice I highlighted in yellow because another page.
And so what I'm going to do is I can enter financial ratios up to up here it's going to automatically
go down here to page 3.
So watch this just because I want to be consistent with what you copy and paste too.
There you go.
And then we're going to
try to answer.
And then you can just do Control-C or command see if using Mac come over here and you can try to pay
special.
If that doesn't work pasting his image you can always just try pasting itself see if it works.
Looks like in this case doesn't work that that grates me.
We're missing some of the data.
And if that happens too you can even paste or copy and paste one image at a time or one of these at
a time.
He can come here and go copy and you have to select the cells like if you want.
You can even select this entire one here.
And I've tested the heck out of some windows on Mac.
I've been in this for years and I know Excel is kind of finicky.
You can copy them one at a time if you want to.
There you go.
So again you've got the option to pay special or to just paste it directly as is by selecting all that.
If it doesn't work then we'll just do one by one.
OK.
And different versions of Word and Excel opera a little bit differently.
There you go.
Looking good though.
OK great.
Let's move on now we've got the monthly revenue forecast this won't be a little bit easier to paste.
OK.
So run a copy paste it up here and it's just going to take us down there to the fourth page which is
going to take us down there.
But I'll show you how it works here.
You can get.
So it's going to grab all of it now because you see those numbers need to be a bit wider.
We're going to do is this you can highlight all the cells all over growth I should say drag it make
it a bit wider.
And then what will happen is it'll make them a little bit why are the reason I said Don't click as I
don't know if you've put a lot of data below this.
I'm not sure if yes.
And he can paste that in again if you want select a good copy and then back here what we can do is pay
special has a picture great.
So this is just the old one underneath that.
There you go.
Looks like you didn't work for these.
So make a little bit wider.
Excel is finicky.
All right.
And if you just copy and paste it as is.
So it's already in my clipboard.
See what happens.
No way man.
No way.
So what we do is we'll make these up a bit wider here.
Go to the edge here.
Great.
And then I will select it again if I want to I can just go here get that field
copy Gary the old one paste special as a picture.
There you go it works great looks good.
And if you can't read that what you can do is you can even flip it over like this if you want it to.
It's fine for me I can see that fine I think.
And if you can't what you can do is just reformat this and even throw it in the appendix completely
or call or you can just copy certain cells if you want your call it is readable.
It's fine.
Uncap great that is that one.
And here's the next page.
So let me just scroll down here and if you don't see a line around the bottom you can always click it.
OK so makes you click the image first.
Watch what's going to happen up here.
He go up here to a picture format.
And then what you can do is you can put a nice black border around it's all make it black and then you
can select just thin weight if you want to make it look a little nicer.
Let's go to.
And you can even if you wanted to get all on our t c on me you can go here you can go shadow and throw
that in and if that looks nice and if you do that just be consistent with all of.
So obviously you've got the shadows there story for you it looks kind of nice.
Michael.
All right great.
Excellent.
See how we're doing
great.
All right let's see what's next.
All right well then here quarterly
which is here.
So when I entered here it's automatically highlight the quarterly numbers right there.
See and it should be fine when it comes to the width to the cells because we already widened it.
And this pulls everything or you've done already.
So here it's going to say quarterly for year 1 to year 3.
My first year 7:18 in this hypothetical example and my third year was there.
Okay.
And you're going to see here that I've got both revenue lines here.
So I own a copy and then let me just get rid of these because that's dummy data or replacing dummy data
with media.
And I paste it as a picture is one worked out a lot better.
Yeah it's fine.
And if you can't read that if you want you can turn that sideways and formatted differently till you're
caught.
And you can even narrow this if you wanted to.
I'll show you like this.
It's going to look messy for a second.
Copy it's.
And then you can paste it instead that way.
Let's show you.
Pay special as a picture bit easier to read.
And if you only have one revenue line item I have to you can get rid of that as well.
And you know if you only have one red line I'm I don't recommend including this just include the whole
income statement and you can do it if you want.
Whatever.
Or you can do is just kind of you can hide.
You can only copy certain cells right.
So if you want to just do revenue and you only one line and I'm not like me right to go here and you
can copy.
So then what you can do is you can paste it like this.
Pay special needs anything we just it pay special as a picture and then get rid of that.
And I will just be one revenue line item.
Not really that helpful.
But anyway to each their own.
And by the same token up here if you only have one revenue line item you might want to get rid of maintenance
down here.
That's a second revenue line item.
So what you can do is instead of copying this whole table you can just copy everything above that so
it'll look like this copy and then you're going to pay special and it won't show the bottom part.
So let's go up here and let's say that we want to just have one revenue line and pay special paste as
a picture.
OK.
And then you'll see there's no maintenance there right.
We got rid of it.
And if you don't have units then you can even try to make this course work for everybody.
So you don't have units.
It's just this.
Then you can just do this if you wanted to and just copy just the revenue here if you want to include
this at all or just even go right to here.
OK.
You don't have to though.
I don't know how much value this is going to have that one line item but it's always good to provide
a little bit more detail for your reader of the business plan the less you're called.
OK.
Next up we have got the next page.
Scroll down here.
All right.
We're done with that.
And you can delete the How to hear delete the how to OK.
I want to be fair to everybody taking this course and show you how to turn it sideways.
All how did this guy.
So this is a little bit advanced if you want to skip what I'm about to show you by going to landscape
mode from portrait to landscape than you can get to this part here in the lecture.
But I assure you.
How did this go.
So what's going to happen is you're going to insert a different section because you can insert a page
break or section Rick and I don't want the whole document to be in landscape mode only a couple of pages.
So what I can do.
Kill Let's go up here.
OK.
So what we'll do is just for the next couple of pages will have a different section.
So I'll go here and I'm going to go insert.
You can't do it.
Here you go.
Insert can break and then you to go to section break on the next page or right there will say next page.
Next Page new section.
Because they're OK.
This is a new section.
And then with this new section here it's going to look really different.
It starts at page 1.
We wanted to continue the page numbers in the previous section.
So what you can do is you can tell it to continue from the previous section which is Page 30 so you
want to appear as Page 31.
And so what you can do is you can go here.
Here page number and you format that page number and you say hey man start at 31 or continue from previous
section which will go to 31 directly.
So we got all right.
Now we're in.
This is complicated.
So.
So you can skip this if you want to but I've spent years trying to figure this out.
So Section 1 was last section and we're now on Section 2 and Section 2 is just going to be landscape.
So let me bring back that stuff.
OK we're still in section 2.
Okay good.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to change the layout of section to OK time to go orientation.
I would make this landscape see just Section 2 because the different section completely.
This is Section 1 This is Section 2.
OK.
It's in landscape mode now.
And so I'm going to bring all that stuff over here.
Monthly revenue forecast Okay I turn up before members I can turn back ok we get dragged here and make
it bigger.
And if we want to be consistent just for fun I like to make these things look good.
You can go shadow as well and like that that's fine.
OK good.
How we look at OK.
Good.
That's a section a section break if I turn that off.
You can't see that anymore.
Pain in the gut.
All right.
And I get changed the next section too you'll see.
So going to stick with us for a while.
Looking good.
I want this to apply there the shadow so let's go paint brush that boy there.
Paint brush here.
Good.
All right.
Next slide.
Where are we at now.
Annual revenue forecast.
Let me get rid of this.
I'll get rid of the sample and I'm going to copy this here.
Final BP.
So you know we're good copy and then I'm going to pay this on top.
Here we go.
Pay special as a picture can.
And then we want to look the same.
We're going to go here and paint brushes again to get that bad ass shadow to show up here.
And you can even make these more narrow if you go back here and so he can just kind of select here and
make that little bit less narrow if you want.
Whatever it's up to you.
OK.
Looking good looking good.
And again if you don't have maintenance you can just highlight what you want to copy over and see just
kind of highlight the first couple rows or whatever.
All right so we're done.
What does next page next.
We have got the monthly operating expense forecasts.
And I'm going to copy this immediately.
This first cut this go back here paste.
Will select it there oh we've got to arrange this a little bit bigger ginks I mean it more narrow a
second ago OK that's good.
And if you don't have these items down here that's OK.
You can actually hide these if you want.
So you can right click and go hide it's fine and you can unhide them later if you want as well.
So it's going to take a second and pull up a couple rows there just hiding is not the leading.
There you got and then what you're going to do is you're going to select this stuff and copy it over
right here and then paste special has a picture.
Good and when I go up here and use the same paint brush stuff get great not just for year one if you're
year one is 7:19 will show up at 19 there.
And this is just as monthly operating expense that means SGA and R&amp;D and then depreciation as well.
And I can hit control-C Now just let it unhide that.
Okay.
And that's optional obviously.
And so the next one we're going to do is just go back here.
While it's thinking next page we have got the annual operating expense forecast back up pulled down
there so let me delete this and that's fine.
But yes we have annual song at least this guy here.
Cut this way.
We have all these fields of Pequod excels unthinking Paiste.
And here is annual K and again you can get rid of the stuff if you want but let me just pretend that
you had all of these then.
So I'm not going to hide them so I can select this again.
And if you only want a certain number of years you can go up to that year whatever totally up to you.
Copy paste special picture.
OK great.
I noticed the footer up there I'll change out in a second if you cut that picture format I can paint
brushes again or select here again a shadow like that.
Good.
And sometimes it actually makes it go to the next patient to do that.
So here's how to make this a little bit smaller and they'll pull it up on the previous page with it
right.
OK.
Now so inside the margin if you want to change this footer here make it a little bit wider.
Just make sure to go to a shape format OK.
And I'm going to make this easier for you.
Don't click up or down take forever.
Just use this here 9.
That's good enough.
The can go right to nine and then just get on there and you'll see as we scroll up it looks great.
Let's go to the previous s.c are still there.
Good.
We're doing well.
OK good.
And we can turn that off if we want.
Looking good.
Look at that formatting.
Man that's dope.
OK good.
Good.
All right.
And again if you don't have these here you already know how to hide those.
I showed you that.
And you can zoom out a bit too if you want.
You definitely have better eyesight than I do.
OK.
So zoom out.
And we're going to go get the quarterly and come say I'm glad I made this water now in landscape mode
is going to go up better.
OK so let's get rid of this and I'm gonna cut this thing and show you some really cool things I can
get.
So I cut that we go back here and we paste it and you'll find where it is.
Now watch this.
I'm going to zoom way out and zoom out to 10 percent or 25 percent.
Watch what happens when you zoom out.
This is really cool.
This will help you understand all the fields as well.
You see how the fields are here automatically.
Isn't that neat.
Ignore it over there those replace all me.
But you see all the other fields.
So here's all 13 pages case where we're working our way through case so it's awesome.
I love that.
OK.
So that was page one that was page two page three page four page five page six seven eight nine eight
page now and you could see all the fields here.
That's the income statement forecast on a quarterly basis that's on an annual basis.
So I get to stay out this Farje for minutes for fun.
See if this works.
I signed copy and then here I'm going to pay special pases picture and we'll see how it works.
Good.
Every single thing was shown here and you can even make this a bit wire if you want to.
I think it's fine because it traps the margin.
Can we get to go back up here and paint brush this or we can just format individually like paint brush.
It's fun.