Now we look at income or losses from operations and I'll just double click this thing I show you what's
inside.
So our income from operations is revenue that C-8 minus what is c. 45 will go down here.
The cost of goods sold.
See it's red minus see 74.
Whoops the total for
this one here tonight.
It's right there don't I saw might but minus three or three way down there.
I gave you tons of lines if you wanted to for S-G and a lot of other buckets there for you.
You can leave a lot of them blank if you want but I could for you as well.
OK.
So we got three or three Yeah right there.
Again I don't know why it's not color but it's right there and then minus.
One more thing which I think is going to be depreciation see depreciation.
OK.
So we got revenue minus all of our expenses and now we have right here hit escape just to get to there.
Right there you have got our total income or loss of operations so if it's a loss it's negative.
And notice that these are not white.
You cannot click and these cells are not blue either.
So let's take a.
We've entered a lot of data.
Now what I want to do is I want a close look on an annual basis just look at the future.
OK good so you can see here.
Let's just look at income OK.
We're looking at how much money we're making before taxes.
And we're not going pay tax if we're not making money.
So we lose two hundred twenty four thousand dollars this year we lose 100 25000 a year for that.
And then look at this.
We're going to break even in 2020 so for our milestones if you wanted to and this is all completely
optional but for the milestones you can talk about when your milestones being when you break even.
So in this hypothetical example it's 2020 and if you red flagged the milestone to come back to it for
the break even you can go and flag that and just enter and text them.
We will break even by 2020.
We anticipate breaking until spring and then here 2021.
Look at this.
There's leverage in the model.
That's a beautiful thing.
Look at me.
OK.
Now we're only percent of revenue.
And so this here is going to calculate our income from operations to as a percent of revenue.
So we looked at percent of revenue.
What we were doing the same thing here with income from operations operating income margin so negative
91 percent because this year is a bigger number way bigger number than our revenue.
And then this year it gets better.
And now it's positive.
Our operating profit margins are now 15 percent that divided by revenue is 15 percent.
DoubleClick and it says that yeah that's that line their current income or lost the by the by revenue.
And I put a dollar sign there to lock in the eighth row which is rampant and I could have also tagged
it and called it something else.
OK.
Yeah I didn't tag this.
Oh I actually got the financials and put total income or all losses from operations so you can always
come back to here by clicking here dropdown.
I know the drill.
OK.
And now we've got some really healthy profit margins here so a lot of software companies get the profit
margins usually maximum 50 percent or so.
The good ones are around 30 percent.
If it's a services company usually 20 percent or 15 percent if you're Accenture because you don't make
as much money by billing people by the hour.
But you make a lot more money by selling software because you kind of sell it online and you have to
have manufacturing capabilities etc..
Just as an example.
All right.
So this is the annual numbers.
And then if we scroll over here over here there you go you can see the spark lines here.
OK.
So here's our our annual income loss that's a loss loss loss or slightly positive here and then really
really positive.
And our operating margins just that the rate of change is there as well.
Okay great.
And if we open up all of these we can actually see it on a monthly basis.
I'm not going to come back to that.
Okay.
So moving on down we've got something called Ebbitt which is accounting for earnings before I tricked
dumb accounting.
Just kidding sorry that humor earnings before interest taxes depreciation and amortization.
And let me explain what that means.
You have these non-cash expenses like depreciation.
It's not fair to always account for it.
It's an accounting thing because you get tax breaks so the reason you account for depreciation is it
lowers how much money you have to pay in taxes because it's an expense that's a good thing.
However when you're thinking about how much extra cash is going to go in your pockets before I said
if you wash the first lecture in the section I said that the the the income statement is a lie.
And it doesn't really tell you the truth what real kashering says and that's why with Cashell say buy
through this in here would be helpful for you.
And people refer to these as margins.
So if you take earnings before interest tax depreciation and amortization to out of those markets.
And so all I did here is you can take out depreciation.
So let me open this up so I can explain how this works in more detail so let's look at it for one year
here.
Can't let the screen refresh control left Carol I love using the up and down arrow buttons left to right
is better than using a mouse when you're modeling.
All right so even if I don't click and you show you what it means and looks like I've got a written
English up here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm taking our income or loss we calculate before the.
And we're going to add back depreciation because depreciation is a non cash expense.
And so that is going to be higher than what our income is from operations or loss of operations.
So here we have it's seventeen thousand seven hundred which is higher than this.
It's about a thousand bucks better.
And so you'll notice that that is the reason we look at it that also which is earnings for interest
taxes depreciation amortization is so it more closely resembles what our tax or what our what our cash
amount is and what we do is in different countries there's different tax laws different interest laws
different depreciation laws so we're going to compare two companies from different countries with different
tax laws.
It makes sense to compare them on that basis.
That's one of the reasons you look at it as well.
OK so we're now done with it.
OK we'll wrap up the income statement input's discussion here and after this part we're going to move
down on the same spreadsheet to talk about balance sheet and you'll see that the cash flow statements
automatically created for you.
You have to enter anything because if I give you an income statement about sheet cash flows created
for you the statement entirely It's amazing but the balance we've got to do a couple thing but before
we go they're going to finish off the income statement here.
So now we've got what are called below the line items it's just nerd talk for items that usually don't
repeat that often because so if you have other places you're making money from make interest in the
bank IList here or if you're have other miscellaneous negative payments you haven't accounted for above
in expenses you'd make it negative which would be in brackets here.
So I'm going to skip that.
And then if you entered and you can look at this parklands of course and remember to keep all these
things open after you're done with this so that they all the charts can and can update automatically
and the data can be pulled in.
Okay.
So now we've got total income or loss.
If it's in brackets we've got a loss here.
All everything before taxes.
Okay.
And we're not going to pay taxes because of course we're not making money.
And so what happens is in a lot of countries you got to talk to your account and a lot of regions within
countries you get these awesome tax breaks.
And what this means is you calculate how much tax you would have paid that year anyway.
And it goes into a bucket and that bucket is called an O L which stands for net operating loss.
And you can carry forward those operating loss amounts.
So for example I keep a generic let's say here that normally you pay 50 percent tax and this is just
for an example that's obviously high but that would be about let's just call it at nine thousand something
so $9000 tax cap that you'd pay that if that was a positive number.
So we get $9000 and we put it in a bucket.
And when we had to pay our first nine thousand dollars in tax we don't because we have a $9000 credit.
And then when there's nothing left in that bucket then we start paying taxes.
So that's how you calculate it anyway a little bit outside the scope of this course.
But you can do it that way.
And so there's no taxes.
And then once you do break even your bucket is filled up or it's completely empty then you'd pay taxes.
And depending on what country you're in and your tax rate you'd enter it here.
And so every country is different.
Every region is different.
Some places 30 percent some it's 40.
I know some places like riced invest investments in software companies only in Internet years ago and
I remember when I invested in Checkpoint S.H. KP which which I think is in Israel in Tel Aviv you had
this tax break.
There was only 12 percent tax versus every other software company it looked like S&amp;P in Germany or Oracle
in California my troughing in Redmond Washington et cetera.
They had you know much higher over over 30 percent.
And Germany was a little bit tougher for me because I had to account for FX swings foreign exchange.
OK so now net income is calculated for us.
And at the bottom here I've got net income as a percent of total revenue.
That's important.
That's net income margins.
And you can see they're negative they're just terrible.
And then they get really really good soon negative negative Oh hello 2020 we're 15 percent now 49 percent
50 percent which is unheard of high.
It's amazing.
It's great that we have a great company right.
So anyway all that stuff is created for us.
And so we're now done with the income statement and I can I'll show you what the real formal income
statement looks here and then I'll show you really quickly and then we'll go in the balance sheet.
The next lecture.
So everything is pulled in here for you remember.
And these are not blue fonts with a white background so you can't type in looks.
It's actually gray but they're not blue.
And every time you got something green means it was pulled from another sheet.
This is not green because it's just to some of these I mean it's here but everything is pulled forward
automatically.
And so if we scroll down we could see everything is just pulled forward as GNAS.
There are inti a separate line.
I mean we did and this is on a quarterly basis.
Right.
So we did $3000 per month Bresciano our for R&amp;D.
And so that's there and you can look at the spark lines here.
It's just easier because you're looking at fewer buckets here and there's higher depreciation as well
which which we covered for that was a thousand bucks per month.
So $3000 per quarter okay.
And then you see everything as a percent of revenue.
Got it.
And you'll see that it is higher meaning less bad than income from operations because even that is just
adding back depreciation because depreciation is not a tax expense or per capita expense right.
It's back.
So anyway you can double click on things just to learn more about them and then you can just make this
little bit wider.
You can actually see the text below but this just feeds from the previous the screen wins from that
from the previous.
So we didn't do taxes as well.
So you can just open those up if you can learn more about it.
Malls can be a little bit different but I think I understand how it all works.
Then you've got your SPARC lines here.
And the reason it looks different is because some of these ones and twos are open and some are not.
OK.
So leave all that open so we are now done with the with the income statement which which is great.
But before we go from us I'm not going to click away because if I do it will go to the very top of it.
So I'm going to go down here and click here and puts her financials and I did that in Kiska last fired
click there right now which I won't take you right to the top.
Right.
So now we are done.
And before we move on and talk about balance sheet items which are below.
And we already know think of saving looks like it's great.
And we were interested in this guy revenue which he built.
What I want to do is you can go here and show you yes revenue.
This just pulls directly from the previous tab as well.
It's revenue that we calculate.
We had the two line items and look at this well I pulled it over KBR goggles.
It's the maintenance.
I pulled that name over here so this is green.
So you cannot change it.
I mean you can but you know me.
So that stuff is all here.
I want to break it out separately just because it's interesting to look at revenue in a nutshell on
itself because revenue is so important Everything is driven off revenue.
Pretty much everything in the financial statement almost everything.
That's why we spent so much time on revenue.
Now I go back home and I'm going to scroll down and I'm going to show you it's it's so big that these
items have been updated every five years.
So you can see I'm going to zoom out a touch your sorry about this.
Your eyes are better than mine I promise you that.
OK.
Revenant.
So here you can mouseover and I should tell you the numbers well it's kind of it's pretty strong.
Awesome.
All right.
So revenue growth is amazing.
And then net income was.
We lost a ton of money and it got less bad than we broke even 2020.
And then there you we made those two years and here we've got the we got some of the formulas here.
So I did not do.
This is the one year two year five years ten years out.
And so I didn't update anything in 10 years but I did hear you.
So here's revenue.
And it just shows you what the numbers are here as well.
We got here it's 2000 2 4 9 1 6.
When I was 6 I was 19 is 4 four go to one.
Great.
And then 2022 is eight 3:09 That's the fifth year I go here 3:9 right there.
And then we got net income here which pulls forward and you always know exactly where from and I'll
go into the final pit slide and a little more detail very soon.
Net income we've got here is negative.
Two hundred and twenty four.
See mouseover then it goes to.
Are you going to show me or not.
Maybe you have to assume and get a little bit pay fine and then 2020 to our net income is 4 8 8 2 0
8.
See on the left there matches which is great and our gross margins for 2008 team.
Gross margin is revenue minus the costs get sold all that divided by revenue.
So in brackets revenue is Costco so close brackets divided by revenue.
Native 1 percent.
We're losing money the first year on stuff we make then we're positive and we're really positive.
And I didn't do data for that 10th year there and there's a couple of other ratios like return on assets
and return on equity which we'll talk about in the balance sheets actually.
Most people don't care about that stuff or look at it closely initially in a business plan because it's
all about revenue growth initially and you know earnings and most companies are not profitable immediately.
So that's it.
We are done with the income statement and in the next lecture I'll continue with the Belge.
Thanks.