Welcome onboard of this course, I am really happy to see that you join this course. Mongodb
is an exciting technology, an exciting database solution and even more than just a database solution
as you will learn throughout this course and you can use it in basically any project you're building.
If that's a website, a mobile app, a desktop app or if you're working as a data scientist, you're probably
working with some kind of data,
you need to store data,
you need to fetch data and you need to do all of that fast and efficiently without worrying too much
about database configuration, setup and data structures and mongodb is an awesome solution for
that.
In this course, I'll thoroughly walk you through mongodb and teach you everything you as a developer need
to know.
I'll teach you how to use mongodb, how to structure your data there, how you can depict relations
in a
mongodb world, how you can do configurations on your database and most importantly, how you can perform
efficient and powerful crud operations with mongodb in a broad variety of ways.
This is a very comprehensive course on mongodb and I'm super excited to dive into it with you.
Now who am I?
My name is Maximillian Schwarzmuller,
I'm a freelance web developer and 5 star rated instructor here on Udemy.
I got a lot of courses and I got courses as well as free YouTube videos on my channel, Academind
where I do already use mongodb
but the complete course on it was missing and since it's such an awesome technology and such an awesome
database, it was about time to dive into it so that you can become a true mongodb master.
Now this is a hands-on approach course, that means there will be slides, there will be theory because
you always need that but most importantly, there will be a lot of working with mongodb
or I work with mongodb and you can work with mongodb whilst following along in the videos.
So that should be a lot of fun,
now let's dive into the course and let's start with the most important question,
what is mongodb?