Now that you learned a lot about general queries and how to store data and how to retrieve data, it's
time to also learn how to retrieve data efficiently.
Now we'll have a look at indexes in this module and indexes are a feature that can drastically speed
up your queries, though if used incorrectly,
they can also slow down some of your operations.
Now we'll take a look at all of that and the different kinds of queries in this module,
I just want to highlight that in general, you as a developer will most likely not create that many
indexes but if you're working as a single person on a web project for example and therefore are the
single person using some mongodb solution,
you still will need to know how to create indexes and even if you never create them, it's still worth
understanding how indexes and queries work together.
In this module, we'll have a look at what exactly an index is and how it can help us,
we'll then have a look at the different types of indexes mongodb supports and we'll have a look
at how you use indexes and how you can optimize your queries for indexes or the other way around, how you
can optimize your indexes to support your queries.
So with that, let's dive in and let's learn how indexes can help us.