Thus far we already worked a bit with our data in mongodb and we always work with it from inside the
shell, that is also where we will stay in this course since you're a developer and you'll write code
and we do write code in the shell.
But from time to time, you might want to peek into your database in a graphical user interface and mongodb
compass is such a graphical user interface which you can use. In this module,
I'll show you how to use mongodb compass, how to use it to insert data, to update and delete data
and of course how to view it and get a feeling for your data.
Of course you can not just use the insert new data,
you could also open a database server where you have a couple of databases with data in there already,
that would work too.
So let's dive into mongodb
compass then.