In the last module we had a detailed look at how you can get data into the database.
Now often, that is only useful if you have the means to get data out of the database
and that is exactly what this module is about,
it's about reading data that is in your database.
Now we already used find quite a bit in this module but find as we used it always gave us back all the
data essentially. You can of course filter for specific documents, you're not limited to getting all the
data all the time and you can also transform the documents you get back to some extent.
Additionally, we'll talk about that cursor thing again which I touched on earlier in this course, so in
detail we'll have a look at methods, filters and operators, what all of that is and how it works together.
We'll then have a look at query selectors,
so findOne and find and how we work with filters there and add projection operators which will help us
with well transforming the data we get back
you could say. This is in a nutshell what we'll do in this module and for this module, we'll use the
dataset or at least we'll start with the dataset we imported at the end of last module,
so make sure you watch that video to see how that dataset, the movies dataset there
got into the database, we used mongo import for that and we did it at the end of the insert module.
If you know how to use mongo import, you'll find that dataset attached to this video again,
you don't need to re-import if you already did it in the last module but if you skipped that module
but you know how to import data, the dataset is attached.
So with that let's dive into reading data.