When building applications with mongodb, you will most likely also work with some numbers.
Maybe you're building an online shop where you store products, that obviously will have prices and where
you store orders which wIll have order volume or prices or whether you're building a database for
scientific data with which you or other people might run scientific calculations.
Numbers are everywhere
and of course you can store the numbers in mongodb too and so far throughout this course, we heavily worked with
numbers already.
Now actually, working with numbers can be more complex than you might think or there is more to it than
you might think
and therefore in this module, we'll dive into the different number types mongodb supports, how they differ
and when you might use which.