Now that we have mongodb solution up and running in the web with replica sets, we can dive into a certain
topic that was added with mongodb 4.0, transactions. And you need a replica set an environment
for transactions to work
and therefore I couldn't show this earlier in the course but now with the mongodb Atlas deployment
up and running,
you can dive into transactions. Now important, for this module
you need mongodb 4.0
and currently if you deploy mongodb Atlas and you are in the free tier, you can only use 3.6 there.
So if you use that free tier, chances are high you are doing that,
you don't need to upgrade,
you can just follow along with the videos and then try this out on your own once you eventually make
the step into building a real app and you therefore are willing to pay something for that
or until the free tier also supports 4.0
of course.
So in this module, we'll dive into transactions and that of course poses one important question,
what are transactions and then how will we use them? Both will be covered here.