You learned a lot about mongodb and how to use it as a developer.
Now it's time to talk a bit about the things that are not directly your job as a developer but still important
for you to understand and especially important to you if you're working alone on a project. You need
to understand what impacts performance of your mongodb server or your mongodb solution, how
you can improve the fault tolerance of it and how you can deploy your local mongodb database and
server which we used thus far in this course into the web,
so on a cloud machine or on a server in the web and not on your localhost of course because your web
application, your mobile application or whatever you're building will most likely also run well on some
server or on some smart device, whatever it is and will communicate to your server in the web and not
to your local machine you are developing on.
So what's inside this module?
We'll have a look at some factors that influence performance,
some important factors and how you can control them or what you have to know about them. We'll have a
look at a special kind of collection, capped collections that can be helpful in certain situations and
that you should at least be aware of.
We'll then have a look at replica sets and I will explain what this is and we'll have a look at sharding,
I'll also explain what is this, these two things will be related to both performance and fault tolerance
.
And last but not least, I will talk about what it takes to deploy a local mongodb database and server
into the web and which solutions I would recommend there to get your mongodb solution up and
running in the web.
So with that, let dive in.