Now one additional resource I want to draw your attention to which you also find a link to in the last
lecture of this module is this article in the official mongodb documentation.
It talks about how to model monetary data and that is essentially about the things we talked about in
this module,
so how you can get that precision you need and so on.
There you also find an alternative approach to using that decimal 128 bit value we used in the last
lectures and that is using a scale factor which is not the recommended method anymore,
that is why I showed using the decimal type because that is preferable now
but the scale factor method is essentially a way of using or working with numbers by multiplying them
with the precision you need,
so if you need for example here in this example, a tenth of a cent of precision, you could multiply your
price value with 1000 to get that precision,
so you essentially only work with integers there and never with floating point numbers
and that is an alternative to the 128 decimal, though
just to highlight this again, using the decimal is preferrable now but you can of course go for this approach
too if you want to.
So checking out this article is also worth your time
if you're working with monetary data, you'll find a bit more information there.
But I hope that with this module, it became clearer why we have these different number types, what you
use them for, what their limitations and advantages are
and therefore what you could choose in your next application you build.