So that's it
for this module. You learned about performance and fault tolerance. For performance,
there's one thing you could consider and that are capped collections for cases where you automatically
want to clear old data or you're fine with old data being cleared,
so for example for a short term caching mechanism. Performance in general is all about having efficient
queries and operations, fitting data formats and of course, a best practice mongodb server configuration.
You should be aware of replica sets now, which is basically a mechanism or a feature of mongodb
that provides fault tolerance with automatic recovery
with the election of a new primary node and improved read performance as well.
You also have sharding at your disposal which is a way of scaling your mongodb server horizontally,
so across multiple servers instead of running everything on just one machine.
Now at some point, you want to get your mongodb server from localhost up into the web or onto a
real server
and that is called deployment.
Now deployment is a complex matter since it involves many tasks,
some of them like setting up the machine and securing the network,
some of them are not even directly related to mongodb.
Therefore unless you are an experienced admin or you got one, you work in a corporation, you should consider
a managed solution like mongodb Atlas.
Atlas is a managed service where you can configure a mongodb environment and you pay on by usage
or on a per usage basis,
you can always shut it down,
you can always reconfigure, you can upgrade, downgrade
so you got all that available. You've got a best practice mongodb server running in the cloud and especially
when you're working on a project on your own,
you should definitely consider that as a solution to deploying everything on your own which
well as I said, is a very complex task.