Now that we have data stored in a new collection, let's use that new collection and let's create an index,
a geo index in there so that we can actually use the geonear stage which also exists in the aggregation
framework. For this I'll create an index on the location field with db transformed persons create index
as we did it in the geospatial module,
this is the field name and we want to have a 2D sphere index on that.
So now with that index created, we can use transform persons for geolocation queries and also for the
geolocation or the geospatial aggregation pipeline step. I'll run the pipeline I'll build now against
transformed persons
and I want to use a special stage which is built for working with geo data,
the $geoNear stage. Now geoNear takes a bunch of input to configure it.
First of all we need to define the point where we are for which we want to find close points because geoNear
allows us to simply find elements in our collection, documents in our collection which are close to our
current position,
that is what geoNear does.
Now for this, I need to pick a location and I will take the coordinates I have here to guarantee that
I am at least close to at least one document in my collection,
near is not just a pair of coordinates though,
it's a geo json object,
so we have to define a point and then the coordinates and these are now two coordinates, longitude
and latitude and I will slightly modify that so that I dont have exactly the same location,
so now we have that near parameter filled out.
Next we can define a max distance in meters,
let's say we want to have like ten thousand meters, so 10 kilometers,
you can also limit the amount of results you want to retrieve and you can do this in this step instead
of with a limit stage to do this more efficiently and just request this amount of documents instead
of getting all and then limiting it in a new pipeline stage after you already fetched all,
so let's say we want to limit it to 10 and we could also add a query here where we filter for other things.
Now this is available because geoNear has to be the first element in a pipeline, if you want to use
geoNear,
it has to be the first element in the pipeline because it needs to use that index and the first pipeline
element is the only element with direct access to the collection, other pipeline stages
just get the output of the previous pipeline stage,
this is the only element with direct access to the collection.
So therefore if you have any other filters which you want to run directly on the collection, you can add it
here and mongodb will
well basically execute a very efficient query against the collection and not force you to then use a
match stage as a next step which well might mean that you have to fetch all data in order to be able
to match in the next step.
So here we could look for persons who are male for example or female to mix it up.
Now with that, there is one more field we have to specify and that is the distance field, whoops distance field
because geoNear will actually also give us back the distance that is calculated between our point and the document
it found and we can tell mongodb in which new field it should store that and I'll just name it distance,
this name is up to you.
Now let's give it a try,
pretty agregate should be in the right positions and I find no results which is of course my fault because
if I have a look into transformed persons, we see there is no gender in there.
Yeah,
so let's fix this and let's maybe look for a different query,
let's look for age greater than 30.
Ok
so let's try this again with the new query,
then I get no results,
well maybe the distance is the problem,
let's improve that
and let's go from 10 kilometers to a thousand kilometers, so one million meters and now this looks better,
now I have some results. And there, you can also see this new distance field was added to the output,
this is the distance of this person to me,
so you see 10 kilometers was a bit too optimistic,
they're all like six hundred kilometers away from me
and this is how you can use geoNear as a pipeline stage.
One of the most important things to remember here is that it has to be the first stage, thereafter you
can of course add all the other stages in the way I described it in the rest of this module.