Now speaking of operators in the last lecture, we got a couple of different operators we can differentiate.
We got query and projection operators, query selectors, basically the different operators like
$gt which you saw in the last lecture which allow us to narrow down the set of documents we retrieve
and projection operators that allow us to transform or kind of change the data we get back to some extent,
these are read related operators.
Now we'll also learn about update related operators later, where we can also basically update fields and
arrays and there are different techniques for operating these things,
so normal fields or arrays in a document, we'll learn about this in the update module of course
and we also got query modifiers.
Now this allows us to change the query behavior
and this is deprecated now,
so this will not be covered anymore because what you could do with these can now be done with the normal
operators basically.
We also can do some aggregation which is also reading data from the database but allows you to do more
complex transforms
basically. This is a very interesting concept where you basically set up a pipeline of stages to funnel
your data through and you got a bunch of operators that allow you to shape the data you get back
to the form you needed in your app
and therefore we got a whole module for this where this will be covered,
the aggregation module.
So in this module, we'll focus on the read operators, in the update module,
we'll have a look at the update operators. Now for inserts and deletes,
there are no operators, for deletes
there are but these will be the same as the read operators because there you just need to find data
you want to delete
and that works in the same way you find data to output but for updating, we got some separate operators
and they will be covered in the update module.
Now how do operators impact our data? That depends on the type, if we get a query operator like we'll
use in this module, we can use it to locate data,
it does not change our data and an example would be
$eq for equal or $gt which you saw before. Projection operators which we'll also see in this module
allow you to modify the data presentation,
so the data you get back, this will also not change the data in the database though, only change the look
of it which you get. Here, dollar sign is an example,
this will become clearer once we use projection operators,
so in the end we just got some tools to control the look of the data we get back.
Update operators which we'll cover in the update module allow you to modify and add additional data and
this therefore does of course change the data. Inc,
$inc
is an example which will increment a field by one or any amount you specify
and this is also something we'll also see in the update module of course.