Now before we actually run any commands, you might be wondering why I'm using the shell because when
you're building a real application where you use mongodb, you will of course not use the shell for that,
you will use one of the mongodb drivers depending on the programming language you're using.
And on the official docs, a link to this page can be found in the last lecture of this module by the
way,
you find an extensive list of all the drivers mongodb offers
and as you can see, there are drivers for C++, C# Java,
NodeJS, PHP, Python,
so all the important server side or desktop side programming languages.
Now depending on what you're building for, you would of course choose your driver here,
follow the installation docs and then embed it into your application code
but in this course, as mentioned in the first module already, we of course want to show you an approach
that works for every language and therefore we'll use the shell here.
The shell allows us to write queries which are very similar to the queries in the different drivers,
the shell is actually based on Javascript
so it's extremely similar to Nodejs
but if you check out the docs for the other drivers or even batter, in the official docs here,
if you go to getting started and you find a link to this in the last lecture too,
you can also see that there, you find a document about the crud operations and
you don't need to worry too much about that right now,
we'll learn all about these operations in this module.
But if you check out any article there, you can actually switch between the different languages and the
interesting thing is the default always is the shell, these are the commands we'll write
but if you then switch to Python for example, you see this is pretty similar.
We had insertOne in the shell written like this,
now in python it follows the python naming standards but it's still insertOne and it's configured and used
in the same way
and this is true for all the programming languages.
It of course uses the syntax of that language and the best practices you should use for writing code
in that language
but the way you use it, the way you pass data and then you can configure it always is the same
and this is why we use the shell here.
Now with that out of the way, let's start using that shell which is connected to our local mongo server
and let's finally add some data and learn more about the data types we can use and how we can interact
with data in general.