Well let's run mongod --help
again. We obviously got many many many settings here, the
settings at the bottom for example are related to wired tiger which is our storage engine
and there we can basically use the default settings, you can change some configuration there if you know
what you're doing
but in the scope of this course we'll not dive into configuring our storage engine but simply go with its
default settings.
You also get useful commands like repair which is a great idea to run if you have any issues connecting
and see warnings or errors related to database files being corrupted or anything like that, directory
per db would be a setting you can add to not have a db folder with your collection files stored all
in the root folder
but instead they would be grouped in sub-folders with one sub-folder per database in your database environment
so to say.
So if you have four databases, you would have four sub-folders and every sub-folder would contain its collection
and index files, we'll dive into indexes later in the course by the way. You can also switch the storage
engine,
the default is wired tiger and you should really use that. Theoretically mongodb supports multiple
storage engines
but wired tiger is the default one is a high performant one is a really good storage engine,
so unless you really know what you're doing and you've got a strong reason to change it, you should not
change the storage engine. SSL configuration is something I'll come back to in the security and authentication
module, so we can ignore this for now
The same is the case for sharding and replica sets, I'll touch on these options later in the course
and therefore, we're pretty much done.
One setting is worth talking about though and that's the fork setting or the fork option, what does this
do?