Hi everyone and welcome back in this video we're going to be taking a look at the platform and the neo
cryptocurrency.
Before we get started we can examine a few pieces of interesting information related to Neal.
It was released in 2014 ended up going through a rebranding and a really interesting note is that it's
known as the Chinese theory one benefit of Neo and we're going to get into it later is that it's very
useful for developers because it offers a range of mainstream programming languages to use to develop
with.
So keep that in mind as you move through the documentation.
Very easy to use at least from the development side known as a Chinese 3M release in 2014 and went through
a rebranding but let's jump right into it.
Similar to our other block chain platforms and coin's the base asset of the neo block chain is the neo
Tokie a benefit of Neo is that it supports a range of languages such as JavaScript and C++ by using
a customized version of docker called neo V.M..
And this will come into play a little later.
But imagine for the developers standpoint being able to use specific languages or a range of languages
makes it very efficient very easy to implement and work with.
Also we saw in our introduction that Neal was launched originally in 2014 but as it shares through the
development company one chain and rebranded to Neo in 2017 a few months ago in March one chain.
Remember the one chain is the parent company distributed one ontology token for every five Nio in a
wallet that will be used to vote on things such as system upgrades and government issues on the neo
platform.
Similar to some other coins.
Neo is a nonprofit community based block chain project.
It's open source and get help and the organization aims to help transform the smart economy remember
block chain and crypto are part of the disruptive technologies.
But let's take a look at the documentation and get
and we could see it listed here.
If you want to get more into the technicalities and the information related to it you can scroll through
see the support platforms development information how to contribute.
You can scroll through the repository niños you see open source released under the MIT license.
This is just a great reference if you want to scroll through further.
Remember you can visit it at good hub dot com slash Nio dash project slash new
and with that recurring theme with me you know we have the emphasis of the smart contract one aspect
and benefit is that it pushes the benefits for those looking to work with it.
Developers can easily get started with smart contracts.
Remember earlier we mentioned that it offers a range of programming languages that you are able to develop
with.
This helps because for instance if you're only used to working with one so you're working with Python
you can pick it up you won't have to learn a specific language to work with this.
As a developer and now we arrive at the distribution one of the key aspects of the cryptocurrency a
hundred million Nio were created in Genesis with 50 million Neo sold to early investors and the remaining
50 million locked into a smart contract each year 15 million are unlocked for the development team to
fund long term development goals gas tokens.
The alternative tokin are used to pay for transactions on the network and gas is generated at a rate
of eight gas per block.
Production is reduced by one token for every two million blocks and around the year 2039 gas circulation
will reach a hundred million and production will cease.
Gas can be divided though unlike Neo and also for consensus.
Neo uses the deligated Byzantine fault tolerant consensus and its similar to steller and for some related
information.
This actually just happened very recently on July 4th 2000 18 Nijo entered the era of decentralization.
Keep that in mind for the near future.
And on a side note not to digress too much but a great method of keeping up with how these crypto currencies
how these platforms are doing is always to check their documentation to check their blogs.
Quite a few of them have blogs and put out press releases and just general information quite often.
Because with these Kryptos they're trying to be very transparent with block chain.
It's definitely one of the benefits that we can see is the transparency and with this you can scroll
through and take a look at the blog here.
Again other crypto currencies other platforms have them as well.
Just another great way to keep on top of information whether it's just technical or how the corn is
performing or any recent partnerships with the company.
As we wrap it up here with Neal The organization hopes to revive the connection between digital and
physical assets through a digital identity and its use of smart contracts.
Once the assets have been digitized decentralization and transparency become key and this is really
what E-o names are revived by using its blague train platform
so as an overview NIO is seen as the Chinese theorem has many benefits one of them being the adaptability
and use for developers.
Since you're able to take it on with many languages it's very transparent open sourced designed to build
a scalable network of decentralized applications.
Has the distribution created genesis of 100 million Neo coins and with the recent move into the era
of decentralization.
On July 4th it's going to be interesting to see how this performs and keep in mind pay attention to
see which companies are which backing pick it up over the next year or two along with how the market
performs.
It's always interesting to analyze how the market is performing related to how these companies are being
supported along with who is picking them up as always.
If you have any questions please feel free to share them and enjoy cryptocurrency.