Hello to welcome back so of course I'm blogging.
And today we're going to touch on very briefly decentralized applications or DAPs and that's because
it's an important topic as you will hear about it especially in the time to come.
There will be more DAPs and they will be more becoming more widespread.
It's not something called more complex than a smart country but less I think it's worth mentioning.
So let's have a look there there's where we left off previously we've got our smart contracts that go
to a network like this.
The complexity of this system is growing very fast.
I know let's just make some space here at the bottom.
What is a dad.
Well a dad is this it is an interface for people to connect with as well.
It's not just an interface.
It contains an interface for people to interact with something on the block chain.
So ADAP consists of a front end and a back end which is the smart concept.
So in a way your or think of the smart contract as the API or the application programming interface
for applications to interact with the block chain.
So basically if you like let's say if you wanted if you wanted to if you wanted to create an application
for that would like to if an app on the phone or a or some other app that's like on an iPad or on the
computer that would interact to a server you would need to use API you would need to somehow get into
that server and use the right connectors and things like that to get to that server and get information
that's right.
Good information there.
So you got a smart contract has a way for an application.
So this is an application to interact with the block change put things on the blush and take things
from.
And then there's a front end for people to track.
So that's what decentralized applications are.
They use smart contracts to track with the block chain and they allow users to interact with the application
itself.
And let's have a look an example one of the most famous examples is DMARDs and this space is evolving
so quickly so when you're watching this video stream it might not exist or he or it might be super huge.
But surely there are other examples of decentralized applications which you can find.
But it is kind of like Twitter.
But on block change so you can just like go in here and you will actually see that like this is information
being loaded onto your screen onto all in this case my screen and it's quite slow but I don't think
that's the block chain problem.
It's mostly could be Australian internet problem.
It's not the best here but like this information has just been loaded not from a server but from a block
chain.
So it's kind of like Twitter in a way but it's it's totally decentralized.
It's like all of this all of these all of this data is stored on the block chain.
People are interacting or blocking and this is an application.
This web site then application which allows users to like drag which other butts in the back and all
this is going through a block.
So there we go that steam and check it out.
If you would like to learn more it's a it's a new way of life which disrupts Twitter with blocking.
And on that note Popinjay's Tauriel we could see him better next time.
And so then bludgeons.