Hello welcome back to the course on block chain.
And today we're talking about cryptography.
We're going to understand what role the shutdown or 56 hash algorithm plays in watching.
All right.
So there's our map and we're starting with hash cryptography.
So let's look at a person there is a person could be me or you.
And we have a fingerprint and different people have different fingerprints so if you look at many different
people they're all going to have different fingerprints to us it is there is a possibility that there'll
be somebody with the same fingerprint.
But it is very unlikely the ability of that is about one in 60 million.
So in a way you can say that a fingerprint is an identifier of a person and that's a very powerful concept
which is used by forensics departments in the police where they can identify criminals just by their
fingerprints and take that as evidence to court.
Now what if we could take the same principle and apply it to digital documents.
But if we could come up with a sort of fingerprint that would identify these documents for us and such
a fingerprint exists it's called Shower 256 hash and looks like this.
So the algorithm behind Shutt 256 was developed by the NSA.
And I know what you're going to say.
You've probably heard the NSA in the news in the past couple of years and you might have you know some
you know like a great opinion about them or the opposite you might not like them or it might be indifferent
to them regardless of what is said in the news about the NSA and all those things.
One thing they did do really well is this shot 256 algorithm.
It works well.
It's very secure.
And a lot of places in the World War applications use to store passwords.
Check digital documents too.
And in fact in blotching it is used like one of the core things core principles building blocks of block
chain as we will see further down in this section and the code for the algorithm for Shudra and 56 is
not secret.
It's open completely open.
Anybody can learn it.
Understand how it works out at the end of this tutorial I'll actually recommend a paper which you can
read and understand more about how shutter physics works.
Now this hash is called Chateau-Renaud 56 because Shas stands for secure hash algorithm and 256 is the
number of bits it takes up in memory.
The hash is always 64 characters long and it consists as you can see if not just from digits but actually
from letters as well.
That's because it's a hexadecimal hash it has numbers from 0 to 9 and the letters A B C D E F.
So there's a total of 16 of them there.
So that means each character in the resulting hash takes up four bits because for the power of two 16
and 410 64 is turning 56.
That's how these numbers are all linked up together 64 times 4 which is the size of any size of basically
any one of these is 256.
And the important thing to note here is that this algorithm works not just for word documents or text
documents.
It works for any digital document or any digital just anything digital.
So you could put a video into the algorithm you could put like text you could put an audio you could
put an executable file you could put a whole operating system in there whatever you put in there it
will spit out a fingerprint which is a shot of hash.
So let's have a look and action.
You know it's great to describe these things and talk about them but let's have a look at action see
how it works.
So we set up a tools kit for you.
It's at tools not supersized dot com slash block chain slash hash.
And if you head on over there we just go like this.
You will see that there's a whole toolkit over here set up so you can go to log blotching in distribution
and so on.
And we'll talk about these further down in this course but this is what we're going to look at today.
But before we continue there's a copyright notice.
We just wanted to make sure that this is not our original code this was actually created by someone
else created by Anders in 94.
And so Anders Braun Brown we're Thank you very much Anders for making this available.
You can check it all out here and you can actually edit your own website if you like.
And so here what you can do is you can input some data and you will see that you'll come up with.
So let's go so let's say I'll put in Hello.
This is the walk chain a zed course as you can see this data has this hash.
Right.
And so we're going to explore a couple of things and after that will go back to the presentation and
we'll talk about the characteristics of a hash.
So right now first thing I wanted to show you is that if I remove this now and then put it back it'll
have exactly the same hash.
9 9 9 9 4 4 and then do you want one at the end so let's remove it again and then put it back then and
before DD 1 DD 1.
So it always will and always will reproduce the same hash if you put in the same date.
And that's logical right.
So because like we humans take the same person who check their fingerprints and then you take the same
person checked the finger is going to be the same every time.
Otherwise it wouldn't really make sense you would be able to use it for forensics.
Another thing is that if we change one tiny symbol like we add like a another exclamation mark here
the hash changes completely and entirely.
That's called the avalanche effect.
We'll talk more about it just now.
But the main point here is that when you make a slight change it doesn't change it slightly changes
completely.
You can try like remove the question mark and put a dot completely different hash.
And because you don't put anything here you always get two or three just six.
So for example I've got a boy here have got pasted copy the first chapter of war and peace.
It's like the biggest book in the world and this is the first chapter as you can see and pasted so much
text in here and the hash again is just 256 bits so 64 characters.
So there we go.
That's Shad's out of six in demonstration.
Have a look here if you'd like to play around with it.
We're going to go back to a presentation now.
OK.
So the five requirements for hash algorithms is shot out of which six is not the only one.
There's other algorithms shout 512 Chah 3.
And you could come up with a hashing algorithm.
However there are certain requirements for it to be useful.
Number one is it has to be one way.
So basically what that means is that you cannot go backwards.
You cannot go from the hash to the documents so you cannot restore or reverse engineer the document
based on the hash.
It has to be like a fingerprint like for a human.
If you have the fingerprints you cannot restore what the person looks like.
You cannot understand you know what color eyes they had or anything else about them.
But at the same time you have if you have a person you can always get the fingerprints.
There's only one way.
Number two is it has to be deterministic meaning that if I take the same document exactly the same document
later on and I run the same apply the hash algorithm again I'll get exactly the same result as we saw
with that illustration.
So these two or three fourths of our requirement is it has to be has to have fast computation and we'll
see throughout the course why that's important.
And the fourth requirement is the avalanche effect.
And I specifically put an image here because too like ingrain this in our memory so we remember that
we saw this avalanche on the screen.
It is an ultra important requirement of the hash algorithm.
So let's see what it implies.
The average effect means that if I take exactly the same document and I change it like make a tiny oil
change even one bit of data change in the document for instance we've got a plus one over there here.
So if we do that you'll change any change then the hash will be absolutely different.
So we really saw that in the demonstration where when we were adding an X or exclamation mark or making
some other small changes though the reason is called the avalanche effect is because of how that is
implemented inside the algorithm.
We're not going to go into detail now but like you'll be able to check that in the paper if you like
but it basically that one change triggers may a few changes and they in turn trigger more changes and
they are more changes.
So it's very smart how it's caused and it's very similar to an avalanche where like one tiny like wrong
step can cause snow to start moving and then more snow moves and snow more snow more and you get an
avalanche.
So that's what the avalanche effect is and it's very very important in the application of block chain.
And we'll see why when we're talking about mining in the mining tutorials in this section in this module
you'll see why the avalanche expect is so important.
And part five it must withstand collisions.
So what does that mean.
What is static collisions mean.
Well it means like what as we saw with with people that sometimes one in 60 million that you're going
to have to people who have the same thing to print and same thing for the hashing algorithm because
the I got the pictures on the screen already.
In a second so I'll explain what the pigeons are doing there.
So with the hash algorithm as you can see it's 64 bits.
Right so it's very limited.
Even though like there's a lot of different variations as you can have it's still limited it's not infinite.
And yet the quantity of different digital documents that we can create is unlimited is enormous.
We can like there's tons and tons of books tons of different photos being created every single day videos
all this stuff.
So in essence the amount of digital data we have is much much greater than we can possibly have is much
greater than the difference the number of variations of a 64 character representation.
And so that means that there is a principle called the pigeon hole principle.
That means if you have for instance in this case 10 pigeons and only nine holes you're gonna have to
put two pigeons into one of those holes.
There's no way around that.
Right so if you have more of a quantity a then there is slots and quantity B.
Then inevitably there will be what we call collisions in quanta in that representation when you try
to move from quantity which is much greater to quantity.
So naturally they will be collusions and you can do anything about it just pigeonhole principle and
that's OK.
The thing with that is that it is so unlikely it is so rare that that will happen that we can deal with
it.
It's OK it's not going to ruin the whole room.
The problem just like with humans and fingerprints we can tolerate that.
That's a very rare instance and it's pretty much a very very unlikely to happen.
And like it's not going to affect anything if it does happen somewhere sometime.
But we must have some collisions what that does mean is that we need the algorithm needs to be able
to withstand artificial collisions that for instance pirates can create.
And that's a problem.
So if you can find a way to create these collisions to make two different documents purposefully have
the same hash that's a problem because then you can forged documents then you might have an important
document that for instance is who's who this house belongs to.
Like ownership document.
And it might have a name in there.
And if you know if there's a way to forge collisions to create artificial collisions then you will be
able to change the name on the documents and the hash will be the same.
So the person checking the document by the hash will think that you are the owner of the house.
And so that's what we mean by withstand collisions.
So collisions should not be possible.
So there we go those are the five requirements for secure and safe hash algorithms.
They have to be one way deterministic a fast computation the avalanche effect and must withstand collisions.
I know this is quite a lot to take in on cryptography too at the very start.
But at the same time this is the foundation of what we're going to be discussing about blockades so
these things are going to be very very useful to us.
And to finish off here's the promised additional reading if you'd like to learn exactly about how the
hash how the Sharjah on Route 6 algorithm works.
Then you can check it out here.
The paper is called on the secure hash algorithm family.
It's actually not paper it's actually a chapter in a book it's chapter one of cryptography and context
and that chapter one was run by Per Penarth and Cohen and the links are there the link will also be
in the notes for the course.
There you go.
Hope you enjoyed this.
Tauriel and now you're well-versed in Shudra under 56 and we'll start learning more about block chains
and applying this knowledge from the next trial.
And we've seen you there until then in your actions.