Hayyeh is welcome to this need to toil.
So this is a quick one to make everything ready for demo and therefore we're going to prepare the Jason
foules that will need to post and post man when we interact with our blood chain to exchange some crypto
currencies.
So we'll have actually to Jason foules to make one Jayson file that will contain all the addresses of
the notes and one of the Jayson feathers will contain the format of a transaction you know will prepare
the right format with the right three keys.
Send the receiver an amount that will get something ready to post in postman and also what you will
do in this pre final tutorial is get our servers ready and to do this will make actually three bytes
and fouls each of them will be connected to a different port one port for me one port for curial and
one port for you.
So I will be on port five thousand one Kyrle will be on port five thousand two and you will be on port
five thousand three and you will see in the demo I will send lot of coin's to Israel and even more had
comments to you.
So lets do all this in the Statoil So that will be 100 percent ready in the next tutorial for the demo.
All right so first of all let's make the Jayson files and we are going to start with the Jayson file
for the notes and so very simply to create this doesn't file will go to the top here.
In Python you click on file you then click on new file.
There we go.
And the year you select everything and delete and we are going to save that.
So I'm pressing the shortcut CMD your control plus S to save here.
I'm in the right for that that is Mudgal to create a cryptocurrency.
And now just before we give a name to our file Well we are going to change the type of this file because
you know the adjacent file is not a python file but JS and foul so sorry you cannot see here because
it's out of the screen but I'm selecting it right now.
You should be able to find it.
Jason foules you said this.
And there we go we can change the name now.
And we're going to choose the following name.
Note very simply because in this days in fact we're going to register the addresses of the notes we
want to have in our de-centralized block chain.
So if you're ready note all good let's press say OK and now we're about to implement our very first
Jason File which will be used for our very first post and Postman.
So you'll see it's going to be very simple to make edges and found you need to start with brackets and
now we're going to press enter twice because we are going to put the key and the value of the key in
the center of these brackets.
But before we input them make sure to press tab and then you can enter the name of the key and then
the value of the key.
So now the question is what keys do we have for nodes Jason foul.
Well remember there is only one key which is the note notes key and remember that is the key that contains
the addresses of all the notes we should have in the network.
So that's the key.
And now Gullan And here we enter the value of this key and the value as we just said is the list of
the different addresses of the node we want to have in our network.
And so as I said at the beginning of this tutorial we're going to have three notes one for me one for
curial and one for you.
And so we need to input three addresses which we can differentiate with three different points and these
boards are going to be port five thousand one for me.
Port five thousand two for keel and port five thousand three for you.
So let's do this let's put these addresses in this list and remember the addresses are the following.
HTP colon slash slash one hundred twenty seven point open open.
That's the menu to denote will be sharing.
And then we need to add the port.
And so as we said we're going to have three ports starting from five thousand one and then five thousand
two and then five thousand three.
All right so that's the first address.
And now I just added it come up because we're going to answer the other addresses too more.
So I'm copying this than here let's press Enter let's a line at the right level here.
All right then let's paste.
This is our second address so you know Same deal here but then a different port five thousand two.
So that's the address for curial.
And finally one address for you.
There we go and you will have port five thousand three.
Perfect.
And that's done.
That's our Jason felt for the note as you see it's very simple.
Now we're going to save it and we're going to move on to the next Jason File which is the file for the
transaction.
So we're going to do exactly the same we're going to go to file at the top then we're going to click
on new file and then we're going to select this and remove this then save then let's not forget to select
the right type which is Jason Jason foules.
And then we're going to give a name here which will be transaction transaction and not transactions
because we just add one transaction at a time.
All right.
And then we can click on Save.
All good.
Now we are ready to implement this transaction Jayson.
So now please press pause on the video and try to make this transaction yourself before I do it.
I'm going to do it now.
So of course we start with brackets.
Then double enter and inside we put our three keys after pressing tab.
So the first key is the sender.
Then the second key is the receiver.
And then the third key is the amount of coins exchanged between the sender and the receiver.
And more specifically this is the amount of at coins that the sender sent to the receiver.
All right.
Now.
So as I told you this is just going to be a prepared format which means that so far the values will
simply enter some quotes here and here as well.
And the amount doesn't get a string.
So we'll just put a space here and we'll enter a number for example 10 and then you'll see when we post
a transaction in Postman.
Well what we'll do is we'll select all this will copy it and we'll paste in postman to input the right
values for the sender the receiver and the amount and then will the consent or press enter to send the
request to add a new transaction.
But this is just to prepare the format of a transaction.
However for the notes we already entered the value for the notes key.
Okay.
So our Jason fells already.
And so now just to finish this toil and then we'll be 100 percent ready for the demo is we will prepare
the three bison foules which will represent our servers to of our block chain.
So our blood will be a decentralized network of 3 nodes and so basically what we're about to do now
is get these notes around.
So I'm not going to nullify this because this is our final code final implementation so let's save it
for now.
Without any further modification and therefore we're going to make three new files one failure a second
one and a third Nouvelle and we're going to copy paste the at coin implementation.
Inside each of them and we will replace what needs to be replaced that is first the port.
So here this is my notes that will be on board five thousand one.
And the request to mine a new block is OK because the receiver is large.
So that's all good.
So I'm going to save this file and I'm going to call it at coin node five thousand one writes this will
be my note.
Now let's get is not ready.
This is going to be this one selecting on this pasting and curial will be on port five thousand two
and here to mine a block.
Well the receiver will no longer be Adler but curial.
OK let's save that and let's replace it by that coin note five thousand to perfect curial notes is ready.
And now let's get your node ready.
So again selecting on this pacing you will be on port five thousand three and here when you mind a plug
the receiver will no longer be Adna or Curiel it will be you.
All right let's save it.
There we go.
Here you can just like this to be more efficient and you'll be on point five thousand three save all
good port five thousand three let's check if everything's OK here.
Port five thousand one Adlon here.
Port five thousand two curial and eventually port five thousand three.
You.
Right.
And now we're all good 100 percent ready.
So let's mesh this in the next tutorial.