Hello and welcome back to the course on my watch chain.
And today we're going to continue our discussion of soft and hard forums.
All right so previously we left off here where we talked about the real life examples of soft and hard
for us in the human Bitcoin chains.
So just to quickly recap.
We saw that on the 20th of July 2006 when there was a hard fork in the theory chain because of the attack
on the Dow and is here and wanted to revert the transactions in that attack and those miners who agreed
continued theory therian those models who disagreed continue proof Ilium classic in bitcoin on 20 of
July's thousand seventeen there a soft porc associated with the acceptance of segment on first of August
2017.
There was a hard fork which was caused by some miners being unhappy with the block size limit of 1 megabytes
and they decided to increase the block size limit to 8 megabytes and therefore they split off into their
own chain which is now called Bitcoin cash Bitcoin continues here.
And then on 24th October 2002 and 17 there were some miners who were unhappy with the basic mining devices
because they were too powerful and these miners wanted to go back to mining with G-B use.
And that's why there was another four and a hard four.
And this new chain is now known as Bitcoin gold and Bitcoin continued here as well.
So that's the real life examples of soft and hard forks.
Now let's go to the theory.
What is the difference between a soft and hard for.
And what exactly do they do to the underlying software.
So let's have a look.
So this is the rule of thumb that hard for.
They loosen up rules and soft forks.
They tighten up rules.
It might sound a bit counterintuitive like you might think that it's you know soft and hard tight and
what it is what it is.
We'll discuss a little bit later why the name might be what their name is might have been chosen as
such.
But in general just remember this is a rule of thumb that hard force loosen up the rules.
So of course they tighten up the rules even if the way to remember is that it is the definition is the
counterintuitive definition.
All right so now let's look at an example.
We're going to look at an example here.
We've got some placeholders where application will be demonstrated and is coming from the left and then
at some point this red line demonstrates illustrates where the fork actually happened or start of a
hard fork and a great example of hard work is.
First I wanted to mention that in our placeholders we're going to have two rows the top row is four
miners who haven't upgraded to the new rules.
And the bottom row is for miners who have upgraded to the new rules as our blog why would be on the
top or on the bottom.
And the good example to start off with is the maximum block size increasing.
While this is indeed an example of a hard fork as we know because that happened in real life.
Bitcoin and and there's been quite cash.
That's exactly what happened Bitcoin has a box as of one megabyte and cash has a maximum block size
of 8 megabytes.
So in both cases a maximum size of one megabyte maxims and look make 8 megabytes.
And was it a hard for because as we discussed hard forks they tighten up the no hiding.
Hard for say loosen up.
Reading is so hard for us.
You know loosen up the rules and therefore in bitcoin you can only have up to one megabyte.
Now in the current cache you have a broader range.
You can go all the way up to eight megabytes of rules have been loosened up.
And so let's have a look at how a hard fought might play out.
So before the software is updated everybody's on the same chain.
So each year everybody's together and then the software is updated.
And then this happens some some decide to stay with the old rules.
Some of the sites take the new rules and let's say that this block this first block after the upgrade
is actually found by a minor who is sitting in this group and minor who decided not to upgrade and then
this blog is going to be under one megabyte let's say it's 0.7 megabytes.
And if this is the only change to the rules all the network forbit going cash.
So if this is the only change we look at a very trivial example that this is indeed the only change
that occurred in Maxo blocks has increased.
Well this block of 0.7 megabytes it follows the rules of the old network.
Correct.
Because this is one megabyte limit and it follows the rules of the new network.
Because this is eight megabytes them and so this block will be accepted by everybody in the total network
of Bitcoin we can capture all of these miners all except this blog because it falls everybody's rules.
Great then let's say the next block is also found by miners in this group now a miner in that.
Again zero point nine megabyte.
This blog follows the rules of the Bitcoin at work and the current cash flows everybody's rules so it's
going to be accepted by everybody.
Again no conflict there.
But then let's say the next block is accepted or is found by a miner who is in this group who has has
a British soldier and let's say this blog is indeed eight megabytes in size.
Then what happens here is that this block is now is now.
Indeed indeed it follows the rules of the new network of liquid cash.
Correct.
Because eight megabytes is in the limit of eight megabytes.
However eight megabytes is way more than one make about and it doesn't follow the rules of the Bitcoin
that rogue the old.
So what that means is that the miners that haven't upgrade to the new rules they will this they will
reject this block they will not accept them into their chain they will they will look at it and they'll
say this is luck is invalid and they'll continue mining and eventually they'll find their own block
which will be one megabyte for example and this bloke will follow the rules of as you can either get
it or.
And so this is where the split happens as soon as this situation occurs where something in the new rules
which are broader which are looser like how like is found and it doesn't fit in with the old network.
Then there's a split and so between cache will continue mining its own chain and Bitcoin will continue
mining its own chain.
And so as you can see what that means is that a hard fork and why it's called a heart for it is because
it's not backwards compatible.
So as soon as something is found in this new chain with current cash for instance it will not be accepted
so a block from a block found by miners who have a grade will generally never be accepted by a blog
by the miners who haven't read.
And that's why as soon as a block like this comes first then there's a split in the chain and that's
it.
And then from then on forever there's going to be separate chains.
It will them they will never come back together simply because it's back is not backwards compatible
and that's where was the hard for because it is like a hard to change it doesn't allow for the change
to come back together it doesn't allow for the miners from all networks to accept those books and well
there.
So that's hard.
Heartful Now let's have a look at a sophomore.
So for example again here we're going to have haven't upgraded on the top and have upgraded and so is
the names are a bit different so here is haven't upgraded yet and have already agreed and that's shows
that eventually in a soft for all minors will be forced to upgrade eventually so in the software you
generally don't have a split of the network or split up the chains.
Is just going to be one chain and eventually all miners will go here.
But what this word means here a majority it means that a Southfork only will will only actually happen
will only be initiated by the network when the majority agrees in advance.
That's awful.
So in bitcoin like going into different networks the rules are different and that majority is a different
percentage so like this will be initiated only when a certain percentage of the miners agree to it.
And it is is just it.
And number above 50 percent.
And again it depends on the network what it can be and the situation as well.
So what we're going to look at is a soft fork an example of when the maximum block size is decreased.
We don't have an A real life example of that so we're going to make one up we're going to say that in
the aggregate was one made megabytes in the new network or in the in bitcoin.
Again it's the same that we're seeing here is that they're not going to actually split the chains are
going to split.
So the new rules as well as the new rules are that the Maximum block size is half a megabyte 0.5 megabytes
and yeah.
And so why is this a small.
Why is this soft for a while we know that the rules in a soft four are tied I tightened up and as we
can see the R&amp;D tighten up so here we have a maximum boobs maximum block size of one megabyte.
And now we have a smaller range.
We can only go up to zero point five million.
So it's constricting us more and therefore there was a tightening up and so it's software.
So let's have a look the network is here so it can do it so the chain was comes up to here then the
rules are changed because the majority we have the majority who agreed to change the rules then from
here what happens is well let's say that even though the majority is here let's say that the first block
is actually found by a minor from this group it could totally happen right because what money lost is
kind of like a lottery.
And therefore it totally can happen that the first block here does fine by money from this group and
let's say this block is in incise it is only 0.4 megabytes.
Again that could also happen because blocks the size of the limits.
Here we have here we can see here the maximum limit so a block could totally be like 0.4 megabytes.
And so let's see what happens here.
Let's check the rules so 0.4 megabytes does conform to the old rules.
Yes it's accepted by these miners.
Good and 0.4 megawatts also conforms to the new rules is less than half a megabyte.
Great.
So it's also accepted by the miners.
Amazing everything's fantastic.
All right.
So there's no conflict there.
Then what happens.
Let's say the next block is again followed by a minor from this group.
Again that could happen as well.
But this time the block is 0.9 megabytes and so now if we check the rules we'll see that 0.9 megabytes
does conform to the neural to the old rules check.
So it's accepted by these miners great.
However 0.9 megabytes doesn't conform to the new rules which are 0.5 megabytes it's 0.9 is greater than
the new and therefore it is not accepted by the whiners who have upgraded.
So what's going to happen is they're going to see this block they're going to reject it as not not valid
and therefore they are going to continue mining and eventually they'll find their own block which might
be like 0.5 megabytes.
Now this is where the interesting part happens.
So now we kind of have like a chain split right.
So OK we're looks very it looks very similar to what happens in hard for we might like.
Looks like we're about to have a chain split and these two chains are going to go their separate ways.
However this is the interesting part.
So because we have the majority of miners here right.
The only software going to be initiated when we have now is just majority black prevailing which are
like 75 and 95 in a lot of miners sitting in there.
Then what will on this site what'll happen is these miners are going to find the next block likely they're
going to find the next book faster.
And so we will have a situation like this because there's more of them here and we'll have a new block
here.
And what that means is this block this is this is the key that this block is 0.5 megabytes and it follows
the rules of the new network and it follows the rules of the old network as well.
So that is where the backwards compatibility of a software comes out of that software is backwards compatible
on like hardware.
So what that means is that these blocks found by new miters they will be accepted by the new miners
and by the Obamas.
And so what.
So these miners they just see a chain like this great.
And what these miners see they see an or block situation they see a chain kind of split.
So they see gays or pornography.
They also see this change.
They accept these blocks as valid.
And so because they see this chain they see that this is the longer chain.
And it does conform to their rules so they will reject they will reject whoops they'll reject this blog
and will become an orphan block and they will continue with this chain the even the minors that haven't
an upgrade simply because the new rules are stricter and tighter and therefore they still conform to
the old rules.
And so even if this doesn't happen like right away even if you have like 1 1 and then you have another
1 1 1 1.
Eventually because this moment is here eventually this chain will be longer.
Eventually the blue channel way here will be longer and eventually this other chain will be rejected.
And so the new miners will always win because their blocks are accepted by both the new and the old
rules the old miners will always lose because their blocks are not accepted by the new rules and there
is less of them less of the minors and so from there it will continue and again eventually like for
instance here maybe a minor from this group might find the next block great and it might be comparable
to both rules great again.
So it'll be accepted but then a Eventually the next block might be found by minors from this group and
so on.
And so in this case because of situations like this because of situations where there is a chance but
then it turns into an orphan block situation.
And the miners continue this way.
Miners here are going to be at a disadvantage there.
They are more likely to find blocks that are going to be rejected that are going to become or for blocks
and that forces them to move to this group that forces them to accept the new rules and to play by the
new rules that gives them the incentive to do that because otherwise they're going to be spending a
lot of time and electricity mining blocks which are going to become invalid and they're not going to
be getting their war.
So that's the that's how software works very tricky like that.
And the key here is backwards compatibility and that's why it's called the software because it's not
a hard change in the rules.
It's a soft change in the rules even though it can even though it's so because it makes rules tighter.
It's it means that it's a soft change in the sense that minors that it's still the new the new rules
are still compatible.
Excuse me they're still compatible The old rule so the new rules are kind of like a subgroup of the
old rules and that's why I call this a fault because that insures backwards compatibility and that's
that allows for this kind of like game scenario like competition scenario where these guys will always
win and that forces the ones that have an upgrade to the majority.
So for instance that's how Segway was accepted in the beginning.
All right so there we go that's how the software works.
And I know this especially this software business might be a bit complicated in that case there's great
additional reading which I've bought for you.
It's called The Complete Guide on Bitcoin and blotching for Spike.
You had Z and it explains this whole situation with a great analogy of a restaurant the restaurant that's
cooking vegetarian food and then they decide to introduce meat.
And that represents some hard for.
Or the entry they decide to introduce or decide to switch to only vegan recipes and that represents
a soft fall.
And so a great analogy which can help you further understand this topic if you'd like to get a better
grasp of it.
But in general that's how soft often hard forks work.
Hope you enjoyed today's tutorial and I look forward to see you next.
Until then enjoy bludgeons.