[Autogenerated] Okay, welcome to Module three,
where we're going to start diving into using additional
monitoring services offer to us by a ws.
Now, what should we expect to learn in this module?
Well,
the first thing we're going to do is we're going to identify the
benefits of using AWS service catalog And then with that,
we're actually gonna work on publishing a new product to service
catalog from within our account so other users can actually use it
and deploy it into their own accounts.
The very next thing we're going to do is we're going to explore the
different tools available for managing AWS storage.
And believe it or not,
there's quite a few tools that AWS offers for either
extremely cheap or for free for us to use.
So let's go ahead and wrap this overview clip up,
and then I'll see you in the next one where we're going to start diving into what service catalog is and what it's used for.