[Autogenerated] All right, So what does service catalog actually do?
Well, there are four things that we really want to touch on here,
and the first is that it allows us to provide
standardization across our products.
Now, what this means is that we, as the service catalog product owners,
are able to control which services inversions are
actually available for others to use.
It also allows for self service discovery.
And what this means is that basically different account
owners and users can deploy these services or these products
that we publish all on their own,
and they don't have to create things from scratch.
They can reuse or repurpose our products to meet their needs,
and it's all done via a self service portal that the user gets the search from.
It also allows us to implement fine grained access control.
And what this means is that we, as the product owners,
are actually able to lock down the configuration of
the different available services,
the permissions in the different access based on many different specific values,
and we can do it by individual maybe ah cost centre tag
or maybe just a user group in general.
Another example, is,
we can actually locked down what type of V P sees
our products can be launched into,
and the last thing we have is that you can utilize version control now.
In today's day and age version, control is huge,
especially for infrastructure is code.
So by utilizing this version control,
you can slowly release newer versions and publish those
for people to use all without them,
really even noticing it's a seamless integration.
So let's go over a quick example of how service
catalog works we have in AWS architect.
And he's designing this Jason template,
which is a cloud formacion template that we're going to call a
service now when he creates it and tests it,
he can then publish that product to service catalog.
And once it's published,
it actually gets listed in a catalogue that other users can browse.
So then we have our A W s admin is and users that come into play,
let's just say, for example, they're working for their company,
and they need to deploy this standard product that our AWS
architect has created in published Well,
they're going to go ahead and browse that catalog,
the A.
W s service catalog,
which is a portfolio and product list which will look out here in a little bit.
And they're gonna find that particular product that they want to deploy,
and we can see that they're deploying product A into their own accounts.
Now this allows for an exact identical copy of product A in
between account a an account be all because we're using service
catalog as that deployment point.
Now you can see how Service Catalog really allows us to
easily share services and products that we get to define for
quick deployment to other users.
Now we're gonna go ahead and wrap this clip up,
and then I'll see you in the next one where we're going to start
diving into the console and poking around a. W S service catalog.