[Autogenerated] Okay, here we go.
So I've loaded up the service catalogue service screen within the AWS console,
and you can see it brings us to this getting started page.
Now, if I scroll down,
we'll see a get started button will click that here in a second.
But if I continue,
we're going to see we have three different options here where we can learn more.
We can learn more about creating and managing portfolios.
We can learn about adding products,
and we can even learn about managing user access and then at the bottom.
Here we have our documentation links.
Now,
I do recommend you dive into these documentation links
because service catalog can get very detailed.
But for now, let's go and scroll back up and I'm gonna click on get started.
Now, you see,
that brings us to a create portfolio screen and AWS
lists that we can use portfolios toe,
organize our products and then distribute them.
Now, portfolios contain products,
and we actually grant permissions for users to view and launch these
products that are contained within these portfolios.
So I'm gonna give my portfolio and name.
I'm gonna call it plural site and then if we want,
we can give it a description saw.
Go and say this is our test portfolio.
And then the owner is whoever you want to be indicated as creating it.
So Uggla and put myself as the owner.
All right, so we have everything filled out.
We gave it a name, a description in an owner.
So I'm gonna click on Create.
Now, this is going to create our very first portfolio.
Now, from this portfolios view here,
we can see at the top that we can select the portfolio source.
We could do local ones, weaken, do imported weaken, do organization portfolios.
Or we can do a getting started library.
So let's click on that and you can see that AWS
provides us a service catalog in a box.
So if we open this here, we're going to see in a ws provided sample for us use.
And you can see all of the different product names
that they have published in here.
So these air pretty much different cloud formacion templates that we
can go ahead and publish within our own account.
So I'm gonna go back here.
I'm gonna return to portfolio list, will make sure on local portfolios.
And then I'm gonna go down to our new portfolio plural site.
Let me open this up and it takes us to our portfolio screen.
Now,
the first thing we're going to see here is that we do not
have any products in this portfolio, so we need to start adding some.
So what we can do here is we can either upload a new
product or we can add an existing product to our portfolio
so we don't have any existing ones.
So I'm gonna click on upload new product here,
and let's give this a product name.
I'm gonna call it plural site product.
And then in the description here,
let's just put something simple and then provided by is gonna be
the person or organization that's publishing it.
So I go and put my name again here, and then we'll move on.
We'll see the vendor, which is an optional field.
So I'm gonna leave this blank.
But if we were a vendor that's publishing this,
we can put our name here, so I'm gonna click on next,
and then we enter our support details.
So this is going to be who is going to provide support
for our product that we're posting.
So I'm gonna enter my email address here,
and then we're gonna move on to support Link.
Now, if we had a link a u r l that we wanted to provide for support,
we could put that here.
We don't have one, so we'll leave it blank.
But in the description will put plural sites support.
All right, there we go.
So we now have my email contact.
We're not using a support link, and then we provided this simple description,
so I'm gonna click on next again.
Let me scroll down here on version details,
and you're going to see weaken, select the template location.
We can either upload one or weaken.
Specify a your location that stores a confirmation template.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm actually gonna upload a local file here,
so let me select this.
Okay, so I've uploaded it, and it's called service catalog product,
and then I'm gonna give it a title.
So we'll just call this the initial version and then if we wanted to,
we can also give it a description.
And you can see that AWS recommends the description explicitly
call out the differences between versions.
So let's just put a simple description for this,
and then I'm gonna going click on next, all right?
And this brings us to our product reviews screen.
We can see our product details.
Here we can see are optional product information.
And then when I scroll down here, we can see our version details.
So it uploaded our cloud information template to an S three bucket here,
and it has our version title in description.
So what I'm gonna do is click on create, and there we go a success.
We've now added a product to our portfolio.
So I'm gonna close this window down the success message,
and I'm actually gonna go ahead and refresh this page here and there we go.
We see our plural site product that we just uploaded.
So we're going to go in and wrap this initial clip up where we just got done,
creating an up, loading a new product, and then in the next clip,
we're actually gonna start diving into the
different options that come with this.
Such as the constraints and sharing with other accounts. So we'll wrap this one up and then I'll see you in the next one