[Autogenerated] all right in this clip.
Let's go ahead and take a look at some constraints.
Now constraints, which are in this drop down menu,
where on the left are essentially,
are a way to control the way our products can be launched by different users.
And you can see right now we don't have any defined constraints.
And another caveat is that your portfolio must first contain a
product which it does appear our plural site product.
So let's go ahead and look at these constraints here.
If I click on add constraints, we can see we get a constraint type list.
We can use the launch constraint type,
which is going to assign an I am rule for our cloud
formacion to use what provisions resource is.
We can set a notification tight,
which is going to stream product notifications to a specific topic.
On our end, we can do a template constraint,
which is gonna limit the options available to our in users.
They added a stack set, which is a beta template that was recently added,
and it allows us to configure these deployments across
accounts in regions using cloud formations,
stack sets, and then finally we have tag update,
which is going to update our tags after it has been provisioned.
So what I'm gonna do is select our product here.
We only have one.
And let's just do a launch constraint type.
We're not gonna dig into all of these.
I just want you to get familiar with creating them in general.
So I'm gonna click on launch here.
Let's click.
Continue.
And it now brings us to our launch constraint screen.
So this is where we can select our role that clot information is going to use.
So let me find one real quick and I actually have a specific
role for this called Plural Sites Service catalog and you
can see the role are in here, and then I can give it a description.
So if I want,
I can give a simple description that talks about what
restrictions are in place or what constraints.
So now that we have are simple description here we click on submit.
There we go.
We now have a new constraint,
created something close this little green box here and we can
see we have our constraint listed in our list,
and it's a launch type of constraint.
So now any time someone launches our product,
this constraint is going to go into effect,
and it's only going to be able to use our role that we have in
our account when we're deploying our services.
So now if we wanted to weaken, either edit this or we can remove it,
so I'm going to remove it, and now we have no constraints,
and that's actually gonna wrap this clip up.
I'll see you in the next one where we're going to start
diving into assigning permissions to other users or roles and even other AWS accounts.