[Autogenerated] All right.
Welcome back.
Now this clip,
we're going to start diving into the cloudwatch dashboard
capability under operations management.
Now,
Cloudwatch dashboard here is essentially a customizable page or a dashboard
that allows us to view cloudwatch metrics and alarms.
Now, I'm not going to dive into this too much in detail right now,
but let's just go ahead and take this out so I can create
a dashboard here will give it a name.
Let me create dashboard.
And there we go.
We have now created a plural site, dashboard.
We're going to learn cloudwatch dashboards a lot deeper in in
a lot more detail later on in this course.
So for now,
just bear with me and we're just gonna walk through
this so you can see what it does.
Not gonna click line here.
I'll click on configure.
We can give our graph a title and then we can see we have our metrics so I
can look at the different metrics within this region.
Because remember, cloudwatch is a regional service.
So what I can do here is I can goto s three just for it.
An example.
Here.
I can look at my logs directory that I have and my number of objects.
Let's just do number of objects for now.
And if I had some data that was being reported,
we would see it up here at the top on this craft.
Now, I don't have anything here,
so let me go and switch this in number just to be sure.
And there you go.
You can see we have nothing in this bucket.
But what this would allow us to do is create this widget.
And now it's on our dashboard.
So make sure you always save your dashboard when you're done.
I've done it before where I've created this beautiful dashboard.
And then I forgot to click Save in.
All of my work was lost.
So really be sure to save her dashboard whenever you edit or created.
So now what we could do from here is we could view many
different metrics in a single pane of glass,
all under systems manager.
And if we see something out of whack or out of the ordinary,
we could go in the ops center and then resolve some of
those issues if they're occurring.
So this portion really allows us to have an extremely flexible
and customizable display for viewing our source data about a
metrics and alarms within our accounts.
Now, the next thing we have here is trusted advisor in personal health.
Dashboard.
Now a trusted advisor is going to compare all of your AWS
resource is to the A W s recommended best practices,
so you can see that it's came.
My account for 55 of my resource is there's no problems detected.
We have zero investigations recommended, and then we have actions recommended.
So, five, you all check details here.
It brings me to trusted adviser,
and you can see I have a security group that was just
showing up for unrestricted access.
So I created a security group that allowed Internet traffic from
anywhere for a demo that I was doing previously.
So that's why it's picking that up.
So if I expand this,
you can see I have tons of security groups down here in a lot
of them are recommending investigation.
But then I do have the defaults that are left in place,
and this is a best practice to erase default security groups,
by the way.
But these air allowing already P traffic from anywhere,
So that's why they're flagged.
And this is all viewable under one service within systems Manager.
The next thing we see is personal health dashboard.
So this is where if a W s was having events that
affected your resource is health.
Like maybe they had an s three outage which has
happened before in North Virginia.
It would show up here.
Or maybe they're having a E C s or I am related
issue and it affects your accounts.
They're going to show up within this dashboard for you to view.
So if I go to a view,
all you'll see it brings me the personal health dashboard and this is an idea of
what you might see now these are all closed and completed.
So there's nothing showing up on our dashboard, these air all in the past.
So you can see we had a cloud formacion operational issue.
We can go in here and look at the details,
and if needed,
we can look at affected Resource is so if I had cloud
formacion templates and stacks deployed,
it would list My affected resource is here.
So I could be aware there's e C to weaken.
See it was resolved the time stamps when they happened and
were resolved if there was any affected resource is once again
and you can see the list goes on.
It's for any service in A W s.
So that's going to do it for this section on the Operations
Management capability section will go ahead and we're going to
wrap up this section and then move on to application management in the next upcoming clips.