[Autogenerated] All right, let's go and start talking about some logging.
Now Cloudwatch is known for being the default logging
service that Amazon provides us to use.
We can see here on the left that we have our logs sections.
So if I click on logs, this is gonna take us to our logs screen.
Now, on this screen, we can see we have a log.
Groups weakens, er, insights, shortcuts,
weaken set an expiry date and then we have metric filters and subscriptions.
Now we'll talk about metric filters and subscriptions and a later clip.
For now, I just want to focus on the fundamentals here of log groups.
Now, what this does is by default.
Resource is in AWS are gonna push the cloudwatch and you can see
they follow a specific name space type of pattern.
We can see these are E CS related.
When it's slash CCs, we see our Run command law group,
which was from our run command clip earlier in the previous module.
And then we have our AWS Lambda log groups.
So if I dive into here, we can see we then have log streams.
So log groups contain many different log streams and
you can see it follows the dates.
And in this case, it's the latest version of our land of function.
And then the request I d.
For that indication, which is a concurrent invocation.
So any concurrent executions are gonna belong to the same log stream.
And what this means is that all concurrent requests or cold start
requests are going to have their own log stream.
But if you invoke a function, it finishes and you invoke it again.
As long as that back container is going,
we're going to see that it belongs to the same log stream.
So let me go and dive into this.
And before we discuss this, let me go to my presentation here.
Now,
this is gonna be an easier way really quickly before we dive in
the logging to break down what a log looks like.
We can see here at the top.
We have our start of our request.
I d.
With our latest version and then in the middle here,
we actually have our custom logging.
So these are actual logging statements that we put from our
particular either instance or maybe Lambda function.
Now this one is a Lambda function.
But I'm just showing you how you can customize your logging.
And then we have our in request, I d.
So it's ending the request and then we have a report.
So this is a lambda default.
It gives you a billing report to see what's going on.
So let's scroll back here and we're gonna look at this custom logging weaken.
See, here we had our start.
I printed out a message of Andrew and then it ended.
And then we have a report and I did this several times.
So let's actually test this out.
I'm gonna go ahead and I'm gonna go to the S S m parameter law group here.
And then I'm gonna open up Lambda and let's customize some of this logging.
I'm gonna open this up.
I'll edit this function here,
let me scroll down and we can see this was used in our S S M,
which was our systems manager parameter store video.
And we can see we printed the value of that parameter, and we returned it.
So let me add another print statement here.
I'm gonna add in a print statement that says hello Plural sites,
students This is our custom logging with a little smiley face.
So let me save this year, I'm gonna test it out.
So we printed a couple times and then I'm gonna go back to Cloudwatch.
Let me refresh this, and you can see we have a new log stream.
And this is because we made a change.
So it's a new indication I'm gonna open this up.
And as you can see, Cloudwatch is not immediate.
It takes a minute for it to catch up, but you can see the events starting.
We have our first indication There's that Andrew,
which is that value of that parameter.
And then we have our custom logging here.
Hello, plural sites, students.
This is our custom logging.
And we did this two times.
So now you can see how you can utilize custom logging to push the cloudwatch.
Now,
one quick last thing here is if I go back to law groups and I take a
look at this expire events after section I can actually set thes to
expire with a certain retention date.
So you can see we can be one day never expire.
One month we could even go all the way to 10 years.
So this allows us to set a retention period for our
logs in case we wanted to do that.
So if I select this again and let's just say I want to keep these for
one week and then expire them so I'm gonna say OK,
and now if I had any logs that were older than one week,
there would be gone.
But I don't.
So that's not really an issue here.
Now that's gonna do it for law groups and log streams will wrap this up,
and then we're going to continue on in the next clip to discuss metric filters and subscriptions.