[Autogenerated] All right, Welcome back.
Now, In the previous clip,
we discussed setting specific constraints on our products
that we have listed in our portfolios.
And in this clip,
we're going to start diving into allowing users groups and rolls
and other AWS accounts to get in there in,
publish or deploy our product that we have listed.
So I'm gonna expand users groups and rolls here,
and you can see that we can click this ad button.
So I'm gonna click on add, and we can see we can either browse groups,
weaken, browse users or weaken do roles.
So this is going to isolate on which users and our account
can access in view and launch this product.
So let's say we want to lock this down to our deployment Engineers group here.
So all these users that are within this group,
we'll have access to our plural site products.
So I click on add access and there we go.
We now have a user permission set up under our user
groups and Rolls section here.
So this is going to allow this group within our account the
ability to access this published product.
Now,
let's also say we want to share this with some partnering A W s accounts or
maybe an organization account that lives underneath us.
Now,
I won't be able to do organizations because I don't have one
created because I'm Onley in a single account,
but the process is going to be the same.
What I would do here is goto add account and you can see
that we can specify an account I d.
So what we would do here is type the 12 digit account i d,
and this is going to share it with this particular account.
I'll click on share and there we go.
We have now shared our portfolio,
which is the plural site portfolio with this account here,
and you can see that the administrator of that account can now import the
portfolio at this particular link that they provide.
So, just like that,
we can easily share it with specific AWS accounts and allow these accounts
access into viewing our products within our portfolio.
So I'm gonna go ahead and remove this account really quick before I forget to,
and that's going to wrap this clip up.
I'll see you in the next one where we're gonna finish up
editing our existing product and then viewing the service catalog consul screen and running through it