[Autogenerated] All right, welcome back.
So now that we have a grasp on operations management
in the different capabilities, let's dive into application management.
Now,
this is a sweet similar to operations management that allows us to
manage our actual applications that were running in AWS.
Now the first thing we're going to see is there's resource groups.
And if you call back to that earlier clip,
we discussed how resource groups allow us to easily organize.
Our resource is in our account and you'll see why that's important coming up.
The next tool that we have is apt come thick now,
app config is going to allow us to create,
manage and deploy Apcom figs.
To our resource is this essentially allows us to have
controlled deployments of our app.
To most compute resource is in a W s like E C two Lambda or E.
C s containers, for example.
And then our final capability within this suite is we have parameter store.
Now parameter store provides us secure hierarchical
storage for secrets and data management.
So, for instance, we can have user names stored as a parameter,
and then we can have that user names password as a
secured parameter that's encrypted,
and we'll explore this in depth in its own clip coming up shortly.
Now let's go ahead will break here and then when you're ready,
will pick back up in the next clip.
We're going to start diving into the consul and exploring each of these capabilities.