[Autogenerated] now we just got done discussing cross region replication,
and we're going to move on now to storage metrics that
are built in for Amazon s three.
So I filtered out my buckets here to this particular one here
because I have certain objects in there that have lived for a
long enough period of time.
So I'm gonna open up this bucket and I'm gonna go over
here to the management pain again.
And there's a metrics tab now.
So let's click on that, and you can see we have a metrics section down here,
So let me scroll down a little bit and you can see
it's basically a simple graph.
We have our metrics over here on the left.
So we select the bucket that we're trying to measure.
We can add filters if we wanted to.
I'm not going to do that.
So I'm gonna click on cancel or we can even alter
which metrics are getting measured.
So you'll see the 1st 2 which are storage metrics and my 1st 2 I mean,
the actual two metrics within here are free metrics that are provided to us,
the other ones which fall into request metrics which are all of your
different request toe s three and the data transfer metrics so you
can see all of those different ones.
These are going to be a paid feature.
So you're paying per object that's getting measured for these metrics.
So I'm not going to enable these for this demo.
But it's just something to keep in mind to know that you
can enable these if you so wish to.
So let me click on cancel here, and we'll just use the defaults that air free.
Now we see our storage is selected and then we see two options.
There's total size and then object count.
So we click on total size here.
It's going to bring us to our graph,
and you can see we have a standard storage of 26.2
pretty much all the way through out.
So starting several weeks back toe all the way up to a couple of days ago.
Now let's say we want to actually go and switch this so I'm
gonna click on object count now and you can see our graph
changes for all storage types.
We have five objects in this bucket and this is a per day count.
So now you can see how you can actually enable in view storage
metrics within Amazon s three to get a better understanding of how
your objects and buckets are being used.
So we're gonna go and wrap this clip up, and then we're gonna move on to intelligent storage tearing.