[Autogenerated] All right, Welcome back.
Let's dive into maintenance windows and change calendar.
Now, I'm going to do this a little out of order from what you see on the screen.
But I just think it will flow a little bit better for you and allow you to
comprehend it a little bit quicker if I do it in this order.
So I want to talk about maintenance windows first.
Now,
maintenance windows allow us to create a schedule for when
potentially disruptive actions occur.
So that could be patching reboots, etcetera.
So what I do is I go in to create a maintenance window.
We give it a name in a description.
We can't allow this maintenance window to be used for tasks on
targets that are not registered with it.
So we'll leave that checked.
And then we create a schedule so we can specify a Cron.
We can set it to rate, or we can set our own via a string expression.
So a Cron or a rate but define via string.
So what I'll do is I'm gonna run rate.
I'll set it to 30 minutes,
and right now this is the minimum that you can set and then
we can specify how long our window last.
So how long of a gap or how big of a gap do we want
to allow these tasks to occur, so I'll give it a one hour window,
but you can do 1 to 24 now.
We can also stop initiating tasks at a certain point before the window closes so
we can do up to 23 hours before the window closes or zero.
So I'll leave it at zero for now,
and then we can move on to our start and in date.
So if we wanted to,
we could specify a defined start and a defined in so we know
when it starts and when it will stop now.
Typically, maintenance windows don't need Windows start or in dates,
as you usually continually patch and perform
maintenance on all of your workloads.
But if you have a special use case,
a WS allows you to specify a specific start and a
specific end where it will no longer occur.
And when you do this,
you need to schedule your time zone for your starting dates.
If you want a relative to your current one,
we can add our tags, but I'm gonna create our maintenance window.
There you go.
We have our window, we just created it.
And that's how easy it is to create a maintenance window with
specific settings that allow us to define when we want to have
interruptible tasks be performed.
You see, we have a task section.
So how many tasks have been assigned to this window?
We could have a history of when there was executed,
and you can see just now it said, Hey, I have no task to execute,
but it was successful.
So let's actually view these details and you'll
just see it gives you a unique I.
D the window that was occurring and then the start and end time.
So if I go back, I go to targets.
This is where we can register targets for this maintenance window.
So if I click register target, we can specify a name if we want.
So let's just say E c two.
We can give it a description and owner information.
So these are the details that allow us to quickly
identify what this window target is now.
The bottom part allows us to actually specify targets.
So what resource is do we want to target?
Most of the time,
people really only think that you can target instances and easy to,
But you can actually support other systems manager commands.
So run commands and work flows of automation.
You can target lambda functions and step functions.
So this is actually a very customizable peace built into systems manager.
Now, what I want to do is I'm gonna go ahead and choose a resource group.
And this is where we can specify those resource groups that
we created earlier in this module and weaken select what
instances we want or resource types, I should say.
Now, I'm just gonna do an easy two instance.
But this allows you hopefully to connect the dots and see
how we can utilize resource groups,
place them into a specific maintenance window based
on this target details set up.
And then we can run commands at scheduled times.
So you'll see we have two targets right now.
And that's because I have two instances with the tags that group
them into our resource group that we made.
So now what this does is it allows us to schedule
automation based around this maintenance window and
perform things like patching or reboots,
and we'll get into patching a little bit later on.
So with maintenance window out of the way, let's go ahead and go to change.
Calendar now change calendar is exactly what it sounds like.
It allows us to set up dates and time ranges for when
actions can or cannot be performed.
So this is very useful for administrators that have
to perform tasks at certain times.
Change calendars are extremely common in enterprise environments,
so let's just go ahead and create one.
We give it a name, we can give it a description,
and then we choose the type of calendar we want.
Now there's open by default.
So what this does is it allows any actions to be ran except within our
window that we define or we can have closed by default.
And what this does is it's going to block any actions that occur
outside of our change calendar that we specify now.
I have been a part of companies that do it both ways.
It really just depends on your enterprise in your customer
impact that you have in certain industries.
They know specific dates that they don't want things to occur like holidays,
for example.
So open by default might be a better option for this.
As you specify the event Windows,
where you do not want things to occur and then there's closed by default.
That's useful for more strict or stringent enterprises that really
require specific timing for implementing changes.
So all choose closed by default.
And there we go.
We now have our calendar.
So if I open up our change calendar while it's just a calendar,
which is exactly what it's supposed to be,
So this allows us to create events based on dates and times.
Four R A W s account.
So if I create an event here, let's call this prod patching.
We can specify the start date,
so let's just pick a random day here will do the 11th
and then we'll end on the 15th.
So we're going to allow patching throughout that business week.
Now, if we want, we can set this to recurring so we can set it weekly daily,
yearly, etcetera.
And then with that, we can actually go ahead and set until date,
or a number of occurrences specifically to what we want.
Now I'm gonna uncheck this I'm gonna create are scheduled event.
And just like that, we created our change calendar,
maintenance window or change period that can tie in to our
maintenance windows and other tasks.
So what we would have to do here is under details.
You'll see that we do have to add a required step for our automation purposes.
You'll see they provided here, and what we would do is add this to the document.
And again, we'll discuss documents a little bit later on in depth.
But what this does is it's gonna get that calendar
state whenever an automation runs.
It's going to see if the calendar is open or closed for that date,
and then it will either execute or break out and not execute all based
on our change calendar that we just defined here.
So right now,
if I executed something and we had this dependency on this change calendar,
it would not work because we're not in our open period that
we define here on the week of the 10th.
Now, one last feature here is we can actually share this with other accounts,
So if you have a master account for operations and administration.
You can set the calendar there and then share it out across your organ.
This really allows for better compliancy and management of your changes.
So to wrap this up really quick,
we created a maintenance window which defined a period of time where we
want to allow maintenance tasks to be enabled in work.
In that maintenance window, we registered our prod resource group targets.
Specifically E.
C.
Two instances.
We defined a change calendar where we specified a specific time where actions
can be performed and how we would tie this all together is we would add that
detailed dependency in our automation documents that we create and then when
they're executing with our maintenance window,
it would check the current state of our calendar.
That seems like a pretty good stopping point.
What we'll do is we'll wrap up here and then coming up next.
We're going to start diving into instances and nodes and we're going to explore these different capabilities in there