[Autogenerated] Okay,
let's dive into Shared resource is so now that we have all
of the other capabilities out of the way and we understand
them and how to use them, I want to talk about documents now.
Documents under shared resource is have been mentioned several times.
And that's because they are critical to how Systems Manager works.
All of these commands that we looked at run based on an S S M document.
And there are several different types there.
Session policy, run command, and even change calendar documents.
Now,
documents like we saw in the presentation can be
written in the amel or in Jason.
So it offers some flexibility and allows you to write
in whichever syntax you prefer.
Now, this is the default screen here, and you can see we have owned by Amazon.
That loads right away.
And what we're going to do here is I'm going to create
my own document to show how it works.
So what I did is I went ahead.
This is the default version that AWS provides us,
and this is that same create image automation that we
used previously in earlier clips.
It basically has us provide an instance,
I d a role, Ah, bullion for rebooting or not to reboot.
And then it creates an image.
So it creates an AM I based off the instance I d that we supply Now.
What I did is I made my own version building off of that,
and we added some more details,
So you can see we now have this AM I name section
that lives within this document.
It's optional, and we provide a default of parole site supersecret image.
Also, you'll notice under main steps right here.
I added a change calendar check for this document.
So the very first step it's going to check the change
calendar that we have in place.
And if the desired value is met, which is open,
it's going to go on to the next step and create this
image here similar to what we did before.
But if the change calendar state is actually closed, it's going to fail.
Now.
I just have a board on failure right here,
but in a normal use case, you'd want to more than likely,
go ahead and go to a different step that handles that resolution.
For the sake of this demo, to keep it a little bit shorter.
I just went ahead and chose aboard.
So what I want to do here is I'm gonna go ahead and copy all
this code and let's go up to create automation.
I'm gonna give my document a name,
and that brings us to the builder or editor selection.
So this is a newer feature.
S s M now allows us to use this builder section to build out essentially this
script in a friendly manner so you can see the assumed role,
the outputs, input parameters, etcetera.
Everything that we defined over here is in a nice and
pretty gooey that we can use if needed.
Now,
I do recommend that you always put your config files in some type of repository.
So my suggestion is to always figure out how to code it in Jason or Jahmal.
That way you conversion control.
What's being deployed now?
One Brill equal feature here is this mark down?
I'm not gonna go into death on mark down,
but this allows us to build in a description and you can
see the preview over here on the right.
That describes what this document is doing now What I want
to do is I'm gonna actually click editor.
And what this does is brings me to the document editor screen.
And when I click edit, it's gonna say, Hey, if you do this, you can't go back.
So I'm gonna click.
OK,
so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna get rid of all of this paste in my Jason
code that we had and I'm gonna click on Create Automation.
There you go.
Success.
So now if I goto owned by me, you'll see our document over here,
Secret Image Creator.
So we have our description.
The different steps that occur,
we can view the different versions under here and here.
We can look at the content of the document and we can look at
details now under details really quickly.
This is where you can share your document with other AWS accounts
so you can specify your account numbers here,
or you can just make it public for the general public to use.
So if you had a centralized account that hosted all
of your systems manager documents,
you could share it out to your organizational units
that belonged to your company.
So you have a central location to manage them.
Now, I'm gonna go ahead.
I'm gonna go back to description,
and I want to just load really quickly change calendar.
So let me open up a new tab, and I just want to show you what I've done.
I created this global Mantex ________ calendar and you'll
see at the top it's open by default.
So that means events can occur any time outside of our event.
Windows, remember?
And what I did is I created this little black out
period from today through Saturday.
So in theory, when I run this document, it should fail.
So let's just go ahead and try it.
I'm gonna goto execute automation.
It brings us to our automation screen that we've seen before.
I'm gonna go ahead and fill out these values really quickly.
I'll go down the execute and there we go.
So now what I'll do is I'll pause this clip and let this run,
and then when it's done, will resume, all right?
That was actually extremely fast.
You can see that we have an overall status of failed,
and it's our first step, which is our check calendar that failed.
So if I go into our step,
i d We can see our failure details and you can see it's saying,
Hey, the property value we got was closed and your desired output is open,
so we're gonna go ahead aboard like you specified.
So that's how we can look in deeper to the failure messages that SSN provides.
Now, if I go back to our change calendar,
let me go ahead and raise this ________ period.
So now we should be open to do things.
I'm gonna go back toe automation and I'm gonna redo that automation task.
I'll fill out the same values and let's click execute.
So once again, I'll pause really quickly.
And once this is complete, we'll pick back up and start talking about it.
Alright, Awesome.
So you can see we've had success on both steps and if I goto outputs,
you can see we created a new image and it's available.
So if I go to a m eyes which I opened up in the meantime,
you can see our brand new image that we just created.
So this automation document that we created work,
so that's how you can create your own document in order
to run commands in systems manager.
Now, one last thing really quickly.
I want to show you how we can make different versions.
So if I go in here, I can goto actions, and I can create a new version.
So if I goto editor, let me edit and accept,
and I want to go over here and I created an additional Jason
file that has an additional parameter in it,
and I'm gonna click on create new version.
All right, so now if I goto owned by me secret image creator,
you can see our default version is one.
But we have a 2nd 1 that we can choose to make Number
two our second version to fall.
I goto actions and set a new default version I
would select to and then click set.
And there we go.
So now if I go back in, you can see the default version is too.
And the difference here is I added a am I description
that we can populate as a parameter.
Everything else is the same.
So that's how you conversion control within AWS to a certain degree.
Your different documents that you use for automation purposes
Let's go ahead and wrap up this clip here, we'll have a quick module wrap up and then we'll move on.