Or not in today's lecture we're going to be going over texture now texture is very important for creating
realistic artwork and even nonrealistic artwork texture is what makes her artwork look interesting.
So once you get down the fundamentals such as shape and form value and contrast Well then you need to
add another layer of some interesting detail on there to really make your artwork pop.
So today we're going to be going over how to create texture.
The first type of texture you can create is with contouring lines.
So I'm going to quickly draw four circles like so and these are actually going to be spheres.
And what we're going to do with them is we're going to add some conjuring line texture to it.
So how do you do that.
Well let's start with this first one.
So the way I'm going to add in that texture is just like so it's going to be a fur texture and so on
I to do is I'm going to add in some contouring lines in the shape of my fur and some really randomise
knit some of them are a little bit curvier but they're just very short simple lines that give the idea
that this sphere has some fur texture.
You'll also notice that my fur up here at the top is a lot flatter than down here.
Down here it's almost hanging because of gravity.
Now we can go ahead and add in some more fur texturing on the inside of our sphere.
Just like so.
So now that looks like fur even though there's no highlights or shadows but it still gives us the idea
that there's further.
Let's try another one.
So the second one we're going to make sort of a chipped away rock type of texture.
So I'm going to start by creating the outline contour line of my sphere and it's going to be a little
bit rocky and jagged.
Rather than being a perfect sphere.
Like so next I'm going go ahead and start adding in that texture.
So I'm going to do is a master of making some geometrical forms mostly trap a woods and a rectangular
type shapes and maybe a triangle or two in there but I'm just going to start connecting these to create
the texture of sort of a chipped away type of rock texture.
Now as we get towards the edge of our shape these shapes are going to be a lot thinner because they
are curving around or object.
And so you're going to see them in perspective.
And then as they start to come around towards the middle they're going to get a little bit wider.
Perfect So now we have a really cool texture on that.
Let's try another one.
So the next one we're going to do is going to be sort of a holy type asteroid type of a rock.
So let's start with the outside contouring line.
So first off I want to add in some holes on the outside of my rock and these holes look like ovals because
they're on the very edge of them.
And so if I take a circle and turn it sideways you're going to see an oval because of that perspective.
So let's go ahead and start sketching that in.
So we want a very rocky Jagadish type of feel to the outside contouring it line.
Sync so and then we can go ahead and start adding some whole textures in there.
Ruthe perfect.
So now we have that really cool type of asteroid rock texture on that sphere.
Now let's try one more.
This last one is going to be sort of a rock texture that's nice and cracked and has a couple of little
small dots and holes in it.
So first off I'm going to add in those cracks.
Now you want to keep in mind that these cracks are being projected onto this round surface.
So you need to take that into account when you're drawing your crack so you'll see this one right here
kind of comes around in a curve.
Although it can still be a little bit random just because it is a crack.
Right.
Great.
Now let's go ahead and draw our outside countering line.
I mean they have these overlap just a little bit because I think it makes it look interesting.
So you'll see I kind of created a little edge at each one of these cracks and then we can go ahead and
add in some more texture and thereby drawing some really white holes in the spots.
And sometimes texture is just as simple as that.
Just adding little dots and spots onto your object to really break it up.
Sometimes when I'm doing a portrait drawing I like to add little spots and dots in random places in
my background just to add some extra texture to my background.
It just makes it look really nice.
All right.
Perfect.
So now we've created four different textures by using contouring lines now to really make your textures
look realistic.
You need to be using highlights and shadows.
So now we're going to start working with highlights and shadows to create texture.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create a fur ball like we did before but this time we're
going to use highlights and shadows to make that look a lot more realistic.
So first off I'm going to go ahead create my circle like so next I'm going to go ahead and add in my
shadow and I don't want it to be too dark.
I just want to start a base shadow in there and then we'll go ahead and have the rest of the shuttle
and when we add in the fir.
So now we're ready to start adding in her fur.
So the way we're going to add an R for is we want to make sure we first have a nice chirp in pencil
and then we're going to go ahead and start at the top.
And like I said before because of gravity it's going to be pulling our hair down.
So this hair is going to be gone sideways as we get to this point.
It's going to be going diagonally and by how we get down to this bottom it's just going to be hanging
straight down.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So what we want to do is we just want to start adding in random lines like so coming off of our ball.
And remember to keep those angles in mind because of that gravity.
That's really what's going to make your fur look real is how it hangs.
And then the light and shadow
we've got to start off by getting the outside of our ball
some curved ones in there we can add some straight ones.
We want to make it look really random.
The more random the more realistic it will look.
And up here we can have a few that are sticking straight off and more at an angle.
But for the most part want him to be hanging down because of gravity.
And then we can go ahead and start adding more to this inside area.
So go ahead and start adding more random lines and you'll see creating this texture is really just as
simple as adding in simple lines.
Now up here I'm trying to keep my lines a little bit lighter.
And as I get into the shadow area I want to start darkening those lines.
So once I start getting over here on the surface making it darker
and that way we can start introducing the shadow and highlight to our firm.
Next what we want to do is I want to start adding some overlapping shower or some cast shadow coming
from some of these pieces of hair.
So I'm going to start lumping them into kind of large groups of hair so certain that like for example
right here we're going to go ahead and start adding some darker shadow and underneath the hair like
so.
And then that slowly going to fade off into the fur underneath it and we go ahead and start adding that
throughout our entire sketch.
Great.
So no we just created a realistic texture which was for texture by using the highlights and shadows
as well as our contouring lines.
Thanks for watching and I really look forward to seeing you in tomorrow's lecture.