All right in this lecture we're going to be learning how to draw the human form.
Now the first thing you need to do if you want to draw the human form is you need to find some reference
and then you need to study that before we can get into how to break it down into separate shapes you
need at least have a very basic understanding of what the human form is made out of.
And the only way you can do that is by actually looking at photographs or still lifes of real people
and drawing them.
So in this lecture we're going to be drawing some photographs of some female forms and some male forms.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So looking at my reference right now and the first thing I always like to do is I always like to do
a really rough quick sketch that takes about 30 seconds.
So I don't want to spend a lot of time on it.
I just want to really quick put down those lines and try to get the best representation of my pose as
I can get.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So go ahead and start by drawing the torso.
I'm just trying to draw exactly what I see and this doesn't have to be perfect.
You're just trying to quickly get down that pose so you can start to understand it.
And then after we do this one we're going to go ahead and jump in and do some more advanced stuff and
spend a lot more time studying the pose.
All right.
Great.
So now I have a very basic rough sketch of my pose what I'm going to do now is I'm going to spend a
lot more time doing my second sketch.
So it's going to be the same exact pose from the same photograph except this time I'm going to spend
a lot more time studying the photograph and making sure that I get it looking correct.
So let's go ahead and start doing it.
Some paying attention to which direction each line is going whether it's a little bit horizontal or
if it's completely horizontal or a little bit vertical or or diagonal you really want to pay attention
to the angles and make sure that you're getting them all down exactly as you see them all the information
you need is right there in your reference.
So go ahead and use it.
Now this lady is a little bit off.
So many go ahead in every set and move it over a little bit because in my reference image this is actually
a little bit more towards the side.
So when you go ahead and fix that now
all right great.
Now I didn't really do very much explaining with this because there's not really much to explain.
It's just like do any still life you're just going to copy the post exactly as you see it and try to
copy it as best as possible.
I know it's going to be really difficult because drawing human form can be very difficult.
But don't worry in the next few lectures we're going to go into a little bit more explanation of how
the human body works and how to draw the pose and break it up into simple shapes.
But for now you need to have a really good understanding of all the parts of the body.
So like each part of the arm the torso the chest the pelvis the legs.
You need to really start to study that and understand how it's working.
Now the reason why we did this really quick rough sketch was to basically warmer selves up.
So it's just like when you're working out before you start lifting weights you want to warm up so you
can lift more.
And so by doing a really quick rough sketch of our pose before we did the second one that warms us up
to draw something really good.
And you'll be able to do a lot better work if you warm up first.
Now let's go ahead and try one more of these.
But this time it's going to be a sketch of a male figure.
All right.
Great.
So now we've done two sketches of a female form animal form.
Now if any of you're are really skilled at drawing the human form you can probably already tell that
these are not perfect.
And the reason why is because I haven't actually laid out my structure and so I've just been drawing
these straight off of my reference image without actually drawn any shapes or structure making sure
that I have the correct proportions in the next lecture.
We're going to go ahead and learn how to break the human form up into simple shapes that we can then
replicate to draw really quick and accurate forms.
Thanks for watching this lecture and I really look forward to seeing you in the next one.
Your assignment for this lecture is to draw at least one human form from a photograph and then go ahead
and post that to the Q&amp;A section of the Course or the Facebook group.