All right in this lecture we're going to go over values.
So what are values.
Well values are just how light or dark the color is.
And it's based off of this spectrum right here or this value chart.
So it goes from black all the way up to white and so and then everything in between is just a blend
between those colors.
So this black right here and this white right here if you mix them together you get the center color
right here.
And then if you were to mix the center color with this black color you would get the center color right
there and it goes on and on.
Now this is broken up into 11 different values but really the value spectrum is infinite heir's there's
values in between each one of these values.
And so basically you use these different values to create different lights and shadows and shading.
Now let's have a look at some examples of values.
So here I have a black white photograph of these shoes hanging from a telephone wire.
And what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and use my eyedropper tool which is a tool that
allows me to select any color I want in my image and it will show me what the color is right over here
in this little box.
So I'm going to go ahead and use this to find each value in my picture and then I'm going to try to
match that value with my value appear as I do this.
I want you to guess also.
So let's start with this color right here.
It appears to be white.
So let's go ahead and then switch over to her brush tool and try paint the on or white and it's just
barely a little bit darker than white but pretty darn close so it probably would go somewhere in between
these two right there.
Now let's try another color so I'm going to select this gray right here and then I want Guess which
one it is.
So I'm going to guess that this is a mid-tone gray.
And I was way off.
So it's very good to test this and practice with trying to figure out what values are what.
But another thing to understand is that depending on what value is next to another value that will change
how dark or how light it looks.
So this doesn't look so dark because it's next to a darker gray So this green right here this one that
looks like almost white is actually probably more of our mid-tone gray so I would put it right there.
And I was correct.
So now it's re selected this color here.
And I would say this one is goes with that one.
Pretty darn close.
Let's try another one so this darker gray down here.
I'm going to guess that it's not black but I would guess that it is.
Square there and that's wrong.
It's this darker one.
And so it's kind of fun but it's also really useful to do this and test out how well you see value in
images.
It's also a really good way to see how values play off of each other because like I showed you over
here this almost looks like a white.
But it turns out that it's this light gray right there.
Let's try one more value on here.
So I'm going to go ahead and I'm going to select this value right here and then I'm gonna go ahead and
try to find this.
I'm going to guess that that's my middle gray and I was correct on that one.
Now I don't think there's actually any black in this image right here.
Let's try another image.
So right here we have an image of a building.
And I'm not even sure if there's any black on this.
If there were any black it would probably be this down here in this window.
Let's go ahead try painting with that.
And it is black.
All right.
Let's try another color so let's try this right here.
So this may appear black but it might actually just be a dark gray and it's not.
It's somewhere in between.
So it's dark gray but it's not completely black.
Let's try another color so let's try this one right here and we'll try to paint you with that I think.
Did it go right there pretty darn close.
Try another one.
So we grab this gray right there.
I'm going to guess that it's with this guy.
Now let's try one more.
So this over here appears to be a really like great but I'm going to guess that it's not as light as
you think it is.
I would probably put it somewhere around here and it is closer to this one.
So it's our middle grade.
So it's really important to start studying values and things and I know it can be kind of hard when
you're looking at things in color but if you're able to find some black and white photos I want you
to study those photos and try to figure out what values are being used in that photo.
And if you can test it out in Photoshop that would be even better.
OK let's go ahead and hop back over to our paper and pencil and try some stuff out with values.
All right.
Now what I want to do is I want to go over how to create values with your pencil.
So we had to look at them in Photoshop but now how do you create that with your pencil.
Well it all has to do with the pressure that you push on your pencil.
And so right now we're going to practice creating that pressure to create whatever value we want.
So what I'm going to do first is I'm going to draw a rectangle like so and then when I want to do is
I want to create my own value spectrum within this rectangle.
But we're not going to break it down into separate sections like we saw in Photoshop.
We just want to do one gradual gradient from our darkest color all the way up to white.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So basically we just want to start by pushing pretty hard down here and then we want to slowly get softer
as we get up to this other side.
And you really have to be paying attention to about where you are on your rectangle and you have to
pay attention to how hard you're pushing because when you get back right about here in the middle you
want to tap your mid-tone And as you get in over here you want the middle tone between this mid-tone
and white and then it's the same on this side.
When you get to about the middle here you want it to be basically the mid-tone between this dark color
and the mid-tone.
Now even this still isn't looking perfect so we can continue to keep shading it in until we get it looking
correct because we want it to be as even as possible.
And even down here needs to be a lot darker something.
Push harder now.
I think that looks much better.
So now we have a nice gradual gradient from our darkest color all the way to our lightest color or value.
So I want you to practice this so that way you can get really good control of your pencil.
And now what I want to do is I want to go over a drawing a sphere again but we're going to break down
the different values within that sphere.
So let's go ahead and start withdrawing our circle.
So those are circle.
Now let's have a light source coming from over here and then let's go ahead and start adding in our
shadows.
So I'm going to add in my shadows about here and then we want to make sure that we're using cross contouring
So we're going along with the form of the shape.
All right.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and add in our poor shadow on top of that.
So I could show there
the Maleev in that bounce light right there on the edge.
And if you don't remember bounce light it's just the light that's being bounced off of the surface that
your ball is sitting on.
So now let's go ahead and add in a contouring line around this just so we can see your ball a little
bit better.
Yourselves a little bit off of that's all right.
You know we can go ahead and add in our cast shows or cash it is going to be about there and then we'll
go ahead and fill that in
just like so.
All right.
Perfect.
Now let's have a look at this and figure out what type of values we have going on here.
So first off we have our highlight and in this case our highlight is our want and in other cases your
highlight might be a little bit darker than light but your highlight is always going to be the brightest
value on the spectrum.
Next we have our Mathilde's.
So this mid-tone right here is basically this mid-tone right here in the middle.
But as it fades from the mid-tone to the white we get some of these other values in here that are between
these two values then our next value is going to be our core shadow which generally is the darkest value
or close to the Dervis value.
In every case your shadows are not going to be completely black.
Sometimes they're a really light gray.
And then once we get to that core shadow next is the bounce light the bounce light is sort of a mid-tone
gray but it's a little bit darker.
And so we want to come a little bit more to the sides or mid-tone great somewhere in there.
And then next is our cast shadow and our cast shadow pretty well matches this foreshadow.
So it starts out as a dark black and then as we get to the end it fades into more of a mid-tone grain.
So what I wanted to do is I want you to start viewing things not only as geometrical shapes and forms
but now I want you to start viewing things in their values.
So when you look at an object I want you to start thinking about what's the value of the object.
For example this blue pencil even though it's blue it has a darker value than this white paper and you
can tell because if you squint your eyes and look at this image the blue pencil in the white paper they
definitely send out and there's a lot of contrast between them because of the difference in value.
There's all other types of objects such as a pink eraser.
The black area in the pink eraser is a lot darker than the pink part.
And so the pink has a lighter value than this black area.
So definitely start looking at things in that way and it'll really start changing the way you create
artwork.
All right that brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture you learn about contrast and the contrast spectrum and how it goes from black all
the way up to white.
And there's every single value in between.
So don't forget that value is one of the most important parts when it comes to drawing.
That gives you your highlights and shadows and it also gives you contrast with contrast artwork would
not look very good.
And in the next few lectures we're going to get more to contrast and how it works and why it makes things
look so good.