Aren't in this lecture I'm going to show you how to draw an actual well rendered image with perspective
because up to this point we've only been drawing really simple shapes and unrealistic houses and buildings.
But I want to show you how to actually draw a realistic drawing that is well rendered has lights and
shadows and has a lot of detail in it.
So let's go ahead and get started.
The first thing I've done here is I've created my 60 percent mark.
So if you remember the last lecture we went over how you want to stay within 60 percent of the space
between your two vanishing points.
Now I'm creating the 60 percent mark vertically.
And so now that I had that marked off I know within what space I want to create my image.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to create the basic shape for my building.
Now I'm not sure what type building this is going to be yet.
I just want to figure out where I want that building to be.
And I accidentally drew this to the wrong point and drew it to my 60 percent point.
And so I need to erase this and I need to fix that so it's going to mine.
Vanishing Point.
So make sure you're always double checking that you're going to the correct point.
Now adding in my vertical lines for the edges of my building.
Next I'm going to go ahead and draw in two vertical lines and then I'm going to draw in a horizontal
line across here and now I have the base for my doorway.
And then I can start adding in perspective lines to create a ledge on that doorway.
I have to add this bottom ledge so great.
So now I have my doorway and it's nice and indented next I want to add a circle window above my door.
And so what I need to do is I first need to create a square shape and perspective and then like we did
before earlier.
And a court in a lecture.
We're going to go ahead and create the X through our square and then we're going to create the plus
sign through it so we can find where that diamond shape is.
And now we can go ahead and draw that diamond shape.
And I'm actually going to skip the diamond shape part because for me I'm able to just see about where
my circle should be and I can just sketch that in really quickly.
Next.
Let's go ahead and add a bottom edge to that door and a crack in the door so that it's a two door door.
Next I'm going to go ahead and add the lines for sort of a cylinder type tower and now I'm going to
find the center of this square.
The reason why I'm doing that is because I want to create a peaked roof and I want that piece to be
right in the center of my wall.
So now that I know where that center is I can make a point on my center line and connect that back to
each corner of my cube.
And now we have a peat roof.
Next I need to finish up the top of that roof by adding in that line back to my vanishing point.
And now I'm going to start marking about where I want.
The windows on the side of my building to be.
Now these windows are going to have arches.
But for now we're just going to create the rectangle part of them
and notice that I'm drawing my lines really lightly so I can come back any race them later cause a lot
of these are guidelines and they're not the final product line that I need to create a square shape
across these windows because we're going to make them arch.
And so we need to find where that square is to make those circles that I'm going to go ahead and add
the other crossing line so we can find those centers.
And then we can go ahead and draw a vertical line comes straight up through the center of that and then
we're going to come to our vanishing point and draw a line that goes straight through the center of
all the rest of these.
And now we can go ahead and sketch in those rounded corners to get our arch nominal leave out the bottom
arch because we just want the top part of the circle and so we can leave out that bottom part.
Next I'm going to go ahead and create a ledge for an edge for our door or windows so that they look
like they're actually indented into the building.
Now going to go ahead and create the rounded edge for my tower because I want it to be cylindrical so
I'm first going to create a square up here in perspective that's at the top of my tower.
And then I'll go ahead and put the X through it so I can figure out where that circle is in perspective.
And then I'll go ahead and sketch that circle in
there I'm going to go ahead and put a dome on top of that and I'm going to go ahead and create the other
side of my edge for my wall on the inside of my window.
And then I can go ahead and find the bottom of that by placing my ruler to the vanishing point and then
connecting them and then I just want to find about where that ledges there so I can easily sketch in
the inside of the curve.
So
all right and then it's important to really think about your drawing and what you want to do next.
So I took a little bit of time to stare at it for a while and figure out what I wanted to do next and
what I decided is I want to add some flower boxes here on the side of the building.
So going to go ahead and sketch in some very simple cubes.
And once again I sketch to the wrong point so I need to erase that then I'll come back to the right
point.
So these come all the way back to your vanishing point and then I'll go ahead and get the top side of
that
and then I'll go ahead and create the top surface of my box and then I want to break this up into two
separate pieces because I don't just want one long continuous flower box I want multiple ones and I'll
go ahead and connect to the bottom edge and I always make sure that you're leading back to a point.
All right.
And once again I'm sitting and thinking trying to figure out what I want to do next.
Make sure you do that takes some time.
So I decided that I'm going to add a ledge in this box and then I can add some plants on top of it.
So at this point I basically have all of my perspective laid out and now it's time to start sketching
in some detail.
You always want to start with what's in front first because if you start with what's in back you don't
necessarily know what's going to be in front of it that you might have to end up doing a lot of erasing.
And so that's why I'm starting with these planter boxes first so that then I don't have to come back
and embrace things that I accidentally drew where I wanted my plants
and I'll go ahead and do this back one
I'm going to go ahead and add in a tree there.
And with the tree I don't even have to worry about perspective.
I can just draw a tree in
I'm going to go ahead and erase away some of these lines.
Next.
Now go ahead and start darkening in these lines so they become much more solidified.
And make sure you only solidify the lines that you are sure you want to keep.
If you're not sure leave them light until you know later that you want them or you don't want them because
if you darken them it's going to be really hard to come back and erase them
I'm going to go ahead and darken in the circle and then add in a second circle with this one because
this circle is going to also be indented like the doorway.
And then I'm going to go ahead and add in a window with criss crossing boards.
Next I'm going to go ahead and darken my door.
Get this bottom part of the door and then I want to Durkan that crack in the door and I can Durkan all
of these lines because I know I want to keep these and notice that I'm not going all the way up I'm
stopping right at the beginning of that circle because the line won't continue after that.
It's going to curve into that circle.
Then I can go ahead and Durkan in those circles.
So
great then I get to go ahead and Durkan these lines.
Then lastly Durkan in this line right here.
Next I'm going to go ahead and solidify the lines down here at the bottom of the windows and then I'm
going go ahead and solidify the lines at the bottom of the wall and notice that I'm skipping where the
windows are because I'm going to erase those guidelines.
And I'll go ahead and solidify the cylinder and then solidify that dome and even add some detail on
it.
Now what I want to do next is I want to go ahead and add a center line down the middle of my windows
so I can break them up into separate pins.
Then I get to go ahead and draw lines across my windows like so.
And this will be the horizontal dividing panes.
So I'm trying to keep them as evenly spaced as possible and also notice that I'm coming back to my vanishing
point to create these lines.
You always want your lines that are going horizontally to always be going back to a vanishing point.
Right.
Great.
Now lastly I'm going to add a little bit of some detail on the ground just some random lines that are
that are in perspective.
That way it helps us see the perspective on the floor and it will also help guide me later when I want
to lay down bricks and rocks and stuff on the ground.
All right that brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture we drew a entire building and some planter boxes next to it and we made sure that
we were following the 60 percent rule.
And we also wanted to really think about how our building was shaped and make sure that it was actually
shaped like a real building and not a really exaggerated building.
In the next lecture we're going to go ahead and add more detail to this and also light and shadow and
turn into a more realistic drawing.
Thanks for watching and I really look forward to seeing you in the next lecture.