All right.
Welcome to the Part 2 lecture of creating our perspective drawing.
Now let's go ahead and get started.
So the first thing I'm going to do in the second part is I'm going to create a light source soon to
go ahead and put a dot appear.
And that's going to be where my light is coming from.
So now I know where I want to put my chateaus So this side of my building is going to have my core shadow
and the other side of my building is going to have the mid-tone shadows.
I'm just going to fill that in now.
It's important to try to keep your shading as even as possible.
And I know it's really hard to keep it even.
And a lot of times you're not going to be able to make it perfect and that's fine.
Just try to keep it as even as possible.
Sometimes this might mean that you have to go over it with multiple layers.
It's always important to start with your biggest things first.
When you start drawing anything or shading things in.
So always start with your biggest shapes your biggest surfaces that you have to shade in and then move
down to smaller Do tell.
So now we're adding in our mid-tone chateau and noticed that I'm avoiding everything on that side except
for that one surface so that if I need to I can come back in and add different values to those.
I'm going to go ahead and add my core shadow which will then fade into my mid-tone shadow on that rounded
cylinder
and I'm going to go ahead and add in my shadow on this edge since it's on that side of my perspective.
Go ahead and Durkan in that window just a little bit.
And now we can go ahead and add my shadow to this side of my wall.
Since it's also on the side that has my core shadow on it then I'll no shade in this top area.
And you notice the top area is a little bit lighter than my sidewall.
The reason for that is because it's getting bounce light and we'll go over what downslide is later.
For now all I need to understand is that that's bounce light and that's why it's brighter.
Now I'm going ahead and adding in my mid-tone shadow onto this side of my wall and then go ahead and
shade in that top area since it's going to be a little bit darker because it's curving in to the other
side of my wall.
Then I'm going to go ahead and Durcan this bottom area.
This isn't any type of shadow.
This is just the actual value of that part of my building.
Now I to go ahead and darken in that window and just make sure that everything is in nice and even then
go ahead and Durkan in my roof because that's also the value of my roof.
I go ahead and you racists and appreciated because I want to keep the top area a little bit light.
And then I'm just going to add a little bit of detail in there.
The shading in this box over here.
So the side gets the mid-tone and then same with this other box.
And then the other side gets the darker core châteaux.
When I go ahead and grab another pencil and fill that an even better
I'm going to add a little bit of a cast shadow coming from underneath this white part of my box.
And here in a second we're going to go ahead and extend that out.
But for now we're just going to add in that shadow.
And so you'll see it here are racing out these edges of that white part of my box so I can push that
out just a little bit further.
So it looks more like a ledge.
Now I'm going to add that same drop shadow on the other side too.
Administer add in some shadow into my plants now so this side of my plants is going to get a lot more
châteaux than my other side because the other side is going to be getting hit by the light.
So I'm only adding shadow to the left side of my plant.
I'm mean the dirt and the whole.
I want the values of my life used to be darker when I go back in there and add some darker detail just
so it stands out more elsewhen adds some shadow underneath the plant.
And then when I redraw that contrie line so it stands out even more.
Then I'm going to go ahead and Durkan these lines just so they stand out more also.
And now we can start working on our tree.
So I'm just darkening in that trunk.
And then I'm going go ahead and add some shadow to the bulk of my leaves.
And just like any type of drawing it's always important to work the whole image at the same time so
you don't want to overwork one area.
You want to work it for a while and then move on to another part.
So you'll see me switch back and forth between different parts of the drawing throughout the day drawing
great here.
I switched back over to my boxes.
Now I want to start putting in a little bit of a lighter value on my floor because I don't want it to
be completely white and now Minister adding some detail onto my door so I'm just freehand in the perspective
and trying to follow about where that perspective line would be for each one of these little squares
on the door.
And then add some shadow edges to that
and I just want to darken that door just a little bit more.
So important to go over everything again if things start to become less defined.
You want to go back and define them.
Then I'm just going to add a little bit of detail around this window so it's not just a circle window
but it has maybe some pain around the circle.
I'm going to do the same thing for the roof line just out of line across that roof line just to get
a look make it look a little bit more interesting.
Now I'm going to go ahead and start adding in my cast shadows so I'm drawing a very light line from
each top corner of my drawing of my house.
And I'm trying to stay away from drawing it through the house.
I just want to draw at the other end where I need to see those lines.
And then I'm going to go ahead and find where that light source is on my horizon line and then draw
my crossing lines which connect with each corner of my building.
And so I'm trying to figure out where that peak is going to be.
So I draw a line through that bottom corner and then I need to go ahead and draw a line through my other
corner.
So there's my other point.
And then I need to go ahead and draw my third point.
And my third point I'm actually just going to have to guess where it is because it's the point for the
peak of my roof.
And so I'm just about guessing where that is but I'm also deciding that it's just going to fade out
by the time we get to that point where you see that peak.
And so I'm not even going to worry about it.
I'm just going to go ahead and start adding in my cast shadow.
And like I said that cash out it was going to slowly fade out as it gets to the other side.
And since this box is in the way the cash flow is actually going to be cast over it.
And so that's why the cash is coming up like it is onto the box
I'll continue to fill that in
then I need to go ahead and create the cash for this box here.
And I don't need to create it from any other box because it's covered by the shadow of the building
already.
So I only have to worry about this box at sticking it out over the edge of that cast shadow.
So then I'll figure out where each one of those points are and I might go ahead and fill that in with
the same cast shadow and it'll slowly blend into my other cat shadow
and sense that boxes in the show too.
I went ahead and darken the whole wide area of it.
To start erasing some of these lines these guidelines that I no longer need.
And then I'm just going to go ahead and start adding a little bit of detail on to my ground.
So we added in a few extra perspective lines on the ground.
So that way we can them we can see where that perspective is.
And so now we can go ahead and lightly sketch in sort of some bricks or rocks on the ground and they'll
be in the correct perspective.
So as long as we're about following those lines that are criss crossing we should be good and it will
help create more of a ground plane for drawing.
Next I'm going go ahead and add a little bit of detail in the background so some small little houses.
And just like we learned before in the course everything in the background is going to be a lot smaller
because it's far away.
So we're creating space and we're also making it really light.
So we're using the value technique to create that space.
And we're also only adding very minimal detail.
So you kind of get the idea that there are some houses with some chimneys and doors but we don't really
go into great detail because we're trying to create that illusion of space.
I mean go ahead and do the same thing on the other side.
So just very simple shape kind of like a house and then go ahead and add in some clouds in there.
And I'm using the side of my pencil to create this effect where I can create a nice shadow and then
create the edge of my cloud and then go ahead and Durkan in my sky just a little bit.
And it's going to make a gradient into my white I'll do the same thing on the other side.
So that will slowly turn into a white.
All right.
And now I went ahead and I cut off all the areas that were outside of my 60 percent square.
And I also cut off a little bit of the bottom to create more of a composition for my drawing.
And so now that brings us to the end of this drawing.
So in this drawing you were able to see how I created an entire building and the landscape around it
just by using the things we've learned up to this point which is values lights and shadows contrast
perspective and using shapes to create a finished drawing.
I really hope that you learn something from this lecture by watching me draw this picture.
And I look forward to seeing you in the next lecture.
Thanks for watching.