All right in this lecture we're going to go ahead and create a landscape image using the knowledge we
learn about shapes and how to put them together.
So first off I'm going to be using a blue pencil to create this under drawing and then I'm going to
switch over to a darker pencil to do more of my detail work and to solidify the image.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to draw a horizontal line across my page.
Now this line is going to be my horizon line and it's OK if you don't know what a horizon line is.
We'll learn more about that later but for now we're just going to put that horizon line in there.
Next I'm going to start adding in my mountains so my mountains are just going to be simple triangles
like we saw in our breakdown of that one image and it's all added on right there in there.
And then I'll add a smaller one over here and you can really add in the mountains where ever you like.
Next I'm going to add in a rectangle here and this rectangle is going to represent a tower that's going
to be in my landscape.
But for now the basic shape for that tower is just a rectangle.
We're just trying to get the composition laid out and all those basic shapes.
Next I'm going to add in an oval and then I'll add in the second Oval.
Or they can be called ellipses and these are going to be a lake.
So for now the simple shape for them is just going to be a circle in perspective.
Next I'm going to start adding detail to this and turning these shapes into more organic shapes.
So I'll start by first adding a little bit more of movement to the edges of these lines and I'm going
to add a edge to this mountain also.
And I'll add a little bit more detail to that edge.
So we just want to start making these look a lot more organic and less like geometrical shapes.
Now I'm going to add an edge to this mountain as well.
And might add some more organic shapes to that.
Now we can move on to our tower so the tower is just going to taper off towards the top and then add
a nice rounded edge here at the top we will be sort of a platform.
And then on top of that platform I want to add in a sphere.
So I'm going to draw a circle up there next.
Let's move on to the lake.
So now I want to connect these two ovals together to make the shape of my lake.
Now we want to add in the reflections into the lake.
So what I'm doing is I'm copying the image of my tower in my mountains so that they're mirrored underneath
my horizon line and then whatever appears inside of my lake.
That's what I'm going to go in and it darkens.
Everything else is going to stay really light.
We don't really want to see that but anything that's inside of the lake can go ahead and Durkan that
so that I to add an edge on the mountain and then I'll add and darken edges of my tower perfect
now I'm going to start using my darker pencil and I'll go in there and start adding in a lot more detail.
So I'm just going to darken in a lot of these edges.
I can darken the edge of my mountain so it's going to have two different planes.
We go in there and add some shadows to it it's going to make it look a lot more realistic.
And this edge right here
and really the key to making things organic is kind of giving them a random sort of a shape.
So you want to make it look as random as possible and try to stay away from patterns.
Now I'm out here on the horizon line.
I'm going to add in sort of some grass lines just to break it up so it's not such a hard edged line.
I'm going to go ahead and do that all the way across my horizon line.
If you wanted to you could also add some trees to the horizon line you could add some bushes or some
larger plants.
But for now just keep things simple.
I'm just going to add in this grass.
All right.
Next let's go ahead and move onto this tower.
So I'm just going to start targeting these edges.
I might go ahead and add that detail to my sphere and I think I'll soon add two points to the top of
here.
It'll kind of be sort of Lord Of The Rings type of Tower.
Then I'll add a tiny little door down here at the bottom and then I'll add some windows at the top as
you can see they're just extremely simple shapes.
You don't have to get too detailed with it to get the idea across.
Now let's go ahead and move on to our lake.
So we want to darken in the edge of our lake so we know where that edge is.
So this is our contouring line.
Next we're going to go ahead and add in those reflections.
So go ahead and darken the edge of that tower and remember it's only going to be what's within the shape
of our lake.
Anything outside of that shape.
We're going to leave out
great Next what we want to do is we want to start adding in some cross country lines to add more detail
and realism to this.
So Mr. appear at the top of my mountain and as you can see I'm adding the straight contour lines that
are showing the surface planes of my mountain.
And so depending on what direction my cross-country lines are going that's kind of telling you where
that plane is in perspective
an art onto this mountain
then I can add a little bit more detail over here.
So add a little bit of crosscountry there and a little bit here will break this piece of the mountain
up also also perfect.
Now let's add some cross contouring to our tower.
So since this is a round cylinder tower we're going to go ahead and add it like so so it has a nice
curve in there.
And then we're going to go ahead and add that into our refl..
Now we also want to add the cross contouring into the reflection of our mountain
next.
Let's go ahead and add in sort of a darker gradient in our sky.
This is just going to make our background look a little bit more interesting and you'll see here in
a second we're going to add this into our reflection in our water and it's going to make a reflection
look a lot more realistic and you'll see why in a second.
So now we can go ahead and add that into the reflection of our water
so we're going to add that in like so.
And what this does is it makes her legs stand out a lot more from the grassy plain area of already drawn.
All right.
That brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture you learn how to apply the things we learned about shapes and how to put them together
to build up an entire image.
I really hope enjoyed this tutorial and you learn something from it.
And I really look forward to seeing you in the next lecture.
Thanks for watching.