A wrapped in this lecture we're going to go over contouring lines even further.
So like a said observation is one of the most important person when it comes to drawing.
You need to learn to observe things.
Now we're going to draw my book from life.
But the thing is that most people make a mistake on is they usually look at their drawing too much and
they don't look at the object enough.
You should be spending more time looking at the object than you do looking at your drawing.
You need to be studying every tiny little thing.
So for example me grab my booth.
You'll see right here we have this corner and then we have the single right now.
If I were drawing it if I spent all my time looking at my drawing and 10 percent of the time looking
at this angle I'd probably get the incorrect angle.
But by looking at this angle over and over again and then looking at my drawing for a little while and
then looking back at this angle and studying it and trying to figure out what angle that is I'll be
able to draw that a lot better.
Same with everything else on the spool.
So you want to spend most of your time looking at the object and hardly any time looking at your artwork.
Trust me this sounds counterintuitive but believe me this will make your art look way better.
The more you start observing from real life.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So with this I'm going to spend about 50 percent of my time looking at my drawing and about 50 percent
of the time looking at my boot.
So I'm going to go ahead and start drawing.
Now this is not going to be an endless line contouring drawing.
I just want to actually draw the lines in the shapes that I see in my boots there.
So I'm going to do as I'm just going to look at my boots and then I'm going to draw the line that I
see.
So that's the outer edge of my boot on the sole of my boot at least.
Here's the bottom part of my boot.
There's that so comes over like so.
So for example I wanna make sure that I get the sheet correct so I'm spending a lot of time looking
at my boot.
But then as I draw this line I want to make sure that I'm looking at my drawing.
That way I create that the correct thickness of the sole of my boot.
Otherwise it's going to look off and even right here I sort of look away.
And that's why it's off.
So I'm going to take my eraser and I'm going to go ahead and erase that
and then I'm going to go out and sort of redraw that in
like so and then I can finish the sole my boot and I can work on the next shape that I see which is
this back part of the boot which kind of curves up like so.
And then I can start on the tip of the boot or the toe of the boot.
And then I also kind of see the shape right here.
And I also see sheep like sell them that kind of curves around like that and this back area is a little
off so I want to go ahead and erase that
now pressing a little bit hard with my pencils.
So you want to make sure that if you want to race you're not pressing too hard you can always go back
and press harder.
So going to redraw this.
It's not so curved.
And then we'll have a little bit more area for the foot to fit into that boot.
And then I'm also seeing sort of the shape right here for the bill.
My boot and that's basically the basic shape that I've seen for my boot.
Now we can go a little bit further and add some more detail.
So if I wanted to I can end this back area and add more of a curve there and then I can also add in
this back piece I can add more of this loop that I have on the back of my boot.
They use for pulling your boots on.
Let's see if we can add in each individual little hole.
Now the point of this is not to drive perfect drawing.
It's to try to get the lines as perfect as possible when it comes to resembling the lines on your actual
object.
And so then we can even add in those shoelaces.
So there's one shoe lace coming over like so.
And there's another one coming up like so.
And another one come over like so.
And while I'm drawing this I'm really paying attention to everything about this and paying attention
to which shoe lace goes over what shoe lace.
So like over here for example this shoe lace is going to be underneath this shoe lace.
So I'm gonna leave that area out and then I can go ahead and get that one in and I can add that one
in.
And I'm also paying attention to how the shoe laces are curvy and so as we get up here to the top we're
going to get a little bit more of a curve.
And I missed the shoelace hole but we're going to get a little bit more of a curve.
So it's going to curve more up like so.
Same with the other side.
So we're going to get more curve toward shoelace just like so and then we can also go ahead and add
in those stitches and we see them making sure that I had the same exact curve that my shoe has.
And then I can even go a little bit further and add some of the wrinkling that I see on the top area
of the boot.
And so I'm kind of seeing a wrinkle here.
So now even on life these lines don't appear.
It's good.
So for you to draw them any ways that we start to get familiar with observing objects.
That brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture we learn how to draw conjuring lines and we also learned that we need to spend most
of our time observing the object that we're trying to draw.
Now eventually you're going to be drawn out of your head but until you understand how real life works
and how real objects and real light works you're not going to be able to draw them.
So you need to make sure that you're studying from life objects and you need to learn how to observe
those in great detail.
So spend most of your time observing those objects and spend less time actually looking at your drawing.
You're watching this lecture and I really look forward to seeing you in the next one.