Art in today's lecture we're going to create a drawing using one point perspective.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So if you remember from yesterday what you need to do first is you need to create your horizon line.
So we're going to put our horizon line a little bit more towards the bottom of our page.
So not quite all the way at the bottom but a little bit past the middle.
So let's go ahead and create that line.
Remember you want to keep it pretty light.
Next let's go ahead and decide where one point is going to be.
So I'm going to put it off to this side this time.
Next let's go ahead and decide what we want our picture to be.
So I'm thinking that we want it to be a farm.
So let's go ahead and start drawing our farm.
So the first thing you need to have on your farm is you need to have a barn.
So I'm going to draw that barn in right now.
So we start off by drawing the front face of our barn so barn tends to be shaped like a square and then
we have sort of half a hexagon on top.
Like so and then we can go ahead and solidify that shape by drawing it in even darker.
And if you want you can use your ruler to do this.
Next we want to go ahead and add in our vanishing point lines.
So we're going to draw one from each corner.
Remember to keep these really light so that you can erase them.
And then this one is basically the horizon line itself.
So we don't actually have to draw a line for that next.
Let's go ahead and let's add in the other edge of our barn.
So we'll draw that line right there and then we'll draw this one right here.
Perfect.
Then we can go ahead and solidify these lines like so that we want to go ahead and erase away machine
point lines.
The next thing you might have at a barn or a farm is a road.
So let's go ahead and create a road going along the side of our barn.
So what we're going to do is we basically just create one vanishing point line like so and then we create
another one like so.
And now we have a road we can go ahead and add detail to this if we want so we can add stuff like grass
to the side of our road.
So there might be some grassing you know over the edge
and the further away it gets.
But remember the last detail we're going to have.
And so that grass texture is going to slowly dissipate.
And then this road is probably going to be a dirt road so we can go ahead and sort of a dirt type of
texture to us.
So I'm just going to draw in some lines like so and these might be tire marks
and the further down they go they're going to start to disappear.
Smith over here will do the same thing so sort of creating some tire marks in the dirt.
And then we can go ahead and add in some rocks in there too.
So we might have some tiny little rocks on our road
and the further away they get they're going to get smaller until you finally can't even see them anymore.
All right.
Perfect next.
Let's go ahead and actually add some more detail to this barn.
So first off I'm going to go ahead and add in a door so I'm just going to draw a rectangle like so and
then the barn doors usually tend to have a frame around them.
Then they usually have an axe going through.
So to go ahead and draw in those x clinks
Ixo.
And then there's usually a loft up here at the top.
I want to go ahead and draw that waft in.
So I'm just going to draw a window like so and then I can add the shutters onto that and I'm going to
add in two diagonal pieces of wood like so on the bottom pieces for my shutters.
And then I can go ahead and fill in this window with a Durka value since it's looking into a dark barn.
Perfect.
Next I'm going to go ahead and add in some windows on this side of my barn.
Now since it's in perspective we're going to do something a little bit different.
So first off we need to draw our vanishing point lines for the bottom and the top of our windows.
So then we need to decide where windows are going to be.
So we're in have two windows on the side so the first one is going to go right here.
So we draw two vertical lines like so and then we can go ahead and feel that in the next window is going
to be next to it except the thing with this window is it's going to get a little bit skinnier because
it's further away.
So we're going to go ahead and add that in like so as you can see I've made that one a little bit thinner
than the one next to it and it would continue to do this all the way back to the vanishing point.
So if we had another window next to that it would get even thinner.
Or it's next let's go ahead and add in a fence to our barn.
So I'm going to go ahead and draw one of my vanishing point lines like so now will be the bottom of
my fence and then I'll drive the next one over.
Like sir.
Now this is going to be a wooden fence.
And so it's going to be made out of slots of wood.
So my first lots of wood are going to be vertical and they're going to be about that far apart.
Now for the next little while they're going to appear like they're the same distance apart and eyeball
this as best you can.
But the closer towards the vanishing point we get the closer they're going to get
sooner.
Notice here that they are very very slightly getting closer together.
And then as we get to the other side of a barn so back behind this barn they're getting closer together.
And then when we get to here they're going to be really close together and I'm just going to drive it
in by hand.
They're going to get to the point where you can't even see them anymore.
So there's a fence.
Now let's also go ahead and add in perhaps.
So a lot of farms have house so the farmer can live there.
And so we're going to start off by drawing the bottom vanishing point line for House and then we'll
add the top per So and this house is going to be a little bit closer to the camera.
So let's go ahead and add in that one right there and then we can create the side view of our barn or
house.
Sorry.
So there's a side view of her house.
Then we can go ahead and add this edge in next to what we want to do is we want to add a roof on this
house.
So I get to go ahead and draw a roof shape like so.
And then we also want to add a roof for porch so I'm going to have another shape coming off like this
and we're going to have that on the other side too for this edge.
Then we can go ahead and connect the top of our roof.
So and then we can go ahead and connect these two lines.
So we have the edge of our roof for a porch.
Great.
Now let's go ahead and solidify those lines so go ahead and Durkan all of these lines in much more
power.
Next we need to go ahead and add in some posts that are holding up this porch.
So what we need to do first is we need to find where the bottom of those lines is going to be.
So we're going to come down from each corner like so that will come down from this corner also.
And then we need to connect this line with that one or there's Go ahead and use our ruler to connect
that just like so.
So now we know that's the point where we need to connect this all the way back to our vanishing point.
So let's go ahead and connect that back
so now we know where this point is for the bottom of our other post also.
So now we can go ahead and draw those posts.
We'll go ahead and use my ruler to draw those.
And a lot more darker and then all added this side of the post.
Can also add in the other side of the post.
Now we're going to want to go ahead and erase away this line that's behind the post.
So it looks like a solid object.
Go and draw those lines back in.
Then let's go ahead and do this post also.
So we'll go ahead and we'll draw this line in.
And in this case we're actually only going to see this sign.
All right great.
Now really quick.
Let's go ahead and add in a window on this side of our barn.
And then let's go ahead and add a door on the front of our house.
So we need to go ahead and draw a vertical line like so.
And then we need to take that vertical line back to our vanishing point so we get the top part of our
door.
And then we need to go ahead and draw a vertical line coming down from that point mixer.
So now have a door.
And if we wanted to we could even add an edge to that door by coming in horizontally like that and coming
up vertically and then connecting this like so.
And now we have a door there we can even put a door handle on that.
All right.
So now we just drawn a picture using one perspective and we can go ahead and erase away all these vanishing
point lines because we don't need them anymore.
And our horizon line is really flat.
Usually your horizon line is not going to be flat like that in a drawing or when you look at things
in real life.
So what we can do is we can change that up by church changing the horizon line into more hills.
So I want to go ahead and draw out the shape that I want.
My horizon line to be so.
And then we can go ahead and erase away our straight horizon line.
All right.
So there is a one point perspective drop.
Now you can really take your time on this and spend hours on end you really should.
I just don't want to spend too much of your time each day doing these lectures.
And so I want to try to make this as quick as possible.
But this is the basic idea of drawing a picture with one perspective.
Now your assignment for today is to go ahead and draw a one point perspective drawing and it can be
whatever you want.
It can be a house it can be of a bus it can be of train tracks whatever you want.
Just try to incorporate onepoint perspective into Draw on your picture and then go ahead and take a
picture of that and posted to either the Kewney section of the Course or the Facebook group.
Thanks for watching this lecture and I really look forward to seeing you in tomorrow's lecture where
we're going to talk about two point perspective which is even way cooler than onepoint perspective.