All right in this lecture we're going to go over advanced form in 3D Shadowline and highlights for those
advanced forms.
So first off we're going to start off with the sheep that we created in a few years ago.
So it was sort of a squiggly plus sign.
So and then we had the edges come off and just quickly finish up the shape so we can start demonstrating
on it.
All right.
So there's sort of our organic sheet that is foreign to it.
But how do we add highlights and shadows to this.
Well this is advanced because it's got some curves on it and it's also going to have some cast shadows
on it.
So first off we need to decide where our light source is coming from.
So let's say that our light source is coming from the top up here.
So it's going to be shining down in this direction.
So where are these highlights going to be.
Well we're going to get a highlight on this top edge right here.
Really a highlight on this top edge.
And as this curves under it's going to get more of a shadow.
But then it curves back and you get more of a highlight.
So that's why it's considered complicated.
We're also going to get a cast shadow being cast from this object right here this part of the shape
onto this bottom part down here.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So first let's start off with our core shadows are core shadows they're going to be on the opposite
side of our light source.
So that means it's going to be on these bottom edges of our sheep.
So let's go ahead and fill those in.
Mike so smooth over here
and then we also are going to get those core shadows over here.
All right.
Perfect.
Next we need to add in our other shadows.
So we've already kind of added in our mid-tone shadows here but we need to also add in a midterm shadow
right here because as this piece curves back underneath you're going to get a little bit of a shadow
there and then it's going to slowly fade back into highlight as you get to this surface here.
So we're going to have a little bit of a shadow there.
Perfect.
All right.
Now next what we want to do is sense the light source is at the top and kind of hitting it more from
this side.
We need to add a mid tone shadow to this surface right here.
And so we'll go ahead and we'll add that in
quit.
Now lastly we need to add in a cast shadow from this object right here.
So this is going to be casting a shadow down onto this so let's add the edge of that shadow.
And then we can go ahead and fill in that area like so.
And now that has a nice cast a shadow on it.
Now lastly let's add the cast shadow on tour surface and because this is a lot more complicated and
it's kind of sitting on its edge.
It's going to be relatively complicated but it's ok we can go ahead and added it anyways.
So this is going to be getting a cast shadow coming from this side.
So it's going to be coming off like so then that's going to kind of come around like that and you're
just going to basically get a mimic shape of your shape here.
And as it comes off we don't even have to worry about the shape any more too much because it's going
to fade away.
So let's go ahead and fill that in with our cast shadow value.
Just like so.
All right.
Great.
Now let's have a look at another type of and advanced highlights and shadows so let's say you that we
have sort of an organic shape something like this.
Kate now that just looks like a flat shape.
But by adding highlights and shadows to it you can actually make it a three dimensional form.
So let's decide where are light source is going to be coming from.
Let's have it coming from over here and it's going to be coming in this direction from the switch over
to a sharpened pencil.
So first what we want to do is we want to go ahead and add in there the core shadow on the side that
we needed on.
So since the highlight is over here the shuttle is going to be on the opposite side of that.
So we're going to get core shadow along this edge
as well as along this edge.
Also get some rain here also get a little tiny bit right there and then we'll get a little bit right
here also because all of this is on the opposite side of our light source.
Let's go ahead and add in our mid-tone.
So on a lightly sketch sketching that mid-tone there
and even these edges are going to get a little bit of mid-tone
write cool.
So now we just added some form to that sheet.
So it stands out as a lot more realistic now.
We can also go at it and add in that cast shadows so the cash is going to be cast off like this.
Now in this case the cash out it was so short that I didn't really have time to make it go from dirt
to light so I kept the whole thing dark.
But now you can see we just added some three dimension to this flash shape just by adding some highlights
and shadows to it.
Now highlights and shadows get even more complicated than this.
So let's say that we were doing Iraq.
So let's go ahead and draw sort of a random shape like so.
And then let's decide where our light source is coming from.
So let's say our light source is coming from this side again and it's coming in that direction.
Well now it's a little bit more complicated because there's going to be all kinds of faces and different
angles in here.
So first off what we want to do is we want to start off with the basic form of our rock so we know that
the highlight is going to be hitting the top area.
So we need to decide where this top area surface is so the top area surface is going to be something
like so and then everything over here is going to be filled in with a mid-tone chateau where you can
probably darken out a little bit more.
All right great.
So now that that's filled in with mid term shadow we need to decide where our surfaces are going to
be that are on the opposite side of this as well we know for sure that this rock is going around as
it gets underneath the bottom of the rock.
And so that's definitely on the opposite side of the light source so we can add in some darker shadow
I mean on this bottom area
then let's not forget to blend that into our mid-tone.
All right.
Perfect.
But now what if we wanted to add kind of more texture in there.
Will you do that by using highlights and shadows so let's say we wanted sort of a hole in a rock.
Well what we can do is we can go ahead and add in some of our core shadow and then that would around
underneath like so and now we got kind of the illusion that there's a hole in this rock today and we
can also go ahead and add and some other things such as a crack so we can put a crack along here and
then as it gets into this highlight area it's going to get lighter and not be so dark.
So and we can also do other things like use or CCRI undercuts.
So if I add in more of a dirt shadow like this and it fades in like that.
Now I get a lot more of a look of an undercut my rock and I can add all sorts of stuff like this into
my rock to start playing more with the form of the rock.
And then up in this highlight area we can even add some more form by adding some of the mid tone color
to create some of the same text from but basically any time you have shadows it's just creating form
and shadows are just created from a lack of light.
Cool.
Now let's try one more advanced type of form so let's say we want to do a format made out of a couple
of different shapes.
So let's say our form is made out of a cube.
So let's create a cube first first
and then let's say on top of that cube we have a cylinder.
So going to go ahead and draw a cylinder
and then let's say on the cylinder or in this cylinder actually is a sphere that's partially stuck in
the cylinder so we're going to draw a sphere right there.
Now we're going to go ahead and finish drawing this item out.
Now as we get over here it gets a little bit tricky we need to figure out how that sphere connects into
our cylinder.
So it's basically going to come around like this.
That'll come down like so.
So now it looks like that sphere is actually stuck inside of our cylinder and I can go ahead and erase
away any unwanted areas like that.
So how does the highly shatter look on this form.
Well let's first off figure out where or like source is coming from so we're going to have coming from
up here at this angle.
So we know we're going to get a highlight right here on our ball so let's go ahead and add the pilot
in first off.
So we're going to go ahead and fill in this rounded area.
We had of course Chateau
the next thing we know is that this ball or sphere is going to be creating a cast shadow onto our cylinder.
So we need to go ahead and create that cast shadow.
So it's going to be the cache that it was basically going to be the same shape as a ball.
It's just going to be stretched out.
And also it has to be applied to this form right here.
So cast shadows are definitely applied to the form of an object that is being cast on.
And so since this is a rounded object this is also going to get stretched and rounded around the edge
of this like so
so then we can go ahead and fill in that cash shadow which is slowly going to fade out as it gets to
the other side.
So and then we can go ahead and erase the way that wine a little bit because I got it too dark.
All right then we can go ahead and add a little bit of Chateau up here at the top because that's also
going to be getting hit by the cast shadow.
And let's go ahead and Durkan these lines up so we can see the form a little bit better.
Perfect.
Next let's add the highlights and shadows to our cylinders.
So even though we have this cash out of here we're still going to be more highlight and shadow on this.
So down here we know that this side of the cylinder is going to be the highlight edge because the light
is coming from this side and then this side is going to be our shadow.
And so we can go ahead and add in our core shadow which is slowly going to turn into our mid-tone and
then into our highlife like so then we know that this cylinder is going to be casting a cast shadow
on the to this top surface of our cube.
So let's go ahead and add that in.
So the lights coming from this side.
So we're going to go ahead and add in that cache shadow like so then we'll go ahead and fill that in.
Switch over to more Shervin pencil.
Perfect and it's not going to go over this edge because this edge is just going to turn into a shadow
anyways so we'll leave it like so and then we know this top surface of the cube it's going to be the
highlight outside of our cube.
And then we know this side is going to be our mid-tone so we can go ahead and fill that in with our
mid-tone color.
Now that I'm looking at this I'm actually thinking that this needs have a little bit more of a tone
around it.
So let's go ahead and finish filling in and then decide it needs to be filled in with our core highlights
since it's on the opposite side of this lightsource.
So let's go ahead and fill that in.
Right.
Perfect.
Now the last thing we need to do is we need to go ahead and add in a cast shadow from this whole entire
object down here.
So first let's start off with the cube.
So this light is coming off from that direction.
So you need to go ahead and add in that cash shadow like so now we're going to get the cash out of the
cube and then on top of that we're going to get the cylinder.
And by the time he gets all the way to this this fear we're not going to see it any more because the
cash out will fade off.
So let's go ahead and add that now.
All right.
Perfect.
So now we just went over four different advanced types of highlight and shadowing for form.
They should be given you a pretty good idea of how to highlight and shadow advanced forms.
Most things in life are actually going to be pretty advanced and they're not going to be as simple as
a cube or a cylinder but they're going to have a lot more advanced things to it such as this piece right
here.
Now your assignment for this lecture is to go ahead and find some random objects in your house.
So say a shoe like we did before or anything else you can find that's more advanced and has a lot of
different areas where there can be highlights and shadows.
And then I want you to shine a light on that and then draw that from life.
Once you've done that go ahead and take that image and post it to the Q and A section of the course
or post it to the Facebook group.
I really hope you enjoyed this lecture and I look forward to seeing you in the next one.
Or we're going to look into how forum is used and created in the human face.