All right in this lecture we're going to go ahead and draw a picture using two point perspective.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So the first thing we want to do as always is create a horizon line.
Now I'm going to create my horizon in line more towards the top so we're looking down at our image or
object.
So don't go ahead and lightly draw it in and then I'm going to put my two vanishing points one at this
end and one at this.
And then we can go ahead and get drawn.
So in this image I think what I want to draw is a house and then maybe going to draw street next to
it and a building.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So the first thing I want to do is I want to draw my vertical line for the corner of my house.
And then I'm going to go ahead and draw in my get a little bit taller actually
and then I want to go ahead and draw a line from my vanishing point to that corner.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Remember to draw very lightly until you know exactly where you want everything to be and then you can
go at it and draw those lines in Dogar.
I will go ahead and do it from this vanishing point to this corner.
All right.
Great.
So now we have part of her house.
Let's go ahead and create the edges of her house so create one line right here.
So that'll create the other line over here like so next let's go ahead and create the roof for our house.
So this house is going to have a very simple roof.
I'm just going to make a diagonal roof.
So all I have to do is basically extend this line right here up
like so.
And then I can go ahead and draw a line from this point down to that one.
And now that diagonal roof is incorrect perspective go ahead and do the same thing over here.
So first I want to go ahead and draw this line from this point to that point
and then just eyeballing it trying to copy that same exact diagonal angle I want to go ahead and try
to copy that over to this side.
So I'll go ahead and draw that in like that.
And then we can go ahead and add an overhang on this roof just by extending our lines a little bit further
and do the same thing on the other side.
And then I'm going to go ahead and connect these two lines by drawing a line from my vanishing point
all the way down to this corner edge of my roof.
Go ahead and connect that.
Perfect.
So now we have the roof of our house next to it we want to do is you want to add some doors and windows
to this house.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So first let's start with the door.
So the door is just going to start off as a straight up vertical line.
So go out and draw that in next to it we want to do is want to go ahead and draw from this point.
Back to our vanishing point.
So now we're going to go ahead and draw a vertical line coming straight down from there.
So then we want to have this sort of indenting into her house.
So we want to have a ledge on her.
So what we'll do is we'll connect this vanishing point to that corner right there.
We'll go ahead and draw that in for However deep we want our door to go in.
So we want to go about there and then I'll go ahead and draw a vertical line going straight up from
that point like so.
And then I want to go ahead and connect from this bottom corner to my vanishing point to create the
bottom edge for my door
just like the scenario of a door.
We can go ahead and add in the door knob on there if we wanted to know it's go ahead an ad in a window
on this side.
So going to go ahead and draw a line from my vanishing point to here.
So that's going to be the bottom of my window right there and then I'll go ahead and draw a vertical
line straight up.
But the top point from my window and I'll go ahead and draw a line coming from this point back to my
vanishing point and just eyeballing about where that is coming straight up from there is going to go
ahead and draw that line.
So no we want to add some crisscrossing pieces to our window.
So when they go out and add those and so out of one line coming across like so and then I can go ahead
and add in my vertical line.
So at about there.
Perfect.
Now what if we wanted to add a window on this side but we wanted it to be at the same exact level as
this one.
How do we know where that is on this plane.
Well the way we would do that is we'd go ahead and likely extend our line from the top of this window
to this corner.
And then we do the same thing with the bottom
and then from each one of those two points we connect it back to that vanishing point.
So connect out like so much do the same thing for this one.
So now we have the top and bottom points so that we have a window lined up on the same level as this
one.
So let's go ahead and draw the window in on this side.
So go ahead and start off by drawing my vertical line like so I'll draw my second vertical line race
here and then I'll go ahead and draw the middle one.
Now we can go ahead and solidify those bottom and top lines.
So know we can go ahead and add in our middle one just by starting from our vanishing point in coming
to about the middle.
And if we wanted to we could do the same thing again to get this lined up correctly we can go ahead
and draw a line from this vanishing point to this line and then bring that to this corner.
And then we'll do the same thing over here.
So we'll come from this vanishing point.
Back to that corner where that line is up.
Now we can go ahead and draw in our middle line on our window.
Like so.
All right.
Perfect.
Now let's add a chimney to this house also.
So the way we'll add in our chimney and I know this is really incorrect.
But just for demonstration purposes purposes we're going to add a chimney crack about this window.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to create a diagonal line a little bit further and from
this one.
So I'll add in a diagonal line about there and then we're going to add a line coming straight up off
of that.
So we want to have a vertical line coming off of that and that'll be the corner of the chimney.
And then what we want to do is we want to connect back to this vanishing point and then come back to
here like so and we want to eyeball it so we're about right above this line and we'll connect those
with a vertical line.
Let's go ahead and treat the other plane on this side.
So we have to do is connected that point back to a vanishing point.
So we don't have to finish the line all the way back to the vanishing point we can just make it shorter
because we know that we watch and read and write.
There are about there.
We'll go ahead and create a vertical line on this side and then we need to connect that point all the
way back to there.
So go ahead and connect that to that vanishing point.
So we can go ahead and Durgan in that line and then let's go ahead and create our top surface.
So we already kind of have a line right here for that edge because we already have a roof line lined
up with it.
And next what we want to do is we want to connect that vanishing point to this corner.
Like so and then we want to go ahead and create a hole in the top of our chimney.
So the way we're going to do that is we're going to go ahead and create a smaller square within this
square.
So we're going to connect this.
So we want it to be a little bit shorter so it doesn't touch the edge or that edge and we do the same
thing down here.
So connected right about here.
Whoops that was really off.
Sorry.
So let's try that again.
Want to come a little bit further and from this line we want to go ahead and connect a little bit further
and so we're connected to you about here should be good.
All right that works better.
Now we want to go ahead and connect from that vanishing point.
Back over here.
Like so will do the same thing on the bottom
you know I have sort of a smaller square on top of this larger square.
What I want to do next is we want to go ahead and draw a vertical line comes straight down from there.
And now that makes up here like it's a an actual hole.
All right.
So next let's go ahead and create a road or street for our house.
So we need to finish creating these bottom line so we need to solidify those will solidify the site
also.
And then we want to have a road coming straight down here right in front of our house.
So let's go ahead and create that.
So it's just like one point perspective we just come from this point come all the way down
like so and then we can do the same thing on this side
just like so.
And then if we want to add a ledge to this curve all we have to do is go ahead and draw a line coming
from our vanishing point.
But a little bit lower than our first line
just like so perfect then let's go ahead and add a corner to our occurred.
So we're going to bring this line come in over here.
Connecting it.
And we might want to come out a little bit further.
So maybe two out there we'll go ahead and connect those and we can just go ahead and draw that in by
hand.
Draw that went in by hand and then just go ahead and create the bottom line for her sake.
So and then we just added vertical line right there to add the corner ever occurred.
So now we have a sidewalk curb for our street.
Next let's go ahead and let's create a skyscraper over here.
So I'm going go ahead and draw a line coming off of my vanishing point over here.
Like so and I think I want to corner my skyscraper to be right there.
So now I'm going to go ahead and draw a vertical line coming up off of that
just like so all the way up into the sky.
And then I'm going to go ahead and connect my top edge.
Remember to draw lightly that way you can always come back and erase.
All right.
Now let's go ahead and connect these two vertical lines.
So we want this edge right there.
We'll put this edge right over here on this side and then we can go ahead and solidify all these top
and bottom line.
So my go ahead and put a line right there and I'll put a line right on the bottom edge.
So do the same thing for the top
just like that.
Then let's go ahead and add some windows onto our skyscraper.
So we're going to make this in a glass skyscraper.
So it's going to be very simple.
We're just going to put basically a grid system on a skyscraper.
So what we want to do is we want to go ahead and use a ruler and I'm using centimeters.
But whatever you want to use go ahead and use that unit of measurement.
What I'm going to go ahead and add a little mark every one centimeter
and then what I want to do is I want to go ahead and connect a line coming from each vanishing point
to each point on both sides.
So I'll go ahead and do that now.
So starting with this one I'm going to go ahead and speed this up because this might take a little while.
Right great.
Now we want to go ahead and add in the vertical lines for Windows.
So I'm going to skip every other on rectangle on here because we only want the windows on one little
area and then the next part is going to be the floor and all the air conditioning and stuff.
And so in real life you'd probably only have every other one of these being Windows so that's the way
we're going to do it.
So what we want to do is we want to create a vertical line coming down like so
them or to come over and we want it to be about the same space.
So at this point you are going to be that noticeable but the further down we get it's going to get smaller.
So I added another line like so
as we come over here we might have it become a little bit skinnier
and come down a little bit further and it gets a little tiny bit skinnier
and then we'll come down a little bit further.
That'll come down a little bit further.
And then let's go ahead and move onto this side.
Now I'm going to go ahead and speed this up so it goes a little bit quicker.
All right.
Great.
So now we have the windows on our building.
So now we've created a house and a building and a road into point perspective.
Now the last thing I want to do is I want to go ahead and break up my horizon line because like we said
before horizon lines generally aren't going to be completely flat and straight unless you're out in
the desert or on the salt flats.
So let's go ahead and add in a skyline of a city so City one I guess.
So let's go ahead and we're just going to draw some random sort of rectangles just to represent some
buildings out there we might even add a dome on one of them.
All right great.
So there is our city line.
Let's go ahead and erase away any of these lines that we don't want to see that we're just our guidelines.
All right.
Great.
So now we have our 2 point perspective drawing.
Now I wanted to do this demonstration drawn for you so you guys can understand how to point perspective
is incorporated into drawings of real life objects.
So your assignment for this lecture is to go ahead and draw your own two point perspective drawing.
If you want you can copy this one or you can draw your own of whatever type of building you want whatever
it is as long as it's square and cube.
Then once you do that I want you to go ahead and take a picture of it and post it to either the Q and
A section of the Course or the Facebook group.
Thanks for watching this lecture and I really look forward to seeing you in the next one where we're
going to draw a two point perspective drawing.
But we're going to incorporate all of our highlights and shadows and all those things that we've learned
about up to this point in the course.