Overlooked in this lecture we're going to go ahead and do one more example of using form to draw out
the base of our drawings.
So what we're going to be drawn in this lecture is the landscape and it's going up mountains and trees
and we want to break those down into simple geometric forms.
So let's go ahead and get started.
The first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to decide where my horizon line is now horizon line is
just the line between the sky and the earth.
So that's going to be my horizon line right there.
Next I need to decide where I want the mountains.
So I'm going to make my mountains sort of pyramid shapes so I'm going to make one right about here.
So and then I'll put a second one right next to it.
It's just like so that I'm going to put a shape over here that sort of connects into the shape and little
sister sort of be rounded cube type of shape so that has its top surface right there.
And then I'm going to add another surface behind this mountain.
You get a view of that plane right there.
All right cool.
Now let's go ahead and add the foreground so I'm going to go ahead and draw a line right about here
to represent my foreground and my actually slowed up a little bit on this site and then I'm want to
go ahead and add another mountain over here.
So go ahead and draw on the second pyramid.
Just like so.
All right.
Perfect.
So now we have the basic set up for our landscape drawing.
The next thing we want to do is we want to start adding in that detail.
So first off I'm going to decide where my light source is coming from.
So I want to put my light source coming from up here down in this direction.
So it's going to be hitting the surface and the surface as my highlights.
So I'm going to leave those bright white and then I'm go ahead and shade in the side areas with my mid-tone.
And in this case both of these are going to be my highlighted areas of this background.
And then with this when I can go ahead and shade this side with my midtown then also Let's go ahead
and add a tree in here.
So I think I want to have my tree in right here.
So let's go ahead and draw a cylinder like so and then I'm going to draw a sphere on top of that to
represent the leaves of my tree.
And then I can go ahead and shade that in
next I'm going to go ahead in work on the reflection of my mountains.
So this area right here is going to be a lake.
So I want to create a reflection of these forms.
So what I want to do is go ahead and just copy them but flip them upside down so I have that line going
from there to there.
And then this line would connect back here.
So I have it coming from there.
And this one would come down to about there.
So all of this would come from there to there.
So then I can go ahead and try this one.
I should have done this one first.
It was in front of that other one.
So there we go.
And then I'm going to go ahead and shoot in this area because you'll be able to see that visually behind
this reflection of the mountain.
All right.
Perfect.
So now we can go ahead and start adding in some detail.
So the first thing I want to do is I want to start adding some more detail to these mountains so I might
add some more rigidly edges to my mountains.
On this one might even come more out like so.
And this might get some.
The sky might be received a little bit
and definitely get some reshaping.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and switch over to our dark pencil and now we can go ahead and start adding in some
real detail.
So starting with my background mountain I'm going to search this guy.
So first I just want to draw out the outline of my mountain.
It doesn't get down to the bottom.
It's not just going to be a straight line.
It's going to be a little bit more of a shape to the bottom here.
And then this edge here of the mountain is also not going to be a straight line will be some more to
that shape than just that straight line.
So it might be a little bit more bent and skew aka's.
And then we can go ahead and shade in that area and we'll come back and add a little bit more detail
to this texturing on the mountain.
So it's not just one solid form with two planes.
Let's go ahead and move on to our next mountain.
So we'll draw out the contouring line so this mountain
you can draw this.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and
create that bottom line of our mountain so that we can go ahead and add ins or shading on the side.
Perfect.
Now let's move on to this back area.
So I want to draw this a little bit lighter just because the further away things get in real life the
lighter they become.
So I don't hold that line to be too dark.
And then I'll move onto this guy here.
So this guy needs to be a lot more of a organic ex-chief.
Otherwise it's just going to look like a big one up the hill.
So I want to go ahead and sort of ADD and some rocky sort of a sheep to that
thought.
Perfect.
Now let's go ahead and add in are other mountain over here.
So draw this country line
and we'll have this Erich's year.
It's then we want to add this edge of our For around.
And I think I want it to be made out of grass.
Some of.
Go ahead and add on sort of grassy going to that.
All right perfect.
Now I want to move on to this story.
Someone to go ahead and start with the trunk of the tree.
So you have a basic cylinder here but we can go ahead and add some roots to that to make a look a lot
more realistic.
And then I'm going to go ahead and add my leaves and so my leaves are just going to be one big basic
sort of a geometrical form but a little bit more organic.
But I don't want to do every individual leaf because I'll take too long.
So there's my truth.
Now let's go ahead and add in this country line on this mountain.
Go ahead and shoot that in
this.
Let's go ahead and ask who shading on those trees.
So since a light source is coming down from here we're going to get some cast shadow shadow We're going
to get some mid-tone colors on this side.
So let's go ahead and shake that in
as this tree curves around we're going to see just a little bit of that foreshadow some moment of really
dirt some of these just over here on the side
next.
Let's go ahead and decide where are cast shadows are going to be.
So if the lights come from the side.
First off there's going to be a cache showing cast by this book of the leaves onto our trunk.
So let's go ahead and add that in.
So probably going to be cast down to about there.
So and then the whole tree itself is going to be cast and shadow off in this direction.
So let's go out and add that.
So basically we just want to draw the tree shape coming off in this direction.
So so and then we can go ahead and fill that in with our cast show.
So you
the next let's move on to the trunk.
So if the lights come from this side we're going to get our core shadow on this side of the trunk and
that's going to slowly fade into our mid-tone and then into highlight.
Because it's a cylindrical type of shape.
Of a shadow this side of that route.
Perfect next.
Let's go ahead and move onto this mountain and add some more detail to it.
So if the light is coming from up here at the top we might have some undercuts in our mountains.
So for example right about here we might have a little bit darker shadow
I'll just start creating more of an interesting form for us in our rocky mountain.
Same for shear.
It's
know here on this side we might have some good times creating the same thing that we have over here.
So we might have a couple of undercuts.
Nonetheless go ahead and move on to these mountains going to grab a piece of paper to lay on top of
us.
So as I'm drawing I don't smudge it.
So this is a really good trick to know is if you don't want to smudge your drawings make sure you play
a piece of paper down or paper towel for your hand to rest on.
So let's go ahead and get started with this mountain.
I have a few hundred cuts in here.
And these small holes
and then this mountain sort of curves around it's going to get a little tiny bit of that core shadow
on the edge.
We can also sort of fade this mid-tone into this area.
Six months you go into this mountain
and we can move on to the Skydeck here and he's going to have very light detail because he's so far
away.
So like I said the further something is a way that lighter is going to be
session work and we can move on to this rocky plane right here.
And so the light is coming from the side but we might be getting some shadows on the other side of let's
say some of these rocks so if there's a rock right here we're probably going to be getting a shadow
on this side of that rock.
So we can just add in see stuff like that.
Now I'm not looking at any reference for this drawing I'm just drawing out of my head.
But if you were to be drawing a landscape like this let's say for a fantasy comic book or something
you'd really want to look at some reference so that you can really understand how rocks work.
I'm just doing this for demonstration purposes to show you how to create form and highlights and shadows
in a landscape by using geometrical shapes.
So for now this work fine.
Then as this piece curves around we're going to start seeing more of that mid-tone shadow.
All right.
Cool.
Now lastly I'm going to go ahead and add and this is reflection.
So I just want to copy the same shape that I've created here.
Whoops I just realized that I accidentally drew over this mountain so you want to make sure we erase
that.
You don't want to see that part of it.
We go up this mountain to be coming in front like so only that out then we can go ahead and copy these
reflections over
and then just to differentiate the difference between our highlight and our shadow government or go
ahead and add a dark edge along the bottom of our mountain.
So how did it just right there.
I'm going to add that all the way along the bottom and that's going to allow us to see the difference
between our reflection and the actual mountain itself.
Our options I think this looks pretty good now.
It can be a lot better.
And look way more realistic.
But like I said I just wanted to demonstrate to you how to take geometrical three dimensional forms
and use those to block out your images your landscapes your characters whatever it might be and then
build on top of that.
That brings us to the end of this lecture.
So your assignment for this lecture is to go outside and look at the landscape around you whether you're
in a city or you're in the mountains.
And I want you to go ahead and draw what you see.
Except I want you to draw it out of geometrical forms and then I don't want you to add any detail to
it just draw the geometrical forms and that's it because we're watching this lecture and I look forward
to seeing you in the next one.