All right in today's lecture we're going to be learning how to draw round objects in perspective.
Now this is very important if you want to draw more than just cubes in perspective.
So first we're going to do is we're going to have a look at this square right here.
Now this square represents the flat surface of one of the planes of let's say a box in 2D or in 2 point
perspective.
Well we need to figure out how to create around object within this that we can replicate even when the
square is warped into perspective.
So first of all we need to do is we need to draw an X through this.
So we're not drawn X from one corner to the other.
So one line like so and then we'll draw the other one like so.
And so what does this do.
Well this tells us where the exact center of our square is or if this was a rectangle and tell us exactly
where that center is so when you're in perspective let's say you're in perspective like so and that's
your plane.
Well you can still do the same thing.
You can draw a line from there and a line from there.
And now you know exactly where the middle of this plane is in perspective because this is going to be
wider than this part yet that's still the center.
So once we know where our center is we need to go ahead and draw a plus sign through this.
So basically we need to draw one vertical line through the center like so and then we need to draw one
horizontal line through the center
like so and so now what we can do is we can draw a diamond within this square.
So we're going to draw a line from this corner to that corner just like so and we want to do that all
the way around our box
or perfect So now we have a diamond.
The next thing we want to do is we want to go ahead and draw a circle within this square.
So the reason why we're doing this is because we're trying to see where that curvature is in comparison
to this straight line.
So a circle is going to basically come to about here.
And then it's going to curve back down to this point like.
So it will do the same thing right on over to this side and then we need to go ahead and do that all
the way around or circle
and this actually come out just a little bit more.
All right so there's our circle.
So basically by drawing this diagram we have a good understanding of how to recreate the circle on a
plane that's in perspective.
So what we want to do now is we want to apply this to a perspective drawing.
So we're going to start off by drawing our horizon line them we're going to go ahead and add in our
two points.
So I had one vanishing point there and another vanishing point right here.
Let's go ahead and draw
our vertical line like so and then I'm going to go ahead and connect this so I'm going to connect one
to that bottom point.
And I'm actually not going to have this talk.
I'm going to go ahead and only bring it to about there like so.
So none of that line really matters.
Don't just go ahead and connect these two.
And then I'm going to go ahead and erase this line since we actually don't need it that toll anymore.
And then we're not going to worry about making a top surface for this because you'll see why in a second
what we want to do is we want to create a circle on this plane perspective right here.
So let's go ahead and add in our edge to our cube.
And then what we're going to do is we're going to do the same pattern but on this face.
So first off we need to go ahead and draw an extra.
So when I draw a line from one corner to the opposite corner.
So now we'll do the same thing on the other corners.
Great.
So next we want to do is we want to go ahead and find where those vertical and horizontal lines are
that are in the center.
So first we'll draw a vertical line right down the middle like so.
So it crosses right through that middle point and then we want to find our middle line going horizontally.
And so what we'll do is we'll line up our ruler with this midpoint right here.
All the way out to our vanishing point then we can draw a line right through that like so.
So now we have our plus sign and or X next.
We want to go ahead and create our diamond.
So I'm just going to quickly do this by hand.
So I going to draw a line from there I'll draw another line from here to there and I'll draw another
line from here to there and I'll do this same thing with this last two points like so.
So now we've created this same pattern but in perspective the last thing we want to do is we want to
go ahead and draw and circle shape.
So we want to mimic this again so our circle comes to about the middle between this line and this corner.
So we want to do the same thing over here.
So we want to find out where that middle is and then we want to go ahead and draw a curve that comes
and matches up to that point and then comes the matches back up to this point here.
So then we'll do the same thing over here so we'll find the midpoint there.
And so this one is actually since it's in this perspective it's going to be a lot more stretched out
than this one.
So we'll go ahead and draw that one in
like so and then just go ahead and do the same thing for these bottom ones.
So we'll put a line right here in the middle we'll put another line right here in the middle also.
So this you'll see gets really squished because of the way the perspective is
normal normally this last one.
All right great.
Now this isn't perfect but if you wanted to spend more time making sure you got those curves perfectly
right it would look much better.
But for now this will work well enough.
So we have our basic circle shape in two point perspective.
Now if we wanted to create a cylinder All we'd have to do is draw a line coming off of this corner right
here.
Back to our vanishing point.
And the same thing for up here would draw from this top right here back toward vanishing point.
So let's go ahead and do that.
But before we do that let's go ahead and erase away all of these guidelines because we don't actually
need them any more.
All right.
So now let's go ahead and draw those two vanishing point line so we'll go from right here and we basically
want to line up with this line right here.
So at that point all the way back to our vanishing line and then we'll go ahead and do the same thing
from here to that top point like so now as we get to this edge of our cylinder the perspective on the
circle is going to change because it's in a different position.
So what you need to do is you need to basically do the same thing we just did here.
But down here.
So you're first going to draw your lines coming from this vanishing point.
But over to this area here you create a flat square surface and then you want to redraw your pattern
onto it and then Krieger's circle and whatever edge you get on this side of your circle that's going
to be the edge of the cylinder.
But for now I'm going to go ahead and eyeball it in about where it should be.
But for you you want to make sure that you redraw this that when you get the correct perspective.
So since it's further down it's going to be stretched out just a little bit more.
Like so Nemo go ahead and solidified that top and bottom line
right.
Perfect.
So now we have a cylinder and two point perspective.
Now where else might you want to draw a rounded edge.
Well let's say that you're drawing on a building that has arches.
And so you have your one point here and then you have your lines coming off like so and so here's your
flat surface and then let's say that you have arches going like this on that surface.
Well to figure out how those arches are going to curve you do the same exact thing.
You draw the same square right here and then you'd have to draw your X through it and then your plus
sign through it and then your diamond and then you would need to draw your circle around in that.
But there's all different types of places where you would need to use a round perspective in your drawing.
Let's also say for example that you're drawing a current perspective.
Well if you need to draw wheels on that car you're going to need to know how to do that in perspective.
And so knowing how to draw roundings in perspective is extremely useful.
That brings us to the end of this lecture.
So in this lecture you learn how to draw objects that are around in perspective.
So just remember that the way you draw around the object is first by finding the center of your object
then by drawing it drawing a diamond.
To use as a reference for your curve.
And then once you do that you want to apply that on to your surface area better in perspective.
And then you want to replicate that curved line in proportion to your reference line which is the diamond
lines.
Thanks for watching this lecture and I really look forward to seeing you in the next one.
Now if you have any questions about this.
I know that this can get kind of complicated.
Make sure you ask them in the Q and A section of the course.
Thanks for watching and I look forward to seeing you in the next lecture.