Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to learn about a security vulnerability related to cookies.
Remember, our application does indeed use cookies for session management.
The type of attack that we're going to learn about in this lesson is named a C SRF attack.
The Casares acronym stands for Cross Site Request Forgery.
Now, instead of trying to explain what that means with just words, let's instead look at an example
of a six R.F. attack.
So here I am logged into our application with my brat account.
And let's imagine that I am an innocent, normal regular user.
However, imagine I receive an email from someone who's targeting users of our application.
In other words, imagine one of your innocent users perhaps clicking on to a page that they should not
have clicked on to.
So in code pen, I've set up an example, malicious page.
So imagine this wasn't code pen and it was just a full screen, regular website without the code visible.
So the idea is that one of the innocent users of our application is now viewing a potentially malicious
website.
So this is on a domain that has nothing to do with our app or project.
So visually, it looks like a normal Web site.
But if you look at the HTML, it actually contains a form and the action is pointing towards our apps
create post route.
And then look, there are hidden input fields with the title and body names and look at the values.
Now, what's scary about the Web is there is nothing within the default behavior of Web browsers to
stop this from working.
As soon as this form is submitted due to the nature of cookies, this attack will be successful.
Now, the innocent user would not even need to necessarily click on the submit button.
Notice there's a bit of JavaScript that's going to select the form element and then tell it to submit
and this is going to run on page load.
Now, the only reason this attack did not already go through the millisecond I opened this malicious
page is because our local application is running on HTTP instead of https.
So this has nothing to do with a kharif attack.
This is just because code pen uses http s.
So my browser is not going to load any resources from HTTP.
Right.
But you can imagine that if our application was actually launched and public, clearly it's not going
to be localhost, it would be our app dot com or whatever our domain is.
And in that case it would probably be https.
Right.
In just a few lessons, we are going to learn how to push our application up to Heroku and at that point
it would indeed begin with https.
What I'm getting at is that in Google Chrome, as of this moment, the attack did not go through.
So we see this little icon up here and it says insecure content blocked.
This has nothing to do with the topic at hand of CSR attacks.
This is just because our local site is not using https to get around this.
I can click load unsafe scripts and as soon as I do that, our attack was successful.
Can see our application new post successfully created.
You have been hacked, and if I go back to the tab where I'm logged in with Brad and I go to my profile,
you can see the newest post created on my behalf.
Ha ha ha.
You have been hacked to see a cleaner example of this attack in this window.
I'm using Mozilla Firefox and you can see I'm logged in with my Bachs lot account.
Now, as of today, Firefox does not care if you load an HTTP resource from an resource.
So imagine if our poor, innocent Bachs, a lot users somehow ended up on the malicious page.
Notice that the attack just works immediately.
So poor Bachs a lot.
If I go back to their profile, they just had a ha ha you have been hacked post created on their behalf.
At this point, you probably have two questions.
Number one, how and why in the world is this super simple attack actually working?
And question number two, how can we adjust our application to protect ourselves or to prevent this
sort of thing from happening?
Let's start with question number one, which is how is something this simple, just a basic form submit?
How is this actually working?
Well, the answer is cookies.
The cookies are the culprit.
Cookies are to blame.
So when a user logs into our application, remember, we set up sessions and cookies.
So the server tells the browser to store a cookie with their session ID.
And then remember, the nature of cookies is that on every subsequent request for that domain.
So in this case, localhost in three thousand for every future request to that domain, the web browser
just automatically sends the cookie along with the request.
So back to this malicious page.
If I zoom in on the HTML, even though this code is not executing from this domain.
Right, we're currently on code pen.
That doesn't matter.
This is just a traditional HTML form and we are telling it to submit to this you url.
So our Web browser, Google Chrome or Mozilla Firefox, it sees this domain and it goes, aha, I have
a cookie associated with that domain.
I'm going to send the cookie along with this request.
Our server sees that that cookie is tied to a valid and current session ID because this Web browser
is indeed signed into our application.
So the request goes through.
Now the next question is, well, how in the world do we stop this from happening?
Right.
How can we adjust our app to protect ourselves from this sort of attack?
Well, to answer that, we need to learn a little bit more about what this attack can and cannot do.
So what it can do is send off traditional HTML form, submits to your apps, you URLs.
So worst case scenario, imagine our application was a bank website and they submitted a form request
to a U.
RL that ended in transfer money and then they had a hidden field with the name of transfer amount and
they set the value to nine billion trillion quadrillion dollars and they set the transfer to and then
they set the value to malicious person.
Smith So really this is all a CSS RF attack can do.
It's relying on the innocent user already being logged in to an existing application.
And then the malicious site just sends a request to a U.
RL that they know makes sense and where they know the names of the fields that the server is expecting.
So that's what a six hour R.F. attack can do.
Now, let's talk about what this type of attack cannot do.
So at no point can this type of attack actually see or access the application itself.
Right.
So thankfully, Web browsers do protect you on a tab to tab basis.
So any HTML and JavaScript in this tab cannot access the DOM or the HTML from this tab.
With this in mind, it becomes very easy to protect ourselves from a CSS RF attack.
So let's take our create post action as an example so our actual innocent real users can see this HTML
form right where they type in a title and body content.
But there's no way for the malicious page to read this HTML template, right.
The malicious code is just blindly sending off post requests.
A different Jarrell's, so to protect ourselves when the server sends this HTML template to the browser,
we could just send along a random string of characters and then set things up so that when this form
is submitted, in addition to a title and body content value, you must also provide that random string
of characters.
If you don't provide that random string of characters, we will reject this request.
Right, because we will know that it was not a normal, safe, valid request, because if you are actually
logged in and viewing our application, you should have no problem grabbing that random string of characters
that the server sent along.
But if your request is coming from a malicious cross site request, forgery attempt, well, you would
have no way of accessing that random string of characters.
In other words, the only thing the cookie with our matching session ID proves is that the request is
coming from a Web browser that has recently been logged in.
It does not prove that the user of said web browser actually wants to perform that request.
So that's the whole idea of our randomly generated string that we're going to require.
There's no way that an outside source could ever get access to it.
So as long as we are not allowing malicious JavaScript to actually run on our page itself, then the
random generated string proves that the current request is actually desired by the user.
OK, so now that we've covered the big picture of what a cross site request forgery attack is, let
me show you the easiest way to protect ourselves, right?
The easiest way to implement or require this randomly generated string idea I've been talking about.
Let me show you what I would do.
So within your text editor or I should say within your command line, we want to install a new package.
So if your server is already running press control, see to stop it and run this command with me, npm
install.
And the name of the package that we are interested in is C.
S U RF.
So it's a play on words or a play on sounds.
If you sound it out CSF, it would sound like Ceaser.
So npm install C CERV go ahead and press enter.
Once that finishes then we would just want to start running our app again.
So npm run watch.
All right, now let's go leverage that new package.
So within the root of your project, I want you to jump into app jacks up at the top.
Let's require in that new package.
So maybe right above the line where we say CONSED app equals and then we call Express.
Let's add a new line and let's say const.
You could make up any name you want, but I'm going to say C srf let that equal and then just require
in the package that was named C SIRF, you could name your variable C serve if you wanted to.
I just think if I review this code maybe a year or two from now, this name would make more sense to
me.
Now let's scroll down to the area where we are actually using our router.
So for me it's around line number forty eight.
So right above this line where we say app use forward slash router, let's add a new line above that
and let's say app dot use within the use parentheses.
Let's just call that new variable.
So C.
S RF parentheses to call it OK.
And now this will set things up so that any of our post put delete or any requests that modify state
will need to have a valid and matching CSS, RF token or else the request will be rejected and we'll
throw an error.
So right after this, let's set up a piece of middleware to make the RF token available from within
our HTML templates.
So I would just say app use within these use parentheses.
Let's provide a function, function parentheses, curly brackets within the parentheses for this function.
Be sure to include parameters of request response.
And next, OK, now within this function, let's say response dot locals dot and then you can make up
any name you want, but I'm going to name it C.
S RF token.
So this will contain that token value that I want to output into the HTML template.
So let's set it to equal request dot and then call the function from the package that will generate
that token.
So C.
S RF token parentheses to call it finally right below this line.
Be sure to.
All next, OK, now let's jump in to one of our HTML or Ejaz templates and actually leverage this property.
So let's save this file.
And then within your Views folder, I want you to jump into the file that is named Create Dash Post,
DOT, SJS.
OK, so we see a form element that is submitting a post request to slash create post.
Right.
And we have an input for the title and input for the body.
Well maybe right above the submit button.
Let's add a new line and let's add a hidden input.
So input element and let's give it an attribute of type that equals hidden and then let's give it a
name of a underscore C SRF.
Finally, let's give it a value.
And this is where we want to do something dynamic.
So drop in to SJS.
And remember, we just created that property in response to our locals that was named C.S. R.F. Token.
Now the name of this is very important.
It needs to be exactly underscore C SRF.
That's the name that the C serve package is going to be looking for.
Let's go ahead and save this and let me show you what it's doing for us.
So now back on the create post template, if we refresh that input that we just added is hidden, but
I want to show it to you visually.
So maybe if you.
Right.
Click on the body content field and choose inspect that will open your developer tools.
And then right below the divide, the text area lives within.
We should see an input type of hidden.
And here's the important part.
Look at its value.
This value is what's going to protect us from CSR if attacks.
There's no way for code from another browser tab to access this string of characters.
So by including this underscore our value in our request, we are proving to the sea serve package that
this is a valid, trustworthy request.
So let's do this.
Let's try to create a post.
So I will give it a title of innocent post and give it body content of this is a real post.
And then if we go ahead and submit.
Cool, you can see the post went through successfully and now let me go try the malicious code Penn
page and it should fail now.
So if I visit the malicious code pen, cool, we can see forbidden error, invalid CSS, RF token.
And just to confirm that that did not work.
If I go to my profile, you can see the newest post is Innocent Post.
There's not another copy of hahaha you have been hacked.
Now we wouldn't actually want to display an error message like this on the front end of our website.
We would want to handle the error in a more graceful fashion.
So maybe we could have a red flash error message that says cross site request forgery detected and redirect
the user back to the home page.
Let me show you how I would set that up.
So back in App Jass, let's scroll down a bit and maybe right before we begin with the concept server
and IO lines right above that, let's add a new line and let's say app dot use.
And within these parentheses, let's give it a function.
We're going to do something a little bit different from the parameters for this function instead of
giving it to parameters like request and response, and instead of giving it three parameters like request
response.
And next, we're actually going to give it four parameters.
So let's say Aarav for error and then request and response.
And next, within this function, let's write an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition, let's say if there is an error, then inside this
if statement, let's write another if statement.
And after that let's also add an else block to it for the condition.
Let's say this e r code if that and then double equals signed a check for equality if that equals and
then quotes E bad C srf token all capital.
So if the error is related to the CSF token not being a match, then let's do this, let's set a flash
message so requestor flash onto the errors collection.
Give it a second argument with the message.
Let's say cross site request forgery detected.
OK, then I would drop down and manually save session data.
So request session save was provide that an arrow function and then I would just redirect to the home
page show response redirect to forward slash.
OK, but else that means there's an error.
But the error had nothing to do with our CSS RF token logic.
In that case you could create a generic error template or I'm just going to render our 404 template.
So response render 404.
All right.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now if I tried the malicious code pend screen again, so if I force it to reload.
Perfect, it tried to perform its request, but it kicked me back to the home page and here we see the
red air message cross site request forgery detected.
This is great, but our work is not done yet because if I go back to the tab where I'm actually logged
in, yes, I was able to create a new post because we added the CSS RF token to our create post template.
However, if I try to do anything else, for example, even just signing out, you can see I'm not signed
out and we see cross site request forgery detected.
So in the next video, we just need to go through our application and anywhere where we are performing
a post request, we need to pass along that matching CSS RF token.
Don't worry, it should be a lot quicker than it might sound.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.