Hello, everyone, and welcome to the next chapter.
Let's take a quick look at where we are.
So we've learned the basics of the JavaScript language itself.
We've also learned the basics of how to use JavaScript in the Web browser environment.
And now our next step is to learn how to use JavaScript in a server environment.
But why?
So we need to ask ourselves a few questions.
What is a server and why do we want to use one?
Let's start with what is a server?
So when I visit Google dot com, my web browser sends off a request to the Google server and the Google
server sends back a response with the HTML to display this page.
Now, when I search for something, so if in the main Google field I search for JavaScript, my Web
browser sends off a request to the Google server with JavaScript as my search term, and then the Google
server sends back a response with the data needed to display these results.
So what is a server?
Well, my own oversimplified answer is that a server is the thing that we can talk to in order to send
and receive data.
As a user of an app or website, we can send requests to a server and then the server sends back a response.
For now, that's as deep as we need to go in terms of what is a server.
Now, let's move on to why we want or need a server.
I would say there are two main reasons.
No one is directly related to what a server is, right?
Communication.
Our app needs to be a good listener.
It needs to listen for incoming requests and then it can send back a response.
Or in other words, we need a way for our users to access our app.
And that's the case even if we're building the simplest website ever, even if it's just a simple brochure,
website that is literally just a headline that says hello.
Even in that case, we still need a server that visitors can connect to in order to view the page.
Even if that server is just serving up the file system and sending back statically created basic HTML
files, it's still a server that's listening for incoming requests.
OK, so that's reason number one for why we want a server.
Now, here's reason number two.
If we want to build something a bit more complex than just a static read only brochure type of website,
and we want to let our visitors actually perform actions instead of just viewing pages, we need a server
of some sort.
And the reason for this is because we cannot implicitly trust the Web browser or incoming requests.
Let me explain why.
And also just sort of what I'm talking about.
For example, let's imagine that we wanted to use our banks website to transfer money from one bank
account to another.
So instead of Google Dotcom, imagine right now I was logged in to my bank's website.
Well, from a code perspective, perhaps the bank website would send a bit of JavaScript to me and my
Web browser.
Maybe they would send over an object money transfer and you don't have to type this out.
This is just for a quick explanation.
There's no need to follow along with this code.
But maybe the bank server would send over to me an object.
So say money transfer equals and they would set the from account to whatever my logged in user is.
Right.
And then the two account would be whoever I wanted to send money to.
So they would probably pull this value from the input field of whoever's name I type in.
And we could imagine there would be a property named amount which again would pull in the value of a
user input field of how much I want to give to someone.
And then finally, we could imagine there would be a property named Message, which is a place for a
memo or a brief description of the money transfer.
Now, most people are not evil and most people are not familiar with code and their browsers console.
However, what if we were an evil or malicious user?
We could log into our bank's website, come into our browsers console, and we could just change this
stuff programmatically.
Right?
We can fire up our console and say money transferred from account should not be the logged in user that
I actually am.
It should be really rich person.
Smith and the two account should be me.
Give me the money and the amount should be some disgustingly large amount and the message should be
my money.
Now, right now I could add that into my web browsers memory and then if I.
Went back to the bank screen, I could click a button that says perform money transfer and if the bank's
server implicitly trusted me, I would now be a very rich man.
Right.
The request would go through.
Now, obviously, that's not the world we live in.
If servers implicitly trusted you and your requests, the world would spin out of control into complete
chaos in about two minutes.
The reason we have any sort of sanity in this digital age is because a server has the job of making
sure that you really are the person that you're claiming to be.
Now, you might be thinking to yourself, why couldn't we just use JavaScript to send over an if statement
to the Web browser?
Right.
We already learned how to make decisions in our code.
So imagine the bank assigns you a variable when you first log in.
Maybe let user equal your name.
Right.
And then maybe you think we could use an if statement and say only if the following is true.
Only if user equals money transfer, not from account.
Right.
So only if this is the case.
Only if the user is who they say they are, then let the money transfer go through.
Well, this line of thinking is good.
This is similar to the line of thinking that we would use on the server side.
The problem is just that we cannot rely on this on the client side or the Web browser side or the user
side, because there's nothing stopping a malicious user from simply saying, well, users should equal
really rich person Smith.
Right, they could modify the user variable in their Web browser, and then this if statement would
evaluate to true or better yet, a malicious user could simply modify the JavaScript that you send over
to them and just get rid of the if statement check or a malicious user could just completely disable
JavaScript in their browser entirely.
So getting back to reason number two of why we want a server trust issues, we need to run this decision
making code in a trusted environment and we can never truly trust the user's Web browser.
So the idea is that with a server, we can write JavaScript code, we can write if statements and all
sorts of things to make sure that it's a legitimate request.
So long story short, a server is really just a place where we can write code that cannot be tampered
with or manipulated by the user of the application.
And for now, that's really as deep as we need to go in terms of why we want or need a server.
Now, before we bring this video to a close and start talking about our next steps, I first want to
address two common questions that you might have right now.
So question number one, you might be thinking, OK, sure.
So you could write this if statement on the server side, but couldn't the user still just send along
a fake user value and try to impersonate someone?
And the answer is yes.
Malicious users will try to do that.
However, I don't want you to worry about that right now.
We are absolutely going to learn about authentication later in this course.
But I don't want you to burden your mind with it right now.
Don't worry.
We have a lot of tricks up our sleeves on the server side and we can get creative in terms of making
sure that users are who they claim to be.
For now, all you need to know is that if our app is even going to have a chance of being secure, we
need to run our verification and authentication code in a trusted environment, not in an environment
that the user is in control of.
So we need a server.
So that's common question number one.
Common question number two is, hey, Brad, what about serverless applications?
I keep hearing this phrase serverless app.
It's a really popular buzzword right now.
There's a lot of hype surrounding it.
So if an app can be Cervalis, do we really need a server?
And my answer to this question is that it's really just a matter of semantics.
Serverless apps still use servers.
The difference is that instead of writing an entire server and then pushing it up onto the Internet
with a Serverless app, you're just writing individual functions and then you're handing those functions
off to a big company like Amazon, Google or IBM.
And then those billion dollar companies are hosting your functions for you.
It's the same idea, though.
You are writing server side functions.
You are having a place that is trustworthy and private.
It's just that you're letting some other company, host or individual functions instead of you needing
to host your entire server yourself.
Now, if everything I just said made zero sense and you've never heard of the phrase serverless apps,
that's OK.
You can just forget the last 60 seconds ever happened.
Rest assured that later on in the course I will briefly talk about and explain Serverless apps.
But for now, we do not need to worry about that.
And I can tell you with the utmost certainty that whether you want to create a traditional app or a
serverless app, you are going to need to write server side code.
And in the JavaScript universe, as soon as you want to start writing code outside the context of a
Web browser, you need to learn about something named Node JS after the Web browser node is by far the
most common or popular JavaScript environment.
Now Node can be used for just about anything, so I don't want you to think that it's just for creating
servers that just happens to be one of its many use cases.
Big picture learning about node is going to open up so many doors for us and it's exactly what we're
going to start learning about in our very next lesson.
This is an exciting portion of the course because when you start to learn about node, you can legitimately
call yourself a JavaScript developer.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.