Hello, everyone.
In this video, we're going to talk about our next steps or where we go from here.
Let's go ahead and take a look at the overview or topics that we're going to cover in this video.
First, we'll talk about front end framework's.
After that, will talk about a technology or paradigm known as Cervalis.
And finally, no, this is not just a cheesy motivational topic.
It's something that I really believe wholeheartedly.
We'll talk about how you are enough.
OK, let's go ahead and get started.
So up at the top, our first topic, front and framework's.
You might have noticed that on our backend or server side, we did indeed use a framework.
Right.
We used Express, however, for our front end or browser based JavaScript, we did not use a framework.
We did this because Xpress.
Right.
The framework we used on the server side is very un opinionated.
But what does that word un opinionated mean within the context of technology?
It means that Express doesn't really force a lot of ideas on us.
It gives us a few tools to work with that can save us a lot of time, but it doesn't tell us exactly
how we should set things up or view the world.
And that's great.
And that's why we used it for our back end.
However, when it comes to the front end, there is no such thing as an unhappen united framework.
They are all incredibly opinionated.
Now, that's not a bad thing.
The complex nature of Web browsers demands an opinionated or creative solution.
It's just that from an educational perspective, that's not something we want to run or rush into because
there's no sense in trying to wrap your head around the opinions and idiosyncrasies of a framework before
you've even had a chance to wrap your head around the Web browser itself.
But the good news is that now that you've worked your way through this course, you have wrap your head
around the Web browser.
And so now it makes perfect sense to take on that extra challenge of understanding and adhering to the
opinions and philosophies of a particular front end framework.
Now, there are a hundred different reasons to learn a front end framework, but I think there are two
reasons in particular that are especially exciting.
So let's talk about those reasons.
Number one is front and routing.
Don't worry.
I will explain what that is in just a moment.
And reason number two is efficient updating of the DOM.
So before I explain what that is, let's start with number one.
So what is front end routing?
Well, to explain this, let's use our app's search feature as an example.
So let's say I search for something like lorem ipsum.
And then maybe I want to click on this, being a dog is fun post now currently if I did that, it would
send me to an entirely different euro and the Web browser would not only have to wait for the servers
response before doing anything, but then even once the browser does receive the response from the server,
our browser has to reload the entire page, which, if we think about it, is not the fastest or most
efficient way.
So picture this.
What if instead, when I clicked on this link, we used browser based JavaScript to send off an asynchronous
request to fetch this data and then as soon as we did fetch the data, we could hide this search overlay
and only update the one div on the page that would need to show that new content for that post.
That way, our Web browser never has to lock up and then re render an entire page and render the entire
dom.
That approach would feel way faster and more responsive and instantaneous for our visitors.
Now we already have all of the skills to make that happen, right?
We know how to manipulate elements on the page with browser based JavaScript and we know how to send
off asynchronous requests with Axios.
But we'd be forgetting about one crucial aspect of Web development, and that is the address bar or
the U.
RL, right.
Because if we used browser based JavaScript to load the content for the link we clicked on and then
just render that one div to display it here.
Well, the address bar would not update.
So even though I clicked on being a dog is fun, I wouldn't have a U.
RL that I could easily share with friends and family or on social media.
Now, yes, I'm aware the year is not nineteen ninety five.
We can have our cake and eat it too.
We could implement front end JavaScript that micromanages or babysits the euro and then we could also
write JavaScript to listen to back button clicks and forward button clicks.
And our JavaScript could update the user interface portion depending on the current you are out.
All of that is possible with JavaScript.
And no, we would not need a front end framework to do that.
We just need to learn a little bit about the pop state event on the global window object and also the
browser's history push state method.
However, setting up the code to power that in a way that is organized and not repetitive and easy to
dig through the code.
A year later after you set it up and have it still makes sense to you.
It's actually a bit trickier than you might think.
But if we use a front end framework, client side routing like that becomes a piece of cake.
All of the big front end frameworks either come bundled with a router or they have a community supported
or sort of standard router plug in that is bulletproof.
So that's the big reason.
Number one, to learn a front end framework, you can implement simple organized client side routing.
OK, that was reason number one.
Let's talk about reason number two to learn a front end framework which is efficient updating of the
domain.
So you can imagine that as your applications become more complex, you're going to need to update more
and more elements on the screen with data changes.
Now, we are familiar with selecting an element with browser based JavaScript and then manipulating
its content on the fly.
But micromanaging or babysitting 20 different elements on the page can become very tedious very quickly.
So instead, if you were using a front end framework, you can just spell out your whole HTML template
or user interface in one convenient template or view, and then you can have that template be powered
by raw data and values.
And then as those data and values get updated, your template is just automatically re rendered.
Now, at first you might say, Brad, why do we need a front end framework to make that happen?
Couldn't we just write a big giant back tick template, literal template and then re output it or render
it every time our data changes?
Well, yes, you absolutely could do that, but that would be terrible for performance.
Any time we update an element in the DOM and force the browser to re render or repaint it, that is
a fairly expensive operation from a performance standpoint, meaning we want to update as little as
possible or only the content that we truly need to update.
We don't want to just constantly be re rendering our entire template just because one little piece of
data somewhere updated.
But that's the beauty of front end frameworks.
They all have brilliant rendering engines that take what your updated template would look like with
the newest data and then compare that against what the browser currently has on screen and then only
changes the specific elements that would actually be different.
This gives you the best of both worlds you no longer need to select each into.
Visual element and babysit its value, you can just have one declarative template and you're also getting
lightning fast performance because the browser doesn't have to render your entire template.
So in my opinion, those are the two biggest reasons to begin learning a front end framework.
Now, if you're thinking, Brad, these features sound amazing, why didn't we use a front end framework
in this course?
Well, that takes us back to the whole topic of front end frameworks being very opinionated.
They each have their own unique way of doing things and their little idiosyncrasies.
And I feel that to cover a front end framework properly, it really deserves its own course dedicated
to that topic.
I didn't want this course to become dominated by the opinions and philosophies of one particular front
end framework.
But before we move on to the next topic in this video, I just want to let you know that learning a
front end framework should definitely should absolutely be your next focus.
Now, as of today, there are three big popular frameworks that you can choose from react, view and
angular.
I'll let you perform your own research and make your own choice.
But if I had to give my own totally subjective and personal opinion, I would recommend react.
OK, now let's move on and talk about the next topic in this video, which is Cervalis.
Before we even get into what the word Serverless means, I need to say that it is a big topic so big
that to cover it properly, it definitely deserves its own dedicated, devoted course.
Having said that, Cervalis is so hot right now that I feel like I'd be doing you a disservice if we
didn't at least briefly discuss it.
I think the best introduction to the Serverless paradigm within the context of JavaScript and Web development
is this website titled Jamm Stack Dawg.
Let's begin by breaking down the letters of the JAM acronym.
So it stands for JavaScript APIs and markup markup just means HTML.
I encourage you to read through this website at some point, but for now, let me explain Cervalis by
doing this so I have a file on my desktop named Home HTML and I'm literally just going to drag this
file on top of Mozilla Firefox.
So clearly, this is not being powered by a server I'm just viewing in HTML file in my Web browser,
so it's got a heading, a paragraph, a link you should read about my favorite colors.
And if I click on that link, it takes me to a new HTML file, my favorite colors.
I like blue, green and purple and then a link back to the home page.
So really, that's all the website is, right?
It's connected HTML pages.
You can take a look at those two files.
Here they are on my text editor writes, Just adding a level one paragraph aliments.
Now, at first glance, we might think that Web pages like this can't do anything dynamic, right?
Because they're not being served up by a Web server.
They can run dynamic code and serve up new, interesting things.
This is just a static HTML file.
However, let's not forget about the power of JavaScript and APIs within this static HTML file.
I could very easily include a bit of browser based JavaScript to send off an asynchronous request to
an API to fetch a bit of dynamic data or maybe send in a username and password to get a Jason Web token.
And then once we have a token, we know that we could connect to an API and create a post or delete
a post or do anything.
So if you really think about it, even though we're just viewing a static HTML file, we're really not
limited.
Maybe we don't need a server at all.
Hence the name Cervalis.
However, what if we don't just want to leverage other people's APIs?
What if we want to create our own API?
Because, yes, we don't need a server to run static HTML and JavaScript requests to an API, but we
absolutely do need a server to power, said API write.
The server is our trusted safe environment that a malicious user cannot tamper with, and it's where
we would check the incoming username and password to determine if they are valid or not.
So wouldn't we still need a server after all?
Well, this is where we get into semantics.
It turns out we don't really need an entire server.
All that we really need is a safe, trusted environment where we can run individual functions.
Let me show you a real world example of what I'm talking about.
So back in this browser, I want to show you a service named Net Lafi.
I'm not affiliated with Net Lafi in any way, shape or form, although I'd like to be in the future
anyways.
I just think they are an amazing service.
So what is net lafi?
Well, you send them your static HTML and KSN JavaScript files and they host it for you, but it goes
beyond that.
Remember when I said that we don't need a server, but we do need a safe, trusted environment where
we can run individual functions?
Well, Net Lafi offers that even on their completely free plan, they offer this so net.
Lafi makes it really easy to set up what is commonly referred to as a serverless function or a cloud
function, essentially, in addition to the static HTML, CSC and JavaScript files that you send a net
lafi, you also send them individual functions and these functions would be written in JavaScript for
the node environment.
Write a server side environment net.
Lafi will handle all of the configuration, but essentially they are going to run your node server side
functions on Amazon Web Services hardware, which believe me, is a safe, trusted environment that
malicious users cannot tamper with anyways.
Then Net Lafi gives you a U.
RL that points towards your function and that you URL is what you can use to make your API requests
within your front end javascript so your node functions would do the same type of things we were doing
within our apps.
Controller functions, right?
Talking to a database, performing validation, responding back with a bit of JSON.
The only difference is you're no longer building a holistic or monolithic app or server.
Each one of your cloud functions needs to be able to stand on its own.
Which brings us to the entire advantage in point of adopting the Serverless paradigm in the first place.
With the Serverless paradigm, our applications can scale infinitely and effortlessly because we don't
need to worry about our apps server crashing.
We no longer think in terms of servers, we think in terms of individual functions.
And our functions are running on the hardware from the richest company in the world.
Right.
Amazon Web Services.
They can handle infinite amounts of traffic.
However, I don't want you to think that the serverless paradigm is inherently tied to Amazon Web Services.
That's just the solution that Netflix.
Uses, there's also Microsoft's Azure functions, Google offers Google cloud functions and IBM has IBM
cloud functions, you get the idea.
Anyways, that wraps up our big picture, super oversimplified explanation of the serverless paradigm.
If you are even one percent interested in Cervalis, I encourage you to read up on the Jam Stacked Dog
website and also definitely sign up for a free net account to play around and experiment with.
Now, before we move on to our next topic, I do want to stress that you don't need to adopt the Serverless
paradigm.
It's not always the right choice for every project.
Even though Serverless is very hot right now, there's also a beloved framework named next J.S..
I won't even get into what next is.
But one of the features that it advertises and is proud of is its server side rendering and its thanks
to its server side rendering that it can claim things like exceptional performance, search engine optimization
benefits and much more.
My point here is that sometimes the Internet can't figure out what it thinks is the next biggest, hottest
technology.
There is no one right or best way to build a website or web application.
Ultimately, the choice is up to you.
At the very least, Serverless is a very interesting trend that's worth understanding.
And being able to say on your resume that you're familiar with both monolithic servers and the serverless
paradigm definitely will not hurt.
Now, speaking of resumes, that brings us to the final topic in this video, which is just a bit of
career advice, and that is that you are enough as of today, as of this very minute, you are enough.
I know it can be very tempting to think I'm not ready.
I need to learn a front end framework.
I need to learn about Serverless.
There's five hundred other billion technologies I need to learn about, and I'm not going to apply for
any jobs until I'm ready.
Well, even though it's totally normal and natural and tempting to think that way, I urge you not to
do that.
The truth is, none of us are ever truly ready.
Technology changes at such a fast rate that we're all always learning.
Now, I've been on the hiring side of developer interviews before, and so I just want to leave you
with a single story.
I once had a student who had never had a job in the tech industry complaining to me that they couldn't
get a job because they didn't know super advanced topics A, B, C and X, Y and Z.
And I told this student that I really don't think you need to know all of that and that I personally,
in my real life, knew senior developers and chief technology officers who didn't even know all of those
things.
And this student said to me, No, Brad, you're wrong.
I don't know topics A, B and C, it is hopeless.
I can't get a job.
The moral of the story here is that I think when we have a goal that seems difficult, we have a tendency
to make it seem impossibly difficult.
Right.
We blow it out of proportion.
Now, don't get me wrong, landing your first tech job can be very, very challenging, but you absolutely
do not need to be an expert in every programming topic.
There are all sorts of jobs, beginner focused jobs, junior developer jobs, mid level roles.
And to tell you the truth, when I was on the hiring side of dev interviews, the biggest qualities
that I looked for were a positive attitude, open mindedness in the ability to cooperate with others.
Right.
Because those are the sort of things that you can't really teach.
Someone either has those qualities or they don't.
So the biggest thing I want you to walk away from this course with is an unshakable confidence that
you are enough.
As of today, as of this moment, you are enough, even if you only absorbed twenty percent of the material
in this course.
If you take that and you put your willingness to learn on full display, I'm very confident there's
a job out there with your name on it.
And that's going to bring this video and this course to a close from the bottom of my heart.
I want to thank you for coming along on this journey with me.
I wish you nothing but the absolute best.
And until next time, take care.