Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to add real time validation to our registration form.
So earlier in the course we added server side validation to this form, and that's a necessity.
You always need to validate data on the server side because a malicious user could disable client side
or front end validation.
So while it is true that we can never trust client side validation in this case, we don't need to be
able to trust it.
We're just going to add it to enhance the user experience.
And if a malicious user should disable the client side validation, we don't care because we know that
we have the server side validation that's still going to do its job no matter what.
So our goal in this lesson is to write browser based JavaScript that will run after every keystroke
and show any potential validation messages right above that particular field in real time.
Without further ado, let's get started.
Let's begin by creating a brand new JavaScript file just for this feature.
So do this with me in your text editor within your front and JS folder.
Look for the modules subfolder and on that modules folder.
Let's right click and choose new file.
Let's name this new file registration form JS within this new empty file, we'd want to export something
so that it can be imported from another file.
So let's say export default class and let's give it a name of registration form curly brackets, OK,
within the curly brackets you know that I like to break things up into three sections.
So the first section is a constructor constructor, parentheses, curly brackets after the constructor.
I like to have an area for my events, so let's add a comment and then say events, parentheses, curly
brackets and then below that I like to have a section named Method's OK now within our constructor,
let's be sure to call events.
So this dot events parentheses and then just as a test within events, let's have an annoying alert
pop up that says registration form J.S. is running cool.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And now I want you to jump into Main JS.
So within your front end folder you should have a file named Main James.
And at the top of that file, let's import in our new registration form code.
So add a new line and say import registration form from and then quotes and then dot forward slash and
then let's look in the modules folder and the name of the file was registration form.
Cool.
Now right below that, let's write an if statement to only actually run this code if the registration
form exists on the current Web page.
So I would say if parentheses curly brackets for the condition we can just say document dot, query
selector and then quotes and then a hash tag of registration dash for ok then within the if curly brackets
we would just create a new instance of uppercase registration form.
Parentheses to call that constructor cool, let's go ahead and save this and then be sure to refresh
your front end and you should see an annoying alert that says registration form JS is running now for
our first real task.
Let's use browser based JavaScript to insert a red validation message above each of the three fields.
Let me show you how I would do that.
So back within registration form J.S., since we know that it's working, we can get rid of that annoying
alert within the event's area and up in the constructor.
Let's do this.
Let's add a property and let's say this dot all fields.
Let's set this to equal document dot query selector only don't type in the parentheses yet.
We actually want to call a method named query selector all and now add the parentheses.
Instead of returning a single element, this will return an array or a collection of multiple elements.
So within it, let's give it quotes and let's say hash tag, registration, Dasch form, but then we
can have a space to look inside it and let's select any element that has a class.
So a dot of form Dasch control.
OK, so this should return an array of three different elements.
Right, the fields for username, email and password.
And now right below this line, let's do this.
Let's call a method that doesn't exist yet, but one that we can create in just a moment.
So let's say this dot insert validation elements, parentheses to call it OK, and now down and our
methods area, let's create a method with this name.
So down here I would add a new line and say insert validation elements, parentheses curly brackets
within this method.
I'd begin by working with the this dot all fields property, which is actually an array.
And we know that all arrays have access to a method named for each within these parentheses.
Let's provide for each a function, so function parentheses, curly brackets within the parentheses.
For this function, let's include a parameter.
We could name it anything, but let's name it l short for element.
OK, now within the body of this function we can say L and now we can do something to each one of those
three fields.
Let's do this.
So l dot insert adjacent html parentheses to call that and then we give it to arguments.
So a comma be.
The first argument is where you want to insert the HTML.
In this case I would actually say after and so right after each form field I want to add in a bit of
HTML instead of the B placeholder, we just include the HTML that we want to add.
So let's say quotes and then let's add a div.
So opening and closing div tag on the opening tag.
Let's give it a class of be sure that you use different types of quotes here.
So the entire HTML string I have wrapped in single quotes and then for my HTML attributes inside here
I'm using double quotes, but let's give it a class of alert space and then alert dash danger and then
a space small and then a space and then live and then uppercase v validate and then uppercase M message
and then finally space.
And just as a test let's give it a class of live validate message dash dash visible.
OK, once you've given it all of these classes, go ahead and save this.
And now if we refresh in the browser you should see these little red boxes above each field.
The styling and sizing looks a bit off because we don't have any text in the device.
So if we went back in and just as a test in between the opening and closing div tags, if you said hello
and then if we save that and refresh.
You get the idea.
So that's where you would include the validation message, such as that username is already taken or
that's not a valid email address, or your password must be at least 12 characters long.
Now, we don't actually want to preemptively show these red boxes.
So let's go back into our code and do this.
First of all, let's get rid of the text in between the opening and closing div tags.
And then let's also get rid of this class that ended in dash dash visible.
So now I just have alert, alert, danger, small and live, validate message, let's give that to save.
So now each field has its own area for validation messages.
Obviously they're not going to show it first.
Now it's up to us to show them at just the right moment.
Let's begin with the user name field.
Let's begin with the rules that enforce how long your username should be.
Let's think about when we should show the validation message.
So if someone begins to type in their name at this point, their user name is only two characters long.
But I wouldn't want to immediately show a message that says your username must be at least three characters
because we haven't even waited long enough to give the user a chance to type.
What I'm getting at here is for certain validation checks.
We would not want to run immediately after each keystroke, but if the user started typing in a really
long name and they surpassed our 30 character limit for the username, then we would immediately want
to show the message that says username cannot exceed 30 characters.
Also, if a user used a character that we are not allowing, right, we're only allowing alphanumeric
characters so A through Z and zero through nine the millisecond they used a special character that's
not allowed, I would want to show them the validation message.
On the other hand, another example where I would want to wait for a delay would be to check to see
if the user name has already been taken or not.
So let's assume someone else named Brad was trying to register that username.
I would not want to send a request to the server to see if there's a username of B, and then after
they type R and A and D, right.
You don't want to flood your server with network requests after every single keystroke.
So, again, just like I'd probably want to give the user five to eight hundred milliseconds to type
something in that's longer than two characters.
I also want to give them a certain number of milliseconds before I waste a network trip to see if that
username has already been taken.
So, again, big picture.
I just want you to be aware of the fact that some checks should run immediately, but other checks should
run after a delay.
Just be aware of that because it is going to slightly complicate our coding setup.
OK, having said all of that, at this point, let's start moving forward.
I would begin by selecting this username field.
So within our constructor, maybe right below this insert validation elements line, let's say this
dot username equals document, dot query selector quotes and hash tag because it has an idea of username
Dasch register.
OK, now let's just listen for each keystroke event on that element.
So within our events area, I would add a new event so we can just say this dot username dot add event
listener.
Within these parentheses we would give it to arguments.
So A comma, B for the first argument.
We're interested in the key up event.
Now, the second argument would be a function that we would want to run in response to that event.
But this is where things get interesting, because if we think about it, if I select that field, what
if I press a key that does not in any way change the value of the field?
For example, what if the user pressed one of their arrow keys right, the left, right, up or down
Iraqis?
Or what if they pressed the shift key or the control key or the caps lock key?
You get the idea.
We wouldn't need to actually do anything unless the key that they just pressed actually somehow just
changed the value of the field.
And if we think about it, that's going to be the case for all three of the fields.
So in terms of the function that we want to run in response to this, why don't we create a reuseable
function that will check to see if the field has changed its value?
Trust me, this should make sense in a couple of minutes.
But let's do this.
So instead of the B placeholder, let's create a function.
Let's actually use an arrow function.
So parentheses, arrow symbol, curly brackets.
I'm using an arrow function so that the this keyword doesn't change.
Let's dropdown inside those curly brackets and let's say this dot is different.
So I just made up this name, but now let's go create a method with this name.
So down here in our methods area, let's create a new method name.
It is different parentheses, curly brackets.
And now let's do this when we call this method, let's provide it with two arguments.
First, let's give it the element in question.
So that would be this username karma.
Then let's give it a function that we would want to run if the value of the field has actually changed.
We haven't created this method yet, but we will in just a moment.
So let's say this dot user name handler, OK, now, when we create this is different method inside
these parentheses, let's include two parameters to receive those two incoming arguments.
So for the first one, I would say E-L short for Element comma and then let's say handler.
OK, now within the body of this method, what we really want to do is see if the field's value has
changed after this key press.
Let me show you how I would handle this.
So up in the constructor at the very top, right after this DOT username, I just create another line
and say this dot username, dot previous value and I would set this to equal an empty string.
OK, now with that in place, let's go back down to is different and within the body of is different.
I would just create an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition check I would just say if the element in question
dot previous value, if that does not equal the element in question's current value, well that means
the value has changed.
So then in this if block we would just call the handler function.
OK, but right after this if block but still within the is different method, let's say the element
in question dot previous value should now be set to equal the current value.
So then the next time when this runs, these values will make sense.
Right.
And it will actually keep track of the previous value each time.
If the value is actually different, it's going to call the handler function.
Right.
Which is the second argument or parameter.
And in this case for the username, we are telling it to run a function named username handler.
So let's create a method with that matching name, user name handler, parentheses, curly brackets.
And just as a test within this method, let's have an annoying alert message that says username handler
just ran cool.
Now, before we save this and test it out, and once we test it, I think it will start to make sense.
But before we get to that, we do need to address the this keyword when our handler method runs.
We do want to make sure that within it the this keyword is still pointing towards our overall object.
However, because we are calling the handler like this, JavaScript is going to consider the this keyword
to just be the global object.
Right.
Because there's no object right before it.
That's obviously calling it to get around this.
Here's what we can do.
Let's get rid of the parentheses after handler here and let's say handler dot call.
Coal is a method that is available to functions.
And now within these parentheses, we can just say this.
So now call will run this function and it will make sure that the this keyword is whatever we set it
to, which in this context is still pointing towards our overall object.
Let's go ahead and save this and let me refresh your memory of what we're really trying to achieve here.
So if you reload in the browser, if you click into the username field and push a key that does not
change the value, like an arrow key, like left, right, up, down, or if you push caps, lock or
shift noticed, nothing happens.
But as soon as we actually type in a letter like B cool, we see username handler just ran perfect and
now we can reuse.
That is different function for these two fields as well.
This actually brings us to a good stopping point for this video.
It may not seem like we've accomplished very much, but we have laid the foundation and groundwork.
And I think you'll be surprised how far we will get in the next video.
That's when we will display error messages at just the right moment with just the right message.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.