Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to get started learning about databases, we have two primary goals in
this lesson.
Number one is to get our first look at a database.
During this part of the lesson, I want you to relax and take your hands off the keyboard and mouse
and just observe, OK?
Then after that, goal number two is for you to create your own new database.
This goal is very hands on.
And I will want you to follow along with me.
But for right now, let's begin with goal number one and have our first look at a database.
OK, so here is a database that I created off camera prior to filming this lesson.
And let's use our imagination to picture that this database powers a pet adoption website or app.
So naturally, this pets portion of the database stores all of the data about the different pets.
So down here we can see that each white rectangle.
So here's one and here's another represents a pet.
So this first pet has a name of fuzzy IT species is a cat and it's spayed or neutered.
Value is set to true.
If we look at the next pet in the database, we can see that its name is purs loud.
It's also a cat, but it's spayed or neutered.
Value is set to false.
You can see the next one is a dog with the name of cuddles.
And then a dog named Bella, so on and so forth, you get the idea.
Now, I only created eight pets in this simple example database, but you could imagine that a real
pet adoption website could have hundreds or even thousands of pets or animals.
And this brings us to the other main point of having a database in the first place.
Not only does a database let you permanently store data like this, but once you start to have a lot
of data, it becomes super important to be able to dig through that data or work with the data in a
meaningful way.
Let me show you what I mean.
So let's imagine that I only want to see the dogs in the database.
Now, do not worry about fully understanding what I'm about to type in.
You will learn about this later.
But just as a quick example, I could say that the species should be set to dog and then if I run this
query.
Now, in the results area, we only see dogs, so you can start to imagine how this would be very useful
for a pet adoption website or application, right.
Someone opens up your app and says, I'm only interested in adopting a dog.
No other types of animal.
Or imagine if someone wanted to adopt the cat that's already been spayed or neutered.
So behind the scenes, we can talk to our database and say that the species should be set to cat.
And then also the spayed or neutered property should be set to true.
And then if I run that query.
You can see we only received two pet documents, right, Fuzzy, the cat that has been spayed or neutered
and whiskers the cat that has been spayed or neutered.
Now, neither of the last two examples have been very impressive because there's only eight total pets
in our database.
But imagine if our database had five hundred thousand pets.
In that case, being able to run queries like this and dig through the data is incredibly powerful and
valuable.
Now, in terms of our first goal for this lesson, getting a quick look at a database, that's really
all I need you to absorb right now, that we can use a database to permanently store data and that a
database also makes it very easy to stay organized and work with that data, if that makes even a little
bit of sense than we are ready to move on to goal number two.
And this is where you're going to roll up your sleeves, get your hands dirty, and create your very
own new database that you are in control of.
Let's get started.
The first step is to open a new tab in your Web browser and visit Mongo DB dot com.
Or you can just perform a Google search for Mongo DB.
And this website should be the first result.
Now the question becomes, what in the world is Mongu GB?
Well, Mongo DB is just one of many different database systems.
You might have heard of other database systems such as MySQL or SQL Server or Oracle or Maria DB or
many, many others.
Now, these different database systems have different philosophies and different features.
But at the end of the day, all databases are used to store data and to make that data easy to work
with and dig through.
Now, the reason that I chose Mongo DB as our database solution for this course, aside from its tremendous
popularity, is because it does not require us to learn a new language aside from JavaScript.
So I am not saying that Mongo DB is the quote, best database system, nor am I saying that it's the
right choice for every type of application.
But what I am saying is that given the focus of this course JavaScript, I do think that Mongo DB is
the simplest and most logical choice for our database needs.
OK, so at this point the question becomes how do we get started using Mongo DB?
Well, from the Mongo DB website.
We want to go ahead and sign up for a free account at the time that I'm recording this on the homepage
of Mongo DB.
There's a sign up form right at the top, but if that's no longer there in the future, when you're
watching this video, you can also use the try free button up in the header or you can also look through
the navigation under products and look for Mongo DB Atlas, big picture.
We just want to sign up for a free Mongo DB Atlus account.
So go ahead and sign up by entering your email address.
Aside from your email address, you should just need to enter a first name, last name and choose a
password.
And what's nice is that this account is truly free.
You do not even need to enter a credit card or any type of payment info.
So once you fill in your basic data, go ahead and submit the form.
The page might go blank for a couple of seconds and then redirect you a few times, but you should end
up with a page that looks like this.
So it gives you a bit of a welcome message.
And then it says that you can get started by building your first cluster.
And that's exactly what I want you to do.
I want you to click the build my first cluster button.
If you don't see this exact pop up welcome message, that's OK.
Just look for a create cluster button somewhere.
OK, so I will click build my first cluster.
OK, and then we just need to choose a few options, so the first thing is that we need to choose our
cloud provider and region for cloud provider.
I'm going to choose HWC, which is Amazon Web Services.
Basically, this is just choosing which big, huge company is going to store or save our data.
If Amazon can host all of the data to power the world's most popular shopping website, I think they
can host the data for a simple to do list app without breaking a sweat.
OK, let's scroll down a bit for the region.
I'm going to choose North America.
Feel free to choose whichever location is closest to where you live in the world, but you will want
to choose between the options that include the phrase free tier available.
Right, because we don't want to spend any money on this example project.
OK, I've selected my region.
Let's scroll down.
All of these default options should be OK, you can go ahead and leave your cluster names at two cluster
zero.
That's not important.
And finally, let's click this button down towards the bottom right that says create cluster.
We can see different messages appearing up here with the status of our cluster that's being created
and this could take a few minutes.
So be patient down here in this area that I've highlighted, you can see that it reads your cluster
is being created and it could be up to seven or ten minutes before the Mongo DB service is completed,
creating your cluster.
But eventually the process will complete and that message will go away and that part of the screen will
then look like this.
So you might want to pause this video and go get a snack while you wait for your cluster to finish creating.
But once it is created, the question becomes, what in the world is a cluster, right?
What did we just do or what did we just sign up for and create?
Well, let me answer a question with another question.
When we need to store data for an application that we're going to build, where do we want to store
that data?
We know that we'll want to store the data in a database.
But what I'm getting at is where should that database live?
For example, we could save the database on our own physical personal computer, right on your computer,
hard drive.
But then you would be the only person in the world that could access the data.
Now, that is what many developers do while they are creating or testing an app, because in that case,
they're the only person in the world that needs to be able to use the app.
But eventually you're going to want to push your app and its data up onto the Internet.
So it's accessible to friends, family and other people.
So instead of saving your database locally on your computer's physical hard drive and then having to
worry about moving the database onto the Internet later on, we're just going to skip that complication
and mess entirely because we are going to create a database that lives in the cloud from the very start.
So for the purposes of this course, we don't really need to worry about what a cluster is.
All you really need to know is that we just created a place on the Internet or up in the cloud where
our database can live.
And in our very next lesson, we are going to create a new database in this area so that you can begin
adding a few sample items in the database just for fun and just for practice, similar to my pet adoption
database that we saw at the beginning of this lesson.
Or in other words, in our next lesson, we are going to learn about the most essential acronym when
it comes to working with databases, and that is crud.
So let's keep our momentum rolling.
And most importantly, let's find out what in the world crud means.
I'll see you in the next lesson.