Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to get started with Noad J.S. However, before we download and install
Node onto our computers, let's first ask ourselves what exactly is node?
So very early in the course, we learn that there are multiple environments in which we can speak the
JavaScript language, and each environment has its own unique made up words or slang or lingo that relate
to its super powers or abilities.
So the Web browser is a JavaScript environment and its special abilities include viewing web pages and
responding to user events like clicks and keyboard presses, so on and so forth.
Well, node is another JavaScript environment and its special abilities include things like being able
to create new files and folders on your computer, hard drive, being able to listen for incoming network
requests and much, much more.
In other words, the Web browser can do web browser ish things, whereas node is more open ended, node
can do general computer ish things.
For now, that's all we need to know about node.
So that's enough talk for now.
Let's get to the action right now.
Let's go ahead and download and install node onto our computers so we can get started using it.
So follow along with me.
Here is the official node web website.
It's no just dot org.
I will include a link to this website in the resources for this lesson.
Or you can just perform a Google search for node J.S..
OK, from the website, we want to download it.
In my case it says download for Mac OS.
In your case it might say download for Windows or something similar.
Now the version numbers that you see in this video are going to be different when you actually visit
the website yourself, because Node is constantly releasing new updated versions of the software.
That's OK.
Your version number does not need to exactly match my version.
No.
Now, there are two different download options that we see here, one with the absolute newest, latest
and greatest features and another one that is slightly older but is super reliable and stable and dependable.
Either download link will work just fine.
You can't go wrong, but personally I usually recommend the long term support version.
So go ahead and click on that to begin the download.
Depending on the speed of your Internet connection, it could take a while.
But once the download finishes, go into your computer's downloads folder and open up the install file,
all of the default options in the automated installer are OK.
So you should be able to just click next, next, next without any trouble.
So at this point, I'd recommend you pause the video lesson while you go and install node.
And once the installer is complete, you can come back and resume the video.
OK, our next step is to make sure that node was successfully installed.
To do this, we want to open up a command line on our computer.
If you have no idea what a command line is and what you're looking at right now on your screen, don't
worry.
Don't panic.
That's OK.
I know from firsthand experience that when you first see a command line, it can be terrifying.
But if someone's guiding you through things and holding your hand, it really doesn't need to be scary
whether we like it or not.
If we want to become a full stack developer, we absolutely need to use a command line.
There's just no getting around it.
So the question is, how do you open up a command line on your computer?
Well, it's going to be different depending on whether you're using Windows or Mac.
OK, so on Windows, you can open up the start menu and then just start typing on your keyboard, start
typing command prompt.
It should show up in the list of programs or applications, so go ahead and open it.
Or another way to get to the command line on Windows is to just hold down the windows, key on your
keyboard and simultaneously press the ARCHEY.
This will open up a run prompt and click into the run prompt field and type C and D and then push enter.
OK, so that takes care of windows.
If you're on Mac, simply look in your applications folder for another folder named Utilities.
Inside the utilities folder, you will see an app named Terminal.
Terminal is the command line on Mac, so go ahead and open that up.
OK, at this point everyone should have a command line open.
Now I want you to type this in node and then a space and then dash or the minus sign.
Right.
And then V so node space dash V go ahead and push.
Enter and in response, your computer should output a version number of node, if you see something
similar to this, even if your numbers are different, that means you have successfully installed node.
Give ourselves a pat on the back if you do not see a version number after running node space dashboard
and instead you see something like unknown command or command not found.
That means there was a problem when you tried to install node.
If that's the case, you can try restarting your computer and then opening up the command line and trying
this again.
Or you could try running through the node installer file again.
Or you might need to do a bit of personal Google research.
I'd recommend searching for install node problem blank where blank is your operating system, because
there are unique potential issues that are slightly different for Windows seven, Windows eight, Windows
10, as well as the different versions of Mac OS.
There's also a lot of different personal variables as to why Node did not successfully install, such
as the antivirus software that you have running in the background or different security settings that
you have enabled on your computer, so on and so forth.
So unfortunately, there's no way for me to preemptively list solutions to all of the possible reasons
as to why Node didn't successfully install.
However, I will say this learning how to Google and perform research is a huge part of becoming a developer.
So if you were not able to install Node successfully on your first try, don't worry, you're not alone.
Whatever issue you're running into, someone else has already ran into that issue.
And that's the beauty of Google.
And as you're digging through Google results, I want you to be on the lookout for any stack overflow
dotcom results.
A common joke in the programming world is that developers get paid to Google and find answers to their
problems on stack overflow.
OK, now, at this point in the lesson, I'm going to assume that everyone has successfully installed
node if you're moving forward.
So let's get our hands dirty and get our first taste of node in the command line.
I want you to simply type node, no space, nothing else, just the word node and then push, enter
or return.
By doing that, we have now entered into an interactive node environment.
In other words, we can start speaking the JavaScript language and our computer will understand us so
we can say two plus two and push enter.
We see four.
This is very similar to earlier in the course when we first started to experiment with the Web browsers
console.
Basically right now we are in the node console, so we are free to speak the JavaScript language.
We could create a variable, say, let my favorite number equal ten push enter that gets stored in the
memory and then I can say seven plus my favorite number.
Push, enter.
We see seventeen.
Now what if instead of just simple JavaScript language features like this, we wanted to leverage nodes,
unique abilities and super powers.
For example, what if we want to create a server and listen for incoming network requests?
Well, doing that with node is relatively easy, but it's going to take more than just a single line
of code like this.
And if we're going to be writing more than just single line code examples, we really should be doing
our typing in a dedicated text editing program instead of the command line.
Just like earlier in the course when we moved from the Web browsers console into code pen so we could
write multiple lines of code easily.
Right now we are going to move from our command line into a text editing program.
Ultimately, the reason we are doing this is so we can begin to do actually interesting and complex
things with Nog.
If you're scratching your head right now and still not really seeing the point of node and you're not
sure what the goal of all of this is and why node is necessary, don't worry.
That's to be expected.
I think the bigger picture of what's going on is going to come into focus and become very clear over
the next several lessons.
Trust me, when we finally do something interesting with Node and we see how that can interact with
the Web browser and how the puzzle pieces fit together, you are going to have an unbelievable aha moment.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.
Just a super quick note at the end here to exit the interactive node environment in your command line,
you can just press.
Control see twice, or if I jump back into the node console, another way of exiting node is just a
type dot exit.
It's not the end of the world if you don't exit node like this, but it should make closing your command
line window a bit easier.
All right.
I will see you in the next lesson.