Hello, everyone.
I want to begin by emphasizing that this video is optional.
If you've enjoyed the way the course is structured so far, feel free to skip this video.
However, everyone learns differently, and some people really prefer to start with the finished product
and dissect it or reverse engineer it or break it apart just to put it back together again.
Or for some people, if their code isn't working, it's really helpful just to see a proof of concept,
a working example of how things are supposed to work.
So in this lesson, I'm going to help you set up the finished product of the complex app that we build
together throughout the course.
Again, just to be clear, this video is entirely optional if you don't need or want to have the finished
product right away.
Please feel free to skip this lesson anyways if this sounds like something you're interested in.
If this matches your learning style, here's how we can begin.
It all starts by making sure that you have something called Docker installed on your computer.
To be more specific, it's something called Docker desktop.
So from the official Docker website, you can just look under products.
Click on Docker Desktop.
OK, and then just download the version that's appropriate for your computer.
Now all of the default options should be great, so you can just click Next, Next, next through the
installation process and then come back and resume this video once you've actually installed the Docker.
OK, but once you come back and resume the video, what do we do next?
Well, within Udemy, you'll see that there is a downloadable resource associated with this lesson called
complex finished product ZIP.
So go ahead.
Pause the video.
Download that zip file and then if you extract it, you'll have a folder.
Now, let's take a look at what's inside that folder.
So there's an app folder that has all of the source code, so you and I throughout this course will
write all of this code together.
But the idea is that this is the finished product.
So this is what you would end up with after the very final lesson in the course.
OK.
There's also a DB folder that's completely empty right now, but this will store the MongoDB database
contents of your app as soon as we actually spin up these containers.
OK, and then finally, there's a Docker compose file and this is really cool.
So even if you don't have Node.js installed on your computer, this will use Docker and it will create
a Node.js environment and it will create a MongoDB server.
The two are totally connected.
And this command will even run npm install for you and npm run watch.
So check this out.
Watch how easy this is.
Assuming you've downloaded the zip file and extracted it and you have this folder, you just need to
have a command line or your terminal point towards this new overall folder.
So since I have it open in vs code, I can just open up the terminal control or command j and you're
just one command away.
So you would type this in Docker, compose up, go ahead and press enter.
And now you will need to wait a good minute or two or depending on your internet speed, maybe even
up to five or 10 minutes.
But once you no longer see a steady stream of new text in your command line, that means you're ready
to try to view the application in the browser.
Do be patient, though it might look fast in this video, but that's because I edited out the boring
part of waiting the minute or two for everything to download and install back in the web browser and
a new tab.
Just visit local host colon and then instead of three thousand, it's 80 80.
So if I visit that perfect really quick off camera, let me sign up for a new user, OK, and then let
me create a post just as a proof of concept.
So first post lorem ipsum, go ahead and create that I can create a second post, second post testing.
Create that now I can test out the search feature.
The live search features if I search for the word first.
Cool first post.
So things are working just as we would expect.
Let's talk a little bit about how our Docker setup is working.
So for example.
What if you wanted to change this homepage template, maybe instead of a period right here, I wanted
this to be an exclamation mark.
Well, back in our code inside app and then views, there's home dashboard E.j.'s around line number
19.
Your feed is empty exclamation mark.
Now, the way things are set up, an Aegis template file is not going to trigger the server to refresh.
But what you can do is just make a save change.
You even need to change anything, just open up any main JS file.
So for example, if you open up app dogs or DV dogs, any of our main JS files and just press controller
commands, even though we didn't change anything that will trigger the entire system to sort of rebuild
or refresh.
So now back in the browser, if I refresh or reload, we see that change.
There it is.
Cool.
Now let's talk about how to stop and start this Docker project.
So in the command line, if you press control C and then you might need to press control, see a second
time, so that stops it.
Now how do we start the system back up again?
Let me clear the screen.
Well, the first time we ran Docker compose up, but you only run that the very first time to initially
create things.
Going forward, what you would run is Docker compose start.
So you can run that.
And that's going to run in the background so you can press control, see now, and that's not going
to do anything.
Your Docker containers are running in the background, so they're still up and available.
You can see I can refresh.
Cool.
So now if you actually want to stop the Docker containers, you would say Docker compose.
Stop.
Cool.
Now those start and stop commands are really the same thing as if you went into your Docker desktop
application.
If you hover over your project, you see the play button or the Start button, and you also see the
Stop button.
Finally, let's talk about how you can connect to the database that's powering the application.
Well, the applications already connecting to the database.
But what if you wanted to visualize the data yourself?
Well, there's an excellent and free tool called MongoDB Compass.
So even though we don't have a MongoDB Atlas cloud account that we can log into and visualise our data
with, we can just use compass instead.
So from the official MongoDB website, or if you perform a Google search for MongoDB Compass, you'll
find this website.
Just go ahead and download it.
It's a free download when you open MongoDB Compass, it'll look something like this, and now we just
need a connection string to include here.
So back in vs code to find the connection string, you would just look for the Dot EMV file inside the
app folder.
So in the app folder, here it is Dot EMV.
So it says connection string equals and then after the equals sign, you would just copy the rest of
this line into your clipboard.
So just like this copy that before we actually connect encompass, make sure that your Docker container
set up is actually running.
So I would just use the Start button to make sure that it's actually up and running and available to
connect to.
Cool.
Now, back in MongoDB Compass, you would just paste in your value here, and we just need to change
one word.
So we see route call and route at.
And then instead of Mongo right here, this part that I have selected, delete that and replace it with
local host instead.
Just like this.
So if I go ahead and connect cool, it works flawlessly.
There is complex app.
Can click into that, I can click into the Post's collection, and there are the two posts that I created
in the browser just a moment ago, and that is going to bring this video to a close.
Let's keep our momentum rolling.
And I'll see you in the next one.