Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to continue working on the front end or browser side JavaScript for our
live search results.
Let's jump right back into the action.
OK, first of all, as of right now, if I visit any page in my application, I see this annoying search
just as successfully being executed.
So right now, let's go get rid of this alert message.
So jump into your text editor and within your front end James folder, dig into the modules folder and
jump into search dogs.
OK, let's get rid of this alert line.
But before we move on any further than that, let's first discuss the words class and constructor.
If you've ever worked with another language besides JavaScript, such as C++, Java, Python or countless
others, then throughout this course, when you've heard me say, let's create a blueprint that can
be used to create new objects, you've probably been scratching your head and wondering why is he calling
it a blueprint instead of just a class in many other languages?
Aside from JavaScript, the official or correct or technical name for a blueprint for objects is a class.
However, JavaScript does not actually have classes.
Yes, we are successfully using the word class here and then in our main file we are successfully creating
a new instance using that class.
So yes, clearly JavaScript knows what we mean when we use the word class.
But behind the scenes or underneath the hood, JavaScript is still using prototypes and it's not actually
using classical inheritance.
So in JavaScript, classes are what's known as syntactic sugar.
It's an alternate syntax that might feel cleaner or more familiar or easier to read for many developers.
But it's really just a different way of achieving the same thing that we set up before.
So you don't need to type this.
But remember earlier when we would create a function, maybe function search and we could say this DOT
example property and set that to something and then we could leverage this constructor function so we
could create a new instance from that constructor.
Right.
And that would return a new object.
And then we could add functions or methods to this by saying search dot, prototype dot.
My cool method equals a function.
The idea is that in JavaScript we can use class syntax to achieve this same thing.
Only our code can feel a bit cleaner or more readable or familiar because so many other languages do
support classes.
So it has a special reserved method name of constructor.
And just like this syntax, this is what's going to run as a new object is being created.
So just like in our traditional constructor function, this is where we could say something like this
dot example property equals a value.
And then in terms of making a method available to any object that is created using this class, well,
right after the constructor still within our search class, you can just list out a method name so you
can just say my cool method and we don't need to set that to equal a function.
It can just be the function.
I think we can all agree this feels a lot cleaner than this.
But at the end of the day, both of these techniques are achieving the same thing behind the scenes.
JavaScript is still going to convert this into using a prototype based approach.
But as the developer, we don't really need to worry about that.
We can just write class code like this.
That's enough theory for now.
So let me get rid of this example code and let's get back to the actual task at hand.
So if you need to pause the video to make sure that your file looks like this, so we're on the same
page, that's OK.
But at this point, we're going to begin work on the search feature for our first task.
Let's set things up so that when you click on this search icon, maybe then we show an annoying alert
message.
Right.
Our first task is to just capture the action of a user clicking on this icon.
So back in our search dogs file, let me show you my personal, subjective approach towards writing
browser based classes.
I like to break things down into three areas so the constructor and we can leave comments to ourselves
to stay organized.
So I'd say no one.
So in the constructor, I like to create properties that select DOM elements, so then I can just easily.
Reference those later in the code, so for a comment, maybe, say, select DOM elements and keep track
of any useful data, OK, below the constructor, let's add a comment and say this is our second area
and this is where I like to keep track of my events.
So things like a user clicking on something or the user scrolling or the user pushing a key on their
keyboard.
Right.
These are the events that I want to respond to.
And then finally, for a third area, this is where I include my methods.
OK, let's walk through an example.
So first we would need to select the HTML element that is this little search icon.
So back in our code, I would do that in the constructor.
So let's make up a property this dot, let's call it header search icon and set that to equal.
And then we just want to look in the browser for that element.
So document is the browser object and then it has a method named query selector and I can let you know
that that icon has a class, an HTML class.
This has nothing to do with a JavaScript class but to look for a HTML or CSS class.
We say DOT and its class name is header dash, search dash ikon.
Cool.
Now that we've stored that element, we won't need to retrieve it again.
So now in our events area, let's create a method named events.
So events, parentheses, curly brackets and let's just add an event listener to this element.
So this dot header search icon, dot add event listener.
We give this to arguments a comma be.
The first argument is the browser event we want to listen for.
In this case it's a click.
The second argument is a function that we want to run.
In response to that, let's provide an arrow function so that the this keyword is not changed.
OK, now, because this is an a or link element, you'll notice that when I click it, it adds a hash
tag to the euro.
I set this up to be an element instead of a button or spane.
This way, if you wanted to, you could set up a fallback search page that doesn't use browser side
JavaScript.
Right.
Instead of having this point towards hash tag, you could have this point towards slash search or slash
traditional search.
Setting up a traditional search might be a nice extra credit assignment, but for now, we're just going
to focus on the JavaScript solution.
I bring this up because I would want to prevent the default behavior of clicking on a link.
Right.
I don't want to add the hash tag to the user's you.
Órale.
So back in your code, within our parentheses for this function, let's pass it a parameter.
Let's say E and then in the body of our function, we can just say e dot prevent default.
OK, then what do we actually want to do when someone clicks on that icon?
We'd want to open up our full screen search interface or search overlay.
So in about 30 seconds from now, we can create a method named open overlay.
So we can just call that here, this dot open overlay.
OK, now let's go create a method with that matching name.
So down here under Section three with this comment, we can just say open overlay parentheses, curly
brackets.
And now just as a quick test, let's show an alert message that says open overlay method just ran.
OK, and then finally, before we saved this file, we just have one last step up at the very top in
our constructor when a new object is created using this class.
Let's not forget as our final action in the constructor to call the events method.
So this DOT events this way we can stay organized and keep all of the events we're listening for in
one area without cluttering up our constructor.
But they will indeed begin listening or running as soon as the object is created.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in the browser, if I refresh, you can see the annoying alert on page load is gone.
But now if I click on the search icon, perfect open overlay method just ran.
Now that we're successfully responding to that click event, we don't actually want to show an alert.
Instead, we want to show a full screen search interface that looks something like this.
So there wouldn't be any results at first.
Your cursor would just automatically be placed into the search field and then you can type what you're
looking for.
Then a little spinning progress load or icon could appear here while the browser sends off a request
to the server.
The server talks to the database and then responds with raw JSON data for the appropriate results.
Then our front end passes that JSON and outputs HTML that will look like this.
But let's not get ahead of ourselves for now.
Let's not worry about actually sending off a request to the server.
Let's just worry about showing this interface when someone clicks on the search icon.
So we're going to need the HTML to create this full screen search overlay.
And again, this is not a course about HTML, so let's just copy and paste it from the same repository
that we've been working with.
So from the GitHub Dotcoms, Learn Web code, slash JavaScript, Rebo, dig into the complex app folder
and then the HTML templates folder.
In this case, the template we're interested in is search dash visible dot html.
Go ahead and click that and then click on raw.
We do not need to copy this entire template.
If you scroll down even below this area where we see footer begins, we see a new comment that says
search feature begins.
So begin selecting right below that HTML comment and then if you scroll down, you'll see search feature
end so we can stop copying right below that.
Go ahead and copy that into your clipboard and then back in our JavaScript file.
Let's do this down at the bottom below our open overlay method, but still within the overall closing
curly bracket of our class.
Let's add a new method.
We could name it anything, but let's name it.
Inject HTML parentheses, curly brackets.
OK, now in this method, let's just insert a bit of HTML at the end of the body element.
So document body dot insert adjacent HTML.
We give this to arguments.
So A comma B the first is where in that element you want to add the new code let's say before and so
right before the closing or ending tag.
And then for the B placeholder argument, this is just the code that you want.
So I would include two back ticks and then in between those we are free to paste in our clipboard.
OK, now before we save this file, let's be sure to scroll up to the very top and within our constructor,
let's make sure the very first thing we do is call that function.
So this dot inject HTML, let's give this a save and test it out.
So back in the browser, if I refresh the app, the good news is that we do see the search interface.
The bad news is that we would not want to see this until the user clicks on the search icon.
So let's do this back within that inject HTML method towards the very beginning of the code that we
pasted in.
You'll see a div with the class of search overlay, but it also has a secondary class of search overlaid,
dash dash visible.
Let's delete this class.
So then it just has the one class of search overlay.
Now if we save and refresh, the overlay is not visible.
Now we can just set things up so that our open overlay method add that class back on to that div.
So let's do this up at the top of our search, not just file within our constructor.
Let's add a new property.
Let's say this dot overlay and then let's select that div.
So document dot query selector and it had a class of search dash overlay.
OK, now we can leverage this within our open overlay method.
So within open overlay, get rid of the alert line and instead let's say this dot overlay dot class
list dot add and let's just give it back that class of search dash overlay dash dash visible.
Let's save that data for a test drive, refresh and click on the search icon.
Perfect.
Now let's set things up so that if they click on this X, we close or hide the overlay.
It would be as simple as just removing that visible class.
So I'll let you know that this X element here has a class of close live search.
So let's do this back up in our constructor.
Let's create a new property that selects that closing icons.
This dot close icon set that to equal document dot.
Query selector, and it has a class of close live search.
OK, now within our events area, let's create a new event that listens for that close icon being clicked
on.
So maybe right above this event, we can add on a new event and say this dot close icon, dot add event
listener.
The event we're listening for is a click and the function that we want to run in response.
Well, let's give it an arrow function.
So the this keyword is not changed.
And because this fits on a single line and we only have one action, we want to run, we don't even
need the curly brackets for the arrow function.
We can just call a method that will create in 10 seconds from now.
So this dot close overlay parentheses to actually call that, OK, now within our method area, we can
just copy and paste open overlay to avoid a bit of typing.
So I would just duplicate that right below it.
Pasted in.
Let's change its name to close overlay and then all we would need to change is removing instead of adding
a class.
Right.
Remove the class that makes it visible.
Let's give this a save and test it out.
So if I refresh so I can click the search icon to view it, don't worry, we will get rid of this tooltip
bug in the next lesson.
And then if I click the X, it hides it.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we'll begin working on the behavior for when you begin typing into this field.
This should be a lot of fun to set up because this is where our application really starts to feel interactive
and responsive.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.