Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to continue working on our registration form in our previous lesson,
we set things up for the username field so that if you actually change its value, we detect that and
show this annoying alert pop up.
So right now, let's go get rid of this alert, pop up and do something more meaningful within registration
form.
James, I want you to scroll down to your username handler method within the method.
Let's get rid of that alert line and instead, let's do this.
Let's set up the skeleton that will run some code immediately and run other code after a delay.
Now, this method doesn't exist yet, but we can create it in just a moment.
Let's say this dot user name immediately.
We can set this method up in just a moment.
But this is where our validation checks that should run immediately will live.
OK, now, right below this, let's create a time out that will only run after maybe eight hundred milliseconds.
So I would say this dot username.
Dot timer.
Right.
I'm creating a new property on this property and I would set this to equal so equal set time out and
then we give this to arguments.
So A comma B for the first argument I will give it an arrow function.
So parentheses arrow symbol.
We don't need curly brackets if we're just on one line with one statement.
But let's call a method that doesn't exist yet.
But we will create in just a moment.
So let's say this dot user name after delay parentheses to call it OK, and then instead of the B placeholder,
we say how many milliseconds we'd want to wait.
In reality, I'd probably go with 800.
But just to really prove the point that this is working, let's go with something large, like maybe
three thousand.
OK, now this method is going to run after every keystroke that changes the field's value.
Now, after each one of those keystrokes, I would want to reset this timer.
Right?
If someone types rapidly, I don't want this to run only if they have not typed in a new character after
three thousand milliseconds.
What I ever want to run this method.
So right above that line, we can just say clear time out and in the parentheses, just provide at the
time out we want to clear.
So this dot username, dot timer.
OK, now let's just create methods with these matching names of username immediately and username after
delay.
So let's create a brand new method username immediately.
Parentheses curly brackets.
For now, just as a test, let's log to the council and say immediate method just ran.
OK, then let's create a new method named user name after delay, user name after delay.
And in this case, let's show an annoying alert, pop up and stay alert after DeLay method finally ran.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in the browser, if I refresh and make sure that my browsers console is visible, so if I click,
inspect and then choose the console tab.
Notice that as soon as I begin typing in this field, we see these messages, but only after three thousand
milliseconds.
Does this eventually display now, as long as I just keep typing and never stop and wait three thousand
milliseconds, that alert is not going to display.
This is perfect.
But if I actually do stop typing and wait three thousand milliseconds.
There you have it.
Cool.
At this point, let's actually begin setting up the validation checks.
Let's begin with one of the validation checks that should run immediately, and that is if you include
a special character, write a character that is not alphanumeric.
So if you include any character that's not a through zero through nine, we should immediately display
a validation message right here that says we only allow numbers and letters in our usernames.
Let me show you how I would set that up.
So within our user name immediately method, let's get rid of this console, that log test line in its
place.
Let's write an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets now for the if condition, we would want to check to see if that field
contains any non alphanumeric characters.
Now in the past we achieved that on the server side by leveraging the validator package from NPM.
However, in this case, this is JavaScript that's going to run on the client side.
So in this case, I don't want to have to bundle the validator package along with our front end JavaScript,
because even when minified, the validator package is an extra thirty four kilobits that our visitors
would have to download.
In other words, let's go ahead and write this check ourselves.
So let's do this.
Let's say if this dot username dot value, let's first make sure that it's not completely empty or blank.
So if it does not equal an empty pair of quotes and so double ampersand and if it does contain a non
alphanumeric character, right then in here we could show the validation message that says that's not
allowed.
So for the second condition here, in order to check, to see if it contains a non alphanumeric character,
I would actually use something that's called a regular expression.
Now, we are not going to jump into a fully in-depth explanation of regular expressions.
That could be an hour or two rabbit hole.
So the next minute or two is not going to be very educational.
But if this intrigues you, I encourage you to learn more by researching on Google for regular expressions
in JavaScript.
OK, but let's go ahead and type this out forward slash and then a carrot.
So that's shift and then the six key and then a pair of parentheses within the parentheses include a
pair of square brackets and then say lowercase a dash lowercase z and then uppercase a dash uppercase
Z.
And then the number zero dash, the number nine after the closing square bracket include a plus sign
and then after the closing parentheses include a dollar sign.
Finally include a forward slash.
So from the forward slash to the closing forward slash, this is a regular expression and now we can
use it.
We can say dot, text parentheses and we would just want to test it against whatever the user has typed
into that field.
So just this dot username dot value.
Now this would evaluate to true.
If they've only typed in alphanumeric characters, we would want to check for the opposite of that.
Right.
We want to know if they typed in something that's not allowed.
So right before this opening forward slash to check for the opposite, we can just have an exclamation
cool.
Now within the curly brackets for this if block, let's just have an annoying alert message that says
username can only contain letters and numbers, OK?
And since we've already proved that our username after delay is working, let's get rid of that annoying
alert message.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in the browser, if I refresh, I'm free to type in a name with alphanumeric characters.
But the millisecond I try to use a character, that's not alphanumeric.
So for example, exclamation cool.
We immediately see the alert username can only contain letters and numbers.
Now we don't actually want.
To show an alert, we actually want to show a validation message right here, so let's make that happen
back in our text editor within our IF statement, let's get rid of this alert line.
And in its place, this method doesn't exist yet, but we can create it in just a moment.
Let's say this DOT show the validation, error, parentheses to call it, and this is going to be a
reuseable method.
So we'd want to give it to arguments to make it dynamic.
First, let's tell it which element or field we're working with.
So this dot username, comma, and then let's give it the message that we would want to display.
So quotes I will say username can only contain letters and numbers.
OK, now let's just go create a method with this matching name right below this new method show validation,
error, parentheses, curly brackets within its parentheses.
Let's have two parameters.
Let's call it E-L, short for element, comma and then message.
OK, within the body of this method, let's begin working with the element in question and then let's
look for the next HTML element right after it, because we know that that's going to be those red validation
boxes that we set up in a previous lesson.
So DOT next element sibling.
Right?
Remember those empty divs that we added?
Well, now we would just want to select its inner HTML and set that to equal whatever message is being
passed into this method.
And then we'd also want to make the red div box visible instead of invisible.
So on a new line, let's also select that element, look for its next element sibling, and then let's
adjust its class list.
And I would want to add a class of live validate message dash, dash visible.
All right, let's save this and test it out.
It's back in the browser.
If I refresh, if I type in an innocent username, nothing happens.
I can type in any of the numbers as well.
But if I include an exclamation cool you see immediately username can only contain letters and numbers.
Next, let's set things up so that the millisecond I get rid of the character that's causing the problem,
then the red validation box should disappear again.
Let me show you how I would set that up.
I want you to find your show Validation Error Method.
Let's add a new line within this method and let's deal with the element in question.
So l dot and then let's just create a new property on that called errors and let's set it to true.
Right.
Because if we ever call this method, that means that there is a problem or there is an error with this
field.
OK, now let's go find our user name handler method and lets out a line at the very start of the body
of this method.
And let's say this dot user name dot errors equals false.
So this way, each time this runs, we're giving the user a clean slate.
We're assuming that there are no errors.
We're setting this to false and then it's up to our validation checks to check each time.
Now, remember, our goal is if the user enters a problem character, write something that's not alphanumeric.
We would want to show this message.
But then on a future keystroke that removes the problem characters, we would want to hide this validation
message.
So let's do this within our user name immediately.
Method right below this.
If the checks for alphanumeric, let's add a new line and let's say if parentheses curly brackets and
for the condition.
Let's say if this username dot errors and then let's just check for the opposite of that.
So include an exclamation here.
So we're saying if errors is set to false meaning, if there are no errors, then within the if curly
brackets, let's hide that red error rectangle.
Now, the following method does not exist yet, but we can create it in just a moment.
Let's say this dot hide validation, error, parentheses to call that.
And then we'd want to tell it which field or which element we're talking about.
So let's just say this DOT username.
OK, now let's go create a method with this matching name.
So maybe right above show validation error.
We can create a new method and say hide validation, error, parentheses, curly brackets.
Be sure to give it one parameter.
Let's call it L short for element and then to save a bit of typing, you can actually look within show
validation error and just copy and paste this line where we add the class of dash dash visible.
So I would just copy that line of code and then within hyd validation error just pasted in only instead
of adding the class that makes it visible.
Let's just change add to remove.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I refresh.
I choose a username of new user.
Everything looks OK, but if I add an exclamation mark or an at symbol or anything else, we see the
error message.
But the millisecond I get rid of all of those problematic characters, you can see the message goes
away.
Perfect.
Next, let's set things up so that if you type in more than 30 characters for your username, you should
immediately see a validation message.
So back in our text editor within our user name, immediately method right below the if statement that
checks for alphanumeric.
Let's set up a new if statement.
Let's say if parentheses curly brackets for the condition, let's say this dot user name, dot value,
dot length.
If that is greater than 30, if this is the case, that's a problem.
So within our F block, we can just say this dot show validation error.
Let's give this to arguments.
So the first argument is the element in questions of this dot user name, comma, then we give it a
message.
So quotes, let's say user name cannot exceed 30 characters.
Let's go ahead and save that and test it out.
If I refresh.
If I start typing once I hit the limit of 30, you can see that message immediately appears.
If I go back down below 30 characters, it immediately hides the validation message.
If I go back over the limit and then if I go back under the limit, you get the idea.
It's giving me validation messages truly in real time.
Next, let's set up the validation check that says that your username must be at least three characters
long.
So within our text editor, let's look for the method that is named username after delay within the
body of that method.
I would just set up an if statement if parentheses curly brackets for the condition this dot username,
dot value, dot length if that is less than three.
If that's the case, we have a problem.
So within the if block I would say this dot show validation error.
The element in question is this dot username comma and then include a message of username must be at
least three characters.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So the idea is that the millisecond I begin typing, I would not want to see an annoying message telling
me my name is not long enough.
So if I begin typing, but I never wait three thousand milliseconds in between each letter, we don't
see the message right.
But if I only type in a letter or two and then actually wait, the three thousand milliseconds we do
indeed see username must be at least three characters.
And then as soon as I correct that problem and type in additional letters, you can see the validation
message goes away.
And that's actually going to bring this portion of the lesson to a close.
In our next video, we are going to work on the validation rule that checks to see if the user name
has already been taken or not.
Setting up that feature should be a lot of fun because it's going to use both the front end and the
back end.
So in addition to our live search feature, it should be fun to work on another feature that leverages
the Web browser.
No J.S. and Mongo DB.
I'm excited to set this up with you, so let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.