If I refresh the home page, it's still pulling in my real avatar, and now if I visit the create post
screen, awesome, it's using that uniform new header file.
Now, another area in our code where we can remove duplication is when we pass session data into the
current template that we want to render.
What I mean is I think it's safe to assume that for nearly every single template in our app, we are
going to want that template to have access to the current user session data like username and Avatar,
so on and so forth.
Let me show you what I'm getting at.
So back in our text, Ed, I want you to jump in to user controller J.S. within user controller, scroll
down to the bottom.
And we are interested in the home function.
If a user is logged in, they're going to see the home dashboard and we're going to need to pass that
template.
A bit of session data, right.
The user name and the avatar.
And we have this exact code that we want to pass into the template in our post controller as well.
So instead of duplicating this highlighted code, whenever we want to render a template with our unique
header, well, let's save a ton of duplication by creating a middleware function.
Let me show you how we can set this up.
So right now, I want you to jump in to our main app, JS file within our app file, maybe in between
when we call flash and pull in our router.
In between those two lines, let's add a new line and let's say app use within these parentheses.
Let's provide a function.
Within our functions, parentheses, let's include three parameters request response and next.
OK, and now within the function, I want to let you know that if we say response locals, well, we
are now working with an object that will be available from within our Ajay's templates so we can add
any objects or properties we want onto this locals object.
So let's just say dot user and then let's set that to equal request dot session dot user.
OK, then below this line, let's just be sure to call next.
So all together, when we say app dot use, we are telling Express to run this function for every request.
And because we are including this before our router, this means this will run first.
And then since we are calling next, Express will move on to run the actual relevant functions for a
particular route.
OK, but big picture, this means that we now have access to a user property from within any of our
SJS templates.
So let's go ahead and save this file and then let's jump into our two controller files and remove that
duplicated code where we passan session data to a template.
So first in user controller Gorgias down at the bottom within our home function for this response,
not render home dashboard.
We can just get rid of this second argument.
Cool.
Let's save that and then we can do the same thing within our post controller in post controller.
When we are rendering the create post template, we can now get rid of this second argument.
Let's go ahead and save that.
And now we just need to update our heterozygous and home dashboard SJS templates to pull from that new
user object.
Let's first jump into home dash dashboard and on line number five, when we say hello and then their
username, your feed is empty.
Well, instead of just looking for a properly named username, we would now want to look inside a user
object for that property.
OK, let's go ahead and save that.
And then finally, let's jump into our header SJS file and on line number twenty, when we are pulling
in the gravity image, let's just scroll over to its source.
And instead of looking for an Avatar property, we'd want to look within our user object for Avatar.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in the browser by refresh the create post screen, everything's still working.
And if I click this to go back to the home page, awesome.
We're still in business.
There's my username and there's my granddaughter.
Except now we don't have to manually pass in that session.
Data for every template render.
And while we're at it, let's go ahead and get rid of even more duplication.
Let's set things up so that our guest homepage template also pulls in our one shared header include
file.
Let me show you how we can set this up back in our text editor within our Views folder.
Let's jump into home dash guest SJS.
And before we delete all of this header code, let's first copy the login form into our clipboard.
So around line number seventeen, we see an opening form tag.
Go ahead and begin selecting there and then select down until the closing form tag.
Be sure to copy that into your clipboard.
What we're going to do is move that into our shared header, include file and then just check to see
if there is a user object on the section.
If there's not, then we can show them this form instead of the top right menu.
OK, with that in your clipboard, go ahead and select from this area that says header ends here and
just delete from there all the way up to the top of this file, OK?
And in its place, let's just say less than percentage dash.
Let's close that out.
Percentage greater than in between.
Let's just say include give it a path.
Look in the includes folder for header.
All right.
Let's go ahead and save that.
And now let's jump into that shared header file.
So within our views folder, inside includes there's header.
And I want you to focus on line number sixteen.
That's where we should see an opening H four or heading level for tag.
That H for Element represents our logo or home link in the top left.
Now the code right after that.
So right below sixteen should be different depen.
On whether you're logged in or not, if you're logged in, we want to show you this menu of options.
If you're not logged in, then right below this age, for we would want to have that log in form.
So do this with me right below line 16, add a new line and let's just set up if Elst blocks so in Ejaz
to do something dynamic, less than percentage to close that percentage greater than, let's say, if
parentheses curly brackets drop down right below the closing curly brackets for the if, let's say else,
curly brackets.
OK, now for our condition.
In these parentheses, all we have to do is just say user.
Right, because we created that function that's going to run for all requests.
And we said response dot locals, dot user.
Well, if it's able to find any relevant session data, then this would evaluate to true.
But if it's empty or doesn't exist, this will evaluate to false.
Let's start with the else block first.
So this would mean that the user is not logged in.
So within the else block, just paste in your clipboard.
Cool, so non logged in users see the login form for users that are logged in, all we need to do is
scroll down and just move this div with their profile photo and the log out form.
Just move this up into that if block.
So begin selecting this div and then select down to the closing log out form tag and then also select
one more closing div, but not two more closing div tags.
So let's cut that into our clipboard and then back within this if block just paste it in.
Now before we save this, we do need to pay attention to when we are dropping in and out of our dynamic
SJS mode on this first line with the IF statement after the opening curly bracket, we do want to drop
out of dynamic mode so percentage greater than and then on this line with the else at the beginning,
we'd want to drop back into dynamic mode.
So less than percentage at the end of this line drop back out, so percentage greater then.
And then finally on the line where we close the else block should be sure to jump into dynamic mode.
And then at the end we've already jumped out.
So let's go ahead and save this and test it out back in the browser.
If I refresh the homepage while I'm logged in, cool.
We still see the header.
That makes sense.
And if I visit the home page in a browser that's not logged in, if I refresh, we still see the log
in form.
Perfect.
Now let's complete one final super quick task before bringing this lesson to a close.
Since we've set up a reusable file for our header, let's go ahead and set up a reusable file for our
footer.
That way, our templates will not have any duplicated code.
So to set this up back in our text editor, let's start with our home dash guest SJS template.
Technically, you could start with any of our three main templates, Home Ghast, Home Dashboard or
create post.
But if you scroll down to the very bottom, you'll see this comment that says footer begins.
So just begin selecting right after that comment.
So include the opening footer tag down to the bottom of the file.
Let's copy that into our clipboard.
And now let's go create a separate include file for that.
So within our views folder inside includes let's create a new file, let's name it Footer Dot, SJS
in this new file, just paste in your clipboard and save now back in home, dash guest.
Just delete that code and also delete this comment.
Footer begins and let's just pull in that include so less than percentage dash close that tag out and
then just say include give it a path.
Look in the includes folder for footer to save typing.
Let's copy this include command into our clipboard.
And now let's just go update Home Dashboard and create post, so in-home dashboard SJS, scroll down
to the bottom where we see this comment footer begin.
Select that down to the very bottom.
Delete paste in your clipboard.
Save that.
Let's do the same thing for create dash post SJS down at the bottom.
Select from here down, replace it with your clipboard, let's save that looks like I forgot to save
home, Dash guessed, save that.
And now, no matter which template we go to homepage, create post or the guest homepage or footer is
still working and now our templates don't have any duplicated code.
I know this was a long, tedious lesson, but now that we've gotten rid of all that duplicated code
in our next lesson, we can actually work on the task of saving a post into the database.
Right.
We can get back to the actual task at hand of letting users create posts.
That should be a lot of fun to set up.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.