Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to continue working on our API to be more specific.
We are going to learn how to leverage a technology named JSON Web tokens.
All right.
So at the end of our previous video, we had set up a new route of slash API slash log in.
And if you send a post request to that route, including a bit of JSON with a valid username and password,
then the server will respond back with good job.
That is a real username and password only.
This is not an interesting or exciting response because remember, our goal for this API is to let users
create and delete posts.
And if you think about our application, remember, we set things up so that you need to be logged in
in order to create a post.
And then obviously to delete a post, you would need to be the owner or author of that post.
So what I'm getting at here is if someone sends a valid username and password combo to our API slash
login route, then we should respond with something that would allow that person to authenticate or
prove to us that they are who they just claim to be.
Right.
Something that they can use for their future requests when they try to create a post that would identify
them.
Now, when we created the Web browser version of our app, we used cookies and sessions to handle authentication.
But this time around for our API, we are going to do something entirely different.
If you think back to several chapters ago when we first learned about authentication and identifying
requests, I mentioned that there are two main ways of handling it.
No one is sessions and number two is tokens.
And as of today, the most common way of handling token based authentication is using something named
JSON Web tokens.
Instead of trying to explain with words what a JSON Web token is, let's instead just use them and see
them in action and then I can explain things along the way.
Now, when you want to use JSON Web tokens in a node application, we simply need to go to the JavaScript
grocery store or NPM.
So right now, jump into your text editor or command line.
And if your app is currently running, just press control.
See, because I want to run this command with you, so type this in with me.
NPM install in the name of the package that we're interested in is Jason Webb tokin all lowercase,
all one word.
So that's Jason Webb token.
Go ahead and press enter.
And just so you know that I'm not forcing you to install random obscure packages.
This is the official NPM website and you can see that the JSON Web Tokens package just in the last week
has been downloaded over two point six million times.
So in the world of JavaScript, this is the industry standard way of implementing JSON Web tokens.
OK, back in our command line, now that we've installed that package, let's tell our server to begin
running again.
So NPM run watch and now let's go leverage that package.
So within your controllers folder, I want you to jump into user controller J.S..
OK, now up at the top of this file, let's require in the JSON Web token package.
So I would just say const you can name it anything you want, but for sure I'll name it JWT equals and
then just require in that package of quotes, its name was JSON Web Token.
OK, now let's go actually use this within this file.
Look for your function that is named API log in.
So we set this up in the previous lesson.
For me it's around line number sixty eight, but it's the line that begins with exports.
Dot API log in.
So let's do this.
If the login is successful.
Right, if it's the real correct username and password, we still want to send back a response with
Jason.
But let's just get rid of this message text.
So get rid of the quotes with the text.
So now it's just response JSON and empty parentheses.
So instead, what we want to send as a response is a token.
So this is where we would use the JSON Web token package, let's say JWT and then let's look inside
it for a method named sine parentheses to callsign within the sine parentheses.
We're going to give it three.
Arguments, so just as placeholders, let's say a comma, B, Kamasi, for the first argument, instead
of the A placeholder, let's provide an object so curly brackets.
And this is where we include any data that we want to store in this token.
So previously when we used cookies and sessions, we stored things in session data like the user ID,
the user's username, maybe their avatar in this case with the API, really the only thing we'd need
to store is their user ID.
We don't need their user name or gravitas because we're not going to power a visual user interface.
So we really only need one property, let's say underscore Idy colon and then just give it a value of
lowercase user data, underscore ID.
So this is the only property we need in this object of data.
But the idea is you're free to include whatever you see fit.
OK, for the second argument, instead of this be placeholder.
This is where we include a secret phrase or a secret string of characters that the package will use
when it generates the token.
Now you could just include the string of text right here, but instead I'm going to include it in our
dot envy file.
So right now, do this with me in the root of your project.
I want you to jump in to the DOT N.V. file.
Let's drop down to a new line and we could make up any name we want, but let's call it JWT secret,
all capital letters and then include an equal sign, no spaces in between just the name and then equal
sign.
And now we don't even need quotes, but just go ahead and type in a random phrase.
So I'll say my super secret phrase and then you could even just add in a few random numbers.
You get the idea it doesn't matter what you type here, just as long as it's difficult to guess.
Go ahead and save this file.
And now back in our user controller instead of the B placeholder, let's pull in that environment variable
that we just created.
So that's process DOT, N.V. Dot and we named it all uppercase JWT secret.
OK, for the third and final argument, instead of the C placeholder, this is where we give it an object
of options.
By default, the token that this generates will never expire, which in my opinion maybe isn't the best
idea.
So I would want to set an expiration date.
So in the options object, I would say expires in uppercase II and then Colon quotes and then you can
say thirty m four minutes or thirty four hours.
The point is you can use any number in the letter.
So if you wanted a month you could say 30 D for 30 days or if you wanted a week you could say seventy
for seven days.
You get the idea, let's go ahead and save this and test it out in Postman.
So back in the Postman app, go ahead and send a new post request to slash API slash login.
Make sure that under the body tab you have raw selected and you have a bit of JSON with your correct
username and password also in your headers tab.
Make sure you have content type set to application JSON.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and send this new request and if we scroll down to the bottom, we see that the server
responded with this token.
Now, no matter if it's an iOS, Android, Windows, Mac or Linux app or even just a Web app, it's
up to the application that's leveraging our API to save or store or hold on to this token in some fashion
so that it can use this token again in the future.
Because this token proves to our server that you are the user that just logged in this token authenticate
you or identifies you.
So since we're not actually building another standalone application right now, I just want you to copy
and paste this token somewhere where you can hold on to it.
Actually, I don't know if it's just my computer, but I noticed the weird bug where if I.
Right.
Click on this to copy, it doesn't actually work.
So with it selected, try using your keyboard shortcut of control, see on windows or command, see
on Mac and then we don't need to permanently save it anywhere but just temporarily maybe in your text
editor open a new file or a new window and just paste it in.
Even if you lost this token, it's not a big deal.
You can just send a new request to slash API slash log in.
Anyways, moving on, now that our API is handing out tokens, let's set up a new route that would allow
users.
To create a post from our API, so do this up in the euro or address bar, change the ending portion
of the URL from log in to create Dasch post.
Right.
So now its API slash create post.
Let's also scroll up and make sure you click on the body tab and then have the raw option selected and
instead of a username and password, now we would want to include title and body values.
So let's do this.
Let's change the first property to title and give it a value of my new post through the API.
And then let's change the second property to body and just give it a value of this is the content for
my first post created through the API.
OK, and then in addition to title in body, let's include one more property.
So at the end of this line include a comma dropdown and let's include one more property.
So quotes and let's call it token.
We could name it anything, but that's just what I'm going to name it Colon and then quotes and then
in between the quotes, just paste in your clipboard.
The token should still be in your clipboard.
Cool.
Now, obviously, if we clicked send, this would not work because we have not created this route yet.
So let's go do that.