Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to update the rest of our application to work with our new system of protection.
Let me show you what I mean.
So at the end of our previous lesson, we saw that if a innocent user tries to sign out.
Our application now considers that a cross site request, forgery attempt.
This is because we set up the sign out button to submit a form that sends a post request to our server.
And we are now using the C surf package that's going to demand a six R.F. token on any post request.
Now, remember, we already updated our create post form screen to include that matching CSS, RF token
value.
So now we just need to do the same thing for our other forms.
Let me show you what I would do.
So within your text editor, jump back into the create dash post SJS template right within your views
folder.
Remember, we set up this hidden input with the name of Underscore RF and the value of the CSS RF token.
Go ahead and copy this entire input line into your clipboard because we're going to be pasting this
into several locations in our app.
So with that in your clipboard now, I want you to jump into your header file.
So within the views folder, look in the includes subfolder and then jump into header Ejaz.
OK, we are looking for the logout form.
For me it's a round line number twenty four.
So you should see a form element with an action of slash logout.
Let's do this within the form, maybe right above the submit button element.
Just paste in your clipboard.
Let's go ahead and give that a save and now let's test things out.
Be sure to reload the page so your front end has that new CSF token.
So now if I try to sign out, perfect, I was successfully logged out.
However, if I try to log back in.
Notice that attempt fails, so we would also just need to dig into our header and add the RF token to
the login form.
So for me, around line number 30, I see a form that points towards slash log in.
So maybe towards the end of that form, right above the sign in submit button to drop a new line and
paste in your clipboard.
Let's save that.
And now if I try to log in, by the way, be sure to refresh your page, because if you don't refresh
the front end, your front end isn't going to have that new RF token.
All right.
But now if I try to log in.
Perfect.
Now, even though we are logged in, let's not forget about new users that would see the guest registration
form, right.
So let's go update that right now within your views folder.
I want you to find the file that is named Home Dash Ghast SJS.
Right.
When new users come to the website and try to register or sign up, this is what they will see.
So he received a form with an action of slash register.
So maybe down towards the bottom of the form, here is the button that submits the form right above
that.
I would just paste in my clipboard.
Let's save that.
And then just really quick to test that if I logout.
And then try to fill out this form.
You'll notice that no matter what I choose as my username, it's going to tell me that it's already
been taken.
So before we can test to make sure that this form can submit without a ceasefire, we first need to
update our front end JavaScript that powers the live validation.
Because remember, we used Axios to send off a post request to check to see if a certain username has
been taken.
So that asynchronous post request would also need to send along the RF token.
Let me show you what I'm referring to.
So in your text, Ed, I want you to look within your front and dash Jase's folder and look in the module's
subfolder and jump into registration form dodginess.
So let's do this up in the constructor.
Let's create a property that grabs the X R.F. value from one of the hidden inputs on the page.
So I would just create a new property in the constructor, say this DOT, let's call it underscore C
SRF and set that to equal and then just say document dot query selector and then let's select that input
based on its name.
Now selecting based on name instead of a class or an ID is a bit trickier, but type this out with me.
So a pair of single quotes and then square brackets and then say name equals and then a pair of double
quotes and within that say underscore C.
S R.F..
OK, so this will select that input.
And then at the very end of this, after the closing parentheses, just say dot value.
Cool.
So now we are storing that matching RF token value in this property.
So now when we send off our axios requests, let's just pass this along with it.
So let's do this.
Let's scroll down and find our user name after delay method.
Here it is, user name after delay.
And remember, we said if there are no errors, then send off a post request using Axios.
Now, at the moment we're just sending over an object with one property of username.
But let's do this maybe right before that user name we can say underscore C SRF Colon and then just
give it a value of this dot, underscore CSS R.F. Be sure to include a comma.
Cool.
So now the data that we're sending to the server has two properties username and underscore CSS, RF
while we're at it, let's do the same thing for the e-mail check that sends a request to see if an email
has already been used.
So find your email after delay method.
Here it is.
And we said if there are no errors related to email, then send off an Axios post request.
So right within this object that we're sending over, just say underscore kowsar f colon.
Give it a value of this dot, underscore css R.F. Be sure to include the comma after that property value
pair.
Cool.
And now let's save this and test it out.
So be sure to refresh on the front end.
And now if I try to sign up with a random name, perfect, it's still available and if I type in a valid
email address and email and password and then try to submit.
Cool, the forum went through perfectly without triggering any RF problems.
Now, while we're at it, let's also fix our live search feature that is powered by front end JavaScript,
because remember, after you type something into the search bar, it's going to send off an asynchronous
post request to our server.
So let's do this back in your text editor within the registration form file that we were just in, scroll
back up to the very top so that we can copy this line into our clipboard, this line that adds an underscore
CSS, RF property.
Just copy that entire line and then let's do this.
Let's jump into our front end search file.
So within your front end JS folder and within the modules folder, jump into search dot J.S. towards
the very top of the constructor.
Let's just drop down and paste in our clipboard.
OK, now let's just scroll down and find the method that is named send request for me.
It's around line number fifty, but here we can see axios post.
So in the objective data that we're sending, just give it a new property.
So underscore c srf colon this dot underscore s R.F..
Be sure to include the comma.
Let's go ahead and save.
And now on the front end, if I refresh and then try to perform a search, maybe if I search for lorem
ipsum or just search for something that you know will bring back results.
Cool.
There we see the results.
So at this point, let's review.
We've adjusted our sign in, sign out and registration and search form.
We know that in the previous lesson we adjusted our create post form.
Why don't we go update our edit or update post form right off camera?
Let me sign back into my account, OK?
And if I go to my profile to view one of my existing posts, so innocent post if I try to edit this
post.
So it takes me to this screen because that was a request.
But if I make a change to the post and then try to perform a post request, we should see a six hour
F error.
Yep.
So all we need to do is update that edit form.
So within your text editor, let's save ourselves a bit of typing by jumping back into our create dash
post SJS template and just make sure that you had the hidden CSF input copied into your clipboard.
So I will copy that.
OK, and then I want you to jump into the template that is named edit dash post dot SJS towards the
bottom of the form right above the submit button.
Just paste in your clipboard.
Let's save that.
And now we should be able to go back and try to edit one of our posts.
Maybe I'll add a few exclamations and then hit Save Perfect, next, let's cover the ability to delete
an existing post, for example, maybe I will try to delete this post that's titled Hahaha, you've
been hacked.
So if I view that post and then try to click the red trashcan, we're probably going to see the CSS
RF error.
Yep.
So to fix this, just jump in to the exact template that is named single dash post dash screen.
And for me it's a round line number 12.
But you're looking for a form that has a class of delete post form, as you might have guessed, just
right above that submit button paste in your clipboard.
Let's give that a save.
And now if I go back to that post refresh and try to delete it, it should go through successfully.
Perfect.
At this point, we just need to update our Biggin following and stop following actions.
So visit a user profile for someone other than yourself.
So if I go to the Bachs lot profile, let's just update the stop following and begin following form
submits.
So within your text editor.
So within your views folder, look in the includes subfolder and then jump into the file that is named
Profile Shared.
Cool.
So here we see the form to remove a follow, as you might have guessed right above that submit button,
just paste in your clipboard and do the same thing for the ad follow form.
So right above the button paste, lets go ahead and save this and refresh the front end.
So let's make sure that I can stop following Bachs a lot.
Cool successfully stopped following barks a lot, and then if I change my mind and want to begin following
them again, just click follow.
Perfect, successfully followed barks a lot, and that's actually going to bring this lesson to a close,
we have successfully protected our application against CSF attacks and we've also updated all of our
features and forms with this new Ceaser Tolkan requirement in place.
In our next lesson, we are going to work on our final feature before we push this application up onto
the Web.
We're going to learn how we would set up our own API.
If you have no idea what an API is, that's OK.
We will review that.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.