Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we're going to continue working on our follow feature, let's jump right into the action.
So in our previous lesson, we set up this follow button.
Well, now, in this lesson, if I'm already following this user, I should instead see a button here
that says stop following.
Now, before we rush to create that logic or functionality, let's first realize that there are multiple
pages within a user's profile.
Right now, we're on the default view or the posts view, but we're also going to want to be able to
click on followers or following to go to different pages to see a list of their followers and a list
of who they are following.
What I'm getting at here is on all three of these pages, we would still want to know if you're following
the current user or not.
So what I want to do is create a function or an area that can run for all three of these different routes.
Let me show you how I would do this.
So within our text editor, I want you to open up your router JS file.
OK, here we see a comment profile related roots, right?
Slash profile, slash user name.
The first function checks to see if there's an account with that matching username, if it even exists.
If it does exist, then we're also calling profile posts screen.
Here's what I'm going to do in between these two functions.
So right about here, let's call a function named shared profile data and we can reuse this function
for the other two routes as well.
So for now, for the slash profile slash user name route, right after the if user exists, let's add
another function call user controller DOT shared profile data, comma.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now we better go create a function with this matching name within our user controller.
So in our controllers folder, let's dig in to user controller James.
We want to create a new function.
It doesn't matter where we could create it right at the top here.
So I would just say exports dot shared profile data should equal a function.
And within the parentheses, let's be sure to include three parameters, not only request and response,
but also next, right after this function does its job, we want to call next.
So the final function for this route can run.
OK, now that we've created this reusable function that can be leveraged for multiple U.
URLs or routes, let's get back to the actual question or task at hand.
So when a user visits a profile screen, we want to know if the current visitor is already following
this account or not.
So let's do this within the body of our new function here.
Let's create a variable.
Let's say let's is following and by default, let's set it to false.
But right below this, let's write an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition, if the current visitor is signed in or logged in.
So if request session user.
Well, if the current visitors logged in, then let's just ask our follow model.
If this current visitor is following the current profile before we try to leverage our follow model
here up at the top, we need to require in or import the follow model to save a bit of typing.
You can just duplicate one of these lines, copy paste, change this to const follow and change this
to require in the follow file.
OK, now within our IF statement, let's do this, let's say uppercase follow.
We haven't created this method in our follow model yet, but you can imagine that in 30 seconds or so
we will, let's say, is visiter following.
In order for this method to do its job, we'd need to pass it two things, either the user name or ID
of the current profile.
So in this case, the bark's a lot account.
Let's go ahead and give it the ID.
So request profile user dot, underscore ID.
This will already exist on our request object from our function named.
Does user exist or I believe the exact name was if user exists.
OK, the other piece of data this method would need to do his job is the current visitor ID.
So let's just include a comma here and say request dot visitor ID.
OK, now we have not created this method in our model yet, but since it's going to have to visit the
database, it's going to take a while to complete.
So at.
Start started this line, let's be sure to await also, you can imagine that will set this function
up to eventually return either a value of true or false right.
Is the current visitor already following this profile account or not?
Let's store the true or false value that this is going to return in.
This is following variable.
So at the start of this line, we can just say is following and update its value.
OK, finally after this if statement, we would now have a correct, true or false value.
So let's just add that on to the request object.
Let's say request dot is following equals our local is following, variable is following.
At this point, this function has done its job.
So then we can call next.
OK, let's go ahead and save this.
And now we better go into our follow model and make sure that it has a function named is Visiter Following.
So within our Models folder, let's jump in to follow Dot J.S. let's scroll down to the very bottom
and right before the closing module, dot exports, let's say uppercase follow dot is visiter following
and this should equal a function within these parentheses.
Let's be sure to include two parameters.
So followed idee colon visitor Idy.
Now within this function, we know that we're going to need to talk to a database.
So let's just go ahead and make this function asynchronous right away.
So async cool within the body of this function.
Let's do this.
Let's create a variable.
We could name it anything, but let's call it follow doc and let's set it to equal.
And then I just want to look within our follows collection in our database.
So follows collection and then I want to see if I can find so dot find one.
I want to see if I can find an existing document where the followed ID matches the current profile I'm
viewing and the author ID matches the current account I'm logged in with.
So let's do this within the parentheses for find one.
We would include an object so curly brackets and describe what we're looking for.
So let's say we want the followed ID field to have a value of this parameter.
So followed I d comma.
We're also looking for the author ID property Colon to match the current ID of the logged in or visitor
user.
Now we don't just want to pass that string of characters, we want it to be a Mongo DB object ID object
so we can say create a new instance of object ID and then pass that visitor ID.
Cool.
Now altogether this is going to return a promise.
So at the start of this, let's be sure to include a wait.
We want to wait for that database action to finish now below this line.
Let's just set up an if else.
So if parentheses curly brackets also add an else block.
Now we can just say if follow doc, if this is able to find a document matching our conditions, well
then let's just return a value of true else.
Let's just return a value of false.
Let's save this and then jump back into our user controller file to refresh our memory of what's going
on.
So this function of shared profile data is going to run for a profile route like when I'm visiting Bachs
allots profile by default or setting a is following property of false.
But if the current visitor is logged in, then we can check to see is this visitor following the current
profile.
So that's either going to be true or false.
We're storing that value on the request object so that we can use it within our next function for this
route.
So let's go find that next function.
I believe it has a name of profile screen or view profile posts screen.
Yep.
Towards the bottom of our user controller here we see exports dot profile posts screen.
So when we are rendering the profile template, let's just pass in a new bit of data.
So maybe right after this property we could add a comma and then say maybe a property named is following
and give it a value of request.
DOT is following.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now let's jump into that profile template.
Right.
The edges or HTML that controls this screen.
We can use that true or false value to show either the follow button or the stop following button.
So back in our text editor within the root of our project, Look for your views folder within views,
look for profile.
Dot Ejaz towards the top around line number eight, we see an opening form tag.
So that is the form that contains the start following button.
Let's do this let's go ahead and cut the entire form element into our clipboard, so it should just
be four lines of code for the entire form.
Let's cut that.
And in its place, let's set up an if statement.
So drop into SJS.
We do not need the equal sign because we're not outputting or escaping anything.
We just want an if statement.
So then I will close the edges inside it.
Let's set up and if parentheses curly brackets for starters, let's say only if user.
Right.
Only if you're logged in should you see either of the follow or stop following buttons.
OK, now within this if statement, let's add one more if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets this time below that we also want an else block for the condition.
Let's just say is following.
If this is true, if the current visitor is already following this profile, then this is where we'd
want to show the stop following button else.
Otherwise this is where we'd want to show the begin following button.
So within the block right now, we can just paste in our clipboard.
This is good to go.
Now let's also paste in our clipboard within the IF block, but we need to make a few adjustments.
So first of all, for the action instead of ad follow, this would be remove follow.
OK, and then for the actual button that you click on, you can just get rid of this existing button.
And below that we see a commented outline.
Let's uncommented this.
So get rid of this beginning portion and then at the end, get rid of the dash dash greater than OK.
And that is the red stop following button.
Now that we've got that set up, we can go ahead and remove that comment and outline from the else block.
We no longer need it there.
I only included it there for your reference.
Cool.
Now, before we test this out, we need to pay attention of when we should drop out and drop back into
SJS on this line with the second if statement after the opening curly bracket.
Let's drop out of SJS and then on this line with else at the beginning, let's drop back in to SJS.
At the end of the line, we can drop out of SJS and then finally right after the final form tag.
But before this closing curly bracket, we can drop back into SJS.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
Oops.
Looks like we have an error in our user controller file.
So jump into user controller and up at the very top within our shared profile data function, we used
the await feature, but I forgot to make this an async function right here.
Just say async.
Let's give this to save and go test it out.
So back in the browser, as soon as I refresh, I should now stop following button because I'm already
following Bachs a lot.
So if I refresh.
Perfect.
Now let's go set up a route to support the slash remove follow Eurail pattern.
Right.
Because that's the route that this form is going to submit to.
Let me show you what I mean.