Hello, everyone.
Right away, I want to emphasize that this video is optional.
If you don't consider yourself an intermediate to advanced student, I recommend skipping this video.
However, some of you may not want to sign up for the free MongoDB Atlas Cloud account that we set up
in the previous video, and you would rather host your database locally on your own computer.
Now that does mean that you won't be able to push your applications up onto the web to share with your
friends and family.
So if you do want to be able to share your apps, be sure that you use the Atlas Cloud approach from
the previous video.
So this video represents an alternate path.
If you are OK with your apps in this course, just being for your own personal experiments and you're
the only one that can view them if you're OK with that and you would prefer to host your databases locally.
Well, then this video will show you how to do that.
To get started, we need to make sure that we have something called Docker installed on our computer,
so you can visit the official website Docker dot com, and in particular, we're looking for something
called Docker Desktop.
So if you look under products, here it is Docker desktop.
You click on that it is completely free to download and use.
So just choose the appropriate version for your computer.
All of the default options should be great, so you can just click next next next through the installation
once your download finishes.
So feel free to pause this video lesson right now while you go and install Docker on your computer.
OK, but once you resume the video at this point, I'm going to assume that everyone now has Docker
installed on their computer.
So up next in Udemy, you'll find a downloadable file for this video lesson called host Mongo locally
dot zip.
So I want you to pause the video, go ahead and download the zip file.
When you extract it, you'll get a folder and it has just two files inside it.
This Docker composed why HTML file?
This will configure Docker perfectly to spin up a MongoDB instance.
And then this other file connections drinker?
Well, we will need the value inside this file in just a minute.
But for now, we don't need to pay attention to either of these files.
What you need to do is point a command line towards this new folder that you extracted from the ZIP.
So you can see I have this folder open in vs code.
So if you open your terminal well, then your command line will be pointing towards that folder.
And now you just need to run this one command with me.
Docker compose up.
Go ahead and press enter.
And assuming that Docker is installed and up and running on your computer, that's really all we need
to do.
Now you will need to wait here, perhaps a minute or two.
I believe the download size is about 700 megabytes for the MongoDB image, but you'll know that things
are ready when you stop seeing a new constant stream of text in the command line.
Cool.
So this means that Docker is now hosting MongoDB locally on our computer.
Now the question becomes How do we actually connect to it or view it?
Well, there is an excellent free tool officially from MongoDB called Compass.
So from the MongoDB website, or, you know, you can just perform a Google search for MongoDB Compass.
Go ahead and download now it's a free download and then come back and resume this video.
Once you have MongoDB Compass installed, when you open MongoDB Compass, the application will look
something like this and you can see here to connect to a database, you provide a connection stream.
Now this is that text file that I provided for you in the folder.
So remember when we downloaded that zip a couple of minutes ago?
If you jump into the connections, drinks, text file, just select this value control or command.
Select the entire thing.
Copy it into your clipboard.
And then back in MongoDB Compass.
In this field, just paste in your clipboard and click Connect.
From this screen, let's use the Green Create database button.
So we've connected to a database server, but you can have as many databases on that server as you want.
So maybe let's name this database example and let's have a collection name of items.
And then down at the very bottom, it's falling off the edge of my screen, but there's a green create
database button.
You can click that cool and now you see example database from here.
This interface is almost identical to the MongoDB Atlas Cloud account screens that you'll see throughout
the videos.
In other words, if you click on this collection of items.
Well, this screen is going to look.
Virtually identical to these screens throughout the course when you see me working with a database in
my web browser.
So you should be able to follow along quite nicely.
Now when it comes to connecting a node J.S. application to this database.
Well, again, that's what your connection string is for.
So if you take a look at your connection string after the root root, local host and the port number
and then a slash, you see this your name here, you would simply change that to the specific database
that you want to work with.
So we just created a database called example.
So you would change this to be example, and then you would use this entire connection string within
your Node.js code files to connect to the database.
However, don't worry about getting too many steps ahead of yourself.
For now, you have a MongoDB database up and running locally, and that's really all we need to accomplish
in this video.
So now you can continue to follow the course step by step.
Only in a future VIDEO When I say, you know, use your MongoDB Atlas Cloud account connection string.
Well, obviously instead, you would use this as your connection stream really quick.
Let's talk a little bit more about Docker.
So in the command line, if you click down there, you can press control, see, and that will stop
your Docker container from running.
Now, if you want to start it up again, you use a different command.
So we used Docker compose up.
That's just what you run the very first time to sort of create things, but you only run it that one
time initially.
So now to start your database server up again, it's Docker compose start.
Go ahead and press enter.
And now it's just running in the background.
So Control C wouldn't stop it.
Now, if you wanted to stop it, you would say Docker compose stop.
Now those commands are the same thing as just going into your Docker desktop application.
Here you can see host Mongo locally, and instead of saying Docker compose start, you can just click
this play or start button.
OK, and then once it's running instead of Docker Compose Stop, you can just click this button.
Cool.
That is going to bring this video to a close.
Let's keep our momentum rolling.
And I'll see you in the next one.