Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to get started creating our next new act together, let's not waste any
time.
Let's begin by creating a completely brand new empty folder on our computer for this new project.
So on my desktop here, I'm going to create a brand new folder and I will give it a name of complex
app.
So right now, be sure that you create a brand new empty folder with me.
Just create it somewhere that you can easily find again in the future.
And then we want to go ahead and open this new empty folder within our text editing program.
OK, and now let's create a new file within this folder.
Let's name this new file app, Dot J.S..
All right.
And within this file, this is where we will use the express framework to create a server that listens
for incoming requests.
So we're going to need to go out to the JavaScript grocery store or NPM to pick up Express.
So let's open up our command line.
And before we install any packages, let's first create our package, JSON file that will act as our
recipe list or ingredient list to do this type in this command with me, npm inmet and then dash y press
enter.
Cool.
So that created this package JSON file, which will keep track of all of the packages that our app needs.
So with that in place now, let's install Express.
So in the command line, run this with me.
NPM install in the name of the package is Xpress.
Go ahead and press enter.
OK, and now within our empty aptness file, we can actually use Express, so for our first line of
code, write this out with me.
Let's create a variable and name it express instead.
It's equal and then just require in the express package now just a random JavaScript tip instead of
using let here let's get rid of let we can instead say consed.
The difference between const and let is that a let variable can be reassigned.
So with let we can give it an initial value and then later on we can change that value.
We could come down here and say, you know what, express should actually equal the number five.
That would be valid JavaScript.
However, if instead of let we say const this stands for constant, it means that we cannot reassign
it with a new value.
So if we came down here and said, now express should equal the number five JavaScript would throw an
error telling us that we are not allowed to reassign a constant variable.
So the idea here is that if you're in a situation where you're never going to need to change the variable,
it's best to use const instead of let.
Const is a nice contextual clue that improves the readability of our code.
Now, when we or any of our co-workers look at our code, we immediately see CONSED and know that this
variable is not going to change big picture.
That sort of predictability is a good thing.
It's just nice to have another tool in your toolbox.
In some situations.
Let will be the right call.
In other situations.
CONST makes more sense.
All right, enough with that tangent.
Now that we have this constant variable named Express, let's actually use it.
So on a new line, let's create another constant variable named app and let's set it to equal and then
just call Express.
Next up, let's tell our app what it should do if it receives a get request to the base uttara so we
can say app dot get for the first argument, just a forward slash to represent the home page.
You are l.
Let's include a comma.
And for the second argument, we just provide a function.
So function parentheses, curly brackets within our functions.
Parentheses.
Let's include parameters of our Q and our Yes Right Express is going to pass those objects into our
function when it calls our function.
And just as a quick test within the body of our function, let's just send back a response.
So response send.
And for now let's just have it be a string of text that says welcome to our new app.
Cool.
Finally for now, down at the very bottom of this file, let's tell our app to begin listening for incoming
requests.
So we just say app.
Listen, let's tell it to listen on PT. three thousand four.
Now, let's go ahead and save this file and test it out by trying to visit in our browser.
So down in the command line, let's launch our app by running node and then the name of our file.
So in this case, node app, go ahead and press enter and then over in our Web browser, if we visit
local host Colen three thousand.
Awesome.
We see.
Welcome to our new app.
Now, this is not what we actually want to send to our visitors.
What we actually want to send is the HTML that will create this Web page.
But this is not a course about HTML and success.
This is a course about JavaScript.
So it would not be an efficient use of our time to type out this HTML template together, character
by character.
Instead, let me show you where you can copy and paste this HTML template from.
So right now, open up a new tab in your web browser and I want you to visit GitHub dot com slash learn
web code, slash JavaScript.
Now, there are a couple of different ways that you can copy and paste the reference code if you'd like
to.
You can download a copy of this entire repo to your computer.
So if you look for this green clone or download button and then click on that, there's an option here
named download it this way, you can find the folders and files on your computer and use a text editing
program on your computer to open up the relevant file and then copy and paste its contents.
That's one way, another way, just directly in your Web browser would be to click onto this.
Oh, to underscore complex underscore app folder.
And from this screen, we are interested in this folder named O1 underscore HTML templates, and even
if you downloaded the zip file for this rebo, you would still need to navigate this folder structure.
But within this O1 HTML templates folder, this is where you'll find all of the different static HTML
templates that we are going to use for this complex application or app number two for right now.
In this particular instance, in order to create this user interface, this home page that a guest or
someone who is not logged in would see, we are interested in this file named Home Dash Guest HTML.
If you downloaded the zip, you'll just want to open up this file and copy everything inside of it or
within your Web browser.
You can just click on this home dash guest and then from this screen you can finally click on this raw
button and that will show you the raw contents of the file from here.
I just want you to select everything you can press control A or command AI to select everything, and
then just copy that into your clipboard.
All right.
So now in our clipboard, we have the HTML that will create this page or this user interface.
So now back to our express application.
Remember, at the moment, it's just saying welcome to our new app.
So let's jump back into our text editor and remember that this time around with this application, we
do not want to create a tangled mess of spaghetti code.
So instead of just including everything within our Apgar's file, let's start breaking things out into
separate files where each file has its own responsibility.
In other words, we do not want to paste in that HTML template in place right here.
Instead, I'm going to show you a much more organized way of handling this within the root of our brand
new project folder.
I want you to create a new subfolder so I can right click in this area and choose new folder.
And technically, we could name this folder anything, but just so you and I are on the same page.
Let's both name this new folder views and this new folder will contain all of our HTML templates or
views.
Now, let's go ahead and create a new file in our views folder.
And let's name this file home dash ghast dot SJS, do not worry, I will explain what the dot means
in just a minute or two.
OK, and within that brand new empty file of home dash guest, I want you to paste in your clipboard.
Cool, so we now have this dedicated file just for this template.
Be sure to save that.
And now let's jump back into Applegate's.
So now, instead of responding to this request by sending a bit of text, we instead just want to render
that entire template file.
To be able to do that, we need to configure our express application a bit.
So right above this app, Dot Getline, let's write a new line of code and let's say app dot set and
we want to set the views configuration option.
So views in quotes and then comma next argument.
And then this is where we provide the name of whatever folder we created for our views.
So this first part needs to be exactly views.
This is an express option.
And then this second views just happens to be viewed because that's what we named our folder.
You could have named it something else, though, and then that value would go here.
OK, so now Express knows where to look to find our views or our templates on the next line of code,
we need to let express know which templating engine or which template system we are using.
So we say app dot set.
First argument is view engine and then the second argument for now I'm just going to include an X placeholder.
This is where we tell Express which template engine we are using.
We have many different options to choose from in the JavaScript community.
You might have heard of popular choices such as Pug or Handlebars or SJS.
SJS is actually the one that we're going to use in this course.
So that's why we named our file, ending with DOT SJS.
Each different template language has its own syntax and features.
So back to this line of code instead of the X placeholder, let's include quotes and just say SJS.
Now, if we're telling Express here that we want to use the Aegis engine, we better go out to the JavaScript
grocery store or NPM and actually install SJS.
So let's go down to our command line, press control, see to quit the server and type this in with
me.
NPM install in the name of the package is simply SJS.
Go ahead and press enter.
Cool.
So now that we've configured our view or template engine, we are ready to actually use it.
So check this out for this git request for the homepage instead of saying response dot send, let's
get rid of that.
And in the body of this function we can instead say response dot render within the parentheses for this
render method.
We just give it the name of a template or a view.
So quotes we named our file home dash guest.
You do not need to include the DOT SJS at the end here when referencing the template.
All right.
With this in place, let's go ahead and save this file and test it out.
So down the command line, be sure to start up your server again.
Node app.
All right.
And then back in our browser at localhost three thousand if we refresh.
Cool.
Although we can see that we're missing a bit of success or styling this top header bar should be a very
dark gray or black.
That's OK.
We can go ahead and set up that txt file or those styles.
Right now let's jump back to our text editor and we want to create a new subfolder within our main project
folder.
So new folder.
And let's name this new folder public.
Remember, we set this up for our to do app as well.
And this is the folder where we can keep things like CSC files or our browser based JavaScript files
that we want to be accessible by anyone who views our app.
So now that we've created this new public folder, we want to tell our express server to make that folder
accessible.
So maybe right above these app set lines, let's add a new line and say app dot use.
Inside the parentheses, we can just say express dot static, which is a method so it gets its own set
of parentheses, and inside those we just include a string of text and include that folder name.
Be sure to save that.
And now we just want to add a CSC file into this public folder.
So back in your browser tab where you visited the GitHub repository a few minutes ago, if you click
back into that HTML templates folder.
Right, the same directory where you found the home dash guest HTML file within this same directory,
you'll also find a file named Main Dot CSX big picture.
We just want to include this file within our public folder.
So if earlier you downloaded an entire zip of this repo, you can just copy and paste or move this file
into the public folder or in your browser, you can just click on Maned Access and then click this raw
button.
And then just select all of this and copy it into your clipboard and then back in our text editor.
Let's create a new file in that public folder and I will name it main success.
Inside that file, just paste in your clipboard and save cool, this includes all of the matching styles
and custom styles for the HTML templates that we will be using.
Finally, one more CSFs related change.
I want you to go back into our home dash guest, Ejaz File and online No.11.
I want you to find the attribute and write before the letter M in Maine.
I just want you to add in a forward slash just like this.
The reason I didn't include the forward slash here for you by default is because if you wanted to download
that zip file for the repo, you could actually just double click each of those HTML templates to preview
them.
Right.
And it would be able to find the CSFs file so you could visually see what the template is going to look
like.
But for this to work within the context of our application, we do want to include a forward slash here.
All right.
Let's go ahead and save this file and then let's be sure to quit our server and relaunch it down in
the command line.
Don't worry, we can set up automatic restarts for our application in just a minute or two.
So in the command line or press control, see to quit and then just fire up the app again.
And if we refresh in the browser, awesome.
Now we have all of the custom styles ready to go.
Now, since no one enjoys having to manually quit and relaunch a node app every time you make changes.
Before we bring this video to a close, let's set up automatic restarts.
So back in our text editor, the first step would be to quit our server because we want to go out to
the JavaScript grocery store and pick up a package.
So type in this command with me, NPM install.
And the name of the package is Node Maun.
You might remember that we use this in our to do app.
Let's go ahead and press enter.
OK, and then to actually use that node MOND package, we want to jump in to our package JSON file towards
the top of packaged JSON.
We see this area code named Scrimps within scripts, maybe right above this test line.
Let's add a new line and let's say quotes and let's name this watch and then a colon and then a pair
of quotes after the pair of quotes.
Be sure to include a comma.
All right.
But inside the quotes, we can just say Node Gnomon app.
If you named your main server file something other than Applegate's, you would use the file name here.
We just don't need to include the dot js to reference it here.
All right.
Now, if we go ahead and save this file, we can run this watch command by going to the command line
and running NPM run watch.
Cool, so our application is still available from localhost three thousand, except now we are free
to make changes without having to quit and relaunch, quit and relaunch, and that's actually going
to bring this lesson to a close.
Looking ahead to our next lesson, we are going to learn how to make our app JS file even more organized.
For the moment, we only have this one euro or this one route to look out for.
But you can imagine that as your application grows in complexity, you're going to have quite a few
routes to be listening for.
And we don't want to clutter up this main app that just file right.
With larger projects, organization becomes more and more important.
So we want to start creating separate files with distinct responsibilities.
With that in mind, in our next lesson, we are going to learn how to create something that is called
a router.
Setting up a router is an essential part of staying organized.
So let's keep the momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.