Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to continue working on our registration form to be more specific.
We're going to set up the validation rule that checks to see if the user name that the user has typed
in has already been taken or not.
If they've typed in a name that already exists, then they should see a message here, letting them
know that that name is not available.
So without further ado, let me show you how I would set that up.
Let's jump into our text editor and make sure that you've opened up the registration form JS file and
we're going to begin by importing the NPM package named Axios.
Axios will make it very easy to send off an asynchronous request to our server.
So up at the very top, even above our export default line, let's say import axios from and then just
quotes Axios.
We already used the axios package during our live search feature, so we do not need to worry about
going to the command line and running NPM install.
OK, now let's go leverage Axios.
I want you to find the method that is named username after delay.
Here it is.
Currently, the only thing we're doing in this method is checking to see if the username is less than
three characters long now within this username after delay method.
But after this existing, if Jack is right below that, let's set up a new if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets, I would only want to send off a request to our server if there are
no other problems with this potential user name.
What I'm getting at is if the user has typed something in that has invalid characters, then there's
no point in sending a request to the server to see if that username exists.
We know for a fact that it doesn't exist.
So for our new IF statement for the condition, I would just say only if this dot username dot errors
and then I would check for the opposite of that with an exclamation here.
So only if there are no problems with the current value, then within these if curly brackets, I would
say this axios dot post right after the parentheses for post.
Let's include a dot then and right after those parentheses let's include a dot catch.
Let's provide arrow functions within both the then and catch parentheses parentheses arrow symbol.
Curly brackets do the same thing for catch.
So parentheses arrow symbol curly brackets.
OK, and now let's shift our focus to the parentheses right after post.
Within these parentheses we give it to arguments.
So A comma B and the first argument is the you are rel that we want to send a request to.
So instead of the placeholder a let's say quotes and then let's say forward slash for the root of our
server and then this Utrillo root does not exist yet.
We can set it up in just a moment or two.
But let's say does username exist.
OK then for the second argument instead of the B placeholder we provide an object so curly brackets
and this is any data we want to send along to the server.
So let's give this object a property.
We could name it anything, but let's name it username Colon.
And then I would just grab the current value of whatever the user is typed into the field.
So this dot username, dot value.
All right.
And then you can imagine that on our server we will set up a root to match this.
You órale and the server will send back a response of either true or false based on the current username.
Now, once Axios receives that response from the server, then our function within the then area will
run.
So within the parentheses for our then function, let's say response, OK, and then within the body
of that then function, let's just set up an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets right after the closing, if let's also add an else block gain for
the if condition, let's say if response data.
Right.
Because this does username exist, Routt is going to respond with true or false.
So if it responds with true, that means the username already exists.
So if that username does already exist, then within these curly brackets we would want to show that
red validation error message.
So we could just say this dot show validation error.
Give it to arguments, the first would be the element in question, so this username, comma, and then
a message, let's say that username is already taken still within the if block.
Let's drop down one more line and let's set a property of this username.
DOT is unique and let's set this to false.
This will come into play later.
Ultimately, a bit later on.
We will not want to let the user submit the overall form unless we are happy with all of the values.
Right.
So this code's only going to run if there's a problem, if that username is already taken and then within
the else block, this would mean the username is available.
So within the else block, let's just say this dot username dot is unique and set it to true, OK.
And then finally within the function for catch, well this would only ever run if there's some sort
of unexpected technical difficulty.
So for now I would probably just log a message out to the console and say, please try again later.
OK, at this point, let's go ahead and save this.
And now let's set up a route within our server side or within express that matches this U.
URL right forward slash.
Does user name exist?
So within the root of your project folder, look for the file that is named Rouda J.S..
Here we see a comment that says user related routs, so maybe at the end of that section we could say
router dot post for the first argument quotes and then slash.
Does user name exist after the quotes?
Let's include a comma.
And the second argument is a function that we'd want to run.
This function doesn't exist yet, but we can create it in just a moment.
Let's say user controller DOT, does user name exist?
OK, let's go ahead and save this file and now we better jump into our user controller and create this
method.
So within your project controllers folder, let's look for the file that is named user controller.
Within this file, we want to create a new function.
It doesn't matter where.
Maybe up at the top here we can just say exports DOT does user name exist and set that to equal a function
and then let's begin leveraging our user model.
So uppercase user and we actually already have a method on the model named find by user name.
Within these parentheses.
We would just pass it the user name that we're interested in in order to do that within our overall
functions parentheses, we'd want to include parameters of request and response.
All right.
And then in the find by username parentheses, we can just say request body dot user name.
Right.
That's what the axios request is sending over to the server.
All right.
Now, this method on our model is going to return a promise.
So at the end of this line, after the parentheses, let's just say dot then and then at the end of
that dot catch.
Now, to refresh your memory on the way that we set up this promise, it's going to resolve with the
user document.
If it finds one, if it doesn't find a user document by that username, it's just going to reject.
Now, remember, we want this does user name exist function to respond with the value of either true
or false?
So here's what I would do within the then parentheses.
Let's give it a function function, parentheses, curly brackets within the body of this function.
I would just say response JSON with the value of true.
Right, so that's the data that our axios request will receive.
And then within the catch parentheses I would provide a function, function, parentheses, curly brackets
and then I would just say response JSON with a value of false.
OK, let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So be sure to refresh on the front end.
And if I choose a username of unique that should still be available.
However, if I try to sign up with the user name of Brad and then wait three thousand milliseconds,
perfect.
I see that username is already taken at this point.
We are done with the user name field.
Now let's focus on the email field.
So to start working on that, back in our text editor.
Let's jump back into registration form, Gorgias, and scroll up to the very top.
Let's look within our constructor and right below these lines that begin with this DOT username.
Let's just drop down and add a new line and say this dot email equals and then we will select that element,
document dot query selector and it has an ID.
So hash tag of email, Dasch register right below that.
Let's also say this dot e-mail dot previous value equals an empty pair of quotes.
OK, now let's begin listening for key presses on that email field.
So within our events area we can actually just copy and paste these three lines of code that are listening
for the username field.
I will select those, copy it and then right below it, still within the event's method.
Just paste in in the new copy.
Just change this username to this email.
And then when we call the is different, let's change the first argument to this DOT email and then
let's change the handler to email handler instead of user name handler.
OK, now let's go find the username handler method.
Here it is.
And we can just duplicate this and name the new copy email handler.
So I would just select all of this.
Copy it.
Maybe right below this, just pasted in, let's change the name to email handler and then let's change
the first line to this email errors when it comes to the email field.
We actually don't need to run any validation checks immediately.
Right, because if someone begins typing in an email address well after their first few keystrokes,
clearly that's not going to look like a valid email address with the at symbol and a domain.
So we would want to give them a chance to type before we evaluate what they've typed in.
So within our email handler, we can get rid of the immediately function call.
Let's keep the clear time out, but let's change this to this dot e-mail dot timer and then let's update
this as well.
This email timer equals and then let's just change the function it calls after the delay.
Change this from user name after delay to email after delay.
And since at this point we know that the after delay functionality is working, we no longer need to
leave these at three thousand milliseconds.
So I would change both of these to maybe eight hundred milliseconds.
OK, now at this point, let's go create a method with this matching name, email after delay.
So I would just create a new method, email after delay, parentheses, curly brackets within this method.
Let's set up an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for our condition, let's check to see if the format looks nothing
like an email address.
I would actually use a regular expression for this.
So this is not going to be super educational, but typed this out with me.
Forward slash carrot symbols.
So hold down shift and press six backslash.
Not a forward slash but a backslash uppercase s plus at symbol backslash s.
And again, that's an uppercase s not a lowercase plus symbol dollar sign forward slash.
So from the opening forward slash to the closing forward slash, this is a regular expression.
Now we can use it.
So at the end of it we can say dot test and we would just test it against the current value in the email
field.
So within these parentheses for test we'd say this email dot value.
So this will evaluate the true if there is text and then the symbol and then additional text.
Since we're checking for a problem, we would actually want to check for the opposite of this.
So right before the opening forward slash, I would include an exclamation, OK, and then within the
curly brackets for this statement, I would just say this dot show validation error.
We give this two arguments.
The first is the element in question.
So this email comma, the second argument is just the message, the quotes.
You must provide a valid email address.
OK, if you need to pause the video to type all of this out, that's OK.
But let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I refresh on the front end, as long as I type at a reasonable speed and don't wait eight hundred
milliseconds in between keystrokes and I say Brad at Brad dot com, we don't see any error messages.
But if I get rid of the at symbol so that this no longer looks like an email address at all and then
if we wait eight hundred milliseconds perfect.
You must provide a valid email address.
OK, now next, assuming that they have entered a valid email address, we would want to check our server
to see if that email address has already been used or not.
So to set that up, let's do this within our email after delay method.
But after this if statement, let's just set up a new if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition, let's say only if exclamation this email dot errors.
In other words, only if the email address is valid.
Only if there are no problems, then we would want to send off a request to the server.
So within the IF statement I would just say axios dot post.
At the end of that, let's set up the dot then dot catch, let's set up arrow functions within both
then and catch the parentheses arrow symbol.
Curly brackets do the same thing for catch parentheses arrow symbol curly brackets.
OK now within the parentheses for post we give that to arguments.
The first is the you are l that we want to send a request to quotes forward slash let's say does email
exist or in other words, is there already a user using this email address.
OK then comma after those quotes.
And the second argument is an object that we want to send to the server.
So let's give it just one property of email Colen with a value of this email value.
OK, now you can imagine that we are going to set up a route in our express app that matches this and
it will send back JSON response of either true or false.
So within our then function parentheses we would want to receive.
That response from the server, so within these parentheses, just say response.
OK, then in the body of this arrow function, I would just write another if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets after the closing curly bracket, also add an else block and for the
condition it would just be if response data, because this is just going to be either a value of true
or false that the server responds with.
Now remember, the question is, does email exist?
So if this is true, that means a user has already used that email address and that's a problem.
So within the if block, I would say this dot email dot is unique and I would set that to equal false.
And then I would also say so new line this dot show validation error.
Give that to arguments.
The element in question is this dot email, comma, and then just give it an error message so that email
is already being used.
OK, but else if this is false, that means there is no user that's already using the email.
So I would just set this email that is unique to true and then I would also hide any validation errors
for this field.
So this dot hide validation error and the element in question is this dot email.
OK, finally, let's take care of the catch function.
If this ever runs, that means there was some sort of unexpected technical difficulty.
So I would just log to the console and say, please try again later.
OK, at this point, let's go ahead and save this.
And now we need to go into our express app router and add a root for slash.
Does email exist?
So jump into your rutabagas file.
And within the commented area that says user related routes, right under this most recent route that
we've created, we can just add a new line and let's say router dot post.
First argument will be, does email exist after the quotes, comma, second argument is just a function.
So let's say user controller and this function doesn't exist yet, but let's say does email exist?
Let's save this and then jump into our user controller and create a function with this name.