This function doesn't exist yet, but let's say does email exist, let's save this and then jump into
our user controller and create a function with this name.
So in user controller up at the top, we've already created this.
Does user name exist function?
Maybe right below that I would just create a new function.
So exports dot does email exist, set that to equal a function within the parentheses for the function.
Be sure to include request and response.
OK, now within this function, we know that we are going to want to leverage our uppercase user model.
But from here there are several different directions you could go in.
You could create a method named find by email that would potentially be useful somewhere else in the
application down the road.
At this point, I don't think we would use that anywhere else.
But sometimes it's a good idea to create functions that you can imagine being useful in other scenarios.
Or we could just create a method named does email exist?
Right.
And its job would literally just be to return a value of true or false.
So that's actually the approach I'm going to go with.
So uppercase user DOT, does email exist?
Now, you can imagine that we will set this up on the model to be a promise, so let's actually do this.
Let's tell this function to be async.
And then at the start of this line, I would say let email.
Bool Bhullar short for Boulin, meaning true or false, I would set that to equal this and then I would
just say awaked right.
This promise is going to resolve with a value of either true or false.
So then right below this line, well, that's what I would send back as my response to the Web browser.
So just response JSON with the value of email boole.
OK, let's save this.
And now we just need to go into our user model and create a method with this name.
Does email exist?
So within your project folder, look in the models folder, and I want you to jump in to user J.S..
Let's scroll down to the very bottom of user, not Jess, and right before the closing module exports,
let's say upper case user DOT, does email exist?
And let's set this to equal a function, a function parentheses, curly brackets.
And I just realized we forgot to step in our previous file.
So jump back in the user controller, back in the controller.
When we say uppercase user DOT, does email exist within these parentheses?
We need to give it an email in question.
Which email address are we checking?
So request body email.
OK, let's save that and jump back into the model.
So within the parentheses for this function, we'd want to receive that incoming email address email.
OK, now within the body of this function, we want it to return a promise to return a new instance
of uppercase promise within these parentheses.
Let's give it an async function.
So async function, parentheses, curly brackets within the function parentheses.
Let's include parameters of resolve and reject.
OK, now within this function, let's begin by checking to see if the email value is just an innocent
string of text or not.
So I would begin by saying if parentheses curly brackets for the condition I'd say if type of and then
check the incoming email and I'd say if that does not equal a string then we have a problem.
If that's the case, I would just want to resolve with the value of false.
But more importantly, I would want to return I'd want to stop any further execution of this function
because I don't want this value getting anywhere near my Mongo DB database.
OK, now after this if statement, let's drop down.
And now this is where I would just want to check within my database to see if there's a user with this
email.
So I would say let user equal and then I would just await and then I would use a Mongo DB method so
we'd look within our users collection and call a method named find one.
We give this an object.
And I'm looking for a document where the email field has a matching value of whatever email value is
just passed into this function right below this line.
I would just say if parentheses curly brackets right after that closing if adeno else block.
And I would just say if user write because if it found a user at all, that will be an object that evaluates
to true.
If it does not find a matching user, then this variable will essentially be empty, which would evaluate
to false.
So within the if block I'd say resolve with the value of true within the else block, I'd say resolve
with a value of false.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in the browser, if I refresh, if you type in an email address that you have not used yet,
everything should be OK.
But if you type in an email address that you have already used.
Perfect, that email is already being used.
Also notice that if you type in an email address that is not valid, that does not contain the at symbol
and then additional text, you see, you must provide a valid email address, but then if you fix it.
And type in an email that has not already been used, that message gets hidden perfect, that takes
care of the email field.
Now let's work on the password field.
It should be very simple and quick to set up because it does not require a trip to the server.
Really, the only thing we need to check for is the minimum length and maximum length.
So let's do this back within our registration form.
Gorgias, right.
Our front end file.
Let's scroll up to the top and within our constructor, right below the two lines that begin with this
email.
Let's add a new line.
Let's say this dot password equals and then just select it's a document query selector.
It has an ID.
So hash tag of password dash register I below that, let's say this dot password dot previous value
equals an empty pair of quotes.
All right.
Now let's listen for keyboard presses on that field.
So within our events area, let's just copy and paste these three lines of code that were for the email
field.
So copy that right below paste.
Let's change this email to this DOT password and then let's change the first argument from this email
to this dot password instead of email handler, let's say password handler.
OK, now let's go find our username handler and we can just copy and paste this.
So just duplicate the username handler method, copy paste right below it.
Let's change this new copy to be named password handler.
Let's change this username errors to this dot password errors.
We do want afunction to run immediately because that will check the maximum character length.
So let's change your username immediately to password immediately.
Let's still keep a time out, but change it from this dot username to this dot password and then let's
change this username timer to password timer.
And then finally, username after delay should now be password after delay.
OK, now right below this, let's create a method named password immediately password immediately parentheses
curly brackets within this method, let's set up an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition, I will just say this dot password dot value dot
length.
If that is greater than fifty, we have a problem.
So within the if curly brackets I would just say this dot show validation error.
The element in question is this dot password comma and then we give it a message.
So password cannot exceed fifty characters.
Now after this if statement but still within password immediately I would say if parentheses curly brackets
for the condition if this dot password dot errors and then right before this I check for the opposite.
So exclamation.
If there are no errors then I would want to hide the validation message.
So this dot hide validation error element in question is this dot password.
OK, now below this method let's create a new method named password after delay, password after delay
parentheses curly brackets.
Let's say if parentheses curly brackets.
The condition is just this dot password dot value length.
If that is less than twelve then we have a problem.
So I would say this show validation error.
The element in question is this dot password comma and let's just give it a message of password.
Must be at least twelve characters.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I refresh, if I only type in one or two characters from my password and then wait eight hundred
milliseconds perfect.
As soon as I begin typing again it gives me a chance.
But if I go over the limit we immediately see you cannot exceed fifty and the millisecond I go back
under fifty it goes away.
Not to bring this to a close.
Let's set things up so that if you try to click on the submit button, we prevent the browser from actually
submitting the form unless we are perfectly happy with all.
Revalues, let me show you how I would set that up.
So back in our registration form, not just let's scroll to the very top and at the beginning of our
constructor, let's add a new line and let's select the overall HTML form element.
So I would just say this dot form equals document query selector and it has an ID of registration Dasch
form.
All right.
Now, before we listen for the event of that form being submitted, I first want to do this at the end
of our constructor right after the this dot password lines.
Let's set the is unique value for both our email and username to be false by default.
So I would just say this dot username dot is unique, set that to be false when the page first loads
and do the same thing for the email said this email is unique set.
It defaults this way.
It's up to our axios requests to actually run and update these to a value of true before we would ever
let our form actually submit.
Let me show you what I mean.
So within our events area at the top of the events method, let's listen for the overall form being
submitted.
So this dot form, dot add event listener, the event that we're listening for is submit, right?
It's not click, it's not give up, it is submit and then comma for the second argument, let's give
it an arrow function.
So parentheses arrow symbol and then curly brackets.
Let's dropdown within the parentheses.
Let's give it one parameter of E short for event.
And if you only have one parameter you don't need the parentheses within the body of this function.
Let's say e dot prevent default.
Right.
We do not want to let the form submit which is its default behaviour.
OK, and then after that let's just call a method that doesn't exist yet, but one that we can create
in just a few seconds.
So let's say this dot form submit handler parentheses to call that OK.
And now let's go create a method with that matching name.
Let's scroll down underneath our methods area.
Let's create a new method form submit handler parentheses, curly brackets.
OK, now let's ask ourselves, what do we want to happen when this runs.
Because think about it.
Someone could visit this page and before they trigger any key press events on any of the fields, they
could just click submit right away.
But before we let the form submit, we would still want all of our validation rules and checks to run.
So here's what I would do within our form.
Submit handler.
I would just manually run all of our validation checks.
So this DOT username immediately call that.
It's also called this DOT username after delay.
Let's also call this DOT email after delay and let's call this dot password immediately and this dot
password after delay.
OK, so after we manually run all of our validation checks, then let's write an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets, the condition will be if everything is perfect, just the way we
want it, then we can let the form submit.
So within our if curly brackets, what we would want to do is this dot form which selects the overall
form element, and then we just want to call the submit method.
Now let's focus on the condition that needs to be true in order for us to actually allow it to submit.
So within these parentheses, first, I'd want to make sure that their user name is unique.
So this dot username DOT is unique.
That would need to be true.
And so to ampersands, I'd want to check for the opposite of this dot username dot errors.
Right?
Only if there are no errors on the field.
So exclamation to see if this is false and I would need their email address to be unique.
So this email dot is unique.
We need to add more conditions here.
But I'm already running out of horizontal space here on my screen.
So I do want to let you know that you can break up conditions on the separate lines.
So, for example, after the opening, if parentheses, you can drop down and then I could also drop
down after every double ampersand like this.
So this way we have one condition per line.
So let's add another one.
And I would want there to not be any email errors.
So exclamation this email errors.
And I wouldn't want there to be any password either, so exclamation this dot password, dot errors
and then if you wanted to, you could also drop down right before the closing parentheses.
And then if you wanted to just to make things look more organized, you could indent these conditions
a bit.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I refresh and if I never even click into any of these fields and just try to submit the form right
away.
Perfect.
Do you see the form was not submitted and I have different validation messages at this point.
There's just one more detail I want to take care of before we bring this lesson to a close.
So if I refresh and if I type in a username of fluffy cat, we see that that is a valid username.
Now, clearly, if I had a character that's not allowed, for example, a period we see the message
right.
Username can only contain letters and numbers.
But watch this if I add the period.
But then immediately after I press that key, I press the tab key to switch off to the next field.
So if I press dot tab super quickly like this notice it doesn't trigger the validation error message.
Clearly that's an issue.
So if a user types in a value really quick, it is common for them to hit tab and immediately go down
to the next field.
So what I would do to get around this is just also listen for the on Blu event for each field.
Let me show you what I mean.
So back in our ED scroll up to the events area.
Now, at the moment, we are listening for the key up event on our three fields.
So what I would do is just duplicate all of these events.
We don't need to duplicate the event that listens for the form being submitted.
But for these three key up events, I would just copy all three right below it, Paiste and on the new
three copies just change the key up event to the blurr event.
Blur runs.
When you exit off of or when a field loses focus, change those to blur.
Let's go ahead and save.
OK, now back in the browser.
If I refresh, I choose the name of Fluffy Cat.
Clearly we see the error message if I say dot, but if I hit dot and tab instantly like this.
Cool.
The problem is still being caught.
Now if I try to submit the form cool it's also going to let me know.
Hey, you need to enter a password first.
Now let's go ahead and fill out the form properly.
All right, so there are no problems with any of my fields, and now if I try to submit the form, you
can see that that submit request actually goes through and I am now logged in with that new account.
Perfect.
And that's actually going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we are going to learn about security to be more specific.
We're going to learn how to protect ourselves from a cookie related vulnerability.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.