Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to learn what in the world the CRUD acronym stands for and how it can
help us make sense of working with databases.
Let's dive right in.
So in our previous lesson, we created a Mongo DB Atlus account and we also created a cluster, which
is just a place on the Internet where a database can live.
So our next step is to add a database here.
So I want you to do this with me.
I want you to follow along from your Mongo DB Atlas screen.
That should look something like this.
I want you to look underneath this overview section, and here we see a few different buttons.
We see connect, we see metrics and we see collections.
I want you to click on collections.
As soon as I click on collections, you can see this new screen appears and here we see a button named
Create Database.
I want you to go ahead and click on Create Database.
The name of this database does not matter.
This is just a testing database just for practice, just to get your feet wet.
You could name it anything.
For example, I'm going to name it just a test, OK?
And then we need to enter a collection name.
A Mongo DB database can have many different collections inside of it.
For example, if we were creating a database for a pet adoption app, we would have one collection named
Pets.
We would have another collection named users and maybe another collection named locations or stores.
The idea is that you can create multiple different collections to help you keep your data organized.
So again, the name doesn't matter.
You can choose anything.
But just to follow along with me in this example, why don't you go ahead and name it pets?
OK, finally, let's go ahead and click this create button.
OK, and now you can see instead of being in the overview tab, we are in the collections tab and we
now have a brand new database named Just a Test.
You can also see the name of the database here.
And inside of that database is an empty collection named Pets.
So let's start experimenting by working with a bit of data inside the pets collection.
But the question becomes, where do we begin?
What do we do first?
How do we even know what our options are or what we can even do?
Well, I've got some good news.
There's an acronym that can help us remember what our options are.
And the acronym is Crud.
Crud stands for Create, Read, Update and Delete.
These four actions are the heart and soul of working with the database.
So I really want to burn this acronym into your brain, into your memory crud, create, read, update
and delete.
Once we learn how to perform these four actions, we can do just about anything.
So right now, let's go through and practice each of these actions one by one.
Let's start up at the top with the C in crud, which is create.
OK, so with the pets collection selected, let's create a new item inside of it to use more technical
language in Mongo DB we call each item that lives inside a collection, a document.
So in this case, let's create a document that will represent a pet.
So you'll notice this green button that says insert document.
Let's go ahead and click that.
And in this case, the word insert could really be replaced with the word create, so from this new
pop up, we can create a new document.
You can see my cursor is placed right about here, and this is where we can choose the name of the first
field or property for the document.
For example, we know that every pet needs a name.
So let's create a field or property with the name of a name and then for its value here we can type
in maybe miaows a lot.
OK, now if I press tab on my keyboard, you can see I am ready to add another field or property.
You're free to choose any name for the field that you want, but I'm going to go with species and then
if I had to begin, I can set the value for that.
So I will say that miaows a lot is a cat.
OK, for now I think just these two fields of properties will do the trick.
OK, so to actually create this document or this pet, let's just click this green insert button.
And congratulations, you just created your first entry in a database right here, we can see total
documents in our pets collection is now one instead of zero.
Let's practice creating a few more pet documents just so we have multiple pets to experiment with later
on in this lesson.
So let's click the insert document button once again, set the first field to name and give it a value
of maybe purs loud and then give it another feel the name species and send it's a cat.
OK, go ahead, insert that.
So we now have two documents in our collection, let's add one more, and this time let's set the species
to something other than cat.
So let's say the name can have a value of barks a lot.
And let's set a field named species to have a value of dog.
Let's go ahead and create or insert that.
OK, now let's circle back to the CRUD acronym, so we've taken care of the C, we just walked through
an example of how to create a document in the database.
Now, let's change gears and talk about the R, which stands for Read.
In this case, read could really be interchanged with the word load or retrieve.
It just means you are reading or retrieving data from the database.
So from this basic screen where we can see all of the pet documents that we just created, well, the
Mongo DB Atlas admin interface that we're looking at, it just performed a read operation for us, right.
Because it is loaded this data or it has read this data from the database.
Another example of the R and crud of reading from a database would be if we performed a query on our
collection.
So imagine we only wanted to see the cats in this collection.
Well, in this filter area, you can click onto that field and then type this out with me.
Let's include a pair of curly brackets to create an object.
Right?
This is basic JavaScript syntax inside there.
Let's set the species property.
So Colen not equal sign because this is inside an object.
So species' colon and then just say quotes and give it a value of cat.
Now, as soon as you press, enter or click the fine button, you will perform that query.
And now you can see there are only two documents, right, and those are both of the cat documents.
So that query is an example of a read action, right?
We just read data from the database.
What if we only wanted to see the dogs in the database?
We could just come into this filter, change the value to dog, run the query again or perform another
read action and there you have it.
So back to the acronym of CRUD.
The order or read just means that you are loading or retrieving or reading data from the database.
OK, next up, let's move on to the U.
Which stands for Update.
So back in the Mongo DB Atlas screen, go ahead and click this reset button here to clear out your custom
filter.
So that way it's just showing all of the documents once again.
OK, let's talk about the U.
In Crud or update.
As you can probably guess, update just means that you edit or update an existing document, for example.
Let's imagine that I want to update this.
Barks a lot dog document perhaps.
I want to change its name from barks a lot to barks loud.
Well, as you're hovering over a document, you'll notice these icons here and the first icon looks
like a pencil.
Go ahead and click on that to edit or make changes to that document.
So as soon as I click that pencil icon, now, these fields are editable, so I can just click my cursor
onto the barks a lot, name value and change it to barks loud and then come down here and click this
update button.
And there you have it, the document was successfully updated.
Let's jump back to the cret acronym and we can move on to the final letter D, which is for delete.
I'm sure you can guess what delete means in this context.
So if you hover over any one of your documents again, you'll see these icons here and on the far right,
it looks like a little trash bin.
If you click on that, you'll see this message that this document is flagged for deletion and then you
can choose between cancel and delete.
If you actually click that little delete button again, that document gets deleted and that's it.
That is the CRUD acronym in a nutshell, create, read, update and delete.
And you just learned how to perform these actions on a Mongo DB database.
Now, at this point, you might be thinking to yourself, hmm, this felt too easy.
I thought that working with the database would be harder.
Well, if you're thinking that you are correct, working with the database usually is a bit more difficult
than what we just saw in this lesson, performing the CRUD operations in this lesson or super easy because
we were within the Mongo DB Atlas admin interface, meaning we didn't write any code to programmatically
have Mongo DB perform CRUD operations for us.
We were simply clicking on interface buttons and doing everything manually.
Now, where the real challenge comes into play and where the real value of a database comes into play
is when we learn how to perform CRUD operations on our database remotely from a node server.
So remember the idea of the server and its request and response request and response pattern?
Well, imagine if in between the request and response slices of bread, imagine if we did something
really interesting in the middle of the sandwich, like load data from a database or create a new document
in a database or update an existing document or delete an existing document.
That is how you can begin to create meaningful applications.
So just like we use JavaScript syntax here to perform a query on the database, we can use JavaScript
code from within a node JS server to communicate with the database.
So in this lesson, we learned how to perform the four CRUD operations by clicking on simple buttons.
But now our next big picture goal is to be able to perform those same actions by writing code, by writing
JavaScript.
So that's why in our very next lesson, we are going to begin creating this to do app.
Now, what we are looking at right now is a sneak preview of the finished product of what we are going
to build together.
But the general idea is if you add an item with this field, so if I say feed the dog and click, add
new item that gets added to a database.
So the important idea is that that action of saving this to the database needs to be automated.
Right.
Because when someone uses your app, you're not going to be sitting at your desk waiting to see what
they typed in and then be able to manually go over to the database admin screen and manually insert
a document and type in there.
Same values that would be crazy.
Instead, we need our no JS server or our app to be able to automatically connect to the Mongo DB database
and perform those CRUD operations on demand with whatever data the user is including in their request.
Right.
So when you add a new item that is the C and crud, you are creating an item as soon as the app load.
So if I refresh the page, it is loading or reading the existing data from the database for the you
and crud.
You can update or edit an item by clicking on our edit button, say Feed the dog today.
So that just performed an update action on the database.
And then clearly if you want to delete a document in the database, that's what this delete button will
do.
Do you really want to delete feed the dog today permanently?
Yes, I do.
At this point, I think the bigger picture might be starting to come into focus.
Hopefully you're starting to see how all of these different JavaScript technologies can play together
to create a meaningful application.
The Web browser can send off requests to a node server.
And then not only can that node server send back a response to the Web browser, but the node server
can also communicate with a Mongo DB database.
If you're still a bit confused on how all of these puzzle pieces fit together, don't worry, because
we're going to walk through all of it step by step as we build this application together.
And that's exactly what we're going to begin in the next lesson.
So let's keep our momentum rolling, this is going to be a ton of fun and I will see you in the next
lesson.