Hello, everyone.
This lesson is completely optional, but in this video, we're going to convert the dot then syntax
way of waiting on a promise to instead use the async await syntax throughout the course.
We've seen both approaches, which I think is very real.
World long term projects that you work on or inherit will definitely have everything.
We'll have callbacks they'll have, then they'll use async.
Wait.
So it's good that you are familiar with all of the different ways of writing your code.
However, now that async await has been around for several, several years, it's definitely the standard.
And so I thought it would be useful to walk through a few examples with you where we convert Dot, then
to instead use async await.
Let's jump into the action.
So here I have the code for our complex app, and let's give ourselves a goal for this video.
So I'm just going to replace any dot then inside our post model and our post controller that should
give us a good amount of practice several examples.
And then if you want to do this for all of your files, absolutely go for it.
But right now on camera, let's begin with the post dot JS model file.
So I'm going to jump into that file.
If I perform a controller command f search for Dot, then OK, I can see there's just one instance of
that, and it's in the create method for creating a new post.
So the promise that we're using then on is the Mongo DB insert one method.
So let me walk you through my own thought process of how I would convert this code to instead use async
await.
So the first thing I'm noticing is that we want to have access to this parameter called info, right?
Whenever this action completes, we want to be able to access that info value.
So that's where I'm going to start my code.
So maybe right below this comment, I'll leave the old code in place, but I'll start writing my new
version of the code.
So I would say contest info equals and then I want to await something.
And then it would just be posts collection dot.
Insert one parentheses to call it in the parentheses.
It looks like we had this dot data.
So this dot data.
So we've recreated this only now.
It's very flat.
We're not nested in several layers indented.
So literally right below this line.
Now we would have this resolved line so you can just copy and paste that right here.
It's not going to run until this has actually finished.
Cool.
But now we do need to address the whole, you know, if this is successful, do this if it fails to
do this.
So here's what I would do again, right above our new code.
Maybe below this comment, I would just set up a try block and then right below that, a catch block.
If you know that you don't need to access this specific error, you don't even need the parentheses.
After the word catch, I got in the habit of always including them because certain old versions of Microsoft
Edge or Microsoft Internet Explorer would throw an error if you didn't have them.
So if you ever look at my code, you'll see I'm in the habit of just including that.
But what I would do is then take these two new lines of code that we wrote and just cut them into the
try block just like that.
And then if things fail, right, if there's an error when it tries to run these two lines of code,
what do we want to do?
Well, I would just take these two lines of code from the catch block down here.
So just those two lines cut those into our catch block up here.
And that's it.
So now you can delete this entire old bit of code.
So from post collection down to this catch block with the closing curly brackets in parentheses, just
like that, we scroll back up so it fits on the screen all at once.
So I'm going to save this.
And now let's go test it out.
So in the browser, I'm logged in.
Woops.
And this is actually a great issue to leave in the video.
I'm not going to edit out this mistake.
I forgot to include the word async right.
So back in our code, you can only use a tweet if you are within an asynchronous function.
Now it needs to be the nearest parent function.
So instead of adding async right here where my cursor is, we would actually add it right here, right?
Because this arrow function is the direct function that's housing this code right before the parentheses.
For those two parameters right here, I would just say async just like this, let's give that a save
back in the browser.
If I refresh cool, let me try to create a post just to test that out.
Quick test post lorem ipsum.
Cool.
It automatically redirected me to the new URL for that post.
However, we can do better.
So why don't we clean up this code a little bit?
In particular, I'm talking about this bit of code that I'm highlighting right now.
So let's take advantage of what an async function truly is.
Or I should say, let's take advantage of what an async function returns, which is a promise.
So if this async function returns a promise, then we don't need to explicitly spell things out like
this.
So let's still return something, but we don't need to spell out a new promise.
So I'm going to get rid of new promise in this opening parentheses like this.
We're just going to return our async function because an async function returns a promise.
Anyways, we got rid of that opening parentheses up here.
So now let's get rid of the closing extra parentheses right down here.
OK.
Now, since we're not explicitly spelling out a promise using that traditional syntax, that means we
no longer have resolve and reject.
So let's get rid of those.
We don't need those.
They don't make sense any longer.
Cool.
So for now, just an empty arrow function like this.
But now we do need to change our terminology down here.
We can't use, resolve and reject.
So instead, in an async function, you can just return something instead of resolving a value.
So I would just change this line instead of resolve in parentheses.
I would just say return info, dot inserted ID just like this, OK?
And then instead of using reject like this, you can instead just throw an error or just throw a value,
and that's going to behave very similarly to rejecting with a value.
So instead of this line, I would say, throw this dot errors, let me get rid of the reject line like
that.
Do the same thing down here.
So instead of this, it would be throw this dot errors.
Cool.
We can still clean this up a little bit more, though we no longer need this extra wrapper function
because its sole purpose was just to prevent the immediate execution of a new promise, right?
As soon as JavaScript sees a promise, it's going to try to start executing it.
So our solution was to wrap it in a function, and only when you call that function with the promise
then exist.
Well, if we're using an asynchronous function, we no longer need that the promise that this async
function returns won't actually exist until someone calls or executes the async function.
So to clean this up even further on this line, where we say prototype tocreate equals, we can get
rid of the function, parentheses, curly brackets and then on this line, just bring that back up and
we don't need the word return.
We're just setting it to equal our async function.
With that in place, we no longer need this very closing curly bracket right down here.
So I get rid of that.
And then to fix the indentation, you can just select all of these lines and then press control or command
and the left square bracket key on your keyboard to just indent back a little bit.
OK, and then one last detail.
We do need to address the fact that just a moment ago, this overall function here was an anonymous
function instead of an arrow function.
That's a big deal, because that's what's allowing that this keyword to point towards the overall object
that we would expect it to.
Remember that when you use an arrow function, the this keyword doesn't change.
And in this case, we do not want the this keyword to just be pointing towards the global object.
We want it to be pointing towards this instance of our overall post class.
So in order for that, this keyword to point towards what we want it, to just change this from an arrow
function to an anonymous function.
So just change this arrow symbol to just say function parentheses just like this.
So now if we go ahead and save this, let's truly test it out by both creating a new post successfully
and making sure that when we're throwing the errors like this, that they actually successfully get
to the controller.
So first, let me try to create a post successfully.
Brand new post.
Hello.
Cool, so that works.
However, let me try to create a new post, and you can do this if you want to to make sure those error
messages are getting through.
We need to open up your developer tools and just remove the required attribute on one of these fields.
All right, click off it.
Now, if I try to post this while leaving it blank and we removed the required attribute well, our
server side validation should kick in and should prevent this from working.
So if I click Save New Post, Oops, let me remove the required from that overall text area to in this
div on the text area, just remove the required attribute.
Click Save New Post.
Perfect.
The array of error messages successfully made it from our model when we used to throw this dot errors,
and that made it into the controller using this syntax.
Cool.
Now that was the only instance of Dot then in our model file.
So at this point, let's change gears and in our controllers folder, let's jump into post controller
dot Jess.
And now let's begin converting then to use async await.
So let me walk you through my thought process right above this line where we're using Dot then.
For now, I'll leave this text in place so we can look at it as a reference, but above it, I'll write
the new code.
So first, I would begin by setting up a try block and then right below that, a catch block.
And I'm going to give the catch block this parameter of errors.
I'm giving it this specific name because in our original code down here, we're already looking for
a parameter with that exact name of errors.
Cool.
So we've got to try catch blocks set up in the try block.
What do we want to do?
Well, we want to call this create method, but I'm noticing we are interested in the new ID value that's
going to arise or be returned from it.
So I would begin by saying Konst new ID equals a and then it's just post Doc Create, then directly
below that line, but still in the try block, I would just move so cut or copy and paste everything
that was in the body of this function right here.
So send SendGrid lines.
And then these two lines where we're saying request, dot, flash and request dot session.
So I would just cut that into my clipboard.
Paste it right below this line in the try block.
And then if there's an error, if there's a problem.
I would just cut or copy and paste these two lines in my clipboard, paste that into this tribe block
just like that.
Now we can get rid of this code called delete it.
And now let's save this and take it for a test drive.
So it's the same overall action, just creating a post on the website.
So does it create post?
And once again, you were probably screaming at the screen, but I forgot to include the word async.
So back in our code, we can only use this tweet feature if we are within an async function.
So right before function here, just say async, save that again.
Let's give it a refresh.
Perfect.
So new Test one, two three.
If we want to see those error messages on purpose, let's just remove the required attribute from the
text area and then I'll provide a value for the title, but not for the body.
Click Save New Post.
Perfect.
So that takes care of the create post functionality in this file.
I'm just going to push control or command F and search for Dot then.
So it looks like the next instance is in this API create function.
And for the rest of these examples, I don't believe there are any new concepts.
So now we're going to really start moving quickly.
So here's what I would do.
Right above that, all the code, I would just set up the try block with the catch block.
In the try block, I would say Konst new ID equals await post-hoc create right below it.
I would just cut and paste this congrats line in the catch block.
Just cut and paste this cool.
We no longer need this old code and I almost did it again.
Do not forget to include async right here just like that.
Cool.
Let's move on to the next one.
So Controller Command F four then looks like it's in our edit function.
So here's the old code using DOT.
Then right above that, I would just set up try catch blocks, so try catch with errors in the tri block.
It looks like we would want to run this, but we're interested in whatever status value it returns.
So I would say Konst status equals a weight post and then call update.
Then directly below that line to still the try block, I would just cut and paste and move all of this.
So from this comment down.
Until the else bloc closes right here, so I would cut all of that.
Paste it right below this line that we wrote in our tribe lock for our catch block.
Well, I would just take all of this content.
Cut that pasted into this catch block and then just get rid of this old dot, then dot catch code like
that.
Let's give this a save and give it a quick test to make sure that it still works.
So that was the edit or update functionality.
So if I go to my profile, yes, I did it again.
This would need to be an async function.
So don't forget async, give that to save.
Now, if I go back to my profile and try to edit one of my existing posts, so maybe if I try to add
a few exclamation marks, give that a save.
Cool.
Let's move on to the next one.
So if I search for then in this file, it looks like it's the delete functionality.
So above that line, I would set up a try, catch blocks or try catch.
This time around, it doesn't look like we're interested in any value that it returns or resolves with,
so we don't need to set up a variable.
We can just literally say a wait uppercase post, dot delete and then you can just copy and paste these
values inside the parentheses.
So it's a request dot parameter ID and request dot or idea.
Just move those or paste them right below that line.
But still, in our new try block, I would just cut and paste or move these two lines of code paste
that here for the catch area.
Again, just move those two lines of code.
Just like this.
We no longer need this old code, but save this.
And before I even test it out, I'm not going to forget to include async right before function.
So save it, refresh if I try to delete this post.
Perfect.
Let's command F for the next instance of it then.
So it's our API delete right above it.
I would just set up try, block, catch block in the try block, await uppercase postcard delete.
You can even just copy and paste these values.
Right below that line, just move this line of code in vs code, if you want to hold down the altar
option key, you can use the arrow keys to just move a line of code like this.
In the catch block, you would just move this line, so alter option up call, we no longer need this
bit of code.
Make sure that's an async function.
OK, the next one looks like and this is the final one, it's our search functionality.
Let's actually change it up and begin by turning and turning it into an async function and then just
set up try block.
Catch block this time around, we are interested in the value that gets returned or resolved, so I
would say contest posts equals await uppercase post call search.
You can just copy and paste the value in the parentheses.
Like this right below that line.
I would just move this response that JSON online.
Cool.
And then in the catch block, I would just remove this empty JSON array line.
We no longer need this old code.
Let me save this and let's test it out.
So to test out the live functionality of the live search functionality if I search for the word brand
should just be that one post.
Yep, brand new post.
Cool.
So that was all instances of the DOT then syntax in our post model and post controller using these concepts
feel free to adjust all of the other models and controllers if you're interested in doing that.
But I think this was a good bit of practice.
This is definitely the modern or standard way of dealing with asynchronous actions in JavaScript.
Behind the scenes, it's all still promise based, but this bit of syntactic sugar makes the code a
good bit cleaner.
That's going to bring this video to a close.
Let's keep our momentum rolling, and I will see you in the next one.