As soon as I refresh, I should now say stop following button, because I'm already following barks
a lot.
So if I refresh perfect.
Now let's go set up a route to support the slash, remove, follow neutral pattern.
Right.
Because that's the route that this form is going to submit to.
Let me show you what I mean.
So back in the route of our project folder, jump into Rouda or JS down at the bottom of our router,
we have follow related routes to save a bit of typing.
Just duplicate this line for adding a follow.
Select that line, copy right below this.
Paste it in this new copy.
Just change add follow to remove follow.
OK, we still want to begin by running.
Must be logged in but for the second function instead of add follow, let's change this to remove follow,
let's save this and now let's jump into our follow controller and create a function with this matching
name.
So in follow controller there's no sense reinventing the wheel or typing all of this out again.
Let's just copy and paste our add value and make a couple of adjustments.
So I will copy all of this.
And right below this, just paste it in in the new duplicated copy.
Let's change this name to remove follow now instead of calling follow dot create.
Let's call follow dot delete for the success message.
We can just change it to successfully stopped and then change this word to following so successfully
stopped following barks a lot.
OK, everything else here can stay the same.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now within our follow model, let's be sure to add a delete method.
So within our models folder let's jump into follow dot J.S. Let's scroll down and find our create method
and we can just copy and paste this to just select the entire create method with that in your clipboard
right below it.
Just paste or duplicate.
Let's change this to delete.
And then the only other change we need to make is the database action that we want to run.
So instead of insert one, it would be delete one.
OK, now before we save this and test it out, let's first add two more validation rules.
Those two rules being you cannot remove a follow if you do not already follow the user.
Right.
Because in that case, then this delete one method wouldn't find a document to delete.
And also you should not be able to add a follow if you're already following that user.
So to enforce these rules, let's do this within our delete method.
When we call this dot validate, let's just pass it a string of text and let it know which action we're
currently performing.
So in this case it would be delete.
And then if we scroll up just a tiny bit into our create method, when we call this dot validate, let's
say create.
OK, now let's go up to our validate method and enforce these rules.
After the closing curly bracket for the else block, so right here, but still within the overall validate
function, let's create a variable named does follow already exist to see if a follow already exists.
We could simply set this to equal and then look within our follows collection in the database and run
the find one method curly brackets to describe the document we're looking for.
And let's say the followed I.D. should match.
So Colon, this dot followed Idée.
Comma and the author ID should match and then create a new instance of object ID and pass it this author
ID.
OK, now this find one method is going to return a promise.
So at the beginning of this, let's include a wait.
OK, now, right below this line, let's set up an if statement, let's say if parentheses curly brackets,
if the current action parameter equals a double equal signs create.
And in order for this to work, we need to receive this with a parameter within the parentheses for
this function.
So right here, be sure to add in a parameter named action right below in this file.
Just a minute ago, the two times when we called the validate, we passed to the value of either create
or delete.
So now we're saying if the current action equals create, then we'd want to make sure that a follow
matching these two IDs does not already exist.
So let's say if parentheses, curly brackets, if it does follow, already exist.
If this is able to find a matching document, then this will evaluate to true because any object will
evaluate to true.
So if one already exists and the incoming request is trying to create another one, well then within
the curly brackets, we just want to push an error onto our array.
This dot errors dot push and say you are already following this user.
OK, now to save a bit of typing, we can just copy and paste these three lines of code and do the same
thing for the delete action.
So let's copy this right below this pasted in.
Let's say if action double equals sign delete, then we want to check for the opposite of this.
So let's include an exclamation mark at the beginning here.
Right, because you should not be able to stop following or remove a follow from someone you're not
already following.
Then for the error that we would push in this instance, it would say you cannot stop following someone
you do not already follow.
OK, let's go ahead and save this and test it out first.
I should say that because we just now implemented these rules, you might have already accidentally
created duplicate follows, meaning if you clicked, begin following more than once for a given user.
If that's the case, then when you click, stop following.
It wouldn't truly stop following them because it would only delete the first matching document.
So to avoid that frustration, I recommend going into your Mongo DB Atlus account and within the following
collection click find the pull in the latest data and make sure that there's only one document with
the same followed ID and authorized values.
And you could just delete any existing follow documents to give yourself a clean slate now that those
new validation rules are in place.
But let's test this out.
I'll be sure to refresh, so please stop following.
Button has the updated action and let me try to stop following Bachs a lot.
Cool successfully stopped following barks a lot, and now it's a follow button again, if I go into
the database and search the find collection, you can see it's gone.
But if I change my mind and want to begin following that user again, perfect successfully followed
barks a lot.
And you can see there's a matching follow in the database again.
Now let's enforce a new rule being you should not be allowed to follow yourself.
So if I visit my own profile before we visually hide the follow button on your own profile, let's first
set up validation checks to make sure that that would never go through anyways.
So back in our text editor below this if statement for the if action equals delete, let's add a new
line and we can even leave a comment to ourselves and say, should not be able to follow yourself to
enforce this.
Let's just set up an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets and say if this dot followed ID equals this dot author ID, if that's
the case then we just want to push an error.
So this errors push and let's say you cannot follow yourself, let's save this and test it out.
So now if I try to follow my own account.
Cool, it kicks me back to the homepage, you cannot follow yourself now that we've enforced that validation
check, let's visually hide this button.
If you're currently viewing your own profile to make this happen, I want to jump back to our shared
profile data function that we're going to run for all three of these routes.
Right.
That area where we already created the property named is following to determine if the current visitor
is following the current profile.
Let me show you what I mean.
So within our user controller file, in the controllers folder, user controller dot J.S..
Remember, towards the top, we created this function named shared profile data.
Well, we've already created this.
One variable is following right above that.
Let's just create a variable Soulet and let's name it is visitors profile by default.
Let's set this to equal false.
However, if you're logged in, let's perform a check.
So then the if curly brackets we can just say is visitors profile equals and now we can just look within
our request profile user underscore ID to get the actual Mongo DB object id object for the current profile
user and any Mongo DB object ID has a method named equals so we can just check it against the current
session user ID request session dot user dot underscore ID.
The equals method will either return true or false.
So that's going to be the correct value.
Now down here, let's just add on to the request object and say request dot is visitor's profile equals
our local variable.
So is visitors profile.
Cool.
So now this true or false value will be available from the next function for this route.
So let's scroll down and find the function named profile posts screen.
When we render that template, let's just give it a new property so we can include a comma and say is
visitors profile colon and then look on the request object for is visitors profile.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this and then jump in to our profile dot SJS file to actually leverage it to
refresh your memory.
Remember, we just want to hide or not display this button if you're currently viewing your own profile.
Now, luckily for us, we already have both of those buttons wrapped in an overall if the current visitor
has a user session.
So within this outer if condition, let's just add on another check.
So ampersand, ampersand and say and you are not so exclamation to check for the opposite is visitors
profile.
So only if you're logged in and it's not your profile, should you see either of the stop following
or start following buttons.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I refresh on my own profile screen.
Perfect.
It's gone completely, but if I go back to the bark's a lot profile.
The appropriate button is still there.
Excellent.
And that's going to bring this lesson to a close now before we change gears and work on our homepage
feed, that should show the latest posts from the users you follow.
Before we get to that, let's first actually complete the profile screen, meaning you should be able
to click on followers to view a list of this current users followers.
And you should be able to click on Following to see who they are following.
Not to mention these counter numbers that we see here should actually represent the number of matching
documents in our database instead of just this fake hard coded HTML data.
Right.
Clearly, the bark's a lot.
User does not have three posts.
So all of that is what we're going to implement in our next lesson.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.