Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to learn how to receive form data from a visitor and work with that data
in our server.
Let me show you what I mean by giving you a sneak peek of the finished product of what we're going to
build together in this lesson.
So we see a bit of text.
What color is the sky on a clear and sunny day?
And then here is a text input field.
Now, if I type in an incorrect answers, if I say orange and then click to submit, we see.
Sorry, that is incorrect.
But if I click back to the home page and then type in blue and submit, we see congrats.
That is the correct answer.
Now, this may not seem very impressive or exciting, but trust me, being able to respond to user input
like this marks a huge milestone in your journey towards becoming a full stack developer.
Right.
If you think about how you log into your bank's website or your email or any online account, you have
to fill out a username field and then you have to fill out a password field and then you submit and
then the server decides if what you typed in is correct or not.
So we're starting simple here and just checking to see if the user types in blue or not.
But we need to learn how to walk before we can run.
So how can we start building this together?
Where do we begin?
Well, in our previous lesson, we used the HTP functionality of node to set up a basic server.
So as we've already seen, we can technically create a server this way.
But the truth is, is that you can use node to build just about anything, not just Web servers.
Now, this open ended nature and flexibility of node is great, but in the real world, we have a specific
goal, right?
We want to create a Web server so it makes more sense to use a solution that is less open ended and
instead is specifically designed for the purpose of creating Web servers.
And that's exactly where something named Express comes into play.
So what in the world is express?
Well, let's start with their official description or slogan and then I will explain it.
So it says that Express is a fast on opinionated, minimalist web framework for Node J.
Yes, but what does that mean in plain English?
So I would say that Express is a bunch of pre written JavaScript code for the node environment that
we can leverage.
So Express takes care of a thousand different details for us so that we can avoid reinventing the wheel
and also so that we can keep our code more organized.
Now, personally, I'm not always a fan of leveraging pre written JavaScript code like this.
However, I am a huge fan of Xpress largely because of these two words that I've highlighted here,
because it is an opinion dated and minimalist.
Express doesn't automatically do a ton for us.
It doesn't babysit us so much that it prevents us from learning and it doesn't really force any rigid
or dogmatic ideas on us.
It simply provides functions or methods that are specifically designed for creating Web servers.
You can think of it like this node on its own.
Without express is like Legos.
There's all kinds of different Lego block types, some that you'll want to use, a bunch that you will
not need to use.
And you can use these Lego blocks to build anything.
On the other hand, if we use Express, we are still using node.
But Express gives us new Lego block types that were specifically designed to be used to build the one
thing that we're trying to build a Web server if that metaphor didn't make any sense.
That's OK.
Let's keep things moving.
But before we move on, I do want to let you know that Express is not some small, seldomly used framework.
So by us using Express, I'm not forcing some odd opinion on you.
Express is absolutely the industry standard when it comes to creating Web servers with node in the real
world.
You are going to run into express all over the place to give you a frame of reference.
Just in the last week alone, Express has been downloaded over five million times.
So at this point the question becomes how do we use or download express?
Well, we actually do not download anything from the Express Web site.
Instead, let's jump back to our text editor or more specifically, jump back to our.
Command line, so I'm using voice code so I can just click view and then terminal.
And then in your command line, I want you to run the following command NPM and then Espace and then
install and then a space and then express.
Now, before I push enter to actually run that command, I want to explain what's going on here.
So first of all, what is NPM?
Well, when you installed node on your computer, it automatically installed something else named NPM.
These letters stand for node package manager.
For now we can think of NPM as a giant grocery store of pre written JavaScript goodies that we can leverage.
Right.
So, for example, if you were baking a cake in real life, you probably are not creating your own flour
from wheat.
Instead, you're probably just go into the grocery store and picking up a bit of flour.
So NPM is the centralized place where we can grab all sorts of pre written JavaScript goodies or packages.
Right.
Node package manager.
And then the second word here is install.
We want to install something.
What do we want to install?
Express?
That's the name of the package that we are interested in.
So let's go ahead and push enter to run the command.
Give it a few seconds, and now you'll notice that in the left hand side bar, NPM automatically created
a new folder for us named Node Modules.
And if we look inside that folder and if you look through this list, you'll see Ahar Express.
If you're wondering why NPM downloaded all of these other packages, aside from Express is because Express
depends on these other packages.
To be honest, there's never really a need to actually open the node modules folder and look at all
the different packages.
I'm only doing that to show you that NPM successfully downloaded the package for us.
You'll also notice that NPM created this new file named Package Lock JSON.
For now, we do not need to worry about this file later on in the course.
We will learn more about it.
Before we move on, I do want to let you know that when you run and NPM install command, NPM is going
to create these files and folders for you in whatever directory your command line is currently pointing
towards.
Remember, in my case, I created that folder on my desktop named First Node Experiment, and that's
the directory that my voice code command line is pointing towards.
But if you're not using VX code and you're using a standalone command line, that's just something I
want you to be aware of.
OK, now, moving on.
We have successfully used NPM to download or install Xpress.
So now let's begin using Express in our code.
So within my test file, the file that we've been writing all of our code and so far I actually want
you to select everything and delete it.
We want a completely brand new clean slate in this file.
This time around, we are going to create a server using Xpress.
So things are going to be a little bit different.
Now, just to jog your memory, remember that our goal is to create this application that receives the
user input and then we evaluate whether they typed blue or something else.
OK, so back in our text editor, our first step, if we want to leverage express, is to import or
include or require in express.
So type this out with me and then I will explain it.
So say let's express equal require and then parentheses inside the parentheses quotes express.
Now this syntax is identical to when we said let htp equal require http.
The difference here is that Express is not a built in part of node meaning.
Before we wrote this line of code, we needed to use NPM to actually go out onto the Internet and download
Express for us.
So when we say require in the express package, node will know to look inside a folder named node modules
and it will know where to look.
OK, so this line of code gets expressed ready.
Now we can actually begin leveraging express and that's exactly what we're going to do in the next part
of this lesson.
So with this first part of the lesson coming to a close, you'll know that you're on track.
If you ran the NPM install express command and it created a node modules folder in your project folder,
as long as you've got that, you're good to go.
You're right on track.
So let's keep things rolling and begin writing code to actually use Express.
And to get to that, I will see you in the next part of this lesson.