Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to begin building our simple to do app, let's dive right into the action.
So this is a sneak preview of the finished product of what we are going to build together.
And we definitely will not complete the app in this lesson, but we should be able to get a nice skeleton
up and running.
So go ahead and follow along with me.
Our first step is to create a new folder anywhere on your computer that you can easily find again.
And let's just create a brand new empty folder where we can begin to create a new app.
So in my case, I'll just right click on my desktop, click new folder.
Feel free to name the folder, whatever you like.
I'm going to name it to do dash app.
OK, and then you need to open up this folder within your text editing program.
In my case, that's visual studio code.
All right.
Now, within this brand new empty folder, what is our first goal?
Well, let's create a JavaScript file that will run in the node environment.
And our goal in this new file will be to create a server that listens for incoming requests.
So in our new folder, let's create a new file.
I'm going to name it Server Dot J.S..
Technically, you can name it whatever you want, as long as it ends in danger.
Yes, but just so you and I are on the same page, let's go with the name of server.
Yes, OK.
In this new empty file, our goal is to create a server that listens for incoming requests.
And as we learned earlier in the course, if that's your goal, it makes a lot of sense to use the express
framework.
So let's create a variable, say, let express equal and then let's require or load or import in and
then inside the parentheses after require.
Let's just say quotes express.
But remember, the express framework is not a bundled or native part of node.
So before we can actually use express like this, we first need to go out onto the Internet or go to
the JavaScript grocery store and pick it up and bring it home to our project.
To do that, we need to open up our command line in voice code.
You can push the control until the key to open the command line, or you can just click on View and
then terminal.
OK, now down in the command line, before we actually run the command to download and install Express,
let's first run a command that will create a grocery list that will keep track of all the different
ingredients that our app needs.
I'll explain what I mean by that a bit later on.
But for now, in the command line, type this out with me and PM and then a space and then a minute
I and I t and then the space and then dash y and then press enter.
You'll notice that that command just created a new file in our folder named Package.
Jason, we will circle back to this file in just a minute.
But for now, let's jump back down into the command line and this time let's actually install Express.
So to do that type in the command NPM install and what package do we want to install express.
So NPM install, express and then push, enter.
All right, now, two things just happened.
Number one, the actual files or ingredients for the express package got stored in our Noad Modules
folder that lives within our project folder.
So that's like when you get home from the grocery store and you unload the groceries into your cupboards
and your refrigerator.
But the other thing that just happened is our packaged JSON file was modified to include express in
its list of dependencies.
That means that this package, JSON file is like our grocery list or our recipe.
It keeps a running list of all the ingredients our application needs in order to run.
Now we will learn why that's so important and why that's necessary later on in the course.
But for now, I don't want to get dragged down into a tangent for now.
All you need to know is that this file is very important and that we will circle back to it a bit later
on.
For the time being, let's get back to the task at hand and build our server that listens for incoming
requests.
So within our server JS file on a new line, let's say let app equal and then let's just call Express
Express and then parentheses to call it.
OK, on a new line, let's tell our app to begin listening for incoming requests.
So let's just say app dot listen parentheses to call that listen method in between the parentheses,
let's tell it to listen on PT..
Three thousand.
OK, and then maybe right above that app.
Listen line, let's add one more new line and tell our app what it should do if it receives an incoming
request to the homepage url.
So let's say app dot get meaning if it receives a gett request.
And the first argument inside these parentheses should be the euro that we're looking out for.
So we can just say quotes forwards to represent the base or homepage you rl then let's include a comma
and the next argument should be a function that will run when this request happens.
So let's include an anonymous function.
So function parentheses, curly brackets, feel free to drop down in between the parentheses for the
function.
Let's include parameters that are named RFQ in our S for request and response.
OK, and then within the body of the function, let's just respond to this incoming request by sending
back a bit of HTML or text that says welcome to our app.
So to do that, let's just say RSS for response.
Look inside it for a method named send, call that method and pass it a string of text that says Hello,
welcome to our app.
OK, at this point, let's go ahead and save this file in our text editor and then try to visit our
server in a Web browser.
So let's first make sure to tell our server to begin running.
So down in the command line area, let's run a command and say node and then the name of this file that
we want to feed into the node environment.
So the name of the file is server.
You can leave off the dot js.
So just say node server, press enter.
OK, it's up and running.
Now if we jump over to the web browser and try to visit local host Colen three thousand.
Cool.
We see.
Hello and welcome to our app.
However, this is not what we actually want to send to a visitor.
What we actually want to send is each HTML that will create this user interface.
However, this is not a course in HTML, so I'm not going to walk through keystroke by keystroke and
type out an HTML template with you.
So instead I've included the bare bones skeleton of an HTML template up on the Web.
And right now I'm going to show you how you can visit it, so then you can just copy and paste the basic
template.
So right now, open up a new tab in your Web browser and I want you to visit git hub, dot com slash,
learn web code, slash JavaScript if you need to pause the video while you type out this URL.
That's OK.
I will also include a link to this in the resources for this lesson.
OK, from this GitHub page, if you scroll down a bit towards the bottom of the page, you'll see a
list of files or folders click on the folder that's named O one underscore simple app.
Then you'll see one file named Template HTML, click on that.
And then finally, at the bottom of this page, you'll see the actual code that we're going to work
with now, instead of trying to select this to copy and paste it, I actually recommend you first click
this button here that says raw once you click the raw button.
Now, all this on your screen is the raw HTML code.
So just select all of this or press command or control a to select at all and then just copy it into
your clipboard.
OK, then jump back into your text editing program and on this line where we say response dot send,
let's get rid of this.
Hello and welcome to our app.
And let's also even get rid of the quotes.
Let's replace those quotes with Back Tick's, two of them.
So this is the character to the left of the one key or right above the tab key in between those two
back decks.
I want you to paste in your clipboard.
Awesome.
Now, we did not miss an educational opportunity by simply copying and pasting because there is no JavaScript
code going on in this, all we pasted in was simple HTML, a basic user interface template that will
create the overall look that we're going after.
Now, I do want to mention that in the real world, you would not mix in your HTML template with the
rest of your server code in a single file like this.
What we just did is very messy.
But don't worry, when we build our more complex app or app number two later on in the course, we will
learn how to stay organized and keep our HTML template in a separate file.
But for now, this simplistic approach of having everything in a single file will work just fine at
this point.
Go ahead and save this file again and then let's come down into our command line and press control and
see to stop the server and then let's just fire the server up again.
So node server.
OK, then jump back to your Web browser where you were visiting Localhost Colen three thousand and refresh
the page.
Awesome.
You should see something that looks like this.
So it's our to do app and it has three fake hardcoded items.
So this data is not being read from a database.
This is just static HTML content and none of these buttons do anything.
So trust me, we did not miss any educational opportunities by just copying and pasting this code.
It's our job now to bring this interface to life.
Now, before we worry about learning how to connect to a Mongo DB database, let's first just be able
to respond to this form being submitted right before we worry about a database.
Let's first be able to extract whatever value the user types into this field and then tries to send
to our server to do that.
Let's jump back into our text editor, scroll down to the very bottom of our server, not just file.
And maybe right above our app listen line, let's add a new line and say app dot post within these parentheses,
we want to pass this method to arguments.
So A comma B is placeholders.
The first argument is that you are l that we want to look out for.
So let's say quotes and then a slash and then you could make up whatever you want.
But I'm going to go with create dash item.
So the idea here is when the web browser sends a post request to this U.
RL, well what do we want to do in response?
We want to run a function.
So instead of this placeholder B include an anonymous function, function, parentheses, curly brackets,
it's dropdown within the function parentheses.
Be sure to include request and response that the express framework is going to pass into our function.
OK, and now within the body of this function, what do we want to do in response to this incoming request?
Well, let's do two things.
First, let's log out to the console.
So console dot log and ultimately as a test, I want to log to the console whatever value the user typed
into this field here.
But for the time being, let's just include a test that says make this dynamic in a minute from now.
So we will circle back to this line of code.
But aside from logging that to the console, let's also add another line and send a response back to
the Web browser that just says thank you for submitting the form.
So let's say R.
S and then send and then let's just send back a little bit of text so quotes and say thanks for submitting
the form.
OK, next, what we need to do is adjust our HTML template so that when someone actually does submit
this form, it sends a request to the u r l that we're expecting.
Right, because we just wrote code.
That's assuming the form is going to submit to this U.
RL slash create item.
So let's scroll up to the top of this file and let's dig into this HTML template.
Scroll down through the HTML template, and we are looking for the opening form tag, if you find the
opening body tag, it should just be about five lines below that.
So on the opening form tag, we want to give it an action attribute, say action equals and then quotes
and then say slash create item.
This controls which you orell the form sends its request to when the user submits the form.
And then finally, also we want to add another attribute named method and say equals and then quotes
and say post all uppercase post.
OK, let's make another change.
Just two lines below the opening form tag.
We see an input element.
This is the field that users actually type into.
And right after the word input, let's give it an attribute of name and say equals quotes and give it
a name value of item.
There's nothing special about the word item.
You could choose any word here, but choose item just because it's easy to remember and you'll be on
the same page as I am.
OK, and now that we've told our form where to submit to and we've given that input field a name.
Now let's jump back to the very bottom of this file, OK?
And within our app post area, right.
The area where we say thanks for submitting the form instead of logging out this make this dynamic in
a minute from now to the console.
So let's get rid of that and get rid of the quotes, too.
And just as a test, what we actually want to log out to the console is whatever value the user types
into this field.
Right.
We want to make sure that we can successfully extract that value before we even worry about a database.
So back in our code, let's say console, dot log and look inside the request object.
So HQ look inside it for the body object and then look inside that for the item property, because that's
the name of that input field that we just adjusted in the HTML.
OK, now we just have one more step before we can save this and test it out.
Let's scroll up to the very, very top of this file and right below our LET app Equal Express Line.
Let's add a new line and we just need to tell Express to add all form values to a body object and then
add that body object to the request object because by default, express does not do this.
So this is just a bit of boilerplate code.
It's not very educational, but type this out with me.
App dot use inside of the use parentheses, let's say express dot u rl encoded parentheses to call that
inside that create an object with curly brackets and then set the extended property so extended colon
and set it to false.
Again, this just configures the express framework to include a very convenient body object that gets
added on to the request object.
In other words, it makes it very easy to access the users form data that they are submitting.
OK, at this point, let's go ahead and save the file, come down to our command line and restart the
server.
So control easy to quit.
Fire it up again.
Jump back to your web browser and refresh.
Localhost three thousand and go ahead and type something into this form, I will say by cinnamon and
as soon as I submit the form I see.
Thank you for submitting the form.
But more importantly, back in the command line we see that that value of by cinnamon was locked to
the console.
Awesome.
So we now have our HTML user interface up and running and we are able to successfully access whatever
value the user types in.
This means we are 100 percent ready to learn how to connect.
Are no JS application to a Mongo DB database.
Right, because we want to permanently store or save whatever value the user types in.
This is where the Big three JavaScript technologies all come together seamlessly to create a meaningful
experience.
Setting this up is going to be a ton of fun.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.