For our next task, we should probably set things up so that messages from you yourself appear differently,
maybe if it's a message that you sent, it's aligned to the right instead of the left, and maybe it
has a blue background instead of a gray background.
Also, if we think about it, it's a waste of server resources to send your own message back to you.
Your message data would really only need to be sent to all of the other connected browsers.
Let me show you what I'm getting at.
So back within our app James file, when we receive an incoming message, right.
So socketed on chat message from browser, we are responding by sending it out to everyone on this line.
However, this is actually sending it to everyone, including the person who sent the message in the
first place, when really if you think about it, the author of a message doesn't need that data.
They're the one that sent it.
So instead, if we change this from I omit to get rid of the IO and say socket dot broadcast dot imit,
this will emit this event to any and all connected browsers except the socket connection that sent the
message in the first place.
So now we can set things up in our front end JavaScript so that when you send a message to the server,
well, the browser just grabs whatever text was in that field and adds it into the chat log.
However, our browser based JavaScript would still need to know the username and avatar of the current
user that you're logged in as.
So let's do this within app dot js right below this line.
When we say let user equal right below that, let's drop down and let's do this.
Let's say socket dot imit and let's omit a new event time.
We can name it whatever we want.
I'm going to name it.
Welcome.
Right.
So this is going to run when a new connection is established and then let's include a comma and an object.
A bit of data that we want to send along with this event.
And I just want to send to the browser the current user name and avatar from session data.
So within these curly brackets, let's say username, Kolan user, dot username, comma, one more property
named Avatar, Kolan user dot avatar.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now let's go adjust our front end JavaScript to leverage this welcome event.
So back in chat, James, I want you to look for the method that is named open connection, maybe right
above this line where we say this dot socket on chat message from server right above that lets out a
new line and let's say this dot socket dot on within those parentheses, we're going to give it to arguments.
So A comma B is placeholders for the first argument.
Let's say quotes.
Welcome.
Right.
When we first open a connection, the server is going to send a welcome event.
And when that happens, we just want to run a function.
So get rid of the B placeholder and let's create an arrow function.
Within the parentheses for our aero function, let's say data, technically, since we only have one
argument, we don't even need the parentheses.
OK, then within the body of this function, let's just store that data within our overall object so
we could say this dot user name equals data dot username.
And then we can also say this avatar equals data avatar, now that we've stored those values in memory,
we can use them again later on.
So now let's go find our method that is named send message to server for me.
It's up towards the top around line number twenty five.
And remember, when you send a message, the server is no longer going to send it back to you.
It's going to send it to any and all connected browsers except for the person who originally sent that
message.
This means that within send message to server we would now want to handle adding the HTML to the chat
log.
So let's do this within send message to server, maybe right below this this socket emit.
Let's add a new line here and let's say this dot chat log dot insert adjacent html parentheses for the
first argument before and comma for the second argument.
Let's include back ticks within the two back ticks.
Let's drop down, I'll drop down one more line so we have this clean empty line.
And now I don't expect you to type out a bunch of HTML by hand.
So instead let's jump back to GitHub and within this same chat, Dasch visible the HTML template.
I want you to look for line number sixty two so you'll see a comment that says template for your own
message.
And here we see a comment that reads End Template.
So I just want you to select these eight lines of code and copy those into your clipboard.
OK, now back in our text editor within the two back text, just paste in your clipboard.
OK, now let's just hollo things out and make everything dynamic, so let's get rid of this hardcoded.
Hello, how are you?
In its place, let's say dollar sign curly brackets, and we would just want to grab whatever value
the user has currently typed into this textfield field.
So within the dollar sign curly brackets, we could just say this dot Chatfield dot value.
OK, and then let's make the Avatar dynamic.
So instead of this hardcoded value for an avatar, get rid of that https until the end of the quotes.
Now within the quotes we can say dollar sign curly brackets and just say this dot avatar.
It turns out we don't actually need this username property we set up.
That's OK.
I think you get the idea.
We did still need to hold on to that avatar value in memory.
So you get the point.
Let's go ahead and save this and take it for a test drive back in the browser, refresh all connected
browsers and if I reopen up the chat, I can say hello.
Perfect.
So since I'm the author of the message, it's aligned to the right.
It has a blue background.
But in this window for Barbes a lot, it's aligned to the left and has a gray background and then it
barks a lot, says please feed me.
Perfect.
You get the idea.
It's displayed this way for the author of the message, but for all other connected users, it's displayed
like this at this point.
Let's change gears and work on a few final details.
So, for example, once there are enough chat messages to make this area, I have to scroll.
So let me spam a bunch of messages to show you what I'm referring to.
It becomes clear that after each new message, we would want to automatically tell this div to scroll
down to its bottom so that the newest message can be seen.
Right.
We can't expect users to continuously be manually scrolling down as new messages come in.
So let me show you how I would set this up back in Chatterji.
Yes, within our send message to server method, maybe right after our HTML template and right before
this line where we reset the value of the field, lets out a new line and we can just say this dot chat
log dot scroll top.
This will let us say how far down the element should be scrolled.
So we would just want it to be scrolled down all the way to the very bottom so we can just set this
to equal this dot chat log dot scroll height.
So this will set its scroll position to its exact scroll high value.
In other words, it'll scroll to the very bottom.
Now, let's go ahead and copy this line of code that we just wrote.
Copy it into your clipboard because, yes, we've updated send message to server, but we need to go
update our display message from server method as well.
So for me, that's a round line number sixty five, right, display message from server right after
the end of this HTML template.
So right after the back take and closing parentheses, I'll just drop down and paste in my clipboard.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I refresh in the browser and I'll refresh in the bark's lot window as well and open up the chart
again.
So now if I spam enough messages to create vertical scrolling, let's see.
Cool.
Now, the user never has to worry about scrolling to the bottom to see the newest messages, and if
I check the box a lot, browser, cool, we can see it's working for messages from other users as well.
Let's take care of one more miscellaneous detail before we change our focus and think about security.
Let's set things up so that when you first open the chat feature, this field is automatically focused,
right?
My cursor should be blinking in that field so I can just begin typing immediately.
So to make that happen back in Chattooga.
Yes, I would just find our method that is named show chat at the very end of this method.
So maybe below this line and add a new line and just say this dot chat field and then call the focus
method.
Let's give that a save.
And now if I reload, notice how as soon as I click the chat icon, my cursor is blinking down here
and I don't have to click anywhere.
I can just immediately begin typing.
Cool.
At this point, let's change gears and talk about security.
Actually, instead of trying to use words to explain the security vulnerability here, let me just show
you visually.
So imagine I'm logged in to our application, but I am a malicious user.
Well, in the chat box, I could do this.
I could create a span element, right.
In HTML element and inside the tags, I could say, hi, how are you?
But on the opening span tag, I could say on mouse over equals quotes and then I could create a JavaScript
alert message that says ha ha, JavaScript just ran close out the single quotes, close out the parentheses.
Cool if I push enter and then if anyone hovered over this message, it runs the JavaScript code now
instead of an alert box, that could be something malicious, that could be anything JavaScript is executing.
And look at this.
It's executing for anyone connected to the chat right now.
If poor old innocent barks, a lot hovers over that message.
Their account on our app is compromised and potentially they're having malware installed on their computer.
So to protect our users from malicious users in the chat like this, let me show you what I would do.
Let's begin on the server side and let's sanitize any incoming messages before we broadcast them out
to any and all other connected users.
So jump into app dot J.S..
And towards the bottom of this file, remember, we have this area where we say Eyo on connection and
then six or seven lines down, we have this area that says sock it on chat message from browser.
So we are receiving an incoming message.
And then this line is where we broadcast it out to any and all other users.
So let's just do this for the data that we're sending out for the message property after message call.
Let's get rid of data on message and instead, let's say sanitize each HTML parentheses to call it.
So we've already included this package up towards the top of Applegate's, so we are free to leverage
it here again.
So within these parentheses, we give it two things.
A, comma, B, the first argument is the string of text that we want to sanitize.
So that would be data dot message.
And then the second argument instead of the B placeholder would be an object.
So curly brackets and we just give it a few options.
So let's give it a property of allowed tags, colon and I don't want to allow any HTML tags.
So an empty array, so empty square brackets, comma.
Then we say aloud attributes colon and I don't want to allow any attributes so just an empty object.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
Now remember we set things up so that when you send a message the server doesn't send it back to you,
the author, it just sends it to everyone else.
Meaning at the moment, if a malicious user tried to send over a bit of malicious code, yes, they'd
be able to add it to their own chat log because that's not being processed by the server.
So we can see the JavaScript still executes.
But the idea is they're not able to do that for other or innocent users.
So in this window, the bark's a lot window.
Now, if I hover over that message, nothing bad happens.
It has been sanitized to make the issue obvious.
Back in this window, I could create a heading level one and say, hey there.
And it's truly a heading level one for this user because the server isn't sanitizing it.
But for all other users, clearly it's not a heading level one.
Right.
It's been sanitized.
OK, let's take one extra security precaution.
Let's assume the worst.
Let's assume for some reason that server side sanitisation did not work for innocent users.
We'd still want some sort of last line of defense within the client side.
Let me show you what I would do back in our text editor.
Let's jump in to chat.
James, up at the very top of this file, I want to import in a package so even above the export default
line, let's add a new line and let's say import dom, purify from quotes and then all lowercase dom
purify.
This is a package we've already used earlier in the course, so we do not need to worry about running
NPM install.
OK, and then I would just go leverage this.
So let's find our display message from server method.
For me it's around line number sixty eight and here's what I would do.
So we are inserting adjacent HTML before the end.
I would just select this entire template literal into my clipboard so I would begin selecting this first
back tick and then I would just select until the closing back tick and I would cut all of that into
my clipboard in its place.
I would just say Dom, purify, dot, sanitize and sanitize as a method so it gets its own parentheses
to call it.
And then in those parentheses we can just paste back in our clipboard while we're at it.
We could also do the same thing for send message to server.
So if we scroll back up.
Here is the send a message to server method now modifying this method would not actually enhance the
security, right?
We don't care if a malicious user wants to infect their own browser, but if you wanted to, you could
do the same thing here so you could find the insert adjacent HTML, copy the entire back tick template
into your clipboard copier, cut that and then just say Dom purified, sanitize parentheses and then
paste back in that template.
Literal.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So now back in the browser, if I refresh and if I pretend I'm a malicious user and paste in that span
on mouseover code, you can see now even if I hover over it, that JavaScript has been sanitized or
removed now.
Yes, a malicious user could modify the JavaScript on their client side, but you get the idea.
Dom Purify is now running both for messages from yourself and for messages from other users.
So now, even if our server side sanitisation for some reason failed, we can rest assured that our
innocent users still have client side sanitisation to protect them.
That takes care of the security aspect.
Now, one final detail before we bring this lesson to a close, and that is it would be nice if we could
link to a user's profile when you hover over their username or avatar in the chat.
So let me show you how we can set that up back within Chattooga.
Yes.
Let's find our display message from server method and within the HTML template, just find the link
that is wrapped around the image.
And instead of this hash tag for the graph, we could just say slash profile slash and then we'd want
their username so we could say dollar sign, curly brackets and then DataDot username.
We'd want to do the same thing as well for when you hover over their username so we could just copy
and paste this value within these quotes.
Copy that.
And then within this HSF hash tag, replace that and paste in your clipboard.
Lets go ahead and save that.
And now if I refresh both instances of the front end and then say, hey, check out my profile.
Well for all the users that would see that message, they see my username and avatar and you can see
down in the bottom left corner when they hover over it, it would take them to that uttara.
For example, if I click on this Avatar takes me to the Brad profile.
Cool.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson.
We're going to change gears and it's going to be a quick miscellaneous fix, but we're going to learn
how to make the title for each of our pages dynamic right now, no matter which page you go to, it
always just says our app as the title, for example.
It would be nice if when you go to a post if the title of the post was reflected in the title for this
page, not only would this help with search engine optimization, but it's also just a nice change in
general.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.