Hello, everyone, welcome to part two of this lesson.
Let's pick up right where we left off.
In the first part of this lesson, we used NPM in the command line to download Express.
And up in our file, we've written this line of code to get express ready.
Now we can actually begin to write code that uses Express to build the server.
So let's create a new variable.
So let and then you can name anything you want, but I'm going to name it our app and let's set it to
equal and then just call Express.
So this will create or return an express application or server.
Right.
That's leveraging that pre written JavaScript code that we downloaded.
And now we have a server that lives in this variable named our app.
So now let's tell our server to begin listening for incoming requests.
So on a new line, we can just say our app and then dot and call the listen method and let's listen
on PT..
Three thousand, OK.
And then right above this listen line, let's add a new line to tell our server what it should do if
someone sends a request to our homepage.
So let's use our our app variable and then call a method so dot and the method is named Git.
I will explain what the word get means in this context a bit later on in the lesson.
But for now, all we need to know is that we give it to arguments so we could say A comma B as placeholders.
The first argument is the you are L that you want to be on the lookout for.
So let's just say quotes and then a forward slash.
This represents the home page or base.
You all right.
And then the second argument is a function that express is going to run any time someone sends a request
to this U.
RL.
So instead of this placeholder B, let's write an anonymous function.
So function parentheses, curly brackets and then dropdown inside those curly brackets.
When Express calls this function, it's going to pass it to arguments.
So inside these parentheses, let's include two parameters RFQ comma R.
S OK, now within the body of our function here, what do we actually want to do?
Well, when someone sends a request to the home page URL in response, we just want to send back a bit
of HTML that would create this page with this text and form field.
So back in our code within the body of our function, we can use the response object from Express and
then look inside it with a dot and then call an express method named send.
And what do we want to send?
Well, instead of just simple quotes for a string of text, let's actually use back ticks.
Remember, this is the key to the left of your one key or right above your tab key.
And in between the back ticks, we are free to break down onto separate lines like this.
You don't have to do this.
I'm doing this just to stay organized because I think HTML is easier to read for the human eye if it's
on separate lines.
So now we can just start writing HTML.
Let's create a form element.
So in opening form tag, closing form tag inside that form, why don't we create a paragraph and inside
the paragraph we can say what color is the sky on a clear and sunny day, maybe right below that paragraph.
Let's create a form input field that the user can type into.
So just create an input element.
Input does not need a matching closing tag, but on the opening input tag, let's give it a name so
name equals and then quotes and let's say sky color.
I just made this name up of sky color.
It doesn't matter.
It could be unicorn or pizza or anything.
OK, let's also give this input an attribute named auto complete and set that to off.
You don't need to do this.
I just don't like the annoying pop up auto suggestion feature in the browser.
OK, and then right below the input element, let's create a button so the user can click on it to submit
the form.
So opening button tag.
Closing button tag and we can say submit answer.
OK, now before we save the file, let's address the opening form tag.
Let's give it a couple of attributes.
Let's say action.
Quotes and let's say forward slash answer.
And then after those quotes, let's give it one more attribute named method and set that equal quotes
and say all capital post post.
Now I realize I did not explain what action equals answer or what method equals post means.
Don't worry, we will circle back to that in just about a minute from now.
For the time being, let's go ahead and save this file and then come down into the command line and
take it for a test drive.
So let's run the command node test or whatever your file is named.
Push, enter.
And then if you jump over to your Web browser and visit, localhost three thousand, you might need
to refresh the page, but you should see something that looks almost identical to this.
Now here's where things get interesting.
Let's try to fill out and submit the form feel right.
So click into the field.
Doesn't matter what you type, but just go ahead and submit the form and we see some good news and some
bad news.
The good news is if you look up in the euro or address bar, our form redirected us to a slash answer
you R-AL.
That means that we typed out the HTML for that form correctly.
And as you might have guessed, this is where the slash answer comes into play.
Whatever you set as the action for an HTML form.
Well, that's the Eurail that the browser is going to send the form results to.
Now I just randomly chose the word answer here, but there's nothing special about that.
You could have set this to pizza or unicorn or anything.
OK, so that explains the action attribute.
But what about the method attribute?
What in the world does method equal post mean?
Well, this controls the type of request that the browser is going to send to the server in the land
of the Internet and HTTP requests.
There are actually many different types of requests.
But for now, in the context of this lesson, we really only need to be aware of two different types
of requests, a request and a post request.
So in your Web browser, when you visit a U.
RL.
So if I typed in Google dot com.
My browser just sent a gett request to the Google servers, or if I clicked on one of these navigation
links at the top of Google, like if I clicked on there about Link to go to the about page, my browser
sent a get request to that about you URL.
So when you're surfing the web, a get request is sort of the standard type of request.
If you manually type in a Eurail or if you click on a traditional navigation link, it's a request.
You're saying to the server you want to get a bit of information.
So if I go back to local host, call in three thousand, my browser sends a request to the server.
However, if I fill out this form and then tried to submit it, my browser not only wants to get information
about that new Eurail of answer, but it also needs to send along its own data to that.
You are right.
It needs to send along whatever I typed into the form fields.
So it needs to send that data or in other words, it needs to post that data, hence the word post.
So if I submit this form, we see cannot post to answer.
And that's because we never told our express server what it should do in response to receiving a request
to the answer you RL.
Now, before we worry about actually evaluating the user's answer, let's first make sure that we actually
understand the difference between a get request and a post request.
Trust me, I've seen many different full stack development courses and I feel like they always gloss
over this difference and it's usually confusing and a bit blurry.
So let's run through a quick exercise to make that difference between git and post crystal-clear back
in our code.
Perhaps this method named Git right here is starting to make a bit more sense.
We are telling our app what it should do if it receives a get request to this U.
RL.
So let's do this.
Let's scroll down to the bottom of this code and maybe right above this listen line.
Let's add a new line and say our app.
And then instead of Dawngate, let's say Dot Post.
So we are going to tell our app what it should do if it receives a post request to the slash answer.
You are going just like with the git method.
We want to give the post method a second argument.
So comma, and then we include a function that Express will run in response to this request occurring.
So after this comma include an anonymous function function in parentheses, curly brackets inside the
parentheses for the function include the parameters are Q and R.
S inside the body of our function.
Let's just send back a bit of text that reads Thank you for submitting the form so we can use the response
object and call the send method a bit of text.
Thank you for submitting the form.
OK, now before we save this and test it out, I want to do something to make the difference between
a get request and a post request.
Crystal clear.
What I want you to do is select these three new lines of code that we just wrote, copy them into your
clipboard and then right below this.
But before the listen line, just paste in your clipboard, so duplicate it.
And on this new copy, I want you to change this word post to get so on the second copy.
It's our app yet.
So if someone sends a post request to this answer you URL, this makes sense.
But if someone sends a request to that same you rl let's do this instead.
Let's just send back a bit of text that says, are you lost?
There is nothing to see here.
OK, at this point let's go ahead and save the file and then test it out in our browser.
So let's come down into the command line and press control, see to stop the old server and then let's
just run.
No test to fire up a new copy of the server with our latest code.
All right.
And then back in the browser, if I just go to localhost three thousand and fill out the form, submit,
thank you for submitting the form.
So this is in response to the post request to answer.
However, if I go back to the home page and then up in the euro address bar, if I manually type in
slash answer, that is a get request.
So that's why we see.
Are you lost?
There is nothing to see here.
So hopefully this illustrates the difference between a request and a post request.
A get request happens when you type in a neutral or you click on a traditional navigation link.
A post request typically happens when you submit a form, right?
When.
The user wants to send or post a bit of data to the server, so even though in both cases the Eurail
ends with slash answer, our server is able to respond differently depending on whether it's a get request
or a post request.
All right.
So now that we have at least a very general understanding of what a post request is, let's get back
to the actual task at hand.
So when someone submits the form, we don't want to just say thank you for submitting.
We want to actually evaluate their answer and tell them if it's correct or incorrect.
Right.
And we are asking them what color is the sky on a clear and sunny day?
So the question becomes, how can we access the data that the user submits from within our server?
Well, the good news is that Express makes it very simple.
So let's jump back into our code and within the hour app dot post area.
Right.
This is what's going to occur when someone submits the form.
Let's actually get rid of this response send line.
So now we just have an empty body of the function because before we send back a response, we need to
decide if they typed in the correct answer or not.
So we know that in JavaScript we have a tool to do just that.
And that is the if statement.
So let's say if parentheses curly brackets inside the curly brackets, let's drop down right after those
curly brackets.
We can say ls a new set of curly brackets.
OK, and let's fill in the condition.
So in the parentheses right after the word.
If let's say if X equal equal sign blue.
Now I just typed in X as a temporary placeholder.
So now the million dollar question is how do we actually access the user's typed in value here?
Well, instead of the placeholder X, get rid of that and let's say R e q for request.
This is the request object that express passes into our function, which contains all sorts of information
about the incoming request.
So within our IF statement, we can say if our Q dot body dot sky color equals blue.
So the request object and then body is the body of the post of what they're sending.
It's the main meat and potatoes.
And then we are looking inside that for the sky color property because an HTML form could contain multiple
fields.
So we need to specify which specific field or value we are interested in.
If you're wondering where this name Sky Color came from.
Remember that this will be exactly whatever you typed in for the input name when we were building the
HTML for our form.
OK, so if this evaluates to true, then the user typed in the correct answer.
So within our IF statement curly brackets, let's just send back a congrats message.
So response dot send.
I'm going to include back tick so I can drop down onto multiple lines.
And in between the tactics let's just send an HTML paragraph that says congrats.
That is the correct answer.
And then maybe right below the paragraph.
Let's include an HTML link that they can click on to go back to the home page.
So a four anchor in the middle, let's say back to home page and on the opening attack, let's give
it an H ref and then let's just say forward slash to represent the home page.
OK, but if the user types in something other than blue, that's incorrect.
So we need to fill in this else part of our code.
So to save a bit of typing, let's just copy and paste these lines right here from the start of our
S to the end of the closing parentheses for the send.
So I'm just going to select that and then copy it.
And then in the else brackets, I'm going to paste in my clipboard.
This time around, we just want to change the message that's in the paragraph.
So this time we'll just say sorry.
That is incorrect.
All right.
Now, before we save our file and test it out, we need to do one more thing by default.
Out of the box Express actually will not add the user's inputs to the body object that belongs to the
request object.
So in order for this code that I'm selecting right now, in order for this to work, we need to tell
Express to enable that feature.
So do this with me.
Scroll up to the very top of our file and right below this line where we say let our app equal and then
we call Express right below that.
Let's add a new line and let's just say our app dot use and now the rest of this line of code.
Is not going to be educational in the slightest.
This is more of boilerplate code that you would find on the Express Documentation website and then you
would just copy and paste it and include it in each of your new express projects.
So this is not something that you need to memorize.
But let's say express dot, you are l encoded parentheses to call that method.
Then we give it an object.
So curly brackets inside those brackets, we include a property named Extended and then Colon and set
it to false.
You might need to pause the video lesson for a minute to type this in with me.
But again, I'm not going to explain it because this is just boilerplate code and it's not educational.
All it's doing is enabling that feature and express so that the user's input is easily accessible from
the request body object at this point.
Let's go ahead and save our file.
Come down to the command line, stop the old server, fire up the new server.
Let's go back to the browser by refresh the homepage and type in something other than blue simit.
Sorry, that is incorrect, but if I go back to the home page and type in blue, congrats.
That is the correct answer.
Now you might be thinking to yourself, what if someone types in all capitals blue or just the first
letter capitalized?
We see.
Sorry, that is incorrect, even though that is the correct answer.
So really quick to make our code case insensitive instead of case sensitive.
All we need to do is come into our IF statement and right after the request body dot sky color.
Just say dot to upper case parentheses to call that method.
So whatever the user typed in will be converted to all capitals and then we can just check to see if
that equals.
And then for here we can just say all uppercase blue.
So let me save that and then restart the server, jump back into the browser if I type blue or maybe
leave the E lowercase just to really prove a point and submit congrats.
That is the correct answer.
And that's actually going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we are going to do two things.
Number one, we will review why this example app was so important.
And number two, we will identify the missing ingredient that is going to let us create more advanced
applications.
Let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.