Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to learn how to set up a router.
So first the question becomes, what in the world is a router?
Well, to answer that, let's jump right into our code.
A router has the responsibility of listing out the Urals or routes that you want to listen for and then
say what should happen for each of those routes.
So essentially, any time we would write app dot get or app dot post, we are defining a route.
And so we'd want to keep all of those within a router.
The idea is to stay organized so we keep all of our roots in a separate file and that's the only responsibility
of that file.
It's just the router.
So right now, let's create a new file in the root of our project folder.
So new file.
Technically, we could name this file anything.
But just so we are on the same page, let's name it router dot J.S..
OK, now, before we actually learn how to set up roots from within this file, we first need to learn
how to let one JavaScript file communicate with another or let one JavaScript file share its code with
another.
So for the next couple of minutes, this has nothing to do with Roots or Express.
Instead, this is just a basic node, jayesh skill of learning how to share code from one file to another.
Right.
Because we want to be able to write code within this rutabagas and then we want to leverage it within
our app JS file.
Now, at the very top of our app that we see require, this is something we've used many times in the
course already.
We know that we can use require to load in or import in or require in a package.
So we know that we can use require with packages that we didn't create, but we can also use require
to pull in JavaScript files that we did create.
Let me show you what I mean.
Let's jump back into our new empty rutabagas file and let's write two lines of code just as a test.
So first, let's log a message to the console console dialog.
And let's just say I am executed immediately.
All right.
And then right below that line of code, let's add one more new line and let's say module dot exports.
I know that this is our first time seeing this module exports.
Don't worry.
I will explain what this means in a minute from now.
But let's set this to equal.
And for now, let's just set it to a string of text that says I am the export for the router file.
OK, if you need to pause the video to type this out with me, that's OK.
But let's go ahead and save this file.
And then back in our Apgar's file, let's use require to load that file in.
So maybe right below this const app equals express line.
Let's add a new line and let's say const.
You could choose any name, but let's choose router and let's set it to equal and then we can use the
require function and the question becomes, what do we put in these quotes?
If we were looking for an NPM package, you can just type the name of the package.
But in this case, we actually want to provide it with a file path.
Right, a path that points towards that rutabagas file so we can say dot forward slash to look within
the current folder or directory and then we just type out the file name.
You could include the dot just at the end here, but it's not necessary.
Now, before I save this file, I'm just going to make sure that my app is running.
So down in the command line, I will say NPM run watch.
OK, and now as soon as I save this file in our console, we see I am executed immediately.
Cool.
So that was that console, that logline that we just wrote in our router file.
This means that we successfully executed code from a separate file.
And this is all thanks to the require function.
So the require function in node does two things.
Number one, it executes said file, but number two, it also returns whatever that file exports.
Right.
And that's what's going to get stored into this variable that we are creating.
So back and router, I guess that's why we wrote this line where we say module exports equals something.
The no jazz environment knows what this means.
It's on the lookout for this special variable.
And whatever we set it to equal to will be returned when we require this violin.
So just to see this come full circle back in our Apgar's file, let's try to log to the console, our
router variable.
So console dot log router as soon as I hit save.
The app automatically reloads, and down here we see I am the export for the router file, so big picture
when you require in a file, the entire file is going to get executed.
That's going to happen immediately.
But the idea is that whatever you export, that is going to be stored in our variable and then we can
use that whenever and wherever we see fit.
Right now we can use this variable later on in this file.
Now, before we move on and change gears and actually learn how routers work and express, I do want
to let you know one more thing about exports in node, and that is that you are free to export whatever
you want.
So in this example, we exported a simple string of text, but you could export a number or an array
or a function or perhaps most commonly you can export an object.
So, for example, instead of this string of text, you could include curly brackets to create an object
and then just to stay organized, you could drop down in between those curly brackets.
You could provide different properties so you could have name and set that to me as a lot comma.
You could have another property species set that to cat comma, and then you could have another property
that's actually a method or a function.
So we can have a method named MÃ and that could be a function.
And inside that function we could just log to the console and say MÃ.
And just to clean up this example a bit, we can get rid of this console, that log.
I am executed immediately.
Line.
All right.
Now if I go ahead and save this file, you can see that object got logged to the console.
This is because back in Applegate's, we are logging the router variable, the variable that equals
the result of requiring that file.
The reason I'm spending so much time explaining this is because now you are free to use that object
and its properties anywhere in this file.
So, for example, we could say router, name or router, not species' or router, not MÃ.
Right.
Because that variable is going to equal literally whatever you exported.
This may not seem like a big deal right now, but trust me, this allows for some very powerful and
very organized code.
OK, so that concludes our introduction to requiring our own files at this point.
Now we can actually learn about routers in Express because believe it or not, a router does not typically
have a MIAOW method.
That was just an example of working with separate files and staying organized.
All right.
At this point, let's get rid of this router, drop me out line, and let's also jump in to our router,
not just file and let's delete everything so we have a clean slate and now let's actually build a router
for our application to refresh your memory.
It's the routers job to list out all of the Urals or routes that we are on the lookout for.
All right.
So within our Radagast file, let's begin by including the express framework so we can say const xpress
equals and then just require in the express package.
All right, then let's create our own constant variable named router.
You could name it anything, but that's what I'm going with.
And let's set that to equal.
And then let's look inside the express package for something named router and parentheses, because
we're calling it this way.
The express framework will return sort of a mini application or a router.
I'll explain what I mean by mini application in just a minute here.
Down at the bottom, let's say this, let's say module dot exports and let's just export that new router
variable that we just created.
So module exports equals router.
All right.
Now, check this out above that last line.
Let's add a new line of code and now let's use our router variable and say router dot git.
So this is just like before when we would say app dot get for a get request or app post for a post request
only instead of working with our overall express app.
Now we are just working with our router, but it works the exact same way.
So we would say router get the first argument, we will say the base you Aurel and then for the second
argument, so comma and then a function function parentheses, curly brackets, let's dropdown.
We know that within these parentheses we include request and response as parameters and then within
the body of this function.
So what do we want to do if someone sends a request to our homepage?
We just want to respond by rendering our homepage template.
So remember we named that template or view home dash.
Yes.
And that's it.
This could might look familiar, this is the exact code that we typed into our app that file.
This is what I meant when I said that this is sort of like a new mini express application, just like
we told our app what to do for getting post requests.
Well, we were telling our router what to do.
And then obviously that router variable of ours, that's what we are exporting.
That's what we are making available to any file that requires in this file.
So let's go ahead and save this rutabagas file and then let's jump into our Applegate's file and now
check this out.
Find the area that says App Dawngate.
And we no longer need this code because now we set that up in our router file.
So just delete these three lines of code from Apgar's.
And in its place, we just want to tell our overall express application to use that new router that
we set up so we can just say app dot use.
And in this case we want to give it to arguments.
So A comma, B for the first argument instead of this A, we just want to tell it, which you are able
to use this router for.
In this case, we want this to be our overall or based router.
So just forward to represent the base of our site.
And then the second argument instead of this be placeholder, this is the router that we want to use
so we can just say router.
Right, because that is the name of the variable that imports our file.
Right.
That will be what that file is exporting at this point.
We can go ahead and save our file and let's test it out.
So if we go into the Web browser and refresh localhost column three thousand, our app should still
be working perfectly.
Nothing interesting is going on yet.
This is just a static template.
But you get the idea now really quick.
I do want to jump back into our Radagast file and show you how this is going to work.
Right now we just have the one you RL.
But you could imagine if we had a slash about page, we would come into our router file and say router
DOGGETT We would pass it to arguments for the first argument.
It would be the U.
RL that we're listening for.
Second argument is a function.
Again, you don't need to type this out.
That's just an example.
But within these parentheses, we would have a request and response.
And then just as an example, I can say response dot send in reality, you'd want to render an HTML
template, but just for a quick test, I can send back a message that says this is our about page,
give that a save.
And then back in the browser, if I visit Slash about, we see this is our about page.
So the idea here is that we now have this dedicated file router, not JS, whose sole job is only responsibility
is to list out our applications, different routes.
This allows us to keep our main file.
Are Apgar's file very clean and organized?
This may not seem very impressive right now because there wasn't a whole lot of code in Apgar's even
at the start of this lesson.
But trust me, as we start to build out the different features of our application and the complexity
grows, we are going to be very happy that we have separate organized files like this.
It's going to make it very easy to know exactly where to look when we want to add a new feature or modify
an existing feature.
Now, in our next lesson, we are going to learn about something called a controller.
The controller will allow our router file to stay cleaner itself, for example, instead of our router
file having to include these functions of what we actually want to do, we can instead keep those functions
within a controller file.
Now, I promise this is not just me being obsessed with being organized.
Splitting your code out into something called the controller is an industry standard practice.
It should be a lot of fun to set up.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.