Hello, everyone, and welcome back to the 10 days of JavaScript, here we are in day number six.
And in this lesson, we are going to learn about higher order functions.
Let's begin with the question.
What in the world is a higher order function?
So the boring technical definition is a higher order function is a function that either accepts a function
as an argument or a function that returns a function as a result.
OK, so that wasn't helpful at all, because if you learned the way that I learn technical answers like
that, do nothing for me, I need to see examples in order for me to actually learn anything.
So this lesson is going to be broken up into three parts.
First, we will look at an example of a function that accepts a function as an argument.
After that, we will create our own brand new higher order function that returns a function as a result.
And finally, at the end of the video, we will learn about some of the most useful, higher order functions
that are part of the core JavaScript language that you would leverage in the real world on a daily basis.
OK, so let's begin up at the top and look at a function that accepts another function as an argument.
So believe it or not, we've actually already seen a function that does this.
So type this out with me.
If we say document dot, add event listener, and this is a function or method that belongs to the document
object.
So we include parentheses to run or call the function.
And you might remember that it takes two arguments.
So the first argument is which event you want to be on the lookout for.
So we could say quotes, click and then a comma to include another argument.
And remember that the second argument is supposed to be a function that you want to run when this event
happens.
So we could say our amazing function and then down on a new line, we could create a function with this
matching name.
So function our amazing function, parentheses, curly brackets, and maybe we just alert a pop up message
that says thank you for clicking.
OK, now if I check out the preview area of this and click down here, we see the pop up.
Thank you for clicking.
We've done this before.
It's not impressive.
The reason I'm showing you this is I want to point out what a higher order function is.
We would say that this ad event, listener method or function is a higher order function because the
second argument that it expects to receive is a function.
If you've never worked with another programming language before, you might not see what's so special
or noteworthy about this.
However, in certain programming languages, you are not allowed to pass a function as an argument.
You can usually only pass simple values like a string of text or a number.
So JavaScript is special in the sense that functions are not considered weird or special entities with
their own unique set of rules of where and how they can be used.
In JavaScript, a function is just like any other entity or value.
To explain what I mean by that, let's jump in to our next example.
But really quick back to the definition.
Right?
So a higher order function is a function that accepts a function as an argument and or returns a function
as its result.
So we just saw an example of the first part of that definition.
Right.
We saw a function that accepts a function as an argument.
And now the last part of the definition, a function that returns a function as a result.
That is a bit trickier to understand.
So right now, I'm going to get rid of this code and let's start fresh.
And I want you to type this out with me first.
Let's begin with a simple function that is not a higher order function.
So let's create a function and name it double mi parentheses, curly brackets, and imagine that we
want this function to double whatever number you give it and then return that value.
So within its parentheses we can include a parameter and then inside the body of the function we could
just say return that parameter times to OK and then below this function we could test it out.
So maybe we could write a sample number out to the Web page down here.
We could say document dot.
Right.
And then let's say double me 20.
Cool, so down the private area, we see that it worked properly.
Right, we see 40.
So the point here is that this double meat function is not a higher order function.
Clearly, it does not accept a function as an argument.
We expect it to receive a number and it also does not return a function.
Right.
It just returns a simple number.
Now, if you're like me, you might be scratching your head and wondering when would it ever be useful
for a function to return a function?
Well, let me give you an example.
So let's imagine that we also wanted a function named Triple Mi and quadruple MI.
So we could just copy and paste our double function, right, and change the name to Triple MI and then
adjust this to multiply by three and then we could paste it again and name this one quadruple mi and
change the multiplier to for you get the idea.
But this code is getting repetitive.
Literally, the only thing that's changing is the number that we are multiplying by.
So just like each one of these functions returns or generates a value, what we can do is create a new
function that generates or returns one of these multiplier functions.
Let me show you what I mean, because it's really confusing until you see it in action.
So I'm going to get rid of the triple and quadruple my functions and let's create a brand new function.
The name doesn't matter, but I'm going to name it, create multiplier parentheses, curly brackets
in these parentheses.
Let's give it a parameter.
I'm going to say multiplier, OK?
And then in the body of this function, instead of returning a number, we can literally return another
function, function, parentheses, curly brackets.
And now let's just pretend that this function is the double main function, but let's make it flexible.
Right.
So within its parentheses, we could include X as a parameter.
This would represent whichever number is getting doubled or tripled or quadrupled.
And then in the body of this function, we would just return that number times and then this is where
we make it flexible.
So instead of doubling it or tripling it or quadrupling it, let's just pull in this parameter, the
multiplier parameter.
Now, don't worry, I do not expect this to make sense yet.
OK, now, at this point, we can get rid of our double function.
Now check this out.
This is where it will start to make a little bit of sense down here.
We can say let double me equal and then we can just use this create multiplier function to create our
Doublemint function so we can say create multiplier.
To right, and then we could try to get we could say, let triple me equal, create multiplier three
and then let quadruple me equal, create multiplier for.
OK, now before we actually try to use these new double, triple, quadruple functions, let's take
a minute to understand what's actually going on here, because there are two really interesting and
potentially confusing things taking place here.
So first, our create multiplier function is considered a higher order function because instead of just
returning a simple string of text or a number or an array, it's returning a function.
Now, that may not seem very special or interesting, but it's noteworthy because in other programming
languages, functions are considered special entities with their own weird or unique set of rules governing
when and where they can be used in other programming languages.
We might only be allowed to return a simple number or string of text within a function right here.
But in JavaScript, a function is an entity just like any other value, which also means that not only
can we return a function within a function, but we can also assign a function to a variable like we
see down here.
So just like in previous lessons and you do not need to type out this part, just like in previous lessons,
how we would set Let Strawbery Count Equal 20.
So just like in the past where we would set a variable to equal a number or a string of text or an array.
Well, in JavaScript, we can set a variable to equal a function, and that's exactly what's going on
here.
Now, again, this might not seem super interesting, but it is because we cannot necessarily do this
in other programming languages.
So the point here is that JavaScript is special in the sense that functions are considered first class
citizens or entities.
So we can pass them around as arguments.
We can return them inside of a function and we can even assign them to a variable.
And believe it or not, but this makes JavaScript a very flexible and powerful language.
OK, now, just to prove to ourselves that this code works, let's test out these double Metropol mean
quadruple MI functions.
So let's output a sample value down into the preview area down here.
So maybe below our code we can say document dot.
Right.
And then let's try doubling the number 10 so we can call one of these functions just like we would any
other function.
We just type out its name and then a set of parentheses to actually call the function and then in the
parentheses, just give it an argument.
So 10, we see that it gets doubled.
We could try tripling the number five.
So Triple MI five, it helps if I spelled triple correctly, but there we see 15 and then we could try
to quadruple MI really quick.
So quadruple mi.
Awesome.
There we see 20, if you're still a little bit confused as to how this is working, we can take double
me as an example.
So we are creating a variable and saying let double me equal.
Whatever this create multiplier function returns.
And we know that that function returns a function.
So then literally the dummy variable is going to equal this function that gets returned here and then
we can call it just like any other function.
All right.
So now that we've covered both halves of the definition of a higher order function, let's move on to
the third and final part of this lesson.
So I'm going to erase everything we have so far.
We begin this lesson by looking at an example of a higher order function that the Web browser environment
offers.
And then in the second part of this lesson, we created our own functions.
OK, and now in this third and final part, I want to show you a few higher order functions that are
part of the core JavaScript language itself.
And actually some of the most useful ones that you would run into on a daily basis all have to do with
arrays.
So let's begin by pretending that we have an array.
You can type this out with me.
I'm going to say let my colors equal and then square brackets to create the array.
And then I'm just going to spell out the first few colors of the rainbow.
OK, so we've got this example.
Now, let's imagine that we want to do something once for each item in the array.
For example, let's imagine we want to output down onto the preview part of the Web page, a little
bit of text that says the color red is a great color and then the color orange is a great color.
The color yellow is a great color.
Right.
So we want to perform this repetitive task and do it once for each item.
Well, check this out in the JavaScript language.
Let's begin working with our variable.
So my colors in the JavaScript language, all arrays have access to a method named for each.
And just based on its name, you might be able to guess what it does within its parentheses for the
argument.
We just give it a function and then it's going to run that function once for each item in the collection.
Let me show you how it works.
So maybe down on a new line, let's create a brand new function and name it.
Say something nice.
The name of the function doesn't matter.
That's just what I'm going with.
So I've got the name and then parentheses curly brackets.
OK, now we can spell out what this function should do in just a minute.
But on this line, within the parentheses four for each.
Let's pass it that function.
So say something nice.
And now this line of code almost makes sense in plain English.
We've got our array of colors and we are saying for each, for each item in that array, say something
nice.
So now check this out.
Down in the actual function definition within these parentheses, we need to create a parameter.
So you could just say X, which is easy to type or we could say color.
The name of the parameter doesn't matter.
But then down here in the body of the function, let's say document.
Right.
Because remember, we want to output something down here that says the color blank is a great color.
So I'm just going to say quotes the color and then space and then add on our parameter.
So for you, it might be X or whatever you name the parameter and then add on another string of text.
Begin with the space and say is a great color, cool.
And there we see the color.
Red is a great color, color orange, the color yellow.
If you want each one to sit on its own line, it's just a matter of HTML.
So right after this period we could just add a brake tag.
Perfect.
Now, this may not seem that impressive, but it's cool because our code is now flexible, meaning in
the future, if we ever added new colors to our array, it's going to automatically display onto the
Web page.
So if we came up here and at the end of the array added on Karmal Green, that's all we need to do.
And now we see the color.
Green is a great color.
Now, the real reason we just learned about this for each function is to show you that it is a higher
order function that is part of the core JavaScript language itself.
Right.
For its argument, it accepts a function.
However, indirectly, we also just learned why arrays can be so useful once you have items in a collection
like this, computers are very skilled at performing a repetitive task or looping through the array
and doing something once for each item.
So we could just as well imagine that each one of these was an email in your inbox or a post on Facebook
or a photo post on Instagram.
OK, anyway, so that was a quick look at the for each method.
Now two of the other most useful higher order functions in JavaScript that I leverage on a daily basis
also have to do with arrays and you do not need to type this out.
But they are.
Map and filter, I only typed out the name of our array variable here to show you that these are functions
or methods that all arrays automatically get access to.
Now, we actually are not going to learn about map and filter in this lesson because we've already covered
enough new ground and material for one lesson.
But we are going to learn about map and filter in our very next lesson.
And this is great because these functions are the perfect segue way into our next topic.
Now, this next topic might seem like a minor detail, but in actuality it's crucial to understanding
JavaScript.
It's a concept that might be obvious if you're familiar with another programming language.
But I know that personally, in my own experience, I wish that someone would have stressed this concept
to me when I was first starting out.
And what is that concept?
It's the difference between returning a value and mutating a value.
So what in the world does that even mean?
Well, we're going to learn all about it in our next lesson.
So let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.