Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to complete our live search feature without further ado, let's jump right
into it.
OK, so at this point, a user can click on the search icon, search for a phrase, and currently we're
simply logging the results to the console.
So our goal in this lesson is to use this resulting raw data and generate the appropriate HTML to actually
show results visually.
Right here to get started, let's adjust our send request method so that once it receives its response
from the server, instead of just logging the data to the console, it can call a separate method that's
responsible for generating and rendering HTML.
So in our text editor within Search Dogs, let's find our send request method.
So here it is.
Send a request and right below this console dot log, let's just add a new line.
And we haven't created this method yet, but we will create it in about 20 seconds from now.
But let's just call this DOT Renderer results, html parentheses to call it.
And let's also pass into it response dot data.
Right.
That array of raw JSON data.
Cool.
Now we better go create a method with this matching name.
So maybe right below our send request method we can just create a new one and say render results.
HTML parentheses, curly brackets within the parentheses less include a parameter, let's call it posts.
Right, because it's going to be an array representing one or multiple posts.
Or if the array is empty, that means there are no results or no posts within this new method.
Let's begin with an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets, let's also include in the else block for the condition within these
parentheses.
Let's just say posts dot length, meaning if the array has any items, even just one item, we would
want to display it or else that means there were zero results in either case within the if or the else,
we would want to manipulate the HTML for the results area div.
So we've already created a property that points towards that div.
So we can just say this dot results area and then just look inside it for a property named inner HTML
and then we can set that to equal something.
For now, let's just include a placeholder X and we can circle back to this.
Let's do the same thing.
So just copy and paste that into the else block.
OK, now let's do this.
Let's scroll down into the HTML template for the search overlay.
So this is within our inject HTML method and we see two chunks of HTML separated by this line break
in the second chunk, about three lines down we see a div with a class of live Dasch search results.
Let's go ahead and do this.
Let's hollow out this div.
But before we just delete its contents right now, let's first copy them to our clipboard.
So I want you to begin selecting from this div with the class of list dash group and shadow dash s.m.
Begin selecting there and then scroll down.
You'll see several elements after the final AI.
Also select one of the closing div tags like this.
Go ahead and copy that into your clipboard and then you're free to delete it here.
OK, just to keep this a bit cleaner, we can move the closing div tag for this live search results
to sit on the same line as the opening tag.
So just delete this empty space.
Cool.
Now let's use our JavaScript to add appropriate HTML into this results div.
So let's scroll back up to our render results HTML method.
We just created this a moment ago, remember, it has the if and else if this is true, then there are
results to display.
So we would just want to set the HTML for that results area to the code that's in our clipboard.
So get rid of the placeholder X in its place, include two back ticks and in between the two back sticks,
just paste in your clipboard, OK, within the else block.
If this is true, we'd want to set the HTML for that area.
Let's get rid of the X Factor X.
We want to set it to a paragraph element.
So opening and closing P tags and then let's just say sorry, we could not find any results for that
search just for style reasons.
On the opening P tag, let's give it an attribute named class and set its value to alert and alert Dasch
danger and text Dasch Center and maybe Shadow Daxam.
OK, now after the else block, but still within the overall closing curly brackets for this method.
So right here, let's do this.
Let's hide that spinning loader icon, right.
Because we have HTML that we're ready to show instead of the waiting icon.
So we can just say this dot hide loader icon parentheses to call that we have not actually created this
method yet.
We can create it in just a moment.
OK, and then right below that, let's reveal or show the results area, because until this code runs,
that div is set to be hidden or invisible.
But now that we've populated it with either the results HTML or the sorry message, it's ready to be
displayed.
So we can just say this dot show results area.
OK, now let's go set these two methods up.
So just a little bit below this, we see a method named Show Load or icon.
Let's just copy these same three lines of code to save typing and turn the new copy into Hyd Loader
Icon instead of show load or icon.
So take these three lines, duplicate them.
It's name this new one hyd loader icon.
All we need to change is class list instead of add should be dot remove the class that makes it visible
right below this.
Let's also create methods that hide and show the results area respectively.
So let's say show results, area parentheses, curly brackets.
So just be this dot results area dot class list and give it a class of live Dasch search dash results.
Dash dash visible.
OK, then to create the hide version of this we could just copy these three lines right below that,
paste it, change this new copy to B hide results area and then just change class list from dot add
to remove.
OK, before we save this and test it out, let's scroll up to our key press handler to make sure that
the right events are taking place at the right time.
So remember, towards the top of our methods area, we have a method named QI Press Handler.
Now if a user performs one search and the results appear and then they begin typing to perform a new
search, well, we not only want to show the loader icon again, but we also want to hide the results
area once again.
So this does not hide results area.
OK, and one last detail.
What if someone performs a search and then empties out the text field entirely?
Sure.
That changed the value of this field, but we wouldn't actually want to start running a search or showing
this loading icon.
We want to hide the icon and hide the results area.
So within key press handler right above this if statement, let's just set up another if statement and
say if parentheses curly brackets for the condition if value equals nothing.
If this is the case, let's clear or reset our timer.
So clear.
Time out, time out.
We want to clear is this not typing.
Wait timer.
After that we'd want to hide both the lower icon and the results.
So this dot hide loader icon and this dot hide results area.
OK, let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So in the browser, be sure to refresh.
All right.
And if I perform a search for JavaScript.
Cool, obviously, we still need to make this dynamic content instead of the static HTML.
Don't worry, we'll get to that soon.
But if I start hitting backspace, you see the loading icon.
But if I get to an empty string of text, the loader icon goes away.
I'm free to perform another search.
So success.
Cool, so things are working as expected, we just need to do two things.
Number one, let's set it so the delay is no longer three thousand milliseconds.
Let's set the delay to maybe seven hundred and fifty milliseconds, OK?
And then after that, let's adjust this so that it uses the raw data instead of this hard coded static
HTML for each link back in our text editor.