Hello, everyone.
I know that I promised we'd connect our app to a database in the next lesson, but I have a really quick
productivity tip that I need to share with you.
I promise this lesson will be short and quick, and then we will be right on our way to focusing on
the database.
OK, now the productivity tips that I want to share with you has to do with the annoying need of manually
restarting your NOAD app every time you make changes to it.
So, for example, in my command line we can see that I'm currently running my node server or app and
so I'm able to visit it in my Web browser.
Now, just for an example, what if I wanted to edit this headline here to include an exclamation point
at the end?
So if I go into my text editor and inside that server, James File, if I scroll down into the HTML
template here, is that heading level one here you can see to do app.
So if I add a few exclamation points at the end of that and save this file, if I refresh the browser,
we do not see that change.
This is because once you launch a node app, once you go to the command line and say node and then the
name of the file node is going to keep your app running in memory node is not going to keep reloading
and looking at your code file every time a new request comes in.
That's why we've had to perform that annoying pattern of coming into the command line and pressing control
C to quit the server and then running the command to start the server back up again.
Right now, if I refresh, we do see that change now.
Having to manually go into the command line and quit the server and relaunch the server is a huge waste
of time.
Instead, it would be nice if we could automate that process somehow.
For example, it would be great if any time we saved a change to this file node, detected that change
to the file and then just automatically restarted the server for us.
Well, learning how to set up automatic restarts like that is exactly what we're going to do in this
lesson.
It's going to save us a ton of time in the long run.
So right now, I want you to follow along with me right now if your node, app or server is running.
Be sure to go into the command line and press control, see to quit the server.
OK, now our first real step is to go out to the JavaScript grocery store or NPM and install a package
that makes this automatic restart possible.
So in the command line, type this out with me.
NPM install in the name of the package that we want to install is Node, Maun and Demona.
OK, then press enter.
And depending on the speed of your computer and Internet connection, it could take a few seconds.
So be patient.
But as soon as the install command completes, the question becomes, how do we actually use this node
on package?
Well, essentially, what we want to do and this is just a demonstration, you do not need to type this
out.
But instead of saying node and then the name of our file, what we really want to do now is run a command
that says Node Mohn and then the name of our file.
This way, the node one package will watch our file for us.
And any time it detects a change, it will automatically relaunch the app for us.
So not only this node Mohn initially start your app, but then it monitors your app for future changes.
It's a great time saver, however, being able to run this command directly in the command line node.
Mohn and then the name of your file.
This would require us to install Node Mohn globally on our computer, whereas we just installed Node
Mond locally just for this particular project.
Right.
We just installed Node Mond into our node modules folder that lives within this project folder.
This means we installed it locally.
Now there is nothing wrong with installing a package globally, but from my experience, many, many
people and students run into technical difficulties when trying to install a package globally.
So we are not going to run the command directly in the command line like this.
Instead, we're going to leverage our package JSON file to be able to run Node Mond locally.
This is a great way of setting things up because you're way less likely to run into technical difficulties.
So right now in your text, Ed, I want you to open up our package JSON file, not the package dash,
lock, file.
We're looking for the file that is packaged JSON.
So go ahead and open that file just for fun towards the bottom.
You can see this dependencies area.
Cool.
We can see that node.
Mohn was added to our list of dependencies.
However, that's not why I wanted us to jump into this file.
So, yes, one of the responsibilities of this file is to keep a running list of our dependencies.
But if we scroll up to the top of this file, we can see an area named Scrimps.
This is where we can create our own custom commands.
So check this out once you find the area named scripts and then we see a colon and then an opening curly
bracket right after that opening curly bracket, I want you to create a new line or dropdown to a new
line just like this.
OK, let's create our own custom scripts or command named Watch.
So quotes watch, then include a colon, then include a pair of quotes, a beginning and an ending quote
include a comma right after that pair of quotes.
OK, now in between the quotes, we can type out our command, so type this out with me Node Maun and
then the space and then the name of our file.
So just server.
Even though we would not be able to run this command in the command line directly because we didn't
install node Hmong globally, NPM is smart enough to look in our package Dodgson's scripts area and
within that context it will be able to intelligently look in our node modules folder for the node MOND
package.
So setting up a command or script like this is a great way of organising things.
With this in place, go ahead and save your package, not JSON file.
And now check this out down in your command line.
I want you to type this command with me, NPM and then run and then we just type in whatever we named
our script or command.
So we named it Watch.
So in the command line, npm run watch, that's going to run our command.
Go ahead and press enter.
And we see these Gnomon messages, it says that it's starting up our server.
So if I go to the browser and refresh, I can visit our app.
Here we can see the three exclamation points, but if I go back into my text, Ed back into server J.S.
right, the file that's powering our app, if I look through the HTML template and what if I get rid
of those exclamation points?
Now, check this out as soon as I save this file.
It happened really quick, so you might have missed it, but we saw new lines appear down in the command
line, Noad man said, restarting due to changes.
So it's relaunching the app for us.
I didn't have to do anything in the command line.
And now if I refresh my app in the browser, you can see those changes took effect.
Awesome.
This may not seem very impressive, but trust me, in the long run, this is going to save you so much
time.
Now, you don't need to constantly go to the command line to quit and restart, quit and restart.
You're free to just make changes to your application, save it and then refresh in the browser.
And life is good.
OK, so just to recap, back in package, Jason, here is the line of code that I added in the scripts
area.
If you need to pause the video and type this in.
OK, now if I come to the command line and actually do want to quit my server, so control see, and
I just want to let you know that throughout the following chapters in this course, you are not going
to see me use node server to launch my app any longer.
Instead of that, I am now going to use NPM Run Watch to launch my application and that will trigger
this script or command that we just set up.
Don't worry, if you feel like you can't remember this command, that's OK, because you're going to
see me run this command in the following lessons again and again.
Cool.
Now that we've covered this productivity tip, that's going to save us a lot of time, we are ready
to move on to the next lesson where we will indeed connect our node application to a Mongo DB database.
This is going to be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you then.