Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to continue working on the ability to view a post from our Web app.
Now, before we jump into the real topic or challenge of this lesson, which is pulling in the username
and avatar of the author for a post, let's first go ahead and set up our 404 or page not found template.
Right.
Because if someone includes a segment at the end of the post, you are URL.
That is not a real post.
So if you just type in a few random letters.
Instead of just plain text here, we would instead want to see a template that looks something like
this.
It's got our uniform header and footer with a bit of text here.
We cannot find that page.
You can always visit the home page to get a fresh start.
So right now, let's set up a new Ejaz file for this template.
As always, you can pull up the repository and look in the complex app and then the HTML templates folder.
And right now, the template that we are interested in is named 404 HTML.
So open that up from the GitHub website.
You can just click on Raw for that file.
And now actually instead of copying this entire file, let's ignore the header and footer because those
should pull from our reuseable include files.
So let's scroll down and right below this comment that says header ends here, let's begin selecting
and copying and then we only need to select just a few lines because we do not need the footer begins
area.
So go ahead and copy this section into your clipboard.
And then within our text editor within our views folder, let's create a new file so I can right.
Click on Views new file.
Let's just name it 404 DOT SJS in the new file, paste in your clipboard and then to save a bit of typing,
we can just copy and paste the include header line from another template.
So for example, if I jump in to create post SJS here is that include line that you can copy into your
clipboard and then back in 404 up the very top, just paste that in and then down at the very bottom
again paste it in but change header to footer.
OK, let's go ahead and save this file and now let's jump in to our post controller file.
So in controllers post controller and within our view, single function, if our find single by ID Promis
rejects instead of resolves, then our sketch block will run.
So instead of sending back plaintext, let's get rid of this response send line and instead you say
response, render and then render the template that is named 404.
So if we save this and then back in the browser, if we send a new refresh to a U.
RL that does not have a matching post.
Cool, we now see a styled uniform 404 page now that this is set up, let's go back to our real post
example.
You, Orell, if this isn't still in your browser history, remember, you can always just go into your
Mongo DB Atlus account and find the ID from one of your post documents.
Right.
And then just visit slash post, slash that ID, OK?
Our real goal in this lesson is to pull in the author's username.
And Granovetter, the reason this is more challenging than just pulling in the post title or content
is because if we look at a post document, remember it only stores the I.D. of the author or user account.
We're not actually storing their user name or avatar in our post document.
But luckily for us, Mongo DB has an operator named Lookup that is perfect for this situation.
So right now, let's jump back into our text editor and let's work on our post model.
So in our Models folder, let's jump into postgraduates towards the bottom of this file.
We have our find single by IDE function, and right now we're interested in this line of code.
So this is where we talk to our Mongo DB collection and ask it to find one document.
Well, right now we need to do something a bit more complex than just find one.
So right after posts collection DOT, I want you to begin selecting at the beginning of find one and
just select until the end of this line and delete.
So this line of code should look something like this now, OK?
And from our posts collection, instead of calling find one we want to call something called aggregate.
Aggregate is great when you need to perform complex or multiple operations.
Now Aggregate is going to return data that makes sense from a Mongo DB perspective, but maybe not just
from a plain JavaScript perspective.
So at the end of this line, we want to be sure to call DOT to array.
Now, in this case, we're only interested in one single post, but that's just the way this works.
It's going to return an array, even if that array only contains one item, because we're only interested
in the first item in the array.
Our instinct might be to include square brackets here and say zero, just give us the first item in
the array.
However, we don't want to do that.
Ultimately, we need this line of code to return a promise.
Right, because talking to a database is an asynchronous operation and ultimately to array here is what's
going to return a promise.
So we do want to end the statement with that.
So let's do this at the start of this line.
Let's change let post to be let posts as in plural now.
Right, because it's going to be an array of posts and then within our if checked down here for the
condition, let's just say if posts dot length.
Right.
Meaning if that array has more than zero items in it, this will evaluate to true.
And then for the value that we're going to resolve instead of post, we'd want to resolve posts and
then square brackets zero to just return the first item in that array.
OK, now the real question here, though, is how does aggregate work?
Well, aggregate lets us run multiple operations.
So within these parentheses we give it an array.
So square brackets in between the opening and closing square brackets here.
Let's drop down to stay organized.
So we're passing aggregate an array.
But an array of what?
Well, an array of database operations.
Let's start with at least two.
So each operation is an object.
So there's one object, comma, then there's a second object for the first operation.
Let's perform a match.
So Dollar Sign Match will tell Mongo DB that that's what we want to do, then include a colon and then
we include an object.
And this is basically describing documents that we want to match with.
So we're interested in a document where underscore I.D. matches the incoming or requested ID for this
route or coming from our controller.
So down here we would just say a new instance of Mongu DHBs Object ID that gets its own parentheses
in those we would just pass in the requested ID.
OK, so that's our first operation.
We're performing a match by the requested I.D. Now let's perform our second operation.
So.
Within this empty object, let's say dollar signs look up and then Colen and then provide an object
here.
So currently we are within the Post's collection.
But what we want to do here is look up documents from another collection.
Right.
Remember, our ultimate goal here is to pull in the relevant user account document so that we can access
its user name and email address for aggravators.
So within this object for Look-Up, we're just going to give it a few different properties.
First, let's add a property named from Colen and let's set this to a value of users, meaning the users
collection.
So, again, we're currently in the Post's collection and now we're saying the document that we want
to look up should be pulled from the user's collection.
OK, after those quotes, let's include a comma and another property, let's say local field colon,
and let's give it a value of author.
So this is saying when we're looking in the user's collection for matching documents, the local field
or the field from within, the current post item that we want to perform that match on is the author
field.
Right.
That's what contains the idea of the matching user.
After this, we include a comma and then another property named Foreign Field Colon, and this would
be underscore I.D. So local means the current collection, that's the post collection.
Foreign means the other collection that we're trying to look up within the field in those documents
that we want to perform.
The look up or match on is the IDE field.
After the quotes, let's include comma and let's include a property named as Colon and let's give that
a value of we could make up any name we want, but let's choose author document Mongo DB will use this
name when it adds on a virtual field or property with the matching user document to this post.
Now I realize this was a lot to follow along with, so if everything didn't make perfect sense, that's
OK.
A bit later on in the lesson we will visualize the data that this results in.
And once we see the data that it returns with our own two eyes, I think things will start to make sense.
For now, though, let's go ahead and save this and let's make sure that we can still view a post from
the front end.
So if I refresh the screen, cool, we can see our app is still successfully pulling in these values
from the database.
Only now we have a bit of extra data to work with.
Let me show you what I mean.
So back in our editor right below the match and look up operations that we just added, just a line
or two below that.
We have this, if else statement.
And when we resolve with that first item in the array right before this resolve line, let's add a new
line and let's say console dot log.
And let's just log the first item in that post.
Soraya's post square brackets, zero.
I want us to be able to see with our own two eyes the data that this aggregate and lookup operator are
returning.
So let's go ahead and save this and then make sure that your command line is visible.
OK, now back in your browser, just refresh or send one more request, this post screen, and now we
should see a bit of data in the console.
Cool.
So there's our post object.
We see the post ID, the post title Body Content Created Date, the idea of the author, but there's
that new author document name that we chose.
So the lookup operation is adding this new property to the returned object.
And we can see that it's an array of any matching documents based on that look up.
Right?
It's an array of any user documents that's ID matches this author ID.
Now, keep in mind that our aggregate operations are not actually manipulating any data in the database.
It's simply returning data that we can use however we want.
In this case, we know that we want to use this data within our controller and ultimately our controller
is just passing it on to an HTML or Ejaz template.
What I'm getting at here is that in terms of this HTML template, we don't need that to know the author
ID.
Instead, we'd really just want the author property to be an object that contains the user name and
their avatar.
So our first step towards making that happen is to use another aggregate operator named Project.
Let me hide my console and show you what we can do within our code.
So right now we just have two items in our array of aggregate operations.
Let's add a third.
So at the very end of this Look-Up line, we can just add a comma and then create another object.
And this time we want to use the operator named Dollar Sign Project Colon.
And then we give that an object in between these curly brackets.
Feel free to drop down just to stay organized.
So what project does is it allows us to spell out exactly what fields we want the resulting object to
have this way instead of just returning every single field for that document, we have a bit of fine
grained control on what we return.
So we know that we want to include the title of the post.
So title Colon one to mean true or yes, do include it, comma.
Let's also be sure to include the body field.
So body one, let's also be sure to include the created date of created date call and one comma.
And finally for the author field.
We don't want to just say one.
Because that would just be what's already being stored in the post document, right, just a reference
to the matching user ID instead we would want the user property to be that author document.
Right.
Or the entire user document instead of just the ID.
So instead of one here, we can include an object and type this out with me.
Dollar sign array Ellem at Colen and then square brackets and then quotes, let's say dollar sign author
document after the quotes comma zero.
Let's unpack this code.
So let's actually start here and work our way backwards.
So for this data that's ultimately going to get passed into our HTML template, we would want the author
property to be an object with the user's username and their avatar.
So that's what we're setting it to with author document.
Right?
That's the document that was found during the lookup.
So Mongo DB will see the dollar sign here and know that we don't just mean a simple string of text.
This means to actually pull in that author document.
OK, and now remember, Look-Up is ultimately going to return an array, but because we know there's
only ever going to be one author document, we're just returning the first item in that array.
Right.
So we're interested in the array element at the zero position.
So this way, author will not be an array.
It will just be that one single object representing that user.
Let's go ahead and save this and then make sure that your command line is visible.
And let's go send a new request in our browser to trigger the console dialog.
Refresh back in the console.
Let's go ahead and expand this.
So this is our post object.
And now we can see that the author property, instead of just the user ID, is an object and it contains
useful things like the username and the email address that we can use to pull in their graviton.
However, we don't need to pass this entire document to the controller.