Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to finish our user profile screen, so in our previous lesson, we set
things up so that from a user's profile, you can click on followers to see a list of who is following
this user.
However, if I click on this following link, we see an error message.
So right now, let's just jump into our router and set up a route that would match this Eurail pattern.
Let me show you what I mean.
So in our text, Ed, I want you to open up router J.S. here we see a comment profile related routes,
and we can actually just duplicate this line, the line with the route of profile and then username
and then slash followers.
Let's just copy and paste or duplicate that entire line.
And then on the new duplicated copy, just change the closing forward slash followers into forward slash
following.
OK, now for this following route, we still want to begin by checking to see if this user exists and
we'd still want to call our shared profile data function.
But the final and third function should no longer be profile follower's screen.
Let's instead change this to profile following screen, right.
If someone comes to this route, they want to know who that user is following.
Now let's go ahead and save this file.
And now we better jump in to our user controller and create a function with this matching name.
So within our controllers folder, jump in to user controller Dot J.S..
If we scroll down to the very bottom, we should see a line that begins with exports dot profile, follower's
screen.
We can actually just duplicate this function and then adjust the new copy.
So select this entire function, copy that into your clipboard and then right at the very bottom of
this file, just paste it in on this new duplicate copy.
Let's change the name to profile following scre.
OK then on this line when we create a variable and say let follower's equal, let's change this from
followers to following.
And then in terms of what that should equal, we still want to use our follow model.
But instead of calling a function named git followers by ID, let's change followers so that the function
is named git following by ID.
OK, and then when it comes time to actually render a template, you can imagine that we have a new
template file named Profile Following instead of followers.
Let's adjust the name of the template to profile Dasch following and then the data that we're passing
into the template.
All of these properties can stay the same, but let's change followers into following, right?
This should be a list of the users that this user is following.
Cool.
At this point.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And now we better go into our follow model and make sure that it has a function with this matching name.
Right git following by ID.
So in our models folder, let's jump into follow dot J.S..
OK, down towards the bottom of this file, we're looking for a line that begins with follow dot get
follower's by IDE.
Let's go ahead and duplicate this entire function.
So begin selecting.
Go ahead and copy that into your clipboard and then right below it, just paste it in in this new copy,
let's change it to follow DOT get following by I.D., OK?
It should still return a promise.
The first thing we need to actually change is the match aggregate operator.
So instead of looking for documents where the followed ID matches the current ID, we'd instead want
to perform the match.
Where the Let's change this to author ID field matches this ID just a quick typo.
The D should be lowercase here, so it should be lowercase author and then uppercase AI and then lowercase
D..
So author id just like this.
OK, so that will find documents in the follow collection where the author ID matches the current profile
user.
But remember, a follow document only contains the I.D. of the two user.
It doesn't contain their user name and gravitons, which is what we would actually need to display on
the front end of the site.
So that's why we have this Look-Up aggregate operation.
Only this time, instead of the local field being authorized, let's change the local field to be followed
I.D. So we're finding follow documents where the current user is the creator of that follow.
And then we want to look up information about the document in the user's collection that they are following.
Right.
Because we want to show a list of the users this person is following.
Now, technically, we could go ahead and update this to say let following instead of let followers.
But at the end of the day, it doesn't really matter.
That would just be for your own organization and attention to detail, because ultimately this promise
is going to resolve with a value and our controller isn't going to know or care what we named that data.
Within this function.
All the controller cares about is that it's receiving an array.
So just for our own human purposes, you could go through in anywhere you see follower's change it to
following throughout this code.
But from a computer's perspective, it won't make any difference.
So we're actually safe to go ahead and save this.
And now let's jump back into our user controller to refresh our memory of what we're doing here.
So we now have this variable named following.
And ultimately we just want to show that within an HTML template that we're rendering.
So let's go ahead and create a new Ajay's file named Profile Following, and then we can just loop through
the array named following.
So within the root of your project folder, look in the views folder and let's just go ahead and copy
and paste from our profile dash followers dot SJS file.
So jump into profile followers, select everything into your clipboard and copy and then we can just
create a brand new file in our views folder.
Let's name it profile dash following SJS in that new file, just paste in your clipboard and then around
line number nine, instead of calling for each on followers.
Let's change this to following.
And now this code would work at this point, but for our own organization purposes, you could update
the word follower here to be followed user instead.
If I select follower here once and then press controlled the on windows or command the on Mac, you
can see that each time I press it, it selects the next instance of that word.
So this way I have four instances of it selected at once and I can just begin typing followed user and
you can see it was updated in all four blinking cursor locations.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And now back in the browser, if I click on the following link for barks a lot, it makes sense for
this area to be empty because this user is not following anyone.
However, if I go to my own profile, I know that my account is following the Bark's line account.
So now if I click on following Perfect, you can see that my broad account is following Bachs a lot
at this point.
Let's change gears now.
Let's work on visually selecting or highlighting the actual current page.
What I mean by this is we are currently on the following screen or following you around, but visually
it still looks like the posts link is selected.
Let me show you how I would set things up.
So that the current page will actually appear highlighted back in our text.
Ed, I want you to jump in to user controller Dot J.S. within our exports profile following screen area.
When we render our template, let's just give it one additional property that tells it the current page.
So, for example, I'd create a new property.
You could name it whatever you want.
I'm going to name it current page and just give it a value of a string of text that says following.
Be sure to add a comma at the end of that line and then let's just do this same thing for the followers
and posts screens as well.
So if we just scroll up a little bit within our user controller file, here's the function for the followers
screen.
So I would just give it a current page property and set it to follower's comma.
And then if we scroll up a little bit further, we should see exports dot profile posts screen.
So again, give it a property.
Let's say current page should be posts include the comma.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And now we just need to dig into the file that outputs this navigation HTML to refresh your memory,
to find that we would look inside our views folder and then within the includes subfolder.
We're looking for the file that is named Profile Shared SJS towards the bottom around line number 15.
We see several links, right posts, followers and following.
Now you'll notice that the first link has a class of active.
This is why the posts link always appears to be selected.
So what we need to do is write a bit of dynamic code to add this class of active to the actually current
page.
Let me show you how I would set this up.
So let's get rid of the word active here and in its place.
Let's drop in to SJS instead of an IF statement, we could use a ternary operator.
So we first include our condition, let's say current page, if that equals again, double equals sign
to check for equality.
If that equals single quotes, let's say if that equals posts, then we include a question mark and
let's have a placeholder X to say what we would want to do.
If this is true, then we include a colon and then I'll have another placeholder X, and this is where
we say what we'd want to do if this evaluates to false.
So for the first placeholder X, if this is true, that's where we could just get rid of the placeholder
X have single quotes and just output the phrase active for the second placeholder X..
Let's get rid of that and we can just have an empty pair of quotes.
We don't want to output anything.
OK, now we can just copy and duplicate this ternary operator for the followers and following links
as well.
So begin selecting from the opening tag to the closing of the tag.
Let's copy that.
And then on the followers line right before the closing quote for the class value, just paste in your
clipboard.
Only this time the condition we check for is if current page equals instead of posts, it would be followers.
Let's do the same thing for the following link.
So we'd paste in our clipboard here and then check if current page equals following.
Let's go ahead and give this a save and then test it out.
So back in the browser, I'm currently on the following U.
RL and if I refresh perfect, we see that that link is now actually visibly selected.
And if I go to the follower screen, cool, it's selected as well.
Perfect.
Now for our one final task in this lesson.
Let's set things up so that these values or these numbers in these links actually make sense and are
actually pulling in real data.