This is our post object, and now we can see that the author property, instead of just a user ID,
is an object and it contains useful things like the username and the email address that we can use to
pull in their graviton.
However, we don't need to pass this entire document to the controller.
Right.
We would not want to include the password field here.
So let's do this.
Let's hide the console.
And right after this line where we say Daudt to Arae right below that, let's add a new line.
Let's add a comment to ourselves to stay organized and let's say clean up author property in each post
object.
OK, so let's make this happen.
Ultimately, we know that we're going to have a variable named posts and it's going to be an array in
this case.
It's only going to contain one post.
But let's write reusable code that we can leverage in future lessons.
Right?
We know there are going to be other times where we do want to pull in multiple posts, for example,
a user's homepage feed or search results for a user's profile.
So let's do this under this comment.
Let's work with our array of posts so posts and let's set that to equal and then let's loop through
each item in that array.
So let's say posts, dot map.
Remember, map lets us return a brand new array.
So essentially we're going to create a new array based on the posts array.
And then that new array that map generates is what we're ultimately going to save or overwrite into
this variable within the map parentheses.
Let's give it a function within the function parentheses.
Let's include a parameter, let's name it post within the body of this function, we are going to return
post.
But the idea is that before this line than the body of the function, we can add a new line.
Anything we do before this, we are essentially manipulating the current item in the array.
So let's do this.
Let's say post dot author equals and then we want to create an object and we're just going to customize
or overwrite the author object.
Right, because we don't want to include things like the user's password.
So within these curly brackets, let's drop down and just manually spell out what should be in this
author object.
So we know for sure we want their user name.
So user name calling and we can just say post dot author, dot username, comma.
And we also know that we want their avatar.
So Avatar Colen for now.
Let's just put a placeholder X here.
Cool.
So those are the only two properties that we want the author object to have.
Now the question becomes, how can we use the user's email address to pull in their Gravitron?
You are Elvir.
Well, let's just reuse our user model.
So up at the very top of this file, right.
We are within our post model, maybe right below line number two.
Let's just require in our user model, so let's say const uppercase user equals and then just require
in a file path.
Look in the current directory because we're already in the models directory and look for uppercase user.
OK, now back in that function that we were working on right within this author object that just has
these two properties for Avatar, let's do this.
Let's create a new instance of user using our blueprint in terms of what we want to pass the constructor
function.
Let's just say post dot author.
Let's also say comma and give it another argument of true.
Don't worry, I will explain this very shortly.
For now, let's actually jump in to our user model file.
So within our models folder, let's jump into user Gorgias up towards the top within our user constructor
function.
Right now we just have the one parameter well lets out a comma here and include a second parameter.
We can name it anything, but let's name it, get Avatar.
Let's set things up so that if this is true, then within the constructor function, we just automatically
call our git avatar function.
If this is false or if you call this constructor function without including a second argument at all,
then we just won't automatically call that function within our constructor.
Here, let's add a new line.
Let's say if parentheses curly brackets for the condition if get avatar equals undefined meaning.
If you call this constructor function and you don't include a second argument at all, this would be
the case.
Well, let's just provide a default value then.
So let's say get Avatar should equal balls, OK, then below this, let's say if parentheses curly brackets,
if you get Avatar, if that's true, then just call our method this dot get Avatar right.
We know that that method is going to automatically create a hash based on the current email and then
generate that avatar you are.
So let's go ahead and save this and then jump back into our post model.
Cool.
So this is going to return an object and because that get Avatar method ran, it's going to have a property
named Avatar.
Let's go ahead and save this and make sure your command line is open.
And then if we go back to the browser and refresh or send a new request, we should see new data in
the console.
Perfect.
So it's the post object.
Now, the author property is just an object that literally only contains the two things were after username
and Avatar.
Cool to bring this lesson to a close.
Let's just go use these values within our HTML template.
So within our views folder, let's jump into single post screen SJS on line number 15.
That's where we see the image for the Avatar.
Let's just get rid of this hardcoded source value.
So for source, let's just empty out the quotes and instead we want to do something dynamic so less
than percentage equal, let's close that out with percentage greater then and then we can just say post
dot author Dot Avatar, OK, on the line of code right below this we see posted by.
And then here is a fake hardcoded username.
Let's just get rid of that and replace it with this opening dynamic tag.
Let's close that out within there.
We would just say post dot author dot username.
Let's give this a save and go refresh.
Currently, it's the fake hardcoded Kitty Doe, but if I refresh.
Cool, it pulls in the real user name and photo for this posts author that's going to bring this lesson
to a close.
In our next lesson, we are going to start working on the user profile screen.
So that way, if you click on the user's username link here or if you click your own avatar in your
top right header, either way, you should be taken to a profile for a particular user.
And we would want that template to look something like this.
So it will show all posts created by that author.
And this way, we don't have to keep going into our database to find the ID for a post to paste that
into a U.
RL.
Right this way we could just click on one of the posts and it would automatically take us to the appropriate
you are.
Now, I know that this lesson that we just worked through was very tedious, but I think this next upcoming
profile lesson should be a lot of fun.
So let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.