Hello, everyone, and welcome back to the 10 days of JavaScript.
Here we are in day number eight.
And in this lesson, we are going to talk about scope and context.
So what is scope and what is context?
Well, here are my own sarcastic definitions.
So I would say that scope is the biggest source of confusion regarding variables.
And my definition for context would be the biggest source of confusion regarding objects.
Now, these tongue in cheek definitions are not actually helpful, but right away they do let us know
that scope has to do with variables and context has to do with objects.
But beyond that, let's dive deeper.
So let's start with scope.
And then in the second half of this lesson, we can cover context.
Now, instead of trying to explain the scope with only words, let's work through a few examples together
where we can see scope in action.
So imagine we have a variable.
I'm going to say let my name equal a string of text.
And now let's try to access this variable from within a function, so maybe down here, let's create
a brand new function.
You can name it whatever you want.
I'm going to name it maybe amazing function, parentheses, curly brackets.
And just as an example, let's try to log out to the console, the my name variable, just to see if
we have access to it.
So console dot, log my name, OK, and then let's actually call or execute this function to test it
out on a new line.
You can just call that function amazing function, OK.
Now if we check the console.
Awesome.
Now this is just review.
We've already done this before.
So the question is why am I showing this to you?
Well, it's because the topic of scope has to do with where we can access a variable from.
Let me show you what I mean.
So this code is working perfectly, but what if we move this first line of code here?
What if we cut and paste it to live within the function?
Let's try that out.
Let's cut this first line into our clipboard.
And then inside the body of our function, maybe right above the console line, paste in your clipboard,
OK, and then let's cut and paste this console log line.
Let's cut that into our clipboard and let's move it down below this function call.
Now, at first glance, as a beginning programmer, we would think that this would work right.
We've got this function that's going to create a variable named my name, and then we are calling the
function.
So we know that that code is going to get executed.
So we would think that we would be able to log out to the console my name.
But if I checked the console, we just see a big error message that says my name is not defined.
So we just smashed our head up against a brick wall.
And this is our first example of running in to an issue with scope.
Now, before we worry about what the word scope means in this sense, let's first answer the question
as to why this code is not working.
Why are we receiving that error message in the console?
Well, it's because within the body of this function, or I should say within this block of code, within
these curly brackets, as far as variables are concerned, we are in our own little new world that is
separate or private from the outside world.
So we would say that this variable is scoped to this block, these curly brackets, meaning it cannot
be accessed from outside the block.
So down here, when we try to access that variable, as far as this line of code is concerned, this
variable doesn't even exist.
Now, let me put things back to the way they were at the beginning of the lesson and explain why that
was working.
So let me cut the variable line back up out of the function up at the very top here and let me cut and
paste the console logline back into the function.
Now, this code will work just fine.
It works because up on this line, when we are creating the variable, we are not inside a block or
any curly brackets.
Right.
We are just out in the open in what we would call the global scope.
This works because SCOP is like a one way street.
The traffic only flows in one direction.
Code can reach outwards to access a variable, but it cannot reach inwards.
Now, don't worry.
I don't expect you to understand what I just said.
That's what we're going to work through.
A new example right now to understand what I mean by inwards and outwards.
So right now, make sure your code looks like mine.
If you need to pause the video for a second to catch up, that's OK.
Inside our function, I want you to cut the console log line.
So just cut it into your clipboard and in its place.
Let's write an if statement.
So let's say if parentheses for the condition.
Why don't we say if two plus two double equals sign four.
Right?
Because we know that will always be true right after these parentheses.
Let's include curly brackets and dropdown and now inside the if statement, let's just paste back in
the console log line.
OK, now if I check the console, we see that things are working just like before the if statement.
So you might be wondering why I even added this if statement at all.
Well, it's because it's a great example to explain what I mean when I say that scope begins inwards
and moves outwards.
Right.
That analogy when I said that scope is a one way street.
So when this line of code runs JavaScript, its first instinct is to see if there is a my name variable
as close to home as possible, meaning within this scope, within this block, within the curly brackets
for the IF statement.
So just as a quick test within the if statement, right above the console, that log line, if I say
let my name equal Brad the third and then check the console, we see Brad the third.
However, if we either delete this line or just put two forward slashes to comment it out and pretend
that it's deleted, if JavaScript sees that there is no my name variable within the current local scope,
well, it's then going to look up the scope chain or look one level outside of itself.
So outside of this scope, the next closest scope is within the body of our function.
So just as a test, if we said let my name equal Brad Junior and check the console, we see Brad Jr,
OK?
And then finally, if we either deleted this line or just got rid of it with two forward slashes, JavaScript
would say, OK, there's no my name inside the local block, there's no my name in the block.
That's one level up.
Why don't.
We check another level up from that, and that would finally land us in the global scope and it would
see that, aha, that variable exists, if we check the console, it's back to just Brad.
So the idea is that when a line of code runs and you're looking for a variable, JavaScript is first
going to look for that variable as close to home as possible within the current scope.
If it's not there, it's just going to keep moving up the scope chain one level at a time until it finds
what it's looking for.
Now, it's important that we really understand what's going on here.
So really quick.
This is not a case of these lines overwriting or updating this original variable.
That is not what's happening, even though these three variables of my name all have the same identifier
or label name, they are three completely independent and separate variables.
Let me show you not only how we can prove that, but also what I mean, because I remember when I first
learned programming and I saw an example like this, I actually misinterpreted it and saw it backwards.
I saw it as, OK, we're creating the variable in the global scope and then we are updating the variable
in this scope and then we're updating it again in this scope.
That is not the case.
These are three completely separate variables and I can prove that to you by removing the slashes to
uncommented out these two lines.
So let's get rid of the SIGIR and then get rid of the stigma here and now.
Let's do this within our innermost block of code, within the if statement, inside the console that
log.
Let's begin by saying inside the if statement and then a comma and then output are variable.
OK, now, right after the if statement, but still within our function.
So right here, let's log out to the console and say.
Inside our function and then comma and then our variable and then finally down at the very bottom on
the last line of code after we call the function.
So we are in the global scope.
Now, let's log out to the console and say in the global scope and then comma and then output my name.
OK, now if we check the console we see inside the if statement is one variable with its value inside,
our function is a different variable with its own value.
And in the global scope, that's another variable with a different value.
What was the point of this experiment?
It's to show you that these are three completely separate variables, even though they have the same
identifier or label, it doesn't matter.
The left statement creates a variable within the current local scope.
It does not matter if that identifier or label name has been used in outer scope.
Remember that inside a block of code, inside these curly brackets, it's like our own new private little
world as far as variables are concerned, meaning it's almost like we get a clean slate.
We can reuse the same variable names.
And JavaScript knows that we do not want to affect any of the variables in outer scope.
We just want to create a brand new separate variable that is scoped to this block.
Now, you might be scratching your head right now and wondering, well, what if we wanted to mutate
the global original variable from within our innermost block?
Is there a way we can do that?
And the answer is yes, absolutely.
Just to save confusion, why don't we get rid of this?
Let my name Brad Jr..
And let's also get rid of the two console loglines within our function.
OK, now, within the if statement, what if we wanted to update or mutate or change the value of the
global scoped my name variable?
Well, all we would need to do is remove the word left from this line of code.
The left statement says create a new variable for this local scope.
But if we get rid of that now, we are just trying to work or access the variable and we're setting
it to equal something.
So here's what JavaScript is going to do.
It's going to see this variable and ask itself, does this variable already exist within this current
local scope?
It doesn't.
So then it's going to look one level up just within the function.
It's going to see that it doesn't exist there either.
And then it's going to check one level up and it's going to say, OK, it does exist in the global scope.
That must be what you're talking about right here.
So I'm going to let you update or change that variable.
This is what I was talking about earlier when I said that scope moves in one direction.
It's a one way street inside code can reach outwards for variables, but outside code cannot reach inside
four variables.
So long story short, we set it to equal the third.
And now down here where we are logging out to the console in the global scope and then our variable,
if we check the console, we see browed the third.
Awesome.
Now, before we switch gears in this lesson and move on to the second half and talk about context instead
of scope, there's one more scope related thing we need to cover.
So throughout this course, when we've been creating or declaring a variable, we've been using the
word let.
However, until about three or four years ago, there was no let in JavaScript and instead we had to
create variables by saying VAR and then the label or identifier and otherwise the syntax is the same.
Right.
So if you're looking at older code or if you inherit a project from someone, you might see var being
used instead of let.
Now there are several subtle differences between VAR and let.
But right now I want to show you the one big, huge glaring difference between the two.
The biggest difference between VAR and Let is that let uses block scope whereas var uses function scope.
So what in the world does that mean.
Let me show you.
So within our if statement at the beginning of this line of code, if we put the word let here, we
know that that's going to create a variable that is scoped to this block.
Right.
Scoped to the if statements curly brackets.
So let is going to look for the nearest enclosing block and a block can be several different things.
Right.
We know that an if statement uses a block, these curly brackets.
We know that a while loop uses the curly brackets in a block.
Clearly the body of a function uses a block.
OK, but the idea here is that LET is going to make it so that this variable is only accessible from
within the nearest enclosing block.
So right now we would not be able to access the variable right here outside of the IF statement.
However, if we changed this to a var instead of let var uses function scope instead of block scope.
So VAR is going to say, you know what, I don't care that the if statement has curly brackets and that
it's a block since I'm a var, I only care about the curly brackets of a function.
Right, because var uses function scop instead of block scope.
This means that this var variable is accessible anywhere inside it's inclosing function, even outside
of the if statement.
So we could access my name right here within the function.
Now again, historically that's how we created variables in JavaScript.
But in the last three or four years, JavaScript finally got access to let.
And the reason that 99 percent of developers used the word let instead of VAR is because almost all
other programming languages besides JavaScript use block scope instead of function.
SCOP block scope is just what most of us are used to.
It's a paradigm that we are familiar with and it's a super popular opinion that Block SCOP leads to
less confusing code, less scope confusion and just less problems overall.
So long story short, that's the difference between let and VAR.
But in the current year and looking forward, I encourage you to always use the word let and never or
I should say basically never.
Use the word Hvar.
All right, and that's SCOP in a nutshell, if you're still a bit confused regarding SCOP, that's OK.
That's completely normal.
In fact, I have worked with professional mid-level developers who were even sometimes still confused
by SCOP.
Big picture.
You do not need to be a scope guru at this point.
I just want the topic to be on your radar.
It's something you need to be aware of.
And if your code isn't working, you might want to double or triple check your scope and make sure your
variables are pointing towards what you think they are pointing towards.
Remember, you can always use console log to check the value.
OK, at this point, let's change gears.
We've talked about SCOP.
Now let's talk about context.
So I'm actually going to delete all of the code that we have and start fresh.