Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to learn how to connect a Node.js app to a MongoDB database.
Let's jump right into the action.
So this is where we left off with our simple to do app.
This is just a static HTML template at the moment.
But remember, we did already set things up so that if the user typed into this field.
So if I say buy dog food and then submit the form.
Not only does the visitor see, thanks for submitting the form, but if I go look at my command line.
We also logged the users typed input to the console.
Now we only logged this to the console to make sure that we were able to access the user's input value.
What we actually want to do is permanently store this data in a database, and that's exactly what we're
going to learn how to do in this lesson.
Let's get started.
So right now, I want you to follow along with me.
Make sure you have your server dot js file open and scroll down to the very bottom.
Because that's where we have this section of code where we respond to an incoming post request to this
URL.
In other words, this is what we do in response to a user submitting that form.
Now, when it comes to this line of code, we don't actually want to log this value to the console.
This is the value that we want to instead save into a database.
So right now, do this with me.
Let's delete this console dot log line and in its place, let's write a bit of code that will create
a new document in a MongoDB database.
Let's begin with a variable named DB for the time being, do not worry about where this variable is
coming from.
Trust me, we will address that a bit later on in this lesson.
So let's look inside it.
So Dot and let's call a method named collection.
Remember that a MongoDB database can contain multiple collections.
Remember back to a lesson or two ago when we created a pet's collection and then created different documents
that represented cats and dogs?
Well, in this case, for our To-Do app instead of pets, let's imagine we have a collection named items
so we can just say quotes items.
OK, and now this collection method is going to select that collection in the database.
Now that we've selected that collection, we can tack on and at the end of this line include a period.
And this is where we can perform the basic crud operations.
In this case, we would want to create a new document in this collection.
So right after this dot, let's use a method named Insert one.
In this context, the word insert essentially means create now within these parentheses, we need to
pass this insert one method to arguments.
So let's say a comma b as placeholders for the first argument instead of the placeholder a let's add
a pair of curly brackets because this is where we create an object.
This is the object that's going to be stored as a document in the database.
So this is where you can make up different properties and values.
For example, you can say that the name should have a value of meows a lot and then have a comma and
say that the species should be set to cat.
Right.
This is just a regular old JavaScript object.
Now, in this case, we don't actually need name and species properties.
So let me go back to just the empty, curly brackets for an object.
In this case, we only need one property to represent the text for a To-Do list item.
So you could make up any property name you want.
But let's just call it text and then colon, and then let's give it a value of whatever the user typed
into that form field.
So that would be the request object and then look inside it for the body object and then look inside
that for the item property.
Awesome.
So that will create a new document in the database.
That's the first argument.
Let's move on to this be placeholder, which is the second argument.
What the insert one method actually expects here instead of this be placeholder is a function that it
will call once it's had a chance to actually create this item in the database.
The idea is that as the developer, we don't know how long it will take to create that item in the database.
It could take three milliseconds or it could take three thousand milliseconds.
All that matters is that this method will call this function at the appropriate time.
So let's get rid of that B placeholder, and let's just add an anonymous function.
So let's say function parentheses curly brackets was dropped down in between the curly brackets.
All right.
And then let's just move or cut and paste this response dot send line to live inside this new function.
So I'm just going to select that response dot sandline and cut it into my clipboard.
And then inside this new function just pasted in, you might be wondering why we just moved this line.
I don't want to display this message the millisecond the user submits the form.
I want to wait the appropriate amount of time that it takes the insert one method to actually create
that item in the database, whether that's five milliseconds or 5000 milliseconds.
Anyways, that completes this section of code.
All we need to do now in this lesson is address this magical and mysterious deep variable that I said
we would circle back to.
Now, I hate to break it to you, but there is no DB variable that exists by default out of the box
like this.
You and I need to put in a bit of work to create this variable ourselves.
Big picture we need to set up a variable that represents a MongoDB database that we've opened a connection
to.
The variable could be named anything.
It doesn't have to be DB.
That's just a common choice.
Anyways, right now, I want you to scroll up to the very top of our file and maybe right below this
let app equal express line.
Let's add a new line and say Let DB and that's it.
We don't even need to say equals anything.
For now, we are simply saying that a variable with this name should exist in the global scope.
Don't worry, in a few minutes, we will update the value of this variable.
For now, though, the question becomes How in the world do we open a connection to a MongoDB database?
Well, I'll let you know that our first step is to go out to the JavaScript grocery store or npm and
pick up the official MongoDB driver for the Node.js environment.
To do that, we need to jump down to our command line.
If your node, app or server is currently running, be sure to press Control C to quit the app or server.
All right, and then I want you to run the following command with me npm install.
And the name of the package that we are interested in is Mongo DB, all lowercase and all one word.
So go ahead and press enter to install the MongoDB package.
And this is the official package that gives Node.js the ability to work with a MongoDB database.
So now up in our code, maybe right below this very first line.
Let's drop down and say let MongoDB equal and then just require in the name of the package is Mongo
DB right away, though, I do want to let you know that we're not going to use the package directly.
Instead, we want to look inside it so you don't need to type this next part.
But for example, in our actual code, we would need to say MongoDB Dot and look inside it for something
called Mongo client.
So the idea is if we know that we need to look inside it for this specific thing, why not just import
that specific thing?
So let me get rid of that code.
Now there are a few different ways we could handle this.
So option number one after this require you could just say Dot Mongo client, and then you could give
this a name that makes sense, right?
Like Client.
However, what if there were two or three or four or five different things from the MongoDB package
that we want to sort of pull out or select like that?
Well, then you'd have to have four or five different lines of code like this.
So instead, something you'll see a lot of developers do.
If we get rid of this Mongo client at the end, here is something called deep structuring.
So instead of saying let and then making up a name, we can say let curly brackets and then we don't
make up a name.
We choose the name of the thing that we're trying to import from this object, so we know that it has
something inside it called Mongo Client, and that's capital M Capital C.
And now imagine if there were two or three other things in this overall object that we wanted to make
available from an easy to access variable name.
You could just say comma, you know, if there was something called a something called B, you get the
idea.
So we're sort of doing two things at once.
We're taking these named properties from this existing object and we're making them available from these
variable names.
So now anywhere in our code, we could use Mongo client or we could use A, B, C or D.
Now, obviously, the MongoDB package doesn't actually have items called A, B, C or D, and we don't
need those.
So it would just be curly brackets.
Mongo client.
Cool.
Now how do we actually go user leverage this?
Well, right below this line where we said, let db, let's drop down and say Mongo Client Uppercase
M and see parentheses to call it in these parentheses, let's just have an empty quotes or empty string
of text will fill this in later.
Essentially, this is the connection string to our database that gives us access or permission.
OK, now at the very start of this line, when we called Mongo Client, we would want to create a.
New instance of it, so new Mongo client, and then that's going to return something we don't want that
just sitting or floating in outer space.
We want to hold on to that.
So also at the very start of this line, let's say let and then let's make up a name.
I'll just call it lowercase client equals a new instance of Mongo client.
Now on a new line, we can leverage our client variable.
We can just say client dot, and it has a method called Connect.
So parentheses to call that once the Connect method finishes, we will have an ongoing connection to
the database.
So on a new line now we can say DB equals client dot and then call its DB method.
However, there's one big problem with this code, and that is that we need to wait for this connect
method to actually finish or complete before we do anything else.
Because we don't know how long this is going to take to complete could be.
One millisecond could be 5000 milliseconds, and this line of code won't work unless we actually wait
for this to finish.
Now we ran into a timing situation like this down below in our code earlier in the video.
And in that case, we used a callback function.
But right now, I want to show you a more modern approach.
What we can do at the very start of this client connect line is just add the word await.
However, there is one tiny complication and that is that in JavaScript, we're only allowed to use
the await word like this if we're inside an async function.
So let me show you what I would do.
Just select these three lines of code.
Cut them into your clipboard.
We're going to want them back in just a minute and say async function.
You can give it any name, you could name it go or start or unicorn.
So we're just creating a function, but we're including the word async in front of it.
Now, right after this function, let's actually call it or execute it.
So whatever you named it, I named Mongo.
I'm calling it now in the body of this async function.
You can paste your clipboard back in.
And now, because we are within an async function, we are allowed to use this magical await keyword.
Now, this line of code will make our database available from the global DB variable.
So we want to make sure that that's ready before our application actually starts running.
So to do that, all we need to do, scroll down to the very bottom of your application.
Cut this apt listen line into your clipboard.
Scroll back up to our asynchronous function and just right below the DB equals client line.
Paste in your clipboard.
Cool.
Now, by the time our application actually starts running and tries to reference DB, it will actually
be pointing towards our database.
Now, at this point, we just have one more step before our app will be up and running with a database.
We need to fill in this connection string value.
Again, this is where we tell Mongo where or what we want to connect to.
In our case, we want to connect to a database that lives within our Mongo DB online atlas account.
So the MongoDB Atlas website will give us a little snippet of code that will include an address that
points towards our database and also a username and password.
All bundled together in one big, long string of text.
And then we just include that here and that will get plugged into the connect method.
And that will give us access that will give us the security or permissions in order to actually connect.
So let's go retrieve this together.
Right now, I want you to open up a new tab in your web browser and log in to your MongoDB Atlas account.
All right.
And from this main overview screen down here, we see a few buttons.
I want you to click on the Connect button.
And we see that we need to fill in two options.
The first setting is where we whitelist our IP address.
Now, in our case, we do not want to just add our current IP address of our actual computer because
a bit later on in the course, we are going to push our application up onto the web up to a hosting
company.
And we have no definitive way of knowing what their IP address will be.
So do this with me.
Click this Add a different IP address button in this first IP address field.
Go ahead and type in 0.0 0.0, so four zeros all separated with periods in between them and then at
the end, a forward slash and one more zero.
This is just our way of telling the Atlas Service that it should allow incoming connections from any
IP address.
And no, this is not a big security risk because you would still need our username and password to actually
connect.
OK, let's be sure to click this green button here that says Add IP address.
Cool, and now we just need to create a new MongoDB user.
So we choose a username and password.
Now you might be a bit confused and think that you already chose a username and password when you signed
up for your MongoDB Atlas account.
But this is something different.
This is the username and password that will actually be used in the connection string text that we include
in our code.
So go ahead and make up a username.
I will choose to do app user.
OK, and then choose a password.
Make sure you choose something you can remember or write it down because we are going to need this password
again in just a minute or two.
OK, and then finally, click this create MongoDB user button.
Cool.
Now we can click this choose a connection method button down here.
It gives us a few different options.
We are interested in this second option that says, connect your application.
You can see it reads Get a connection string.
And that's exactly what we are interested in.
So go ahead and click on that.
By default, you can see the driver is set to no, which is perfect.
That's our development environment.
If for some reason your driver is not set to it, be sure to set it to node OK.
And below that.
This is what we've been looking for.
This is the magical connection string.
We just want to copy and paste this into our text editing program so you can see there's this convenient
copy button here.
So click that copy it into your clipboard.
And now let's just jump into our text editor.
Well, in between those empty quotes, paste in your clipboard.
We're not quite done yet, though.
We need to fill in a few details in this connection stream because you'll see that it does list your
username that you just chose, but it does not list your password.
Now, not only do you need to replace the word password with your actual password, but you also need
to get rid of the less than symbol right before it and the greater than symbol right after it.
So replace this entire selection that I have highlighted here with your actual password.
And again, this is the password that you just chose about 30 seconds ago, not your MongoDB Atlas account
password.
OK, for our final step, we need to look at the very end of this line of code.
So at the very end we see you, retry rights equals true.
But right before that we see a question mark and right before that we see the word test instead of the
word test.
This is where we can include which database we want to work with.
So really quick do this with me back in MongoDB Atlas from the main overview screen, click on collections.
You'll remember in a previous lesson, we created this database named just a test.
And that's fine.
But right now, let's create a new separate database just for our To-Do application.
So go ahead and click this create database button.
For the database name, let's call it to do app and for the name of the first collection.
Let's go with items, then let's go ahead and click the Create button.
Awesome, we now have a new database just for our application.
Now back in our code at the end of this connection string instead of the word test here, get rid of
test and just type in whatever database name you just chose.
In my case, I chose to do app.
Awesome.
At this point, we are ready to save this file and test it out as soon as you save jumped down into
your command line.
And let's launch our app by running npm run watch.
Press Enter.
OK, let's jump over to the web browser and let's visit local host 3000.
And let's test it out.
So in the form field, I will say buy grapes and then submit the form.
Thanks for submitting the form.
Now this is the moment of truth.
We want to see if that was actually saved in the database.
So in the Atlas tab from the collection screen, you can click on the arrow near that new database name
to do app to expand it.
And we can see it contains a collection named Items.
Click on the items collection.
Awesome.
We see that the collection has one total documents, and there we can see it.
It has a property name text, which is set to buy grapes.
It may not seem like it, but what we just accomplished is a huge step forward for us as a developer
looking ahead to our next lesson.
We are going to learn how to read or load the existing items from the database and display them right
here in our application, right?
Because we just created an item named by grapes.
So that should be appearing here in the list.
Let's keep our momentum rolling, and I will see you then.