Perfect now for our one final task in this lesson, let's set things up so that these values or these
numbers in these links actually make sense and are actually pulling in real data.
Right.
Because at the moment, as we can see in our HTML or Ajay's template, these numbers are hard coded
and fake.
So within our user controller, we would want to ask our model to retrieve those real number or count
values now instead of including the code to request those count numbers three times within our profile
post screen and our profile follower screen and our profile following screen, let's instead remember
that up at the very top of this file within user controller for you, it might not be at the very top
of the file, but somewhere in our user controller you should have a function named shared profile data.
Remember, all three of our profile based routes call this function, which makes it the perfect place
to fetch these count numbers.
So let's do this towards the bottom of the function, maybe right before we call.
Next, let's add a comment to stay organized.
Let's say retrieve post follower and following counts.
All right.
And let's begin with the post count.
Right.
We would want to know how many posts this current user has created.
So let's say let post count equal and then we'd want to begin working with our post model.
And this method doesn't exist yet.
But you can imagine that it would have a method or function named count posts by author.
And we can imagine that when we create this function, it should return a promise.
So then we would want to await right before calling it OK, after this line, we would want to count
how many followers this user has so we could create a variable, say, let follower count equal.
And then you could imagine we'd want to use our follow model.
And we haven't created this function yet, but we could call it Count Followers by Idy.
And again, when we create this, we can set it up to return a promise.
So we would await that promise.
And then finally, we'd want following count so you could just copy and paste and duplicate this line
and change this to let the following count.
And we could call a function named count following by ID.
OK, and then finally, we just want to add these values onto the request object and then we can call
next.
However, this is not the most optimal way of setting things up from a performance or speed perspective.
We can do much better.
This current setup would make sense if each one of our promises relied on the previous promise completing
before we wanted to begin the next promise.
However, in this case, we're just grabbing the counts of different values and none of these things
rely on one another.
In other words, all three of these tasks can run independently from one another.
None of them depend on a value from the other, meaning there's no sense in a weighting or freezing
the execution of further JavaScript actions like this.
So instead of telling this action to begin and then freezing the world while we wait it to complete
and then doing the same thing here, let's instead let all three of the promises begin running at the
same time and then wait for all three to complete before calling next.
Let me show you how we can do this.
So first things first.
Let's get rid of the word a wait here in all three instances.
So delete a weight, OK?
And since we're no longer waiting for these promises to complete or resolve, it really doesn't make
sense to name these variables count.
Instead, for example, we should name this post count promise.
Right.
Because that's what this is going to immediately return a promise.
So let's do the same thing here.
Let's say follower count promise equals and do the same thing here following count promise equals.
And now check this out below all three of these promise lines.
We can say a wait uppercase promise dot all within the parentheses for.
All we give it an array, so square brackets, and then you just provide promises, so let's include
all three of these.
So post count, promise, karma, follower count, promise, karma following count, promise this approach
will be noticeably faster from a performance standpoint.
Now, there's no guarantee which one of these will complete or resolve first.
But in this case, it doesn't matter.
We don't care which one completes first.
We are just waiting for all of them to complete before moving on.
Now, ultimately, this all method is going to return an array.
It will be an array with the values that each one of these promises resolves with.
Now we want to keep track of those values.
So at the very beginning of this line, let's say let results equal the array that all is going to return.
So, for example, we could now say let post count equal and then look in the results array and grab
the first item in the array.
And then we could say let follower count equal.
The second item in the array.
Now, this approach would work just fine, but I actually am going to delete these two lines and instead
show you a cleaner approach named Array D structuring.
So instead of saying let results equal, let's get rid of results here and instead include square brackets
within these square brackets, let's say post count, comma, follower count, comma, following count.
This will create three different variables with these names and the first item will use the first value
from the array that we are structuring.
As you can guess, the second item will use the second value from the array that we are d structuring.
Cool.
So finally, let's just add these variables on to the request object before we call next.
So down here we can just say request dot post count equals post count and then let's say request dot
follower count equals follower count and request dot following count equals following count.
OK, and then at that point we are ready to call next.
Now before we save this file and then go actually create these promises, let's first be sure to include
the current IDE within these parentheses.
Right.
In order for any of these three functions to do their job, they need to know which profile user we're
looking for.
So, for example, within the parentheses for count posts by author, let's say request dot profile
user dot underscore ID and then you can just select that and copy and paste it into the parentheses
for count follower's by idy in the parentheses for count following by id.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this file and now let's go jump into our post model and create a function with
this matching name count posts by author.
So within the root of our project, let's dig into our models folder and open up post Jass.
Let's go ahead and scroll down to the very bottom of this file and right before the closing module exports,
let's add a new line and say uppercase post dot count posts by author.
Let's set this to equal a function within the parentheses.
For this function, we'd want to receive the incoming ID and then within the body of the function,
we'd want to return a promise.
So return a new instance of uppercase promise within the parentheses for Promis.
Let's give it an async arrow function.
So async parentheses with parameters of resolve and reject and then the arrow symbol and then curly
brackets.
Within this function, let's create a variable.
Let's say let post count equal and then let's begin working with our Mongo DB collection.
So in this case, that's posts collection.
We created this variable up at the top of this file and then we want to look inside it and call a Mongo
DB method named Count Documents.
Within these parentheses, we give it an object.
Describing which documents we want to look for and count, so in this case, it would be a post document
where the author field, so author Colvin matches whatever I.D. was passed into this overall function.
So we can just say I'd cool.
Now, this Mongo DB method is going to return a promise.
So right after let post count equal, we would just include a wait here.
OK, now below this line, let's say resolve our promise is ready to resolve with this as its value.
So resolve in these parentheses post count.
Now in order to save a bunch of typing, we can actually just copy and paste this entire function and
use it in our follow model.
Let me show you what I'm referring to.
So copy this function into your clipboard, then let's go ahead and save this file.
And now I want you to jump into the follow model.
So in our project, look in your models folder and then jump in to followed JS down at the very bottom
of this file, right above module exports.
We can paste in our clipboard and then instead of uppercase post, let's change this to uppercase follow
and then instead of count posts by author, this should be count follower's by IDE.
OK then let's change this variable name.
So instead of let post count we could say let follower count and then instead of working with our posts
collection, we want to work with our follows collection.
And then in terms of which documents we're trying to find to count instead of the author field matching
our ID, we would want the followed ID to match the current ID.
Cool.
And then when this promise resolves, we'd want to resolve with this value.
So instead of post count, we'd resolve with follower count.
Cool.
Now we just need to create one more function named count following by ID so you could go ahead and copy
these lines into your clipboard and then right below this, just paste and change this name to count
following by ID.
You could change this variable from follower count to maybe just lowercase count.
We'd still want to work with our follows collection only in terms of the documents that we want to count.
Instead of performing a match on the followed ID field, we would want this to be the author ID field.
And then in terms of the value that we resolve, we can just resolve with lowercase count.
Cool at this point.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And now let's jump back into our user controller file to refresh our memory of what we're doing.
So within your projects folder, inside your controller folder, jump into user controller J.S..
OK, so all of those promises that we just set up are ultimately running within our shared profile data
function.
Remember, this function is going to run for all three of our routes, the Post's route, the followers
route and the following route.
So now that we have these numbers or values, we just need to dig into the profile posts, screen function
and actually pass that number into the template that's getting rendered.
And then also do the same thing for the follower screen and the following screen.
Let me show you what I mean.
So within our user controller file, I want you to find the function that is named profile posts screen.
For me, it's around line number ninety four.
It begins with exports, dot profile posts screen.
So let's do this when we are rendering our template.
So response dot render.
We just want to update the data that we are passing into the template.
How about at the end of all of these properties we can add a comma and add one more, let's say counts
colon and then let's set it to be an object.
So curly brackets and let's give it a property named post count which should be request dot post count,
comma, follower count, which should be request dot follower count, comma and then following count
which should be request dot following count.
Cool.
Now we can just go ahead and copy this entire line into our clipboard and then we added it to the profile
posts screen, but then we could paste into.
To the profile, follower's screen and profile following screen, so be sure to select this new counts
line into your clipboard, so copy that and then let's scroll down and find our profile follower's screen
function.
Here it is.
And when we are rendering that template at the end of all these properties, just add a comma at the
end dropdown and then paste in your clipboard.
Cool.
So the following screen now has that counts property.
Let's scroll down and add it to our profile following screen.
So within response to our render, let's just add one more property.
So comma, dropdown and paste.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now we just need to go into that shared template that powers this HTML.
So remember that lives within your views folder and then the includes folder and its name is Profile
Shared SJS.
Remember, down at the bottom we have the three links.
So the first link is the post count.
Let's get rid of the hardcoded number of three and instead drop into SJS and we can just say counts
dot post count.
You can just copy and paste this section and do the same thing for these two lines.
So get rid of the hardcoded three four follower's paste in your clipboard, change this to follower
count and then let's get rid of the hardcoded two for following Paiste on your clipboard and change
this to the following count.
But go ahead and save this and test it out in the browser.
So from the Brad profile, if I refresh.
Perfect, I'm following one user, I don't have any followers, and if I click on posts, you can see
that I yes, do indeed have four posts.
Let's go check out the Bark's lot profile.
So if I click on following go to Bachs a lot.
Cool.
We see Bachs a lot.
Yes, they have one post click on followers.
Yep.
They have two followers and they are following zero users.
Perfect.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we are finally going to set up our homepage feed.
This should be a lot of fun to set up.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you then.