Hello, everyone, in this lesson, we are going to work on our home page feed for users that are logged
in the home page should show the latest posts from the people they follow.
If a user has not followed anyone or if the people they follow have not created any posts yet, then
we would expect to see this message that your feed is empty.
However, I know that my browed account is following the Bachs a lot account and I know that Bachs a
lot has created at least one post, so we should see that on our homepage feed.
So our goal in this lesson is to swap out this hard coded HTML and make this page come to life with
dynamic logic to get started.
Let's dig into the controller function that powers this homepage root.
So in your text editor within your controllers folder, I want you to dig into user controller J.S.
Within this file, we're looking for a function named home.
For me, it's around line number seventy seven.
Yours will likely be on a different line number, but we're looking for the area that begins with exports
dot home.
This is where we've already set up, if else blocks.
If you were logged in with user session data, you see the home dashboard.
If you're not logged in, you see the guest registration page.
In this case, we're only interested if you are indeed logged in.
So maybe right above this response, not render home dashboard line.
Let's add a comment to stay organized and let's say fetch feed of posts for current user.
OK, now, right below this, let's create a variable.
So I will say let posts equal and then you can imagine that we would want to use our post model.
So uppercase post and we have not created this function yet, but we can create it in just a moment.
So let's say post dot git feed again.
We have not created a function with this name yet, but you can imagine that in order for it to do its
job, it needs to know which user to create a feed for.
So within these parentheses here, let's include the current logged in users id so request dot session
dot user dot underscore ID.
OK, now you can imagine that when we create this git feed function we will set it up to return a promise.
So right before this we want to be sure to include awaked and since we're using a wait, we want to
be sure that we are within an asynchronous function.
So up on this line, when we say exports dot home right before function, just include async.
Cool.
So now when it comes time to render the home dashboard, we will have a list of posts that we want to
pass into it and render.
So right after the quotes for Home Dashboard include a comma and then an object so curly brackets.
And let's pass this template, a property named posts with a value of our posts variable here.
So posts Kolan posts.
OK, at this point let's go ahead and save this file and now we better jump into our post model and
create a function with this name git feed.
So within our models folder, I want you to jump into post JS.
Let's scroll down to the very bottom of this file and right above the closing module exports.
Let's add a new line and we want to create a new function.
So uppercase post dot git feed.
Let's set this to equal a function within the parentheses for this function.
Let's be sure to receive the incoming ID.
OK, now within the body of this function, let's analyze what we need to do.
Let's use comments to break it down.
So our first task, so comment would be to create an array of the user IDs that the current user follows.
Right, because if I follow twenty different users, I would want to see the latest posts from all of
those people.
So in order to query the posts collection, we need to know which authors of posts to look for.
So this is our first step.
Create an array of the user IDs that the current user follows.
Then after that, let's dropdown and add another comment.
Then we'd want to look.
For posts where the author is in the above array of followed users, right, and then that collection
of posts is ultimately what we want this function to return or resolve with.
So let's get to work.
Let's start with step number one.
We need to create an array of the user IDs that the current user follows.
Now, technically, depending on how strictly you want to follow the MVC pattern, you could have your
user controller ask the follow model for this data and then pass that data into this post model.
But personally, I'm OK with looking directly in the follows collection from within this post model,
since I'm not modifying the follow data in any way, shape or form, I'm OK with this.
So in order to complete this step, number one, let's scroll up to the very top of this file, because
we need to be able to work with our follows collection.
We can actually just duplicate line number one, where we create posts collection.
So if you just select that line, copy it right below it, paste it in the new copy, change the name
from Post's collection to follows collection.
And then at the end, the collection that we want to work with instead of posts, it would be follows.
OK, now let's scroll back down to the function that we were just working on.
So back down at the very bottom, our posts get feed function right below the comment for step number
one.
Let's do this.
Let's create a variable.
So let and let's name it followed users.
Let's set this to equal and then let's begin working with our follows collection.
Let's look inside that for the Mongo DB method named Find.
And actually at the very end of this line, since Find is going to return data that makes sense to Mongo
DB but maybe doesn't make sense from our raw JavaScript perspective.
Let's also tack on dot to array.
OK, now within the parentheses for find, which documents do we want to look for?
Well, let's provide an object so curly brackets and we're interested in follow documents where the
author IDE Colon would match whatever ID was passed into this overall function.
Now the idea that stored in session data is just a string of text, so we'd first want to convert it
into a Mongu DB Object ID object type.
So right after the colon here, we just say a new instance of object ID.
It gets its own set of parentheses and then we just pass an I.D..
OK, now ultimately this is going to return a promise.
So before this, let's be sure to include the word awaked.
And if we're using a wait, we want to be sure that we are within an asynchronous function.
So right before the word function here, let's include a sink.
OK, so now we have this variable named followed users.
That is going to be an array of follow documents.
Now, each one of these documents is going to have several properties.
If we look at our Mongu DB database in Atlus within our follows collection, if we take a look at a
document each followed has an idea of its own and then it has the user IDs for the user that is doing
the following and the user that they want to follow.
However, in this case, the only property or value that we actually care about is the followed I.D.
This represents the user that they follow.
So let's do this.
Let's adjust this array of documents to not be an array of objects with multiple properties, but instead
just an array of various user IDs.
Let me show you what I mean.
So right below this line, let's say followed users equals and then let's just use the map method.
So followed users dot map map will create a new array and it will let us specify the value for each
item in that new array.
So within these parentheses, we give map a function within these function parentheses.
Let's be sure to include a parameter, let's call it follow doc.
And then within the body of this new function, let's just return follow doc dot followed ID right.
And then ultimately this new array that map returns is what we are storing in this same variable name
followed users.
So this way followed users is now an array that doesn't contain anything other than the actual specific
values that we are interested in.
So if someone came to our home page and they followed 15 different people, it would just be an array
with 15 different user IDs.
Cool.
Now, that is an array that we can very easily leverage in step number two.
Let me show you what I mean.
So below this comment for step number two, let's add a new line.
And remember, ultimately, we just want this function to return or resolve with a collection of posts
that would make up the user's feed.
So let's do this down here.
Let's return another promise.
Remember that we've already created uppercase post DOT Reuseable post query.
This function is going to do several things, but in this case it's useful because it's going to look
up the author's username and figure out their aggravator.
Now, within the parentheses for this function, we give it an array of aggregate operations within
these square brackets for this array.
Let's drop down and each aggregate operation is an object.
So curly brackets for the first operation, let's perform a match.
So dollar sign match colon.
And then we give that an object and we want to look for any post documents where the author field author
Colon and then check this out.
Instead of just looking for a specific or single value, we can include another object here.
So another pair of curly brackets and say dollar sign in colon and then we can give it an array.
So this is where our followed users array comes in.
So let's just say followed users.
So altogether this is saying find any post document where the author value is a value that is in our
array of follow users.
Cool.
After this, let's just include a comma and include one more aggregate operation.
Let's sort things so that the newest posts are up at the top.
So dollar signs sort colon give that an object created de colon and then negative one.
So the newest values are up at the top.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now let's jump back into our user controller to refresh our memory of what we're doing.
So in user controller, within our exports home function, we are creating a variable named posts and
is leveraging that function that we just created in the model git feed.
So ultimately this function returns a promise from the reusable query function and then we are awaiting
that promise.
Cool.
Now we've already.
Set things up to pass the posts into the template, right, that's what's going on here.
So now all we need to do is go into our home dash dashboard file and actually leverage or output this
data.
Let me show you what I mean.
So in the root of your project, open up your views folder and I want you to dig into home dash dashboard
SJS around line number seven.
We see this div with a class of text center.
This content should only be displayed if there are no relevant posts to display.
So let's do this.
I want you to cut this div into your clipboard.
So now the template should look like this, there's just the one closing div that matches the opening
container div and in the place of that code that we just cut.
Let's set up an if statement.
So let's open up in each section.
We do not need an equal sign here because we're not immediately trying to output something.
We just want to run a bit of JavaScript.
So we want an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets right after the closing curly bracket let's also add and else block.
OK, now for the parentheses or for our condition, let's just say if posts length.
So if there are posts to display we can show them here.
But first, let's take care of the else within the else block.
This is where we can paste back in our clipboard.
Right, because this is only going to run if their feed is empty.
OK, now in terms of what we want to do, if there are posts to display, instead of reinventing the
wheel and writing a bunch of code here, we can actually just recycle code from our profile template.
Let me show you what I mean within your views folder.
I want you to jump in to profile Dot Ajay's around line number eight.
You'll see a div with a class of list group.
We've already written code that will loop through a collection of posts and for each post it will create
a link.
Right.
And that will include the title of the post, the author's avatar and the created date.
So let's do this.
Let's just copy this entire div with a class of list group.
So I will begin selecting here and then grab the one closing div tag.
Let's copy that.
And then back in our home dashboard file within the if block, just paste in your clipboard.
OK, now I do want to make one adjustment on the profile screen.
We do not list the author's username.
This is because if you're viewing someone's profile, it's safe to assume the list of posts are all
by that particular author.
But in the context of our homepage feed, we would want to display the author's username.
So maybe right after this strong tag with the title of the post, let's wrap everything after that in
a span.
So opening span element, you can see that Vrsaljko code just trying to automatically close the spane
element for me.
I don't want that.
So I'm going to get rid of that closing span tag.
And then at the very end of this line is where I would want the closing span tag.
Now, let's go back to that opening span tag.
And just for styling reasons, I want to give it a class of text dash muted and a class of small.
OK, now, within that span tag, the first thing I wanted to say is by and then the author name.
So we would just drop in to SJS and output post dot author dot username.
Cool.
We just have one more detail before we test this out.
Right above this div with a class of list group, let's add a heading level two so H two within it,
let's say the latest from those you follow.
And just for styling reasons, let's give this heading level to a class of text dash center and M.V.
Dash four for margin bottom for cool.
Now before we save this file, let's be sure to pay attention to where we are dropping out and in of
SJS.
So, for example, on this line where we have our IF statement after this opening curly bracket, let's
end our SJS and then on the line where our else block begins.
At the start of that line, we see the closing curly bracket for the IF statement.
So let's drop back in to SJS there.
At the very end of this line, we will exit SJS and then finally, when our else block closes right
before that, we'd want to drop back in to Ejaz.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back on the home page, if I refresh, I should see one post from Barzilai.
Awesome.
The latest from those you follow and there is the post from Bachs alot.
Now just to test things out and make sure that this works with multiple posts and from multiple authors.
Let's do this in this window.
I'm logged in with the Kitty Doe account, so let me create a post with Kitty Doe.
Catnip is delicious.
It's very good to create that post and then back in this window where I'm logged in as the Brad account,
if I search for catnip and if I click on that post and maybe I really enjoy this, so I want to view
that author's profile and begin following them.
Well, now, if I go back to the home page, I should see that post by Kitty Doe.
Perfect.
And you can see they are sorted so that the newest post is on top.
And that actually brings this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we are going to work on our chat room or live chat feature.
This will use an entirely new technology to allow for real time, two way communication of data.
This should be a lot of fun to set up.
So let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.