Remember, you can always use console log to check the value, OK, at this point.
Let's change gears.
We've talked about SCOP, now let's talk about context.
So I'm actually going to delete all of the code that we have and start fresh.
OK, so SCOP is about variables.
Context is about objects.
So with this in mind, let's go ahead and give ourselves an example object to experiment with.
So I'm going to create a variable and I'll give it a name of John and set it to equal an object.
So curly brackets, let's give it a property of first name instead.
It's equal John, and then let's give it another property of last name and give it a value of go.
OK, and then let's also give this object a method named drive car.
So drive car, parentheses, curly brackets.
And let's imagine we want this method to log out to the console, a bit of text that says John Doe is
driving a car.
So console dot log only.
We don't want to necessarily hard code John into the string of text.
Instead, it would make more sense to pull in the value of the first name property.
Right.
Because that way, if in the future they ever legally change their name to Jonathan or something different,
our drive car method would automatically pull in that value.
So the question is inside of a method like this, right inside this function that belongs to the object,
how can we reference this property?
Well, instead of just saying first name, we instead want to say this dot first name.
Now, the entire topic of context in JavaScript is centered around the this keyword.
I will explain how the this keyword works in just a minute.
But first, let's finish out our line of code here.
So right after a first name, let's say plus and then a string of text with a space in it and then let's
add on their last name.
So this dot last name and then let's add on a string of text that says is driving a car.
OK, now, really quick, let's test out this method and then we can dive in to really understanding
the this keyword.
So maybe down here at the very bottom of our code, below our object, we can say, John, to work with
the object, look inside it with a dot, and then call that method drive car parentheses to call the
method.
And if we check the console awesome, we see John Doe is driving a car again.
This is nothing new.
We've done this before.
The reason I'm showing it to you this time is because this is a chance to dissect the key word this.
So what in the world does this mean?
Well, that's a loaded question.
Even some of the best JavaScript developers in the world, if they're being honest at one point in their
career, they were definitely confused by the this keyword.
So in our current example, the this keyword is pointing towards our John object.
So if we use our imagination, we are basically saying John Dot, first name, John Dot, last name.
Right.
We know that to look inside an object, you just say Dot and then whichever property you're interested
in.
Now, at this point, you might be thinking, what's the big deal?
What's so confusing?
Right.
This seems really straightforward.
You might be thinking that within a method, the this keyword simply always points towards the enclosing
object.
However, that's not the case.
So in a search for the truth, let me confuse you on purpose just for a minute to show you why the this
keyword gives developers so much trouble.
Check this out right above this console, that logline.
But still within our drive car method, let's create a brand new function.
So function and let's name it.
I'm a function, not a method.
And parentheses, curly brackets, this name is just for fun, you could choose any function name you
want, but we are nesting a function inside of this method and check this out inside the body of this
function, lets log out to the console, the this keyword.
Now, currently, this function would never actually run, right?
This is just a function definition or the recipe for the function.
So then maybe right below it.
Why don't we try and call that function?
So I'm a function, not a method parentheses to call it.
And if I check the console right above, our John Doe is driving a car.
We see this window object.
Let's not get too hung up on what window is for.
Now, I can tell you that in the web browser window is the root or global object.
We could say that it's the top level object that houses or contains all of the web browsers, other
objects.
For now, let's just call window the global object.
Now, the important concept here is that the this keyword is pointing to two different things at two
different times.
Right.
In this context, this line of code that I'm highlighting, the this key word pointed towards our John
object.
But then on this line of code, the this keyword is pointing towards the global object.
So the million dollar question, the question that confuses programmers all around the world, the question
that they're ripping their hair out of their head over is how does JavaScript decide what this keyword
should be pointing towards?
Well, here's the answer.
The this keyword does not point towards the enclosing object.
Clearly, that's not the case.
If that was the case, then this instance of the this keyword would be pointing towards John.
But it's not.
So the real answer here it is, is that the this keyword points towards the object that is executing
or calling the current function, or in other words, instead of focusing on these two lines of code
that used the this keyword.
So this line and this line, what we should really be focusing on are the two lines of code where we
are calling the functions.
So this line and this line on this line of code, the object that is calling or executing the function
is the John object.
So that's the object that the this keyword is going to point towards inside that function.
Now, here's where the confusion comes from.
You might be thinking to yourself, well, hey, this line of code lives inside that drive car function.
So why on this line of code is that this key word also not pointing towards John?
Well, the answer is because that's not the context in which this function is actually being called
or executed.
The only reason that this function ever actually runs is because we are calling it right here.
Now, on this line of code, it's painfully obvious which object is calling or executing the drive car
function or we should say the drive car method.
But on this line of code, it's not as obvious, right?
It's not like there's an object right in front of it and then a dot.
So in cases like this, when we are calling a regular old function, JavaScript essentially says, you
know what, let's say that it's the global object that is calling or executing this function.
So that's what the this keyword gets set to when the function runs.
Don't worry.
I do not expect you to fully grasp this yet.
My only goal right now is for you to just be aware that the this key word exists, that what it points
towards changes depending on the context, and that it's a source of confusion for developers of all
different skill levels, not just beginners.
In the future.
When you were creating applications, I guarantee that you're going to run into that this keyword.
And I can also guarantee that at some point your code is not going to work the way that you want it
to work.
And there's a good chance that it's because the this keyword is not pointing towards what you think
it's pointing towards.
Don't worry.
This is a concept that we can review and practice again later on in the course.
Now, really quick, before we bring this lesson to a close, I want to answer the question of why why
does this key keyword even exist?
We just spent a lot of energy trying to understand how to use it, but what about why we would use it?
So let's give ourselves a quick goal now.
Right now, we just have this one object named John.
But imagine we had 500.
And other objects that represented people in cats and dogs and imagine that we wanted to give all of
those objects a method named breathe and maybe the breathe method logs out to the console, the message
that says their name and then it says they just inhaled and exhaled.
Now, technically, we could just type out a function like we did for drive car and then copy and paste
it into all five hundred objects.
But that would be terrible code, right?
That's super repetitive.
So let me show you what else we can do.
Maybe down here.
Let's create a brand new function function.
Let's call it breathe parentheses, curly brackets.
Now if you're more experienced in programming and you're just watching these lessons as a review, you
might be screaming at the screen right now wondering why I wouldn't just use a prototype or class syntax
and inheritance.
But those are concepts that we have not gotten to yet in this course.
So bear with me.
So we've got this new function and imagine inside it we say console log.
And then to save a bit of typing, we can literally just copy and paste the code that I'm highlighting
right now.
Right.
So up in the drive car method, I'm going to highlight from this until the closing of the quote.
And then paste that into our brand new function and then for the ending part of the string, let's just
change it to say just inhaled and exhaled.
OK, so now we've got this new function named Breathe.
Now, what if we want to let our John object use the breathe function?
Right.
So we would expect it to say John Doe just inhaled and exhaled.
Well, at first glance, this function looks hopeless, right?
Because it's a stand alone function, not a method that belongs to an object.
Meaning how in the world do we expect this to point towards anything meaningful if we tried to call
or execute the breathe function down here because it's just a regular old function, JavaScript is going
to consider the global object, the object that is calling it meaning.
That's what the this keyword is going to get set to the global object.
And clearly, there's no first name and last name properties attached to the global object.
However, check this out.
Here's an example of why it's so amazing to be comfortable with this key word.
We can begin with our breathe function.
And in JavaScript, a function is an object just like any other object or entity.
And functions have access to a method named call so we can include the name of our function.
And then instead of parentheses right after it, to call it directly, we can say dot call and the call
method is going to call or execute our function, but not before first giving us a chance to control
the this keyword, meaning whatever we place inside these parentheses here call will make the this keyword
point towards that.
So if we want our John object to be able to use the breathe function, well, this function would make
a whole lot of sense if the this keyword was pointing towards John.
Right.
So down here inside the call parentheses, let's just pass in our John object.
And now if we check the console, awesome.
John Doe just inhaled and exhaled.
So maybe now you're starting to see the purpose of this keyword.
It allows our code to be flexible.
If we had another object named Jane or miaows a lot or barks a lot, we could just as easily include
that here.
And thanks to the this keyword, this function is flexible enough that it would still make sense and
work perfectly in the future.
We will learn about other situations where you use the this key word that are even ten times more useful
than this example.
OK, that's going to bring this lesson to a close.
To be fair, you probably didn't need to know this much about scope in context this early on in your
JavaScript career.
I usually try to air on the side of protecting you from complicated topics early on.
But really, I just feel like scope and context are such a common source of confusion for developers
that even if none of this makes sense right now, we at least planted the seeds in your mind and maybe
a week or two down the road, if your code is not working and you're super confused and frustrated,
maybe a little light bulb will go off in your mind and you'll go, aha, maybe it's scope that's causing
the problem or maybe it's context that's causing the problem.
And you might even need to come back and watch this lesson.
But big picture, I think you're going to be happy that you learned about these topics.
Cool.
Now, looking ahead to our next lesson, we are going to learn about miscellaneous features of the JavaScript
language that are super useful, but maybe didn't need an entire video just for themselves.
So it's going to be sort of a fun grab bag of useful tips and syntax and tricks.
It's going to be a much shorter lesson than this one, I promise you that.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.