Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to set up our first model.
Remember that in the MVC pattern, the M or model is where we enforce rules or business logic on our
data, or we could say it's where we model our data.
Now, aside from learning how to stay organized, the actual task that we're working on right now is
user registration.
So before we go ahead and create a user model file that says what a user should be, let's first make
sure that our user controller can successfully access this form data that gets submitted right.
We need to make sure that our user controller can access whatever the visitor types in for these values.
So right now, let's begin by configuring our express app so that we can easily access the user's submitted
data.
So in our text editor, begin by opening up our app JS file and maybe right above this app, use express
static public line right above that.
Let's add a couple of new lines.
Let's say app dot use and within the parentheses, let's say express dot you URL encoded and that's
a method.
So it gets its own set of parentheses to call it.
And then inside those parentheses we include an object so curly brackets and then we set a property
of extended to false.
Again, this is just a bit of boilerplate code and there's no need to memorize this.
It just tells Express to add the user submitted data onto our request object.
Right.
So then we can access it from request body while we're at it right below this line.
Let's also say app use inside the parentheses, let's say Express, DOT, JSON and another set of parentheses
to call that cool.
So now our application, except the two most common ways of submitting data on the web, a traditional
HTML form submit and also just sending over a bit of JSON data.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And now I want you to jump in to your user controller JS file.
Remember, in our previous lesson we created this register function and our router is going to call
this function.
Whenever someone submits this form right at the moment, that function simply sends back a response
that says thanks for trying to register.
Well, just as a test right above that response that send line, let's log to the console, whatever
data they submitted from that form, just as a test to make sure that we can successfully access that
data.
So let's say console the log.
And what we want to log is just request body.
OK, let's go ahead and save this file and then also make sure that your command line is visible so
that we can see the console, that log message.
OK, and now let's test this out.
So back in the browser for username.
If I say Brad for email, if I say Brad at localhost, you just type in a random password and then submit
the form.
Thanks for trying to register, but back in our command line or in the console, we see an object in
this object has three different properties username, email and password.
Cool.
And there are the values that I just typed in from the browser.
So now that we've confirmed that our controller is able to access the visitors input, our next step
is to validate this data and enforce our rules or business logic on it.
So, for example, we need to make sure that they didn't leave one of the fields blank.
We need to make sure that their password is a certain number of characters long for security reasons.
We need to make sure that their email value is a valid email address, so on and so forth.
Now, in the MVC pattern, all of those things I just listed are the responsibility of the model, not
of the controller.
Now, from a conceptual standpoint, we have a general idea of what a model is.
It's where we define the structure of our data for our user model.
It would be where we describe what a user should be.
So that's simple enough from a conceptual perspective.
But from a programming or JavaScript perspective, what would a model be?
Well, there are many different ways that we could set up a model.
But if we really think about it when we ask ourselves, what should a user be, we're probably going
to answer that question by using nouns and verbs.
And you know what lines up nicely with nouns and verbs and the JavaScript world?
I would say an object, right.
Just like nouns and verbs and object has properties and methods.
Now, in a model, in this case, our user model, we don't want to create an object.
As much as we want to create a blueprint or cookie cutter mold for an object, now, luckily for us,
JavaScript allows us to create a reusable blueprint for an object by using something called a constructor
function.
We can set up a constructor function that spells out all of the properties and methods that a user object
should have.
And we can keep that constructor function neatly tucked away in a separate file that will be our user
model.
Then within our user controller, we can simply import or require in that model file and use it as a
blueprint to create a new user object specific to the current request and user submitted data.
Remember, the idea of the MVC pattern is to create three distinct components, each with their own
responsibility.
So all of the logic that checks the incoming data for validation errors and all of the code that makes
up the blueprint of what a user should be that will live in a separate user model file.
This way, our user controller stays uncluttered and is really just a middleman, calling the appropriate
model and view commands at the appropriate times.
Now, don't worry, all of this sounds a lot more complicated than it actually is.
We're going to walk through it step by step together.
So right now, I want you to follow along with me and let's create a new folder in the root of our project
folder.
So new folder and let's name this new subfolder models.
Now, within this new models folder, I want us to create a new file.
We could name this file anything, but just so we're on the same page, let's name it user dot JS and
have it begin with an uppercase you so user.
Yes I will explain the uppercase first letter in just a few minutes.
But for now in this new empty file, typed this out with me.
Let's create a variable, let's name it user to follow along again.
That's an uppercase you and let's set it to equal an anonymous function function parentheses, curly
brackets and this will be our constructor function.
This will be the reuseable blueprint that can be used to create user objects.
In other words, we're going to want to be able to leverage this function from within our user controller
file.
So at the very, very bottom of this file, even below this closing curly bracket, let's be sure to
export this function.
So to refresh your memory, you can control what a file exports by saying module dot exports and then
just set it to equal whatever you want.
In this case, it would just be our user variable.
Now, obviously, a completely empty function isn't very useful, but for the time being, let's go
ahead and save this file, because since we've set up what it exports, that means we are ready to import
it from within our controller file.
So jump back into the user controller, DOT Jazz and up at the very, very top of this file, let's
import or require in our model so we can just say const user equals and then let's use require to pull
in that file and we're going to provide a file path.
Let's begin with dot, dot, dot, dot, slash is how you can move up one directory or folder.
Right, because this file lives within the controllers subfolder.
So we want to move up one folder out of the controllers folder.
So where our cursor is that would place us into the root of our project folder.
And then we want to look within the models folder and then we want to pull in the file named user.
All right.
Now that we've taken care of the organization factor of splitting our code into separate files, let's
get to the actual JavaScript or programming factor and learn how to create a new object using this reusable
blueprint or constructor function.
So check this out within our controller file, within our register function.
Let's get rid of this console log test line and instead let's create a variable, let's name it user.
But this time with a lowercase, you all lowercase and let's set it to equal.
And this is the interesting part, a new instance of uppercase user.
Now, this is our first time seeing the new keyword or new operator in JavaScript.
So what in the world is it doing?
Well, the oversimplified answer is that it's going to create a new object using this as its blueprint.
This is where I'll circle back to the uppercase U.
And user here.
We did not have to capitalize.
This is just a common conventional preference amongst many programmers.
To capitalize your blueprint, we capitalize the blueprint or cookie cutter mold for objects so that
it's easy to distinguish it between the actual object that we're creating.
So, for example, we could have other variables like user two equals a new instance of user and user
three equals a new instance of user.
Right?
So uppercase user is the reusable blueprint.
It doesn't need to be uppercase, but it helps us distinguish it from the actual objects that are being
created using that blueprint at this point.
Let's try spelling out our blueprint a bit.
So let's imagine, just as a silly experiment, that we want all of these user objects to have a property
named Home Planet and we would want it to have a value of Earth.
Let me show you how we could set that up.
So in our user JS model file up on line number two within the body of our constructor function, type
this out with me.
This don't worry, I will explain how the this keyword works in this context in just a minute.
But let's say this dot home planet and then just set it to equal a string of text that says Earth.
And now any object that is created using this constructor function is going to have a property named
Home Planet.
So back in our controller below these three user objects, we could say lowercase user dot home planet.
Right, and this would pull in a value of Earth and we could do the same thing for our user to object
and our user three object, right?
Any object that is created using that blueprint will have that property.
Now, let's talk about how this is working from a technical standpoint.
So let's jump back into our model file.
And in particular, let's talk about the this key word.
So back in the 10 days of JavaScript, we talked briefly about this key word back then to refresh your
memory.
We learned that this key word points towards whatever is calling or executing the current function.
So in the case of the new operator and a constructor function, let's take this line of code for an
example.
The new keyword is going to create a new empty or plain object.
And then it's essentially as if that new empty object, that's what's calling or executing the constructor
function.
So since that new object is what's calling the constructor function, the this keyword is going to be
pointing towards that new object.
So then when that function actually runs, when we say this home planet, it's like we're actually saying
the current object that is being created, dot home planet, or, for example, on this line of code,
the object that this is going to return is getting stored into our variable lowercase user.
So it's almost as if we are saying lowercase user, home planet.
And then on this line of code, when we're creating a variable named user two, it's almost as if we
are saying user to home planet so that this keyword is what allows our blueprint to be flexible.
It's how we point towards the current object that is going to get created.
OK, now, moving on.
At this point, we've seen an example of how to set up a property within our blueprint, but what about
a method?
So, for example, back in our controller, what if we wanted our blueprint to give our objects a method
named jump so we could say something like user to dot, jump and then parentheses to actually call or
execute that method?
The idea being we would want our blueprint to spell out the basic actions that are object should be
able to perform things like jump, run, walk.
So how would we set this up?
First, let's look at the obvious way and then after that we will look at the more efficient way.
So back in our model file, right below this this home planet line, we could just say this dot jump
and just set it to equal a function.
This is the obvious way to set things up and there's nothing wrong with it.
It would definitely get the job done.
And in this example case, since we're only creating three objects, there's absolutely nothing wrong
with that way of doing things.
However, what if we were creating five hundred objects using this blueprint, or what if we were creating
10000 objects using this blueprint?
Well, in that case, this would not be the ideal way of adding a method, because JavaScript is going
to create a copy or add this method to all 10000 objects that are being created.
And that's a lot of duplication.
So that's not the most efficient way from a computing standpoint.
So let's get rid of this this dot jump line.
And let me show you another way that you can add methods to your blueprint right below our constructor
function.
Let's do this.
Let's say uppercase user dot, prototype dot.
And then the name of the method in this case, we'll call it jump and then we can set that to equal
a function using this syntax.
JavaScript will not need to create a copy of this function once for each new object.
Instead, any object created using this constructor function will simply have access to this method.
So even if we created 10000 objects using our blueprint, JavaScript is not going to duplicate the jump
function.
All ten thousand objects would just point towards or have access to this one copy of the jump method,
which is much more efficient.
All right.
At this point, let's change gears.
Now that we've learned how to add both properties and methods to our object blueprint, let's get back
to the actual task at hand of user registration and validating their form field inputs.
So back in our user controller file, we do not actually need to call a fictitious jump method.
So let's get rid of that.
And we don't actually need to access a fictitious property.
Amed home planet, let's get rid of that, nor do we need to create user to or user three.
In this case, we just need one object to represent the current request.
Right.
The form that was just submitted by the current visitor also and this is important when we are creating
this new object.
Right.
When we are using the new keyword and then calling the constructor function within these parentheses,
let's pass it an argument.
Let's posit the form field values that the visitor just submitted.
So within these parentheses, let's just say request body, OK?
And then back in our user model file up on the first line of code within the parentheses for our function,
let's receive that incoming data with the parameter.
So within these parentheses, I'll make up a parameter name of data.
You could use any name for your parameter, but let's go with this just so you and I are on the same
page.
All right.
And then within the body of this function, we don't actually need a property named Home Planet, so
let's get rid of that.
And instead, let's say this DOT data equals data.
In other words, we're taking that data that just got passed in via the parameter and we're storing
it within a property that we can access again later.
Just a quick note to avoid confusion.
These names do not need to match.
This could be this dot pizza or this dot unicorn.
The idea is that we're just creating a property.
The name isn't important to store that form data that would otherwise be gone as soon as this function
finished executing.
So we are storing the user's input.
Let me put this back to data, OK?
And then down on this method, we don't actually need a method named jump, but let's just change this
to register because our user object absolutely should have a method named register.
All right, then back in our controller file, after we create our lowercase user using our constructor
function, let's just say user dot and then call our register method.
So let's go ahead and save that.
And then back in our model file within that register function before we would actually register the
user or in other words, save the user to a database, we would first want to validate their user name,
email and password values.
Or in other words, we would want to enforce all of our business logic.
And that is exactly what we're going to set up here in our very next lesson.
Just a quick note at the end here.
If you want to see an example of the new keyword and new operator and how it works with the constructor
function without the complication of splitting things up into separate files, you can check out a super
simplified code pen example that I've included a link to in the resources for this lesson.
You do not need to take a look at that example.
It's only if the new keyword is still a bit confusing and cloudy for you.
Cool.
Either way, let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.