Hello, everyone, I know in the last video, I promised that in this lesson we begin our follow feature.
However, there's one quick important security note that I do want to cover first.
OK, so in this lesson, I want to talk again about cross site scripting attacks, because in our previous
lesson, we set things up so that we are rendering user generated content.
And because we generated this HTML ourselves using template literals, we did not have a template language
like SJS automatically escaping everything for us.
So as of right now, we are in an interesting security position.
We are not actually open to cross site scripting attacks because our post model enforces its own HTML
sanitisation before accepting data into the database.
However, whenever you're generating HTML from user generated content, you want to assume the worst
on the front end.
It's a best practice to assume that somehow your back end was compromised.
Right, and there is malicious code waiting for us in the database.
This way, even in a worst case scenario, our front end still does not actually execute malicious JavaScript.
So right now, let's walk through an example.
Go ahead and create a new post right now and let's name it test post.
Give it a bit of content test.
Let's save this, OK?
And now, even if we tried to include malicious code in those fields, it wouldn't have mattered because
our post model would have sanitized it.
However, let's create a situation that assumes the worst.
So right now, I need you to jump into your Mongo DB Atlus account from collections, look in your complex
app database and then jump into the Post's collection.
If you were already on the screen, you might need to click the green find button to load the latest
posts.
But let's find that test post that we just created.
Here it is.
Now, let's assume that we are in some alternate universe where somehow malicious HTML or JavaScript
did make it into this field.
Realistically, this wouldn't happen.
But the idea is that our front end should always prepare for the worst.
So if for some reason our back wasn't doing a great job with security, at least we're not vulnerable
to front end JavaScript attacks.
So to assume the worst, let's click this pencil icon to edit this test post.
And for the title field, let's do this.
Let's rap test post within a div and on the opening div tag, let's give it an attribute of on mouse
over equals pair of quotes, use the double quotations instead of single quotations and then in the
middle let's say alert parentheses in those parentheses single quotes and let's say Moha evil J.S. here.
OK, let's go ahead and update that in the database.
OK, and now back on our Web site, if you view the individual listing for that, you are URL for that
post, we will not have our security compromised, even though this is a worst case scenario on the
back end, because this template is being rendered with the Aegis Library.
Remember, SJS is going to automatically escape values for us.
So in our code, if I look at single post screen here, is that H2 for the title?
Because we include an equal sign right here.
Ejaz is going to escape that.
So we see the code, but it's not actually going to execute.
This is a good thing.
Even if our server side validation and sanitisation fails, our front end is not actually executing
malicious JavaScript, however.
Watch this.
What if we perform a live search for test to pull in that test post?
Well, watch what happens when I hover over that title.
It actually executed that malicious JavaScript.
This is because we are generating this HTML using our own JavaScript and template literals and we're
not using a templating engine like SJS that will escape values for us.
So in situations like this where I need to sanitize HTML on the browser or front end side, I like to
leverage a package from NPM that is named Dom Purify.
Let me show you how we can use it.
So right now in our text editor, open up your command line if your server's running, let's go ahead
and stop it and run npm install.
And the name of the package that we want is Dom or Dom purify all one word.
Go ahead and press enter.
OK, now that we've installed that, let's go ahead and start our server back up again, npm run watch,
OK, and let's jump into our search dogs front end JavaScript file up at the very top where we are already
importing axios.
Let's also import that new domme purify package.
So let's say import domme purify from quotes.
And the actual name of the package was lowercase dom purify.
OK, now let's go leverage this within our render results HTML method.
So let's scroll down.
OK, here's our render results html.
This is where we are creating that template literal for all of the HTML.
Here's what I want you to do.
Begin selecting this opening back tick and select all the way down until the closing div and closing
back tick.
Let's go ahead and cut that into our clipboard.
So now we just have this, this dot results area in our HTML equals blink.
Well, now let's just use our DOM Purify package and look inside it for a method named sanitize parentheses
to call sanitize and then we can just pass it in our clipboard.
So paste and that's all we need to do.
The Dom Purify package will automatically remove any malicious code that could create a cross site scripting
attack.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now back on the front end if we refresh.
And if I perform a search for test, pull in that post, notice that now when I hover over that title,
nothing happens.
You'll notice that the title is still sitting on a different line from the Avatar.
This is because the Dom Purify package does not remove all HTML.
So remember we added a div tag around that title.
The Dom Purify package is not going to remove the div itself.
It's just going to remove any potentially malicious places where JavaScript could be being executed.
Technically we could use the HTML sanitised package on the front end instead of dom purify.
However, that package is over 600 kilobits on minified, whereas Dom Purify is only about 40 kilobits
on minified.
And since this is browser based, our front end JavaScript, we're needing to send those libraries to
the front end to download.
So in this case, I'm a big fan of Dom Purify.
Remember, this is just our last line of defense.
Our server will already be removing any HTML from the content.
We had to artificially go into the database to create an absolutely worst case scenario.
And Dom Purifies still protected us from any actual cross site scripting attacks taking place.
Cool.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson.
We will indeed begin working on the following feature.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.