Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to work on creating a user profile screen, so, for example, when you're
logged in, you would always be able to click on your profile photo in the top right to visit your profile,
or if you're looking at a post created by someone else, you would also see their author name listed
here and you could click on that link to go to their profile visually.
A profile screen should look something like this.
So for our first step in this lesson, let's create a new Ejaz template to create this interface.
Now, again, we're not going to type this HTML out by hand.
Let's just copy and paste it.
As always, you can look within our repository under complex app and HTML templates.
And right now we are interested in the template named profile dash posts dot html to open that up and
then you can click raw and we're not interested in the header or footer, we just want the unique middle
portion of the code.
So find where it says header ends here and only begin selecting right below that line and select until
you see this message that says footer begins.
Just select right before that begins.
OK, let's copy that into our clipboard and then in our text editor within our Views folder, let's
create a new file.
Let's name this file profile Dot Aeger.
Yes.
Go ahead and paste in your clipboard up at the very, very top of this file.
Let's add a new line and let's include our header.
So it's less than percentage Dasch include and look in the includes folder for the file named header.
Let's close out this dynamic tag.
Let's just copy and paste this so we can do the same thing for the footer.
Copy that down at the very bottom, pasted in and change header to footer.
OK, let's go ahead and save this.
And now let's talk about what you r-al you should be able to visit a user's profile from.
So for example for posts we said slash post, slash whatever post you're looking for, how about four
profiles, its slash profile slash and then their username.
So to set that up, let's jump into our router file.
So within the root of our project, let's open up router JS.
I suppose we could say a user profile screen would fall under a user related route, but just to stay
organized, maybe under that we could create a separate comment and say profile related routes under
this new comment.
Let's say router, dot git and for the route, let's say slash profile slash and then to make something
dynamic we can say colon and then we can make up a name, let's call it user name.
OK, then after the closing quote, let's include a comma and include a function that we want to run
for this route.
Let's actually list two functions here.
So first, let's dig into our user controller.
And this function doesn't exist yet, but we can create it very shortly and let's call it if user exists.
OK, then let's include a comma and then we would want to run another function, let's say user controller
DOT.
And again, this function doesn't exist yet, but let's imagine profile posts screen.
All right, let's go ahead and save this file.
And now we better go into our user controller and create these matching function names.
So if user exists and profile posts screen so within our controllers folder, let's open up user controller
dot js.
Let's scroll down to the bottom and let's create a new function.
So exports dot if user exists and let's set that to equal a function within the parentheses for this
function.
Let's not only include request and response, but also include next within the body of this function.
For now, let's just immediately call next.
So essentially at this moment this function is completely pointless.
But a bit later in this lesson, we will circle back to this and actually do something interesting and
worthwhile before calling next.
For the time being, let's create another function in this file.
So down here, let's say exports dot.
Profile posts screen, and let's set that to equal a function within the parentheses for this function,
it only needs request and response.
OK, and then in the body of this function, let's just render our new profile template.
So response render in the name of that was simply profile.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in the browser, if I visit a U rl of localhost, call in three thousand slash profile slash
and then just choose random characters.
Cool.
We see that new template.
Now obviously this is all just fake, hard coded data at the moment.
So the question becomes, how do we pull in real relevant data for whichever user you're looking for?
Well, let's divide that task up into two parts.
That's why I had us create two different functions.
So first, within our if user exist function, let's get rid of this next call so we have a clean slate
again.
And let's begin by pretending our uppercase user model has a function named find by user name.
OK, and then we would pass that the user name that's included at the end of the current U.
RL.
So to get that ending U.
RL segment, we can just say request forams dot username.
Now we have not set up this function yet within our user model, but you can imagine that when we do
in just a couple of moments, we can set it up so that it returns a promise.
So if this is going to return a promise, then at the end of it we can just say dot then dot catch within
both the then and catch parentheses.
Let's provide functions.
So function parentheses, curly brackets, dropdown within catch function, parentheses, curly brackets.
OK, now if our promise resolves we can set it up so that it resolves with the value of the user document
that it found in the database that matches the requested username that would get passed into this function.
So let's receive it with a parameter here and say user document.
And then within this function, let's store that user document that we just found based on username.
Let's store it somewhere so that the next function for this route can access it.
So what we can do is just create a new property on the request object.
We could name this whatever we want, but let's name it profile user and just set that to equal the
document that we just found.
So user document, OK, right after this line then we can call next.
OK, and what about the catch.
Well if this find by username promis rejects or fails, that means there is no matching user in our
database.
So what we'd want to do here is just render a 404 or page not found screen.
So response dot render and let's choose the 404 template.
Let's save this.
But before we test it out, let's go and do our user model and create a function with this name find
by user name.
So within our models folder, let's jump in to uppercase user J.
Yes, let's scroll down to the bottom.
And right before this closing module dot exports equals user line right above that, let's say uppercase
user.
And we're not taking an object oriented approach here, so we don't need to add it to the prototype.
We can literally just say uppercase user dot find by user name.
Let's set this to equal a function within the parentheses for this function.
Let's include a parameter, let's name it user name.
Right.
Because our controller is going to pass in whatever username is at the end of the euro.
OK, now within the body of this function, we want it to return a promise.
So return new promise within these parentheses.
We want to be sure to include, resolve and reject, OK, within the body of this function, let's first
check to make sure that whatever is getting passed in as the username, let's make sure that it's just
a string of text.
If a malicious user tried to pass in an object, we would not want to pass that on to Mongo DB.
So let's say if parentheses curly brackets within the if let's say if type of username if that does
not equal a string, well then in the if block we would just immediately want to reject.
And also after that we'd want to return to prevent the further execution of this function.
OK, but below the closing of this block.
Well, we know that that username is just an innocent string of text, so let's go ahead and query our
database to see if there's a matching username document so we can use our users collection object.
And let's look inside it and call its find one method.
Within these parentheses.
We include an object and we tell Mongo DB what we're trying to find.
So we would want to document where the user name field matches whatever username value was at the end
of the URL.
So username.
Now we know that this Mongo DB method is going to return a promise.
So at the end of this line, let's just say dot then dot catch.
Let's provide functions within both of those sets of parentheses.
So that's then let's do the same thing for ketch include a function.
Now if this Mongo DB method rejects, that does not mean that it couldn't find a matching document.
That means that it actually ran into some sort of error.
If that's the case, let's just reject technically, this wouldn't be rejecting because we couldn't
find a user ID be rejecting for some sort of unexpected technical error or database connection problem.
But as far as the end users of our application are concerned, they can just see a 404 screen for the
time being.
OK, but if the Mongo DB operation is successful and resolves well, it would resolve with the data
it found.
So potentially a document so we can receive that within these then function parentheses.
Let's include a parameter and call it user doc, OK.
And then within the body of this function, let's just write an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets at the end of the if closing bracket, let's also include an else block
and let's say if user doc exists, if it's not empty, well then we would want our promise to resolve
or else if it couldn't find a matching user we would want to reject.
Now on this line where we resolve, we'd actually want to resolve with a value within these parentheses,
because if we successfully found a user, our controller is going to want to save that user data onto
the request object so that we can use it later to actually display the profile user's user name and
their avatar and also know their IDs so that we can find posts written by them.
Now, we could just resolve with the entire user document, but that contains information like their
password.
And even though that password value is hashed, I like to make it a practice of not letting my model
unnecessarily leak out or expose data that I really don't want it to into the controller.
So what I'm going to do right above this resolve line, still within the if block, I'm just going to
customize or clean up that user document.
So let's say user doc equals a new instance of our user blueprint.
Passed it in user doc.
Let's give it a second argument of true.
So this way we're taking that raw data from the database that has fields like username and email, and
we're using that to create a new user document and we're feeding that into our user blueprint and saying
true.
So remember, that's going to automatically get the avatar based on their email address.
OK, now after this, let's also say user doc equals and let's just spell out an object bit by bit.
So this way we aren't passing the password or any other data into our controller.
So what would we want this to have?
Well, we'd want it to have an underscore I.D. so that later on in this request, we can look up posts
by this user.
So we could just say user doc dot data, dot underscore ID click, comma.
We'd also want it to include their username.
So username, Kolan user data, dot user name, and we'd want it to include an Avatar property.
So user dog dot avatar.
Cool.
So now these are the only three properties that will get passed back into the controller.
So within resolve parentheses just include user dog.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in the browser, if you visit a new RL of slash profile slash and then if this ending part is
not a user name that exists in your database, we should see some sort of error message.
Yep.
Whoops.
We cannot find that page.
But if you do just this ending, you are segments to be a username that does exist in my case.
Brad cool.
We see the profile template, OK, and now let's just begin pulling in real data.
Instead of this fake hardcoded content to work on this, let's jump back into our user controller.
So end user controller this if user exists, function is done for now.
Let's focus on profile posts screen.
So on this line of code where we are rendering the profile template within these parentheses, let's
give it a second argument and it's going to be an object of data that we pass into that template.
Feel free to drop down in between these curly brackets for organization reasons, OK?
And we can make up any property names we want.
So for example, let's say profile user name should have a value of and this is where we can leverage
that data from our previous function because we stored it on the request object.
So down here we can just say.
Request profile user dot username.
OK, let's do the same thing for their Avatar profile, Avatar should have a value of request.
Dot profile user dot avatar.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now let's jump into that profile, the Aegis template, and actually use these values.
So within our Views folder, let's jump in to profile DOT SJS.
Around line number four, you'll see an opening heading level to tag.
It contains an image element and we are interested in the source value for the image.
Let's get rid of this existing Eurail for the photo and instead let's do something dynamic so less than
a percentage equal sign.
Let's close out that tag percentage greater then and then let's just say profile avatar.
Just to the right of this, we see a hardcoded value for the username.
So get rid of that.
And instead we'd want to say less than percentage equal sign.
Close that out in between profile username.
Let's save this and test it out back in the browser.
When I refresh, I don't see any difference because the fake hardcoded values were already set to Brad
and my face.
However, you likely see new values now to demonstrate this.
If I go up into the address bar and if I visit the profile for Bark's a lot behind the scenes, I created
a new user account for a dog.
Cool.
So it pulls in the user name and photo for the current profile that we're visiting.
Feel free to jump in to an incognito window and create alternate accounts so you can test this out as
well.
Let me go back to the Brad profile and our next step would be to load in the posts that this author
has created.
And that's exactly what we're going to work on when we continue this lesson in the next video.
So let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.