Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to work on letting a user update or edit one of their existing posts.
Without further ado, let's jump into the action.
OK, so from the home page, assuming you're logged in, let's set things up so that you can click on
your profile photo in the top right to go to your profile.
That way, we don't need to go up to the address bar and manually type in profile and then slash your
username.
So to set up this link, let's jump into our text editor and within our views folder, let's open up
the includes subfolder and then jump into header SJS around line number 22 will see an opening, a element.
You'll know it's the right element if it contains an image with the title of my profile.
So on the opening, a tag for the ref just change it from this hash tag to slash profile slash and then
let's do something dynamic so less than percentage equal sign and then close that out percentage greater
than in between, let's just say user dot user name.
OK, let's go ahead and save that.
And now back on the home page, if you refresh, you can simply click that to go to your profile.
Cool.
Now let's visit one of our existing posts.
OK, now, before we actually set things up so that clicking on this blue edit button takes you to an
edit screen, let's first adjust things so that only the author or owner or creator of this post would
see these edit or delete buttons.
For example, if I visit this same you URL in an incognito window or in a different browser entirely.
So this is Mozilla Firefox where I'm not logged in as any account I should be able to visit that you
are well and see the post content, right.
The post itself should be publicly viewable, but I should not see these edit or delete buttons.
It only makes sense for the actual creator or owner of this particular post to see those.
So in order to set up that restriction or that bit of logic, let's go to the controller that is powering
this route.
So back in our text editor, look inside our controllers folder and jump into post controller Dot JS
towards the bottom.
We have a function named View single.
Now, here's the important part.
When we call our post model and ask it to find a single post by a certain ID.
Well, if we just include a second argument within these parentheses, that argument being the user
ID of the current visitor, then our model will have all of the data it needs to determine if that user
ID is the same.
User ID is the author for a given post.
Now, if the current visitor is a guest, meaning they're not logged into any account, then obviously
they will not have a user ID.
So to set things up in a reusable and fail proof way, let's do this.
Let's set up a piece of code that will run at the start of every request and it will check to see if
the current visitor has a user object in session data.
If they do, we can grab their user ID.
If they don't, we'll just consider their user ID to be zero and that zero can signify that their guest.
So to set up something that will run for every request, let's jump into our main app, JS file within
app that just for me it's around line number eighteen or right below the area where we set up session
in Flash.
You'll see that we've already created a function that's going to run for every request.
It begins with app use and then we have this function that's going to take the current user session
object and make that available within response that locals meaning so we can access it from our templates.
Well, since this function is going to run for every request, we can just write a bit of additional
code within it.
Let's add a comment here just to stay organized and let's describe what we're doing on this line.
Slash slash for a comment.
Let's say make user session data available from within view templates.
OK, now above this.
Let's write another comment and let's say make current user ID available on the request object.
OK, now all we need to do is write an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets, let's say if request session user.
If that exists then within the curly brackets, let's say request and let's make up a new property that
we're going to add to the request object.
Let's call it visitor ID.
And we would set that to request session users underscore ID at the end of this line after the closing
curly bracket, let's add an else block and say else.
Otherwise, let's set request visitor I.D. to equal zero.
Cool.
So now, no matter which control or function we're in, we can reliably know that there's going to be
a visitor ID property on the request object.
If the users logged in, it will be their actual ID.
If they're not logged in, it will just be a zero.
Let's go ahead and save this and then jump back into our post comptroller.
OK, within our view, single function, when we are leveraging our post model and telling it to find
a post, let's just give it a second argument here.
So right after a request up Ramsgate ID, let's say Kamma and then just say request dot visitor id cool.
At this point, our post model has everything it needs to determine if the visitor is the owner or author
of a post.
We're telling you which post to look up for the current You URL and we're also telling it the current
visitor ID.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now let's jump in to our post model.
So within our models folder, jump in to post JS.
So our controller is calling a model function named Find Single by I.D. So let's scroll down in our
model to find that function.
Here it is, upper case post finds single by Idy now ultimately this function is leveraging our reuseable
post query function.
So let's do this within this outermost function named Find single by Idy within its parentheses, let's
add a second parameter to receive the incoming visitor ID.
OK then when we use our reuseable post query function, the first argument is an array of aggregate
options.
But we can just provide a second argument.
That's the visitor ID.
So right after this closing square bracket to close out that array or first argument we can say comma
visitor ID.
OK, now let's just go into our reuseable post query function and actually leverage that visitor ID.
So if we scroll up, we're looking for the area that begins with uppercase post dot reuseable post query
within this function's parentheses.
Let's receive that incoming visitor I.D. So comma visitor I.D. And now if we scroll down to this area
where we see posts equals post dot map within this map function, we're already filtering the data or
customizing it a bit.
So I think this would be a great place to add on a property onto the post named is visiter owner.
And then we can just check to see if the Post author ID matches that passed in Visitor ID.
Let me show you what I have in mind.
So right above this line where we say post dot author equals an object right above that.
Still within our map function.
Let's say post DOT is visitor owner, OK, and for now let's just set that to equal a temporary placeholder
X and we can circle back to this in just a moment.
Really, what we need to pull in here is the author ID for the current post.
However, up in our aggregate operations, we already changed what the author property is ultimately
going to return, right?
Originally it did contain the author ID, but we changed things here so that it's going to be the object
for the related user to get around this.
What we can do maybe right after this created date line, we can just add a new line and say Author
I.
D So I just made up this property name and then we can just give it a value of quotes.
Dollar Sign author.
Be sure to end this line with a comma in Mongo DB.
If you include a dollar sign within quotes, it knows that you're talking about that actual field,
not a literal string of text.
So I'm just making up a new property that's going to have that original authorized value.
So now we can leverage that down on this line within our post dot map area where we are saying post
dot is visitor owner should equal and then we want this to either be a true or false value.
Well, check this out.
Instead of the X, we can just say post dot author.
I said this will be a Mongo DB Object ID.
We can look inside it and call a method that it has named equals in these parentheses.
We can just give it something that we want to compare it against.
So let's just use that Pastan visitor ID.
Cool.
Now this equals method is going to return either a value of true or false.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
What I mean by that is let's jump into the Edge's template that powers this screen.
What we can do is around these two edit and delete buttons.
We can wrap them within an if statement.
We can just say if post DOT is visiter owner only.
If that's true, then display these.
So within our editor, let's look in our views folder and let's jump into the file that is named single
dash post.
Dash screen within single post screen on a round line number six or write below this heading level two
with the title.
We see a span element.
I want you to go ahead and select that span down until the closing span tag and cut that into your clipboard.
OK, now let's do something dynamic.
Let's write an if statement.
So less than a percentage percentage greater, then let's just use an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition, we can just say post DOT is visiter owner.
Right.
Is the current visitor the owner or creator of this post at the end of this line, let's be sure to
drop out of Ejaz dynamic mode.
And then at the start of this line, let's.
Dropped back into dynamic mode and now on this line, we can just paste in our clipboard.
OK, let's go ahead and save that.
And now in the window where I am logged in as the bride account by refresh.
Cool, I still see the edit and delete icons, but back in the window where I'm not logged in, if I
refresh, they're gone.
Also if I log in with my Bachs slot account.
And then view that same post created by the browed account.
Cool, the system knows that, yes, I'm logged in, but I'm not logged in with the account that authored
or created this post.
And aside from just visually hiding those icons, we can reuse that.
Same is visiter owner property when it comes to the routes that will actually let you edit and delete
a post.
But before we get to that, let's set up the ref or link value for this edit button.
Right.
The question is, if a user clicks on this, what you URL should it take them to?
Well, let's jump back into our text editor.