Hello, everyone, welcome back to the 10 days of JavaScript, here we are in day number 10, the finale
of this first chapter.
And in this lesson, we are going to finally move from theoretical to practical or from abstract to
concrete.
I want to begin by showing you the finished product of what we are going to build together in this lesson.
So we've got a headline here to do that.
And then we have a form or input field which I can type into feed cat, submit it.
It gets added to this need to do list and I can add a few others.
So by carrots, walk dog wash car.
And now if I want to get rid of one, maybe by Carrot's, maybe I completed that task, I can just click
the delete button for that one and it's gone.
Now clearly this app is very simple, right?
There's not a whole lot going on here.
However, it gives us enough to sink our teeth into for us to really learn a lot about front end JavaScript
and working with the Web browser.
So without further ado, let's jump right into the action.
Go ahead and create a brand new code pen.
And instead of JavaScript, let's actually begin with a bit of HTML.
Let's begin by creating a heading level, one that reads to do app.
And just a quick note that I want to keep the focus in this course on JavaScript instead of HTML.
Now, even if you've never worked with HTML before, the syntax is fairly simple.
So you might be able to just follow along with me and have it somewhat make sense.
But if it's super confusing, you might just want to pause this lesson and go search Google or YouTube
for a quick HTML beginner guide.
You don't need to do that preemptively.
I would only do that if the HTML is making zero sense to you and you're super confused.
OK, let's keep the train rolling.
So after the heading level one, let's create a form element.
So opening tag, closing tag inside this forum, let's give it two things, a text input field for the
user to type into and then a button that they can click on to submit the form.
So to create the field, we can just say input.
Let's give it a type of text.
I'm also going to set its autocomplete to off just because I don't like the annoying little pop up on
the field that tries to suggest things that you've typed in the past.
OK, next, let's include the button that the user clicks so button and let's have the button read create
item.
OK, and then finally below the form down here, let's create a heading level three that reads need
to do.
And while we're at it, let's also add a bullet hit list with a few hard coded example items.
So you go for unordered list and a quick code pen HTML tip.
You can actually just type the name of the tag you want without any of the less than and greater than
symbols and then push tab on your keyboard and it automatically does that for you.
OK, inside the unordered list, let's create a couple of list items.
Ultimately, we want the user to create these.
We don't want to preemptively hardcoded them, but let's just do this to give ourselves something to
work with.
So I will say buy carrots and then we want to include a button here that says delete.
And I'm just going to copy and paste this a few times just so we have something to look at.
So maybe buy apples by lettuce.
OK, now all together, this HTML should look something like this in the Web browser, right?
So this is our basic user interface for the app.
Now, when a user visits the app, we don't want there to actually already be items like this.
We would expect this to be empty and then the user would use the input form to add the items.
So big picture, it's the job of HTML to display content on the Web page, but HTML on its own just
sort of sits there and doesn't move or do anything.
So it's the job of JavaScript to make this come to life.
So where should we begin with our JavaScript?
Well, I think we should focus on our form input now before we jump right into the JavaScript column
and start coding, let's first adjust our HTML to give the form element a unique identifier.
In other words, we need some sort of way to hook on to this form in JavaScript.
So in our HTML on this opening form tag, we can just give it an ID.
So maybe say ID equals the name doesn't really matter, but I'm just going to choose our form.
The idea here is that now we can search for the element that has this ID over in our JavaScript.
So now let's switch gears and go into the JavaScript column.
Now, in the past, we've learned about the document object, which represents the Web pages, content
and abilities, and in the past, when we want it to be on the lookout for an event, we would use add
event listener write, this is how we would listen for click events.
However, in this case, we don't want to use our event listener for the Web page as a whole, so we
don't want to use it directly on the document object.
Instead, we want to select just that one particular form element.
So check this out.
Over in our JavaScript we can say document dot get element by IDE for the argument.
We just give it the IDs.
So we called it our form.
And this method is going to return an object that represents that HTML form element.
Now, since that's what this method is going to return, we could just add a dot here and say add event
listener all on one line like that.
But instead what I like to do is save the object.
This is going to return into a variable.
So at the beginning of this line we could say let our form equal the object that this is going to return
this way.
Our koja stays a little bit easier to read.
So then on a brand new line, we can say our form and then we want to add an event listener.
So add event listener.
And just as a quick test, because we are familiar with it, let's pass it click.
And then remember, the second argument is the function that you want to run when this event happens.
So let's just include an anonymous function here or even one step better.
Why don't we use an arrow function so parentheses and then the arrow symbol and then curly brackets
and we can drop down inside the curly brackets.
And just as a test, when someone clicks anywhere on the form, let's show an annoying alert pop up
message that says thanks for clicking the form.
OK, now let's test out our code if we come down to the preview area, notice that if I click somewhere
random on the Web page, like the heading level one title, nothing happens.
But if I click onto the form, we see the alert.
Awesome.
I think you can already see that adding an event listener to a particular element instead of the document
as a whole.
This already opens up so many doors.
Now, we don't actually want anything to happen when the user simply clicks onto the form.
So instead, the event that we want to be on the lookout for is actually called submit.
So up in our JavaScript code, instead of click here, let's get rid of that and say submit.
So any time the user submits this form, we want to do something in response.
However, the default behavior of a Web browser, when you submit a form, is that it's going to try
to send that data off somewhere.
In this case, we want to handle things completely from within our JavaScript.
So we don't want the Web browser to try and send the data anywhere.
So what we can do within the parentheses for our function here, let's include a parameter.
I'm going to call it E, but you could name it whatever you want.
OK, and then inside the body of our function, we want to look inside that parameter.
Now, I named it E because the ADD event listener method is going to pass our function.
A bunch of information about the event that just happened.
So the E is short for event, but basically down here in our code we want to say e dot prevent default
and parentheses to call the method.
I realize this is a bit confusing and not very intuitive.
It's just one of the intricacies of the Web browser that we have to deal with.
Right.
Its default behavior is to try and refresh or reload the Web page and send that data off somewhere.
We don't want that to happen.
So we are just preventing it.
OK, now let's check out our app again.
So now I'm free to click onto the form and nothing happens.
But as soon as I tried to submit it, awesome.
We see our alert.
OK, now, next, we don't actually want to show this annoying pop up.
So when the user submits the form, what we really want to do is grab the value of whatever they typed
into this field and then add it as a new item into the list.
So we are going to need to be able to access this input field from within our JavaScript.
So let's go into our HTML and give it a unique ID so we have something to hook on to.
So back up in our HTML column.
Here is the input that lives in our form and maybe right after the word input, let's give it an I.D.
and you could come up with any name you want, but I'm going to call it our field, OK, our field.
So then over in our JavaScript, just like we did with the form, remember, we created a variable that
stored the object that represents that HTML element.
Let's do the same thing for our field.
So up here, I'm going to say let our field equal document get element by ID and it had an idea of our
field.
OK, now inner function that runs when the form gets submitted instead of this annoying alert pop up.
Let's get rid of that.
And just as a test, let's log out to the console, whatever the user has typed in to that input field.
Right.
We want to practice accessing the user's input so we know that that field is represented by this our
field object.
So we can just say our field and in the Web browser, the object that represents that form field has
a property so we can look inside the object for the property named value.
Let's test this out.
So back on our Web page, be sure to open up your console if I type into this field.
Hello there.
And submit awesome in the console.
We see.
Hello there.
Now, we don't actually want to just log it to the console.
What we really want to do is add a new item to the bulleted list.
So why don't we go into our HTML and give this unordered list and ID so that we can hook on to it from
within our JavaScript.
So in the HTML down towards the bottom.
Remember, the bulleted list is contained in this unordered list element.
So on the opening you'll tag to say ID equals the name I'm going to choose is our list.
OK, so we can hook on to this in our JavaScript.
So back in our JS code, up at the top, let's create an object that represents that unordered list
element.
So let our list equal document, get elements by ID our list.
OK, now we could write the necessary code right within this arrow function, but I want to stay organized
so that at the very bottom of our code, let's create a brand new function and name it create item.
The name doesn't matter.
That's just what I'm going with.
So parentheses curly brackets.
OK, now up in our arrow function, instead of logging to the console that value that the user typed
in instead, why don't we just pass it to our new function?
So instead of console log, let's just say create item.
OK, now if we are passing this as an argument into the function, we want to be able to receive it
as a parameter.
So in our create item function, let's just include an X or something easy to type for the parameter.
OK, now here's the fun part in the body of this function.
Let's select our our list object.
Remember, this object represents that bulleted list and then let's look inside it and call a method
named insert adjacent HTML.
So we give this method to arguments, the first argument is where in the element do we want to add the
new bit of content?
Well, I would expect that a new item gets added to the very end of the list.
So in our code for the first argument, I'm going to say before and and then the second argument is
just the content or HTML that you want to add to this element.
So we could just say a string of text that says hello or some sort of test, but instead we know that
we can just include our parameter here.
Right, because this parameter represents whatever the user typed into the field.
Right.
Because that's what we're passing into our function.
So for the second argument, I'm just going to say X..
Now, let's test this out.
So if we come down to our app, I will type in, wash my car and then submit the form.
Awesome gets added to the end of our list.
Now, it doesn't look quite right.
And that's because we need to wrap it in Elai Tag, just like we did with the other elements.
So let's actually go back into our HTML.
And we don't need these anymore, right?
We want the list to be empty when the user comes to the app, but why don't we copy and paste one of
them as an example to save ourselves a bit of typing in the JavaScript?
So I'm just going to copy the first one, copy that into my clipboard, and then we can get rid of all
of these hard coded items, but keep the empty, hollowed out unordered list, OK?
And then back in our JavaScript, down in our create item function instead of just X.
So instead of just literally adding the word that the user typed, we want to add a bit of HTML.
So here's what I'm going to do inside this function, right above this line.
Let's create a variable and call it our HTML.
The name doesn't matter.
That's just what I'm picking.
And then let's create a template literal so to back ticks inside the template, literal.
Let's just paste in our clipboard.
So this is the template for an item and then let's hollow out by carrot's.
We don't want it to be hard coded to that.
We want to do something dynamic, so in a template literal, you can say dollar sign, curly brackets,
and that is where we would pull in the X parameter, whatever the user typed in.
OK, so now we have this HTML template for the new item.
We saved it into this variable.
So down here, instead of adding X into that unordered list, let's just add our our HTML variable like
this nice little template.
So let's test this out down in our app.
Let's say feed cat, submit the form.
Awesome.
There it is.
Create another one by carrot's.
Perfect.
Let's do two more things.
First, let's set it up so that when you submit this form, it erases the current item that you've typed.
Right.
Because if we successfully added by carrot's to the list, we don't need that in the field anymore.
We want to be able to just type a new item in instead of having to select it and delete it.
And then after we set that up, let's also make it so that when you click the delete button for one
of these, something actually happens.