Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to learn how to update an existing database item or document.
So, for example, what if the user wanted to change this existing by graps item to instead, say,
buy two bags of grapes today?
Well, before we even worry about how to write a. code that will talk to the Mongo DB database and actually
update this document, we need to first take care of the user interface or user experience question
of how and where do we give the user a new place to begin typing their updated desired text?
If we want it to use what we already know, we can set things up so that when you click on this edit
button, it takes you to a new page and you URL specifically for this document and that new page.
And you would have a form and a text field that you could type into and then you could submit that form.
But taking the user to an entirely different page just for a simple task like typing in a new value
does not seem like the pinnacle of interface design and user experience.
So instead of setting things up like that, let's learn something new in this lesson.
Now, up until this point, the only way that we've known how to have the Web browser send user typed
in data to our server is by submitting a form.
But there's actually another way.
So if we write a bit of JavaScript for the Web browser environment, we can actually program the browser
to send data and requests to our server behind the scenes or on the fly without a hard page, refresh
or reload or redirect.
Now, this technology of being able to send seemless on the fly requests without a reload or form submit
has absolutely nothing to do with databases.
But this is a great time to learn about this new technique.
So this lesson is actually going to be broken up into two videos in this first video.
Our goal is to handle the user interface aspect and just get the user's new text value sent over to
our node server.
All right.
Then in our next video in part two, we will actually use our node server to update that document in
the Mongo DB database.
OK, now let's jump into the action for this video.
And we want to begin by writing JavaScript code for the Web browser environment, not the node environment.
So let's jump into our text editor and within our server JS file, let's find the HTML template that
we are sending back to the browser for the home page.
You are out towards the bottom of this HTML template.
We will see a closing body tag now right before or above that body tag.
Let's add a new line and say script for an opening script tag and then let's close the script tag.
And now in between this tag pair, we can include JavaScript designed for the web browser environment
and it will execute it right.
So just as a test, we could create an annoying alert pop up message so we could stay alert and then
parentheses to call the alert method.
And let's include quotes in a string of text says hello, OK, let's save this file just to test it
out.
OK then back in the browser, if I refresh, you can see that annoying.
Hello alert pop up.
Cool.
So technically this works.
We can include JavaScript for the web browser environment right here.
But in order for us to stay mentally organized, I think we should create an entirely separate file
for our browser based JavaScript.
That way we don't get confused.
Right.
So we can have server GSB for our server based code and we can have a file named Browser ARGs for our
browser based code.
So let's do this in between the opening and closing script tag.
Delete this code.
But on the opening script tag, let's include an attribute and say SIRC for source and then say equals
and then quotes in between the quotes.
Let's point towards forward slash which is the root of the server, and then let's just point towards
a non-existent file named browser JS and we will create this new file in just a minute or two.
Now, there's nothing special about the name of this file.
You could have chose Pizza, Jass or Unicorn Doorjambs.
The idea is that we're just telling the browser to load a file that lives at this location and file
name.
OK, now, before we actually create this file, we need to recognize that by default, visitors of
our website or web application do not have access to the root of our folder.
So we don't want to just create browser JS right here.
Instead, let's create a new subfolder within our project folder and then we can give special permissions
to that folder.
Let me show you what I.
I mean, so within our overall project folder that contains our server and package that Jason just create
a new subfolder and let's name it public, technically the name doesn't matter, but just go with public.
So you and I are on the same page.
OK, now, within that public folder, that's where we want to create our new JavaScript file.
So I'm going to right.
Click on the public folder and click new file, let's name it browser J.S..
And within this brand new empty file, just as a test, let's alert out, pop up.
That says hello from browser, James.
Let's give that to save, OK?
And now we just need to tell our Express app or server to allow incoming requests to have access to
the public folder and its contents.
So back in server, just scroll up to the very top and let's do this maybe right below this.
Let DB line.
Let's add a new line and say app dot use call the use method inside the parentheses, let's say express
dot and then call a method named Statik.
This is how we can serve up static existing files.
So within these parentheses we just include the name of our folders of quotes and we named it public.
This will make the contents of that folder available from the root of our server.
Let's go ahead and save that.
And now if we refresh in the Web browser, cool.
We see hello from browser.
James, now that we have that set up for our first actual bit of business, let's use JavaScript to
tell the Web browser to listen for the event that one of the edit buttons is clicked on.
So in our text editor, let's jump into the new browser JS file and let's get rid of this alert test
line so we have a clean slate and write this out with me.
Let's begin with the overall document object and then let's look inside it and call a method named ad
event listener.
We're going to give this to arguments.
So a comma B for the first argument instead of this a placeholder, we are interested in the click event
for the second argument.
This is a function that we want to run when this event happens.
So instead of B, let's create an anonymous function, function, parentheses, curly brackets.
Now, we did not specify which element we are listening for clicks on.
We just said the entire page or document.
Now, if we want to listen for only clicks on these edit buttons instead of just clicking anywhere,
even an empty space, we can do this within the parentheses for our function here.
We can include a parameter.
Let's just call it E for event.
The name of this parameter doesn't really matter.
But now within the body of our function, we can use this.
So let's write out an if statement and say if parentheses curly brackets inside the parentheses for
our if statement.
Let's say only if and then say e dot target.
This E parameter contains all sorts of information about the event that just took place and we can look
inside it for the target property and that's going to be the HTML element that actually got clicked
on.
Now after target we can say dot class list DOT contains and contains is a method, so parentheses to
call contains.
Now in between these parentheses we can say quotes and let's type out edit me.
So all together we're saying only if the element that was actually clicked on contains a class of edit
me do we want our code here to actually run.
OK, now within the body of our IF statement here, just as a test, why don't we alert a pop up message
that says you clicked the edit button.
OK, let's go ahead and save that and then let's jump in the browser and refresh now when I click one
of the edit buttons.
Awesome.
We see that alert, you click the edit button and this will work for any of the edit buttons, but we
don't actually want to display an annoying alert pop up.
Instead, what we actually want to do is give the user a place where they can type in a new value.
So back in our editor, let's actually get rid of this alert line.
And in its place, let's call a Web browser function named prompt within the parentheses for prompt.
We can give it a string of text and let's say enter your desired new text.
OK, let's save that and test it out.
So be sure to refresh back in the Web browser.
And now when I click on one of the edit buttons.
Cool, we see enter your desired new text and there's a place where we can type.
However, right now, even if I click on the OK button that.
Value is not being stored anywhere, so let's do this back in our ED at the beginning of this prompt
line, let's say let and then a space and let's make up a variable name.
I will call it user input and then a space and say equals and a space.
So we're just saving whatever the user types in from this prompt into this variable.
We can make sure this is working by maybe dropping down on a new line still within the body of our IF
statement.
And let's just log that variable to the console console log.
The name of the variable is user input.
Let's go ahead and save that.
And back in the browser, be sure to refresh.
And when we said console that log, that is the Web browsers console, not the no JS server console.
So be sure to open up your browsers console.
Right.
Click and choose, inspect and then click console.
OK.
Now if I click on one of the edit buttons and maybe say testing, one, two, three, four or five and
hit.
OK, back in the browser console we see the value that the user typed in.
Now we don't actually want to log this value to the browsers console.
What we actually want to do is send this value to our node server.
Now, this is going to be one of the aha moments of becoming a JavaScript developer because we can actually
tell the Web browser to send a request to our server without submitting a form or visiting a new URL.
We can just send a request to the server on the fly or behind the scenes.
To do this, we could use a feature that modern Web browsers have that is named Fetch, but instead
I like to leverage a solution named Axios.
Axios lets us keep the code that we write super clean and super minimal.
Let me show you what I mean.
So right now, do this in a new Web browser tab.
I want you to Google for Axios JS and within the first few results, what we are looking for is GitHub
dot com slash, axios, slash, axios.
Go ahead and click on that from that GitHub screen.
If you scroll down a bit below all the list of files, you'll see a bit of instructions.
Keep scrolling down.
Look for this area named installing.
If you scroll down a little bit further, we see this area named using CDN and then it offers this little
snippet of code.
What I want you to do is copy that snippet of code into your clipboard.
So I'm going to select it.
Copy it.
OK, now let's jump back into our text editor.
And in our server JS file, I want you to find the HTML template that we are sending for the home page.
Scroll down to the bottom of the HTML template and right before the line where we include our browser
JS file right above that line.
I want you to paste in your clipboard.
Cool.
This code will make the Axios library available to us.
So let's save this file and then jump back into our browser JS file and let's get rid of this console
dot log line and in its place instead we want to send that data to our node server.
So let's use the Axios library and then look inside it and call a method name to post.
This is how we can send an on the fly post request to a server right after the parentheses for post.
Let's also include a dot and then call a method named then and then after that let's include a dot and
finally call a method named Catch.
Now let's go through this line of code and understand what's going on.
So within the parentheses for post, we want to give it to arguments.
Let's say A comma, B as placeholders.
This first argument is the U.
RL that we want to send a post request to.
So instead of the placeholder a, let's include a string of text with quotes and let's just make up
a U.
RL, let's say forward slash and then let's go with update Dasch item.
OK, for the second argument, instead of this B placeholder, we include a JavaScript object, so curly
brackets and this is the data that's going to get sent along with the request to that.
You are all right.
This is the data that the server will receive.
So within our object, let's just create a property.
We could give any name, but I'm going to go with text and let's just set it to equal so colon and then
let's just pull in the value of this variable, whatever the user typed in.
So that's user input.
User input.
All right.
Now, this axios post method is going to return a promise.
And this is the first time in the course that we have heard of a promise.
We will learn more about promises later on in the.
Course, for now, all you need to know is that a promise is very useful when we're not sure how long
an action is going to take.
Right.
This action of sending request to the server could take one millisecond or it could take five thousand
milliseconds.
We don't know.
So instead of the familiar callback function pattern that we've been seeing when we're not sure how
long an action is going to take, this is another way of handling that situation.
Basically, once you have a promise, you can then say dot then and inside the then parentheses is where
you include a function that is not going to run until the action has had a chance to complete.
And then finally, within the catch parentheses, this is where you include a function that will run
if the action runs into a problem.
So let's start with the then parentheses inside the then.
Let's just include an anonymous function.
It's a function parentheses, curly brackets for the time being.
Let's not worry about doing anything on the browser side once this action completes.
So inside the body of this function, let's just include a comment to ourselves with two forward slashes
and say, do something interesting here in the next video, OK?
And then finally, within the catch parentheses, let's include an anonymous function function, parentheses,
curly brackets.
For now, if we run into a problem list, just log a message to the browser console and say, please
try again later.
So now let's go ahead and save this file.
And our final step in this video or this part of the lesson will be to receive that from the server
side.
Let me show you what I mean.
So let's jump into our server JS file, and I want you to scroll down to the very bottom.
So at the very, very bottom, let's add a brand new line and say app dot post, give it to arguments,
a comma B for the first argument that you are all we are interested in would be slash update item.
And then for the B argument, let's include an anonymous function.
So function parentheses, curly brackets within the function parentheses.
Let's include the parameters.
Are you and R yes.
Now in the next video, this is where we will actually communicate with the database to update a document.
But for this video, let's just log the users typed in new value to the node or server console just
to make sure that our server is successfully receiving that data.
So let's say console, dot log.
What do we want to log?
Well, let's look inside the request object for the body object.
This is the data that the axios request is sending over and inside that object.
We are interested in the property named text.
Right.
That's the name we chose just a moment ago.
Once we've logged that to the console, let's add one more line and just say R.
S response and call the send method.
And let's just send back a little bit of text that says success.
Now, before we save this file, let's take care of one more detail.
Scroll up to the very top of this file.
And I want you to find the line of code where we say App Use Express.
You are encoded.
Remember, this line of code tells Express to automatically take submitted form data and add it to a
body object that lives on the request object.
Well, we just want to tell expressed to do that same thing only instead of four submitted forms.
We want it for asynchronous requests.
So right above this line of code, let's just add a new line and say app.
Don't use inside the use parentheses, just say Express DOT, JSON and Jason is a method in this case,
so include a pair of parentheses for it.
All right, let's go ahead and save this file and be sure to have your command line visible so you can
see our servers console.
Let's go to the browser, be sure to refresh the application and if we click on an edit button and I'll
just type something in like unicorn pizza, click, OK, jump back to our server console and there we
see that value.
This may not seem like a big deal, but this is a huge milestone in your JavaScript career.
You just set up browser side JavaScript code to asynchronously, send a request to our node JS server.
This means you are successfully using JavaScript on the front end and JavaScript on the back end.
This, my friends, is what's referred to as full stack JavaScript.
And in our very next lesson, we are going to learn how to take this data from our node server and actually
update an existing document in our Mongo DB database.
So excited to set this up with you.
Let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.