Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to continue working on the feature where a user can edit one of their
existing posts.
All right.
So we've already set things up so that you can visit your profile.
And then if you visit one of your posts, you can click this blue icon to go to the edit screen.
And we are successfully pulling in the existing values for this post from the database.
Now, in this lesson, we want to work on what should happen when this form is submitted.
So let's begin by jumping into this SJS template and paying attention to the forms action value.
Right.
Where is it going to submit?
So in our text editor in your Views folder, jump in to edit Dasch post DOT SJS towards the top on this
opening form tag.
Let's change the action value, so let's get rid of slash create post and instead say slash post slash
and then we'll pull in the idea and then slash edit.
Now we don't actually just want this hard coded text of ID, we want to pull in the actual ID, so jump
into SJS and then in there we can just say post dot underscore I.D..
OK, let's save this file and now we need to set up a route for this.
You are URL pattern.
We've already used this exact pattern, but before that was a request, whereas a form submit this is
going to be a post request.
So within the root of your folder, jump into Routon J.S. down towards the bottom to save a bit of typing.
You can actually just duplicate this line where we say router target post idy edit.
So I'm just going to duplicate that pasted in below and let's just change it from a git request to a
post request.
OK, and then for the second argument, in terms of a function we would want to run, we can still look
within our post controller.
But instead of you edit screen, let's imagine that we're going to have a function that's just named
edit.
OK, let's save this and now we better go into our post controller and create a function with this matching
name.
So within your controllers folder, jump into post controller.
Let's scroll down to the very bottom and let's add a new function.
So exports dot edit set it to a function within these parentheses.
Be sure to include request and response.
OK, now within the body of this function, let's say let lowercase post equal a new instance of uppercase
post.
So this is the same pattern we used when we created a post.
Right.
So then in these parentheses we would pass our blueprint, the submitted form data.
So request dogsbody.
OK, and then below this, let's use that new object that it's going to create.
So lowercase post and let's just imagine that it's going to have a method named update.
It doesn't actually have this method yet, but we can go create it in just a minute or two, OK?
And when we do create it, we can set it up so that it returns a promise.
So right after this, let's use the dot, then catch syntax.
So dot then dot catch.
Let's provide functions within both the then and catch parentheses.
I'll use arrow functions just because they're a bit shorter or cleaner.
Add one for catch as well.
So at this point, I would start leaving comments to myself that explain how I would expect this promise
to work, then when we're actually creating this promise, we'll have some sort of plan in terms of
when and how we want it to resolve or reject.
OK, so let's start first with if the promise rejects.
This would be if a post with the request, that idea doesn't exist.
Or if the current visitor is not the owner of the requested post.
So if either of these things is the case, I probably just want to redirect the user back to the home
page with a red error message that says you do not have permission to perform that action or something
along those lines.
So let's set that up.
I would use the flash package.
So request flash and add on to a collection named Errors and I'd give it a string of text.
Says you do not have permission to perform that action, OK.
After that, I'd want to manually save the session data and then redirect them back to the home page.
So request session, save, give it a function and then finally redirect them as a response.
Redirect back to the home page.
OK, so that takes care of the catch.
If this update promise rejects.
But what if the promise resolves.
So let's start adding a few comments here to stay organized.
If the promise is successful, that would mean that either A The Post was successfully updated in the
database or it could also mean that this user does indeed have permission.
Right.
They are indeed the owner of this post.
But maybe there was a validation error, meaning maybe they left the title field blank or the body field
blank, which is not allowed.
Right.
You must provide content for these.
So even though they had permissions to modify the post, it still didn't successfully go through.
So I could just say or user did have permission, but there were validation errors.
Now, in order to know which one of these is the case, we could just set up our update promise to resolve
with a status value.
Right.
So it could just be a string of text that either says success or failure.
So we'd want to receive that value.
So within these parentheses for this arrow function, let's just make up a parameter, let's call it
status.
Now, below these comments, we can just set up an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets, let's also set up an else block for the condition.
We can just say if status equals success, well, that means the Post was actually updated in the database.
We can leave a comment here to ourselves.
Post was updated in DB else.
Otherwise that means the user had permission.
But there were validation errors like maybe they left the title or body fields blank.
If that's the case, I would just want to redirect the user back to that same edit screen and show them
red error rectangles with the validation errors so we can just say lowercase post dot errors.
We would want to loop through those and create a flash message for each one.
So for each give that a function.
But then those parentheses, let's work with the current item so we could say error within this.
For each function we could just say request dot flash.
We want to add on to a collection named Errors and the value should just be the current item in the
errors array.
So error, OK, after that I just want to manually save the session data and then redirect them.
So request session save give that a function.
To redirect, just response, redirect, and now instead of quotes, let's actually use back tactics,
so let's redirect them to slash post slash I.D., slash edit only.
Instead of hard coding this to ID, we'd want to do something dynamic's a dollar sign curly brackets
and then we can just say request Paramo I.D..
Right.
That's the idea of the post they were trying to edit.
OK, finally, let's circle back to this area where we say Post was updated in database.
So this is if everything went perfectly, so what would we want to do in that case?
I'd probably want to redirect them back to that same edit screen that just submitted from so they could
continue making edits if they needed to, only up at the top.
I would include a flash message only instead of a red error message.
It could be a green success message that says Post successfully updated.
So let's get started right underneath this comment.
Let's say request dot flash.
We'd want to add on to a collection, let's call it success, or you could call it success messages
to be plural.
It's up to you.
But let's give this a second argument with the message that we want.
So post successfully updated.
OK, below that, I would want to manually save the session data and redirect them back to that same
edit screen.
So request session save give that a function, let's redirect them.
So response stop redirect.
Instead of quotes, I'm going to use tactics and redirect them to slash post slash idee slash edit.
Let's hollow out that I'd make it dynamic.
So dollar sign curly brackets and just say request Ramsgate id.
OK now before we save this and then jump into our model to actually create this update function, let's
first make sure that when we are using our blueprint, we're giving it all the information it needs
to do its job and perform the permission check.
So when we're creating a new instance of our post blueprint, let's give it additional arguments within
these parentheses so common we need to give it the ID of the current visitor.
So request visitor ID, comma, and we need to give it the ID for the current post that is being requested
to edit.
That's part of the Eurail for this request.
So we can just say request programs.
ID cool at this point, let's save this file and now we need to jump in to our post model and create
a function named update that returns a promise and we'll either resolve or reject in a way that follows
this pattern or structure that we just set up.
So let's jump into our uppercase postgrads model file.