At this point, let's save this file and now we need to jump in to our post model and create a function
named update that returns a promise and we'll either resolve or reject in a way that follows this pattern
or structure that we just set up.
So let's jump into our uppercase postgrads model file and let's scroll down and find our create method.
So here is a post prototype.
Create maybe right below this.
Let's create our update method.
So right above our postdoc reusable query, I'm going to add a new line and say Post Dot Prototyp DOT
update.
Let's set that to equal a function.
And remember, our controller expects this function to return a promise.
So return a new instance of promise within the parentheses for promise.
Let's give it an arrow function parentheses.
Be sure to include resolve and reject.
After those parentheses, we can include the arrow symbol and then a pair of curly brackets.
OK, now within this function, our first step should be to find the relevant post document in the database,
because before we worry about updating anything, we want to make sure that the post ID that was just
included in this URL.
Well, does it even exist?
Is that even a valid ID?
And we need to know who the author of it is so we could directly use the Mongo DB, find one method
on our collection.
However, we've already created a method named Bind single by ID and that functions already going to
check to make sure that the incoming ID is valid, that it's a string of text and not a malicious object.
And it's also going to automatically run the check to see if the current visitor is the owner of that
post.
So let's do this.
Let's set up a try block and then right below that, let's set up a catch block, OK, within the tribe
block.
What do we want to try to do?
Let's create a variable named post and let's set that to equal and then just call our find single by
IDE method.
So uppercase post find single by IDE.
To refresh your memory, we'd want to give this function to arguments.
So Akama be the first argument is the post idy that you want to look up.
Now back in our controller, when we said that we wanted to create a new instance of our post blueprint,
we made sure to pass into it the requested post ID.
So let's do this, let's scroll up to the very top of this file.
And this is our constructor function within the parentheses.
We already have two parameters, data and user ID.
Let's out a third, so comma and let's call it requested post ID.
OK then within our constructor function, let's just say this dot requested post ID equals and then
just pull in the parameter value.
So requested post ID.
Cool.
Now we can access this from within any of our prototype methods.
So let's go back down to our update method.
OK, and remember we are calling our find single by ID.
So this first argument should be the post ID instead of a we can just say this dot requested post ID.
OK, the second argument instead of B, this should be the current visitor ID.
We've already stored that on our object so we can just say this dot user ID, OK, now right below this
line, still within the tribe block.
We're going to want to set up an if statement.
However, let's not forget that this is going to return a promise.
It's going to take some time to complete.
So right before it in between post and the equals sign, let's add a weight also since we can only use
a weight within an async function right before the parentheses for our arrow function.
So right here, let's just say async.
Cool.
So now on this line we can reliably access this post variable.
It's going to be the post document that this resolves with.
And since this function uses our reusable query function, it's going to already have a property named
is visiter owner.
So we're going to write an if statement on this line, but I don't want to get sidetracked yet.
So I'm just going to write a little comment here that says if and we can circle back to this.
But first, let's ask ourselves, what if this function can't find a post with the matching ID write?
What if someone sends a bogus you URL with something that.
Is not a valid ID at all.
Well, we've already set up this promise to reject if that's the case, right.
If this is not a valid, innocent I.D. or if it's not an ID that exists in our database, this promise
rejects.
And since we are within a tri block, if this promise rejects, our catch will automatically take care
of it.
So big picture within the catch block.
This is where we would want our overall promise to reject.
OK, now let's circle back to this if statement that we want to.
Right.
Let's say this if parentheses curly brackets right after that.
Let's also add an else block.
And for our condition, let's just say if lowercase post DOT is visiter owner, if this is true, then
we are safe to actually update the database document.
So let's write a comment to ourselves, actually update the DB.
We'd also want to resolve our promise here, but else.
Otherwise, if this is false, that means whoever is trying to send this request is up to no good.
Right?
They're not the owner or creator of the post.
So then the else block we would just want this promise to reject.
All right.
Now let's circle back to this area where we have the comment.
Actually, update the DB We could write the code that talks to the Mongo DB database right here, but
we are already indented several layers deep here.
So just for the sake of organization and not being indented, even several layers deeper, let's do
this right below this comment line.
Let's say this DOT actually update.
This method doesn't exist yet, but we can create it in just a moment.
Let's set it up to return a promise and then right before it, we can just say, oh, wait.
So within this method, actually update is where we will talk to the Mongo DB database.
And then once that has actually completed, this overall promise will resolve.
So let's go create this actually update method.
Let's scroll down right after our update method ends.
And right before this reuseable post query, let's create a brand new line and say uppercase post,
prototype dot actually update.
Let's set this to equal a function within the body of the function.
Let's return a promise to return a new instance of promise within these parentheses.
Let's give it an async arrow function.
So async parentheses, arrow symbol, curly brackets within those parentheses.
Let's be sure to give it resolve and reject.
OK, within this function, let's call this clean up and let's call r this dot validate.
OK, after that let's run an if statement.
Let's say if parentheses curly brackets.
Let's also include an else block for the condition within the parentheses.
Let's say this dot errors dot link, let's actually check for the opposite of that.
So include an exclamation right before this.
So we're saying if there are no validation errors then we would actually want to make these updates
in the database.
So let's use our object that represents the Mongo DB posts collection.
We've already set that up at the top of this files of posts collection.
Let's look inside it for the Mongo DB method named Find One and update.
We need to pass this to arguments so Eikon will be the first argument is the object that you want to
find.
So curly brackets.
We're interested in a document where the underscore ID and then colon and then when you're trying to
match an ID in Mongu DB instead of just giving it a simple string of text, we actually want to create
a new instance of the Mongo DB Object ID.
OK, then within those parentheses is where we would say this DOT requested post ID.
All right.
Now for the second argument, instead of this placeholder B, we would also provide an object so curly
brackets.
And now this is where we say what we want to do with that document that we find.
So let's say dollar sign set and what do we want to set?
We just give it an object and now we just list the properties that we would want to change.
So we want to change the title title Colon to use the new title.
So this data, not title comma, we'd also want to update the body property or fields of body colon,
this data body.
OK, now back at the beginning of this line, this Mongo DB method is going to return a promise.
So at the start of this line, let's be sure to await.
Its completion.
OK, and then right below this line, let's just resolve this promise, so resolve now.
Let's take care of our else block.
If this evaluates to false, that means there's validation errors.
So within the else block, we would also want to resolve except in the else.
Let's resolve with the value of failure and in the IFLA, let's resolve the value of success.
OK, this actually update function is now complete.
Now let's just scroll back to our update method and let's do this.
Find the comment that says actually update DB.
And at the start of this line before a wait, let's just say let status equal.
And we know that this promise is going to resolve the value of either success or failure.
So then that's what this overall promise can resolve with status.
OK, at this point, our work in the model is complete.
But before we go, test this out.
Remember that in relation to this promise, either resolving or rejecting our controller is making extensive
use of flash messages to show relevant messages to the user.
Let's also not forget that instead of only red error messages, we also want to display a green success
flash message if the update actually happened.
So right now, let's save this file and let's jump in to our edit dash postgrads file and make sure
that flash messages are set up.
OK, so within this template, right below this div with the class of container.
So right here is where we would want to display flash messages.
Now there's no sense in typing out the code to make that happen.
We've already written that code in another template.
So right now, let's go copy and paste and borrow from our home dash guest template.
So in our views folder, jump in to home, dash just towards the top.
We see these three lines of code that power flash messages.
Go ahead and copy those three lines into your clipboard and then back in our edit dash post template,
just paste right here.
However, this only takes care of red error messages.
What about green success messages?
Well, after these three lines of code, let's just dropdown and paste in our clipboard again.
Only this time, instead of looking within an array named errors, let's look within an array named
success and then in the HTML that we would output instead of alert dash danger.
Let's change this to alert dash success.
All right.
And if you stop and think about it, we would actually want this code at the top of almost every template
in our project.
Right.
There's a lot of different cases where we want to display different types of flash messages.
So in order to avoid a ton of duplication, let's select all of this.
So the code for the errors and the success, let's copy all of that into our clipboard and let's create
a shared or reusable include file.
So within our views folder, within the sub folder named includes this right.
Click and choose new file.
Let's name the new file Flash Ejaz.
OK, within that new file, just paste in your clipboard.
Go ahead and save that.
And now back in edit Dasch Post, we can get rid of all of this and just include that file.
So SJS with a dash and then include give it a path includes dash flash.
Let's close out this SJS tag and now let's copy this include command.
And now let's just insert it in almost all of our templates with that in my clipboard.
Let's first of all, save this file, but then let's jump in to create dash post and end up at the top
right below that container div.
Just paste it in, save that.
Let's also jump into single dash post.
Dash screen.
Paste it right below that container div, let's also update both our home dashboard and home guests.
So Home Dashboard first right below that container div just paste it in your own home dash guest.
We can replace these three lines of code that were powering the errors.
Place that with the include.
Go ahead and save.
All right.
Now we just have one more task before everything comes together, since we potentially want to leverage
flash messages in almost every template.
It would become tiring to manually pass flash data into the template every single time.
To show you what I mean.
Right now, let's jump into our user controller file in the controller's folder, jump into user controller,
and I want you to scroll down and find our home function.
So the line begins with exports home and pay attention to this line where we are rendering the home
guess template.
So this is where we're passing data into the template.
And here you can see we're manually creating a property named Errors and then calling Flash to get the
appropriate data.
This works perfectly, except we probably don't want to have to include this same code every time we
render a template.
So for this home dash guess template, let's leave the registration errors because those are unique
to the home page.
But let's get rid of this errors.
Colen request dot flash.
So delete that and the common space.
So now all we're passing into home guess template is the registration errors.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now within our main Apgar's file, we can set up a function that will run for every request to sort
of automate what we were doing here manually just a moment ago.
So let's jump in to our app JS file and scroll down to the area that begins with app use.
And then we have our own custom function.
You might see comments in here like make current user IDs available on the request object and make user
session data available from within view templates within this function.
Let's just add a new line and let's add a new comment and let's say make all error and success flash
messages available from all templates.
So to do this, we can just say response dot locals dot errors should equal request dot flash errors
and then do the same thing for success.
So those will be the green success messages.
Response dot locals dot success equals request dot flash success.
Cool.
So now we don't need to manually pass that data into our templates within all of our post controllers.
Let's go ahead and save this and test everything out.
So back in the browser within the edit post screen, be sure to refresh so your browser has the updated
action value for the form.
Let me try to update this post by maybe just adding a few exclamations at the end.
Let me go ahead and submit.
Perfect, we see the success message and that latest data, you can test this out by going up to your
address bar and if we get rid of the slash edit at the end and just go back to viewing that post, we
do indeed see those updated values.
Next, let's see what happens if I try to edit a post I don't own.
So if I go back to that edit screen for this post, I'm logged in.
So yes, I am the author of this post.
But if I copy this, you RL and then in this window where I'm logged in with my Bachs alone account,
if I try to visit that you URL and submit a bit of data, don't worry.
In our next lesson we'll set things up so that you can't even view this screen if you're not the owner.
But if I try to submit a bit of new data, send off that form.
It kicks me right back to the homepage and says you do not have permissions to perform that action perfect.
And that's going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we're going to work on several different features, but probably the most noteworthy
feature will be letting users include Mark down in their posts.
If you've never heard of Mark down, don't worry.
Essentially, it's just going to let users include bold content or italic content or create different
headings within their plain text content.
Here, it should be a lot of fun to set up.
And by the end of our next lesson, this application is really going to start coming together.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.