Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to save a registered user into a database.
Let's jump right into the action.
So in our previous lesson within our User Dogs model file towards the bottom, we set up this register
function and we know that this is what our user controller is going to call when someone submits the
user registration form.
Now we've already set up our validation checks and assuming that there are zero validation errors,
right?
Assuming that we are happy with the username, email and password they chose, well, we are ready to
now actually save that into a database.
So our first step is to make sure that we have a database to save into.
Technically, you could reuse the same database from our To-Do app, but I strongly encourage you to
create a new database for each application that you create.
So right now, I want you to jump into your MongoDB Atlas account.
So in a new tab, you can just visit MongoDB dot com and then sign in and to create a new database for
this new project we're working on.
We can click on this collections button.
From this collection screen, we see this create database button here.
Let's go ahead and click on that for the database name, you can name it either our app or you can name
it.
Complex app the name doesn't matter.
Just choose something that will make sense to you.
And then for the collection name.
Let's have our first collection be named users, right?
Because the first feature we are working on is saving a user into the database.
So within this user's collection, each document will represent one user.
So collection name users, and then let's go ahead and click Create.
All right now from this collection screen, you can see complex app is listed here.
In my case, it did not select that new database by default, so you actually have to click on it and
then I can click into the user's collection.
OK, and here we can see that collection is completely empty with zero results.
So our goal for this lesson is to connect our app to this new database so that when someone submits
this user registration form with valid values, well, we would expect to see a new user document appear
in this collection.
So how can we make that happen?
Well, our first instinct might be to go into our user model file and down here under step number to
open a connection to that new database.
However, if we think about the big picture and look ahead, we know that we are also going to have
a post-Games model file to describe what a post or article should be.
And we're also going to have a follow J.S. model file to describe what a follow should be.
What I'm getting at is instead of connecting to the database in each of our model files, why don't
we instead connect to the database once in a separate file whose entire job is just to connect to the
database?
And then we can leverage that one single file from within each of our models?
Let me show you what I mean.
So right now, within the root of our project folder, I want you to create a brand new file.
So new file.
And let's name this new file.
D.B. Dot, J.S. we could name it anything, but let's go with this just so we're on the same page.
All right now, within this new empty file, we want to open a connection to a MongoDB database.
Now, in order to do that, we need to go out to npm and grab the official MongoDB package.
So to do that, let's open up our command line.
If your app is already running, be sure to press Control C to quit the app.
So now we can run this command npm install.
And the name of the package is Mongo DB.
All lowercase, all one word.
Go ahead and press enter.
OK, now up within our new file, let's require in that package.
So let's create a variable.
And instead of spelling out a name, let's actually have curly brackets to restructure or pull something
out of the package.
So in these curly brackets, let's say Mongo client, now we are not making this name up.
This is the name of a property from within the package.
So after that will say equals require in the MongoDB package.
The idea is that the overall package object contains all sorts of different things, but right now there's
one property called Mongo Client with Capital M Capital C.
That's really the only thing we're interested in.
Cool.
Now on a new line, we can use it.
We can say Konst Client.
So we are making up this name.
This could have been anything.
But Konst client equals a new instance of Mongo client for now.
In these parentheses, let's just have an empty string of text, so empty quotes and we will circle
back to what this value should be in just a minute.
However, for now, below this line, we can leverage our lowercase client variable to create a connection
to a MongoDB database.
We don't know how long it will take to create that connection could be one millisecond could be five
seconds.
So let's use the async await syntax.
So we'll create an asynchronous function, async function, you can name it anything start go unicorn
pizza.
So just create an async function, then right below it.
Call it whatever renamed it.
In the body of that function, let's use our client variable and look inside it for a connect method
and call that.
Now this is the line that we don't know how long it will take to create that connection.
So at the start of this line, let's be sure to include a weight.
So once this line of code finally finishes.
Well, now below that we can say client dot and call a method of DB.
This will return what we're truly interested in an object that represents a real database that we are
connected to.
Now, before we worry about actually leveraging whatever this DB method returns, let's first circle
back to this empty string of text here on this line when we created a new instance of Mongo client.
So in these empty quotes, this is where we want to provide a connection string.
Now remember in a new tab in your browser, you can go into your MongoDB Atlas Cloud account to find
your connection string.
However, here's what I like to do to save yourself some time.
Go ahead and open up your server.
Just file from our previous to do app project when we set up our To-Do app.
We already configured the connection stream.
So if you dig into that old file of yours, it will already have the username, password and your MongoDB
Atlas address.
So go ahead and pause this video while you go and open up your old to do app server dogs file and then
just go ahead and copy and paste your connection string value from that file into this file.
So once you do that, it should look something like this.
You will have a different username and password value, but scroll to the very right edge or end of
this line of code at the end of your connection stream right before retry rights equals true.
Right before that, we see a question mark and then the name of the database that you want to work with.
In this case, let's get rid of this To-Do app, and let's replace that with the new database that you
just created a couple of moments ago for this lesson.
So in my case, I would get rid of To-Do app and replace it with complex app.
Cool.
So this connection string is now good to go at this point.
Let's circle back to this DB method down here, Client DB.
So let's do this.
This is going to return the database object that we're interested in.
So let's be sure to store or saved this somewhere.
Actually, instead of saving it to a traditional variable, let's do this at the beginning of this line
right before client, let's say module dot exports equals client DB.
So this way, if we require this file from within another file, it's going to return the database that
we can work with.
Now, before we save this file, let's do one last thing.
Let's set it up so that this DB D.J.s file is our opening or starting file meaning to start our node
application instead of starting up our app digest file.
We would want to start our DB D.J.s file, meaning we don't even want to launch or begin our application
until we've had a chance to establish a connection to our database.
Because remember, we don't know how long it's going to take to create a connection to the database.
It could take five milliseconds or it could take 5000 milliseconds.
But we do know that this line of code.
Isn't going to run until we actually do have that connection.
So right below this line within this function, this is where we would want to actually start our express
app, right, because our database will be ready.
So let me show you what we can do right now.
I want you to open up our app JS file.
Within App Dogs, scroll down to the very bottom.
The file ends with App Dot, listen, and then we're listening on Port three thousand.
Let's get rid of that line.
Delete it entirely.
And instead, let's just say module dot exports equals app.
So in this way, we are still creating an express application under this variable app.
But instead of telling it to actually start listening, we're just exporting it from this file.
So let's go ahead and save App Dot J.S..
And then back within DB Dot J.S. right below module dot exports equals client DB.
Let's say this let's create a variable named app, so Konst app equals and then let's require in our
main app file.
So require quotes and then dot slash to look within the current directory and its name is app.
OK, so that requires in the express application.
And then right below that line, we can just tell it to actually start listening, right listening for
incoming requests so we can just say App Dot listen on Port three thousand.
If this is not making perfect sense yet, that's OK.
We're going to review it again in just a minute.
For now, let's go ahead and save this file.
And now we just have one last step.
I want you to jump in to our package doc JSON file.
Remember, when we want to run our server, we type in the command npm run watch well within this package.
JSON file is where we defined what that watch command should do.
Basically, we were telling it to monitor our app JS file and restart it any time we saved a change.
Well, let's just change this from App Dot J.S. to DB Dogs only we don't need to actually include the
Dodgers.
So now when we run npm run watch, it's going to monitor and restart the DB file for us.
So let's go ahead and save that file and test it out.
So down at our command line to start up our server again, run npm run watch.
Let's test it out if you go in your browser and refresh local host Colin 3000.
Everything should still work perfectly and you should see this homepage.
And to review why this is so cool, let's jump back into our DB Scott JS file.
So our express application is running just like it always has.
Only now it's not going to begin until we've already had a chance to export the MongoDB database.
This means that we can now very easily access and work with our database from within any file where
we just require in this DB dogs file.
In other words, this setup is perfect for our MVC setup.
So right now, you can go ahead and close all of your files except our uppercase user gorgeous model
file.
Remember, down at the bottom of our user model file, this is where we have.
Step one Validate the data and then step two.
If there are no validation problems, actually save it into the database.
So now we are ready to do that.
So check this out.
Up at the very top of our user model file, let's create a new variable.
And let's say Konst, and let's name this user's collection and let's set it to equal.
And then we can just require in that new DB file.
So require provided a file path.
So quotes.
Dot Dot slash to go up out of the models folder into the root of our project, and then we want to pull
in the DB file.
So remember, within that file, we sent module dot exports to be the database object.
So that's what this is going to return and then we can look inside that.
So dot here and we can say collection and then we just provide the name of the MongoDB collection that
we want to work with.
So quotes users.
Awesome.
So we now have this variable user's collection that we can perform crud operations on.
So let's scroll down to the very bottom of this file and under step number two.
Let's do this.
Let's check to see if there are any validation errors.
So let's say if parentheses curly brackets, let's say if this dot errors dot length.
Now this would evaluate to true if there was one or more errors, so we would want to check for the
opposite of that.
So let's just put an exclamation mark right before the this.
So essentially, we're saying only if the errors array is empty, then do this.
So now within these curly brackets, we can drop down and let's just add or insert a new document into
that database collection so we can use our users collection variable and then look inside it and we
want to perform a crud operation.
We want to create a new document in MongoDB.
The command name for that is insert one, and within these parentheses we give it an object that we
would want to save as a document.
In this case, we can just type this dot data right because we've already cleaned up and validated that
data.
We know that this code is only going to run if there are no validation problems so that data is safe
to store in the database.
Let's go ahead and save that and test it out.
So back in the browser, let's choose valid values here.
So for username Brad, email Brad at Brad dot com and then choose a password that is at least 12 characters.
And let's sign up.
So we see congrats.
There are no errors, but more importantly, if we go into our MongoDB Atlas account and within our
complex app users collection, if we click the Find button here to refresh or reload the data.
Awesome, we see one document, the username is Brad Brad at Broadcom.
And here we see the super secure and safe password.
Curti nerdy.
Cool.
So now that we've permanently stored these values.
Now, when a user tries to log in, right, if they use this login form in the top right and enter a
username and password, we can determine if those values are correct or not.
Right.
We have something to reference now.
And as you might have guessed, logging in is exactly what we're going to focus on in our next lesson.
We're going to set up this login form to submit data to our server, and then we will evaluate their
username and password values.
This should be a lot of fun to set up, so let's keep things rolling, and I'll see you then.