Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to learn about client side rendering, so first of all, what in the world
is client side rendering?
Well, it ties in to the duplicated code from our previous lesson that I promised we would solve in
this lesson.
So remember, the HTML template for a row item or list item was originally only in our server JS file,
but then we improved our create feature to use asynchronous or on the fly requests.
So we needed a way to visually add a new list item to the user interface without a page reload.
And that required us to also include that HTML template in our front end or browser JS file.
But in a perfect world, we usually want to avoid duplicating code like this because then in the future,
if we ever wanted to change the HTML template for a list item, we would need to update that HTML code
in multiple places or in multiple files and that would be a pain.
So how can we avoid this duplication of code?
Well, one answer would be client side rendering or browser side rendering.
Let's jump into a text editor and I'll explain what that means within our server JS file.
Let's scroll down until we see our HTML template.
And in particular we are looking for the unordered list where we then generate a list item for each
document in our collection.
So the question is what is client side rendering?
It just means that instead of generating HTML for our dynamic data on the server side and then sending
that HTML to the Web browser instead of that with client side rendering, the server would only send
the browser the raw data.
In this case, our array named items and then it would be up to the web browser or client to use that
raw data to generate the appropriate HTML.
So basically we're just offloading the responsibility of generating HTML from the server over to the
browser.
So to get started implementing client side rendering, our first step is to send over the raw data or
our items array to the Web browser.
So check this out.
Scroll down towards the bottom of this HTML template and towards the bottom.
We see these two script tags right above those script tags.
Let's add a new line and type this out with me.
Let's add another script tag pair.
And in between the two script tags, let's type this.
Let's create a variable.
Remember anything inside the script tags will be interpreted as JavaScript by the web browser.
So we are creating a variable, let's name it items and let's set it to equal.
And then we are within a template literal.
So to do something dynamic we can say dollar sign.
Curly brackets in the web browser has a built in object named JSON.
Again, JSON stands for JavaScript object notation and it's a super popular way of sending data back
and forth.
Now we can look inside the JSON object for a method named Dring Afie and what this will do is convert
JavaScript data or JSON into a string of text.
So within these parentheses we just let it know which data we want to convert.
Let's say items.
Right, because that is the name of our array of database objects or database documents.
All right.
Now, with this in place, go ahead and save this file and then let's refresh on the front end.
And what I want you to do is right.
Click and choose view page source.
This is the HTML that makes up our Web page, and if we scroll down to the very bottom here, we see
that new script tag that we just added.
And this is the raw data for our items array.
Right.
We see it's an array of objects and each object has a property of underscore ID and text.
And here we see things like walk the dog by coffee.
This means that our server is successfully sending over the raw data to our browser or to our client.
With this in place.
Let's take a leap of faith and actually delete the list item HTML template from our server code.
Let me show you what I mean.
Back in our text editor and server EGAS.
Scroll back up until you find the unordered list area.
And remember, this is where we used Map to loop through our items array and generate this template
once for each item.
Let's delete all of this so that the unordered list is completely hollowed out and empty.
So just delete all of the lines of code in between the opening you will and the closing you will.
All right.
If we save that and then refresh, obviously that area is now completely empty.
But the idea is that we can now use browser based or client based JavaScript to generate that same exact
user interface.
Right.
Because our front end JavaScript has access to this raw data.
So let's start writing a bit of browser based JavaScript.
Back in our text editor, we are done with server Gorgias.
Instead, let's jump into our file named browser Gorgias towards the top of the file, maybe right above
our create feature area.
Let's create a new comment to stay organized and let's say initial page load render.
OK, and let's begin by selecting that empty unordered list element.
You can see we gave that an ID of item Dasht list.
So back in our browser, not just let's say document dot git element by IDE and had an ID of item Dasch
list.
OK, once we've selected that element then we want to tack on and say dot insert adjacent HTML.
We give this method to arguments.
The first argument is where we want to add on the HTML so we can say before end.
And then the second argument is the HTML that we actually want to add to it.
Just so this line of code doesn't get super long and unreadable.
Let's make up a variable name, for example, maybe our HTML and then on the line of code right before
this new line of code, let's just create a variable named our HTML and let's set it to equal something
now for a quick test.
We could set it to a string of text that is just hello.
And if I save that and refresh, we see that it's in the right place.
So now instead of hello, we just need to leverage this raw data to generate the appropriate HTML.
So let's take note that this data is being stored in a variable named items and this variable does not
live within a function.
So that means it's available in the global scope.
So we will have no trouble accessing it from anywhere within our code to check this out back in our
file instead of setting our HTML to equal quotes.
Hello, that's get rid of the quotes.
Hello.
And let's begin by working with that item's variable that contains the raw data.
We know that it is an array and all arrays have access to the map method.
The MAP method will create a new array based on the original array.
So within the map parentheses we just give it a function.
So function parentheses, curly brackets that it will run once for each item in this array within these
parentheses.
For the function, let's include a parameter named item, OK, within the body of our function, let's
just return.
And our goal here is to return the HTML template for each list item.
Well, luckily in our previous lesson we already created a function up here at the very top named item
template and we set things up.
So you just pass this function a bit of data for the current item and then it will generate the appropriate
dynamic HTML.
So within our our HTML equals area, what do we want to return?
Let's just call our item template function and within these parentheses, let's just pass in the current
item from the array.
So item.
All right, now the method is going to return an array.
We don't actually want an array.
We want a string of text.
Right.
A string of HTML.
So after this closing parentheses here for map, let's.
Say, Dot, join, join, will convert an array into a string of text, and then instead of having them
be separated by commas, if we just include an empty pair of quotes, they will not be separated by
anything cool.
So this variable will now contain a big string of HTML text and then we're adding that in to our empty
unordered list.
Let's go ahead and save that and test it out.
So back in the browser, if I refresh the application, awesome.
We are in business, we can test it out by maybe trying to delete this by carrot's item.
It's gone, and if I refresh, you can see it's still permanently gone, so this solved are duplicated
code issue and it was a super simple example of client side rendering.
At this point, our application is complete.
So where do we go from here?
Well, in our next lesson, we are going to talk briefly about security.
And then in the lesson after that, we are going to push our application up onto the Internet so you
can share it with your friends and family.
Trust me, it's going to be a great feeling to have people, you know, use and add items to your application.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.