Well, the answer is that we're going to leverage a super popular tool named Mark down instead of trying
to explain what markdown is with words.
Let's just go install it in npm and see it in action.
So do this with me right now.
Open up your command line.
If your app is currently running, Press Control C to quit and run the following command npm install.
And in the JavaScript universe, there's a popular package named Markt that will give us access to markdown.
So npm install marked.
Go ahead and press enter.
OK, and let's get our server back up and running.
So npm run watch.
All right, now, let's jump into our main app Dot JS File and leverage markdown towards the top.
Let's require in that package.
So maybe right below this flash line, let's say Konst markdown equals and then just require in the
package that was named marked.
OK, so we now have this constant variable named markdown.
Now I want you to scroll down to the function that we have that's going to run for every request.
So it begins with App Dot use and then it's a function.
And then we have several comments in here towards the top.
Let's just add a new comment and let's say make our markdown function available from within E.j.'s templates.
All right.
So let's begin working with response dot locals because we can access that from within our templates.
And let's just create a function.
We can name it anything we want, but let's name it, maybe filter user HTML and let's set that to equal
a function within these parentheses.
Let's add a parameter, let's say content and then within the body of the function, let's just return.
And then we will use the markdown package.
Well, the package name marked, but we name the variable markdown and look inside it for a method called
pass.
Now, be careful, this code will try to recommend something called uppercase parser, so do not let
voice code perform the autocomplete.
We want a lowercase method named pass, so you can see as I tried to type that in vs code corrected
it for me.
We don't want that.
So press the escape key on your keyboard right about here.
So that auto suggestion goes away.
And then just parentheses to call it like this in these parentheses, let's pass it content.
Don't worry, I do not expect this to make sense right now, but I think in about 20 to 30 seconds,
it'll be crystal clear.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now let's jump in to the E.j.'s template that powers this screen where you're viewing an individual
post.
So within our Views folder, let's open the file that is named Single Dash Post Dash screen towards
the bottom, we see a div with a class of body content.
And here is where we are actually outputting that body field content from the database.
Well, let's adjust this a bit.
So within the E.j.'s tags, get rid of post-op body.
And instead, let's call that function we just set up.
We named it filter user.
Each HTML.
And let's just pass this function post dot body.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now I can show you what markdown is.
So back in our browser?
Let's try editing an existing post within the body field.
Let's give ourselves a clean start, and let's say this should be bold.
And imagine we wanted this word to actually be bold.
Well, in markdown, you can just wrap it in two stars or asterisks in markdown if you drop down two
lines like this.
It will automatically create each HTML paragraphs for you.
Let's imagine we want something to be italic, so we could say this should be italic.
You would just wrap this in one star or asterisk if you want it to create a heading level one.
You can just include one hash tag and then say, This is my H1.
If you wanted to create a heading level two, it's two of them.
This is my H2.
So on and so forth, all the way up to a heading level six.
If you want to create a bulleted list, you can just include a dash at the start of the line item one
and then item two.
Item three.
You get the idea.
Let's go ahead and click Save.
OK, now let's actually view that post.
The idea is that we didn't write any HTML, but Mark Down will convert its own unique syntax into HTML.
So line breaks automatically turn in paragraphs, double asterisks automatically turn into strong tags.
The hash tags or pound symbols automatically turned into heading level one and heading level two.
And here we see an unordered list with list items.
So that's the good news.
The bad news is that because E.j.'s is protecting us and escaping this, we still don't actually see
any of this formatting.
Well, let's try a quick experiment.
So back in our text editor on this line, where we are outputting that content on the opening E.j.'s
tag.
If we change this equal sign into a dash instead, E.j.'s will no longer protect us.
It's no longer going to escape this, and we would now potentially be open to cross-site scripting attacks.
So if we save this and refresh.
The downside is that our security is now totally gone.
The upside is that users can now provide basic formatting really quick.
Let me show you why this is a malicious users.
While this fantasy, if we go into the edit screen for this post and within the content, since nothing
is escaping any potential HTML, I could just open up a script tag and within it I could say alert.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
Evil JavaScript is being executed here, OK, and then if I submit this and then go back to actually
view it, this is our worst nightmare as a developer.
If a user is able to actually execute JavaScript from the front end of your app, it's game over.
You've lost the security battle because now anyone that visits this URL is going to have this JavaScript
execute, and you can use your imagination instead of a weird alert pop up message like this.
You could instead use JavaScript to program the web browser to send off an asynchronous HTTP request
to the server, and you would be doing so on behalf of their account or their browser.
Whoever's viewing this page effectively allowing the malicious user to do whatever they want on your
behalf.
They can delete all your posts.
They could create a bunch of weird posts on your behalf.
If this was a bank website, they could take all your money.
Not to mention about five other billion bad things they could do if they're allowed to run JavaScript
on the front end of your site.
Big picture you never want to allow this.
So the question becomes How can we let our E.j.'s template not escape this output so that users can
use markdown while at the same time protecting ourselves from things like this?
Well, let's go ahead and leave this as a dash instead of an equal sign, meaning E.j.'s is not protecting
us.
And instead, let's go into our post model and take care of the protection ourselves.
So in your models folder, jump into Post Dot J.S. towards the top.
We have a method named clean up, right?
Post up prototype dot cleanup.
Within that method, we have a comment that says get rid of any bogus properties, and this is also
where we are trimming any empty whitespace at the beginning or end of the title or body.
Well, let's just go ahead and use a sanitized HTML package to remove any and all HTML tags, attributes,
script tag style tags, everything.
We can just aggressively strip out all of that before we store this in our database.
So let's go out to npm and pick up a package.
So open your command line First Control C to stop your server.
Let's run npm install and the name of the package is sanitized.
Dash HD html.
Go ahead and press Enter.
OK, then let's start our server up again.
NPM run watch OK at the top of our post model.
Let's require in that new package.
So Konst sanitize each HTML, set that to equal and then just require in and its name was sanitized.
Dash HD html.
OK, let's go leverage this within our clean up method right below this.
Get rid of bogus properties.
Comment for the value of this body property.
Let's just cut this into our clipboard from this.
To the closing trim, cut that and then let's call our sanitize each HTML package within these parentheses,
we'd want to give it to arguments, so a column will be the first argument is what you're trying to
sanitize.
So this is where we could just get rid of the placeholder and paste in our clipboard.
And the second argument instead of the placeholder be is where we provide an object with a few configuration
options.
I want to aggressively strip out just about everything that isn't plain text.
So I'm going to say aloud tags, colon and I don't want to allow any tags.
So I would just set this to an empty array comma and then allowed attributes column.
I don't want to allow any attributes, so just an empty object.
So that takes care of the body field in terms of the title of a post.
We're never going to output that unless it's escaped.
So it's not a big threat.
But while we're at it, we could also sanitize it to save a bit of typing.
You could just begin selecting at the start of sanitized HTML and just copy the rest of the end of that
line.
Copy that.
And then for title, just get rid of this value.
Paste in your clipboard, except change this dot data dot body to this dot data dot title.
Anyways, let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in the browser, let's try to edit this existing post.
So we've got our evil, malicious JavaScript here.
Just a further show off our sanitized HTML functionality below this, we could try to add in our own
custom HTML.
We could create a development and inside it say this is my custom HTML.
OK, and then if we save or submit this now, our model can do its job and sanitize all of this.
So you can see it completely removed.
The script tags, the JavaScript is gone, and it's stripped the device on either side of this.
This is my custom HTML.
But if we go back to actually view this post, cool markdown is doing its job.
Text is bold.
Italic, we've got headers and bulleted lists.
We now have the best of both worlds are innocent.
Well-intentioned users can style or format their posts, and malicious users cannot enter any sort of
JavaScript or custom HTML.
However, before we close this out, I would not want to allow users to add links to their content.
However, markdown does allow links.
Let me show you what I need if I go into edit this and if I say square brackets, click on me and then
parentheses each http colon malicious link and save that.
And go back to view it.
You can see that because I knew the markdown syntax to create a link.
Well, here's a link.
I'm not comfortable letting users of my app include links in their content.
So here's what I'm going to do.
Let's jump in to our app Dot JS file.
And remember, this is where we set up the function that will be available within response dot locals
within our templates.
Now, when we are creating this function, filter user HTML, let's just use our sanitized HTML package
to sanitize whatever markdown outputs.
We can list a few innocent elements that we would want to allow.
And just not include the a or link element.
So up at the top of this file, I would require in that sanitize HTML package Konst Sanitize HTML equals
required in.
OK, then go back down to our function instead of just returning.
What markdown returns?
Let's say this let's call sanitize HTML.
We're going to give it to arguments.
The first argument is what we want to sanitize.
So that would be what markdown returns.
So instead of a placeholder, it would just be markdown dot.
Look inside it for lowercase pass again.
Press escape right here.
So VSCO doesn't go with its auto suggestion parentheses to call it and feed it content.
And then the second argument is just an object, and we can configure a few options.
So let's say aloud tags.
And this should be an array.
And I would only allow really innocent things like a paragraph or a line break or an unordered list
or a ordered list and a list item or a strong tag or a bold tag or italic.
And then maybe heading level one all the way through heading level six.
You don't absolutely have to do this with me.
Maybe you want to allow links in your content.
OK, and then after that closing square bracket for the array, I would say comma allowed attributes
and set that to an empty object.
OK, now if we save this and then go back to the browser and refresh.
Markdowns still tried to convert this into a link, but then our sanitized HTML function ran and disallowed
it.
But because I specifically listed out the elements that I do want to allow things like bold or strong
m or italic headings and lists, all of this is still allowed.
Cool.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
If you're curious about markdown and you want to learn more about its syntax, I recommend this website.
It's a wiki on GitHub.
You can type in this URL, or you should just be able to Google for markdown cheat sheet.
This is a great reference.
OK, looking ahead to our next lesson, we are going to work on the ability for a user to delete one
of their existing posts.
This should be exciting because as soon as we finish the delete ability, we can really change gears
and begin working on the live search functionality of our application.
So let's keep things rolling, and I'll see you in the next lesson.