Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to let a user delete one of their existing posts.
Let's dive right into the action.
So if I visit my profile and then visit one of my posts.
We've already set up the functionality for the blue edit icon, now let's work on the red delete icon.
Let's begin by finding this icon in the Ejaz template that powers this screen.
So in our text editor within your Views folder, jump into single dash post dash screen around line
number 13, you'll see a button.
It has a class of delete post button and this button lives within a form element.
Currently this forms action.
Attribute is a placeholder hashtag.
Let's get rid of that hash tag and instead say slash post slash IDE.
And we can make this dynamic in just a moment.
But slash delete.
OK, now let's circle back to I.D. We want that to be dynamic.
So delete that and jump into SJS and we can just say post dot underscore ID cool.
Let's go ahead and save this and now let's jump into our router and set up a root.
So the root of our project folder routed out J.S..
Down at the bottom, we already have this comment post related routes, you can actually just duplicate
this bottom one for the edit post route.
So I will just select that into my clipboard below that, paste it in.
So make sure that this is post not get write a form.
Submit is a post request.
And let's just change the ending segment of the euro from edit to delete.
OK, we would still indeed want to check to make sure the current visitor is logged in.
They must be logged in.
And then for the second function, let's still look within our post controller only.
Let's imagine that we have a function named delete with this in place.
Let's go ahead and save.
And now let's jump into our post controller and create a function with this matching name.
So within our controllers folder, let's dig into post controller Dot J.S. We can scroll down to the
very bottom and just create a brand new function.
Let's say exports dot delete equals a function.
Let's be sure to give this parameters of request and response and let's look inside our model.
So uppercase post and column method named delete.
This doesn't exist yet, but in just a couple of minutes we can set it up.
We can imagine that it will return a promise.
So then at the end we can say dot then dot catch within the parentheses for both then and catch.
Let's provide functions.
I'll use an arrow function, do the same thing for catch.
Now before we worry about what we would want to do if the promise resolves or rejects, let's first
pay attention to what data we should be passing into this function.
First, we would need to give it the ID of the post that we're trying to delete.
So request param idee, comma.
And the second argument should be the idea of the current user that is trying to perform this delete
action.
So request dot visitor.
I said, OK, now if this promise is successful, if it resolves, then on this line let's just add
a green success message that says Post successfully deleted and then we can redirect the user back to
their profile screen.
So request dot flash.
Let's add on to a collection named Success.
Let's go.
The value of post successfully deleted.
OK, then let's manually save our session data or request session save.
Let's give this an arrow function and then we would want to redirect.
So response dot redirect instead of quotes.
Let's actually give this back tick's and let's say slash profile slash and then we would want the current
users username.
Now we know that they would never get to this point in the route unless they already made it past our
must be logged in function.
So we should be safe here to look for our user object with the property of username.
So within the tactics of a template literal, we can say dollar sign curly brackets to do something
dynamic and then let's say request session dot user dot user name.
OK, but what if this promise rejects?
What if it's not a valid post ID or that post doesn't exist or the person that's trying to perform this
is not the owner of that post?
Well, within this catch area, let's just add a flash message request dot flash, add on to a collection
named Errors and let's say you do not have permission to perform that action.
Then let's save our session data request session.
Save within save, provide a function.
And just redirect them back to the home page, so response, redirect the base, you URL actually since
we used an arrow function all on one line.
We do not need the curly brackets around the body of our function so we can also get rid of them on
this line.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and save this, and now we better go into our post model and create a function named
delete.
So in our models folder, jump into post.
Let's scroll down to the very bottom of this post model file right before the closing module DOT exports
line, let's say uppercase post, dot delete, set this to a function within the body of this function.
Remember, we want it to return a promise, so return new promise within the promise parentheses.
Let's provide it an asynchronous arrow functions async parentheses.
Let's give it parameters of resolve and reject arrow symbol curly brackets.
OK, let's give ourselves a try block and right after that a catch block.
Within the tribe block, let's say let post equal and then we can just leverage our find single by IDE
function post dot find single by ID within these parentheses before we give this function what it needs.
Let's first address the parentheses of our outermost function for delete.
Remember when we call this function from within our controller, we're passing into it the requested
post ID.
So let's add a parameter here.
We could make up any name we want, but let's call it post idy to delete comma.
Remember, we're also passing into this function the current visitor ID.
Right, the person that's trying to perform this delete action for this parameter name.
I will say current user I.D..
OK, so that data is now available within this function.
So when we're calling our find single by ID, let's just give it that data post ID to delete and current
user ID.
OK, now remember this function is going to return a promise.
So right before it we can just await then right below this line let's just write an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets right after that including else block, remember that this reuseable
function we created is automatically going to create a property on the post named is visiter owner.
So within these if parentheses if post dot is visiter owner, if that's true, this is where we would
actually want to find that document in the database and delete it else.
Otherwise this is where we would want our promise to reject.
Also, if this catch block ever runs, we would also want to reject.
If this runs, that means the post ID is not valid or the post doesn't exist.
If this LS block runs, that means someone is up to no good trying to delete a post they don't own.
Either way, we want this promise to reject.
OK, but within this if block, this is where we can actually delete that document.
So let's start working with our object that represents the Mongo DB Collection Posts collection.
Let's look inside that and call a method named delete one, but then these parentheses, we just give
it an object and describe the document we're trying to find and delete.
So it would have an underscore.
I'd love to find it.
Let's create a new instance of the Mongo DB Object I.D. Within those parentheses we can just pass in
the post.
Need to delete post.
I need to delete.
OK, this Mongo DB method is going to return a promise, so at the start of this line, let's just be
sure to await that and then right below this line, our promise is ready to resolve.
So just call resolve at this point.
Let's go ahead and save this file and take it for a test drive.
So back in the browser, be sure to refresh.
So this delete form has the updated action value.
OK.
If I click delete.
Well, not quite perfect, but almost there.
So you'll notice that post is gone now.
It was successfully deleted but we didn't see a green success flash message.
I'm pretty sure this is just because we never included the flash code at the top of the profile template.
Let's do that right now.
So back in your views folder, let's jump into a template that we know we can copy and paste from.
So if we jump in to edit post, for example, we just want to copy this flash command that pulls in
that shareable includes for the flash code.
So copy that into your clipboard and then let's jump into our profile template up at the top, right
below this container div just dropdown and paste in your clipboard.
OK, let's go ahead and save this.
And now back in the browser, I can test things out by trying to delete this post that's named Sample
Post No.
One.
So click on to that.
Click the delete icon.
Perfect.
We no longer see it in my list of posts.
It's been deleted and there's the success message.
Let's test out the permission logic that we set up.
So, for example, in this window, I'm logged in with the Brat account, but in this window I'm logged
in with the Bark's a lot account.
Let me show you how we can test this out.
So in a secondary account, I can create a post dog post.
No one content here.
Submit that.
OK, now try this out with me.
Let's pretend that the barks a lot of count is someone who's malicious and is trying to delete someone
else's post.
Well, first of all, someone like this would probably use a tool like Post Man to send requests, but
this is an easy way to do it right from within your browser.
If I.
Right.
Click on the delete icon and choose inspect, I can see that form element and here's its action.
So I could just change the ID portion of the are to be one of the IDs for a post by the Brat account.
So for example, the Brat account has this post named yet another post and anyone can publicly view
that and see it's posted in your address bar.
So imagine if I copied that into my clipboard and then back in this window where I'm the malicious barks
a lot user, I could just modify the form action you rl to use Brads post ID.
OK, now if I click this red icon I should see a failed message.
Perfect.
It kicks me back to the home page.
You do not have permission to perform that action.
Beautiful, but if I go back to Bachs alot profile and click on a post that I actually own and try to
delete it that goes through without any problems.
Excellent.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close.
In our next lesson, we're going to start work on a new feature in the header.
You might notice this search icon.
Well, when the user clicks on that, it should use front end or browser based JavaScript to open a
full screen search interface.
And then as a user types in what they're looking for, after every keystroke, we can query our server
for live results.
Not only is this a great chance to practice our front end JavaScript, but it should also make our app
really feel tied together because as you can see from your empty home page, your feed is empty.
The search feature is how you can find content from other users and then follow those users.
But for right now, let's not get ahead of ourselves too far and worry about following a user.
For now, let's stay focused on the search feature.
I'm excited to dig into this with you in the next lesson.
So let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.