Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to learn how we can, quote, trust an incoming request.
Let me explain what I mean by this when I say trust.
So imagine I perform a successful log in, so we type in my correct username and password.
So, yes, immediately following that form submit, we are able to respond with either congrats or invalid
username and password.
However, as soon as that HTTP request is complete, right, as soon as our server responds to that
login request that marks the end of the life cycle for that HTTP request.
And from that moment forward, the server now has no memory of the browser and the browser has no memory
of the server.
So the server has its immediate response of success or failure.
But if this user goes back to the home page, the server has no memory that this visitor just entered
the correct username and password.
Right.
The Web browser is still seeing the guest or registration home page when instead it would make more
sense for them to see the actual application that would look something like this.
Right.
So now the top right, instead of having a login form, has basic actions in a sign out button and the
home page should be your feed of content from those you follow.
So this would say hello and then this would be your dynamic username.
So maybe hello, Brad.
Your feed is empty.
However, we have not set this up yet because up until this point in the course, we have not learned
how to set things up so the server can trust an incoming request.
You might have heard the phrase before that HTTP requests are statelets.
That's really just a fancy way of saying that each request is ran without any knowledge of the requests
that came before it.
So the question becomes, how can we solve this case of amnesia that the browser and server have?
Or after a user submits a valid username and password to the login form, how can the server trust subsequent
requests from that browser?
Well, the answer is that there are two primary technologies that can solve this issue of identifying
or trusting subsequent requests.
So the first technology is sessions and the second is tokens.
We will learn about tokens later in the course, but for now, we're going to begin with sessions.
Now, in recent years, there's been a lot of debate over whether you should use sessions or tokens.
But it's not my job to force a personal opinion on you.
So I'm not going to weigh in on the sessions versus tokens debate.
It's as simple as this.
We're going to start with sessions.
And then later in the course, when we set up a simple API for our application, we will learn how to
use tokens.
This way you can see both technologies in action and you can form your own opinions about which one
makes more sense for a particular situation.
I'll just say this.
It's my personal opinion that you don't need to dogmatically choose one over the other.
They are both valuable tools to have in your toolbox.
All right.
Having said all of that, let's get started learning about sessions instead of trying to explain sessions
with just words.
I think it's best to first see sessions and action and then I can explain things further from there.
So first, let's go enable sessions within our express application.
So let's jump into our text editor.
And the first thing we need to do is go out to NPM and pick up a package.
So open up your command line.
And if your app is already running press control, see to stop and let's run NPM install.
And the name of the package is Express Dasch session.
OK, so npm install, express dash session and press enter.
OK, now that we've installed that package, let's go ahead and tell our server to start running again.
So npm run watch.
OK, and let's go leverage that new package.
So I want you to open up the file named App Jass.
So remember this is sort of our top level file where we are requiring the express framework.
We are enabling different features.
We're setting the directory for our views, so on and so forth.
So this is also where we would want to in.
Abel Sessions maybe right below this very first line, let's add a new line and let's say CONSED session
equals and then just require in that new package, so require in the name of it was Express Dasch session.
OK, now let's go leverage that.
So below this concept app equals express line.
Let's add a new line and we need to spell out a few configuration options for how we want to use sessions.
So let's create a variable and we could call it anything, but let's call it session options and then
let's set this to equal and then let's leverage that new package.
So we'll call a session within the parentheses.
We want to provide it an object.
So curly brackets, and now we just provide a few different properties or options.
So first, let's provide a secret so secret colon and then set it to a value so you could just type
in a bunch of random characters.
But why don't we say JavaScript is so cool?
Honestly, it doesn't matter what you include here, it should just be something that someone couldn't
guess.
OK, then let's include a comma and set up another property, let's say receive and set it to false
karma.
Let's include another property, let's say save on unsocialized and colon set that the false as well.
These are just boring configuration options that are not worth memorizing.
This is just boilerplate configuration code that you would only ever need to write once and then just
reference again for your future projects.
OK, let's include a comma and another property and let's say cookie colon and let's set it to an object
because it should have several sub properties.
So the first is Max H Colon.
And this is how long the cookie for a session should be valid before it expires.
It's measured in milliseconds.
So to calculate this, we could say one thousand to represent one thousand milliseconds as one second
and then we can times that by 60.
So 60 seconds is a minute and then we can multiply that by 60 to simulate an hour and then there are
twenty four hours in a day.
So this is measured in milliseconds, but this would represent one day before the cookie expires.
OK, still within the curly brackets, let's include a comma and say htp only colon and set that to
true.
OK, so that completes our configuration or settings to enable sessions.
Now we just need to tell expressed to actually use this.
So right below this we can say at dot use and within the use parentheses would just include our session
options, session options.
Cool.
Our Express app now supports sessions.
Now I realize we still have no idea what a session is, but we're almost there.
Hang in there with me.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And now I want you to jump in to our user controller file.
So within our controllers folder, let's open up user controller lagus.
So within our login function, here's the line that says user login.
That's going to return a promise.
We know that if a promise is successful or resolves the function inside of the then will run.
If the promise rejects, then the catch will run.
So if someone types in a correct username and password, we would want to log them in.
Or in other words, this is where we would want to leverage sessions.
So within the body of this function that's going to arrive, the promise is successful.
Right before this response starts, send line.
Let's add a new line and let's say request or RFQ dot session and now we can add new properties on to
this session object.
Let's make up a property named user.
There's nothing special about this word.
I just made it up.
This could be literally anything.
The idea is that our request object now has this new session object that is unique per browser visitor.
So I'm going to add a new property onto that session object called user and let's set that to equal
an object.
Now, within this object, we can store any information we want and that will be specific or unique
to this one visitor or Web browser.
So we could make up all sorts of different properties.
We could say favorite color Colen quotes blue, and then we could include a comma and include another.
Property just for fun, why don't we include a username, property, so username and set that to equal
user data username, right.
Or the value of the username that they just successfully logged in with.
Now, here's the cool part.
Remember earlier when we said that HTTP requests are stateless and they have no memory of the previous
requests?
Well, the whole idea of a session is that it allows us to have some sort of persistent data from one
request to another, meaning our server is going to remember this session data.
In other words, we can use this session data from any of our use URLs or routes to check this out.
Let's use this session data if someone visits the homepage or base you around.
So within this user controller file that scroll down towards the bottom.
Remember, we have this function named home and our router is going to call this function when someone
visits the base forward, slash or root of our website within the body of this function.
Let's do this.
Let's cut this line of code into our clipboard.
So this line that says response dot render home guest.
We're going to want this in just another 10 seconds.
Let's cut that into our clipboard.
But let's write an if statement.
Let's say, if the current visitor or browser has session data associated with it, let's send them
a custom message that says hello and welcome to the application.
Or else if they don't have any session data associated with them, let's just send them that guest home
page.
So if parentheses curly brackets drop down right after the closing, if brackets, let's say else curly
brackets.
So for our condition within the if parentheses, let's say if request session user write, because the
only way that this user object would ever exist on the session object is if they just performed a successful
login.
So within the if block, let's just say response dot send welcome to the actual application and then
within the else block.
This is where you can just paste back in your clipboard.
Right.
If they are not logged in, if they don't have any session data, send them the guest template.
All right, let's go ahead and save this file and test it out.
So back in the Web browser, let's perform a successful login type in your correct values.
We see the same old congrats message, but if we send a new request to the base, you orell so if I
get rid of the log in and just visit localhost three thousand, you might need to hit refresh one more
time, but awesome.
We see.
Welcome to the actual application.
And no matter how many times I refresh or send a new request, the server remembers that this browser
visitor has session data associated with it.
So according to our logic, that means they are logged in just to test things out.
If I visit this same Nual in an incognito window or a different browser entirely.
So this window is Google Chrome, this is Mozilla Firefox and you can see if I visit localhost three
thousand and Firefox, the server still correctly identifies me as a guest.
I don't see that.
Welcome to the actual app message.
At this point, you might be wondering how is this working from a technology standpoint?
How is the server identifying this unique web browser or visitor or request?
Well, the answer is that it has to do with cookies.
So when a visitor typed in correct username and password values, meaning this code ran well, when
we leveraged the session object here, two things happened.
So no one, as we already covered our server, is going to store this session data in memory.
And number two, what the session package is also going to do is send instructions to the Web browser
to create a cookie.
If you have no idea what a cookie is, that's OK.
Let me show you right now, let me show you how to view your cookies in Google Chrome.
The process is very similar in other Web browsers as well.
So.
Right.
Click anywhere on the webpage and choose.
Inspect.
This will open your developer tools and now within these tabs where I would usually have you click on
the console instead of console, look for one of these tabs that is named application.
I have my developer tools zoomed in so that it's easier to see on the screen recorder.
But if I zoom out, you can see here is the application tab, if yours is zoomed in as well.
It might just be hidden under these extra arrows here.
Big picture.
I want you to click on the application tab from within your developer tools.
If you're using Firefox instead of Google Chrome, you would look for a tab named storage instead of
application.
OK, but within Google Chrome from the application tab, within this left hand sidebar, under storage,
we see an area named cookies.
If you expand the cookies option, you'll see a listing for your current domain.
So in this case, localhost column three thousand.
If you click on that, you will see all of the cookies for this domain.
In this case, there's only one cookie.
So our session package sent instructions to the browser to create a cookie with the name of Connect
Side.
And this is the important part.
It has a unique value.
Now, this value is a unique identifier for that particular bit of session data that's being stored
in the servers memory.
Once a Web browser has a cookie, it's going to send any and all cookies for the current domain back
to the server with every single request.
And this is going to happen automatically.
So now any time I visit any localhost, call in three thousand neutrals.
My Google Chrome Web browser is going to send this cookie and value back to the node server.
So our server is going to see this unique identifier value and our server will say, aha.
The only way that you would know this unique session identifier is if I just sent it to you in a cookie.
So the server says the fact that, you know, this session value, that means I can trust you or I can
trust that you're the same person or the same Web browser that just typed in that correct username and
password.
Right.
You're the same person or same browser that I just sent this value to a moment ago.
If you're still a bit confused and you're not quite sure how all of this is working, that's OK.
One of the big difficulties in this lesson so far is that here we've seen a visual representation of
a cookie, but we still haven't seen a visual representation of the session data that's being stored
in memory on the server.
But don't worry, that's exactly what we're going to take a look at in our very next lesson.
Now, before we jump into our next lesson, I do want to cover one detail that can potentially be frustrating
in this lesson.
So currently our server is storing session data in memory.
Now, storing values in memory is not permanent at all.
Right.
As soon as a computer shuts down or restarts, its memory is cleared or reset.
And remember, when we run the command NPM run watch, we set things up so that our server is going
to restart automatically any time we save a change to any file.
So for now, because I haven't saved any new changes to the server, I can continue to send new requests
to this domain.
And it continues to remember me.
It remembers my session data, however, and you can try this out with me if you go into your user controller
and if you just add a random comment or even come down to the bottom and where it says welcome to the
actual application.
And if I just add on a couple more exclamation points and then hit save, that's going to trigger that
automatic restart of our server.
And when you restart a computer, its memory is cleared.
So now if I try to send a request to that domain because it cleared all of that session data that was
in memory, the server does not remember me.
So to get around this, instead of storing session data in memory, let's store session data in our
Mongo DB database.
Not only is this a more robust way of storing data, but it will also let us visualize a piece of session
data, which I think is really helpful.
To be able to see the session data on the server or in the database with your own two eyes should be
a big help.
So let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.