Hello, everyone.
In this lesson, we are going to learn how to set up a user avatar or profile photo.
So as we can see here, once you're logged in in this top right menu, it's going to show your avatar
or little profile photo.
Now, for the moment, this is hard coded to a placeholder image of a cat, but we would want this to
be specific to the currently logged in user also, once we add the ability to let users create posts.
This is the photo that would show up alongside a post, right.
It would show the photo of the author for that post.
So we're going to use this profile photo in several places throughout our application.
But in this lesson, we're just going to focus on the top right menu.
All right.
Now to power this feature.
We are going to leverage a service named Granovetter.
If you've never heard of Gravitron, just stands for globally recognized Avatar.
Essentially, you sign up or register for an Avatar account and then potentially any website in the
world can pull in your aggravator based on your email address.
So, for example, instead of me being logged in with the puppy account, imagine I was logged in with
my cat at cat dot com account and imagine I had a Gravitron account that used that email address.
Well, if you.
Right.
Click on this profile photo and choose open image in new tab, you can see the URL for that image.
So it's just graviton dotcom slash avatar and then a hash tag value.
And then at the end there's a size parameter where you can say how large the image should be.
Now the thing we want to focus on here is the hash.
This is just the user's email address, but Hashd using the MD five library.
The reason this is so cool is because now we can show this photo publicly on our Web application.
Right.
So on any articles created by this user.
But we aren't publicly leaking that user's email address.
If anyone comes to our website, this is the Eurail they're going to see.
And remember, pashing is a one way street.
There's no way for someone to decrypt this back into the user's email address.
So this graviton system is going to give us the best of both worlds.
We can pull in a profile photo by simply knowing a user's email address, but we're not revealing that
email address to anyone that views that photo.
All right.
Now, without further ado, let's jump into our text editor and begin working on this feature.
I want you to open up your uppercase user JS model file because this feature relies on the data for
a user.
It makes sense to include this in a model.
Let's go ahead and create a new function.
So I'm going to scroll down towards the bottom and maybe right above this module, the exports line.
Let's add a new line and let's say uppercase user dot, prototype dot.
Let's make up a function name.
Let's call it git avatar.
OK, let's set that to equal a function, OK?
And within this function, let's just set this DOT avatar.
So we're just going to add a new property onto our main object and let's set this to equal.
And then instead of a string of text using quotes, let's create a template literal with back ticks
within the two back text.
Type out this you with me htp s Colen forward slash forward slash gravois tar dot com slash avatar slash
email.
And then we can include a parameter that says how large the photo should be.
So questionmark s equals and let's say one hundred and twenty eight pixels.
Cool.
Now all we need to do to make this actually work is replace the word email here with the current user's
email address.
But Hashd using the MD five library.
Don't worry, we're going to walk through this step by step.
So right now, let's go out to the JavaScript grocery store or NPM and pick up the MD five package.
So open up your command line.
If your app is running press control, see to stop and let's install a package.
So NPM install in the name of the package is M d five.
This will give us access to the specific hashing algorithm that the gravitas service expects.
So let's go ahead and press enter to install this.
OK, then let's tell our app to start running again, so npm run watch.
OK, within this user model file, let's go require in that new package, so scroll up to the very top,
maybe right below this validator line, let's add a new line and just say const M.D. five equals and
then require in that package package name was MDE five.
OK, now let's just leverage this so that scroll back down to the bottom within our new git avatar function.
And because this is a template literal using these tactics, check this out, we can just hollow out
or delete the word email here and in its place we can say dollar sign curly brackets.
And now within these curly brackets, we can do something dynamic.
So let's use the MD five package parentheses to call it, and then we just pass it in email address.
So to get the current user's email, we can just say this dot data.
Dot email.
Cool.
So now a user object will have a property named Avatar.
That is a huge URL that points towards a photo.
Now we just need to call this function at the appropriate times.
So first, let's go call it once a user has successfully logged in.
So within this same file, we can just scroll up and look for our login function.
Here it is.
User dot, prototype dot login.
OK.
And if the login attempt was successful, so that would be this area where we say resolve.
So right above this resolve line, let's just call our this dot get avatar function.
Right.
That's going to populate a property named Avatar on our object.
OK, that takes care of logging in.
Let's also call our avatar function when a user successfully registers.
So if you scroll down a little bit, we should see our register function, right?
User dot, prototype, dot register.
And again, if this registration is successful, this is that area.
Right.
We're going to call resolve.
So right before we call resolve right above that line, let's just call this dot, get Avatar.
I should explain why I'm including this after the database action.
It's because I don't actually want to store the avatar.
You are in the database permanently, right?
Because what if in the future the gravitas service changes there you are URL structure.
At that point, I would have to go through every user account in my database and update their Avatar
database field.
I wouldn't want to do that.
Instead, it makes more sense to just generate there you are on the fly when we need it.
It's not a big deal because an MD five hashing operation is a very cheap, quick operation.
So in other words, I'm not worried about storing this permanently in the database.
I'm just storing this in memory on the user object.
Let's go ahead and save this file and then let's jump into our user controller and actually leverage
that Avatar property on our object.
So within your controllers folder, jump into the file named user controller Dot J.S. and let's work
on the login feature first and then the register feature.
So if a user successfully logs in, this is where we are storing a bit of session data about that current
user.
So check this out.
Instead of this made up property of favorite color, let's just change this.
Change the proper name from fav color to Avatar.
And for the value, let's just get rid of quotes blue and instead say lower case user dot avatar.
Right.
Just two lines above this.
We just created a user variable using our model as a blueprint.
So we know that in memory there's going to be a property named Avatar on that object.
Cool.
And we're saving it in a session.
So as long as that user stays logged in, we don't need to calculate their avatar again.
Before we save this file, let's go do the same thing in our register function.
So scroll down, OK?
If a user successfully registers, we are setting a bit of session data.
The first property we're setting is username, but let's just go ahead and set another property avatar
and just set it to user dot avatar.
OK, and now the question becomes, how can we access that piece of session data from within our home
dashboard HTML template?
Because ultimately that's where we want to use this data, right.
We would want to update the source attribute of this image element.
So to accomplish this within this same user controlled or not JS file, let's just scroll down to our
home function.
So on this line, if we users logged in, we're going to read.
There are home dashboard HTML template, and for this second argument where we pass data into the template,
you can see we're already sending it a username that's being pulled from session data.
So let's just do the same thing for Avatar.
So right after this session, user username, just Atacama.
We want to add one more property and let's just say Avatar Colen and give it a value of request session.
Dot user.
Dot Avatar.
Cool.
Now, let's go ahead and save this.
And now let's jump in to that HTML template and actually leverage this piece of data.
So within our project folder, I want you to look within your views, Subfolder.
And let's open up our file that is named Home Dash Dashboard, Dot, SJS.
Within this template, on about line number 20, we see an opening, a tag, and within it we see an
opening image tag within this image element, let's find its source attribute.
So if I scroll over.
Here we see Source or SAAC, and it's currently pointed towards a hardcoded gravity euro, so let's
hollow out or delete the source values.
So within the quotes, just delete everything.
OK, so now our source attribute is just an empty pair of quotes within these quotes, we want to do
something dynamic because we are within an Aegis template.
We can just say less than percentage.
And then to close that, it's percentage greater than in between these two tags, we can just say Avatar,
right.
That property is getting passed into our template now because we don't just want to access this, but
we actually want to output it or print it.
We want to include an equal sign right after this opening percentage.
OK, let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So back in the browser, I'm going to sign out to give the server a chance to regenerate a new session
for me using all of our new code and new logic.
So sign out and then let's sign back in so it generates a new session.
Cool, so there's the default or fallback avatar profile icon, the account that I just logged in with
has an email address of Brad at Brad dot com, which obviously is not a real email address, but to
test this out and truly see it.
User profile photo here.
If I log back out and if I register for an account using my real email address.
So, Brad, to and for the email choose a password.
And if I go ahead and sign up.
Awesome, you can see let me zoom in, even for you, it successfully pulled in my profile photo from
Avatar, you can test this out yourself by signing up for a graviton account and then whatever email
address you sign up for Graviton with, just use that email address when you sign up on our sample application.
Cool.
So it remembered me when I registered.
And if I sign out and signed back into that brand to account, it should also be able to calculate and
pull in my Gravitron.
Woops, it's actually only pulling in the default photo, so there's a problem here, I'm pretty sure
I know exactly what the issue is, so be sure to follow along and perform this fix with me.
All we need to do back in our text editor, jump into your uppercase user JS model file and within the
model's login function before we call our git avatar function, we need to make sure that our users
email address is present on this object because the user only typed in their username and password to
log in and not their email address.
We need to grab the associated email with that user account from the database.
Now, luckily, we already have this attempted user that represents the associated user document in
the database.
So right before we call this doGet avatar, let's just say this DOT data and let's just populated with
the database data.
So attempted user cool.
So now when our get avatar function runs, it's going to have access to the user's email address.
Let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
So if I log out.
And then log back in with that brand to account, right, to give it a chance to regenerate my session.
Perfect, there is the profile photo that's going to bring this lesson to a close and more importantly,
that's going to bring this chapter or section to a close.
Now that we've set up the basic functionality of registering and logging in and out, we can finally
move on to the first real feature of our app, which is letting users create posts or articles.
It should be a lot of fun to change gears and work on something completely new, and it's going to feel
like we're making a ton of progress on our app.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next section.