Hello and welcome to this
Python tutorial.
Alright so now, time for the exciting steps.
We are going to create the architecture of
the newel network, that is the architecture of the RBM.
So we will choose the number of hidden notes,
and mostly, we will build the newel network
just like how it works, that is,
we're gonna make this probability graphical model.
Because, let's remember, a restricted Boltzmann machine
is a probability graphical model.
Alright, and to build this probability graphical model,
we will do it through a class.
Classes are the most practical way to build,
to create anything in Python.
If you want to create a house or a self-driving car
you would use a class because basically,
what is a class?
A class is an ensemble of instructions.
It's the model of something we want to build.
So, for example: if we want to build a house,
well, we need a model home;
we need some instructions on how to build a house
and that's what the class will contain.
So, the guy that will make the class will be the architect.
Because it will define how the house should be built.
And then once the class is made
we can create some objects of this class.
And the objects are nothing else than the houses.
And now that's exactly the same for RBM model.
We are gonna be the architect of this model.
We need to make a class that will define
how the RBM should be built.
And so, in this class, we're gonna give all the info
that we need to build an RBM.
And so, what are these infos?
Well, first that's the number of hidden notes,
then that's the weights.
The weights for the probability of the visible note,
given the hidden note.
Then the bias for the same probability
and also, the bias for the probability
of the visible note given the hidden note.
So these are first parameters that we need
to initialize the RBM.
And so, we will put all this in the first function
called "_init_", but then in a class
we can add more things besides
the parameters that define the model.
We can also add some functions just as an architect
can add tools when making the model of a house.
Or if you wanna have a more intuitive example,
well, if we want to make a self-driving car,
well, the self-driving car will need a lot of functions.
Some functions to recognize objects on the street.
Then some functions to turn right, to turn left,
to move forward, to move backward,
or to stop when there is an obstacle on the street.
Well, we would need functions for all this
and these functions are all defined in the class.
And here again, that's the same for our RBM class.
We're gonna define some functions
beside the _init_ function that will do all the actions
that take place in an RBM model.
And these actions are to sample
the hidden notes and the visible notes.
So, to summarize, we're gonna make 3 functions.
1 function to initialize the RBM
of jig that will be created afterwords.
Then the second function will be sample H,
that will sample the probabilities of the hidden notes
given the visible notes.
And eventually we'll make a third function.
Which will be sample V.
And that will sample the probabilities of the visible notes
given the hidden notes.
So, 1 class, 3 functions to make.
Let's make the first one in this tutorial.
Alright, so first, we need to define the class
and to define a class in Python we need to
start with class then we give a name to this class.
And the name of the class should be in capitols.
Well, the first letter should be a capitol letter,
but we can also put only capitol letters, like this,
RBM; so that's the name of our class.
And then some parenthesis and then colon.
Alright, and inside this class is going to be
everything that will define what we want to create,
that is, our RBM model.
Alright so, we said that the first function
we need to make is the _init_ function
and that actually happens in every class.
You always have to start with the _init_ function
because this _init_ function is to define the parameters
of the object that will be created once the class is made.
So this one is a default compulsory function
and we define it this way, with a double underscore,
init, and another double underscore.
Then some parenthesis.
And now I'm going to input 3 arguments.
The first argument is a default argument
that is here all the time and that is self.
And self, there is no mystery about it,
self corresponds to the object
that will be created afterwords.
And we need this argument because
we're gonna define some variables and we will need to
specify that these variables are the variables of the object
that will be created afterwords
and not some global variables.
All the variables that are attached to the object
will be created by putting a self before the variable.
You will see that very quickly.
So that's the first argument.
And now we're gonna input two other arguments.
The first argument is NV,
and that's the number of visible notes.
And then, a third argument, which is going to be NH.
And that is, of course, the number of hidden notes.
So these are just the parameters of the _init_ function,
but then we need to define what's going to initialize.
We need to initialize the weight and the bias.
So, now to define how the initialization is going to work,
we need to add a column here and then
go inside the function by pressing enter.
And so, now, what we are going to do inside this function
is initialize the parameters of our future object.
The object that we will create from this class.
So, basically, what we will initialize inside this _init_
function are going to be all the parameters that we will
optimize during the training of the RBM.
That is, the weights and the bias.
And since these parameters are specific to the RBM model,
that is, to our future objects that we're going to create
from the RBM class, well, that's what I just told you.
We need to specify that these variables are the variables
of the object and, therefore, to initialize these
variables, we need to start with self then dot and then
the name of the variable.
So, let's start with the weights.
We need to initialize the weights and
we're gonna call them W.
Why capitol W?
Because all the weights are going to be initialized
in a torched tensor.
And so, these weights are all the parameters of
the probabilities of the visible notes
given the hidden notes.
And so, according to the theory, they are initialized
in a matrix of size and H, number of hidden notes,
and NV, the number of visible notes.
And since we're working with PyTorch, well,
this matrix is going to be a torched tensor, remember?
It's tensor is a matrix of one single type.
Alright, so now that we know what we have to do,
we need to use torch, the torch library.
And now we're gonna use a function
that will initialize all these weights.
And so, you know since these weights have to be
initialized randomly according to a normal distribution,
well, we need to use this rendn function because
it will initialize all the weights in our tensor.
And as we just said, this tensor
should be of size and H and NV.
Alright, so to sum up this torch dot rendn NH and NV
initializes a tensor of size NH NV.
According to a normal distribution,
and besides this normal distribution has a
mean of 0 and a variance of 1.
Okay good, so that initializes all the weights
for the probabilities.
P of the visible notes according to the hidden notes.
Alright now, let's initialize the bias.
We also need to initialize the bias.
And remember there is some bias for the probability
of the hidden note given the visible note
and some bias for the probability of the visible note
given the hidden note.
So lets start with the bias for the probabilities of
the hidden notes given the visible notes.
PH given V.
So that's the same, we have to give a name to these bias.
And so for these first bias, we're gonna give the name A.
And I took my self object because
A is a parameter of the object.
So self does A and then equals and then again we take
our torch library then dot and then again we're gonna take
our rendn function to initialize the weights
according to normal distribution of mean 0
and variance 1.
And so now, since there is one bias for each hidden note
and we have NH hidden note,
well, we need to create a vector of an H element.
That is, we're gonna have a vector of NH element
all initialized to some numbers that follow
a normal distribution.
But we need to create an additional dimension
corresponding to the batch, and therefore,
this vector shouldn't have 1 dimension,
like a single input vector, it should have 2 dimensions.
The first dimension corresponding to the batch
and the second dimension corresponding to the bias.
And so, why do we need to create this
fake dimension for the batch?
Well, that's always for the same reason.
It's because the functions that we're gonna use
then in PyTorch cannot accept a single input vector
of one dimension as argument, but a two dimensional
tensor with the first dimension corresponding to the batch
and the second dimension corresponding to the bias.
So that's why here, we cannot put directly NH, like this,
but we need to add a 1 first.
So that creates a 2-D tensor with this one here
corresponding to the first dimension that is the batch.
And this NH element here corresponding to the bias.
Alright?
And now we have a third parameter to define
that is still specific to the object that will be created,
that is our RBM model, and that is the bias for,
this time, the visible notes.
And so that's the same, we need to take our torch
dot rendn function, but this time we have not NH,
but NV, visible note, while we initialize the tensor
of NV element with one additional dimension
corresponding to the batch.
So that makes a 2-D tensor and this tensor has
NV element in this second dimension.
Alright, and that's all we need to initialize
our future objects of the RBM class.
So that's perfect.
We can now move on to the second step
of the creation of the architecture of the newel network.
And this second step consists of making the function
that will sample the hidden note.
So we will explain and do all this in the next
tutorial and until then, enjoy deep learning!