Hello and welcome
to this new, very important tutorial.
Please make sure to have some energy for this one,
and please make sure to focus,
because there are some important tricks
that we will make sure to understand and apply,
and some mistakes to absolutely avoid.
So, if you have the good energy, let's get started.
Alright, so, in this second step of part three,
making the predictions and visualizing the results,
we're gonna get the predicted stock price of January, 2017.
So, that is we're gonna use our regressor,
and we're gonna predict the Google stock prices
of January, 2017.
Now, the first thing to understand
is that we trained our model to be able to predict
the stock price at time T plus one,
based on the 60 previous stock prices,
and, therefore, to predict each stock price
of each financial day of January, 2017,
we will need the 60 previous stock prices
of the 60 previous financial days, before the actual day.
That's the first key point to understand.
Now, second key point is that in order
to get at each day of January, 2017,
the 60 previous stock prices of the 60 previous days,
well, we will need both the training set and the test set,
because we will have some of the 60 days
that will be from the training set,
because they will be from December 2016,
and we will also have some stock prices of the test set,
because some of them will come from January 2017,
and, therefore, the first thing we need to do now,
is some concatenation of the training set and the test set,
to be able to get these 60 produced inputs,
for each day of January, 2017, alright?
But then that leads to a third key point to understand,
it's the way we're gonna make that concatenation.
If you think of making this concatenation
by concatenating the training set and the test set,
that is by concatenating this training set here,
which contains the real Google stock prices from 2012
to the end of 2016,
well, if you can concatenate the training set
with the test set that is the real stock price
that we got here, well, that will lead us to a problem,
because then what we will have to do
is scale this concatenation
of the training set and the test set.
That is we will have to apply the fit_transform method
from our sc object that we created
in the feature scaling section
to scale this concatenation of the training set
and the test set,
so that we can get the scaled real stock price.
But the problem if we do that is that
we will change the actual test values
and we should never do this.
We have to keep the actual test values as they are,
and, therefore, we will handle this problem
by making another concatenation,
which will be to concatenate the original DataFrames
that we still have because these are dataset_train,
and we also have dataset_test.
These are the two original DataFrames and we will get,
of course, the open Google stock price,
so we will make this concatenation
and then what we'll do is, from this concatenation,
we will get the input of each prediction,
that is the 60 produced stock prices at each time T,
and this is then what we will scale.
These are on these inputs.
That's where we'll apply our sc object.
These inputs that we will scale to get the predictions,
and that way we are only scaling the input,
and we are not changing the actual test values,
and this is the right approach to take.
This is what will lead us to the most relevant results,
and that was the third and final key point to understand,
so if you understood these three key points,
you are now ready to understand 100% this tutorial.
And just, for those of you who are wondering
why we have to scale the input,
well that's simply because our recurrent neural network
was trained on the scaled values of the train set.
Therefore, for consistency of the model, well,
we will have to use the scaled input to get our predictions,
and the scaled input should be based on the same scaling
that's replied that is normalization with our sc object.
So, if all this is clear,
now it's time to get these predictions.
So, let's do this.
As we said, we need to start by concatenating
the original DataFrames containing
the open Google stock prices,
and to do this we're gonna introduce a new variable
that we're gonna call dataset_total.
Total, because it will contain the whole dataset;
the training set, plus the test set,
and so to make this concatenation happen,
we're gonna use our super useful library that we have,
which is of course Pandas, and then has a shortcut pd,
and we're gonna use a function from this Panda's library,
which is, you might know it, the concat function.
Alright, and inside this concat function
we need to input two arguments.
The first one is the grepl of the two DataFrames
we want to concatenate,
and the second argument is the axis along which
we want to make that concatenation.
So that is, do we want to concatenate the lines?
Or do we want to concatenate the colors?
So, we'll see that very quickly,
and so let's take care of the first arguments, first;
which is this couple of what we want to concatenate,
and these are the two DataFrames, first.
Dataset_train, which contains the Google stock prices
from 2012-2016, and of course dataset_test,
which contains the Google stock prices of January, 2017.
Alright, so, let's take them,
dataset_train, first.
Which will be concatenated to dataset_test.
Alright, good?
But then remember that these DataFrames, dataset_train
and dataset_test, contain the whole dataset.
It contains, not only the open Google stock prices,
but also the closed one,
and some more data like the volumes,
and we just want the open Google stock price
so the trick to get it is to add some square brackets here,
and inside of which, add some quotes,
inside of which you add the name of the column
you want to get and this is, if you remember,
the name is Open.
So, you just need to put in quotes here, Open,
and same for our other DataFrame,
which is dataset_test['Open'].
Like that.
Alright?
So, and this dataset_train['Open'] and dataset_test['Open']
in the parenthesis, is the first argument
of the concat function, and so now,
let's add the second argument,
which is the axis along which
you want to make that concatenation.
So, of course, we want to concatenate the lines.
We want to add the stock prices of the test set
to the stock prices of the training set,
and, therefore, we need to make a concatenation
along the vertical axis and so to specify this,
we need to add this second argument here,
which is axis and the vertical axis is labeled by zero.
Alright?
So, basically, for a horizontal concatenation,
you would use axis equals 1,
and for vertical concatenation
like what we have to do now, it's axis equals zero.
Okay?
So, this will concatenate and it will get a whole DataFrame
containing the open Google stock price of both
the training set, that is from 2012 to 2016,
and the test set, that is of January, 2017.
Perfect.
First step; done.
Second step, now the second step is to get the inputs,
that I told you about, that is at each time T,
or if you want at each financial day of January 2017,
we need to get the 60 previous stock prices
of the 60 previous financial days.
Or if you want the stock prices
of the three previous months,
because there are 20 financial days in one month,
and, therefore, 60 financial days would make three months.
Right?
We are training our regressor to predict the stock price
at time T plus one, based on what it observed,
what it remembered during the three previous months.
So, now, to get these inputs, we're gonna start this way.
We're gonna start by introducing a new variable
that we're gonna call inputs.
Alright.
Inputs equals, and we're still gonna keep
the DataFrame for now,
then of course that will change,
but we're gonna get what we're interested in
still from our dataset total DataFrame.
Alright, so let's think about this.
We want to predict the stock prices of January 2017.
So, what are gonna be exactly the inputs
we are going to need?
Well, let's see.
For the first financial day of 2017,
we will need the 60 previous financial days
before this first financial day of 2017,
which I remind is January 3rd,
and so that means that the lower bounds
of the range of input needs,
will be the first financial day of January, 2017 minus 60,
and then what is going to be the upper bound?
Well, to get the upper bound, we need to think
what input we'll need to predict
the last financial day of January, 2017,
and that will be the 60 previous financial days
before this last day of January 2017,
and therefore the last stock price we'll need in the input,
will be the previous stock price just before
the last stock price that we predict, and therefore,
this will be the last stock price of our dataset total
and therefore, now what we're gonna get
is first our dataset_total,
because were getting these stock prices from our DataFrame,
dataset total so far, and therefore, as we said,
we're gonna need the stock prices
from the first financial day of 2017 minus 60,
up to the last stock price of our whole dataset.
Alright, so let's first get the lower bound
of these range of inputs we need.
This lower bound is the stock price at January 3rd minus 60.
So, let's first get January 3rd.
To get January 3rd we can take it this way.
We need to find the index of January 3rd,
which we can get this way.
We take the len of the total dataset, dataset_total,
and then we subtract to it the len of our dataset_test.
Alright this gives us exactly January 3rd,
because len(dataset_total) is the final index
of the whole dataset containing
both the training and the test set,
and len(dataset_test) is exactly 20.
So, since len(dataset_total) will be the index
of the last day of January, 2017,
well if we subtract this by 20,
we will get to January 3, 2017;
the first day, the first financial day of January, 2017
and now, remember we wanna get the stock price
at this day minus 60
because that's the lower bound of the inputs we need,
and therefore I'm adding here minus 60.
Perfect.
We get the lower bounds,
and now much easier to get the upper bound,
we simply need to add this column,
because basically the upper bound, as we said,
is the last index of the whole dataset,
because to predict the last stock price
of the last financial day,
we will need the 60 previous stock prices,
and, therefore, the last of the last stock prices we'll need
is the stock price just before the last financial day.
So, there we go.
That's the range of inputs we need
and now with this we get the DataFrame,
but of course we're gonna have to move on
to NumPy Arrays now and, therefore,
I'm adding dot values to make this a NumPy Array,
and these will contain all the inputs we'll need
to predict all the stock prices of January, 2017.
So, that's already a huge step done
and the rest should be easier now.
Perfect.
Now.
Next Step.
The next step is related to the fact
that we haven't used the iloc method from Pandas
to get these inputs, and therefore,
it is not still shaped the right way.
It is not shaped like a NumPy Array.
Of all the inputs and lines and one column
and you will often get this format problem,
this shape problem when working with NumPy,
and the solution to this,
if you don't get this NumPy Array of the format you want,
that is with your observations and lines
and one or several columns,
well, the trick to reshape the inputs
is to use the reshape function, Python Py,
to which you will input as arguments, minus one and one.
You will often get this warning format
when you execute your code sometimes in the console,
and don't worry it will remind you
that you need to use this reshape function
with minus one and plus one as arguments.
So, that's exactly what we're gonna do now
and then we'll be ready to move on to the next
and most important reshape,
which will be about creating this 3D structure of our inputs
with, remember, the observations, the time steps,
and the indicators, and this will be very direct to do.
We'll just copy what we've done before
and make the proper changes.
Alright, so first let's make this simple reshape
to get the right NumPy shape so, I'm gonna update my inputs,
so I'm taking my inputs again and taking my old inputs,
that is the ones right here,
to which I'm gonna add dot and then the reshape function,
and in the parenthesis, as we saw,
we need to input minus one
and plus one.
Alright, so now with this we'll get the inputs
with the different stock prices of January 3rd
minus three months, up to the final stock prices,
in lines and in one color.
Alright?
And now time to repeat the process of what we did before
to obtain the right 3D format
that is expected by the neural network.
It is not only expected
by the neural network for the training,
it is also expected by the neural network
for the predictions.
So, whether you apply the fit method
to train your regressor or to predict methods
to make your regressor predict something,
well, you need to have the right format of your inputs
and this format is the 3D format that we made previously.
So, we're gonna make this 3D special structure right now,
but before we do that we must not forget to scale our inputs
because I remind our inputs
are directly coming from the original DataFrames,
contained in dataset_total,
so we have the original values of the stock prices
and since a recurrent neural network
was trained on the scaled values.
Well, of course, we need to scale the inputs,
and that satisfies the third key point
we mentioned at the beginning of this tutorial,
which is to only scale the inputs
and not the actual test values,
because we need to keep the test values as they are
and with the way we got our inputs here, well, this is fine.
We can scale our inputs.
So, I'm gonna update my inputs again and therefore,
I add here inputs equal,
now I'm gonna take my scaling object, which is sc,
and now, dot of course,
but now I'm not gonna use the fit_transform
because our sc object was already fitted
to the training set.
I'm directly gonna use the transform method
because the scaling we need to apply to our input
must be the same scaling that was applied
to the training set,
and therefore we must not fit our scaling object sc again.
We must directly apply the transform method
to get the previous scaling
on which our regressor was trained.
So, that's why I'm adding here, transform parenthesis,
and of course in the parenthesis we need to input our inputs
because that's what we want to scale.
Alright, so now I guess it would be nice
to have a little break,
so were gonna stop here for this tutorial
and in the next one,
we'll take care of creating this special 3D structure
that is expected by the predict method of our r&amp;n.
So I'll see you in this next tutorial and until then,
enjoy deep learning.