Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
All right, so I hope you enjoyed that homework.
No worries if you couldn't make it work.
It was actually quite a big challenge
because that involved research, doing some research online
on what tools to use to make single predictions with CNNs,
but anyway, even if you didn't succeed,
while trying to do the homework is excellent practice
because that's a big part of the job
of a deep learning scientist.
The deep learning scientist spends a lot of his time
doing research on how to implement models,
or even sometimes on how to use them.
So, what you did is definitely real life deep learning.
All right, so as you can see right now in my model
of this training and the training is about to end,
so we will be ready soon to make that single prediction.
We are at the last epoch.
We reached an accuracy of 86% on the training set,
and let's see the accuracy on the test set
that is on the validation set.
Here we go.
We are about to get it.
And we got 81%, so quite close to what we got before.
Perfect.
We are now ready to make that single prediction.
So, as explained in the homework documentation,
I added a new sub-folder in the data set folder
that is called Single Prediction,
and basically, this new folder contains two images
that are called Cat or Dog One and Cat or Dog Two,
and one of these images contains a dog
and the other contains a cat.
We can actually have a look at them to see what they are.
So, the first image, Cat or Dog One, is obviously a dog,
a beautiful dog, and the second image is a very cute cat.
So now, the challenge is to make our CNN model
that we just built to predict correctly
if each of these images contains a cat or a dog.
So, let's do it and we're gonna start with the first image,
Cat or Dog One, which remember contains a dog.
So, what do we need to start with?
First step is to import a NumPy
because we will actually use a function by NumPy
to pre-process the image that we are going to load,
so that it can be accepted by the predict method
that we are gonna use to make our single prediction.
So, let's do it.
Let's import NumPy
and let's give the same shortcut as usual, NP,
and here we go.
Let's do it.
We're gonna do it step by step
and execute each line one by one.
All right, so NumPy is well imported.
Now, we need to import a second module,
which is the image module from Keras, and more precisely,
from the pre-processing module from Keras.
So, let's import this image module.
Import, then image.
And we import this image module
from Keras dot pre-processing.
Here we go.
We are ready to import image, and that's done.
Perfect.
Now, third step.
The third step is to load our image
on which we wanna make our prediction.
So to do this, we're gonna use the load image function
by Keras, which belongs to the image module.
That's why we had to import image here.
And so, we're gonna create a new variable
that I'm gonna call Test Image,
because you know we're testing the model on new predictions,
and this test image will contain the Cat or Dog One image.
That's what we're about to load, so let's load it.
To load it, we use the image module,
and then dot to get the right function,
and this right function is called load underscore I M G,
then parenthesis, and inside the parenthesis
we just need to import two arguments.
The first argument is the path that leads to this image,
Cat or Dog One, but we have to include the image
because, basically, we are loading the image;
and the second argument is the target size
that must be the exact same dimensions
that were used for the training.
So, here we used 64 times 64 dimensions
for the training set images,
and therefore, that's what the predict function will expect,
even for new images.
Okay so first, let's import the path.
So, the path is specified in quotes.
And so basically, that's the same.
Our working directory starts at the data set folder,
so we can start the path with data set, then slash,
then we need to go to the single prediction folder
because this is this folder that contains the Cat
or Dog One image, so single underscore prediction
to access this folder, then slash again
because we need to input the image
because we are loading it.
So, the name of the image is Cat underscore
or underscore Dog underscore One.
Here we go.
And let's not forget the extension.
We have to include it, which is JPG.
All right, so that's for the first argument,
and now the second argument is the target size,
and so basically, we need to take the exact same
target size that was used for the training set
or the test set that's the same,
so we can copy it and place it here
in our load image function.
Here we go.
Now, we're ready to load our first image, Cat or Dog One.
So, let's do it.
I'm going to select this line and execute.
Here we go.
The test image is well imported.
We can check it out in Variable Explorer.
Here it is, and so far, the type is an image
and it has the dimension 64 by 64, as required.
So, good.
That's the first required step done,
but that's not enough.
Now, what we need to do is add a new dimension
to this estimate because, remember,
the input shape in the input layer of our CNN
has three dimensions, 64 by 64 by three,
and remember, the three here is because it's a colored image
and therefore, now what we have to do
is to use another function by image,
which is the image to array, and that will allow to create
this third dimensional array that will have the same format
as the input shape in the input layer of our CNN.
So, let's do it.
Let's use the image to array function.
So, next line of code.
And so basically, we're going to modify
this test image variable because this will go
from being an image of two dimensions
to a three dimensional array.
So, we'll just take our variable again
and modify it by using the image dot I M G underscore
two underscore array function, parenthesis,
and inside the parenthesis, we just need to input our image
that is contained in the test image variable,
and therefore, we simply input here test underscore image.
All right, now let's check it out.
This test image variable is gonna go from being an image
of two dimensions, 64 by 64,
to an array of three dimensions, as you can see here,
64 by 64 by three, so exactly as the input shape
that was used for the architecture of our CNN.
Perfect, but that's still not enough.
Now, what we need to do is add one dimension again
to our three dimensional array, and I'm gonna explain why.
We are about to use the predict method
to make that single prediction,
but if we use the predict method directly,
well, look what happens.
So, to use the predict method,
it's exactly the same as for A N S.
We take our classifier, then dot and then predict,
and inside the predict method we input the sample
for which we want to predict the outcome.
That is, our test image.
So, let's see what happens
if I input test underscore image directly.
So, I'm going to execute this,
but we will get an error saying that we will need
four dimensions instead of three dimensions.
All right, let's do it.
Here we go.
And we have an error.
Error when checking, expected convolution two D
to have four dimensions, but got array
with shape 64 by 64 by three.
So basically, now what we have to do is add a new dimension
to our test image, and to do this we're gonna use
the expand dims function that will add this dimension.
We're just doing this to give
what the predict method expects,
and for those of you curious to know
what this dimension corresponds to,
well, it corresponds to the batch
because, in general, the functions of neural networks,
like the predict function, cannot accept a single input
by itself, like the image we have here.
It only accepts inputs in a batch.
Even if the batch contains one input,
the input must be in the batch,
and this new dimension that we are creating right now
corresponds to the batch.
The batch that will contain the input,
whether there is one input or several inputs.
So here, we will have one batch of one input,
but then in general, we can have several batches
of several inputs, and we can apply
the predict method on that.
So for example, if for this new dimension
we had two elements, that means that we would have
two batches containing single or several inputs.
So, let's do it.
We need to modify our variable again,
so test image again, equals,
and now, we're gonna use the expand dims function,
but this expand dims functions is not taken from image,
the image module by Keras, it is taken from NumPy.
So here, instead of using image, we're gonna use NP,
which is the shortcut for NumPy,
and we're gonna use the expand underscore dims parenthesis,
and inside this expand dims function,
we need to input two arguments.
The first argument is, of course, our test image
because that's the test image that we want to expand,
that is add a new dimension,
and the second argument is axis, and axis is to specify
the position of the index of the dimension
that we are adding.
So, we need to add this dimension in the first position
because, again, that's what the predict method expects,
and therefore, we will specify axis equals zero
because axis equals zero means that that index
of this new dimension we are adding
is gonna have the first index, that is index zero.
So, let's do it.
Let's input the first argument, test underscore image.
That's the first argument.
And now, the second argument, axis equals zero.
All right, and now my test image has three dimensions,
64 by 64 by three, and now when I'm going to execute this,
we will get four dimensions, one, 64, 64, and three.
Let's check it out.
I'm going to execute.
Here we go, four dimensions, one, 64, 64, and three.
And now, we have exactly what the predict method expects,
and so, if now I select this and execute,
indeed we get our final prediction,
and we can see it as one, but don't worry,
that is not our final word.
We will see what one corresponds to.
So now, what I'm gonna do is put the result
of that single prediction in a new variable
that I'm gonna call result.
So, equals.
Result equals classifier dot predict test image,
and so now, if I execute this, well, this result here,
array one, will go into the variable result,
so let's execute this.
All right, now as you can see, if I click on result,
well, I have my new single prediction, one.
But now, does one correspond to cat
or one correspond to dog?
Let's check it out.
I'm going to press okay, and to get that information
whether one corresponds to cat or dog,
well we need to use an attribute
that is called class indices
and that will tell us exactly the mapping
between the strings Cat and Dogs
and their associated numeric values, zero and one.
So, let's get this.
We need to take our training set,
then we add dot, and then we add this attribute,
class underscore indices,
and now if we select this and execute, we get the mapping;
and so here, we can clearly see that cats correspond to zero
and dogs correspond to one.
Perfect, so that means that the prediction by our CNN model
for this first image, Cat or Dog One, is correct
because this image contains a dog
and our model predicted a dog;
and if you want to make it even more simple for you
or for any person that is going to use your model,
we can add this.
There is this if condition, if result,
then we're gonna get the value of one here,
but as you can notice, this result is an array
of two dimensions.
This is the first line and this is the first column,
so to get this one here,
we need to add a double pair of brackets
to get the first line and the first column,
and so here, we need to take the first line,
which has index zero, so zero,
and the first column, which has index zero, as well;
and so, we add a zero here.
And so, if result zero zero,
that is basically the result of the prediction,
equals equals one, then column,
and then we say, what happens if this condition is verified?
So, we're gonna create a new variable
that we're gonna call prediction,
and that's our ultimate prediction in text, Cat or Dog,
and so we're gonna say that if the result is one,
then the prediction is going to be the string Dog,
and else, column, then the prediction
is going to be equal to the string Cat,
because if result equals one, then we know it's a dog
because one correspond to dog,
and else if the result equals zero,
then the prediction will be cat
because zero corresponds to cat.
All right?
And now, if I execute this, this new variable prediction
will be created and will contain the final result in text.
So, let's do it.
Execute.
Here we go.
And the final prediction for the first image
is this beautiful dog.
Perfect.
Okay, and now let's test if it also gives
a correct prediction for a cat,
that is for the second image, Cat or Dog Two.
So, let's remind what it is.
That's this beautiful cat, and so now,
let's see if your model predicts correctly.
So, what we simply need to do is to replace here
Cat or Dog One by Cat or Dog Two,
and then we don't have anything to do.
The code is ready to get the final prediction,
and therefore what I'm gonna do is re-select everything
and execute to get this new final prediction.
And now, let's see if the model predicted right.
We're gonna go to Variable Explorer
and the prediction is a cat.
Perfect!
Congratulations to the model.
Our model made a correct prediction one more time,
and by the way, when we look at the test set
validation accuracy, well, remember we obtained
between 81 and 83%, so you know our model
had 82% chance to make correct predictions,
and that's how we got these good results.
So, congratulations.
If you managed to get these single predictions,
you really did a great job,
and also congratulations to those of you who tried.
Don't worry if you didn't manage
to get the final prediction.
By trying, you definitely made some progress
and also some experience of deep learning
because that's exactly how deep learning is.
You always have to experiment to make your models work
for some specific tasks.
So, congratulations in both cases.
This is now the end of this section,
and now we're going to move on to the next section
about evaluating, improving,
and tuning convolutional neural networks.
Another challenge is waiting for you
so that you can practice even more.
Another podium will be involved
and I can't wait to see your results
and the medal you will obtain.
So, I'll see you in this next section
and until then, enjoy deep learning.