Hello and welcome back
to the course on Deep Learning.
I hope you're as excited about this section
of the course on recurrent neural networks as I am.
We're slowly venturing into the very complex,
very forward-looking and cutting-edge areas of deep learning
and this is going to be very, very fun.
So today we're going to talk about how we're going
to approach this section, which contains
so many different complex topics, so many concepts
that we need to get our head around.
Alright, so in this section we will learn
first of all, the idea behind Recurrent Neural Networks.
We'll see how they compare to the human brain,
we'll understand what makes them unique and special
as compared to regular artificial neural networks.
Then we'll talk about the Vanishing Gradient Problem,
something that has been a major road block in,
or had been a major road block in the development
and utilization of recurrent neural networks,
something that prevented them from being
what they are now and then
we will move on to the solution,
one of the most popular solutions
to the Vanishing Gradient Problem,
the Long Short-Term Memory or LSTM neural networks
and we'll talk about their architecture,
will be a very exciting tutorial,
it's one of my favorite topics and we will find out
exactly how they work and what that complex structure
is inside them, we'll break it down into simple terms
and you will be able to walk away with a
pretty solid understanding of LSTMs.
Then we'll talk about the practical intuition.
So in that previous tutorial, we will have
a practical example of using LSTMs,
but in this practical intuition tutorial,
we'll look at some great examples posted
by one of the researchers, one of the most well-known
researchers in the space, and we'll understand
even better on an intuitive level
how LSTMs actually work, how they think,
we'll be like neuroscientists trying to understand
what's going on in the brain of an LSTM,
it's going to be very exciting as well.
And then at the end, we'll have an extra tutorial
on LSTM variations, something special, something,
you don't really have to take this tutorial
but it's very quick, just to get you up to speed
on what other options of LSTMs exist out there
in the world, what other architectures
you might come across in your work.
So hopefully, you're excited and ready to get started
and I can't wait to see you in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.