Hello and welcome actually
course on deep learning.
I hope you're enjoying our encounters
and this is quick tutorial on biases.
So, let's start straight into it.
We've got an Auto Encoder here.
Again our simplified version that we work with.
And I just wanna to point out that sometimes
you'll see a bit of a different representation.
It might includes something like this
and these are just biases.
So, biases mean you might an actually might say
plus one inside each one of them and usually it does.
And bias just basically means that in your activation,
a function in your
In your activation function you've got that b over there.
So, it's just weights times x it's plus b
and probably the more correct representation
which you'll more often see than this one
is actually like this.
This is how it should be represented
if people are showing biases.
Then, they're just added there because bias affects
the layer ahead, the layer that's in front.
So, just be aware of that and if you see that
just remember it's just basically a bias in it.
That's all, all it is.
It's just a constant in that equation.
Nothing more to it than that.
And that's pretty much of it.
Just look out for that
and I will see you on the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.