Hello and welcome to this python tutorial.
Alright so let's take this challenge
to reach this 86% accuracy
which is the relevant measure of the accuracy
through careful cross validation
and the solution to succeed
the best tool to use to accomplish this goal
is parameter tuning.
So what is parameter tuning?
Okay, so as you noticed
in this first artificial neural network that we just built
we have two type of parameters.
We have the parameters that are learnt from the model
during the training and these are the weights
and we have some other parameters that stay fixed
and these parameters are called the hyper parameters.
So for example these hyper parameters
are the number of a epoch, the batch size, the optimizer
or the number of neurons in the layers.
And when we trained our artificial neural network
well, we trained it with some fixed values
of these hyper parameters. But maybe that
by taking some other values, we would get to
a better accuracy overall with careful cross validation.
And so that's what parameter tuning is all about.
It consists of finding the best values
of these hyper parameters and we are gonna do this
with a technique called grid search
that basically will test several combinations
of these values and will eventually return
the best selection, the best choice that leads
to the best accuracy with careful cross validation.
Alright, so let's implement parameter tuning
with grid search on our artificial neural network.
So the good news is that it's actually quite the same
as implementing careful cross validation
because we will use the kerasclassifier
to wrap our artificial neural network in a classifier
that can be used for scikit_learn
but instead of using the cross_val score function
we will use the grid search cv class
and so basically we will create an object
that we're gonna call gridsearch of this class
and this is this object that will apply
parameter tuning on our kerasclassifier
that is our traditional neural network.
So that's good news because, basically what we can do
to implement this very efficiently
is to take everything from here to the top,
copy, and we're gonna paste that here in the section
tuning the ANN. And now, as I just explained,
we will not choose the cross_val_score function
but we will use the GridSearchCV class.
And then, we import this class from
model_selection module. If, by any chance,
model_selection doesn't work for you
and that depends on the version you have,
try to import it from scikitlearn.grid_search
module. That's actually the old name of the module
to import gridsearchcv. But it's either gridsearchcv
or model_selection. Okay and now
we need to import sequential and dense
to make our artificial neural network
and as I told you now it's exactly the same.
We use this build classifier function
to build the architecture of our ANN.
So that's what we do here. Nothing has
to be changed so far and then we wrap
the whole architecture in this classifier
using the kerasclassifier class
but in this kerasclassifier class we will not
input the batch size and number of epoch arguments
because that's the arguments we're gonna tune
and the arguments we're gonna tune
will be put separately in the gridsearch object
that we're going to create. So we have to remove
these two arguments here and we'll use them
in the gridsearch object. Okay, and now,
that's when things start to change because
now we have to code the part that is related
to gridsearch. So, it's going to take about 10 lines
but no worries, that will be simple.
So, what do we need to start with?
We need to start by creating a dictionary
that will contain the hyper parameters
that we want to optimize, that we want
to find the best values.
So, let's create a variable for this
dictionary that we are gonna call parameters.
And so parameters is going to be a dictionary.
So, a dictionary in python is a structure of data
that contains keys, that is identifiers,
and some values for these keys
and there can be several values for each key,
and so basically each key is going to be
the hyper parameter that we want to input
and the values of the keys are going to be
the values that we want to try, that is,
to test for our artificial neural network.
And then, all these values for all the keys
will be combined and what gridsearch will do
is it will train the artificial neural network
using careful cross validation
to get a relevant accuracy with the different combinations
of these values and eventually in the end
it will return best accuracy with
the best selection of these values.
So now what we have to do is to
create this dictionary with all the combinations
of the hyper parameters that we want to optimize.
So how do we create a dictionary in Python?
Well, that's very easy.
We have to use some brackets and inside
these brackets we're going to input the keys
that is the hyper parameters, and their
values that we want to test.
Okay, so what would we like to optimize?
Well, we have many hyperparameters
in the architecture and the training
of our ANN, so we can for example tune the batch size.
You know, we can try several batch sizes because one of them
will lead us to a better accuracy.
We can also tune the number of epoch for that same reason.
There is an optimal number of epoch.
But we can also tune some hyper parameters
in the architecture of the ANN, like the optimizer
and some other hyper parameters.
So let's start with the batch size.
We're going to input the batch size
and different values of the batch size
in the dictionary. So how do we do that?
Well, we have to put the name of the hyper parameter
we want to optimize in quotes, like this.
And we put the exact same name as the one
given in the model, that is, we input
batch size. Alright, so that's the key.
And now, we need to test several values for the batch size.
So, we add here a column and in square brackets
we input the values we want to test.
So which one would you like to test?
Well, we've seen in the British tutorial
that a batch size of 10 led us to a relevant accuracy
of 83% and we would like to beat 83%
so we will not test 10 but some
other values of the batch size.
Let's test 2 values of the batch size
and we're gonna try 25 and 32.
So why 25 and 32? Well, that's based on my experience
and that's also common practice to take powers of 2.
Well, you can try other values of the batch size
but let's see what we get with these ones.
Okay, so, that's for the first parameter.
Now, let's take care of the second hyper parameter.
What is it going to be? Well, let's try
to optimize the number of epoch.
So same, we input the real name
of the number of epoch parameter, that is, nb_epoch
so basically it has to be the same name
as the one used to train the ANN.
So nb_epoch and here that's the same, a column,
and in square brackets we input the values we want to test.
So okay, let's try again with a hundred
but we won't get the same result as what we got here
because we used a batch size of 10
and now we use a batch size of 25 and then 32.
So let's try 100 and let's also try another value,
like, for example, 500.
You know, maybe we won't reach convergence with 100
and maybe 500 will lead us to a better result.
We never know.
So okay, that's already 2 hyper parameters
that we are tuning and now
I am giving you a little challenge.
What if we want to optimize
a hyper parameter that is in the architecture here?
For example, let's say we want to tune the optimizer.
Well, what we would need to do is to add a third key here
and, in quotes, we'll put the name of the hyper parameter
that is, optimizer, and column, but then,
how do we input some different values,
considering that we already have a values
of the optimizer here? You know we didn't have values
for the number of epoch and the batch size,
so we can try several of them here,
but here we already have a value for the optimizer.
So how can we test some other ones?
Well there is something specific we have to do.
We have to create a new parameter of the build classifier
function, and this new argument is of course going to be,
an argument that will give us choice for the optimizer.
So how does it work? Well we're going to give a
new name to this optimizer argument,
and we're going to call it optimizer, and here
we're going to copy this and replace the Adam optimizer here
by this optimizer argument that now plays
the role of a variable.
And so now, we have the right to input different values
that we want to test for our optimizer because
what will happen is that this key here, will be associated
to this optimizer and so when we give different values
for this key, well the different values are going
to be tested in this optimizer here.
So that's the trick, and therefore if you want to tune
and hyper parameters that are in this architecture here,
that is the architecture of your ANN.
Well what you have to do, is to create a new argument
for the hyper parameter you want to tune
and then, replace the value here by name of your argument.
Okay, so lets try some different values of our optimizer.
So still we use some square brackets and inside
the square brackets we're going to try several
optimizers, and so of course we're going to try Adam
optimizer and then, lets try another one.
Actually another very good optimizer that is sometimes
a better one for deep learning models, is the
rmsprop optimizer, which is another excellent optimizer
based on stochastic gradient descent.
Feel free to have a look at the Keras documentation
to get more info and you'll see for example,
that they recommend to use this rmsprop
for regular neural networks, this is generally a better
choice and indeed this is the optimizer
that we're going to use for regular neural networks.
But lets still try it for our ANN,
maybe this will lead us to better results.
Okay, so that's it for the parameters that we want to tune,
that is try to find the optimal values.
And now what we have to do is of course
to start to implement grid search, and so remember
we import the gridsearchcv class and so now you can guess
what we're going to do.
We're going to create an object of this class
that will contain this parameter dictionary
with all the hyper parameters that we want to tune,
and the different values that we want to test.
And of course this gridserch object will contain our
estimator that is our classifier
and eventually it will also contain the information
related to kfold cross validation.
Because remember, when we tune our model with gridsearch
well kfold cross validation is going to be used
to evaluate the accuracy and so it we'll need to enter
for gridsearch is, a scoring metric which is going
to be the accuracy, and the number of folds in
kfold cross validation, and of course we will choose ten
like we did for kfold cross validation
in the previous tutorial.
So here we go, let's create the grid search object
that we're going to call grid-search and so this is
an object from the GridSearchCV class,
so I'm copying this and pasting it here
and now some parenthesis and inside the parenthesis
we're going to input the parameters of the
GridSearchCV class, so lets inspect the object.
So as I just said, the first argument we have to input is
are estimator and that of course our classifier
which is our ANN, then second argument is our parameters
that we want to optimize, that we want to tune.
And the name for this argument is param_grid,
and so for this param grid argument we need to input
are parameters dictionary, that contains
all the combinations that we want to try
and for each of these combinations, we will use
kfold cross validation with a specific metric that is
going to be the accuracy and a specific number of folds,
that is going to be ten folds.
And that's actually the last two arguments we need to input.
That is the scoring metric, that is given by the
argument scoring and so that is the accuracy.
And finally the number of folds, which is ten.
So we close the parenthesis and here we go.
Our grid search object is ready, it contains all the
information we need to apply grid search to our ANN.
But now, as you can notice, this grid search objects
is not yet fitted to the training set,
so that's exactly what we have to do now.
We need to fit grid search to the training set,
so to do this, that's exactly the same
as what we used to do with the other objects.
For example when fitted this standard scaler objects
to the training set, we need to take our object
gridsearch, then dot the we use the fit method
and inside the fit method we input the training set.
And the training set is composed of the matrix of
features x_train and the dependent variable vector y_train.
And actually this grid search that fit x train, y train
will create a new object and so we will give the same
name grid_search to this new object and so here,
I'm giving the same name grid search that
will be fitted to the train set.
Okay, so this will fit are ANN to the training set
while running grid search to find the optimal
hyper parameters that we're testing here,
so we would already be ready to execute the code from now
but let's just add two lines of code
to get what we're mostly interested in, that is the
best selection of parameters and
of course the best accuracy.
So we're going to create to new variables that will contain
this information, so lets start with best parapmeters.
So here I'm creating a new variable
and then best accuracy.
Alright, now how can we get these best parameters
and this best accuracy? Well there is nothing more simple,
gridsearch is an object from the class gridsearchcv,
and if you look at the info of the gridsearchcv class
you will see in the end that in contains some attributes
and one of them is best params, that will get us exactly
the best parameters and another one is best score
which gives us the best accuracy that result from this best
selection of hyper parameters.
Okay, so let's get these two attributes?
So to get an attribute from a class, we need take the object
grid_search then dot and then we just need to add the name
of the attribute, so the attribute for best parameters
is best underscore params then underscore and same
for the attribute for the best accuracy, we take our object
grid search then dot and then we add the name of attribute
which is best underscore score and underscore again.
Alright, and with these two attributes
we'll get the best selection of the hyper parameters
that we're searching and the best accuracy
resulting from this best selection.
Okay and now that's the most exciting part because basically
we don't have anything to do, everything will be automated.
Grid search will find the best selection
of the hyper parameters for us.
So, you can totally do something else,
you can have some lunch, have some dinner, have some fun
work on another project, you can even go to sleep
and actually that's what I'm about to do because,
this will actually take quite some time,
several hours maybe, that's why
I'm recommending to do something else because
this is going to take some time.
So feel free to do whatever you want, but in the end
you will get a much better result than this 83% accuracy.
So lets set some goals with this accuracy.
The absolute great goal would be 86%
lets set this as the gold medal.
Then another great goal less hard to reach would be 85%
and lets say that if we reach this goal we have
the silver medal and lets say that if we reach
84% we have the bronze medal.
And before 84% well we're at the same level
as in the previous tutorial, which remember
was 83%, so we get no medal.
Alright, so let's see what happens, I actually
don't know what will happen because this is the first
time I have run this, so I will discover
the results with you, so just like you
I'm hoping to get at least one medal.
Alright, so now we're going to execute the whole thing,
so first we need to import the data set and run the
data reprocessing phase, so we're taking
everything from here to the top.
Here we go, data set well imported and well processed
and now let's finally execute the last section,
parameter tuning, we have the whole tuning ready.
Now we don't have anything to do so have fun here we go.
Alright, this is running and this is going to take a while
so, we'll let this run and we'll
see each other back at the end of the tuning,
so I'll see you soon.
Alright, welcome back, I think this is about to end.
According to my eta, so we are about to know on which
step of the podium we are, remember gold is 86%,
silver is 85% and bronze is 84% so at least lets
hope we get a medal.
Alright, so almost over we can see here the last round
we are at 86%, that's a good sign but
remember that's only the accuracy of one round
and maybe that we won't the same good accuracy
over ten rounds, and that's why we're computing the main
of ten accuracies over ten train test folds.
So that we get a relevant measure of the models performance.
Okay and now this is about to end is 3 seconds, 3 2 1
and here we go, its over we ended up with an accuracy
of 86.26% so that's the accuracy of the last round, but
lets have a look at the real measure of the accuracy.
Which is contained in best accuracy here,
and the medal we get is silver
because we got an accuracy of 85%.
So congratulations, sorry for those who were hoping
for the gold medal but don't worry first of all silver
is a good achievement, and second of all getting
the gold medal is going to be the homework
of this section, so that will be excellent for you
because you'll get to practice with neural networks,
because in order to reach the gold medal
you will have several options.
One of them is to change the architecture of your
neural network, another option is to
do some more parameter tuning.
And now to finish this tutorial lets have a look at the
best parameters that were selected by grid search,
here they are in best parameters and the winners are
bach size of 25 a number of epoch of 500 and
an rmsprop optimizer and so it's with these parameters
that we manage to get an 85% accuracy and a silver medal.
And now it's your turn, try to get the gold medal
put me one set down on the podium, I'll work on
getting the gold medal too and as soon as I get it,
I'll give you some hints and a solution.
Until then enjoy Deep Learning.