Hello and welcome to this python tutorial
We just trained our self-organizing map
and now we're ready to visualize the results,
that is, to plot the self organizing map itself.
So, what we are about to see is
clearly there's two dimensional grid
that will contain all the final winning nodes
and for each of these winning nodes
we will get what is most important for us
that is, the MID; the Mean Interneuron Distance.
And I remind that the MID of a specific winning node
is the mean of the distances
of all the neurons around the winning node
inside a neighborhood that we defined,
thanks to sigma here,
which is the radius of this neighborhood.
And so basically the higher is the MID
Then the more the winning node will be far away
from it's neighbors.
Inside a neighborhood.
And therefore the higher is the MID,
the more the winning node is an outlier.
And since in some way
the majority of the winning nodes represent
the rules that are respected.
Well on that line you're far from this majority
of neurons, is therefore far from the general rules.
And that is exactly how we will detect the outliers
that is this the frauds.
Because for each neuron we will get the MID, so we will
simply need to take the winning nodes
that have the highest MID.
And, we're not going to look at figures, we're not
going to compare figures, we're going to use colors.
That means the winning notes will be colored by different
colors in such a way that the larger is the MID, the
closer to white the color will be.
And so now lets start building this map.
So, will we need specific functions to do this because
will not use matplotlib
Because the plot we're about to make is
actually quite specific.
You know, we're not plotting a classic graph,
like a histogram or a curve.
We're building a self-organizing map, and therefore
in some way we're gonna make it from scratch.
So, the functions will we use,
we will import them from pylab.
And these functions are bone, pcolor, colorbar,
plot and show.
No worries you are going to understand what each
of these functions will do.
So first let's import all this.
Done.
And now let's start making the map.
So first we need to initialize the figure,
that this is the window that will contain the map.
And to do this we use the bone function
so I'll show you what it does, if I execute this
we get a white window without anything in it
because we just initialized the window
that will contain the map.
Okay, so now lets move on to the next step
First, what we are gonna do
is put the different winning nodes
on the map.
And how are we going to do that?
Well in fact we are going to add on the map
the information of the Mean Interneuron Distance
for all the winning nodes
that the self-organizing map identified.
And we're not going to add the figures
of all these Mean Interneuron Distances
instead we will use colors.
Different colors corresponding to the different range values
of the Mean Interneuron Distances.
And to do this we are going to use the pcolor function,
and inside this pcolor function we're going to add
all the values of the Mean Interneuron Distances
for all the winning nodes of our self-organizing map.
And to get these mean distances,
well we have a specific method for that,
it's Distance Map Method.
So that's why now we're going to take our
object som then add a dot,
and now we use this method.
Which is distance underscore map,
parenthesis, and in fact this Distance-Map Method
will return all the Mean Interneuron Distances
in one matrix.
So this will return the matrix of all these distances
for all the winning nodes.
And now, just to get things in the right order
for the pcolor function,
we just need to take the transpose of this matrix
returned by the Distance Map Method.
And to take the transpose, we just need to add here a dot
and then capital T.
That will take the transpose of this MID matrix.
So, right now we can have a look at what we just did
actually if we select these two lines
and execute, well we get the self-organizing map.
With all the different colors corresponding
to the Mean Interneuron Distances,
but now we would like to add one more information.
We would like to see if the white color
corresponds to a high MID or a low MID.
And same for the dark colors,
do they correspond to the lowest MIDs or the highest MIDs?
Well to know this for sure it's good to add a legend
and this is what we're going to do right now
with the next line of code.
We're going to add here below colorbar
that will exactly us the legend of all these colors
so now we will see much better
what these colors correspond to.
If I execute this again we get now the legend on the right.
So this is the range of values of the MID,
the Mean Interneuron Distances.
But these are normalized values,
that means that the values were scaled from zero to one.
And therefore now we can clearly see that the highest MIDs,
the highest Mean Interneuron Distances,
correspond to the white color.
And on the other hand,
the smallest Mean Interneuron Distances
correspond to the dark colors.
So based on what we explained earlier,
we actually already know where the frauds are.
Because, remember the frauds are identified
by outlying winning nodes
because outlying winning nodes are the ones
that are far from the general rules.
You see all these majority of points here
with dark colors are close to each other
because their MID is pretty low.
So that means that all the winning nodes
in the neighborhood of one winning node are close to this
winning node at the center
and therefore that creates clusters of winning nodes
all close to each other.
But, these winning nodes here have large MIDs
and therefore they're outliers
and accordingly potential frauds.
So great we actually identified the outlier, the fraud
it's right here.
So basically we could stop here and get to the next step
to get the explicit list of the customers,
by just proceed to the inverse mapping of this winning node
to see which customers are associated to this winning node.
But we can do better with this map,
because we can actually add some markers.
To make the distinction between the customers
who got approval and the customers who didn't get approval.
Because the customers who cheated and got approval
are more relevant targets to fraud detection
than the customers who didn't get approval and cheated.
So it's good now to see where the customers are
in the self-organizing map.
So what we're going to do right now
is add some markers everywhere,
To tell for each of these winning nodes here
if the customers who are associated to these winning nodes
got approval or didn't get approval.
So I'm going to close this
and let's add these new lines of code,
to add the markers.
So basically it's very simple, we're going to create
two markers, some red circles and some green squares.
The red circles are going to correspond
to the customers who didn't get approval.
And the green squares will correspond
to the customers who got approval.
So first lets create the markers.
We're going to create a new variable, markers
and create a vector of two elements
corresponding to the two markers.
So we said first a circle that is coded by o here
and then a square that is coded by s.
Alright so that's the markers,
but it's also good to color these markers.
So, we're going to add a new variable here
that will contain our colors,
n equal and same I'm going to create
a vector of two elements,
which are going to be first the red color,
coded by r and the green color,
coded by g.
Alright so, so far no association is made
between the markers and the colors
but we will make them afterwards
thanks to the customers.
And actually, this is what we're going to do now
we're going to loop over all the customers
and for each customer we're going to get the winning node
and dependent on whether the customer got approval or not,
we're going to color this winning node by a red circle
if the customer didn't get approval
and a green square if the customer got approval.
So let's see, let's start the loop.
A loop in python starts for and now we're going to use
a trick, we actually need two looping variables
that are going to be i and x,
i is just going be the different values of all the indexes
of our customer database, that is you know
i is going to take the values,
zero, one and two and three down to 689.
And x is going to be different vectors of customers
so x will start by being equal to this vector
that corresponds to the first customer
then at the next iteration x will be equal
to this second vector,
that corresponds to the second customer
and down to the last customer.
So, for i and x, and now what we're gonna do is add n,
enumerate, and inside enumerate we're going to add X.
Which contains all our customers.
So, by doing this for i, x and enumerate X
well i is going to be all the indexes of our customers
and x is going to be all the vectors of customers
at the different iterations.
Okay, so now time to enter the loop.
And therefore we introduce here a column
and now we are inside the loop.
So what do we do inside the loop,
first we get the winning node for the first customer
because at the beginning of this loop
we start with the first customer
because i will be equal to zero,
the first index in python and x will be equal
to the first element of x, that is the first customer.
So we start with the first customer and for this customer
we get its winning node.
And how can we get that? Well first we're going to call
this winning node w then equals and then of course
fortunately we have a method for that.
That returns the winning node for a specific customer
so we take our object som and then we use this method
which is called winner, pretty intuitive
inside this function of course we enter X.
Alright so this will get us the winning node
of the customer x.
Now, what we want to do is for this winning node
place the marker on it, the colored marker on it.
So that's what we are going to do right now
On this winning node we're going to plot the marker,
so what is this marker going to be?
Well that depends on whether
the customer got approval or not.
So what we're going to get now
is this information,
whether this customer got approval or not.
So in this plot function the first thing
that we have to do is to specify
the coordinates of this marker.
And we would like to put this marker
at the center or the winning node.
You know, each winning node is represented by a square
in the self-organizing map that we just saw earlier
and basically we want to put the marker
at the center of the square.
And so where the all the coordinates of the
winning nodes are w zero and w one
that's the two coordinates of the winning node
this is the x coordinate of the winning node
and this is the y coordinate of the winning node.
But this is actually the coordinate
of the lower left corner of the square.
And we want to put it at the center of the square,
and therefore we will add plus 0.5 here
to put it in the middle of the horizontal base of the square
and also plus 0.5 here
to put it at the center of the square.
Okay, so by doing that we just put the marker
at the center of the square
corresponding to the winning node.
And now what we have to do is the most important thing
we need to know whether we have to put a red circle
or a green square, and how do we do that?
Well as you understood that depends on the information
of the customer, you know that customer
that we are at in the loop
is it a customer who got approval
or is it a customer who didn't get approval?
So how do we get this information?
Well this is thanks to the y vector here
that we separated at the beginning.
You know our som was strained on x
but we still had this y vector here
that contains the information of whether the customer
got approval or not.
So this is how we're going to know whether
the markers going to be a red circle or a green square.
So now that we get that it is very simple
what we just need to take is, the markers vector
that we created here and we're going to add some brackets
and inside the brackets,
we're going to put y and square and i.
So why do we put that?
Because i is the index of the customer,
so y i is the value of the dependent variable
for that customer that is zero
if the customer didn't get approval
and one if the customer got approval.
So it goes this way, if the customer didn't get approval
then y i will be equal to zero
and therefore markers y i will be
equal to markers zero, that is a circle.
And on the other hand, if the customer got approval
then y i will be equal to one, then therefore markers
y i will be equal to markers 1
and therefore that corresponds to s, a square.
So that's how we make the association,
between the customer and the marker,
thanks to this y i here.
And now we're going to do the same for the color
because we want to put different colors for markers.
So we're going to do exactly the same,
add a comma here and now get the colors.
So that's exactly the same actually
we take our colors vector which is colors
and same we add this y i information
that contains the information whether the customer
got approval or not.
And, depending on the value of y i, well we will get
a red if the customer didn't get approval
because this corresponds to index zero
and a green if the customer got approval
because it corresponds to index one.
But in fact, this colors y i here
we're going to give this color to the marker
however in the markers we can color the inside of the marker
and the edge of the marker.
And actually we're going to only the color the edge
so what we're going to do is,
add here marker edge color that will be equal to colors y i.
But then as for the inside of the marker
we will not color it, because we can have two markers
for the same winning node.
And if that's the case we will see much better
the two markers if there's no color inside.
You'll be convinced when we plot the map so,
marker face color that's the code to get the inside color
of the marker, so right now we're adding none.
Alright perfect, and to finish lets take care of the size
so, we can add a marker size
because otherwise we'll get too small markers
and we want to be able to see the markers.
So we're going to add marker size equals ten
and eventually we can do the same for the size of the edges.
So we add here, marker edge width
and we'll set it equal to two.
Alright, so now you're going to see
that our self-organizing map will look much better.
Because not only we will see
the different Mean Interneuron Distances
for all the winning nodes,
but besides we are going to see if the customers
associated to the winning nodes are customers
who got approval or didn't get approval.
So, lets check it out right now, we just need to add here
show, to show the graph and lets select everything now.
And here it is, the self-organizing map!
Here it is.
Okay, I'm going to enlarge this, so now not only
we have the Mean Interneuron Distances
but also we get the information
of whether the customers got approval or didn't get approval
for each of the winning nodes.
So for example if we have a look at this winning node,
well we can see that the customers associated
to this winning node didn't get approval.
However, if we look at this winning node well we can see
that the customers associated to this winning node
got approval, but the color is fine its around this level
so it doesn't indicate a high risk of fraud.
However, now let's look at our outliers,
the obvious outliers that are this winning node here
and this one here.
Here, absolutely no doubt the Mean Interneuron Distance
is almost equal to one or perhaps equal to one.
Which clearly indicates that there is a high risk
of fraud for these customers associated
to these two winning nodes.
And what do we see in these winning nodes?
Well we see that we have both cases some customers
who got approval and some customers who didn't get approval
because we get a green square and also a red circle.
So now, what we have to do is catch
these potential cheaters in the winning nodes
but in priority those who got approval
because it's of course much more relevant
to the bank to catch the cheaters who got away with this.
So, now the map is done, we have a good map
and we're going to use this map to catch
these potential cheaters and to do this we're going
to add just three lines of code
and we will do it in the next tutorial,
to get the explicit list of the customers
who potentially cheated.
And we will do that thanks to this map
because we will get the coordinates
of these two winning nodes here
and we will use a function to find the customers
associated to these two winning nodes.
We'll do that in the next tutorial
and until then enjoy deep learning!