Hello and welcome back
to the course on Deep Learning.
In today's tutorial we're going to walk through the steps
that are included in the process
of training an Auto Encoder,
so let's get started.
Here we've got an Auto Encoder,
and obviously we've got some inputs,
and then we'll get some outputs.
In our case,
as inputs will get the ratings of lots and lots of users
for these six movies,
and based on those ratings it'll come up
with a way to compress that information
and come up with those weights that will allow it to encode
or to basically set itself up
to be able to then encode it and decode it
in the future.
So here we go, these are our training steps.
Step one, we need to start with,
you start with an array where the lines
correspond to users and columns correspond to features,
the movies, and each cell contains a rating
from one to five,
zero if there's no rating by that user u.
So, important to understand that
every single row in your data set
is a unique user who rated those movies.
And by the way, these steps will be very valuable for you
when you are performing them
or when you're doing practical tutorials,
because you will be actually working with
exactly this situation,
you'll be creating a recommender system for movies.
Step two, the first user goes into the network.
The input vector contains all its ratings
for all the movies.
So all the ratings of that user for all of the movies.
Step three, the input vector is encoded
into vector z of lower dimensions
by mapping function,
usually you'd use a sigmoid or
a hyperbolic tangent as we mentioned.
And that's the equation that you would have.
Then, step four, z is then decoded into the output
vector of the same dimension as x aiming to
replicate the input vector.
So, this is all pretty straight forward stuff.
The reconstruction error, which is how
different is the output compared to the input
is computed and the goal is to minimize
your reconstruction error.
And then, all this error is back-propagated from
right to left, through your network,
and the weights are updated accordingly
depending on how much they are responsible
for that, so you've got a gradient decent
process happening there.
And, the learning rate describes how much
we update the weight.
That's a perimeter you can tune
during your, you will be tuning or you can tune
during decoding and you will see that
in the practical tutorials.
And step seven, repeats steps one to six,
and update the weights after each observation,
that's reinforcement learning if it's done after
each observation or if you do it
after batches that will be batch learning.
And finally, step eight, when the whole training
passes through the neural network,
that's an epoch, and then just redo more epochs.
So, there we go, those are our steps.
Let's have a look in a more visual way.
So, step one, that's our input.
In this case, this input is the same file as
we used for the Bolster machine, or same example,
you can have ratings from one to five, as we
mentioned in the example, one to five means
basically, a more advanced reccomender system,
and then a zero would mean empty.
In our case we've got one zero and empty,
we can easily change them, we can change these.
One minus one and put a zero in the empty cell.
So, it's very easy to adjust and also you can
build a recommender system with minor ratings,
one and zero, or one minus one,
depending on how you wanna structure it,
it'll be a good reccomender system,
but of course, it will be a more powerful
recommender system if you build it with
ratings from one to five.
In the practical tutorials, good news, you will
be building one with ratings from one to five.
Okay, so there we go.
That's our input, then,
step two, we take the first row, we put it into
our Auto Encoder, and then step three,
we calculate the hidden nodes, voila.
Again, at the very start you'll have some randomly
initialized weights, then that process called encoding.
Step four, we're going to calculate our visible
output nodes, again initially it will be
some random starting weights.
That's a process called decoding.
And then, so basically, this is a summary
that yellow arrow is a summary.
We've just put the information, the data through
our Auto Encoder from left to right.
And step five, we're going to compare
the results to the actual ratings for those movies.
Movie one, two, three, four, five, six.
And then we'll calculate the error, step six.
And then we will propagate it back
through the network, we'll adjust the weights accordingly.
And, next we will take the next row in our data set.
And we'll do the same thing and so on
and so on and so on we'll continue
through all the rows.
And then once we're done, we'll move on to
step eight, that means we've finished a whole epoch.
And then we just repeat these epochs,
we continue doing that with our data set
depending on how many times we wanna do that.
Hopefully, our training converges to some sort of value.
There we go, that's how you train an Auto Encoder,
very straight forward steps,
and as I mentioned at the start of this section
that simply because you've already done
all of the previous parts to this course,
all of this probably sounds very trivial to you.
If you look back at how you were starting out
into this course this probably would have been
a bit more advanced.
But, if this sounds trivial that's good news,
that just means that all of the
knowledge that you've acquired throughout
the course before is benefiting you now.
And that's great, that's why we are able to
fly through this part very quickly.
And, we can move onto some more interesting things.
And by the way, additional reading,
we've got some additional reading today.
Here is a blog by Francois Chollet,
the creator of Keras,
it's called building Autoencoders in Keras,
check it out, it's got some actual
practical applications so even if you want to get
some hands on experience before you start to
practice (mumbles), this could be a good place to
do that, there is some quick exercises which you can follow
and get some cool insights already
and then you'll be even more prepared
when you go onto the practical tutorials.
So check it out, it's called Building Autoencoders in Keras.
And that's it for today, I'll look forward
to seeing you next time.
And until then, enjoy deep learning.