Hello and welcome back
to the course on deep learning.
In today's tutorial we're going to talk about
overcomplete hidden layers.
But before we start, I wanted to mention
that this tutorial and the next couple tutorials
are going to be quick because they are
very kind of overview, high level tutorials
on different types of autoencoders.
Autoencoders are quite a powerful technique
or method in deep learning,
and they are popular, and there are lots
of variations of autoencoders.
As we unfortunately couldn't go
into detail and depth into all of them,
but instead what we're going to do
is we're going to show you the underlying
concepts and principles of these variations
and point you at specific papers
and blogs and articles that you can
read if you want to up-skill on certain ones,
certain types of autoencoders.
At the same time, even these high level overviews
will give you some very valuable insights
and awareness about the different types
of autoencoders that exist and you'll be able to,
not only when you see them, recognize them,
but also you'll be able to operate with the terms,
with their names easily and you won't be caught off-guard
when you come across them in literature,
or in different types of works that
you'll be studying or preforming.
So, let's get started!
First thing that we need to talk about
is overcomplete hidden layers.
This is a underlying concept in a lot of
or most of the variations of autoencoders.
So let's have a look.
So here we've got an autoencoder,
four input values, two nodes in the hidden layer,
and four nodes in the output layer.
The question is here, what if we wanted
to increase the number of nodes in the hidden layer?
What if we wanted actually to have more nodes
in the hidden layer than in the input layer?
Something like this.
And the obvious question is here like why?
Why would we do that?
But the answer is why not?
We said that an autoencoder can be used
as a feature extraction tool,
but what if we want more features?
Remember in artificial neural networks
it was very easy for us to do,
we had a certain number of inputs,
then we could have a whole layer of
whatever number of inputs that,
of hidden nodes that we wanted.
It could be six, it could be 10,
it could be 100, doesn't matter,
we could have as many as we want to.
We could add more layers and so on.
But the point was we weren't restricted
to how many nodes we would have in the hidden layer.
And that allowed us to extract more features
and that would be great in the case of
an autoencoder as well given that we are advocating
it as a feature extraction tool.
But we have a problem, if we were to do this,
obviously the autoencoder can cheat.
The autoencoder,
this goal is to get the outputs to equate to the inputs.
As soon as you give it four or more hidden nodes,
in case you have four inputs, basically
as soon as you give it a hidden layer which is
the same size or greater than the input layer,
it just basically is able to cheat and just say,
"Alright this node is always going to be equal to this node,
"and then this node is equal to this node."
So information is just gonna fly through like that,
and then you'll even have some extra
nodes that are not being used.
And that could be the end process,
the end state that this autoencoder would end up in
after the training and is going to be just useless
it's not going to extract any valuable information,
any valuable features for us through that process.
So this is definitely a problem.
And how are we going to solve that problem?
Well that's what we're going to look at
the next couple of tutorials.
We're going to look at three different approaches
that are used to solve that problem.
And therefore three different variations of autoencoders.
So lets proceed with the next tutorial
and I will see you there.
Until next time, enjoy deep learning.