Hello and welcome
to this very important tutorial, where we'll get more
at the heart of the Recurrent Neural Network,
because that's where we have
to create a special data structure with,
as you can see, 60 timesteps and one output.
So first, let me explain what it means.
Okay, so 60 timesteps means that at each time T,
the RNN is going to look
at the 60 stock prices before time T,
that is the stock prices between 60 days before time T
and time T, and based on the trends,
it is capturing during these 60 previous timesteps,
it will try to predict the next output.
So 60 timesteps of the past information
from which our RNN is gonna try to learn
and understand some correlations,
or some trends, and based on its understanding,
it's going to try to predict the next output.
That is, the stock price at time T plus one.
So that's very important to understand.
60 is a number that I experimented,
trying different number of time steps.
I tried one time step first, which was completely stupid,
because it led to overfitting.
The model was not learning anything.
Then 20 timesteps, which was not enough
to be able to capture some trends, then 30, 40,
and eventually the best number of timesteps
I ended up with was 60.
And the 60 timesteps correspond of course
to the 60 previous financial days,
and since there 20 financial days in one month,
well 60 timesteps correspond to three months.
So that means that each day we're gonna look
at the three previous month to try to predict
the stock price the next day.
So we're gonna have 60 timesteps and one output,
which will be the stock price at time T plus one.
So make sure to understand it clearly.
You will understand it even more, even better,
when we create this data structure
because I'm gonna show it to you in Variable Explorer,
but now if you're ready, let's create this data structure.
So the first thing we need to do
is create two separate entities.
The first entity we're gonna create
is gonna be X_train which will be the input
of the neural network,
and then the second entity will be y_train,
which will contain the output.
So basically for each observation,
that is for each financial day,
X_train will contain the 60 previews stock prices,
before that financial day, and y_train
will contain the stock price the next financial day.
That's exactly what we need to create right now,
but it's a special data structure
because of course we need to do it for every time T.
So let's initialize these two separate entities,
X_train and y_train, and we are going
to initialize them as empty list,
which you can do with a simple square brackets.
So, X_train equal square brackets,
and y_train equals square brackets as well.
All right, so we have now two empty lists.
All right, and then as you can imagine,
when we do some initializations like that,
well the next step is naturally a for loop,
because we're gonna populate these two entities, X_train
and y_train with what we want,
that is the 60 preview stock prices in X_train,
and the next stock price in y_train.
So I'm starting a for loop here,
for i in range, and now focus on this one.
It's actually not obvious at the beginning,
well since we're gonna get at each time T
the 60 preview stock prices, well we can only start doing
this from the 60th stock price of our dataset.
That is, the stock price of the 60th financial day of 2012,
because we're gonna get the 60 previews stock prices
before that stock price, and therefore I need to start
the for loop with 60, because then for each i,
which is the index of the stock price observation,
I'm gonna get the range from i minus 60 to i,
which exactly contains the 60 preview stock prices
before the stock price at time T.
So that's why I'm starting the range at 60,
and then good news, the upper bound
is much more natural and easy to find.
It's of course the last index of our observation,
that is 1,257, but it's not 57, it's actually 58,
because remember the upper bound is excluded in a range.
So we have to go up to 1258.
All right, so let's put that upper bound
for i in range 60 to 1258.
There we go, colon, and now we can start the for loop.
All right, and now it's gonna be easy.
Let's start with X_train.
Right now, X_train is an empty list.
So of course what we wanna do
is append some elements into X_train,
and to do that, well naturally we take X_train
and then dot, and then we use the append function,
which is the first function here
as you can see, so just press Enter.
Append to, depend what we want include X_train.
And what do we want to append inside X_train?
Well, we want to append the 60 previews stock prices
before the stock price of index i,
that is the stock price at the ith financial day,
and so to get them, we're gonna get our training set.
Be careful the scaled one, so training_set_scaled,
and in this training set scaled,
we're gonna take the 60 preview stock prices
before the ith financial day, that is, the range of indexes
from i minus 60 to i, all right?
So for example, let's say that i equal 60,
because I will start at 60,
that will be the first value of i.
Well, when i equals 60, then we will get
the range of stock prices from 60 minus 60,
which is zero, that is the first stock price,
to i, that is 60.
And therefore, we will get the 60 first stock prices
from this one to this one
because we are going up to i, which is 60,
but the upper bound is excluded,
so we are getting this one,
but that's indeed the 60 preview stock prices,
because we are starting at index zero,
and then, the output y_train will contain
this stock price, because it will be the stock price
that the RNN will learn to predict based
on what it observed previously
with the 60 preview stock prices.
That is all the ones from here to the top, this one.
All right, so that's exactly the idea of the RNN.
It is memorizing what's happening
in the 60 previous timesteps to predict
the next value at time T plus one,
the next stock price at time T plus one.
All right, and now be careful we selected
the right lines for X_train, but we need to specify
the column and that's totally obvious.
We just have one column in training set scaled,
and that is the column of index zero.
So we simply need to add here comma and zero.
All right, so now I think we have the right X_train.
It will, at each time there is, at each stock price,
append the 60 preview stock prices,
and you will have a clear look at this data structure
in the end, of course, when I execute.
All right, so now let's do the same for y_train.
So y_train is gonna be much more easy
because we will simply need to include
the stock price at time T plus one,
and therefore we just need to do the same here.
We need to say y_train, then take the append function,
and inside of which we need to input
the stock price at time T plus one.
And therefore, let's copy this to be more efficient,
because this stock price of time T plus one
is of course going to be taken
from training set scaled, so training set scaled.
And now what indexes do we need to take?
Well for the column it's the same, it's zero,
but then for the line, the observation line,
what is it going to be according to you?
Is it going to be i, or i plus one?
That's a tricky one, and the answer
is i, because if we take the same example
where i is equal to 60, well remember
X_train will contain all the stock prices
from zero to 59, because the upper bound was excluded,
but then, what we want to predict
then based on these 60 preview stock prices,
is the stock price at time T plus one, which is 60,
and therefore, what we need to input here,
is i, and not i plus one.
All right,
and that's just because of the classic Python phenomenon
that the indexes start at zero,
so everything is non-intuitively shifted by one,
and that's why we have to get 60.
All right, so okay,
now we have the 60 preview stock prices in X_train,
and the stock price at time T plus one in y_train.
Perfect, we have the heart of our structure.
And now, the important thing is,
remember I told you that we first made the search,
and then we'll take care of getting the right NumPy array.
While that's exactly what we're gonna do now.
So far, as I told you, X_train and y_train are lists
and we need to make them NumPy arrays again,
so that they can be accepted
by our future Recurrent Neural Network.
And so to do this, well it's actually pretty simple.
We need to take X_train and y_train
and then equals, then we're gonna use NumPy of course,
because we are gonna create our NumPy arrays with NumPy,
and NumPy has a shortcut np, so NumPy dot array.
We use the array function of NumPy
that does exactly what we want, that is create NumPy arrays.
And so now, according to you, what do we need to do?
Well we simply need to input in this array function
the object we want to make as a NumPy array.
And so our first object is X_train.
So with this, X_train will become a NumPy array,
and now we need to do the same for y_train,
so I'm copying this and pasting it here,
and replacing of course X_train by y_train.
And there we go, we now have our data structure
in the right format.
So we're gonna have a look
at this special data structure right now.
So I'm going to select these lines of code and execute.
Perfect, everything looks fine.
So, now, let's have a look
at first X_train, the tricky one.
So as you can see this is a special data structure.
So, to make things clear, the first line
of observation here corresponds to time T equals 60.
That is, it corresponds to the stock price
at the 60th financial day of our training dataset.
And all these values that you see here,
are the previous 60 stock prices before that time 60,
before that stock price a the 60th financial day.
All right, as you can see there are 59 values here.
And then, if we take the first line,
that is the observation of index one,
well that corresponds to the stock price
at the 61st financial day of our training dataset,
and all these stock prices are the preview stock
before that 61st stock price of our training dataset.
All right, is that clear?
And so you can notice some same values
in different lines of course,
because since here we're getting the 60 stock prices
before T equals 60, and here, the 60 stock prices
before T equals 61, well of course,
we have 59 stock prices in common.
And that's totally normal,
that's because we have this sliding window
of size 60 sliding with a stride of one at each observation,
that is from one observation to the next.
So that's totally normal, but that's the approach
that's the data structure we need to create
as the input of a Recurrent Neural Network.
But it's not over, you will see that in the next step
we will need to add a new dimension to this structure,
and you will see that it is even more powerful,
because you will realize that to predict
the Google stock price,
you don't have to do it with only one stock price,
which is the previews Google stock price,
but with several other indicators.
And these other indicators can be some other columns
of our dataset, like for example the close column,
or the volumes, or even some other different stock prices
to which you could believe have some correlations
with the Google stock price.
But we won't do this in this implementation,
we'll just use the Google stock price,
but you will see that with this new structure
we're gonna create in the next tutorial,
you will be able to include some other indicators
thanks to this new dimension.
I will show you this again in the next tutorial,
but so far let me just show you y_train,
which is much more simple to visualize.
It contains, of course, the stock price at time T plus one,
so for example, if we take X_train again,
well here all the stock prices
are the 60 preview stock prices before T equal 60,
and based on all the stock prices of this line,
we will train our Recurrent Neural Network
to predict the stock price at time T plus one,
which is exactly this one.
As you can see, this is the stock price at time T plus one.
All right, so that's the idea.
I hope it's clear.
Make sure to understand what's going on here,
because then in the next tutorial
we will add even more complexity
as you understood by adding this new dimension.
All right, so perfect.
Let's close this, and now let's move on to the next step,
and until then, enjoy deep learning.