Hello and welcome back to the course
on deep learning.
Today we're talking about max pooling
and we've got some very exciting slides coming up ahead
and even a special surprise at the very end of the tutorial.
So, let's get started.
The first question is: what is pooling and
why do we need it?
Well, to answer that question let's have a look
at these images. On these 3 images, we've got
a cheetah, in fact it is the same exact cheetah.
On the 1st image, the image is positioned properly
and the cheetah is looking straight at you.
On the 2nd image, it's a bit rotated
and the 3rd image is a bit squashed.
And the thing here is that we want the neural network
to be able to recognize the cheetah
in every single one of these images.
In fact, this is just one cheetah.
What if we have lots of different cheetahs?
Here's a cheetah, here's another cheetah,
here's a cheetah, here's a cheetah.
and here's a cheetah.
And we want the neural network to recognize
all of these cheetahs as cheetahs and how can it
do that if they're all looking in different
directions, they're all in different parts of the image,
their like, their faces are all positioned
in different parts of the image, somebody's
on the right hand side, somebody's in the left corner,
somebody's in the middle.
Uh, they're all a bit different.
The texture's a little bit different,
the lighting's a bit different.
There's lots of little differences and so if
the neural network looks for exactly
a certain feature, for instance a distinctive
feature of the cheetah is the tears that are
on its face going from the eyes or the shadows
that look like tears, the texture, the pattern
that is going from its eyes down on the sides
of its nose, that looks like tears
that's a distinctive feature of the cheetah.
But if it's looking for that feature which it
learned from certain cheetahs, in an exact
location or an exact shape or form or texture,
it will never find these other cheetahs.
So, we have to make sure that our neural network
has a property called spatial invariance,
meaning that it doesn't care
where the features are located, not so much as in which part
of the image because we've kind of taken that
into consideration with our map,
with our convolution layer.
But it doesn't have to care if
the features are a bit tilted, if the features
are a bit different in texture, if the
features are a bit closer or if the features
are a bit further apart, relative to each other.
So, if the feature itself is a bit distorted,
our neural network has to have some level of flexibility
to be able to still find that feature
and that is what pooling is all about.
So, let's have a look at how pooling works.
Here's our feature map, so we've already done
our convolution and we've completed that part
and now we're working with the convolution layer.
Now we're going to apply pooling.
So how does it work?
We're going to be applying max pooling.
Uh, there's several different types of
pooling you can apply, there's mean pooling,
max pooling, some pooling and we'll comment
on those towards the end of this tutorial.
But for now we're just applying max pooling.
So, we take a box of 2x2 pixels, like that,
and again it doesn't have to be 2x2, you can
choose any size of box and again we'll comment
on that towards the end of the tutorial.
And, you place it in the top left hand corner
and you find the maximum value in that box
and then you record only that value.
And you disregard the other 3, so in your
box you have 4 values, you disregard three,
you only keep one, the maximum, which is 1 in this case.
Then you move your box to the right, by a stride,
you select the stride once again.
So here we select a stride of 2 and that's
what you normally select.
You can select a stride of 1, you can select
so they're overlapping boxes, you can select
any kind of stride you like, even 3 if you want.
But we're selecting a stride of 2 here,
that's what is commonly used.
And then you repeat the process, record the maximum.
Here, if you cross over it doesn't matter, you
just keep continue doing what you're doing.
So you still record the maximum here, 0.
Um, here the maximum is 4, here the maximum is 2,
here the maximum is 1, 0, 2 and then 1.
As you can see, a few things happened.
First of all, we still were able
to preserve the features, right.
The maximum numbers, they represent,
because we know how the convolution layer works,
we know that the maximum or the large numbers
in your feature map, they represent
where you actually found the closest
similarity to your feature.
But by then pooling these features,
we are, first of all, getting rid of 75%
of the information that is not the feature,
which is not the important things that
we're looking out for because we're disregarding
3 pixels out of 4 so we're only keeping 25%,
and then also because we are taking the maximum
of the pixels or the values that we have,
we are therefore accounting for any distortion.
So, for instance, 2 images in which, for example,
the cheetahs tears' on the eyes are, in 1 image,
a bit to the left or a bit rotated to the left.
And then in the other one, they're a bit
how they're supposed to be or how we,
like if we take 1 as the basis and
then the other one, they're a bit rotated to the left.
The pooled feature will be exactly the same
so you can see here, if we're talking
about the cheetah's tears then let's say
this is the 4 and this is where it was here.
Then if it was a bit rotated, so for instance
the 4 ended up over here, then when we
are doing the pooling, we're still gonna get
the same pooled feature map.
And that's kind of the principle behind it,
it's a very rough explanation again,
intuitive explanation, but that's the point
of pooling that we're still being able to
preserve the features and moreover,
account for their possible spatial or textural
or other kind of distortions.
And in addition to all of that, we're reducing
the size, so there's another benefit.
So, we've got, we're preserving the features,
we're introducing spatial invariance,
we're reducing the size by 75% which is huge,
which is really gonna help in terms of processing.
And, moreover, another benefit of pooling is
we're reducing the number of parameters, so we're
reducing again by 75%, we're reducing the
number of parameters that are going to go
into our final layers of the neural network.
And therefore, we're preventing overfitting.
It is a very important benefit of pooling
that we're removing information and that is a good thing,
that is a good thing because that way,
our model won't be able to overfit
onto that information because especially
because that information is not relevant.
Remember like at the very start, we were talking
about even for us as humans, it's important
to see exactly the features, rather than all
this other noise that is coming into our eyes.
Well, same thing for neural networks.
They, by disregarding the unnecessary non-important
information, we're helping with preventing of overfitting.
So there we go, that is what pooling is about.
And the question here is of course, why max pooling?
Right, there's lots of different types
of pooling and you know, why a stride of 2?,
why a size of 2x2 pixels?, lots of all these things.
And all that note I'd like to introduce you
to this lovely research paper called
"Evaluation of Pooling Operations in Convolutional
Architectures for Object Recognition"
by Dominic Scherer from University of Bonn.
There is a link and the beauty about
this paper is that it's very very simple,
very straightforward.
So if you've never read a research paper,
but you'd like to give it a go,
this is a great place to start.
It's very short, only 10 pages, very easy to read.
And plus the extra benefit is that now that we've
discussed convolution and pooling, you will be
totally comfortable with everything
they're talking about in this paper.
This is a great way to actually reinforce your
knowledge so I highly recommend checking this paper out.
It will take 20 mins to read it
and you can even skip part 2, which is called
"Related Work" if it feels a bit far-fetched
or alienating, just don't read that part,
go straight from part 1 to part 3.
And the one thing that you do need to know about
this paper, they talk about a concept called sub-sampling.
Well sub-sampling is basically average pooling.
So, remember how here we were taking, we were
taking the maximum, so you now square root,
taking the maximum value.
There's a concept called mean pooling or sum pooling.
Sum pooling is just you sum these values up.
Average pooling, or mean pooling, you take
the average value out of all of these.
And sub-sampling is kind of like a
generalization of mean pooling, it's a more
kind of generalized approach to taking the
average of these values.
And you can read a bit more about it in the paper,
but otherwise just think of it
as average pooling when you're reading that paper.
And so that's where you can get some
additional information on this topic.
And now, kind of, let's recap where have we got onto?
So, there's our input image, then we apply the
convolution operation and we got the convolution layer.
And now, to each of those feature maps that we get,
we've applied the pooling layer so we've done
these two steps: convolution and pooling.
And now, we're going to do something very fun,
something very exciting, we're going to
experiment with this.
So this is a screenshot I took from a tool,
created by Adam Harley from
back when he was at Ryerson University of Computer Science
and now he's at Carnegie Mellon, I think doing his PhD.
And great tool, so let's open up, let's have a look.
So you can find it, you can't actually find it
through Google, you have to know the URL.
It's, it's just hard to find it
through Google 'cause there's no text here.
Well, just this URL. (laughing)
"scs.ryerson.ca" and then this stuff on the end.
And basically, this is exactly
what we're doing but visualized.
So here you need to draw a number,
so let's say I draw a number 4.
And this tool will put the number 4 here,
that's your image in our first step, then this is the
convolution step, right?
And this is the pooling step and also pooling,
by the way, is also called down-sampling.
So, pooling and down-sampling are the same things.
So you can see it's applied convolution and
it's applied pooling and you can see
how it exactly works, so you can see
what kinds of convolutions it has applied,
or what kind of filters it's applied,
what they look like, you can see what
features it's looking out for.
And then it's applied pooling, so it's
reducing the size and you can see here that,
this is important right, so you can see
that this is the convolved image
and this is the pooled image and you can still
see the same features, it's just less information
but same features, right?
The features are preserved, that's the important part.
And moreover, you know if our 4 was a bit to the
kind of like, rotated a bit to the side,
it would still be able to pick
up very similar pooled layers.
And then after that it's got more layers,
we haven't talked about that yet.
So then it's got another convolution layer here,
which we actually won't have.
And then it has another pooled layer,
but it's basically just repeating that same process.
And then after that, this is what we are
going to be talking about further down in the course.
It's got all the fully connected layers and so on.
But you can definitely play around with that,
so if I delete that and if I draw a 7,
you will see that it actually tells you the guess
and it guesses that this is a 7
and the second guess, the second likelihood is a 3.
So you can draw it some challenging things
and see if it can pick them up.
So let's say, if I draw something that
looks like a 0, but is not a finished 0
will it pick it up?
No, this time it didn't pick it up,
looks like a 9 to the image.
What if I kinda like finish like that?
See now, it thinks it's a 0 or a 9 and you can
see what's lighting up, the 0 or the 9,
but we'll talk about that part further down.
Let's do one more, let's say like 8,
I think 8's are pretty hard for this.
No, picked up a 8, so you can see that goes
into an 8 and after that it stops being recognizable.
It stops making sense to us humans, right?
These features that it's working with, but at the same time,
it is correctly recognizing that it's an 8.
Alright, so definitely play around with that,
you can draw a smiley face, see what happens then.
Looks like a 3 to this, to this tool
because the tool is obviously only trained
up on digits from 0-9, so it has to recognize
something there out of those and it recognizes a 3.
It's like in life when you see something
like a type of fruit that you've never seen before,
like a custard apple or something, and you
think that it's a pear because you've
never actually seen one before,
you don't know what to classify it as.
Same thing here so, it hasn't actually trained
on smiley faces and that's why it thinks it's a tree.
It's a three.
So there we go, it's a very powerful tool,
it will be helpful for you to play around with it
and actually put your mouse over a pixel,
it shows you where the feature detector was
to pick up that pixel, so you can see where
this pixel's coming from.
And also, so you can see how the filter was
kind of like going through the image
how we talked about it in the course.
And here, you can see the pooling, you can see
that the pooling is done with a, the pooling is
done with a little square size of 2x2 and you can
see that it's a stride of 2 as well,
just as we discussed in today's tutorial.
So there you go, have a play around with
that and I hope you enjoyed today's session.
I look forward to seeing you next time
and until then, enjoy deep learning!