Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So now we have everything ready, we have our data
well preprocessed and the keras libraries and packages
well imported, so now we're ready to start with first step
of creating our very first artificial neural network
and that's step consists of initializing the the ANN,
that is defining it as a sequence of layers.
They're actually two ways of initializing a
deep learning model, it's either by defining the
sequence of layers or the other way, defining a graph.
So here, since we'll make an artificial neural network with
successive layers as you saw in Kirill's intuition tutorial,
well, we will initialize our deep learning model by
defining it as a sequence of layers.
So, let's do that, it's actually very simple.
We just need to create a nubject of the sequential class,
a class that we, of course, take from the
sequential module here.
Alright, so let's do it.
This object that we're going to create is nothing else
than the model itself, that is the neural network
that will have a role of classifier here because
our problem is a classification problem where we have to
predict a class, so this neural network model is going
to be a classifier and since after we're going to predict
the tested results using this classifier name here,
well, we will call our model, the neural network that
we're gonna build, classifier.
Here we go, so this classifier object is nothing else
than the future artificial neural network
that we're gonna build.
So, equals and then we use the sequential class
because this classifier object is actually a nubject
of the sequential class.
So, we know how to do that, we just need to take
the class here and add some parenthesis and we don't need
to input any argument because we will define the layers
step by step afterwards, we will start with the input layer
and the first hidden layer and then we'll add some more
hidden layers and the finally we'll add the output layer.
So, that's all for the first step.
We are ready to select this line and execute to initialize
our artificial neural network classifier.
Alright, so that's done.
We are now ready to add the different layers in this ANN
and we will start with the input layer
and the first hidden layer.
So, that's exactly our next step which we will do
in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.