Hello and welcome back
to the course on deep learning.
Today we're gonna have an even quicker tutorial
than last time.
We're gonna talk about Deep Boltzmann Machines.
And this is another topic, just like the DBNs,
or deep belief networks,
is another very, very advanced topic
and it is definitely out of the,
way out of the scope of this course,
but at the same time we felt that it's important
for us to at least mention these two topics
so that you know what they are
and you're aware of these things
and that if you feel like you need to delve deeper
into either deep belief networks or Deep Boltzmann Machines
then you know where to find the right materials then.
You know where to start.
So the first thing, and the most important thing
I wanted to point out is that
deep belief networks are not the same
as Deep Boltzmann Machines.
You might come across these terms sometime
and just important to keep them separate,
understand what the differences are,
or what the main difference is,
so that you know which one you're talking about
or which one you're dealing with.
So here we've got a deep belief network
as you remember from the previous tutorial,
so stacked RBMs, and then after the training has happened,
you make sure that all of your layers,
except for the top two, are directed layers
or the connections between them are directed.
Well in Deep Boltzmann Machine, you don't have that.
You don't need to, well actually you just don't
deprive the network of the undirectedness
of its connections.
And therefore, this is what a
Deep Boltzmann Machine looks like.
And that's kind of the main difference,
it's the main architectural difference between the two.
There's a great paper,
which we're going to direct you towards
in terms of Deep Boltzmann Machines.
It's called Deep Boltzmann Machines
by Rusian Salakhutdinov.
I think it's 2009, couldn't determine the exact date.
But the good news is that this paper was written
together with Jeffrey Hinton,
who's the second author on this paper.
So that's always a good thing that Jeffrey Hinton
is part of a paper and Ruslan actually has
quite few papers on Boltzmann Machines
and RBMs and stuff like that.
So these are two people who know what they're talking about.
Here you've got actually two examples on the image,
deep belief network and Deep Boltzmann Machine.
The main thing that if you're curious about
what's the difference in terms of application,
well it is speculated that Deep Boltzmann Machines
actually can extract features
that are more sophisticated, more complex,
and therefore they could potentially be used
for more complex tasks.
So that's a very short breakdown.
If you'd like to learn more,
then this is a good place to start.
Again this is a very advanced topic
and we're not going to delve into it here,
but if you'd like to look into Deep Boltzmann Machines
a bit further, than this paper
is a good place to get started on that.
And I hope you enjoyed today's tutorial
and until next time, enjoy deep learning.