Hello, and welcome back to the course
on deep learning.
In today's tutorial, we're going to go through an
advanced self organizing map,
we're going to have a look at how to actually read them.
So let's get started.
You might come across a self organizing map
that looks like this.
Well, there's actually a lot of self organizing maps inside
or a lot of representations inside this
one self organizing map.
And even though you might not always
have these in your projects,
or in the results that you're trying to interpret
sometimes you might come across them
and it's useful to know what's going on.
So this is an example from Wikipedia,
this is a self organizing map of voting results
or voting patterns in the US Congress
and basically the input data for this map
was like a data sets where you had Members of Congress
and in the US Congress I looked it up it's like over 500
and something members 535 Members, or something like that.
And I think like out of them 100 are Senators,
but basically you had inputs as the Members,
and then you had information on did each,
what did each Member say about a certain question
that they were voting on.
Did they say yes, did they say no,
or did they abstain from voting.
And based on that information, the self organizing map
was able to in an unsupervised manner, as they, as they do,
was able to understand which Members of Congress are close
are similar to each other, which are dissimilar,
and place them onto a map.
And so this is the results that we have.
So we're going to start one by one,
and slowly will start to make more and more sense.
So here we've got a map of the Members of Congress,
how the self organizing map splits the data set
or split the Members into two classes.
And this is very interesting actually, because
the actual split between the parties is modeled over here.
So when you ask the SOM which Member belongs to which
party, the answer is like this,
so red here is Republican and blue is Democratic Party.
And at the same time,
the overall clusters are a bit different.
So this is how the self organizing map,
splits the Members of Parliament,
just based on all of the things that they voted on,
on all of the different questions.
So you can see that it is a bit different.
So over here, specifically, there's a bit of a,
like the red goes a bit to the right,
and here not necessarily red means Republican,
blue means Democratic here,
just red and blue other two colors that are used
to identify the two clusters.
So when you tell the SOM is you can only have two clusters.
It will identify the clusters in this way.
So that's what this first representation shows us.
Then in the second representation,
we see the unified district distance matrix,
is also called the you matrix
and what it shows is the distance between points
on the self organizing map, so between nodes,
and and as you can see here, it's darker,
and what that means is that these points are further apart
from each other, and when it's lighter,
it means that points are close together.
It makes sense over here, because the darker points
are exactly on that ridge on this ridge over here.
And that means that they're further apart
that there's a lot of dissimilarity here
while there's actually a lot of similarity here.
And now, like we've already talked about this one,
this is there belonging to either Democratic Party
or the Republican Party.
And here are actually the votes,
so red means that they voted yes,
blue means that they voted no.
And this is the result that you get when you
apply the self organizing map to the input data.
So this is how the self organizing map
votes more models those votes models those results.
So I can't read the full label here
and this is the all information I have,
and I think it here it says bankruptcy abuse prevention,
I'm not sure if it has more text after that.
But as you can see, in this case Republicans voted yes
and maybe that is a corporate bankruptcy,
rather than an individual purpose bankruptcy.
So basically, you can see that all these people voted yes
and this is the key to today's tutorial
reading and advanced self organizing map.
So you have the results here and then you need to remember
to overlay it visually with your cluster.
And sometimes in these maps you'll actually see
this line will be represented as a black line
like just a black border here,
which will show you the separate cluster,
it'll show you this cluster
and it will show you this cluster.
And but in here, we don't have the border,
just imagine it visually,
and it's good it goes through about the center
so if you imagine the border here visually,
it goes like this and then goes here,
so you can see that most of the Republicans
or all the Republicans according to the
self organizing map voted yes.
And then even some of the Democrats voted yes.
And then they were Democratic voters who voted no.
Let's look at another one.
Border Protection, anti terrorism as I understand,
something else, maybe a law or something.
So here you can see a very interesting split.
So again, remember that you have your split between the
clusters so Democratic so all of this is the main plot
that you always have to keep in mind.
You've got the Democrat the Republican and Democratics
so this is the Republics over here, Democrats over here,
you can see that some Democrats voted no over here,
but most Democrats voted yes,
and then some even Republicans voted yes.
Broadcast decency enforcement.
Looks like there's a lot of consensus on this question.
And like over here, you can see a bit of yellow
so we'll get to this in a second.
So basically, first of all, you can see a lot of red
that means or red is a one meaning that
a lot of people voted yes.
And if you look at the splits, remember the split visually
transitioned over here, you can see that it goes
like around there goes over here, so
all of the Republicans definitely be voted yes.
Most of the Democrats voted yes.
Some people voted no.
So there's a couple of people over here.
But generally speaking, most Democrats also voted yes.
So why do we have these yellow nodes over here
and over here?
Well, the reason for this most likely,
is that here we've got 15 by 15 nodes.
So that means we have about 225 or so nodes
in our self organizing map,
whereas in the US Congress, you have over 500 Members.
So meaning that the way this map has been overlaid
over our data, is not a one to one relationship.
They in every point they can be several Members of Congress
represented within every node
or some nodes might be one, some nodes might be more,
it might be three people represented by every node.
Maybe two and so, this yellow basically means that
maybe overall there was everybody in this area was voting
has a yes, but then there was like one or two people
who voted no, and same thing over here,
so that means there's kind of some sort of
inconsistency there.
All right, through this ridge,
through this border that we have,
you can see that most likely it was on the Democratic side.
Class Action Fairness Act.
So here Republicans mostly yes, Democrats no.
Continuity in representation, something about that.
So here you've got some here but also you can see
a bit of inconsistency here as well.
Personal Responsibility, Private Property Rights.
Interesting stem cell research enhancement,
look at this, it flipped over here,
so usually Republicans on all these questions
that maybe the questions were picked out in such a way,
but usually in all of these questions,
Republicans were voting yes
and Democrats were either voting yes or sometimes no,
but here is other way around,
so here you've got the Democrats voting yes.
And then you've got Republicans,
some of the Republicans voting no.
So again remember this a split
well remember the split and clusters
again this is most of the in like this is very similar
to this why are we using this main class,
we probably not the best way to say Democrats Republicans
because actual split is like this,
is more like this and like this,
but at the same time, we can see that these are similar.
So that's why we've been saying Republicans Democrats,
even though the splits like this in reality,
but in the best way to say it is cluster A, cluster B,
or red cluster, blue cluster.
So, you know, in this case, the red cluster,
they had a bit of some people voting no,
some people voting no, some people voting yes.
And the blue cluster had a lot of people voting yes,
most of the people voting yes so,
cluster one and closer two, so or called left cluster,
right cluster and that's what you're normally going to
have your datas, but in our case,
because we can see that the clusters
and the split between parties is so similar,
it is a subdivision or it's a good enough approximation
to call these cluster Republicans and Democrats,
even though that's not how the cluster organize
these clusters are identified by the self organizing map,
and it, it doesn't just blatantly use a Republican Democrat
identify these clusters, it uses all of this information,
all of the voting results to identify these clusters,
all the information that it has access to.
Tax relief, extension, and so on.
So you can go through these on your own,
just to practice and see how this works.
And while we're on this point, what I wanted also to mention
is that, because of the simplicity of self organizing maps,
you will find that there are lots and lots of different
versions and variations of implementations
of self organizing map.
So let's have a look at this.
So let's kind of zoom out of that one.
And that's one example from Wikipedia.
That's, that's available there.
Here's another example from another website,
and the sources are outlined at the bottom
in order of appearance.
So this one is from R-bloggers,
so you can create a self organizing map in R
which will look like this.
This is a self organizing map which we'll use in this
course, and the source we'll identify the source
when we're going through that through the tutorials
in the practical side of the course.
Here's a self organizing map from Stack Overflow.
Here's a self organizing map from Discovery which is a great
tool specifically designed to create self organizing maps.
Here's the self organizing map from a Visual Cinnamon
and the website, the blog.
And so here you can actually see those lines
which I was talking about,
these highlights and identify the clusters
and then as you go through those separate features of your
visualization or of features of your data set,
you still keep these clusters in mind.
But then you go through the features
and actually same thing over here.
So you can see these are the clusters that have been
identified and then you have separate maps
for each one of your features,
it's showing you that's what we were doing there
we were practicing reading the software using map.
And actually on this one I wanted to reference that because
it's actually quite a cool representation.
This one is coded in D3.js, so it's a Java JavaScript
library D3, really cool, cool library I've played
around with D3 myself and very interesting.
So this is not Java, this is JavaScript,
this is the web based programming language.
So you can actually program in it and in a text editor
and then run it in your browser.
And I wanted to show you this because it's a cool,
great implementation and at the same time, well,
let's look at it for first where did I put it,
there is Visual Cinnamon.
So if you scroll down here, this is the link
that was referenced over there
and you can get it from the course materials.
So if you scroll down here.
So this is by Nadieh Bremer from Netherlands Amsterdam
and she was kind enough to actually explain how she created
this visualization and all the hexagons
and you've got the codes here.
And if you've done any web coding,
then you'll find this pretty straightforward.
It's very interesting library to look into d3.js,
very beautiful things can be created with it.
So there's an example.
So again, you can see this is a good example
that you can see that you've got
the clusters identified with the borders,
with the black borders,
and then you've got the different images
or different features displayed in the background.
So here you've got one, here you got another one
or in different conditions so you can see that
she's changing, she's in this case she's just changing
the color range, but that's what it would look like
if you're looking at different features as well
and where you can get is you can get the actual code
on bl.ocks.org
and so you can actually get the code for this here
if you wanna code in D3.
And by the way, if you're while you're here,
you should definitely have a look at popular stuff
on bl.ocks.org.
So all of these visualizations are done in d3.js,
a really powerful language for programming things.
And a lot of them are interactive.
So if you're here, definitely check it out.
But other than that, this is an implementation in
JavaScript, and the thing about self organizing maps
are so simple compared to all other neural networks
that you will find implementations as we just saw in
R, in Python, in JavaScript, in Java.
You can pretty much code this yourself in any language.
It's not that difficult.
Just in this case using hexagons, you can use circles,
you can use squares, you can use whatever you like
the mathematics behind it is so simple
that it is very straightforward to implement
in any language.
So if you have a preferred language yourself,
that you're comfortable with,
that you're used to programming in,
then this could be a good challenge for you
to implement self organizing maps in that language
or at least find a library online somewhere
that already has some starring elements
or has that that core of SOMs for you
and explore it further.
So there we go.
I hope you enjoyed today's tutorial
and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.