Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
Alright, we completed two steps out of four,
and today is about the third step, Flattening.
So this step is a crucial step to understand,
because basically this step consists
of taking all our Pooled Feature Maps
and put them into one single vector.
This is going to be a huge vector of course
because even if we reduced the size of the Feature Maps
and divided them by two,
well we still have many Pooled Feature Maps.
So to summarize, we have all our Feature Maps
in the Pooling Layer, we apply the Flattening Step
and we get this huge single vector
that contains all different cells
of of all the different Feature Maps.
And this single vector is going to be
the Input Layer of a future ANN,
the ANN that we know from the previous section
that is a classic ANN with Fully Connected Layers.
Now we can ask ourselves to very important questions.
The first question is, why don't we lose
the spacial structure by Flattening
all these Feature Maps into one same, single vector.
And the answer is,
that's because by creating our Feature Maps,
we extracted the spatial structure informations,
by, you know, by getting these high numbers
in the Feature Maps, thanks to the Feature Detector
that we applied on the Input Image
through the Convolution Step.
So basically these high numbers represent
the spatial structure of our images
because these high numbers in the Feature Maps
are associated to a specific feature in the input image.
And since then, we apply the Max Pooling Step,
we keep these high numbers because we take the Max.
And then the Flattening Step just consists
of putting all the numbers in the cells
of the Feature Maps into one, same, single vector.
Well we still keep these high numbers
in this one, single vector and since these high numbers
represent the spatial structure of the Input Image
and are associated to one specific feature
of this spatial structure,
well, we keep this spatial structure information,
even in this one, huge, single vector.
And now the second question is,
why didn't we directly take all the pixels
of the Input Image and Flatten them
into this one, same, single vector, you know,
without applying the previous steps,
the Convolution Step and Max Pooling Step?
Well, that's because if we directly Flatten
the Input Image pixels
into this huge, single, one-dimensional vector,
then each node of this huge vector
will represent one pixel of the Image,
independently of the pixels that are around it.
So we only get informations of the pixel itself,
and we don't get informations of how this pixel
is spatially connected to the other pixels around it.
So basically, we don't get any information
of the spatial structure around this pixel.
However, if we apply the Convolution Step
and the Max Pooling Step to create
all the reduced size Feature Maps,
and Flatten all these Feature Maps into this
huge, single, one-dimensional vector,
then since each Feature Map corresponds
to one specific feature of the image,
then each node of this huge vector
that contains a high number, will represent
the information of a specific feature,
a specific detail of the Input Image,
like for example, the upper left border of a dog nose.
And that is because this high number
doesn't represent a unique pixel by itself.
It represents the study specific feature,
that the Feature Detector could extract
from the Input Image, through the Convolution Operation.
And therefore eventually, we keep
the spatial structure information of the Input Image.
So now, let's go back to Spyder
and let's take care of this Flattening Step.
So as usual, we're gonna take our classifier,
and copy it and paste it here
and then dot to introduce the add method,
that we still use to create this new layer,
well this huge, single vector.
And so parentheses and inside these parentheses,
we're gonna use a new function that we haven't used before.
And that is as you might have guessed, the Flatten Function.
This is the function that will flatten all the Feature Maps
in the Pooling Layer into this huge, single vector.
So let's input this function, Flatten, spell this way,
and then some parentheses of course because it's a function.
But then the good news is, that we don't need to input
any parameters here because Keras will understand that,
you know, since we're taking a classifier object,
that it needs to Flatten the previous layer
that we obtain here, after the Convolution Step
and the Max Pooling Step.
So we're all good, we just need
to select this line and execute,
to complete the Flattening Step and everything is all good.
Now this huge, single vector is created
and basically it contains all the informations
of the spatial structure of your images.
And so now what we only have to do left,
is to create a classic ANN, that will classify the images,
and it will classify them well thanks to this Input Vector,
that contains the informations of the spatial structure.
So three steps down, one more to go
and we will be done with our Convolutional Neural Network,
all ready in the the next tutorial.
So I look forward to seeing you there,
and until then, enjoy Deep Learning.