Hello and Welcome to this Python tutorial.
So, in the previous tutorial, we initialized our
Artificial Neural Network by defining it as a sequence
of layers and now in this new tutorial, we are gonna
add the first layers of our A.N.N.
which is the input layer and the first hidden layer.
Alright, but before we do that,
let's refresh our memories to remind us about the different
steps of how an Artificial Neural Network is built.
So here is the slide.
This is the slide from the intuition tutorial
and as we can see an Artificial Neural Network
is built in seven steps.
The first step is to randomly initialize the weights
of each of the nodes to small numbers close to zero.
So that will be done thanks to the Dense function
which we take from this Dense module here
that we imported previously.
So basically, this Dense function that we're gonna use
is going to take care of this first step.
Then, next step, our first observation row goes into
the neural network and as we can see in the step two
each feature is going to one input node.
So we already know the number of nodes we'll have
in our input layer, and this number is nothing else
than the number of independent variables
we have in our matrix of features.
So what is this number?
That is 11 independent variables.
So that means that in our input layer,
we'll have 11 input nodes.
Then the third step is forward-propagation,
so from left to right the neurons are activated by the
activation function in such a way that the higher the value
of the activation function is for the neuron,
the more impact this neuron is going to have in the network.
That means the more it will pass on the signal
from the nodes on the left to the nodes on the right,
and so speaking of activation function, what we'll have
to do in this tutorial to define the first hidden layer
is to choose an activation function and as a reminder,
there are several activation functions and the best one
based on experiments and based on research is
the rectifier function, which you can see right here.
We also have this sigmoid function which is really good
for output layer since using the sigmoid function
for the output layer will allow us to get the probabilities
of the different class, that means that will get the
probability that the class equals one
for each of the observation and even the new observations
of the test set when we'll make our predictions.
So that means that for each observations of the test set
we'll get the probability that the customer leaves the bank
and the probability that the customer stays in the bank
and so that's great because as Kirill explain when he
described the model, we are trying to build a segmentation
model and by getting the probabilities thanks to the
sigmoid activation function for the output layer,
well we will be able to see which customers have the highest
probabilities to leave the bank, so we will even be able to
make a ranking of the customers ranked by their probability
to leave the bank so that can be very useful and then you
can segment your customers according to their probability
to leave the bank and according to what you decide to do
in terms of business constraints and business goals.
Alright, so to summarize,
we'll choose the rectifier activation function
for the hidden layers and we'll choose
the sigmoid activation function for the output layer.
Alright, so then step four, in step four the algorithm
compares the predicted result to the actual result
and that generates an error and then in the step five
this error is back-propagated in the neural network
from right to left and all the weights are updated
according to how much they are responsible
for this generated error.
And by the way, there are several way of updating these
weights and this way is defined by the learning rate
perimeter which decides by how much the weights are updated.
Alright, and then we have step six, where we repeat
steps one to five either after each observation or
either after a batch of observations like for example
we update the weights every ten observations going
into the network and finally step seven,
when the whole training set passed through the A.N.N.
that makes an epoch and re-repeat many more epoch.
And we will see how many epoch we choose to do in the end.
Alright, so that was a quick refresher
of how we can train an Artificial Neural Network
using Stochastic Gradient Descent
and so now let's do this step here to add the
input layer and the first hidden layer.
Alright, so the first thing we're gonna do is take
our classifier, that's the classifier we initialized
in the previous step by creating an object
of the sequential class and now we're gonna use a method
of this object which is the add method and as you might
have guessed, this add method is the method that we use
to add the different layers in our neural network.
So remember, an object is separated from the method
by a dot, here we go, and as you can see, the first method
here on this list is add, so I just need to press Enter.
Here we go, and now let's add some parenthesis and see
what we need to add in this add method.
So as you saw the yellow rectangle appear here,
there is only one argument and this argument is the layer
that we want to add to our A.N.N.
So as you can see in this title of this section,
right now we're gonna add two layers,
the input layer and the first hidden layer
and we are gonna do this thanks to the Dense function
I've mentioned earlier and so right now we're going to input
Dense and then some parenthesis and as you can see now
there are a lot of arguments and so we'll add the different
arguments of this Dense function and these arguments
are going to be all the perimeters that we can see
on this slide that is how the weights are updated,
what is the activation function we use
and what is the number of nodes we want to chose
in the layer and what is the number of input nodes?
Well, everything happens here in this Dense function.
So, let's have a better look at what we need to input
by pressing here command I to get into the help
and that gives us all the different perimeters
that we need to input.
Alright, so let's have a look at the first perimeter.
The first perimeter is output_dim,
okay so what is output_dim?
That is simply the number of nodes you want to add
in this hidden layer, because more precisely,
what this add function does is not to add the input
layer in the first hidden layer, what it really does
is add this hidden layer, and by adding this hidden layer
we're specifying the number of inputs in the previous
layer which is the input layer.
So, the output_dim here is just the number of nodes
of the layer we are adding in this add function.
So, that's the number of nodes of the hidden layer,
and now the big question is how many nodes are we gonna
add in this hidden layer?
That's a big question in Deep Learning.
You'll get a lot of questions like that in forums
or Deep Learning discussions and the answer that comes
most of the time is that it's art.
Indeed, there is no rule of thumbs on what would be
the optimal number of nodes in this hidden layer.
We can give some rules, like for example if your data
is linearly separable, well you don't even need a hidden
layer and in fact, you don't even need a neural network,
but we have better than that.
I would not characterize it as a rule, but rather as a tip
and this tip is not based on theory,
but rather based on experiment.
This tip is to choose the number of nodes in the hidden
layer as the average of the number of nodes in the input
layer and the number of nodes in the output layer.
That is the tip you want to use if you don't want to be
an artist and if you want to be an artist,
well what you have to do is experimenting with a technique
called perimeter tuning.
Perimeter tuning is about using some techniques,
like k-fold cross validation for example which we'll
study in part 10, model selection and ensemble model
and these k-fold cross validation technique consists
on creating a separate set in your data set besides
the training set and the test that is called a cross
validation set and basically in this set,
you experiment different perimeters of your model,
so typically the number of hidden layers and the number
of nodes in the hidden layers and then you test
the performance of your different models
with the different perimeters.
So we won't do it now obviously, because we want to focus
on our Artificial Neural Network, but keep that in mind
and keep in mind that we'll do this in part 10
and that it will help us choose the optimal perimeters
of our model, but for now we're gonna take this tip
which is to take the average of the number of nodes
in the input layer and the number of nodes in the output
layer so that is, if I go back to variable explorer,
well the number of nodes in the input layer is 11,
because the number of nodes in the input layer is
the number of independent variables, so 11,
and the number of nodes in the output layer is one
because as you saw in Kurill's intuition tutorial
when the dependent variable has a binary outcome
one or zero well there is only one node in the output layer
and so the average is 11 plus one divided by two,
that is six nodes in the hidden layer.
So that's what we'll choose for the output_dim perimeter
here and therefore the first argument
that we'll input here is output_dim
equals six.
Alright, next argument, the next argument is init,
so that corresponds to the step one of the
Stochastic Gradient Descent and so what we have to do
now is we have to randomly initialize the weight
as small numbers close to zero and so we can randomly
initialize them with a uniform function.
Here we see that we have the glorot_uniform
this is kind of a uniform function to initialize the weight
and we even have more simple, there is the simple uniform
function which will initialize the weights according
to a uniform distribution and the sciences will make sure
that the weights are small numbers close to zero.
Alright so let's input the second argument init.
Here we go, init equals in quotes uniform.
Great, now come out to input the third argument
and the third argument is the activation argument
which of course is the activation function we want
to choose in our hidden layer.
So as I just explained, we're gonna chose
the rectifier activation function for the hidden layers
and the sigmoid activation function for the output layer.
So here, since we are in the hidden layer,
we're gonna input here activation equals, and actually
the perimeter that corresponds to this
rectifier function is called relu, r-e-l-u.
Alright, so let's see if we have all the arguments here.
We specified the number of nodes in the hidden layer,
we specified the initialization method,
and we specified the activation function.
If I select this line right now and press Enter to Execute,
I get this raise Exception error, and why's that?
It's because there is another perimeter
that is kind of hidden here, that we must input as well.
Well I think you might guess what it is.
It is actually the input_dim perimeter.
If init appears as one of the last arguments here
this is actually a compulsory argument because
what is this argument?
This argument is the number of nodes in the input layer
that is the number of independent variables.
And why is it compulsory to add this argument at this stage?
It's because so far our Artificial Neural Network
is simply initialized, we haven't created any layer yet
and that's why it doesn't know here which nodes this hidden
layer here that we are creating is expecting as inputs.
So that's why we have to specify this argument here
but then when we'll add some other hidden layers
well since this first hidden layer will already be created
we won't need to specify this input_dim argument
for the next hidden layers because
since the first one will already be created,
the next hidden layer will know what to expect.
Alright so let's add this last compulsory argument here
which is
the input
underscore dim
and that is equal to 11
because we have 11 independent variables.
Alright, so now we are ready to execute,
it should work fine, so we'll select this line
and execute and as you can see, our first hidden layer
and at the same time, our input layer were very well added
in our Artificial Neural Network.
So perfect, now we're ready to move on to the next step,
which is to add a new hidden layer, which to be honest
is not necessarily useful for our dataset
but we're gonna add it anyway for two reasons.
First of all because this part is called Deep Learning
and Deep Learning is defined as an Artificial Neural Network
with many hidden layers and the second reason is simply
that if you need to add more hidden layers in your
neural networks, well you need to know how to do it.
And that's what you'll learn how to do in the next tutorial,
and until then, enjoy Deep Learning.