Welcome to this module on Access Control to EC2 Instances.
In the first clip, you will learn about Amazon EC2 key pairs.
Before we dive deep,
let's understand different types of keys that are used
for encryption and decryption purposes.
First type is symmetric keys.
When symmetric keys are used,
the same key is used both for encryption and decryption purposes.
Some of the common symmetric key algorithms are AES, DES, and RC5.
In a symmetric encryption, you will have two types of keys.
One is public key, and the other one is private, or secret key.
Public keys are used during the encryption purposes,
and the private key is used during the decryption process.
Some of the common asymmetric key algorithms are RSA, DSA, and PKCS.
Amazon EC2 uses 2048‑bit SSH2 RSA keys in securing its instances.
Let's log into EC2 console, launch a new instance,
and see how to create and secure EC2 key pairs.
Click on instances to your left.
Click Launch Instance.
Let me select one of the Amazon Linux instance that is free tier eligible.
Click Configure Instance Details.
I'm going to accept all the default conflagration.
Click Add Storage.
I will accept all the default settings again.
Click Tags.
Choose Configure Security Group.
You can see only port 22 is open to accept incoming
traffic so that we can SSH to our instance.
Click on Review and Launch.
Click Launch.
Before launching,
I can choose an existing key pair to use with this
instance or choose to create a new one.
Since I don't have a key pair yet, I'll go ahead and create one.
Give the key pair a name, and download the key pair.
The key that you're downloading is a private key,
and the public key will be in the EC2 instance.
It's very important that you save this private key in a
secure location as anyone who has access to this key can
access your instance as well.
You will also not be able to download the private key once again.
Click Launch Instance, and your instance is getting launched now.
Let me click on the instance ID, and the instance state is currently pending.
It took a few seconds before the provisioning was completed and
the instance state is changed to running.
Let me connect to this instance.
Click Connect.
You have three options to connect to this instance.
Let me choose the standalone SSH client to connect.
Let me SSH to this instance that we just launched.
I'm using the Globomantics key pair that we just created,
and I'm able to successfully connect to this instance.
Let me show you where the public key is stored in this instance.
Go to .ssh directory.
Open the file authorized_keys.
This lists the public key of the Globomantics.
So any time you connect to this instance using your private key,
it's validated against this public key before establishing a secure connection.
Now consider a scenario where an employee has been moved to a
different project and you need to make sure he or she no
longer connects to this instance.
Asking them to delete the primary key may not be a safer option.
Instead,
you can use a third‑party key generation utility to create new
keys and distribute it to your new team.
We will use ssh‑keygen.
Enter a file name to store the private key.
I'm not going to enter any passphrase.
You can see the public key is stored with .pub extension.
This public key needs to be copied to the
authorized_keys files under .ssh folder.
So let me copy it and paste the contents here and save the file.
It's also very important to download the private key file and delete
the private key to prevent any unauthorized access.
Now that I have downloaded the private key,
let me try to SSH to this instance using the newly created private key,
and you can see I'm able to successfully log in to this instance.
Now,
let's go ahead and delete the key pairs that we created
before and check what happens to our access.
Click Key Pairs to your left.
Select the key globomantics.
Click Actions and choose Delete.
Confirm the deletion by entering delete.
Now that the key pair is deleted, let's try connecting to our instance.
I'm trying to SSH to the instance using the key pair that we just deleted,
and we are still able to successfully connect.
So deleting the key pair from the console does not remove
the access that were already launched.
In order to completely remove the access, you need to remove the public key.
Let me open the authorized_keys file under .ssh directory.
Remove the public key corresponding to Globomantics.
If you are unsure which key belongs to Globomantics,
pay close attention to the last word of the keys which identifies the name.
Delete this public key, save, and exit.
Now let's try reconnecting to the instance again,
and you can see that the permission is denied.
So the only way to access this instance is using the private key globo_dev that we created using the ssh‑keygen utility.