In this clip,
we will take a detailed look at AWS Trusted Advisor and how it is different
from Amazon Inspector that we saw in the first module.
If Amazon Inspector is for your EC2 instances,
AWS Trusted Advisor is for your AWS account.
It offers best practice recommendations for your AWS
resources in five different categories.
Enterprise and business customers can stay up to date and
get alerted of any if the latest deployments violates these
best practice recommendations.
This service can also be integrated with IAM to
control access to specific checks,
and that is also a rich set of API to integrate this and
programmatically check the violations.
There are five different categories where Trusted Advisor
provides best practice recommendations.
Cost optimization, performance,
and fault tolerance are limited to enterprise and business customers.
Security and service limits are offered to all AWS customers.
Under cost optimization,
AWS shows you how you can save money on various AWS resources by eliminating
resources that are not utilized and those that remain idle.
You will see recommendations on EC2 instances that have been running less
than 10% of CPU utilizations for more than 14 days,
an Elastic Load Balancer that is not actively used,
and underutilized EBS volumes.
Under the performance section,
AWS recommends various performance improvements of your service by
checking service limits and making sure you take advantage of
monitoring for overutilized resources.
Some of the typical alerts are EC2 instances using more than 90%
of CPU consecutively for more than 4 days,
a large number of rules in your security group,
and overutilized EBS magnetic volumes.
Under fault tolerance,
you will see AWS recommendations to increase the
availability and redundancy of AWS applications.
Some of the typical recommendations include enabling server access logs to
log the details of incoming requests to an S3 bucket,
which will come in handy during a security audit,
enabling the health check of auto‑scaling group,
and checking the distribution of EC2 instances in an availability zone to
protect your applications from a single point of failure.
Service limits checks for any service usage that is
more than 80% of the service limit.
If you signed up for a free AWS account,
and when your resource utilization exceeded 80% threshold,
you must have received an email alert indicating this.
Some of the AWS services that are monitored by
Trusted Advisor are Amazon DynamoDB, Amazon EBS,
Amazon EC2, Amazon Route 53, RDS, IAM, ELB,
VPC, and SES.
Some of the security recommendations offered by Trusted Advisor
includes checking for MFA on a root account,
checking unrestricted ports, S3 bucket permissions,
IAM usage, to name a few.
We will dive deep and take a detailed look at some of the security
recommendations and how to set up CloudWatch events and monitor any
security changes to your AWS infrastructure.
I just logged into AWS Admin console, and let's search for Trusted Advisor.
You can see the dashboard shows the five categories that we discussed before.
You can see all the actions that are recommended by Trusted Advisor.
Click on Security.
You can see there is a warning and an alert.
Let me click on the alert,
and you can see that MFA is not enabled from a root account and
the recommendation action suggested by AWS.
Let's click on the warning,
and you can see the list of unrestricted ports and the
recommendation suggested by AWS, and links to additional resources.
Let me click on Service Limits, and it looks like everything looks good here.
Fault tolerance checks, cost optimization,
and performance checks are reserved for business and enterprise customers,
like we discussed before.
Let's quickly compare Amazon Inspector and Trusted Advisor.
You should be using Amazon Inspector if you need to assess your EC2
instances and the network in which it is part of.
Trusted Advisor is applicable for the entire AWS account and to
learn best practice recommendations by AWS.
Inspector needs a software agent to be installed for the assessment process,
whereas Trusted Advisor is pre‑built to your account,
and it doesn't need any additional software to be installed.
The first 250 assessments are free while using Inspector,
whereas only security checks and service limit checks are performed freely by Trusted Advisor.