Imagine a scenario where you have been told to increase the
security of the EC2 instances that are in your VPC and to
monitor all the incoming SSH connections.
This is exactly where a bastion host comes to the rescue.
The purpose of bastion host is to restrict the access to a
private network from an external network. Since bastion host
is exposed to external network,
this needs to be hardened well to minimize the chances
of penetration and security breach.
Let's dive deep by presenting an architecture diagram. You have
one VPC with a private and a public subnet.
Our goal is to protect the Linux instances that are in
the private subnet from external users.
In order to achieve this,
you launch a bastion host in public subnet that is exposed to the outside
world, and the Linux instances in the private subnet are accessible only
through the SSH that is coming from the bastion host.
You need to update the inbound traffic rules to the security group
in the private subnet to block the SSH access from all other
servers except the IP address of bastion host. As mentioned before,
bastion host needs to be hardened well so that it is not vulnerable
to security attacks.
This bastion host could also be placed in a separate VPC and set up a VPC peering connection between these two VPCs as well.