In this clip you will see how to create CloudWatch events that
detects a state change in Trusted Advisor checks.
I went ahead and took care of all the unrestricted port violations,
and in this demo you will see how to trigger a
notification if any such violations reoccur.
I'm going to set up a CloudWatch event and trigger an SNS
notification any time a status change occurs in the Trusted
Advisor. Before setting up this rule, please pay attention to the region.
You need to be in Northern Virginia region.
To your left, click on Rules.
Under Service Name select Trusted Adviser.
Under Event Type choose Check Item Refresh Status.
I'm going to leave the default selection on statuses.
You will need AWS Premium Support to select specific checks.
Choose Add target.
From the drop‑down, select SNS topic.
And I already have a topic set up with the name NotificationAlert,
which I'm going to select.
Click Configure details.
Give this rule a name.
CloudWatch rules cannot have spaces in its rule name.
Click Create rule to finish creating this CloudWatch rule.
Let me log in back to Trusted Advisor console.
Choose Security from the dashboard.
Currently, there are no errors or warnings under Security Groups. I'm going
to simulate an alert by opening up unrestricted ports.
Let me go to EC2 console.
To your left, select Security Groups.
Let me select one of the three security groups.
Click on Edit inbound rules.
Under Type, I'm going to select All traffic,
which by default is going to allow all protocol and all port ranges.
Click on Save rules.
In the same manner,
I have changed the inbound rules in the default security group and in
the other Kali Linux security group that ends in 56ab.
Let me go back to Trusted Advisor.
You can see there is an alert for Security Group sections.
Let me expand the section,
and you can see the changes that we performed in the
security groups are listed here.
You have the option of selecting the security groups
directly from the Trusted Advisor,
which will take you back to EC2 console where you can
modify the inbound rules again.
Now this change must have triggered an SNS notification.
Let's go back and validate that.
I just logged into CloudWatch console again.
Let me scroll down, and you can see a data point under SNS
dashboard for the number of notifications delivered,
which corresponds to an email notification that I received. And there are no data points for number of notifications failed.