Let's review both the scenarios in this clip. In the first scenario,
you were asked to identify the rule packages that Steve
must use in his security assessment.
In this case,
the key phrase is restricted ports, and you need to use the
rules in network reachability package to analyze your network
for access to restricted ports.
In the second scenario,
you are asked to identify the rules that Andrew needs to use in his
assessment, and the key phrase here is password policies.
In this case,
you need to use the rules from security best practices
in your vulnerability assessments.
Congratulations on completing this course! Coming out of this
course, you should have a firm understanding of using
hardened AMI in your EC2 instances,
use AWS Systems Manager to open Session and Run Commands, use AWS
Trusted Advisor to identify and assess security concerns in your AWS
account, use AWS Config to monitor non‑complaint and unsecure
resources, install unified CloudWatch agent on an EC2 instance and
collect logs, and finally, create assessment runs in Amazon Inspector and find system vulnerabilities.