Before we wrap up this module,
let's quickly see what VPC flow logs are and understand some of its limitations.
VPC flow logging lets you capture and log data
about network traffic in your VPC.
VPC flow logging records information about the IP data going in
and out of designated network interfaces,
storing this raw data in Amazon CloudWatch where it can be retrieved and viewed.
VPC flow logging is critical for security and
compliance in your AWS cloud environment.
However, it does have a few limitations that we need to be aware of.
You cannot modify a flow log's config parameters once it is created.
You need to delete and create a new one from scratch.
Not all traffic is captured in VPC flow logs. DHCP traffic, traffic
generated by a Windows instance for Amazon Windows license activation,
traffic to the reserved IP address for the default VPC router, traffic
between elastic network interface and the network load balancer network
interface, and Amazon DNS activity are not captured in flow logs. Flow
logs cannot be enabled for network interfaces that are in the EC2 classic
platform.
If your network interface has multiple IP addresses, and if the traffic
is sent to a secondary IP address, the flow log displaces the primary IP
address in the destination of this field,
which may be misleading.
When you are using a nitro‑based instance,
the aggregation interval is always one minute or less irrespective of the maximum aggregation interval that you specified manually.