(futuristic electronic music)
(keyboard keys clack)
All right, in this video,
we're going to look at merge sort.
Now, merge sort is a divide and conquer algorithm
because it involves splitting the array you wanna sort
into a bunch of smaller arrays,
and it's usually implemented using recursion.
You can write algorithm using loops,
but it's usually written recursively.
Merge sort involves two major phases.
The first phase is the splitting phase,
and second phase is the merging phase.
We do the sorting during the merging phase.
The splitting phase is a preparation phase
to make sorting faster during the merging phase.
Now, I wanna make it clear that the splitting is logical.
We don't create new arrays when we do the splitting.
We use indices to keep track of
where the array has been split.
So when during the splitting phase,
we're not actually creating new array instances.
So let's look at the splitting phase.
In the splitting phase, we start with the unsorted array,
and we divide the array into two arrays,
and remember, both of the arrays will be unsorted,
and we call the first array, the left array
and second array, the right array,
and we generally just divide the array down the middle.
If you have an odd number of elements,
it will depend on the implementation.
Some implementation will put the extra element
into the left array,
and some implementations will put the extra element
into the right array,
but the important point is you're dividing the array
or splitting the array into two arrays,
the left array and the right array,
and then, once you've done that,
you keep splitting down even further.
So now you go to the left array,
and you split that into a left and a right array,
and then, you split that left array
into a left and a right array, and you keep going,
splitting all the arrays and the sub-arrays
until you split the original array
into a bunch of one-element arrays,
and remember from our discussion of insertion sort,
a one-element array is sorted by default
because there's only one element in it.
So in the splitting phase, you're taking the array,
you're dividing it in half,
and then, you're dividing the two sub-arrays in half,
and you're dividing those four sub-arrays in half,
et cetera,
until you get down to a bunch of one-element arrays,
and that is the splitting phase.
Once you've done that,
you're going to enter the merging phase,
and in the merging phase,
you're going to merge every left/right pair
into a sorted array.
So let's say we have an array of four elements
just to explain this.
So we're gonna split that into two sub-arrays
of length two each,
and then, we're gonna split those two sub-arrays
into two arrays of one element.
So from that four-element array,
we're gonna end up with four one-element sub-arrays.
So we split the original array
into a left and right sub-array,
and then, we split the left sub-array into left and right
and the right sub-array into left and right,
and then what we do is we take the two one-element arrays
from the left sub-array,
and we merge them back into a two-element array.
The merged two-element array will be sorted,
so when we do the merge,
that's the point when we do the sort,
and then, we'll take the two elements
from the right sub-array,
and we'll merge them into a two-element sub-array.
So now we have, we're back to two arrays,
a left and a right array,
except this time, the left and the right array are sorted,
and then, we'll merge the left and right array,
which are now two elements each,
back into a four-element array,
and at that point, when we do the merge, we sort,
so we get a four-element array that's sorted,
and we have sorted our array.
So basically, we take the bunch of one-element arrays,
and we keep merging them into two-element,
four-element, eight-element, et cetera,
and at each merge, we're making sure
that the resulting arrays are sorted
until we've merged all the arrays back into one array,
and at that point, that array will be sorted
because when we're merging, we're sorting.
So every resulting array from the merge will be sorted.
Now the merging phase does not happen in place.
It uses temporary arrays.
So the splitting phase is in place,
but we need temporary arrays to do the merge.
So let's look at our usual array here.
Our start index will be zero.
Our end will be seven, which is equal to array.length,
and we're going to get our midpoint
by dividing start plus end by two,
so our midpoint will be three,
and in the implementation I'm going to show you,
the extra element will go into the right array.
So the first time we split this array,
elements zero, one, and two will go into the left array,
and elements three, four, five, and six
will go into the right array,
and so, now, let's split the left array.
So we're not gonna do anything with the right array
that's in black now,
and we're gonna look at the left array,
and for the left array, the start index is zero,
and the end index is three.
The end index is always one greater
than the index of the last element in the array.
So once again, we're gonna take the midpoint
by adding start to end and dividing by two,
so we'll have three over two which is one,
and that means that the first element
is going to go into the left array,
and elements one to two are going to into the right array,
and so now, we have this situation.
Now we have finished splitting 20.
We can't split that any further.
It's already a one-element array,
so we only have to worry at this point
about splitting the right array.
So we need to split the array
that's occupying positions one and two,
and so the start index is one.
The end index is three.
The midpoint will be one plus three over two which is two,
and so, we're gonna put the first element
into the left array
and the second element into the right array,
and we have now completed splitting the left array
into one-element arrays.
Now, one and two are both coloured in a green shade
because they're actually sibling arrays.
We go up for a minute.
The left and right arrays are the sibling arrays.
So these are the two arrays we're going to merge.
When we split the left array,
we ended up with a one-element and two-element array,
and those arrays are sibling arrays,
so when we do the merge,
we'll be merging the array that has 20
with the array that has 35 and minus 15.
We were able to split the right array one more time,
and so, the first merge we'll do on the left side
will be merging 35 with minus 15.
So we're always merging the last split.
Okay, so let's look at the right array now.
So the start index is three.
The end is seven.
The midpoint will be five,
so elements three and four will go into the left array,
and elements five to six will go into the right array.
Now let's work on the left array,
the one that has seven and 55.
The midpoint will be four,
so we're gonna put element three to three into left
and four to four into right,
and we've now finished splitting the left array
on the right side.
So now we're gonna split the right array on the right side.
So the start index is five.
The end index is seven.
The midpoint is six.
So we're gonna put element five into the left array
and element six into the right array,
and we have now completed splitting the right array
into one-element arrays,
and once again, seven and 55 are both shaded
gold, yellow, brown, whatever you wanna,
however you wanna look at that.
They're shaded the same because they're sibling arrays.
They're gonna get merged together first,
and the same applies to one and minus 22.
So now we need to merge these arrays back together,
and remember, when we do the merge, we actually sort.
So every time we merge, the resulting array is sorted.
So as I mentioned, 35 and minus 15
are sibling left/right arrays,
so they're gonna get merged.
Seven and 55 are gonna get merged.
One and minus 22 are gonna get merged.
20 won't get merged right now
because it doesn't have a sibling at the moment.
So we started with our original array,
and then, we split that into a left array and a right array,
and then, that left array was split into left and right,
and that right array was split into left and right,
and then here, the right array
was split into two two-element arrays,
and then, they were each split into two one-element arrays,
and that's what we just went through in the slides.
Now because of the recursive nature of the implementation,
it's important to note that
we're going to handle the entire left side of the array
before we start working with the right side of the array
because you'll see from the implementation
that we call a method to partition the left side,
and then, we call a method to partition the right side,
but that method will call itself recursively,
and so, we'll call the method to partition the left side,
and then, it will call methods to partition
itself into left and right,
and this one will call
a method to partition itself into left and right,
and so, once we start down this path,
we go down the recursive rabbit hole,
and so, by the time the method called
to partition the left returns,
we'll have done all this work,
and the same goes for the right side.
So let's move on to the merging step now,
and you'll see that when we do the merging step,
we merge backwards, so we merge bottom up,
and we're gonna merge sibling arrays,
so we'll start by merging 35 with minus 15
and then seven with 55 an then one with minus 22,
and only after we've merged 35 and minus 15
back into a two-element sorted array
will we then merge 20 with the result, et cetera.
So we're gonna merge all these one-element arrays.
We always merge sibling left and right,
and each merged array will be sorted,
and as I said, 20 doesn't have a sibling,
so it's not gonna get merged on the first round.
So the way that the merging works
is we merge sibling left and right arrays,
and what we do is we create a temporary array
large enough to hold all the elements
in the arrays we're merging.
So on the first round,
our temporary arrays will be of length two
because we're going to be merging two one-element arrays,
and what we do is we set i
to the first index of the left array,
and j to the first index of the right array,
and when I say left and right array,
I mean the two arrays we're merging,
and then, we compare the value at the i position in left
to the value at the j position in the right array,
and if the value in the left array is smaller,
we copy that to the temporary array,
and we increment i by one.
If the value on the right array is smaller,
then we copy that to the temporary array
and increment j by one.
So essentially, what we're doing
is we're stepping through the left and right arrays,
and we're taking the smallest value
between the left and the right
and copying it into the temporary array,
and if we keep doing that,
that temporary array will contain the values
in sorted order.
So we're gonna repeat that until all the elements
in both arrays have been processed,
and, as I said, at that point,
the temporary array will contain the merged values
in sorted order,
and then, we have one final step to do.
Remember, we've been copying these values
into a temporary array,
so we then have to copy the sorted values
back into the original input array,
the one that we're sorting, at the correct positions,
and so, if the left array is at positions x to y
in the original array,
and the right array is at positions y plus one to z,
then after the copy, positions x to z
will be sorted in the original array.
So we're gonna overwrite what's there in the original array
with the sorted values.
So we're gonna start by merging the two siblings
on the left, 35 and minus 15.
So what we'll do is we'll create
a temporary two-element array.
i will be initialised to one
because that's the first index in the left array,
and j will be initialised to two
because that's the first index in the right array,
and then we compare array i to array j.
Minus 15 is smaller than 35.
There's a typo there, that should be 35,
and so, we copy minus 15 to the temporary array.
Then, we're gonna copy 35 to the temporary array,
and at this point, the temporary array
will be minus 15 and 35,
and we've now seen all of the elements
in the left array and right array that we're merging.
So at this point, we wanna copy the temporary array
back into positions one and two in the original array,
and so, at this point, minus 15 and 35 are sorted.
Now, they're not in sorted position in the array,
but the merged array is sorted,
and the two sibling arrays have now been merged.
So now, we're back to two arrays on the left-hand side.
We're back to 20, and we're back to minus 15 and 35.
So at this point, the left array contains 20,
and the right array contains minus 15 and 35.
So now we're gonna merge those two arrays
because 20 and minus 15 and 35
are sibling arrays now.
We originally got those two arrays
when we split the left array.
So we create a temporary array of length three.
i will be initialised to zero,
and j will be initialised to one,
and then, we compare array zero to array one.
Minus 15 is less than 20,
so it's gonna be copied to the temporary array,
and because we copied the value from the right array
into the temporary array, we increment j by one
because we've processed minus 15.
i is still zero because we haven't processed 20 yet.
So now we compare 20 to 35.
20 is smaller than 35, so it gets copied next,
and now, only 35 remains, and so, it's copied last,
and so, the temporary array consists of minus 15, 20 and 35,
and now, we copy that back into positions zero to two
in the original array,
and so, at this point, we have completed
merging the left sub-array,
and, as you can see, it's in sorted order.
So now, we're gonna repeat this process with the right
part of the array.
We have two sets of siblings,
seven and 55 and one and minus 22,
so we're gonna start by merging seven and 55.
So we're gonna create a temporary array of length two.
i will be initialised to three,
and j will be initialised to four.
We're gonna compare array i to array j.
Seven is smaller than 55,
so it gets copied into the temporary array first,
and then, 55 will get copied,
and then we copy the temp array
back to positions three and four,
and so, we've now merged the left array
of the right part of the original array,
and seven and 55 are in sorted order.
Now we repeat this process to merge one and minus 22.
The temporary array is gonna end up being minus 22 and one.
We're gonna copy that back into positions five and six,
and we're back to minus 22,
and the merged array is in sorted order.
It's minus 22 and one.
So now we have two arrays of length two,
and we need to merge those.
So we're gonna create a temporary array of length four.
i will be initialised to three and j to five.
Minus 22 is less than seven,
so we're gonna copy minus 22 to the temporary array,
and j will be incremented to six.
So then, we're gonna compare seven to one.
One is less than seven,
so one is gonna be copied to the temporary array,
and j will be incremented to seven.
Now, only elements in the left array are left,
and we know that they're sorted
because all the merged arrays are sorted,
and so, all we have to do at this point
is just copy the two elements from the left array
into the temporary array, and when we've done that,
the temporary array will be minus 22, one, seven, and 55,
and we just have to copy that
back into positions three to six,
and so, now we're back down to just two arrays,
a left array and a right array
that are both in sorted order,
and our final step is to merge these left and right arrays,
and so, we're gonna create a temporary array
that has enough room to hold seven elements.
We're gonna initialise i to zero and j to three.
Minus 22 is less than minus 15,
so we're gonna copy minus 22 to the temporary array,
and we're gonna increment j to four.
Minus 15 is less than one,
so we're gonna copy minus 15 to the temporary array,
and i is gonna get incremented to one.
One is less than 20, so we copy one to the temporary array,
and we increment j to five.
Seven is less than 20,
so we copy seven to the temporary array,
and we increment j to six.
20 is less than 55, so we copy 20 to the temporary array,
and we increment i to two,
and finally, 35 is less than 55,
so we copy 35 to the temporary array,
and we increment i to three,
and at this point, only 55 is left,
so we copy it to the temporary array,
and now we copy the temporary array
back into positions zero to six
because we've looked at all the elements,
and when we do that, the array is sorted.
It is quite a bit of work,
but because we're dividing and conquering,
we're splitting the array into two at each phase,
it actually performs better
than the algorithms we've seen so far.
So just to remind you of what we had
when we started the merging phase,
we had done all of the splitting,
and then, in the merging phase,
we went from the bottom back up.
So we merged 35 and minus 15
into a two-element sorted array of minus 15 and 35,
and we did the same thing with these two elements,
and the same thing with one and minus 22,
and then, at that point, these guys are now sibling arrays,
and so, we merged the left array with the right array,
and we got a sorted three-element array,
minus 15, 20, and 35,
and on this side, we had two two-element sibling array,
left and right.
We merged them into a sorted array,
and then, finally, we merged the original
left and right arrays we got from splitting the whole array
except this time, they're sorted
because we've undergone the merge step,
and so, we merged the sorted left array
with the sorted right array,
and our result from the merge is always a sorted array,
and so, we got our original array sorted.
So let's take a look at how this algorithm performs.
Well, first of all, as I said previously,
it's not an in-place algorithm.
The splitting phase is in-place,
but when we do the merging phase,
we use a temporary array to merge
each pair of sibling arrays.
Now this has a time complexity of O to the n log n,
and the log is to the base two, and why is that?
Well, we're repeatedly dividing the array in half
during the splitting phase,
and so, this is a logarithmic algorithm.
It's a stable sort algorithm
because when we do the merging,
we check whether the element in the right array
is greater than the element in the left array,
and if it isn't, if it's equal to it,
then the element in the left array will be the one
that's copied into the temporary array first,
and because of that,
the relative ordering of duplicate items will be preserved.
Now as I mentioned on the last slide,
the implementation I'm going to show you
has a couple of optimizations,
and I'll explain those
when we go through the implementation,
but it's still merge sort,
and it's still a logarithmic algorithm.
Now these days, memory is cheap and plentiful,
so the fact that it's not an in-place algorithm
shouldn't dissuade you from using it,
but if memory is an issue, then that's a consideration
because there's a lot of temporary array instances created,
and of course, the amount of memory you're going to need
is going to grow
as the number of items you're sorting grows.
As you'll see, the next sort algorithm we look at
also uses a divide and conquer philosophy
and is also a logarithmic algorithm,
but it's an in-place algorithm.
So we'll see that coming up in a couple of videos.
All right, so that's how merge sort works.
Let's implement it.
I'll see you in the next video.