The algorithms we've looked at so far
don't make any assumptions about the data they're sorting.
We can sort integers, floats, strings, objects anything.
The algorithms don't assume a certain data type.
Specific implementations do
but not the algorithms themselves.
They also don't assume that the data being sorted
is bound in any way.
For example, they don't assume that all the values
being sorted will be less than 100.
There are algorithms that do make assumptions
about the data being sorted
and because they make assumptions
they can sort the data more efficiently.
In fact they can achieve linear time, O to the N complexity
and so the next couple of algorithms we're going to look at
make assumptions about the data they're sorting
and the first algorithm is called counting sort.
So counting sort makes assumptions
about the data that it's sorting,
it assumes that all the values are discrete
and they're within a specific range.
So this algorithm only works
with non-negative discrete values.
We can't sort floating point numbers, we can't sort strings
because they don't have discrete values.
So practically speaking, you'll usually use
this algorithm with whole numbers.
So the way it works is it doesn't use comparisons,
so it doesn't actually compare values
in the array against each other
instead it counts the number of occurrences of each value
and you'll see how it does this
when we go through the algorithm
for a specific array in just a minute.
Now as I said, values must be within a specific range
and the range has to be reasonable.
It can't be huge.
You're not going to use counting sort
to sort values that are between
one and a million, for example.
Now our array, the usual array that we've been using,
is not a good candidate for counting sort.
It has negative numbers, so we're going to use a different
array to go through this algorithm by hand
and so this is the array we're going to use.
We're going to assume that we're sorting values
that are between one and 10 inclusive,
so the values can be one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight, nine or 10.
We have 10 possible values and so what we do
is we create a counting array of length 10.
So this is going to be a separate array
from the one that we're sorting
and then we traverse the input array,
the one we're sorting, from left to right
and using the counting array we track how many
of each value are in the input array
and then once we've traversed the entire input array,
using the counts in the counting array,
we write the values in sorted order back to the input array.
And so we're going to sort the array
that you see on the screen
and so when i = 0, we're going to look
at the value at position zero and we see it's two
and so we add one to the counting array at position one
because we know the values are between one and 10,
in the counting array position zero
is going to hold the number of one's we find.
Position one will hold the number of two's we find.
Position two will hold the number of three's we find etc
and so in the first position we found a two
so we increment counting array index one,
we increment it by one.
Then we're going to increment i to one
and at the input array position one we have a five
so we're going to increment counting array four
because that's where we're counting the number of fives.
We increment i to two, we have a nine,
so we're going to increment counting array
position eight by one because we found one nine.
When i is three we have an eight,
so we're going to increment counting array seven by one.
At position four we found another two
and so we're going to increment counting array one by one,
so now we have two there because
so far we've seen two two's in our array.
Next we find another eight, so counting array seven
will be incremented by one so we now have a two there
because we've seen two eight's.
Then we find a seven so we're going to
increment counting array six.
We found a 10 so we're going to
increment counting array nine.
We found a four, so we going to
increment counting array three
and finally we find a three
and so we're going to increment counting array two by one.
And so at this point we've traversed our entire input array
and we have counted how many occurrences
of each value we've seen
and so what we want to do now is using the counting array,
we're going to write back the values to the original array.
So in this slide the counting array is at the top
and the input array is at the bottom,
after we've written it back.
So the way this would work is,
we'd traverse the counting array
and we would say okay so there is zero one's
and so we don't have to do anything.
We just move to the next position in the counting array.
Okay there's two two's
and so at this point we're gonna write
two two's into the input array
and then there's one three
so we'll write one three to the input array.
There's one four so we'll write one four to the input array.
There's one five so we'll write one five to the input array.
There are zero sixes, so we don't do anything.
There is one seven, so we write
one seven to the input array.
There are two eights, so we're gonna write
two eight's to the input array.
There's one nine, so we write one nine to the input array
and finally there's one 10
and so we write one 10 to the input array.
So essentially counting sort has two phases.
The first phase is we traverse the input array
and we count how many of each value we have
and then in the second phase using the counting array,
we write values back into the input array
and so as you can see our input array is now sorted
and we didn't do any comparisons.
We didn't compare any of the elements against each other.
We're just merely counting, how many of each value we have
and that's why the algorithm is called counting sort.
Now this is not an in-place algorithm.
As we've seen we have to create a counting array
and the length of the counting array
will depend on the range of values we have,
and because of this counting sort is best used,
when the range of values you have
is around the same length of the input array.
So if you have an input array of 20,
ideally the number of values that there are,
you want to be that to be around 20
because think about if you have an array of 10 elements
and the range of values can go from one to 10,000,
then your going to have to create a counting array
of length 10,000 to sort 10 elements
which would obviously be ridiculous.
So counting sort works best when
the range of values that you can have,
the number of values in that range
is roughly equivalent to the number of values
that you want to sort.
So in our case we had a range of 10 values
and we had an array of 10 so it was perfect.
As I mentioned this algorithm can achieve linear time
and it can do that because it's making
assumptions about the data
and so because it can make these assumptions,
it can achieve linear time.
Now the counting sort I showed you is unstable.
If we want it to be stable there are extra steps
we can take with counting sort
instead of just incrementing a counter for example
you would perhaps use what's called linked list
in the counting array, we're gonna cover linked list later.
Okay that's it for learning what
the counting sort algorithm is.
Let's go ahead and implement it.
I'll see you in the next video.