Alright, so let's take a look at queues,
like I said in the intro queues are an abstract data type.
Just like stacks they dictate how we can access the data,
and just like stacks we use other
data structures to implement them.
Now unlike stacks queues enforce a FIFO behaviour.
FIFO is first in, first out, remember that stacks were LIFO.
Last in, first out.
So queues are called queues because they're like line-ups,
and line-ups are called queues in some parts of the world.
So if you're at a store, and you get in a line the people
in front of you will be served before you are.
So you'll join the queue at the end,
and then the people in line are going to be serviced
in the order that they joined the queue.
So the first person in line is gonna be served,
and then the second person in line,
and then the third person in line, et cetera.
That's the theory anyway, in real life people can butt in,
but when we're dealing with the data structure queues
nobody gets to butt in.
So items are removed from the queue in the same order
that they're added to the queue.
So if we add item one, item two, and item three,
then we have to remove item one first,
and then item two, and then item three.
So it's first in first out.
With stacks it was the last item that was removed first,
so if we added item one, item two, item three,
it would be item three that was removed first,
but with queues you're removed in the order you were added.
Now, just like with stacks there are three main operations
that we can perform on queues.
We can add an item to the end of the queue,
and that's also called onqueue or enqueue.
We can remove the first item in the queue
and that's also called dequeue,
and just like stacks we can peek at the queue,
and that gets the item at the front of the queue
without removing it from the queue.
Now just like with stacks there are two popular ways
of implementing queues.
Arrays and link lists.
Alright, so here's a queue and ten is at the front,
and 22 is at the back.
So these items were added to the queue in the order
ten, 15, four, and 22
and then if we add 20,
we're gonna add 20 to the back of the queue.
So here's our queue before we add 20,
and when we add an item the front of the queue
doesn't change, but the back
will be now pointing to the new item.
If we remove an item, we're gonna remove the item
from the front.
So we're gonna remove ten, and the front now points to 15.
Now depending on the implementation,
you might clean up the ten,
but this is essentially how this works.
So if you add an item the back pointer will change,
and if you remove an item the front pointer will change,
and of course if we were now to peek
the peek value would be 15 but nothing in the queue changes,
so when we peek we get the item at the front of the queue,
but we don't remove it from the queue.
So nothing changes, the front pointer will not change.
Now I didn't add a slide for time complexity,
but if you're wondering about that
it will a similar situation we had with stacks.
It's gonna depend on what your backing the queue with.
If you're backing the queue with an array,
then whether an operation is gonna be constant time
or linear time it's going to depend
on whether you have to resize the array.
If you're backing it with a link list,
these three queue operations will always be constant time.
Okay, so now that we know what a queue is
and what operations we can do on it,
let's go ahead and implement a simple queue.
I'll see you in the next video.