(lively music)
(keyboard clacking)
So, I've started off the solution a little bit.
This is what was available in the project
in the Resources section for the last video
and then I've copied over the radixSort
and the radixSingleSort methods
from the implementation we worked on
when we covered radixSort.
I did not copy over the getDigit method
because we're sorting strings,
so we're not gonna need it.
So, let's think about the method
that we're gonna have to replace the getDigit method with.
What do we actually want to do?
Well, we're gonna want to get the letter
in the position that we're looking at.
So, when we sort these strings,
we're gonna wanna start at the right
just like we did with the integer values
because the least significant position
is at the right
and so, just like with decimal numbers,
we wanna go from right to left,
so when we're sorting based on the last position
in a string, we're gonna want f,
c, e, d and b,
so we need a method that's going to accept a position
and figure out the letter that we're looking at
and this is actually easier to do
than it was for decimal numbers.
So, let's add that first.
And I'm gonna call it getIndex
because what we're basically looking for
is we want the index into the counting array,
that's what we want the method to return,
so I'm gonna say public static int getIndex
and this is going to accept the position
that we're looking at and the string.
So, if we want to get f, c, e et cetera,
we're gonna pass for as the index
'cause this time we want the zero-based index
and we would pass the string value
and inside here, all we have to do
is call the charAt method.
So, we can return value.charAt position,
so this would give us, for example, f
but that's not what we want
because we want to return where f is being counted
in the counting array.
Now, a will be at position zero in the counting array,
b will be at position one,
c will be at position two,
d will be at position three et cetera.
So, a is at position zero,
so if we wanna figure out where f is,
we'll get f and then we're gonna subtract a.
And that will give us the position in the counting array.
Remember, characters are actually numeric values
under the covers,
so if a has a numeric value of I think it's 65
in ASCII but I'm not absolutely sure about that
but if it's 65, in ASCII the letters a to z,
lowercase all have contiguous values,
so a is let's value 65, b is 66,
c is 67, d is 68 et cetera.
So, if we want to get the position in the count array,
we need to translate these letters into the indices zero
to 25 and so, a would be 65
minus 65 is zero, so it's at position zero
in the counting array,
b would be 66 minus 65 which is one,
so it's at position one in the counting array,
c would be 67 minus 65
which would be position two in the counting array et cetera.
And so, what we're doing with this
is we're translating the numeric value for the character
into an index in the counting array
and because the letters a to z
in the ASCII system have value 65, 66, 67,
and we keep increasing by one,
all the way to z, we can translate a character
to its position in the counting array
just by subtracting a from the value for that character.
And so, that's what we're doing here
and so, this is gonna return us the index
in the counting array.
A brief timeout here.
After I finished recording this video,
I looked up lowercase a in the ASCII table
and it turns out that lowercase a
has a value of 97.
It's uppercase A that has a value of 65,
so I suppose I was half right
but the discussion still stands
because the lowercase a is at 97,
the lowercase b is at 98,
the lowercase c is at 99 et cetera,
all the way up to z.
We can translate the numeric value for a lowercase character
to its index in the counting array
by subtracting out the character a
but I thought I'd record this brief timeout
in case anybody noticed
that I was actually using the ASCII code
for an uppercase A when I was discussing
how we were doing the translation, so that's it,
now we'll return to our regularly scheduled video.
And so, because of that, we can come in here
and we can change the getDigit to getIndex
and we want to pass the position
and the value and that's all we need.
We don't need the radix
and we'll fix this error later.
Right now we were thinking that the value was an integer.
So, that's all we need here for this getIndex.
And the same for this one.
So, we'll change this to getIndex
and we can just remove once again the radix
and we'll fix the other errors later.
So, now that we have our getIndex
and that was probably the most difficult part
of modifying the radixSort
so that we can sort strings,
let's fix the rest of the code.
So, first, let's call our radixSort,
so when we do that,
we're gonna be passing a string array,
so we'll modify that, so we'll say string.
We're still gonna wanna take the radix and the width.
Now, in here we actually want to modify the loop
because the position we pass,
we wanna start at the rightmost position.
It was okay for us to start i at zero
and increment when we were dealing with decimal numbers
because the getDigit method was coded
in such a way that when i was zero,
we were actually raising 10 to the power of zero
and so, we were getting the,
and the calculation we were doing
was giving us the rightmost digit.
But now that we're just using value.charAt position,
we actually want to count i down from the length
of the string down to zero
and so, we wanna count i, we're gonna start i
at width minus one,
we're gonna keep going as long as i is greater than
or equal to zero
and we're gonna decrement I.
And so, this time you really do want i
because of the way the getIndex method is coded,
we really want i to start at four
and then go down to zero,
so that's all we have to change here
for the radixSingleSort.
We're now gonna be accepting a string array,
so we'll change that to string
and because of that, we have some fixes we need to do here
where we're gonna have a string value.
And down here, our temp, we're gonna have a string value
for the loop and then down here our temp array
is actually going to be a string array.
And that's it.
That's all we have to change,
so as I said, probably the most difficult part
was figuring this out.
So, let's run
and
we're not gonna see anything sorted
because we need to actually call radixSort,
so let's do that.
So, radixSort.
We're gonna pass our strings array.
This time we have a radix of 26
'cause there were 26 letters in the alphabet
and our width is five
because each of our strings has five letters in it.
So, now let's run
and we have sorted our strings, abcde
bbbbb, bcdef, dbaqc and omadd.
And so, as I said,
probably the most challenging part of this
was figuring out how to get that index
and maybe you didn't find it too challenging.
And then of course we needed to modify this loop
because we now want to start i
at the rightmost position
because of the way we coded this method.
And the rest was basically just a matter
of fixing up the call to getDigit,
changing it to a call to getIndex
and fixing up areas where we used int
when we actually needed a string now.
So, as you can see from these challenges,
once you know an implementation of a sort algorithm,
it's not really all that difficult
to modify it to sort different types of data,
or to sort in descending order
rather than ascending order.
So, the most important thing
is that you understand the steps
that an algorithm takes to sort a set of values
because once you know these stops involved
with the sort algorithm,
you can then code the implementation that you need
to do what you wanna accomplish.
So, that's it for sort algorithms for now.
In the next section, we're gonna start looking at lists.
I'll see ya there.