(lively music)
(keyboard clacking)
So, let's implement a simple singly linked class.
I've created a project,
I'm putting the code into package
academy.learnprogramming.linkedlists.
I've created our four employees that we used
in the array list video.
This time I've assigned them to employee variables
and I've also added the employee class
and all I did was copied and pasted the class
over from the array list project,
so it's a straightforward class.
We have three fields
and we just have the usual boilerplate code.
We have our equals method
and we have our override toString.
So, the first class we'll work on
is the node class and this class
is going to need two variables,
one for the employee instance
and one for the next node in the list
because remember, when we're working with a linked list,
every node knows about the next node in the list
and so, we need a field that contains a reference
to the next node in the list
and that's why the data structure is called a linked list
if you hadn't already figured that out.
In Java, by contains a link,
we mean that it stores the object reference
of the next node.
So, let's add a node class,
so I'll say New, Java Class.
And I'm going to call this EmployeeNode
rather than just plain old Node
because I'm not going to use generics
to write this linked list,
I want us to just focus
on the linked list implementation
and on top of that you're not going to write
your own linked list, you'll end up using the one
in the JDK and even if you did write a linked link class
for your application,
you'd probably make it specific
to the type of data you're dealing with.
The only reason that you would need to use generics
is if you're going to write a class
that's going to be released publicly
and so that many, many applications
are going to use it
and in that case, you'd wanna use generics
'cause you'd want it to be usable
with a variety of object types.
But for our purposes, we're just gonna focus
on the implementation of the linked list
and so, I'm not gonna use generics
and so, I'm calling this EmployeeNode
to make it clear that this node
will only work with employee instances.
So, as I said, we're gonna need two fields,
we're gonna need one for the employee
and we're going to need a field
that stores a reference to the next node in the list.
So, we'll call that next.
So, for the constructor, we just need the employee,
so I'll say public EmployeeNode
and we just need the employee for that.
And so, we'll just say this.employee equals employee.
And to make things quick and easy,
I'll have the IDE just create me a bunch
of sets and gets, so I'll say Generate,
Getter and Setter, I want it for both fields,
click OK and there we go.
We have our sets and gets.
So, the constructor only takes employee
because when we construct an instance,
we don't know yet what the next node will be.
We'll add that later, you'll see when we implement
the insert method, we create the node first
and then we figure out which node
is supposed to be assigned to it next field.
Now, as we saw in the slides,
if a node is the last node in the list,
meaning that there isn't any node following it,
then its next field will be set to null
and so, when we traverse the list,
that's how we'll know we've reached the end.
We don't have to set next to null
in the constructor because that's the default value
for object fields.
So, we have a class for the node,
what about the linked list itself?
Well, as we saw from the slides,
all we need to know for the linked list
is the head node, that's it.
From there we can traverse the entire list
because every node in the list contains a link
to the next node
and so, let's create a class for a linked list.
And I'm gonna call this EmployeeLinkedList once again
to make it clear that this only works with employee nodes.
And this just needs one field.
It needs a field for the head node,
so private EmployeeNode
head, that's it.
So, let's say we wanna add an item to the linked list.
For the best performance, we should add items
to the beginning, so we don't have to traverse the list
looking for an insertion point
and so, we're going to code an addToFront method.
So, we'll say public void addToFront
and we need the employee instance that we wanna add,
so we'll say EmployeeNode node equals new EmployeeNode
and we just have to pass the employee
and then we need to set this new node's next field.
Its new node's next field is going to point
at whatever head it's currently pointing at
because when we add a new node to the front of the list,
the current head of the list
is now going to become the second node in the list
and so, this new node
is going to point to the current head
as we saw in the slides.
So, we'll say node.setNext head.
And then of course the last thing we wanna do
is set head to the new node.
So, if you're having trouble understanding this,
go back to the slides
but essentially, we're inserting the node right
at the front of the list,
so let's say our list contains employee Jane
and we're inserting John.
When we come in, the head field
will be pointing to Jane.
When we've finished inserting John,
we want John to be pointing to Jane
and the head field to be pointing to John.
So, first we create the new node
and then we set John which is the new node,
John's next field to Jane
because that's currently the one
being pointed to by head
and then we set head to John
and so, we end up with a head field
that points to John and John's next field points
to Jane, I'll just delete this blank line here
and now let's go back to our main method
and let's create a linked list
and add some employees to it.
So, we'll say EmployeeLinkedList
and I'll just call it list equals new EmployeeLinkedList
and then we'll say list.addToFront
and we'll add janeJones,
list.addToFront johnDoe,
list.addTofront marySmith
and list.addToFront mikeWilson.
And we're gonna need a way to print our list,
so let's go back to our LinkedList class
and add a printList method.
So, we'll say public void printList
and we'll say EmployeeNode current
equals the head of the list
'cause we're gonna start at the head
and I'm gonna print out something here
that says HEAD
and then we wanna keep traversing the list
until current hits null,
so while current is not equal to null
because when it hits null, we've hit the end of the list,
we'll say System.out.print current
and I'm gonna change this to print as well
because I don't want that to be printed on its own line.
And then I'll print an arrow
and then we want to move to the next node,
so current equals current.getNext.
This isn't perfect, we're gonna end up with an arrow after
but I can say System.out.print line null
and so, the last item in the list will be null.
This will work fine
but what we'll see right now if we were to call this
is a bunch of object references
because we've overridden employee,
we've overridden the toString method and employee
but we haven't overridden it in our node class.
So, let's do that now.
And what I actually wanna print out
is the employee information when we print a node,
so I'll just call the employees toString method,
so I'll say public String toString
and I want to return employee.toString
and so, when we print a node,
what will actually be printing
is the result of this toString method.
So, let's call our printList method now and let's run.
So, we have the head of our list
and then you'll see that Mike Wilson comes first.
We added Jane first
but we're constantly adding new employees
to the front of the list,
so every time we add a new employee,
the existing employees gets bumped down the list.
So, we added Mike last, so he's gonna be the head
of the list 'cause we're always adding to the front,
followed by Mary Smith
followed by John Doe
and followed by Jane Jones and she'll be pointing to null
because she's the last node in the list
and so, that's all there is to inserting a node
into the linked list at the front of the list.
We could write a method
that adds employees to the end of the list
or that looks very specific employee in the list
and adds an employee after that employee
or before the employee
but those methods will be on the order of O of n,
they'll be linear because then we have to traverse the list
and the worst case will always be
that we have to traverse the entire list.
That would be true if we wanted to add a node
to the end.
Now, some implementations of linked list
will have a pointer to the tail of the list,
the last node in the list
but that's not really a true singly linked list,
it's a variation on them
but you could do that
if you thought you were constantly gonna be wanting
to add items to the end of the list,
you could keep a reference to the last node in the list
which is called the tail
but for a linked list implementation
that's only keeping reference to the head,
if you wanted to insert items at the end,
you'd have to traverse the entire list
and in either way whether you kept a reference
to the tail or not,
if you wanted to insert items
at a specific point in the list,
like before or after a specific employee,
you gonna have to traverse the list looking
for that employee and so, a singly linked list
is best used when you want to insert and remove items
from the front of the list.
Now, the other things to note is is that a linked list
can continue to grow
without having to be resized.
Remember, with arrays, once the array is full,
if we wanna add more items to it,
we have to resize the array
but that's not true of a linked list.
With a linked list, you're pretty much only bounded
by the memory you have.
Now, talking about memory,
one disadvantage to a linked list
is you have to store that extra field with every value.
You don't have to do that with arrays,
so is memory's really tight,
that could be one disadvantage to using a linked list
even if you will only wanna be adding
and deleting items from the front
if memory is tight and you're gonna have a lot of items,
maybe a linked list wouldn't be your best choice.
So, as usual, it's going to depend on your application,
the platform you're running on,
what the application's gonna wanna do
with the data, et cetera.
There isn't a one-size-fits-all answer.
So, let's say that we wanted to know how many items
are in the linked list.
We could traverse the list
and count how many items there are
but another way to do it
would be to just keep a running count
of how many nodes are in the list
and we're gonna do it that way.
So, let's go back to our LinkedList class
and we're gonna add a size field,
so we'll say private int size
and that will be initialised to zero by default
when the list is created
and then whenever we add an employee of course,
we want to increment the size
and it would be nice for us to have a get,
I'll just type this out 'cause it's quick,
so public int getSize and we just return the size.
Let's go back to our main method
and call our getSize method
after we've added these employees,
so we'll say System.out.print line list.getSize
and we should get four.
Let's run.
And sure enough we get four employees in our list.
So, we could now add an isEmpty method
that tells us whether the linked list is empty.
We could just call the getSize method
and test whether the number of items
in the list is zero but there's another way
to test whether a list is empty.
Can you think about what that way is
if we looked at the linked list implementation for a minute?
Can you come up with another way,
a quick way of testing whether a linked list is empty?
If head is null, that means the list is empty, right?
'Cause head is null.
It's not pointing to any nodes.
So, one way we could write an isEmpty method
is to say public boolean isEmpty
and we return head equals null
and so, if we go back to main now,
and we call this right at the top,
before we add anything and we say System.out.print line
list.isEmpty we should get true here.
Let's run.
And sure enough we get true.
Our list is empty before we've added anything to it.
So, the last method we'll look at
is how do we remove items from the front?
And we saw that in the slides.
Let's go to our LinkedList class
and let's write the method,
so we'll say public and we're gonna return the node
that we removed in case the caller wants
to do anything with it
and we'll same removeFromFront.
We don't need to pass anything
'cause we're always gonna remove the node
that's right at the front.
So, the first thing we do
is we need to test if the list is empty
because if the list is empty,
there's nothing to remove,
so we'll say if isEmpty,
we'll just return null.
We don't have anything to do.
If the list isn't empty,
what we're gonna do is store the first node
on the list, I'll call this removeNode,
that's what I called it in the slides,
is the head node, right?
So, the node that we're gonna remove
is pointed to by the head node,
that's the object reference that's stored in the head field.
So, we'll assign that to removeNode
and then we want to move the head.
The head will equal head.getNext.
So, if we have the situation where we're pointing
at Mike, head is pointing to Mike
and we want Mike to be removed,
we want the head field to point
to whatever Mike's next field is pointing to
because right now that's the second item in the list
and that's going to become the front of the list
when Mike is removed, so that's all we're doing here.
Of course we have to decrement the size
because now we'll have one less item
and finally we return the removedNode.
Now, if we wanted to be really diligent,
we could say removedNode.setNext null
and that would completely remove Mike
or whoever we're moving from the list
and that's gonna be an isolated node again
but we don't really have to do that
because the fact that the next field is still set
to a node in the list doesn't mean
that we can reach the node we're removing
because the head field now points
to the node after the node we're removing
but we could do that just to be really clean
and make sure that we're cleaning up all of the references.
So, let's go to the main method now
and we'll remove the item at the front of the list.
So, after we've added our four employees
and printed them, we'll say list.removeFromFront
and let's print the size again,
System.out.print line list.getSize
just to make sure we're decrementing the size correctly
and then we'll print our list again.
And so, let's run.
Here's our list after we've add four employees
and we'll see that Mike
is the first item on the list
and then after we've called removeFromFront,
our size goes down to three
and we'll see that Mary
is now the first employee on the list.
And if we go to the end, we'll see that our list
is one employee shorter.
So, once again, whether to use a linked list,
an array or a list will depend
on what your application wants to do.
If it wants to do a bunch of random accesses,
then a linked list would be a bad choice
'cause you're always gonna have to be traversing the list
to get to whatever you want to access
but if you want to load a bunch of data
into the list and you're always gonna be most interested
in whatever's at the front of the linked list,
then that could be a really good choice,
a linked list could be a good choice
for data structure depending
on what else your application
is going to wanna do with the data.
So, this is a simple implementation
of a singly linked list
just to give you an idea of what would be going on
under the covers in a linked list implementation.
In the next video, we'll take a look
at doubly linked lists.
I'll see you there.