Alright, so in this video, we're going to
add the code to delete a node.
Or at least, start adding the code,
because delete can be quite complex.
Now let's think about what will happen when we delete a node
Well, because we're dealing with a binary search tree,
meaning that nodes can have zero, one or two children,
there are three possibilities.
The first is that the node we want to delete is a leaf.
The second is that the node we want to delete has one child.
And the third is the node
that we want to delete has two children.
The first case will be really easy,
if a node doesn't have any children and we wanna delete it
we can just remove it from the tree.
We have no children to worry about.
In the second case, when there is one child
that's actually pretty easy as well.
If a node only has one child and we delete it,
the child basically replaces the node we're deleting.
The third case is complex, and so in this video
we'll take a look at the first two cases
and we'll handle the third case in another video.
So, here is the usual binary tree,
except I've added node 17 here,
when we go the IDE we'll do the same thing.
And so, node 17 is a leaf node.
So let's say we wanna delete node 17.
Well, all we have to do is knock node 17 off, right?
Because it's a leaf,
so we don't have to worry about any children.
So we basically just knock out node 15's right child.
And we're done. And this is the tree, we'd end up with.
So, here's the tree with node 17.
Here's the tree without node 17.
Essentially, the tree that we had before.
So, that's case one, it's really easy.
Just knock out parent's left child or right child.
Depending on which side is the leaf node,
that you are deleting. So I've put 17 back now
and instead of deleting 17, let's say we wanna delete 15.
And so, 15 has one child and it wouldn't matter
if the child was on the left or the right.
Well, in this case, when there's only one child
all we do is we replace the node we're deleting
with the child. And it's safe to do that because
we know that everything
in 20's left subtree
is smaller than 20. And so it's safe to say,
"Oh, we can just move this value up here,
"We know all the values in this subtree are less than 20".
So, after we've deleted 15,
this is what our tree would look like.
Instead of having 15 here, we have 17.
And the characteristics of a binary search tree
have been preserved. Now, let's pretend
we were deleting a node from over here.
Let's say we had the value 23,
and so we could...
You know, 23 is less than 25, it's greater than 20,
it's greater than 22. So let's say we have 23 here
and we wanna delete 22. We know everything over here
is greater than 20, and so it's safe for us
to just move 23 into this node.
And so, that's how we handle the first two cases,
deleting a leaf and deleting a node, that has only
one child, so let's go over to the IDE
and let's implement the first two cases.