(gentle music)
(keyboard strokes)
So, in the last video we handled the cases
of deleting a node with no children.
A leaf node or a node with one child.
And now we have to handle the most complex case.
Which is a node with two children.
And so how do we do that?
Because we can't just take the two children,
and stick it onto the parent of the deleted node,
because in a binary search tree
each node can only have two children.
And it's possible that the parent already has two children.
So what do we do?
Well whatever we do,
we don't wanna disrupt the existing tree structure too much.
Meaning we don't wanna have to shift around
a whole bunch of nodes.
What we're gonna do
is we're gonna look for the replacement node.
So when a node has two children,
we're gonna replace that node
with one of the nodes from it's subtrees.
And we're either gonna take a node from the left subtree
or a node from the right subtree.
And when you write your delete code,
stick with one or the other.
So your delete code is either
gonna look down the left subtree for the replacement node,
or it's gonna look down the right subtree
for the replacement node.
And so, how do we find the replacement node?
What value should we look for?
Well we have to make sure
that the characteristics
of a binary search tree are preserved.
And so if we take the value from the left subtree,
we have to take the largest value in the left subtree.
If we're going to replace the deleted node
with a node from it's subtree,
so right now the deleted node is the root of a subtree.
In a binary search tree everything to the left
has to be less than the deleted value.
And so if we're gonna look for a replacement value
in the left subtree,
if we take the largest value in the left subtree,
and we take that node,
and replace the deleted node with that node,
because we've taken the largest value from the left subtree,
we know that everything that remains in the left subtree
will still be smaller than the root of the subtree.
And so we'll know that
the characteristic of a binary search tree is preserved.
And so if we're gonna look to the left
we're gonna look for the maximum value in the left subtree,
that's the node that we're gonna use
to replace the root of the subtree,
and because we're taking the maximum value,
we know that everything in the left subtree
is still gonna be less.
Now if we were gonna do it from the right subtree,
we'd wanna look for the smallest value for the same reason.
After we've taken the node, the replacement node,
and put it at the root of the subtree,
everything in the right subtree still has to be greater
than the root of the subtree.
And the way that we guarantee that is
to take the smallest value in the right subtree,
because if it's the smallest value in the right subtree,
then we know that all the other nodes
are greater than that value,
and so it's safe for us to take that value,
and put it at the root.
And so if we're gonna take
the replacement value from the left,
we wanna look for the largest value in the left subtree,
and if we're gonna take
the replacement value from the right,
we look for the smallest value.
So let's look at a picture,
'cause hopefully this will make things clearer.
And so here is the tree that we have right now.
That we're building in our code.
Now let's say we come along and we wanna delete 20.
And so we wanna delete 20,
and so what we're gonna do is
we're gonna select a node from it's subtrees,
and put that node in place of 20.
And so let's say we're gonna look for
that replacement node in the left subtree.
And so we're gonna move down to the left subtree,
and then we wanna look for the largest value
in the left subtree.
And the way that you find the maximum value is
that you move along the right edges until you hit a node
that doesn't have a right child.
So in our case it won't take as long,
'cause we're gonna move down to 15,
and then we're gonna start travelling to the right,
and oh, we find 17.
And so what we're gonna do is,
we're gonna take node 17 and put it here.
And obviously we would null out 15's child.
And so after the deletion,
this is how our tree is going to look.
We have 17 here, and 15 is still less than 17,
and 22 is still greater.
And because of the characteristics of a binary search tree,
because we're taking the largest value in the left subtree,
we know that everything else in the left subtree is
gonna be smaller than that value.
And so when we stick it up here,
we know that everything in the left subtree
is gonna be smaller.
So the left subtree is preserved.
And because we know everything in the right subtree is
greater than this value and everything here is less.
We know that anything we take from here is
gonna be less than what is in the right subtree.
And so the right subtree characteristic will be preserved.
And so this is what the binary search tree looks like
after we've deleted node 20,
and 17 has been selected as the replacement value.
Now, there are different ways you can implement deletes
for no matter what situation you're in.
You can either physically move the node.
So, we could take this node and physically move it up here,
and then we've got a bunch of rewiring to do.
Or we can just take the value of 17,
and replace the value in the existing node.
So basically do a set data on the existing node
to set it to 17.
And then of course we have to clean up any references here.
Now, if 17 had had a child,
because we're looking for the largest value,
17 can't have a right child.
It can only have a left child.
If it had a right child it wouldn't be the greatest value,
so it wouldn't be selected.
And so, the node we find,
it'll either be a leaf or it will have only a left child.
And so, if 17 had a left child, that child would replace 17.
And so, 17 would become the node up here,
and it's left child would become 15's right child.
And so, when we're doing this,
if the replacement node has a child,
it just replaces the node in the tree.
So, the replacement node becomes
the new root of the subtree,
and if it has a child, it's replaced by it's child.
Let's try another one.
So, if we go down here our tree has now been reset.
And let's delete 27.
And so, in this case
we're gonna search down the right subtree.
You wouldn't do this in a delete method.
You'd always be doing the left or the right.
But I wanna show both ways.
So, in this situation we wanna delete 27,
and we're gonna look down the right.
And so, in this case we want the smallest value.
For the same reason that we wanted the largest value
when we look down the left subtree.
We want the smallest value,
because when we replace 27 with the value,
everything in the right subtree
still has to be greater than 27.
And the way to guarantee that
is to choose the smallest value.
Because if we take the smallest value
from the right subtree, then we can be guaranteed,
when we move the smallest value up here,
that anything that's left behind
is greater than the new root.
And so, the characteristics of a binary search tree
will be preserved.
And so, in this case,
we're gonna move to the root of the subtree,
we're gonna search for the replacement value,
and because we're looking for the minimum value
in the subtree, we're gonna move along the left edges.
Until we hit a node that doesn't have a left child.
And so, we're gonna find 29, 29 is the minimum value.
We're gonna move the node for 29 up here,
and obviously we'll null out 30's left child.
Now just like with the left subtree,
if 29 had a child it would have to be a right child.
It couldn't be a left child,
otherwise 29 wouldn't be the minimum.
So if 29 has a right child,
that child just replaces it in the tree.
So if 29 had a right child,
we'd take the node for 29 and put it up here,
and the right child would replace the node in the tree.
And if that node had a subtree it wouldn't matter.
I mean, the subtree would just come along for the ride.
And so, we're gonna replace node 27 with node 29.
And after that's done, this is what our tree will look like.
Let's do one more.
Let's look at what would happen if we deleted the root.
And so, we're gonna look down the right subtree,
and we wanna find the minimum value.
So this time, last time we deleted 27.
So we were just looking at this right subtree.
But now we're deleting the root,
so we're gonna look at it's right subtree.
And we're gonna move to the root of the right subtree,
and then start travelling down the left edges
until we hit a node that doesn't have a left child.
That will be the minimum.
And we're gonna find 26.
And so, what we're gonna do is
replace the root node with this node.
And of course we'll null out 27's child.
And so, after we've done that.
After we've moved node 26 up here,
and nulled out 27's child,
this is the situation that we'll have.
Okay, so now that we know how we're gonna handle
the case of deleting a node with two children,
let's move on and handle that case in our delete method.
I'll see you in the next video.