(futuristic electronic music)
(keyboard keys clack)
All right, so this is a data structures
and algorithms for Java course,
and if you wanna use a linked list in Java,
you're probably going to use
the LinkedList class in the JDK.
So here we are at the Java doc for the LinkedList class,
and the first thing we'll notice
is it says this is a doubly linked list implementation,
and so, if you use this class,
you're actually getting a doubly linked list,
not a singly linked list.
We'll also notice that it implements the List interface
and the Deque interface.
We're gonna look at queues later.
Now because it implements the List interface,
all the methods in the List interface
are in the LinkedList class, so,
we have methods like add,
indexOf,
size, toArray,
remove.
Now, this class uses generics,
so you can use this LinkedList class
with any type of object,
including our Employee object.
Now what about the Node class?
Well, the LinkedList class has its own implementation
of the Node class,
so we don't have to write a Node class ourselves.
Now it's important to note
that this class is not synchronised.
This implementation is not synchronised,
so if you wanna use a LinkedList instance
from multiple threads,
you'll have to synchronise the calls
to any of the LinkedList methods.
You'll have to do that yourself.
All right, let's go over to the IDE.
So I've created a new project.
I've put the code into package
academy.learnprogramming.jdklinkedlists,
and I've created the usual Employee instances.
To do that, I've obviously copied over the Employee class
that we've been using,
and it's the exact same class.
I just copied and pasted the code over from
one of the other projects.
So let's create a linked list for our Employee
so we'll say LinkedList,
Employee,
list equals
new LinkedList,
and it's gonna ask me to raise my language level
'cause the default language level is 1.6,
and I believe this needs 1.7.
So I want that light bulb to come up,
not that one, the red one.
There it is, and I'll just say Set language level to seven.
Okay, so let's do what we did before.
We'll add a bunch of employees to the front of the list,
so I'll say list.addFirst.
So this is the method you call
if you want to add an item to the front of the LinkedList,
and we'll add janeJones.
list.addFirst
johnDoe.
marySmith,
and list.addFirst
mikeWilson.
The LinkedList class doesn't have a handy printList method,
but it does have an iterator,
so that's how we're going to print what's in the list.
So we'll say Iterator,
and I'll call it iter, equals,
and you'll notice there's multiple choices here for Iterator
so I'm gonna press Alt + Enter,
and I want the java.util iterator,
equals list.iterator,
and then, while iter.hasNext.
We'll just print out
iter.next.
We could also use a for loop to print out the list.
I'll put that as a comment, so we could say for
Employee employee
in the list,
System.out.println employee,
so we could do that,
and I'll put this in a comment just so that you can see.
So both of these will print the list.
Now obviously, it's not gonna have
the nice arrow that we had.
We're gonna be printing each employee on a single line.
Well I suppose I could add that in myself, so,
I'll say System.out.print,
HEAD.
Pretty much do the same thing we did before,
and then, I'll change that to print,
and then, I'll say System.out.print,
and we'll do the double arrow
'cause this is a doubly linked list,
and then, at the very end, we'll print null.
So now, we're doing the same thing
that we did in our printList
except we're an iterator to print out the items.
So let's run,
and we'll see that we have the same thing we had before.
We've got our head and then we've got Mike Wilson,
Mary Smith, John Doe, and Jane Jones.
So let's say we wanna add Bill End to the end of the list.
So right now, we've got addFirst,
and so, let me create a Bill End employee.
I'll add him up here, so Employee
billEnd equals new Employee Bill,
End,
and I think his ID
that we gave him in the last video was 78.
Now we can't use addFirst
because addFirst adds to the front of the list,
and so, instead, we use the add method.
So for LinkedList, the add methods adds
an item to the end of the list.
It adds it at the tail,
and so, we wanna add billEnd at the tail,
and then, copy this code.
I suppose I could put this in a method,
but we'll just go with this for now.
Don't need to declare the iterator again, and let's run,
and so, Mike's still at the front of the list.
Everybody's in the same position
except at the end, we have Bill End.
So this is important to remember
when you're working with the JDK LinkedList class.
The add method, the implementation of the add method
from the List interface,
adds the item to the end of the linked list.
If you want an item added to the front,
you have to use the addFirst method.
So it's important to read the description
of the method you wanna use
to make sure it's adding the item where you want it added.
Now, we could also use addLast.
So if I change this addLast and run,
we'll get the same thing.
So we'll see that Bill's been added to the end.
So you can use add, or if you wanna be really clear
that you're adding the item to the end of the list,
you can use addLast.
Okay, and I'll close this down again,
and let's go look at the code for LinkedList.
So I'm gonna right-click and say go to the Declaration,
and we'll see that it is using a Node class,
first and last.
So first is basically the head and last is the tail.
It's got a size and so this looks familiar, doesn't it?
Now what's the underlying data structure
being used for the LinkedList?
Remember when we looked at ArrayList and Vector,
we discovered that it was an array.
Well, we'll see that the class
extends AbstractSequentialList,
and if we take a look at that,
we'll see that this kind of provides
a skeletal implementation of the List interface
to reduce the amount of work required
for classes that wanna implement List.
So basically, if you wanna implement the List interface
and you don't wanna start from scratch
and have to implement every single method,
instead of just implementing List,
you can extend this class if you want a sequential list,
and you get a bunch of stuff for free,
and then, you can just override what you wanna override,
and that's all fine and dandy,
but how is a linked list being stored?
Well, you can see how it's being stored.
It's exactly similar to the way that we implemented our,
our simple, single, singly linked list
and doubly linked list.
The linked list itself is the data structure,
so it's not being backed by anything.
The linked list is just containing
references to a head and a tail,
and this Node class, let's have a look at it,
has the item which is,
in our case, would be the employee,
and then, it's got next and previous.
So the linked list itself is the data structure.
There's nothing that's backing it,
and since we went through
a simple implementation of a linked list,
this should look familiar,
and that's why we went through those simple implementations,
so you have some idea of what's going on
underneath the covers
when you're working with a linked list.
Okay, so let's go back to the main method.
So we've added employees.
How do we remove them?
Well, if you guessed that there are removeFirst
and removeLast methods, you're right.
So let's go ahead here.
I'm just gonna copy this whole thing.
Instead of adding last, let's remove the first,
and we don't have to pass anything
'cause we're always gonna remove the first item here,
and let's run,
and we'll see that Mike is gone.
Because we called removeFirst,
Mary is now the first item in the list,
and if we go to the end, Bill's still there,
but if I
copy this code again
and say list.removeLast,
Bill should now be taken from the list,
and let's check it out.
So Mary's still first on the list,
but we go to the end, we'll see that Bill is now gone,
and so, that's how you remove items from the front
and the end of the list.
You have to be careful, though,
because, let me just close this down,
when we were talking about add,
I said if you just call the add method,
it will add an item to the end of the list.
Well, in the remove case, if you just call remove like this,
it will remove the first item on the list,
so as I said, make sure that you always,
let me just undo that,
make sure that you always read the
description of the method you're using
to make sure that it's gonna be operating
at the end of the list that you want it to be operating at.
So there are other removal methods.
For example, you could remove a specific employee.
Of course, that would mean that
the method has to search the list for that employee,
and so, it's gonna be slower operation.
There are also methods that let you insert an employee
or a node at a specific point in the list.
You know, you can say something like
insert Joan as the sixth employee in the list,
but again, if you do that,
those operations are gonna be slower.
The quickest operations are gonna be those
that are working at the head or at the tail.
Anyway, I encourage you to take a look
at the LinkedList class and see what's available.
The important point here
is that if you wanna use a linked list in Java,
you can use the LinkedList class
as long as you don't mind the extra memory overhead
due to the next and previous fields.
If you're going to need a lot of nodes and memory is tight,
you might want to consider another type of data structure,
or if it makes sense,
you might want to implement a singly linked list,
but most of the time, memory won't be an issue.
Now before we leave linked lists,
I'll just mention that there's another type of linked list
called a circular linked list,
and this is a variation on the singly linked list,
and in this variation,
the last node in the list doesn't point to null.
Instead, it loops back,
and it points to the head of the list,
and one advantage to this
is that you can traverse the entire list
starting at any node.
So if for some reason,
that feature is important to your application,
then a circular linked list might work for you.
So I just wanted to mention that to you.
We're not gonna implement it,
but there is a variation called circular linked list
where the last node in the list points to the head node.
Okay, that's all for linked lists.
I'll see you in the next video.