Hi,
everyone.
Let's go.
Our our celeb us.
What exactly are we going to cover in this class?
I have actually divided my class into five different sections.
Section one,
which is the lab set up in this section.
We will cover what is award for machine.
How does it work?
Downloading and installing award jewel box creating first worship machine and doing the
linens installation.
Now,
please.
Remember,
this section is for those who actually have never installed or who do want to install a lab
linens machine in their laptop or their work station if you already have Ah,
Lennox machine.
And you wanted to start practicing your land exc scripting skills from this course.
Then you could simply skip through this entire section and go right into Section two in
section two will start off with shell scripting basics.
And what those basics are starting with Colonel.
How Colonel interact with shell.
What is a shelter shell scripting How the shell scripting Come along.
How can we take advantage off it?
What are the different type of shells?
Of course,
there are tons of different shells.
Eash Okay,
Shal see,
show bashful.
What is our focus in this limp in this up in this class.
And of course,
our focus is bash scripting.
But I will cover other shells as well.
Starting a shell,
how to run a shell script,
then moving on to section three we have in section three.
We will cover the scripting standards.
What exactly the standards that you should follow when you are riding a shells.
And those are how to name yourself shell scripts.
In this way,
you would have proper naming convention for your shells,
script file permissions.
So when you create a script,
you would need a Pacific execute herbal permissions and what those permissions are,
and how can we assign them,
then shell scripting format.
What goes inside of a script?
What are the comments?
What is,
um where do you define the shell?
What are the variables that sequence off shell script?
Then we'll wing onto the section four,
which is very going to start off his actual writing scrips,
the basic shell scripts.
And I'm not gonna overload you on this section with,
like,
huge script.
So I'm gonna start.
I'm gonna take baby steps with you as if you are starting fresh with me and Lennox Shell
scripting.
Then I'll show you how to create your first group script to run basic task in those task.
Our system.
Administrative tasks.
Defining variables,
input output,
script,
conditional scripts.
If else statements groups will cover the case statements,
groups look over.
Four loose skirts will write it.
I'll give you examples will create do wild scripts.
How do they work?
What are the exits Status?
How can be used the exit status and shell scripting and make use off it.
And then we have a bunch of handouts,
as you could read on shell scripting that will help you write war script and understand
scripting details.
Six Scripting basics as well moving on to the Section five,
which is our biggest section,
and you should be ready for this section.
By the time you come to this,
you would know exactly how to start,
how to get your hands dirty,
and you are already on a driving seat.
At this point,
this is where we have.
He will core their real life scripting examples,
and some off them are accessing data from falls.
Check remote server connective ity script for scheduling and notification script to delete
all files backup file systems when you wanted to back up your system and you don't have a
1/3 party backup tool.
How you could use a scripting language to do that?
Four Loops Scripts for Fire System That is,
for one of the section and I have not included just 14 loop This lesson.
This Pacific lesson would have like four or five four loop scripts that I have covered in
this one section.
So in this one lesson,
then four Loops group for file system to now.
This is another lesson.
I have split that entire lesson into two lessons.
Why?
Because I'm covering like 5 to 8 different scripts moving on copy files to remote host user
directory assignment.
You will see how we could check if if a directory exists and doesn't belong to a user.
This is a security risk.
How we could put a script around in real life examples.
A game moving on to Section five.
Section five is not finish it.
List of user logged in by date Central Logging script.
If you do not have Splunk,
which is a Logan logging third party tool in your environment,
it's OK.
We'll create our own Splunk.
Our own logging system locks script that will run like a Splunk collection logs script for
user CAL management Disabled in active users.
That's a scribble core check process status and killing it.
Status and total number of files.
Scripts to create system inventory,
getting online help,
homework.
And there's gonna be so much,
many other scripts that I cannot just add everything here in the syllabus that I will be
keep adding it later on.
So this is the This is what be actually going to cover in this entire course.
So are you ready with me?
Are you ready to go ahead and start?
Let's go.