welcome to Section four off scripting standards.
What are the basic standards that you need to remember?
Some off them that we will cover in this entire section is how you need to name your script
.
What are the naming convention that you should use?
Okay.
Hey,
I know how.
What?
Naming convention to use?
I don't have to worry about it.
I would remember everything that I would know.
Okay,
if you do know that,
be my guest.
Skip ahead to this lesson.
Double cover,
But trust me down the road if you are.
If you have created a script a year from the time you created script,
you will forget it if you do not have in a proper naming convention.
And if you do not have in a proper directory structure,
so we'll cover about the naming.
Convention will cover out how the script permission works.
So when you create a file by default,
it does not assigned executed permission.
If you want to read a file,
it has to have a re permission.
If you want to execute it,
it has to have execute permission.
We'll cover that in that.
In that,
um,
lesson.
Then shell script format.
How you should write a shell script.
What are the formats?
Um,
standards that you should follow,
followed by the sequence of the script.
Execution.
When you want to execute certain things inside off your script,
you want to execute ABC.
You need to know how they are executed.
And the last one is the variables and how to create them.
Variables is just like aliases will cover that in this in this section as well.
So these are the basic things again.
If you know all that,
be my guest.
You could fast forward.
But I would highly recommend you to please go over and And so this way you will have the
right standard in your in your memory and you will know exactly when you're starting it
from the get go.
You know how to start from the right path.