script format.
Having a proper format inside of a script is very important.
Why is that?
Because I'm going to say I'm gonna bring back the same analogy.
You create a script.
It's a very long script,
and a few months passed by,
and now you need to modify the script or troubleshoot something in the script you have.
Sorry,
you have written down the script,
but it's all over the place.
The variables is up.
Your comments are nowhere to be found.
The description is nowhere.
The commander left and right.
There is no Indention,
nothing.
So there should be a proper format that should be followed so that someone can come in and
take a look at your script,
insist.
Wow,
that's a great job whoever did that so easy to read and so easy to understand.
And what are those format?
One is first and foremost is defined shell.
This is something that you have to define.
You could say it is a part of format are mandatory.
You have to do that.
You have to define a shell.
Then you create a first script.
You have to let your operating system no run that script as Bash script.
If you're doing a corn shell,
you'll have to specify pound hache slash bin slash corn shell.
Anyway,
when we write,
our first group will cover that as well,
then comments.
Right after defining the shell,
you have to put the comments,
and those comments always starts with pound sign.
And the reason I am telling you that you should include comments is because common should
tell what your script does When your script was written who it was written by,
Was it there any modification,
anything that you wanted to include that a user o R.
Someone else reading your script can understand what this script is about?
Please add that to your comments,
then defined variables,
variables what Those variables are real.
Cover that not to worry body,
but just to let you know quickly.
The variables is just like an alias.
If you have a long command or if you have ah,
a bunch of emails.
What people do is they give it,
um,
a letter equals the whole big command that becomes their variable,
so define your variable at the top after comments.
Then you run the commands,
whatever the commands that you want your script to execute.
You need to specify those commands or if you do not have command or if you have any
statement scripts.
That's where you put your statement scripts.
Those statements groups are if then,
while for loop or so on.
Now,
when you have statements defined,
you should start.
If the line where you gonna put an if hit tab?
Because this way it will show that you're f statement is starting.
From this point on,
there is nothing that that script will translate your tab into something else.
You could use spaces.
You could use tabs,
anything that you want.
But try to make your script formatted in a way that if someone or even you read it after
year to year,
you'll say,
Ah,
this is what I did it so easy to read.
So let me log into my linens machine again,
and I'll should tell you exactly how you should format your scrip.
Okay,
this is my Lennox machine.
I'm already in my directory.
Perfect.
I created a script earlier,
or a file earlier.
Call Apache.
I'm gonna take that same script,
and I will formatted the way I have just disgusted so to do that.
I have to now do a V I on that screen.
And I am sure you guys know how to use a V.
I some some of you are familiar with them,
which is probably in a Hass worsen O V I.
I like to use a V I It's kind of old school,
but,
um,
the good things that it's available and pretty much all the units or her linens flavour So
I could never learn something new and not utilize it on older version.
Because I use V I in many system like Solara,
say I X systems.
And sometimes vim is not available.
So v I is something that you will find anywhere,
whichever the system you logging.
Anyway,
I'm gonna use V I to at it this file which will eventually become a script.
So you hit,
Enter now the first thing.
As I said,
you have to define a variable.
It had been bash.
If you look at the back,
you'll see the first thing is defining your shell.
I want to run this script as bash script.
Perfect.
Now the next thing I said to add a comment,
Okay,
I always add a comment.
As usually add a comment is like purpose testing script format date.
Put any date,
Let's say August 22,020.
Um,
modification.
If you have done any modification to the script,
put down the date off the modification.
So zero to 08 So last modification.
Of course.
Since you're creating the first time,
I'll put 20 again.
Okay,
then anything that you wanted to add,
Please Go ahead.
Do so.
So if I just put in block love whatever,
it's just a common.
It has no effect on your script.
OK,
Perfect.
I understand Imron.
But how come the first line that you have is slash bin slash bash has a common in front off
.
It isn't,
that isn't it will be considered as a comment as well.
Awesome question.
Trust me,
I had the same question.
But let me tell you,
this is just how it is.
Sometimes you know,
it is how it is.
So the Lenox will understand this as actually a shell script,
and it always starts with pound and hash.
Why?
I honestly don't know.
If you really want to know why you could ask someone else who really know inside out when
they came up with,
ah,
writing scripts.
Or you could I'm sure,
um,
go online and find out why you have to define with hash.
But anyway,
put that in the back of the head.
You have to remember there's no matter what.
Okay,
so moving on,
then you define next thing is variable.
Variable is something like I want Every time I want to echo something,
I just want to say a and then echo.
So let's say in my case,
I wanted to have,
um single coat Imron epistle.
And you know what?
All the same,
my name is Imron.
This is how you define your variable And then you could just do echoed dollar a Then it is
going when you say echoed dollar A By the way,
this is this a scripting language?
I already started teaching you,
but that's okay.
Ah,
you need to understand the format so variable I have defined here that every time this
command will run,
it is going to call upon this variable.
Why didn't I put that whole thing here?
I can't,
of course.
But what if you are working an environment that requires a huge line and does huge things.
Then you it's better that you put those variables in there.
Then,
of course,
then you put command.
Let's say you want to run a date.
You want to run a command G of minus age or so on,
then The last one I included as statements.
If you are including statements in your script,
please do not start from if,
let's say,
um,
dollar a equal.
Um,
that's a file or whatever.
Do not start like that.
Always put tab like this.
So if something is equal to that file,
enter and then tab again then echo this else echo dad and then fee to close the statement.
You see how it is that if Kantar if statement came to be on the right hand side So you know
that this is the statements that I want to run and they are and then did to the right side
.
What are those statements?
Kits?
I never seen that.
Don't worry about it.
I'm gonna cover that in my next lessons.
The purpose of this lesson is just that you know that.
Why would I follow this format on the following lessons?
That's why I want undercovered that right now,
so you wouldn't know.
This is the best way to put your scripts together,
and it will be so easier to remember when you come back to