basic task rips.
This is our second scripts that we will create together and this will actually execute some
basic tasks,
uh,
that are,
like,
based on some basic commands.
So the task that we will define in our script as the 1st 1 is P W D.
That will print my working directory ls which will list all the files or directories in my
current directory.
Who am I?
Um,
it will print my user name that I'm logged.
And with date the crunch date tell the current cat calendar and the last one I want to
create it.
Three files in my directory that I'm logged in.
Ah,
dead files are A B C.
And the command we was used to create them is touch.
So it's just that simple.
And that script will run sequentially.
If you remember,
it will do.
The 1st 1 is pwd than ls and then so on.
So my machine is right here and I am going to create my second script.
Make sure I am logged in as myself and wish directory on men.
I'm in scripts directory.
Perfect.
That's the directory I wanted to be in.
Um,
so I will go ahead and v I a new file and the name off the file of a pick as they basic
tasks.
It's just that some and her define your show.
Author.
I'm gonna keep making you do that again and again.
So you will remember Date created,
Joe.
Eight money,
20 description Run.
Basic Lennox Tasks Date.
What was this?
Fort one?
Tell me.
Modified Yes.
Again,
You're not modifying.
We just putting today's day and I guess that's pretty much it.
Now,
I always like to start my script with Echo,
so it will be a new line.
And this time I wanted to write down Echo.
This script will run a few basic tasks.
Now,
remember,
this is not a description.
This will actually output on the screen.
Then another echo just for a new line.
Now what we want to do,
we want to see which director we are in.
So simply,
just type P.
W d.
Okay,
it did that.
No,
let's see if he could do ls who am I?
Date cow.
And the last one is I wanted to create three files A b and C,
so that's pretty much it.
It's gonna run 1234 by six commands six basic tasks.
Core those tasks what exactly they're gonna do and go ahead and escape.
Bottle fed and right.
Quit Saved the file and check permissions there.
No permissions assigned the permission.
Basic tasks.
U Unless my cell tr just to confirm you basic task has been created.
Now go ahead and run basic tasks better.
Nice.
Okay,
let's see what it is.
so this script will run a few basic commands.
This is the echo.
Think that we added in right?
Then the next thing we wanted to know which directory we are in,
we are in this directory.
Then l s L s will list all the directories and files inside off my exit current working
directory.
And those files are basic task and hello world.
So it's this own file that I just run the command and then who am I?
That's my name.
I am logged in as myself date.
This is the date.
It's telling you what date is today and calendar.
This is the calendar that is output.
Now the last one is Hey,
what happened to touch ABC?
Did it create that file?
I am sure it has.
But why didn't you see in hair when it was listing that files?
Very good question.
Now let's go back to a sequence.
Remember,
the script works in a sequence in an order.
The first thing first.
So by the time touch ABC,
it hit that touch ABC.
It ran.
Ls command before that?
So that's why you didn't see it.
So now,
if you run it,
you will see your three styles in there.
So without running the script,
just two ls minus l.
And you will see in there.
There you go.
See you.
See?
I said I'll do ls myself to your ltro list everything in,
um,
in ah date format.
When was the last created?
If you see,
it has created a B and three C files.
So this is how we do our basic tax.
So if you are going through all that hassle every day and you want to automate them through
one simple basic tasks,
you could do that to simply this way again.
I like to keep things neat and clean.
So what I would do is I will put echo in every line Cool co and echo and then at the bottom
of us say echo,
end off screen.
Nice.
Welcome.
You guys probably knows hate in Ron just did something I didn't purposely I just put it
down wrong,
um,
command And let's see what the era Messi comes up.
Um,
it's run the basic tasks,
and it did everything I asked for.
Now you see,
it is it has given me those ABC files as well.
And now at the bottom,
it says Line 21 Command not found.
Okay,
so it's something went wrong with the script.
Now,
this is how you troubleshoot a script.
I wanted to cover that troubleshooting help part right here at the beginning.
Because every time you write a script,
there is always,
always a chance.
I would say I'm not gonna say that very little chance.
We are humans.
We make mistakes.
There's always a chance that you fat fingers some of the commander.
Or are you make a mistake.
Then script doesn't run.
Then how do you troubleshoot?
Well,
the Lennox offering system or the scripting shells are smart enough to tell you where the
problem is.
So it's telling you that the script is this and in line 21.
There's a command called E C H.
That command now found You want me to run the command?
I understand,
But there is no such thing as command.
Why?
Let's try it just by simply typing.
Yeah,
there is no such command.
So we know that in line 21 in this script there is a mistake and we have to fix it.
And the way I do it his i v i the script and I will Let's say if I'm right here or anywhere
,
I'll just do Colon 21.
This will bring me exactly to that line where it was complaining they go.
So it brought me right to the line and I see Ha.
Okay,
I'm sorry I made a mistake.
I left out.
Oh,
now it will run it.
Perfect.
I fix my mistake.
That is perfect.
That's how we learn.
So when you hit,
enter again run script and they go,
it is giving you everything that you asked for and at the end is telling you End of script
.
So it's It's It's again.
It's a good practice that you I'll put that What exactly the script will do at the
beginning that will tell the user,
Hey,
the script will run a few basic commands.
It will throw that out on the screen.
And when the script finishes,
it should say End of script Perfect.
So that's how we do.
Ah,
simple basic task using scripting language.
So try it out.
Tried different commands in there.
There are so many commands and Lennix,
I want you to try them out one by one and see how you could automate a few simple tasks and
fueled daily tasks.