keep on moving,
so we are going to create another script that will run basic administration tasks.
So before we had the basic commands that we wanted to create a task in a script.
Tsunami Wine tour on basic tests Those are basic administration task and those basic
administrations task An example I picked as the 1st 1 is one top 2nd 1 is DF minus age.
3rd 1 is free,
which will check the memory us by the A d f.
Is for to check the disc space up.
Time is to tell it,
when was the last time system reboot and system load I o stat,
is input I o,
um,
statistics.
So I'm sure you know these commands already.
If you don't know that,
it's fine.
You could look it up and find out what the command do.
But anywhere these commands are here to check the system health.
So when I actually joined my first company,
this is something that we were doing manually.
So every time a system administrator would come in,
they will run these commands on the servers and checking the system health.
Are there any issues?
Are there any displace issue and so and so.
So when I learned somewhat of scripting the beginning,
I was like,
Wow,
we could do so much about this and raced in middle wasting so much time we come in,
we spend like hours just going through so many systems and running certain command.
So I created the first script called check scrip.
So,
uh,
and that would check the system health.
And it would actually I added so many things later on so many other commands that actually
we needed as for Aziz by the system,
But anyway,
the point is that you could,
um,
and automate all those system administration checking,
type of related tasks.
So let's create a new script and we are logged in as ourself.
And we are in our home directory and script Eritreans.
As you know,
we have thes two scripts have created,
and then we have a few empty files.
That's fine.
Believe them,
dear.
The next group we have,
you want to do admin tasks.
So this is a name I picked.
You could pick anything that bets,
fits the description off your task.
Go ahead and hit.
Enter.
What do you do first?
Define the variable Yes.
Then author who is writing the script that as you and my kids.
Me,
of course.
Um,
then we are doing Ah,
date 08 0.2.
2000 in 20.
Let's see.
Um,
then we are doing description.
The script will run basic admin commands or task whichever that,
um,
you want to pick?
Date modified since you're creating the first time.
Same date.
Okay,
Perfect.
Now I will always like to do at Go and Saiz this script will run basic administrative
commands.
That said,
this is how it's gonna come up.
Um,
of course.
I want to do echo hair and one echo here.
Okay.
Now,
what are we going to do?
We are going to run top command.
First,
I'll do echo again.
The F minus.
Etch Command Second echo again.
Again.
As you know,
Echo is just to put an empty line so it will look more organized of time.
Echo I O stat,
Echo and echo and off.
Perfect.
Okay,
good.
Now let's go ahead.
Save it and assigned permissions and the name off the file waas admin that.
Let's tr verify the permissions are given.
Okay,
so now let's run the script Okay,
so it did run.
And if you notice really quickly,
it spit out the line Where say's this is what the script does.
And now you noticed that the SEC the first command that I wanted to run in my scribbles top
.
And now it's not running other commands.
Why is that?
Because the top command is a command that will keep your session open and give you the
status off your processes,
your memory in a realtor time so it does not exit out.
It just stays there.
So that's why my script is kind of stuck for it to finish so it could run other commands.
So how do we overcome this problem?
Well,
one thing you could do is you could tell the output of the command to be ah,
simpler or,
ah,
pipe it to something else.
So this way it will run other commands.
So how how can we do it?
That's do quit and you see,
as soon as did quite out of,
um sorry.
As soon as I did quit out of top,
it did run all the remaining commands.
But of course we were stuck there and we didn't know what happened.
So what I'm gonna do is we will look back.
You will modify the script again.
And script Knee was admin tasks.
And this time we're gonna do is we are going to say that when top runs to skin me the first
10 lines.
That's fine,
because mostly the top part off the top command has the most important one,
which gives you the information about memory.
CPU process is important.
Most processes that are taking up most of the CPU.
So I'm gonna put pipe it to head of minus turn.
Um,
and then we will run back.
Gin scripted.
Okay,
so let's run it now.
Admin task.
All right.
See it getting gives.
You gonna wait for a few seconds and then I'll give you every because it was processing and
now give you from here?
See,
this script will run basic administrative tasks,
and those tasks are the 1st 1 is top and the top is giving me the 1st 10 lines.
Then it it runs DF minus.
H command,
which is giving me the output up to here then is running.
Ah,
free free is free.
Minus M is for the memory information to be include free.
Ah,
no,
actually,
you forgot.
That's why I was looking for free and it was not there Anyway.
We'll add that,
um the next command that it was running was up time and up.
Time is right here.
And the system been up 47 minutes and the last commanded ran was hyo stat,
which is right.
And the last thing we added was end a script.
So of course we missed a V.
I Mr Free Command.
That's fine.
We'll go ahead and add.
And and it was after DF minus h.
So Echo three minus m here and now the missing command that we wanted to run,
they go.
So see,
it did give us.
Yes,
it is right here.
The city output off free minus m.
Okay,
so this is how you run the basic administration tasks.
You could actually also filter out this output to through a pipe and you give you anything
Pacific that you wanted to know about this output.
So what happened was ah,
in my,
uh,
beginning years of an I join my first company on Iran.
This oven.
I created this check system.
Um What?
I did it Eventually it was throwing up so much information that we really didn't need it.
Toe be modified.
Fills dirt out a lot of output that was coming from thes commands.
So you could do that too,
depending on what exactly you're looking for.
Um,
my recommendation is to you is go ahead and create couple of scripts that will run your
basic administration task and see how they run.