if then scripts.
Now you know how to write script.
Let's get into one.
Step up some advance groups.
Some.
If then scripts these air the scripts,
which will define some variables.
And if they're those variables are met.
Then you could run those scripts.
And if they didn't script statement.
If this happens,
do this otherwise do that.
So whatever that you define that has to be met,
then it will run it.
Otherwise,
I'll give you some different output,
depending how you write a script to better illustrate this concept off.
If then script statements.
Let's get into our machine.
Okay,
Mr To Be are in.
We are in our home directory and the directory inside.
Off it is my scripts and this directory.
We're gonna create a new script.
I'm gonna call it the our if then script again.
It does not have to be the name that I'm picking.
You could pick any name like my script or X Y Z or ABC Anything that you want.
So when you we wanted to write a script,
you do B I and the name off the file.
It will get you into the insert mode.
So the first thing do you do If you want,
Roy,
a script is defined.
Variable.
Now,
I already have a script written that I'm going to copy it from so it will save us time.
And this is the script which checks for the variable.
I'm gonna copy it and I'm gonna paste it.
Now let's look at what's this group does.
This script is gonna look for count equal 100.
So if Count equal 100 which is the variable then is going to say echoed a Countess 100 If
it is not equal 200 that is going to say the count is not 100.
So that's what pretty much if else statement does.
So let's look at our script.
Let's run it that first save it.
And once we save it well,
of course.
Where fly the file is created.
Yes.
What's inside of the file?
The look into it and it has exactly the same thing that we typed in.
Now we need to give execute herbal permission to the script.
Verify it?
Yes,
it does have execute permission and I'm going to run it.
There you go.
It says the count is 100 Perfect because we defined in our variable that the count is equal
.
So what happens if the change the count to,
let's say one?
We save it and we're on it.
Once we were running,
it says Count is not 100.
So this is the exact purpose off.
If then statements is if it looks for the variable,
whatever the variable is defined.
If the variable value is not met,
it will tell you exactly what you wanted to do.
You could also change the output by saying if then else I think.
Sorry,
the count.
Let's make a lower case.
Count is not 100 again.
Countess 100.
This is our variable.
And it says if bracket count equal 100 then a coed Countess 100 Els otherwise echo.
Sorry,
the count is not 100 fee Fi is the opposite off.
If and it is telling the script now,
you should exit out that your work is done.
And if else statement is done so you exit out of it by saving it.
And now when you run it,
it tells you Sorry,
the count is not 100.
So you just change the output to whatever you want and that's what the If statement if else
our if then statement does another example off.
If else statement that I'm gonna pick is right here,
I'm gonna copy it and I'm gonna create a new script is if then new,
I'm gonna define the variable which I already copied.
And the first command I have clear it means when the script runs is gonna create the screen
.
I don't want to see anything that's already on the screen.
Next thing is going to do is if minus e which is used,
which is the option that is used to check if a file exists or not.
So it's staying.
If this file home my absolute narrowed a text file exist than what you should do,
you should then Atco file exist else.
If file does not exist then say echo while does not exist.
And that's what pretty much it's doing to Let's run this command.
And we,
of course,
have to give up.
Execute herbal permissions that's verified has excuse permission.
Okay,
does no let's run at if now new Okay.
And you run it is this file does not exist.
It's telling you the actual thing.
Why?
Because there is no file exist.
There's do cat.
If then and it's the file exists where should define exist That fire should exist in my
home directory.
Error that text.
So I'm gonna create a file.
Now I'm going to just touch it,
and I'm gonna create this file.
The file is created.
Now I'm gonna run the script,
and now it says file does exist.
So this is ah,
sometimes a very useful command.
And it is very useful tool for system administrators who wanted to run this command,
um,
at a certain intervals or a certain day because,
an application create some error files or not.
And they run this script on Cron job to see if the file exists or not.
If it does,
it means the application is running fine.
If it does not,
then it means the file doesn't exist,
and it will tell you an error message.
So this is F if then statement and we do have other effects else statements,
examples in this file as well.
And this file is also part off.
Your,
um,
resource is your handouts,
and I want you to try out every single script,
create every new script and try out different values that you have here.
So this is a very cool script that I have written.
It tells you about your name and it's still asking you,
Do you like working in I T.
And it asks you if you if you respond,
yes,
I will tell you you're cool.
If it does now,
you say you should try.
I t.
It's just a good feel,
so I want you to run the script on your own,
created,
create a new file,
write the script and executed,
and I'm very sure it will run just fine without any air.