All right,
let's look at the exit status.
What are the exits?
Status Every time a command is ran in a shell are in love would say,
Let's go one step back in.
And Lennox,
it always has a status associated with it.
If it is successful,
it will always give us status of zero.
And there are,
um,
statuses from all the way from 0 to 2 55 Every status of the different meaning.
These are the actual Our codes are the numbers that developers associate it with a
different meanings.
So every developers or every application have a different meaning.
But for us,
we only gonna focus on a very few statuses.
And that is number 10 which is yes or no.
If this is a command that we ran previously is successful or not,
if it is not,
then it will give a message one x status one,
which is known as a minor problem.
Or number two.
It's a serious trouble or everything else,
which is exit status from 3 to 255 everything else.
So why do we need actually actually exist?
Status in our scripting?
Good question.
Well,
uneven.
We have to do a lot of comparisons in our shell scripting.
Following this lessons and in comparison,
you need to know if your command rant if it did ran and it was successful,
then do this.
Otherwise,
don't do that.
As we learned that there are statements,
Chris,
if else while statements every every one of those scripts or statements do need some kind
of status before proceed to the next,
uh,
execution.
So me show you real quick by logging into my Lennox machine.
Um,
I am logged in as myself and I am in my home directory.
So now let's see if I run a command ls minus l.
And it runs successfully,
right?
It gave me everything that I was looking for,
but a I want to know,
actually,
the status off my proceeding command,
I would do echo dollar sign.
And then the question mark,
this is telling the shell or the bash that what was a command that ran previously read and
tell me whether that command was successful or not.
If I get a zero return,
there you go.
It means it did run right because I wanted to get a listing off all my Derek Tree files and
directories in District Tree and I did give me and that's why I have zero.
Let's take another command.
That's a advantage to wish directory.
I'm in.
I'm in home.
I have solved directory Perfect Iran.
And if I do echo dollar question mark again,
it will give me zero again that it was successful.
What if I run a command?
That's it.
P W D D right This command,
there is no such command.
So if I run that it says bash commands found similar command is PWD.
Give me a recommendation.
But anyway,
the command was not successful.
So now if I asked the shell whether the last command was successful or not,
I will run the same command echo dollars question more.
And it has giving me error code 1 27 which is different from zero.
So,
as I said,
anything from 0 to 2 55 is not,
uh is this Eric owes,
But anything above zero is all our coats.
Anything that is zero is successful.
Now when we run,
when we create a script.
So let's say I go into I create a script,
I call it,
um test,
um,
code.
Just that.
And I will.
Right?
I will declare my show.
And now I will not define all those stuff that I know you already know.
Since this is a very small,
um,
script,
I'll just do echo.
Hello.
And then I will ask if the command was successful and I will save it.
Test code.
Now when I run that,
you'll see I'm getting the hello.
And but that I'm getting zero.
It means it was successful.
Same thing if I wanted to do something else.
Let's say if I go back to test code and this time I will do instead of echo all just
replaced of it.
Kiki.
So there is no such commanders.
Icky.
So anyway,
let's see what the error message comes up.
Now I'll run again,
and now it's giving me the seamer Massive that it was not successful.
Ah,
same way.
If I try ls minus l l l l.
And it does exist,
actually,
let's say ls minus z.
There is so many options.
Right?
Um ls um tax tax tax tax peak.
Okay,
so there you go.
See unrecognized options.
So now let's see what the area code is the area code is two C.
It's a different.
And that is,
um,
about error code that shows serious trouble.
So this is about you have not defined the option successful.
Now,
let's run another script really quick.
I'm gonna create that script,
I'll call it.
Um,
we I exit code,
um exit code script.
And I was defined the show.
And this time I wanted to make sure I run ls minus l'Homme.
I have solved last check.
This is the command are trying to do.
So what is going to do is is going to do ls minus l.
And it's gonna ah,
Onley,
find out if home IVs all and there is a file named check exists.
Okay,
so now I have to define the statement.
If dollar question mark,
which is command that I ran equal to zero,
which means if the command ran successfully,
then do what an echo file exist else.
Echo file does not exist and feet and let's run it and give executed permission.
Now let's run the script and it will say cannot access home.
I absolve.
Check.
No such file and directory.
Then it stays off Course file.
Does not exist because the Eriko does not match.
Ah,
zero.
So if I create a file check in my home directory So I'm in home directory.
I'm just gonna do touch and check The file is there,
right?
So just verify it.
Check.
And it is,
dear.
Right.
So now when I run that script again that I just created and it did give me that file with
my LS minus l command.
And it's his file exist.
So that's why it is.
That's that's why we the exit status importance is there.
So this way you could actually,
um,
associate each code with some kind of meaning.
So developers like C plus plus or jars other developers like object oriented based
programmers or people who write operating systems.
They are the ones age happily used these codes because thes codes make a lot of difference
.
But in our,
um,
class are,
in our lessons,
going from this point on,
mostly going to you zero to make sure figures exist or not.
And that's why most of the time the system administrator engineers use in the every day
Lennox,
um,
scripting languages to try it out and see how you could create different scripts with Eric
codes and what their code gives you