Now let's talk about another script to delete old files.
Now,
this is a definite script that everyone might have experienced or will be experiencing.
If you are becoming a system administrator or becoming a Lennox,
you are taking over Lennox job.
So you have a system.
And,
um,
as you know,
that you build a system.
Um,
so many people law gained so many program runs.
So many locks get created as a system ages over time.
It creates a lot of files.
When a lot of files are created,
there is no mechanism inside unless you,
um,
enable couple of other services to delete all the files.
So what happens if you don't lead those old files?
Well,
it will fill up your disk space,
and once the disc space is full,
your system will become unresponsive.
So it is very important for all the system engineers administrators to actually keep an eye
on all the old files and that are no longer in use.
So in this lesson,
what we're gonna do is we're gonna create a script from scratch that will delete all the
files for a specified number of days or years,
or whichever that is being specified in the script.
And what are you gonna do?
Actually,
first,
we're gonna create files with all the time step,
because in my system,
my system is fairly new.
And most likely the system you are working on is also new.
So maybe you don't have older files,
so you would have to create files with the whole the time stamps so we could try out our
new a script.
Then we gonna find and delete those files that are older than 90 days.
Um,
why pick 90 days?
It doesn't really matter.
You could pick 100 raise 80 days,
whichever days that you like,
but in a journalist.
And it is that most of time people want to get rid of all the files,
all of them three months,
and then we gonna find another way or another script,
um,
which will find and rename old files.
So if instead of deleting it,
what you could do is you can find all the files that's older than 90 days,
and instead of deleting it,
how can we just rename it and renamed like a dot old or dot archive or whatever that you
want to rename So you need a script for that,
too?
So these these are the type of script that will work on in this lesson.
Um,
I will go straight into my Lennox machine.
Okay.
I have it open through my precession.
I am logged.
And as myself and I am in home,
I've zall p s directory.
PS directory is something that I previously created stands for professional scripts anyway
Or you could put pick any directory,
as I mentioned.
Um,
earlier.
So now we are in this directory,
and when you do ls minus.
Lt are you'll notice that I do not have any file older than August 27th which is not three
months old.
So for me to test my script on older files,
I would have to create some files that will,
with all the time steps.
Well,
can you do it?
Yes.
You could do it.
Um,
you could do it with a touch command and,
um,
before mad.
For for that is touch with minus D option and you specify the time.
Let's sit Thursday,
Um,
Thursday,
Comma first March,
2018 12.
30 AM and create a file called It's called,
um eight Okay,
so now the file is created.
That's verify it.
If it is,
if it is created with all the time stamp.
Yes.
You see,
I didn't ls minus lt r And this option with less months lt are It will give me all my files
and the time Lee order so that the most recent one is created The bottom and all those one
is at the top.
So if you see the top one is this one It is created on march 1st.
Um so March 1st is a lot older.
I created that.
So now I wanted to create just like that.
I want to create other files as well.
So create be I'll create,
see,
create Diar,
create four files.
So this way,
when I run the script,
it will find all these commands all these files and executed.
Now let's create our script to delete it.
So first thing is to find it.
First of all,
every time you need to create a script,
it's better that you run that command so it will work in the script.
So do find,
um,
pat to where you finding it.
So I'm gonna find it in this path,
which is right here.
So find in this path time modify time plus 90.
And then once it finds them than what do you want to do?
You want to execute a command?
And I just wanted to see the listing office.
I'll do ls minus.
L off.
What returns and what has returned is specified with curly braces,
open curly braces,
closed space,
backslash and colon.
This is just a standard way to find files.
It's not something fancy that is only written script is just a simple commanding.
When you're searching online,
you will find exactly commands.
So once I run this command,
you will see I will find all the files that are created three months ago.
And you see it found four files,
right?
Perfect.
So now I will create a script that will do exactly the same thing,
and I don't have to actually run it manually.
I'll just Cron tap that job and it will run on him.
Um um,
on a scheduled basis.
So if I do V I and I will put,
um um delete old files.
This is a name off my script.
I'll hit,
Enter and you know,
here What you need to do is been Bash and Author Imron.
Absolute date do eight 8 2020 description.
Very This script.
Well,
delete all their thin files Older then 90 days modified.
We need to worry about it.
Not really this time because you're creating.
I'll get perfect.
Now,
this is the description.
And,
um,
the shelf has defined I am going to right click,
which I copied that same exact while earlier.
And now just save it.
Give excusable permission to my script.
Um which is the legal files?
This check?
Yes,
the follows There.
Now,
when I run it,
delete old file and you will see it is giving me hold Now I want to delete them.
So to delete them,
you be I'd upon a descript again and instead off execute ls you just do are delete those
files that are return.
So now when I run it the old files and give me my prom back it means it ran So when you do
ls my insult er you'll see all those files that I had earlier a b c d e All of them are
gone,
right?
So that's how you create a script that will really open.
What if you just want to rename it,
Let's try the same script.
And this time I'm just gonna say,
move the lead or piles to rename old files.
So now it's renamed I'm gonna change it to rename Old Falls.
And this time,
what I'm gonna do is I want once that those files are found I want to move whatever is
returned to return name dot old So this is going to find and move whatever it find to the
name off the fine bid dot old extension,
copy and paste.
Now I first before I run it.
I want to create those files and created earlier.
So I'm gonna hit up our key because a perky remembers all the commands that I ran
previously.
Okay,
so this is a one D see b and A that's verified.
Let's do it.
It's my cell tr and you'll see all the parts are now.
When I run this updated script,
it should update the name off these files from D two d dot old si dot old beat.
Our old and a daughter is to run rename old files and it ran.
Let's verify it you see a B C D got old.
So this is about the script again.
It's everyday script that you're gonna be using it.
It's a real life example script.
You need to know that you need to know how to delete all players or rename it or whatever
that you're trying to do with the files.
It will do it for you,
so try it out yourself.
I am going to include the instructions that we just followed in the lectures text in the
same lesson.
You'll find it.
You could copy paste,
or you could start from scratch.