are less.
Next lesson is about listing users who have logged in,
Let's say,
for example,
today or any Pacific Day.
So what happened is you.
Let's say your manager comes.
It comes to you and ask you Hey,
Imron,
can you give me a list of all the users who have logged in today?
And if they are logged into former Pacific machine from a Pacific I p or even,
um,
you could say,
Hey,
can you give me a list of users who logged in on July 25th?
Then what would happen?
You have to actually go in,
uh,
get for,
um,
the right command look for the right options and the right,
piping commands.
And then you run the command.
So what if you already have a script that does this type of job for you?
And you know that your manager is gonna come back to you and ask you the same thing,
probably like two or three times Ah,
week or months,
and then you need to create a script so well,
create the script for our managers so he'll be happy.
So let's go directly into our machine,
and I am by the way.
Ah,
What the script is gonna do is it's gonna look for users who are logged in today.
That's a first script of you'll,
right?
The second,
what it will do is but in the same script,
we'll do as we will add the user input.
Meaning we will ask the user.
Okay.
You want me to get a list of all the users,
but do you want to get it for a Pacific Day or Pacific month?
So we will give that option,
give the leverage to the user so they simply and put the month or date,
and it will get them.
That output sounds,
um,
found entrusting.
Right,
So we'll try that.
All right,
let's go back to our machine.
And again,
you're logged in as ourself,
which direct you you're in.
Let's go to our Profession Scripts directory.
And I am going to named this script list.
Uses.
Okay.
Ah,
regular drill.
Define are variable or water date.
I'm gonna leave to date out.
You could put it in description.
This script will list uses love and by modified two.
And we'll leave that out.
I know you're export now.
Okay,
So the first thing that will do is,
um,
no.
Before I write anything,
let's write and quit out of this.
Save it.
And if you wanted to get a list of users by day,
what do you do?
You do run last command,
right?
You hit enter and you get all those ah users on the first column and the machine there.
Ah,
terminal at the time And the which date they logged in the time and they're still logged in
or not.
If you do,
let's see.
Last you'll see,
these are all the machines user log damage from all the machine the time they're logged in
.
So we wanted to know the list of fuses by the day.
So the command he ran already,
right.
But we need you don't need all that stuff we need to simple users.
So we have to modify our command,
right?
So it will be last,
and then we will do.
Um that's it.
Um um,
grip for like,
let's say Monday,
so it will give us all the Monday in everything.
But we also wanted to make sure that,
um,
it actually goes by the dates.
If I If if I mind my manager says.
Give me all the list of users that logged in today,
so I know I could run that command.
And I know today's date right,
and I could just simply grow up for that.
But what if I want the script to run automatically,
then the script needs to know what today's date is,
and for it to find out you'll have to run the day command and then you could do is simply
grab for this date.
It's a Friday,
August 31st and then sorry.
First you type the last command and then grab for that Pacific date,
and it will give you only their uses for that Pacific date,
right?
That's how you do it.
But again,
script doesn't know what date is today.
So script has to run the command date to find today's date and Parsons and then put that
into the script.
So to do that will get back to our script,
which is list uses,
and here first we'll do is we'll define the very that what is today's date said today equal
,
and we put the tick tickles comes before the date of for the command,
said date talk,
dollar one people on money,
daughter to dollar through.
This is what we want and take again to close it.
But what exactly this command is doing?
So let's copy this command,
save our script and running.
See,
It's giving you the 1st 3 field.
So if you just type date,
give you the three field the time the e d t.
Which is the zone,
the year and bunch of information.
So you don't want to get all that information.
You just want the 1st 3 columns so you could grow up against these cars.
So we already defined that in our ah command,
and it will pick only first recall.
Let's get back to our list of fuses.
We already defined that we put in a variable and variable is called today.
Now we will do is we'll do last,
which is to actually run the command and we want to corrupt for what you want to grab for
our vary and variable is what today.
So basically what saying is run the last command and grab for the variable and variable Is
this so this is what is going to do and now let's run it permissions Hmm Okay,
You see what is happening here?
It's saying August,
No such file directory 31st.
No such file directory.
Why is happening?
Let me tell you why.
Okay,
so let's do the cat off the script.
You see,
it's when you run this command,
it gives you the information,
which is Friday,
August 31st and we are passing this output to the group.
But when you do this this passing off information off grip and then you do this entire
thing,
then the corrupt doesn't know which to grab for.
It has to grow for Friday or August or 31st.
So we have to put that in coats.
So the great would know that this whole thing is one string.
Then it'll grow up.
So you have to modify our script the same way list and we will put the coat around our very
perfect.
Now let's clear the screen.
Let's run it again.
And this time it is giving me,
Ah,
the users that been logged in today.
So system will find out today state and it will grow up for that.
Today's So this is our first group that I mentioned that we wanted to Do you have the list
submitted to your to your manager?
And if the manager only wants to user,
you could modify your script by doing list and instead,
off last and grew up today you could just do sorry.
Talk it to what Column?
Number one,
Cause you don't want all that stuff that comes with it right now.
Let's run it and you only get the uses.
And that's what he or she wants to get the list for,
right?
No.
Next thing is,
we want to create a script that will ask the user input to pull a user.
So what if you have the script in which,
which the script knows that I'm gonna pull users that logged in today?
Only by deep.
But now we want to give the power to the user,
said the user will define its own,
um,
its own variable or its own choices.
Let's put it this So for that will go back into our Lennox ah list user script and what
we'll do is we leave everything as is and no sorry,
we will actually have to REM or because this one actually is for today,
and we we don't want to grow up for today,
and you will get rid of this one as well.
So you know what the best thing is?
Instead of deleting this removing this oops has quit out if it and just copy it Lists user
by in That's a six apps issues by and okay,
so now this is now we come on.
Who?
It?
This way.
We could leave the previous script as is and modify the new one.
So let's get rid of So a description discovered less users logged in by date or now play
users.
Okay,
So first thing is,
it has to ask the user what you're looking for.
So whenever you need to ask you,
is that what you have to do?
You have to display the message on the screen to display the message on the screen is echo
,
and I'll put coat hair because I'm gonna put parentheses.
So please,
and to day now,
put parentheses,
for example,
Monday because I have to let the user know the example,
and I'm putting parentheses.
That's where you when you put parentheses an echo,
then I think you would have to put in coat,
but you could try without code.
Hopefully works.
But anyway,
just to be sure.
Okay,
so now you have to read the so you do D As for days,
echo is to put an empty line.
Next one you need to ask is please enter month,
for example August.
That's how it these s go again.
Just put empty line.
So not read because we have to read the read I m is a very a month bill.
Another echo.
Now you have to ask into the question please enter date for example 28.
Okay,
Read the date.
Devi already have a variable for its of a podium.
Okay,
so we have asked all these questions,
but a quick are We have asked all the questions and we have added those questions into our
very now What do you want to do next?
Next we wanted to do is run the command last and grip for coat,
dollar,
D,
dollar and dollar.
You see how it is going to grip it?
It is going to grow up the entered month the entered.
So I entered a into mountain and to date and we'll put that variables here and I'll grab it
from the last.
That's run it,
and we'll see how it works.
List uses by please Enter day.
Perfect.
Put in,
um,
Monday,
as it say,
Please enter month.
It's a August,
please,
and to date put 20 and it stays.
There is no user that actually has logged in that day to verify our script runs.
Let's run just last command just to see if there's actual users who work.
So we'll pick.
Um,
Sunday,
August 26th.
Uh,
let me clear this.
So your seat,
please.
Sunday,
August 26.
So we know for sure that this is the day month that someone in my machine or I have logged
in.
So when I hit enter now it's giving me All the users have been logged in to my linens
machine on this date again.
If you wanted to just view the list of users,
not the whole information.
What do you have to do is you just put it at the end.
You put it off dollar one,
and this way it will only give you the users clear the screen.
It's run it again,
less user by,
and he's and to date Sunday,
August 26 perfect.
This is what we wanted to know.
And you could just simply copy and paste it to your email and send it to your boss.
And you're happy he's happy and your script has done.
Next time he comes back to you and say,
Hey,
can you give me that same list again?
What do you have to do?
You have to run the command.
Put in all those variables again.
No.
You have a script.
You made your life easy.
So you just run the script and there it goes.
Now you could go one step further.
How is you?
Could actually automate this task by running to the Cron job.
If your manager tells you that I need a list of everyone who logs in on Monday off every
month,
you could specify that as well.
All right,
Hopefully I works out for you.
Try it out.
Try to different options.