disk space.
Check status,
no matter what.
Um,
you are doing an i t.
This is one of the issue that everybody experiences.
Whether you are a database administrator,
networking guy Lennox guy Windows guy are working in any kind of application capacity.
You always going to get to this point where you will have a dis space issue and this space
issue either on your own computer owned a laptop or a server that you're working on,
where you would have to actually tell the administrator Hey,
can you free up to this space and administrator would eventually go in and free up the
space by deleting discs.
But anyway,
ah,
system administrators or engineers who are actually managing the servers,
weather's windows,
Lennox or any other offering system,
they have to be vigilant off all the system health and biggest.
One of the main system health that you have to check is the dis space.
If the Dace base is out,
it's 100%.
Then your system will become unresponsive,
and sometimes what happens is you know you want to delete a file,
but it's too late because you cannot even log in.
The system is not letting you insult.
You have to be proactive and make sure you're dis space does not get to 100%.
So that's one of the real life examples that everybody would faces,
and I'm gonna put a script for it.
And then we will automate that,
and we'll make sure this it's not gonna happen in anybody's,
um of professional career where they will have to face the issue off this base.
So what we'll do is in this lesson is,
well,
first,
find displace using the DF commit.
Of course,
there are different commands as well,
but the most ah,
important command and mostly used command is DF.
You could also use um,
D you to find a disk usage based on a file system as well.
But DF is we'll give you the file system usage on petition level,
and this is what we're looking for.
So we'll run that command,
and what we'll do is we'll run different scripts that will filter output and compare so it
will run the same script D of command.
And then we'll put the filters around like grab this off that column and then do the
comparison.
If this column is greater than 90 then let me know.
Or if it's less than that than what do you want to do if then statement.
So there are different ways we're gonna do that.
Compare comparison.
This is a longer way to do it.
It's always been done like that.
But now on at the end,
I'll also show a simple script which will actually go in.
And it's like a one liner script,
and it will actually tell you the dead space and that I'll show you at the end.
So let's go into the clinic server that we have.
Okay,
I have this terminal open.
And for this space,
you would have to be,
um,
route.
No,
I don't think so.
For DF minus h,
yes.
You could run that command without being so that's what you don't have to be rude.
Just make sure you are in Ah,
ps directory,
which is my home.
I have solved PS directory.
That's where I'm keeping all my script.
Okay,
so the first thing first what do you want to do?
You want to run the command d of mines H and the status that you will get is not from the
size,
not from used not from available from the usage column.
If the usage column is reaching above 90 or 95 in some companies than it's a problem,
and you should be aware of that.
And if you do not have,
um,
some kind off monitoring application deployed in your systems,
then you would have to do it manually.
And sometimes the systems do not behave normal.
When you install a monitoring agent on it,
then you have no luck but to create an automation tool yourself like we are going to do
here in this lesson.
So we will focus on this column,
which is 123 4/5 column and we will compare with our threshold.
If threshold goes above 90 let me know,
complain.
If it's been stays below 90 and perfect,
just keep running it and keep doing your job.
Okay,
so for that,
we know that now,
as you could see,
the first thing we have to do is DF minds H.
And now we have to get rid off these temp FS petition.
These are swap space and you don't want to get any information on that,
so you will do igra minus V T m p f s or Dev TMP fs So I don't want filter out everything
that has TEM profess or deaf Tampa office.
Now it enter.
And now you'll see that you have flow's system right here on Lee,
the one you're looking for now.
You could also get it off the first line if you want to.
So let's see if I could get rid off first line and the first line is file system size used
or less until minus and plus to can it has gotten got rid off the first line.
Perfect.
Now we have four petitions route as D B one as D.
B s D.
A one and V g.
Oracle.
Now you'll probably have a different file system in your environment,
and I'm sure you do not,
just probably because your system is probably built.
Um,
of course,
your system is actually built on a different way or different petition,
so you will see something else on the file system being mounted and actual file system.
But I'm sure you are following me.
What?
I'm talking about how we could get rid off the stuff that we do not want.
Okay,
so that part is done.
Now,
what do you want to do?
We want to get on ley the fifth column,
Right?
Because Fifth column is the one right here.
This is the column that we wanted to do a comparison on.
So we'll do talk 50.
Oh,
yeah.
I accidentally percent signs should be dollar signs.
Um,
I think this is not the right column looking for Oh,
I made a mistake.
I for fourth column on Want to replace it?
Have you know,
72 16 and two?
Okay,
we are hair up to here.
Perfect.
Now,
if we are comparing these inter Jewish with our pre defined number,
let's say we wanted to get an alert.
If the value is above,
that's a 60 and then we know the value of 70.
But it has this percentage sign.
So when we do the comparison,
but if else statements this is gonna complain and script won't run,
so we have to get rid of this percent sign as well.
So to get rid off,
that is,
I would use the cut command cut minus D and unwanted character,
which is percentage coat single coat space minus F one and you will see.
Okay,
let me make this bigger.
So you will see the entire command hit a parakeet.
So command filter,
filter or the first column,
The first raw filter out fifth column and cut and get rid off percent sign.
And once you get rid of a percent sign,
give me the first field and first feel his number one field,
which was right here.
And then if I put f two,
it would give me just percent if you want.
So we got to this point.
Perfect.
Said this is what exactly?
We wanted to get out from D of command so he could do our comparison.
Now,
what you would have to do is now you create a script and do a four loop.
So let's say you did this and you copy it and you create a script called check disk and you
give defined the shell out there.
Um,
date description.
This script will check for disk space modified I put down right here.
Okay,
So this is going to give us all the values in the fifth column off the D of command,
and it will filter out the percent sign.
So if I just run this script like that,
check this B I check disk.
Um oh,
I put it a variable.
That's why didn't run.
So just take other variable and just stick in the command by itself.
And then do check this.
You'll see it is giving me or the entire column and with four roars.
Okay,
good.
So now we know we are getting the result if you want.
Now we have to give this entire command and a sign of variable and I'll give the variable
name A and if it's a command you take,
which is right above Sorry,
which is right below the escape.
And you close it the entire command with tick as well.
This will show that this is a command,
not just a value.
So now what we wanted Now we have to use the four loop he could use.
We could do this first,
like if dollar A is greater than let's say 50.
Then at go check disk space else we don't want to do anything else just fee and done.
But it will not run.
Let's try.
Run it,
C.
It didn't run.
Okay?
The reason it didn't run.
It says too many arguments.
You see,
it's is right here to money argument,
White home.
Any argument,
because when we run that line,
this command,
it gives us more than one value.
Remember,
gives gave us four rose with four different values.
So if it has given us only one value,
let's see if it has given us,
Um,
just draw first role and number is 40.
Then it would work.
But since it has four O's,
then we have to use four loop for that so that so four Luke can go from first roll,
second role,
third row,
fourth row and then done once it's finished looking at every row.
So that's why just for single if is not gonna work.
We have to put a four loop around it.
So how we do it we do for and I'll put I as invariable in dollar eight.
What does Soleri dollar a is this variable?
So what I'm saying is,
whatever the result is coming from this line,
put it into another variable and DeBary with his I Okay,
I put it in.
It's it's in the variables in the container nobody want do now I want to do is if that
container is dollar,
I now not dollar eight.
That container has a value.
Anything above 90% which is 90 then echo check disk space,
see?
And then done cause we're doing for Luke.
Sorry,
I missed one thing.
Four also has do for I in dollar a then do what?
Right.
So I missed that.
Do if which is finishing off a fee and do is finishing up with done.
Or now when I run this quick,
it is not going to give me anything.
Why?
Because I have defined the value as if the output off this command any of the output is
above the number 90.
Then tell me that check this space.
Put none of the output.
This detective,
none of them has 90.
My file system is the highest 1 70 So I have to pick a value that is below 70.
So this baby could verify our script.
So instead,
off 90 I will pick 50.
So now audition work Now it should give me this Check this space so I'll do clear this
green check disk.
They go see it says check this space because it did find one off the values that is above
50 and it complaint.
Now we have to be a little more.
Um,
we need a little more information from it.
That's it.
Not Just check this papers.
Tell me what rich partition.
Right.
So if I have this four petitions that I was looking for,
let me cat my script and the me run this command again,
and you will see I have this for partition.
Let me take out this one has have these four partition,
and it gives me if I run my command,
just check disk.
It gives me check this space because it actually met the value I have defined.
But it only gives me information that check this space,
but not which this space.
So in order for me to be more,
um,
informational about this error,
I have to give it there map drive as well.
So how can I also give the map drive information?
But I could do is I could come in here and I'll say echo this base.
Check this base and output dollar.
I like which the space if this is dollar eyes only gonna give me the number Okay,
Nice.
I have the number.
There's to check the number Bush numbers.
You're the screen.
Check this.
Check.
Disk space 70.
Okay.
Your hair.
So now we know that there is a dead space are disputation with up to 70%.
Now we also need more information that which this partition all right,
no problem will keep working on that.
So for that,
what we have to do is we have to grab that dollar I from the d of command of So if I put in
right here,
I could do tick,
because again,
this is a command DF minus h grip for dollar and take clothes.
So now echo will echo out this.
And if I don't put in right here,
then it will read out the entire eco with DF minus crab.
Let me show.
You know what said this way?
You know what I'm talking about.
So let's say if I take out,
take and run the check.
You see,
it is giving me DF minus age,
as if it's it's actually it wanted to up with the screen.
So that is why I have to put a tick around and close of now.
I should have the exact information They checked this base 70 which is on file system Santo
s dash route and space in an entire thing and it is mounted on slash.
So is basically gripping it.
That number.
And of course,
the number exists.
That's why I'm gonna get So anyway,
this is the four loop that you would have to use to check the displaced.
Another way.
We have the same script written a different way.
I actually got the script.
The second script from online.
I was looking online and this was the script that I found out initially.
So I I have already created the script,
and I What I did is I copied the create disk file.
Sorry.
Check disk and I copied it to one.
And I have to now.
So I'm gonna go to the 2nd 1 but IHS checked this one.
Okay.
And this one,
you will see it is slightly written differently.
Um,
what it is doing is it's running command.
DF minus h upper case h ah which is pretty much the same as the lower case.
H.
If you wanted to see what man DF has with minus h upper case h.
Actually,
this is likewise but use powers off 1000 not one down,
So it's pretty much give the same thing somewhere.
Leave it as is with grab E.
It is trying to filter out anything that starts with file system.
Tim Papacy,
Jerome um,
or death of her temper.
First is doing the same thing than oc print dollar one.
Sorry,
Dollar five and dollar one,
which is the Fifth Column and first called.
So when I run this command just that and mice other terminal I have to put a d of mine
safety before that DF my upper case h And now I run the command and I'll get that up.
So pretty much the same way I did now differences that they instead off doing using the
four look,
they're using the why look so in while Lou,
what they're doing is the while read the output and the output is this entire command.
So put the output of this entire command into the variable call up on,
then do,
and they're defining another variable and enter.
The variable they're doing is echo the output and talking it and print dollar one,
which is the file system cutting it and getting a percent sign if there's any to it.
And um,
no,
sorry,
but the output they're trying to get rid off the fifth column percent sign and putting it f
one second variable.
The defining is echoed the same output,
which is Thea operate hair,
disa variable and auk and dollars print dollar to have a little space here,
I'll just get rid of the space.
Okay,
then.
If the use percentage,
which is this variable,
is greater than 90 then echo running out of the space petition,
which is this petition variable on host name,
which is the host name of this machine as on date,
which is today's date and fee and don't.
So this is written a little differently and let's try to run the script.
This one,
it didn't give me anything because the the set value is 90.
So I'm going to change it to 50 and now I run it and you will see it is giving me this
entire line.
Running out of this base on this file system 70% on my first linens is the host name.
As on September Saturday and the date and time and everything because it has that date in
it,
too.
You could use that one if you want to.
Um,
it's a little bit complicated,
but if you do understand this group perfect.
Be my guest used that one.
It works perfectly as well.
Um,
and it is not using for loop as I was using it in my previous script.
So now you have to scrape.
So the third script that I wanted to show you guys,
which is very easy and simple and straightforward.
I'm gonna copy.
Check disk to check disk three V.
I check this three and let's get rid off.
Um,
everything.
And what this was going to do is DF minus h look.
So oh,
single coat zero plus dollar five.
Greater than or equal to 10.
This is,
ah,
stressful that I wanted to go with and print the threshold.
Okay,
so if I just run this command just like that single,
it is giving me everything that is above 10% on the fifth column.
So what I'm saying is the fifth column has to be cool or greater than 10.
So these are the equal and greater than 10.
So if I modify that to,
let's say 50 then it will give me only the one of them.
One of the rose,
which is slash mounted so put to put it in script.
So what we'll do is we'll who echo this is simple line.
Another echo following is the disc space steps go on more line and then it will do is run
that same command right here.
I'll get rid of this and I will filter or what I don't want.
And I will just print dollar five and dollar six,
and that's pretty much it.
This is just that simple script.
What it's doing is it's running a DF minus,
each command,
walking it the fifth column and saying this is just the way it is.
Zero plus dollar five.
And if the dollar five fifth column is greater than or equal to 10 then print that and talk
fifth and sixth column.
So let's run check Disk three and following is a diss based out of 70 and 16.
Perfect.
No,
Since I have the threshold set to 10 I will modify that to 90 or whatever.
So since I the lowest when I have 70.
So I'll go with Ah,
sixties.
Anything above 60.
I should get a message.
And it sees the following is the dis space status 70% and this is how I'm gonna get the
result.
When I run this command,
I could change the value to whichever the value I want.
So this the last group that I have written this is the one I've been using lately because
very much simpler.
And we clear the screen very much simpler.
And it's one liner.
You don't have to use a four loop.
You don't have to use the while loop.
You could just simply use this command to check the disc space status.
So now you learn how to do how to check the Dace base with four loop.
How to check the displays.
Why,
Luke,
and how to check the display simply by one line,
Three different options.
Try every every,
all three scripts and,
um,
see if you are actually,
having any issues,
and I'm sure all three of them should work for you.