creating virtual machine.
In this lesson,
we will create our first social machine.
And on victory will be installing are sent OS clinics operating system.
But worker machine is basically nothing but a shell.
Ah,
container,
which holds the information off a machine CPU memory disc and all the resource is this
fortune machine is gonna be sharing.
The resource is wherever it is installed.
So let's say if it is installed on my laptop,
it will be sharing.
The resource is from a laptop,
the Oracle work show box.
I'm gonna open it up.
Okay,
so this is the window for the Oracle Horschel box.
I'm gonna click on new.
The name I will pick is my first Lennox,
the M.
And if you notice,
um,
the virtual box is smart enough to OPEC,
the operatives,
his assistant type and version for you.
You probably noticed that you are going to see the 64 bit.
You are probably seeing 32 big.
Now,
if you are seeing a 32 bit,
then either your computer is 32 bit architecture or the virtualization technology is not
enabled.
First,
let's find out if my computer is 64 or not.
So let's go to start menu computer.
I'm gonna click right click and go to properties.
Once the property comes up,
you will see here it will tell you if it's Win seven PC and right here you're gonna see or
is this system type?
It's a 64 bit operating system.
So that's one way.
That's one of the reason that when I'm building my worship machine,
it is coming up 64 bed operating system.
The second reason you might not gonna see it 64 is if you don't have virtual technology
enabled in your bias sitting.
If that's the case,
I have actually pasted an article and in my in this lesson and there is a link to it,
I would recommend that you could go that link and try the settings that are recommended and
see if it changes the 64 setting.
I'm sure it will work.
If not,
you will always email me back.
So I'm gonna leave thes setting sugar click next Now here is gonna ask me the size off the
memory I want to assign to this virtual machine.
Now,
by default is picking up one gig off memory now,
you should also keep in mind How much memory do you have actually in your laptop?
So in my laptop,
I have Let's look at my computer again,
Right?
Click properties,
and you will see here.
My computer has installed memory is four gig.
So it is.
It is wise that I keep the memory below that digit.
That number.
So I have four gig,
so I'm gonna give one gig up that memory to dis virtual machine.
I'm click next,
create a new Horschel desk.
Yes.
It will create a brand new Horschel disk.
Next,
leave the default dynamically allocated.
Lee the default post.
Um then this is the size of the disc.
By default,
it picks a gig.
I wanted to pick 10 gig just to be safe.
So I'm gonna just click inside this box,
remove and type 10 and click create.
And there you go.
This is my first worship machine that is created again.
Think off it as a piece of hardware that's been created for me.
I'm on the assembly line.
I'm putting the CPU and putting the memory and putting the hardest.
I'm putting everything in that machine and I built a machine.
So once the machine is built,
what is the next step?
Next step is to install the operating system,
and in our course,
we will be working with Santo s up a ring system.
So I'm gonna power this on,
and I'm gonna install the operating system.
But of course,
before I go ahead and install the offering system,
I do need the software ISO image.
So in the next lecture,
we will cover how we're going to download the IRS.
So,
software,
and then how you could attach that software to this Lennox of'em,
and then we will boot off off that software.