wild cards.
What are while cards,
just as his name says they are wild cards,
meeting.
If you play cards and,
you know,
in poker or blackjack,
they do pick a card like a 10 or nine,
whatever the card,
and you could match it to any of the card to make your flash trail or whatever that you
like.
So that is kind of a wild card.
So just like that in Lennox,
we used wild cards to get the output that you were looking for.
Ah,
wild card is a character now.
This is a definition right from the Lennox Dictionary that can be used as a substitute from
any off a class of characters in a search.
So there are many wild cards,
but the most basic ones I have listed here they're three.
The 1st 1 is the one I use most of time is asterisk,
which is also referred to as a star.
Ah star represents zero or more characters,
anything that matches but that star placeholder.
We'll look into that in a moment when we actually used the star wildcard in our Lennox
machine.
That we have question more represents a single character so if you have Ah,
file name,
text and you're looking for any files that has the word text.
And you could use t e instead of ex.
You could just put question mark in there and then t that means what ever files that had t
e doesn't matter what's inside off the X and the last letter is X the tea,
then it work.
The 3rd 1 we have brackets,
which represents a range of characters.
So it's better we look at in done limits machine to understand them more deeply.
I'm gonna bring up my machine real quick.
Where did it go?
Right here on long den hallways is myself and I'm in my home directory.
Of course.
Now,
um right now these are the files in directories in Exist in my home directory.
I want to create nine files that has a name that's a A B,
C D one and X y Z and then same thing instead of one.
It just increments the number 23456 I could do this.
Touch a B c d one dash x y z one time,
then hit up Arrow key again.
Change wanted to changed to three and keep going.
But don't you think it's cumbersome?
A tedious It is.
Right.
So we use wild card to perform that task because you're gonna create nine files.
So it's just a practice that we're doing for nine follows.
Trust me.
In a corporate environment,
you're probably gonna have to create,
like,
thousands of miles.
What you gonna do?
You gonna just hit up arrow key and or type it 1000 times?
No,
that's not productive.
So then what do you do?
Use wild cards?
So first of all I'm gonna do is I'm gonna remove these files one by one.
Again.
I could removed vile card as well,
But let's created first and I'll show you how I could remove it.
So I have two left now.
I could use a wildcard to remove both in one shot removed,
ABC wild card.
So what is telling it?
Removed everything that has a farm name that starts with a B C and whatever that comes
afterwards.
You don't care.
Just remove it.
Hit,
Enter.
That's myself here and you'll see all those two files are gone.
Now I'm gonna create nine files and to create nine falls.
I'll use the command touch as you know,
the touches.
A command to use.
And then there's a wild card,
another oil card that's called curly Braces.
So I was creating filed A B C d curly braces one dot dot nine because I'm gonna create nine
files.
So this curly braces 1.9 selling create nine files that has digit one through nine and Dash
X Y z.
When I run this command,
what do you think that I will have listed in my home directory?
I will have nine files right here at the bottom.
You'll see.
I have nine files.
Awesome,
right?
This is what you wanted to do?
It is much more faster to do in the wild card as opposed to typing what by one.
So let's use the gastric.
It what?
I just want to list every file name that starts with a B.
C.
You do ABC ass trick,
and you will have all the files that starts with a B.
C.
I want to remove every file that starts with a B.
You could remove one by one a B,
C D.
One and so on and so forth again.
Very cumbersome.
Don't do it.
Your system administrator.
You are smart folks.
You don't want to use the commands one by one.
What do you would use?
You use a wild card so you'll do a,
B,
C D or a B.
And to Astra the reason I picked the four letters.
Because if I just pick a and hit Asterix,
it will also remove any other files in my home directory that starts with a and which I
don't want to do it right now.
I don't have any file.
So let's say if I create a touch A So now I have all the files and a so I just want confirm
I don't have a so I don't delete any file accidentally.
So yes,
I don't have any.
Father begins with a other than these.
So if I just do it removed a Asterix ever removed all the files that starts with Kate.
Let's check it.
See,
all those files are gone.
Isn't that cool?
Yes,
it is.
I love this asteroid because I use it all the time.
I'm gonna recreate those files again by heard hitting up arrow key that will return my last
ran command.
Just confirm they're there now.
What if I wanted to remove everything that ends with X y z?
Same way removed.
But this time we'll put Asterix in front off X Y z it enter.
Boom!
All gone.
Awesome!
I'm gonna recreate it just for the exercise off this lesson.
It created nine files.
Now we'll want to the next wild card.
But is the question mark,
The next question mark is telling it ls minus.
L question Mark B C d pastoring.
Okay,
what am I asking here?
I'm asking is gave me all the files that has whatever the character is the first,
as long as the other characters has B,
C,
D.
And whatever comes afterwards,
these are the matching files because whatever the first characters weathers a or not,
I don't care.
I just want to make sure I will get the listing of the files that has B,
C.
D.
And after the So that's how you use the question Mark and the last one we have brackets
bracket is gonna tell me that gives me anything that has C or D letter in a file.
It's just that simple either.
See,
either d either f or this and that.
So you put all that stuff that you're looking for inside of the bracket and you will have
all those files you see here.
And it went so fast,
I'm gonna put it in mawr.
Put.
I want to see one page at a time and you'll see it gave me.
And it has a has be every file that I'm getting as either has A or B either has A or B.
So that's how it works.
That's how wild card works again.
Now I want to get rid of all the files that has,
um why x and y in it.
Awesome.
I have my wild card.
I'm not gonna go into leave one by one.
So this command is telling the show that go head and please delete all the files that has X
and Y in it.
And X and Y has to be together,
Of course.
So we do have these matching files X y,
and it was good and delete it,
and all of them are gone.
So while card not necessarily is used just with LS or removed,
you could use it that any of the commands you we have.
You could use it with all the commands we have learned so far.
Try it,
try it with different commands.
If it doesn't work,
that's OK.
Go online.
Google it and try wild clad while Clark Examples Try them.
Just get familiar with them.
This will help you a lot in your job,
I promise you.