Hello and welcome to log monitoring.
Lesson Another and most important way off system administration is logged.
Monitors.
Think of a lot of monitor in a way as if you have.
If you have your person,
physician or a doctor,
every time you go to him,
he or she has a chart on you,
which the record of your medical history,
which tells the doctor What are the problems you had in the past,
whether you had any surgery,
whether you're allergic to any medicine,
said That is the way doctors keep logs on your physical health.
Just like that,
systems also have to keep logs and generate logs and record everything that goes on with
the system.
So in our log directory right here in our learning system,
the primary log directory is war and slash long.
All the logs that are generated on UNIX machines are mainly in warlock directory,
unless specified or changed in the configuration file owner often application to change the
law location.
Um,
a few off the logs of evil Kovar in this lesson are one number one is boot boot is the log
.
When your system boots up reboots,
it generates this long and records everything that goes on to your system.
How it cleans up the memory.
What the process is starting up.
If it hasn't,
if it is having any issues,
it will log everything in there.
Then you have crony D,
which is a newer version off.
NTP has its own log.
Cron may law secure logs.
The next one we have the messages.
Long messages is one of the important logs that every system in Mr uses to monitor system
activities,
everything that is a hardware wise application,
wise or process wise,
anything that has to do with the systems or even application wise,
it goes into war long messages.
Then at the last one we have http D,
which is also an Apache application law.
So without further do I log into my Lennox machine,
I log it as myself.
I already have an I p that I specified.
Um,
so once I log in,
I will go into war slash log directory.
When I am in slash lock directory,
I could go on Ellis minus l command or simply wrong.
Hell,
l and you all the locks.
And once again,
when I run that it has so many logs,
so many files,
so many directories that I cannot view them all on one page.
So I'll do this El Pipe it to more and you will see l l will list all the files by
alphabetical orders.
So the 1st 1 is our did audit Aziz.
One of the files are directory that has all the other information.
Then we have boot dot log.
Let's look at book dot log When you do more on food,
don't log.
I get in message days permission denied.
Why do I get that message?
Because the Buddha log is owned by route and the group who owns that while is also route.
So am I root.
Who am I?
I'm not route.
OK,
so if I'm not ruled to do I have the permission to read the file and as others I should
have read permission right here,
right last three bits.
Or if I'm part of the group,
I should be as you have access here.
So neither group nor regular ordinary users has access.
Read a file,
so only root hasn't.
So we will become route.
Go back to our log and we'll do poop dot lock when I hit.
Enter,
you'll see on the left side.
It is coming up with OK messages.
While system is booting up every time there is an issue with the system booting up,
it will come up with a message saying falls or error or alert.
So you'll see.
It is starting all the services one by one.
It is starting all the processes.
Welcome to Cento Islamic seven.
It's going through each step off the spooks startup and when it starts up completely,
it stops the log.
When you reboot your system this file,
which is let's find L Buddha log.
This file gets over written,
So if I reboot my machine right now,
it will generate a newer file and it will rewrite the speak boot dot log.
Okay,
so the next one we have a Z Ronnie crony is a placement of NTP service,
any type off changes that we make on the crony service.
It actually generates that long and actually locks that information into the logs.
Next one we have in the list is craun.
If you look at it on the left hand side,
I'm just going by what I have listed,
there are many other files.
And if you have time And if you are interested in learning all these different logs,
then please be my guest.
Try out every command.
I'm sorry.
Try of everybody and see what they are used for.
Um,
the next one I want to cover is the KRON,
which is right here.
You,
whenever you're scheduled,
a job or a process through a Cron tab entry,
it generates some kind of activity.
And that activity,
that record is logged into this file so you could do Kron.
And you will see all the information about the Koran.
And by the way,
whenever you open up a log while the first is the month,
second is the date.
Time the name off your host.
Name the demon,
which is crawling D and process.
I d associated with that demon.
Their user Who's running that and the command or the entry that has been associated with
the Kronk moving on.
Um,
we have the next one we have quickly.
There is a command called the message.
Even you run this command.
This one also gives you information about the hardware.
If you do not want to run this command,
you could simply to cat on the messages as well,
which will give you the exact same information.
The next one we have is may log.
Male log has all the information about your send mill demon,
which means every time you send an email out or every time in the email comes and all that
activity is being recorded in this law,
whenever you are troubleshooting issues with send mail service,
this is one of the laws you would have to look into to see why you are where your service
not able to send e mails moving on.
Then we have secure log right here.
Now,
secure logs is the log that actually records all your logging in logging out activity.
So when you doom or on secure,
you'll see all the users that have been long then if they have failed logging in or if they
from which machine there logging in all the information about the users.
So I am.
What I'm gonna do is I'm gonna do tail minus Steph now minus F is the option that will keep
on sniffing the log.
And every time a new record is updated to the log,
that tail minus f will get that newest long at the bottom.
So if I do tail minus f,
um,
secure and I'll keep running this command,
this command is running.
Now I'm gonna open up another session,
another party session I have already saved.
And if I log in as myself and I type in wrong password,
let's say as soon as I type wrong password you see in the background,
it stays right here.
Failed a password for I assault.
And I'm trying to log in from this machine one night,
1 61.8 If I log back in with the correct password,
then I will get that additional record for my sessions in session open for user.
I have solved.
So this is about the secure disc,
your log file and the next one is one of the most important log file that you should spend
your time and is messages.
Every time there's an issue with your machine,
the first thing an administrator does they long into your machine and they will trace logs
in messages while so you go into see you are logged and then you doom or messages.
Now this file has again once again this while has all the hardware,
information,
all the software information,
all the application information,
all the processes,
information everything is being logged into this log.
So if I wanted to see how many lines this log file has,
I could do cat messages and wc minus help will see,
I have 7001 or three lines if I wanted to see if they are any error messages in this file.
So the group minus I I is to ignore upper case,
lower case from messages fall and you will see it actually grabbed every line inside of
this log file that has a message called Error.
So this way you could go in and see what's going on.
Reduced system.
What happened?
Why it failed,
what time it failed.
So anyway,
let's wrap up the lesson and again,
spend some time in this war.
Log messages go over all these log files,
specifically the ones I have in this lesson and see what type of different laws there are.
View them group for certain errors and get yourself familiar with them.