file transfer.
There are many commands that are used to transfer files from one computer to another.
As long as you computer is connected in the network,
you could transfer files or directories for once over to another.
Some off those commands are FTP,
which stands for file transfer protocol.
This is one of the old legendary commands that are used in many different up operating
system.
It is still used in Lenox,
Windows and Mac and many other offering system.
This command is used next one we have SCP,
which is a secure copy protocol.
And then the next one is our sink command.
This command is mostly used by system administrator to perform ah files backups from one
system to another.
They could schedule those commands through Cron job to copy all those sink our sync files.
So let's look at a few off these commands in our links environment.
Here we have our links machine and I'm logged in as myself.
So when you want to copy ah,
fire,
let's say I want to copy file that is called my first file.
The first thing I have to do is type FTP and the machine named that it's going to,
which is a destination server.
Okay,
so as an example to ftp ah,
file from your server to another server I have logged into my legs machines myself and
we'll see who you are.
You are self.
So before you try to do a trash for just see if you could paying Google because without
Internet,
you won't be able to transfer any file now I could paying Google.
It means my computer is on the network now.
Where do we have to trash for?
And what do we have to trash for now,
of course,
you do need a server that is running ftp demon.
Meaning your so for your client and a server that you're trying to connect should have FTP
demon running and a demon name is V s ftp deep for this training.
We do not have an extra external ftp,
so we will try to connect to the red Hat FTP server just for training purposes.
So the command to run is FTP.
It's based FDP dot red hat dot com and you will see as soon as you're connected it will ask
you for the past words for the user name and password.
So you provide the credentials that are given to you by the red hat,
Um,
support.
So when you end to the password and user name,
then you will enter the command put and the final aim.
And that's how it will be Trash Ford to,
um,
to the FTP site.
Now,
if you're trying to trash for to a server that is not running the FDP demon.
So let's say in our environment we have PS minus CF and we'll grow up for FDP and you will
see there is no FTP Damon running right.
So as a training purpose will cry to trash for FDP toe our own server.
And our own server is local host or the name off our host,
which is my first Lennox host legs os.
So first,
if you ping my first Lennox,
the less you'll see you are getting your apply back,
right?
So it means you are connected to your own machine.
Of course,
let's clear it out.
And now I try to do ftp my first Lennox os and they use hit enter.
You will see it says connect ftp connect.
Connection refused.
And why is that?
Because my server are My Lennox machine is not running the demon and the demon is the one
that listens to the incoming traffic.
So anyway,
this is how you run the FTP command and you transfer the files.
And again,
the purpose off doing FTP is if you have a new issue with your system and you
troubleshooting it and you involve,
um support,
whether it's red hat are sent OS or windows.
Whatever the support that you have involved,
they would ask you to send the locks and they will give you the FTP server account
information and credentials.
So you would have to run FTP Command to send the logs over the other Commander V wanted to
cover is SCP.
Now,
SCP is basically copping ah,
file from one machine to another and of course,
this has s in front of us.
It means is copping it securely.
So let's take an example off a file that we will want to transfer.
Let's see,
was directly were in.
We're in our home directory and let's say I have a file called right here la la land.
So I wanted to take this file copy it from machine a two machine.
Be now.
Of course,
we don't have machine be where you want to transfer.
So we was use our own machine and pretend that it's a remote machine.
So the way it works is we'll do a CP la la Land,
which is the file that I'm trying to copy.
Or so where am I trying to copy?
Or I'm trying to copy over to another machine remorse machine.
So we're pretending they're more machine is,
which is our own machine.
Of course,
my first Lennox owe us.
And then you put Colon,
which is first,
is a host name slash Where are you copying it to?
So let's say I wanted to copy it to my home,
my user directory and the director.
You want a copy to,
Let's say,
Seinfeld,
Seinfeld.
It's a directory of wine to copy that file into that folder.
So once you have that command hit enter and it says could not resolve host name my first
Linux os,
Uh oh,
yeah,
because I have miss build first.
These are the type of things that you probably would have to troubleshoot you enter.
Um,
my first,
the Knicks O s still have coming up.
So what we do is we'll just take out this part.
So I'm just gonna What I'm gonna do is I'm gonna copy this,
and I'm gonna paste it and then hit.
Enter.
Okay,
So it is saying that connect to host my first Linux OS port 22.
Connection refused.
So it is refusing a connection.
Why is it refusing?
Not sure,
but let's try to do local host.
Yes.
So you put in the password,
of course.
Your own password.
Because you're logging in as yourself on the machine as well.
This is your own password.
So once you put in the past where you will see it,
say's LA LA Land 100% completed seven bites and the right,
and it's 70.5 kilobytes per second.
This is amount of time it took to trash.
So did transferred.
Now let's where if I if Seinfeld directory has the LA LA land file in it.
So which director I'm in?
I'm in home.
I observe,
Let's go to sign fill.
And now Ellis to do ls myself to your and you'll see.
Yep,
Right here is his la la land.
Very,
um,
Just to confirm that they that see host?
Um,
my first Lennox O s.
So it has one eye to 1 $61.14 Okay,
so now I know.
So this one,
I have hard coded my host name with 19 to 1 68 $1.14 And I'm sure why didn't work?
Because my I p has probably changed by now.
So it's probably hating some other device in my never and you see?
Yes,
it Now my limits machine is one about 13.
And the reason I was not able to connect because $1.14 is probably one of my other laptop
or my iPad or some other device in my home network that got that got 14 i p.
And when I ran the SCP command,
it was actually going to Dad device Perfect.
It was a very good example.
Now,
you guys learn as well that how important s a tse while host father's,
I'll go ahead and modify that have become route,
and I'll do V I at C host,
and I'll just take these two entries out.
I'll just leave these two in close.
So now if you run that command that we were trying to run before hit a barrow.
Kia Paro key?
No,
Sorry.
We work as locked in his herself.
Right.
So now when you run that command,
you will see it will give us a prompt.
They go see right that this was the one,
right?
You hit.
Enter.
See?
It's connected.
The next one is our sink.
And this will tell you exactly if I just type are single.
Tell you how you go.
Copy falls.
If you just want to itemize the changes,
it will also tell you the progress Self it so this command is used.
Um,
it's a very famous command now,
and it is used by many system engineers to do and to perform while systems back up.