welcome to the new section off shell scripting basics.
That's where we actually will learn.
What really a shell scripting is what are its basics?
You know,
starting from ABC or 123 So that's where we're going to start.
So let's see,
what exactly are we going to co were in this entire section?
So we will start with Colonel.
What,
exactly?
Colonel is.
And how does it interacts with the shell?
And is there a colonel in operating system?
And how does it interact with your hardware?
And how does it interact?
Was your shell and your operating system?
What exactly Shell there's.
Of course,
this is the main thing.
We wanted to know how the shell scripting works.
There are so many types of shells,
there are corn shell there,
bash.
There are,
um,
seashell and so many that I will cover in this lesson.
Then we will have starting to show how you gonna start a shell if you are in logged into
into your links machine and by default,
you have a bash shell and you want to say sure,
definite show.
How do you do that,
then,
Wilko?
Or how you gonna run a shell script.
So you have created a script.
Now how do you run it?
So this is a few things Very basic ones that you should really know.
And this is like a fundamental things that you should understand and put it somewhere you
know,
deep in your head that outside of the thes are like a actual guidelines that you have to
follow in order to run.
Ah,
perfect shell script.
So you would know when if there is an error message or if there's a problem when you're
running a shell script,
why did it happen?
This section will explain you if you really go through it.