Lennox operating system Hardening.
This is a lesson about how can you can secure your Linux operating system Well,
there are many different ways that you could secure your operating system,
so it it is not vulnerable to the wires is attacks or anything that could harm your system
.
So this is also one of the most important topic and Lennox,
and many times the recruiters or hiring manager will ask you this question about how do you
secure your lending system,
or how do you harden your operating system?
There are few,
many different ways you could.
Even if you go online,
you'll find a lot of different ways.
But I think the most basic ones that anyone should really know Rs Fall The 1st 1 is about
the account management.
How do you secure the user accounts,
one of the policy of standard that you have in place.
Then we will cover about remove unwanted packages all the package that you have installed
in your system.
If you don't know need them,
then why do you keep them to remove them?
Then we have to stop unused services.
If a service is running that is not required in your system.
Stop it,
toss it.
Check on listening.
Port some off the time we have pores that are listening for traffic for incoming traffic.
But we really don't need any off those incoming traffic.
So what do you do to stop secure?
Ssh configuration will cover their later enable firewall I p tables,
which is all the words in and firewalled in the newer version,
Of course,
again,
the Wilco in detail on how we could enable I firewall in our system to make our system more
secure as the Lennox A ceilings is in your feature,
um,
that you'll cover also as poor off this lesson changing listing service support numbers.
So,
for example,
if your report is running on,
let's say ssh 22 you could change it to a different port.
So the hacker who knows that you know the port 22 runs for ssh when they tried,
they are getting refused then,
alas,
but not the least.
Keep your system up to date,
so you should have all the security patches itself.
So let's cover them all of them one by one,
log into the next system.
So I have here Lennox Machine.
I logged in through the council.
So the first thing that we talked about is about user account management.
How can we secure that?
Well,
the first thing that I should include in this is about the naming convention.
When you create a user name,
for example,
oracle or admin,
I recommend everyone to know I use the standard Jews UNAIDS because it's very easy to
predict those,
um,
there's used name.
So instead of oracle,
you pick like oracle.
123 or 123 oracle instead of admin,
you pick t admin or s admin.
So how do we get the all these names you go at sea?
Um,
the password file and you will see the listing off all the users that we have in our system
.
You see here on 1st 1 call them before the colon.
We have the user name like Spider Man spider.
That's my name.
And many other,
like NFs scrawny eso.
You could change the user name to a different name,
so it's not easily guessed.
Another way,
I would say,
is by default.
When when a user is created,
when you run the command user,
add when you create a user.
It automatically assigns Jews variety,
which usually starts with three digits or are four digits,
with 1002 on.
So I would also recommend or industry standard that to use anything from 10,000 bucks.
This way,
it's not hard to guess.
Another way is about the password policies now had.
Often,
your password changes how long your password should be.
All the information can be looked at by running the command CH age,
which has changed age.
If you do,
minus L on the user name,
which is myself,
you'll see right here last password change.
This is the time,
and I change my password.
Password expired.
Never password inactive,
so passport expired.
Never.
It's not a good sign,
since this is a lab environment is for training purposes.
I don't really care.
But in a corporate environment and production environment,
there should be a date to change the password.
Same thing goes for an active password.
Account expires.
When does it pass work?
What expires a number of days off warning before password expires,
and so on.
All that information can be changed.
You could set your own standard.
Depending on your company's requirement.
You could run ch age commanded.
Dash does help to find more information.
How you could make those changes for each user.
Also,
if you go to that see shadow file,
you will see um,
permission tonight after we root.
If you can't out that see shadow file,
you will see each user has issues.
The name it's past for at the end of the past were in this colon It has these numbers thes
are the same numbers that we have defined and change age.
You could change by David this command see a change or you could coast directly to the etc
Shadow bottom Make the change we'll see here.
This seven refers to this seven this 999 1st this 9990 refers to this zero so you could get
more information about how you could change whether you could do through the etc shadow R c
.
It changed age.
I would before the Hughes change age.
Anyway,
um,
moving forward also another come another file that you should look at is etc.
Log in on deaths.
This is to file that she could also define some of the parameters.
Andi,
those parameters are That's look open the file again and you will see here.
Maximum pass from baxam days.
Thes are the default settings.
You could do it by per user basis.
Or if you want,
apply to a default setting.
You could use it here.
See,
Pastor,
minimum length five.
If you if a user is putting a password and,
um,
for that it's not gonna accept it.
So it has to be five.
But of course,
over a command.
Go at least 12 or 13 and change it right here.
You could also disabled old password.
Another file that actually manages user accounts and security is at sea.
Pandey the directory and file system off.
Um,
and you look at this file.
It has a lot of other parameters that you could define.
I want you to spend some time here or even look it up online and study every field off this
file to understand exactly how this works.
Um,
next one we have is above remove unwanted,
um,
packages.
Right.
So how do we get the listing off all the packages to get to the single packages?
I think you should know that if you have forgot,
that's fine.
R P M minus Qiwei and then you hit,
Enter and you had enter.
You get a bunch of list of all the packages.
Now,
how many packages do I have in my system so that it's just like a quiz for you?
So tell me how many packages were?
Well,
the commander's rpm that's Q A.
WC minus l.
And this will count every line output of our pm que it?
I have a total number of packaged 1350.
So there are so many package that I really don't need it.
So what do we need it for?
Won't get rid of them.
So to get rid of a package the commander's R P m minus E and the package name.
So also,
remember,
when you are deleting a package,
it will ask you that this package has a dependency on another package to be very careful on
on that,
if you remove the package,
it and it and that package has dependencies on another package or other packages.
Dependencies.
On this one,
you will have some corruption and some programs that won't work properly,
So just be careful.
Then we have.
The next one is stop unused services.
Okay,
How do we kid?
What the listing off all the services of your running.
If you run system CTL,
dash A,
this will give you everything active or inactive.
So if there is a service that is active and you really don't need it,
you could just simply stop it.
If a system is serving the pages,
why do you need NFS service on it?
Right.
So that's why we stopped the source's.
Then the next one we have here is about check on listening ports.
Now,
how do we check on the listening ports?
Every service that you run has a port associated with it.
So if you run,
that's that base dash t you in l.
P.
What?
Why am I picking these Pacific options is just that that I've been used to it.
You could pick different options to check the ports.
When I enter,
you will see all the ports that are open and listening right now.
See hairs.
I p address right here.
And this is my local.
I'd be and again,
this is my local I p.
And you'll see everything that after that has of these port 111 53 22 6 31 25 Tell me what
53 is for.
That's a quest.
Well,
if you don't remember,
53 is for DNS.
And as I said,
DNS,
what port it runs on.
Also one of the important question.
So if you if you if your machine is not serving us a DNS,
why do we have a 53 port running to stop it?
The next one we have is about securing as a sage configuration.
Now,
if you know that when you log into system remotely what protocol you use,
you use a sous age and on the poor 22.
So this could be secured as well.
So if you go to CD slash ssh And then there was a file called S H D config.
And then you had entered more on it.
You will see this fall can be modified,
and a lot of its parameters can be modified to make a cessation more secure.
And what are those things that can be modified?
The two basic ones that I usually make changes to is number one is I change the port.
So right now,
if you see the port is running on 22 I would change it to 10 22 of which over the port that
I would like to have sold.
My system is more secure.
Another thing that I like to do whenever a building system is I go in and I enable this
right now.
You see here,
this one has hash sign anything that starts with hash.
It's a common.
So I will take out this hash sign and I'll say,
Permit root log in and I have the same No.
Why?
Because if I'm logging in or if anybody's logging into the system as route,
it will deny it.
They should log in as themselves,
and this way they could become your route.
The reason behind this is because every time a user logs in,
let's say if I log and my activity will be long dead at the time and I logging in and what
time I became crude,
so all that tracking information will be recorded and it will be a lot easier to understand
who did what to the system.
So these are a couple of things I will do with the message configuration.
Then we have enable firewall when the firewall,
As I said,
There are older version of firewall that Courant's In Grete Had six and older is called I P
Tables.
The newer version Off Firewall with seven and above its firewall D both serves the same
function.
The viral D has a few and has functions.
You could look it up again.
If you want to learn more about firewall now,
I could tell you what firewall does.
Fly woman.
You have it enabled in your system.
What it does is that you could filter out meaning if you want to only accept the traffic
that coming in one or 22 you couldn't tell firewalls.
A firewall.
Onley.
Accept traffic coming in for port 22 or only accept traffic coming in for port 1 23 or 423
Anything that you want to make the changes to firewall anything you want,
the service of it running so far,
what is like a ah watchdog,
said defender,
our gatekeeper for your system,
which allows someone or traffic to come in or and it allows the traffic to leave the
commands that you need to know for firewall,
as in Gui in the newer version off Lenox.
If you are using Google,
you go run firewall dash,
convict it enter and you will see it will bring up a gooey.
This gooey will let you enable services.
That's your navel ports add ports.
Remove protocols are at poor cause.
If you see if you want to add important,
let's say if you enable firewall on your system by default,
it will block everything.
So once you enable firewall,
it's not gonna talk anybody outside.
It's not gonna talk.
Have anybody talking to you.
So how do you enable the communication?
You add the ports?
Click on add.
You put the port number.
Let's say I want everyone to talk to me on I'm a DNS server.
So talk to me with 52 three.
I'm allowing it.
That's good.
Click OK and good.
Perfect.
So that's how the firewall or I P table works in your system.
And that has cool.
What if I do not have agreed?
Okay for that,
there's another command for Text Bake based on Command Line Command,
which is firewall that CMD voyages for command.
And then you do help.
You'll get a lot of information.
How do you find Or how do you square your How do you remove a port in all the words in B
Have the command I p tables.
So then you had tea tables.
You could just to help.
And you will see all the information that you have right now if you enable the i p services
and then you run i p tables Daschle list of a list,
All the services anyway,
the configuration file for I p tables,
Theo.
Older version is at sea This config i p and six convicted complaint file his i p tables
convict.
And this is a father you could go in and modified.
If you don't want to modify through the command line,
you can modify through the file and then restart the services.
In the newer version,
the file name is etc.
Firewall the I'm sorry.
Uh,
that see Firewall D is the director and the fire.
What is firewall d dot com?
This is the one that you could modified.
Then we'll move on to the next one about securing our system,
which is change.
Sorry.
Enabled S e Lennox.
Now what is a c?
Lennox?
Let me read you something really off the Internet are standard definition off SC,
Lennox,
etc.
Lennox stands for security and has Lennox is a security architecture integrated into the
$2.6 ex colonel using the living security module,
also known as L S M.
It is a project off the United States National Security Agency,
which is stands for S A or bridges are everywhere.
There's and I say and the SL in his community excellence integration in to read had links.
Enterprise Voice was a joint effort between the NSA and the Readiness s Olympics.
Defines the access and transition.
Writes off every user,
every application process and a file the system on.
So if you have ah,
if you know every offering system has an application,
it has a process.
It has a file,
its as user.
Right.
So we have talked about these user permissions on how we change it.
We change it to the change mod right now.
How do we change the permission of a process?
How do we change the permission of an application,
right?
No,
that's not possible with the operating system.
So what we did?
We have this SC Lennox which controls the access that the permission,
access off process and application.
And it goes deep,
deep down in the detail and control every access off the pot.
The configuration part If you wanted to make sorry,
if you want to make a c Lennox enable the first thing you have to do is run as C status to
make sure if it's running or not.
And if you do s east at us,
you see,
in my system as e Lennix status is enable Now,
a lot of companies that have worked in the past and a lot of people that I've talked to,
um,
they usually keep S c Lennox disabled,
which I understand because many times that computers are there in why am I running in a
private network so that they really don't need it?
Plus,
s ceilings is a very newer technology,
and it's it is a bit complicated when implemented in your system.
So you have to have ah,
very detail on better understanding for SLX.
So if you want to disable it,
you all you have to do is go to see it says config,
and you do the I.
I'm just doing more for now and you will see right here.
Let me clear the screen so there won't be,
um,
confusion when you look at it.
So you see right here anything that has hash sciences,
of course,
is common.
So you see,
right here said at Sea Lennox equal enforcing.
It means it is enforced and it's enabled.
And there are three modes off a salon X one is enforcing,
which means the A seal next security policies enforced right then the second is permissive
,
which is telling that a seal inexistent prints warning but does not enforce policies.
So if someone in making any changes,
it'll print hate.
Something was going on,
but it's not going to stop it.
Then there's another one.
The last one is,
of course,
is the disabled,
which disables at sea Lennox so you could change it here.
And once you have it,
it is recommended that you reboot your system.
Eso to check the parameters of a file,
for example.
Let's say if I go to my home directory and these are the files and directories I have,
So if I just do status or just started just at and I do,
let's say I have this file called La La Land.
You will see right here.
It tells me everything about the ball falls named the size the block the I'll block and
right here says access,
which is read,
write,
execute,
Right?
We already covered that.
And if not,
then you already know that it is like it could be defined.
Changed mod command.
Now,
if you noticed right here,
this is a new thing.
Context to this Pacific file is defined,
but the object is use your home.
So that's how the Assyrians keep track off which directly belongs to which user or rich
file.
And it also gives you access,
modify birth changed on all the different information we could change on Lee the read,
write and execute,
right?
But all that additional stuff,
if you want to have it,
that could be done with SLX.
Anyway,
there are other commands that I want you to look into it,
which I will not cover here,
which is because SC Lennox is a huge topic just for your knowledge or to have you haven't
somewhat exposure.
You should know what s C Lennox is.
So anyway,
some of the Commander Vasily nixes C h con which change file Assulin security context.
Then we have checked policy Nature is a selects policy compiler and the other ones are new
Role set SC bull set SC pool fix files as he manage and so many of the commands that I will
not cover here.
Also,
I have attached some documentation which you could read.
So this is about as c Lennox.
Now,
this second to the last part that I want to color is about change Listing service parole
officer with port numbers.
Now also,
I covered that a little bit on the SC.
Sorry,
a sausage configuration where you could change from port 22 2 different ports.
You could also make the same change to other services.
For example,
DNS by default run on 53 right?
You could make that changes as well to make your system more secure.
And the last one is about keep your operating system up to date Now it doesn't mean you
just go online and do junk update all and just update everything.
All the packages that you have,
you don't have to do or you don't have to update every package,
but you do have to make sure.
Especially anything that is related to security.
You have to update.
And how do we keep on up to date with the security?
Well,
one thing is you keep on running on Young Abdel updated.
Right?
But that's isn't the right way to do it.
Well,
what I do,
I could tell use.
I keep myself up to date with,
uh,
with all the alerts that I get from red hat or sento us or even windows.
Every time there is an issue of there's a new pash that comes out,
I can't notified.
I have an email,
so I would recommend you to do the same.
Go ahead and sign up one redhead dot com on santo esta.
Soon as you get any off those updates going apply.
That's how you keep your system secure.
Anyway,
um,
this is about how you could do your system secure or always hardening if you cover
everything here in detail.
And if someone is asking your question,
trust me.
You're gonna ace it if you go over this.
All right.
Good luck