Setting up a Java EE application demands a few manual steps.
First of all,
we need to create an application folder for the
entire code and configuration files,
then because we need Maven we need to create a Maven
directory structure and add a pom.
xml file.
In this configuration file we need to install the Java EE dependencies and add
minimum number of Java code so we are sure our setup is okay.
These steps are time consuming and error prone.
To save some time, we will rely on Maven and its Maven archetype.
The Maven archetype is a project templating toolkit providing a
consistent mean of generating Maven projects.
Using archetypes provides a great way to get developers up
and running as quickly as possible by providing a sample
project using best practices.
We can either create our own archetypes or reuse existing ones.
Because Java EE is quite famous there are plenty of
Java EE archetypes out there.
I'll be using one from the codehouse foundation.
Let's talk about the standard Maven directory structure
of our bookstore-back Java EE app.
By convention all the application files are located under the folder src.
Here we find this src/main/Java directory where we have all our Java EE code.
The Java EE configuration goes under resources and
the web resources under webapp.
That's for the code of the application.
Then under src/test/Java we find our test classes,
the ones we will be writing later.
When Maven compiles and packages our code,
it uses the target directory to store the generated artifacts.
At the root of the project we have the main pom.
xml configuration file.
That's where we'll find the dependencies to Java EE,
our in-memory database H2, and our testing frameworks,
JUnit and Arquillian.
Let's have a closer look at our pom.
xml file.
In Maven everything needs a groupId, an artifactId, and a version.
I could have picked up any other names, but these ones make kind of sense.
Then we need to specify the packaging,
being a web application we ask Maven to package our code
and dependencies in a web archive.
Finally comes the dependencies,
that's in this section that we'll be adding all the needed dependencies.
We'll start with Java EE 7 and slowly add more dependencies as our code grows.
End of talking, let's dive into the command line.
In this demo I'll bootstrap our application with a Maven archetype.
Remember that our application is called BookStore.
It is split into two,
the Java EE REST API's bookstore-back and the Angular bookstore-front.
Maven is only used on the backend.
Because Maven needs coordinates, I've chosen the GroupId com.
Pluralsight.
javee-getting-started and for the ArtifactId bookstore-back.
Let's go.
So here we are in front of the terminal.
I'm in the directory JavaeeGettingStarted and now I'm going to use a Maven
archetype to bootstrap an empty Java EE application.
Here I have this very long Maven command.
You should pause the video now, look at the read me file,
and copy/paste this very long command that basically uses a Maven
archetype to create our application with a groupId,
getting started, ArtifactId bookstore-back,
a version, and here I'm passing a few commands to generate the application.
Here we go.
Well that was quite quick.
Let's look at what Maven has created for me.
First of all, there's this bookstore-back directory and if I have a look into it,
I can see the pom.
xml file and the src directory.
Following the Maven directory structure,
src/main/Java with a package com/Pluralsight/bookstore,
and because it's a web application it has an index HTML page.
The pom.
xml has the minimal needed dependencies,
Java EE 7 with the right groupId, artifactId,
number and packaging.
This pom.
xml is enough for now.
But throughout the modules we will add more dependencies.
Now Java EE application is bootstrapped,
completely empty, but let's compile, package it and run it so we are sure this code works.