Remember when we used Maven archetypes to bootstrap our Java EE application?
We did that to save some time, but also to avoid configuration errors.
For our Angular application we will do the same thing using
Angular CLI instead of Maven archetypes.
So instead of going through a long list of manual setup,
Angular CLI will create the application directory,
also create the Node.
JS directory structure and all the needed configuration files.
Angular CLI will then use Yarn to install all the Angular dependencies and
despite generating all the setup files and boilerplate code,
Angular CLI will add some TypeScript code so our
application can display some text on the browser.
This is a higher view of bootstrapping an Angular application.
Let's now dive into command lines.
Angular CLI is much richer than Maven archetypes.
You can execute a set of commands with several options to
make it easy to create an application that works and follows
best practices out of the box.
On a terminal we just execute the ng command followed by different options.
For example, ng version gives us the version of Angular CLI we are using.
To create a new project we just type ng new and the name of the project,
here bookstore-front.
If we don't want to generate test files, we just use skip-tests option.
If we want Angular CLI to generate some routing between our components,
we add routing true.
And then we have several commands to create Angular artifacts.
For example, ng generate component generates a graphical component with HTML,
CSS, and TypeScript files under the right location.
Here the component is called book-list and I can specify that I
don't want the test class to be generate and that I don't want a
separate CSS file for this component.
Same thing to generate a service,
one ng generate command with a service parameter and the name of the service,
and we are done.
Angular CLI allows us to generate code for components,
services, pipes, modules, guards, and so on.
If you need some help,
just type ng help and if you need help on specific commands,
ng help and the name of the command.
Let's talk about the directory structure that is generated by Angular CLI.
On top we see the node_modules directory.
That's where the project's dependencies are downloaded and installed by Yarn.
By convention, all the application files are located under the folder src/app.
Angular CLI creates a few files for us.
App.
component.
html and.
ts are respectively the HTML representation and the
TypeScript code of our main component.
We won't talk about Angular models in this course,
as this is an advanced topic, but notice the app.
module TypeScript file to configure our Main and only module.
App-routing.
module deals with routing, as we'll see later.
The index.
html page is our entry point.
This is the HTML page that will be loaded in the browser.
In terms of configuration, we have a few files.
First, the angular-cli.
json file.
It's all about the Angular CLI configuration.
What is the name of the application?
What's the name of the source directory?
The output directory?
The name of the main HTML pages in CSS file and so on.
We will update this file to include Twitter Bootstrap into our application.
Then we have the package.
json configuration file.
This Node.
JS file holds various metadata relevant to the project,
such as the project description, it's version,
license and so on.
Last but not least, the yarn.
lock file is used by Yarn to specify dependency versions.
The package.
json is the configuration file of any Node.
JS application and therefore Angular.
It is the JSON file that contains information about the project and
configuration details used by Yarn to build a project.
We find the name of our project is version,
company name, open source license, and so on.
Then we find a script section.
This is very handy to write our own scripts.
Angular CLI creates a few default ones, start being the mostly used.
To execute our application, we will have to ask Yarn to execute the script start,
which is just a shortcut for ng serve as we will see in the next demo.
Then, the dependencies of our application.
Angular CLI has already set all the needed Angular dependencies.
We will just add Twitter Bootstrap,
but other than that the list of the dependencies is the one we need,
angular/core, angular/compiler, and so on.
By the way, notice that in Java EE the configuration files are written in XML.
In Angular JSON is preferred.
Back to the command line,
we'll now use a single command ng new to scaffold and entire application.
And by default, ng new just needs one parameter,
the name of the project, in our case it will be bookstore-front.
So if we execute ng new bookstore-front,
Angular CLI will apply all the defaults and generate a running application.
But I'm going to customize slightly these default values.
First of all,
I find the word bookstore-front a little bit too verbose for our components.
So I'm going to use the prefix bs like bookstore, but shorter.
We will come across this prefix pretty soon.
Because this course is mostly about Java EE and not Angular,
I will skip testing.
Testing an Angular application is a course on its own.
So I'll use the skip-tests and skip-e2e options.
This will not generate test classes nor end to end tests.
I choose to inline CSS style sheet.
This means that our components will not have a separate CSS file.
Again, I want to make it easy.
And because in module 14 we will work with routers,
I'll also enable the routing true flag so we have routes to play with.
We're all set now, let's switch to the terminal.
So IntelliJ IDEA only as the bookstore-back project.
So with Angular CLI command, I'm going to create the bookstore-front.
So here I'm doing ng new bookstore-front and I'm skipping all the tests,
read me's, get and so on.
Angular CLI is creating a few files,
Yarn is downloading all the dependencies and here we are,
now we have the bookstore-front with a node modules
directory and all the dependencies.
The src directory with the main app, the component,
so we will quickly have a look at these components.
And the few configuration files that we mentioned,
the Angular CLI and the package JSON. So now that our application is bootstrapped, let's execute it.