From 10, 000 feet high, our BookStore application looks like this,
and Angular front-end invoking a Java EE back-end.
Let's start from the Java EE back-end.
After setting up our Java EE environment and bootstrapping
our application with a Maven archetype,
we focused on the domain model of our application.
The Book entity gets mapped into an in-memory relational database.
The Book entity is just a Java class representing a
book and using JPA annotation,
so the attributes get mapped to a specific column of the table.
We then added a transactional repository to allow CRUD operation
on the Book entity as well as querying it.
The way database access works is through the EntityManager.
Once injected,
it's just a matter of calling the method find to get the Book
from the database or persist to insert it.
To do these operations in a transactional manner,
we annotate the class or the methods with the annotation
transactional and specify the right transaction policy.
Because finding by identifier is not enough,
we can use a query language to get all the books
from the database or count them, for example.
We introduced integration testing, thanks to Arquillian.
We then kept refactoring our tests throughout the modules as we
progressed in adding more features to our application,
such as validating data.
We used bean validation to constrain the Book entity attributes
and make sure that the data we persist is valid.
We also validated the methods parameters of our Book repository.
TO validate data, it's just a matter of annotating our attributes.
One annotation size and bean validation will make sure the description of a
book can't be less than 1 character and more than 10000.
We then added some business logic to our application,
Number Generator and Text Util are two utility classes used by the Book
repository to generate ISBN numbers and sanitize book titles.
To get a reference to these utilities classes we use
CDI and its @Inject annotation.
That's because, in fact, BookRepository,
NumberGenerator, and textUtil are all managed beans,
beans that are managed by the Java EE container.
Once we add all our business logic setup,
we expose it through the REST API Book Endpoint talking to the Book Repository.
We even used our browser to visualize some JSON content.
The BookEndpoint acts as a proxy.
It delegates all the calls to the BookRepository,
redefines all the methods,
and exposes them through HTTP thanks to JAX-RS annotations.
Exposing a REST API is only good if developers know how to use it.
That's when we use Swagger to document our API and generate a JSON contract.
It was just a matter of adding Swagger annotations to our BookEndpoint
and leaving a Maven plugin to generate the contract.
This contract was then later used to generate the Angular services.
Our Java EE back-end was tested and exposed a documented API.
We then entered the second part of this course,
building an Angular application to communicate with the REST API.
For that we set up our Angular development environment and
bootstrapped an empty application so we could at least visualize
a simple HTML webpage with our browser.
Then with Angular CLI we quickly generated our three components,
book-list, book-detail, and book-form,
and beautified them with Twitter Bootstrap components.
An Angular component is made of an HTML template and a TypeScript class.
The glue between the two is made through binding.
Bundling our three components into a single one wasn't what we want.
Thanks to the Angular router we easily added navigation between our components,
either by clicking on a menu or a button.
The Angular router is very rich and flexible,
it's just a matter of creating routes and using them on the HTML template,
thanks to the routerLink directive.
Finally, we managed to invoke our REST API using an Angular service and model.
The Book service uses the Angular HTTP module and its reactive
API to execute HTTP calls to our back-end.
It was then a matter of injecting the Book service
into our graphical components.
We finally have the entire pieces working together.
And thanks to our JSON contract and the Swagger CodeGen tool,
we saved a lot of time by simply generating the TypeScript code.
In terms of deployment,
we packed our Java EE application into a war file and deployed to WildFly.
The Angular application was executed in memory running in Express, which was very handy in development mode.