There are several editors that support Java EE APIs,
either out of the box or after installing a few plug-ins.
Some people use basic text editors such as Vi or Emacs,
and add a bunch of plug-ins so they get extra functionalities.
These two editors are quite basic and you can go for something richer,
such as Atom and add the right plug-ins.
But keep in mind that your developer's experience will be more pleasant
if you use an editor that fully understands Java EE,
such as Eclipse, NetBeans or IntelliJ IDEA.
For this course I'm using IntelliJ IDEA, but it's purely a personal choice.
Feel free to use the IDE you feel more comfortable with.
IntelliJ IDEA runs on Mac OS X, Linux, and Windows.
It supports both Java EE and Angular, adding code completion and refactoring,
of course, but also more advanced ones such as refactoring persistence queries,
for instance.
IntelliJ IDEA brings support for most of the Java EE APIs,
including Java persistence API, context and dependency injection,
transaction, and REST.
It also supports several testing frameworks,
including the one we'll be using, JUnit and Arquillian.
If you want to use IntelliJ IDEA with all these great features,
you will have to buy a license.
But you can also use the community edition,
which is free, but it includes less functionality.
Here is the website of IntelliJ IDEA.
IntelliJ has a Java background, but as you can see here,
under the Download button, it is actually much more than just Java.
If we scroll down the website, we see several features,
the most interesting ones is the building tools and supported frameworks.
Here you can see that IntelliJ IDEA supports Java EE as well as Angular.
And that's exactly what we want.
But as I said,
you are free to use whichever editor you want or feel more comfortable with.
If you want to use IntelliJ IDEA, take a few moments to install it. Now that we've selected our editor, let's select our building tool.