So let's start by answering this question, what is Java EE?
Java EE, or Java Enterprise Edition,
is an extension of JavaScript Standard Edition to simplify the
development of multi-tiered enterprise applications,
thanks to its simple programming model.
It is a standard,
meaning it has been through the standardization process of the Java
Community Process and is implemented by multiple vendors,
such as Oracle, IBM, or Redhat.
In the early days of Java,
if you were doing any kind of web or enterprise development,
you were living in a proprietary world by creating your own frameworks or
locking yourself to a proprietary or commercial framework.
Then came the days of open-source framework, which were not based on standard.
So you were using open-source, but still being locked to a single implementation.
Java EE is based on standards,
this means that Java EE goes through the standardization process of the JCP or
Java Community Process and is described in a specification.
Open standards are collectively one of the main strengths of Java EE.
More than ever an application written with Java EE
will be portable across containers.
But documents are not enough.
Once the specification is final, several vendors are then to implement it.
This is often called a Java EE application server.
The reference implementation is called GlassFish,
is open-source and pushed by Oracle.
TomEE is the Apache foundation application server,
is also open-source, such as Payara.
Redhat has two implementations, JBoss application server,
open-source and supported in production, and WildFly, which is the community edition.