An Angular application is comprised of a set of components.
A component is an encapsulation of a visual aspect and a behavior.
On the web the visual aspect of a component is made through HTML and CSS.
Imagine a button, a calendar or color picker.
These components have graphical properties such as their color, size, or font.
But component also has behavior through JavaScript or
TypeScript when it comes to Angular.
So when we click on a button or when we choose a color on a color picker,
we can add some behavior.
Components can be simple or complex and they can
represent a single widget or an entire page.
A component can have any granularity,
it depends on the technical and business needs of the application.
For example here, this page can be seen as one single component.
If we don't need to reuse anything,
nor do we need to navigate between components,
we can just bundle everything into a single component.
But we might need finer grain components.
For example,
the navigation bar could be a component on its own
so it can be reused elsewhere.
In our case,
the app component that has been generated is a
component and it embeds several components,
such as the book-list, the book-detail, and the book-form.
Here those components are quite simple, they are just text basically,
but they will get much richer soon.
In Angular, each component is made of three pieces,
the HTML page, also called the template,
represents the visual aspect of the component.
It can be more or less complex, use external component libraries,
or have its own CSS stylesheet.
For the behavior of the component we need a TypeScript class.
That's where we will process the validation of the component,
toggle a visual aspect of the component depending on some business rules,
or invoke the backend through HTTP.
This class contains properties and methods that will be
bound to the template through binding.
You can see the binding being the glue between the template and the class.
Let's see these three pieces in action.
In Angular it is common to suffix our components with component.
html and component.
ts.
So here we have the HTML representation of our main component called app.
So the file is called app.
component.
html.
This HTML represents the navigation bar of our application
with the menu List and another menu Create.
Then comes the TypeScript file, as you can see it is a class called AppComponent,
which imports some Angular dependencies here angular/core.
So far this is just a TypeScript class.
So we need the @Component decorator specifying that
this class is a graphical component.
Two important information with this decorator, the first one is the selector.
This is the name of the component.
Notice the prefix bs that we used when bootstrapping the application.
So this component is called bs-root.
Second, is the template of this component.
Here the templateUrl points at the app.
component.
html.
Now let's say this component has an attribute called title,
which value is BookStore.
If we want to display this title on the page we use property binding.
Notice the curly braces syntax.
When the component is displayed,
the value of the property title will be bound to the page.
This will show BookStore on the navigation bar.
Let's see how to use this component now.
On the right top side, we have an app.
component TypeScript file.
Thanks to the templateUrl this class points to the HTML file.
On the top left side we have our main index.
html page where we need to include our component.
Remember that the component has a selector,
which basically gives it a name, bs-root.
So it's just a matter of using this name as an HTML attribute.
When the index.
html page will get rendered, it will embed the component.
That's the way it works and that's how we will be
embedding our components in this module.
Binding is basically how to glue properties on a page.
We've seen interpolation.
We used two curly braces around a component attribute and
its value gets bound within the HTML.
Interpolation is in fact a shortcut of a different syntax, property binding.
When we need to bind the value of the property book.
title, book.
title is between quotes and the property text
content is between square brackets.
Then comes event binding.
This is the syntax to bind an event instead of a property.
Notice the parenthesis.
On the event click of a button, the method deleteBook is invoked.
Finally, we have the two way binding.
The syntax is made of square brackets followed by parenthesis.
Two way binding, because the property book.
unitCost will be displayed on the page,
but if the value changes it will update a property value. Two way binding is often used on forms, as we will see later.