So now we have all our Java EE backend ready to share data through a REST API.
But this API is valuable only if it's accessible by other systems.
And for that it needs clear documentation.
When we talk about documentation,
it's nothing about writing a word document in English,
explaining with sentences what you're REST API does,
no, it's more about using a format that is human readable,
but also machine readable so it can be processed.
That's when the open API initiative comes along.
For your systems to communicate,
there needs to be a standard vocabulary for defining and documenting an API.
The open API initiative is a standard body which is part
of the Linux foundation responsible for the specification
called OpenAPI Specification, or OAS.
The OpenAPI Specification is a JSON or Yaml document describing an API.
It declares a valuable operations such as GET,
POST, DELETE, the parameters of these methods,
what they return, or the error response code.
For example,
here we have a JSON document describing the API of our BookStore application.
This API is accessible through HTTP and HTTPS,
at localhost 8080/bookstore-back/api.
Then we enumerate all the paths of the APIs here /backs.
This means that for accessing our books,
we need to go to localhost 8080/bookstore-back/api/books.
If at this URL we execute an HTTP GET,
the API will return all the books in a JSON format.
Several response can outcome from this code.
If it's a 200, it returns all the books in an array format.
As you can see, if the API adheres to the OpenAPI Specification,
it is easy to read, easy to iterate and easy to consume.
Additional utilities can also take advantage of this JSON contract.
An example of such utilities is Swagger.
Swagger is a powerful set of open source tools that help us design,
build, document, and consume our REST API contract,
written with Open API Specification.
Being language agnostic,
we will use these tools to produce a JSON contract of our
Java EE backend and generate TypeScript for our Angular
front-end to consume our REST service.
The Swagger website is full of documentation and also tools.
We will actually be using a couple of tools from Swagger.
Swagger Codegen, this tool can generate code from a Swagger contract.
As you can see, it can generate several languages from Scala, Java or Angular.
Another tool we will be using is Swagger UI. It is a nice web interface to visualize our JSON contract.