In domain driven design terminology the domain model describes the business
we are working with and the problems we want to solve.
The model is a system of abstractions that represent an
aspect of reality or something of interest.
In an object oriented language, such as Java,
the model is represented by an object that incorporates both behavior and data.
We can recognize the domain by focusing on the nouns of our domain.
Typically in the bookstore application we manipulate books.
So a book is part of our domain model.
Let's represent a book in Java.
A Book is a class that contains attributes such as a title,
a description, a unitCost, an isbn number,
a publicationDate, a URL pointing to the image of the book cover,
and the language in which the book has been written in.
Being the domain of our business, this book can also have a set of constructors,
getters and setters, and business methods.
That's it.
As you can see, no extra information is added to this class.
Actually there is nothing specific to Java EE in this code.
But that's because we still haven't had the need for an external service.
Well actually, there is one.
Object relational mapping.
In the bookstore application we need a way to store the information
of our books into the relational database H2.
We could do this programmatically or we could rely on Java
EE the brings object relational mapping.
Object relational mapping brings relational databases and objects together.
Objects have a state only accessible when the Java virtual machine is running.
If the JVM stops or the garbage collector cleans its memory,
objects disappear as well as they state.
But sometimes some objects need to be persisted like our object book.
By persist we mean objects that are stored and can get reused later.
And relational databases are the perfect component to store object state.
The principle of object relational mapping is to delegate to external tools or
frameworks the task of mapping between objects and tables.
In Java EE this framework is called Java Persistence API.
Java Persistence API is the Java EE solution to map
objects to relational database systems.
In JPA to map an object to a relational database the
client needs to use the entity manager.
It is called entity manager because in JPA
persistence objects are called entities.
The entity manager is the API to perform database related operations.
These operations can be simple ones, such as CRUD operations.
CRUD stands for create, read, update, and delete.
But JPA also comes with a more powerful query language,
allowing us to retrieve data with an object oriented syntax.
This language is called JPQL or Java Persistence Query Language.
In fact,
there is so much more that JPA can do that I would recommend
following the dedicated Pluralsight course.
When talking about mapping objects to relational database,
the term Entity should be used rather than object.
Objects are instances that just live in memory.
Entities are objects that live shortly in memory and persistently in a database.
They have the ability to be mapped to a database and need a persistence
identity that uniquely identifies them in the database.
For those of you who know JDBC,
JPA brings eye level of obstruction by removing all the JDBC
boilerplate code of mapping attributes to database columns.
Yet JPA uses JDBC underneath and relies on it to connect to the database.
In terms of code, little defers a book object from a book entity.
In fact, the difference comes with metadata.
Metadata is extra information that will be used by JPA
to map this object to a database.
So we first add an Entity annotation to the class and an Id annotation,
so JPA knows which attribute adds as a primary key.
The GeneratedValue annotation is an easy way to get increment.
The Column annotation informs JPA that the title of the book should
be stored in a column that is 200 characters long.
The description 1000 and the publication date into a
column called publication_date.
Notice that we can use another annotation to indicate that
the publication date is represented as a date into the
database and not a timestamp, for example.
Like most Java EE specifications, JPA also has its XML configuration file,
also called deployment descriptor.
In this file called persistence.
xml we define our persistence unit called bookStorePU.
That's the name that will be used later by the entity manager.
I'll come back to this in the next module.
We then define the properties of this persistence-unit.
For example, a few properties related to database schema generation.
The schema generation.
database.
action property instructs JPA to drop and create the
database schema at each deployment.
That's very useful in development mode,
and remember that we use the in-memory H2 database.
Dropping and recreating a database in-memory is really quick.
The schema generation script action is for being able to
generate the DDL script of the database.
If this property is set,
we need to name the file that will contain all the create statements.
These will be a great help actually.
We will be able to see the impact of an annotation directly into the database schema.