So let's answer this question first, which is validation?
Validating data is a common task that developers have to do.
That's because processing, storing,
and retrieving valid data is crucial for an application.
Indeed our applications spend most of their time constraining our model,
making sure the address is valid, the email is well formatted,
checking that the customer's name is not null,
or that it's date of birth is in the past.
All these constraints to ensure the data is correct and
therefore that a service processing this data will behave
correctly without throwing exceptions.
If data is invalid,
it is important to send some feedback to the user so she
or he can correct the invalid values.
Simply put, a constraint is a business rule that can be more or less complex.
Simple ones, such as is the address valid?
Is the customer's email well formed?
Is the name null?
Is the birth date in the past?
But also more complex ones that need more computing power,
such as the total amount is greater than the previous quarter?
Or the annual revenue has 10% growth?
Validation is so important that it has its own specification in Java EE.
It's called bean validation and it can be used in all the Java EE components.
The way we usually program is that we invoke a method on a component,
passing some data and if the data is invalid,
the component throws an exception.
With bean validation the component defines a set of
constraints using annotation on its attributes,
method parameters or return values.
Then a valid data will validate the components set of constraints.
Bean validation comes with a set of built-in common
constraints and it also comes with APIs to allow us to
create our own business constraints.
I will not cover this point,
but Pluralsight has an entire course on bean validation explaining
how to create your own business constraints.
Let's have a look at all these already defined commons constraints.
AssertFalse and AssertTrue will make sure a Boolean is either false or true.
Other constraints will target the size of the string,
the number of digits a number can have,
a maximum or minimum value for numbers or big decimals.
We also often want to make sure a date is in the future or in the past.
Bean validation has two simply annotations that we can use.
Making sure an object is null or not null is also a
common rule we apply to our objects.
Last,
bean validation comes with an annotation to verify that a
string follows a certain regular expression. Let's see how we can use them.