Time to develop our book entity.
I'll go step by step so you understand how things get together.
First of all, I will implement the Book object, our domain model.
Then I'll add the needed Java Persistence API annotations so
you will be able to turn the Book object into a Book entity and
map it to a relational database.
I'll also generate the DDL so you can see what annotations are used for.
So here I am in front of my IDE.
I'm going to use IntelliJ IDEA wizard to save me a bit of time.
So here I'm creating a persistence XML and src/main/resources.
Click on OK.
Here it is.
So for now it's empty.
Let's create a persistence unit.
I'm going to call it bookStore and PU for persistence unit.
Here it is.
Again it's empty,
but now that I have a persistence unit I'm going to create an entity,
the Book entity.
So I'll give it a name, Book.
And the package, I'm going to go under the sub-package model, so com.
Pluralsight.
bookstore.
model.
Here it is.
IntelliJ has put the Entity annotation and now I just add the attributes.
So to be persistent a book has to have an identifier id of type Long,
then a book has a title, a description.
A book has price, so I call the attribute unitCost of type Float,
an isbn number, publicationDate of type Date,
so when is the book published.
A book has a number of pages and it has an image to be displayed on the webpage.
And a book is written in a language,
so I'm going to create the language enumeration,
here it is, and let's add English, French,
Spanish, Portuguese, Italian, Finish, German,
Deutsch, and Russian.
So while you can see, and we have several languages to choose from,
back to the book Entity and let's add private Language language.
So this is just a Java class with getters and setters
and let's put a toString method,
so again I'll leave IntelliJ IDEA to generate all that for me.
So here we don't have any specificities of JPA yet.
What we need to do is to tell JPA which attribute is the identifier,
so that's the annotation @Id and generated value will
automatically generate an Id for us.
Then I'm using the @Column annotation to change the
length of title and description.
For unitCost I'm also using the @Column annotation,
but that's to change the name of the column,
so I want the attribute unitCost to be mapped on a column called unit_cost,
and same thing for publicationDate.
Here I'm specifying that the publicationDate is a date,
I could have chosen a timestamp.
Okay let's generate the DDL now with these annotations.
So here in the persistence XML I have to add some properties.
Javax.
persistence are the default properties of JPA and now I'm saying
drop-and-create the database each time you re-deploy the application.
So that's for the in-memory database,
but I'm going to add another property to get the DDL script.
So again I will create a DDL for creating tables and that
will be on the file bookStoreCreate.
ddl, and another script to drop the tables,
and that's going to be on bookStoreDrop.
ddl.
Okays so now I have annotations, I have these properties.
So I deploy the application, so again running WildFly,
the code is compiled, packaged in a war file,
WildFly deploys it, and now if I go to the directory,
here it is, of WildFly, I should find the bookStoreCreate.
ddl.
So that's the physical structure of the database our
Book entity will be mapped in.
Let's look at imageUrl.
As you can see, I don't have an underscore,
so it's just a matter of going back to the entity,
adding the appropriate @Column, so image_url,
redeploying the application in WildFly, and here it is,
image_url.
I can do the same thing for number of pages.
So Column name and the _of_pages and redeploy the application and here it is,
I'm looking for number of pages, yep.
So this is how we map an entity in a physical structure of the database.
It's just a matter of finding the right name for
the columns and the right length.
Okay so we finished module 4. So let's commit some code so it's easier to get back if needed.