Now that we know how to develop a component in Angular,
let's see the components we'll be creating for our BookStore application.
As we've seen, the main component has already been created by Angular CLI.
So we already have the app.
component.
html and ts files.
Then we have three main components, the one listing all the books, book-list.
component HTML and TypeScript file.
The one displaying the details of a single book called book-detail.
component and the form to create a new book called book-form.
component.
Let's start with the component listing all the books of the database,
the book-list.
component.
As you can notice, the book-list.
component is the component in the center.
Around it, it's the main app.
component, the one with the navigation bar.
If we only focus on the book-list.
component despite the title of the page showing the number of available books,
we have the book title, image, and description,
repeating itself.
It is the same information iterating through the list of books.
Let's see how we code such components.
As we know now, we need two files, the HTML representation, book-list.
component.
html and the TypeScript file.
The book-list.
component has a component decorator specifying its name and template.
Now let's say this component has a property number of books,
to show this information on the HTML template we use interpolation.
Here the title of the component will be list all the books 3,
3 being the value of the property nbBooks.
Now we need our 3 books.
For that we will use the nice JSON integration in TypeScript
and describe our books using JSON syntax.
We have an array of books with book number 1 and book number 2 and so on.
To iterate through this list in HTML, we use the ngFor directive.
Basically we are binding the ngFor to the books property,
plural, and giving it the name book, singular.
Then it's just a matter of using interpolation to
display the image of the book cover, the book title and description.
When we click on the book title, we go to our second component, the book-detail.
component.
This component displays all the information of the book in read only.
So we get the full description, the unit cost,
the isbn number that has been generated on the backend,
the number of pages and the language it is written in.
To develop this component we need two files, the HTML and the TypeScript.
By now you know that the book-detail.
component class has a component decorator with a
component selector and a templateUrl.
Let's use the same technique as before and declare a
property book with a JSON structure of data.
To display this data in HTML, it's just a matter of using interpolation.
So book.
title in curly braces will display the Title property of book,
the Description, the Unit cost and so on.
The last component is quite identical, it's the form used to create a new book.
It has more or less the same fields, but this time not in read only.
The code is also roughly the same.
The TypeScript class BookFormComponent defines a component with a property book.
Nothing special here.
What defers is the HTML page.
Being a form to create a new book, it needs the HTML form tag.
Then the title property of the book is bound thanks to the two way binding.
This allows the data entered in the input text to be set in
the attribute title of the property book.
In a form,
all the data that needs to be entered by the user needs to follow the two way binding syntax.