To understand where the boundary between unit and integration test is,
let's test our book repository using both methods.
In unit tests we test only one class here, book repository, in isolation.
This means that we do not use container services such
as database mapping or transaction, or we mock those container services.
Let's say we have this simple create method that takes a
book as a parameter and returns it.
How do we unit test this code with JUnit?
Well using a JUnit test case,
by convention we call this class BookRepositoryTest and create
as many methods we need annotated with test.
This should create a book method, creates a Book object with some data,
invokes the create method of the BookRepository and
makes sure the Book object is not null.
If you look carefully at this code, there is one thing missing.
We need to instantiate the BookRepository class.
That's it.
Now if we execute this test it passes.
Great.
But this is not the code we have in our BookRepository.
We actually inject the EntityManager to persist a book
into the database in a transactional way.
Our unit test does not work anymore.
Why?
Because the EntityManager needs to get injected by the container.
Testing in isolation we don't have a container.
We don't have the service of injection and therefore the EntityManager is null.
Calling the method persist will throw a null pointer exception.
This test will fail.
That's when we switch to integration tests,
when we need to access the container services.
So the way Arquillian works is that it packages the business code,
here the book repository and the book entity,
and the test class altogether.
Then it automatically deploys the archive into WildFly and
executes the test inside the container.
So let's go back to our test class.
Arquillian integrates with JUnit so we won't need much to make this test pass.
First of all,
to use Arquillian we just annotate the class with a specific Arquillian runner.
Then we need to refactor this code a bit by removing the book
repository initialization and instead use injection.
Now the integration test works,
the repository inserts a book into the database in a
transactional way and the book identifier is generated by
JPA and can be checked is not null.
For the integration test to work, we rely on the Arquillian run time.
Before executing this test we need to package our business
code so Arquillian can deploy it to WildFly.
For this we use ShrinkWrap.
ShrinkWrap is an API to create deployable archives such as jar,
war, or zip files.
It can even add external dependencies if needed.
ShrinkWrap creates the archive, Arquillian deploys the archive.
To create an archive,
our test class needs to have a method here called
createDeploymentPackage annotated with Deployment.
Notice that this method returns an archive.
We use ShrinkWrap to create a JavaArchive.
It also could have been a WebArchive if we wanted to.
Then it's just a matter of adding the business code to the
archive and the needed deployment descriptor,
here the JPA persistence. xml.