We've just seen the basic behavior of Angular router.
Actually in our BookStore application we use this simple navigation quite often.
But we also have other patterns.
For example,
we also need to pass parameters to the router when navigating
or executing an action before navigating.
Let's see how we handle these three different scenarios.
The simple navigation is clicking on a link and displaying a new component.
We do that on our navigation bar, for instance.
When clicking on the Create menu, the book-form component is displayed.
Or when clicking on the bar title, the book-list is displayed.
Another example is when we create a new book and need to cancel this action.
We click on the Cancel button and it brings us back to the list of books.
If we look at our main app.
component.
html template where our navigation bar is defined,
we see some HTML using the routing link directive.
Here when we click on the navigation bar title or the list menu,
we navigate to the book-list path, which executes the BookListComponent.
When we click on Create,
the navigation follows the book-form path and executes the book-form component.
But simple navigation is not always enough.
When we display the list of books we can click on the
link to visualize the book details.
But these details depend on the book we select.
So clicking on Beginning Java EE 7 navigates to the book details component and
displays all the information about this particular book.
The way it works is that we pass a parameter when navigating,
in this case the book identifier.
As you can see, the router link directive takes an array of parameters.
The path and the given parameter book.
id.
So the URL will be routerlink/123 if the book id is 123, for example.
The last scenario that we have is doing an action before navigating.
When we want to create a book we fill the form and click on Create.
This will do an HTTP POST on our REST API and then,
only then, will the user be directed to a different component.
Same mechanism when we visualize a book,
clicking on Delete will first execute an action on our REST API
and then display the book-list component.
Let's take this last example,
the book-detail HTML template gives the detail of a book.
And when clicking on the Delete button, it invokes the delete method.
Notice the ngSubmit directive,
here we are just saying when clicking on a button take all the data
in the form and submit it to the delete method.
The delete method is defined on our component class.
It first invokes our backend, but that's for next module,
and then uses the Angular router to navigate to the book-list path.
This will have the same effect on what we've seen so far.
It will execute the book-list component.
The router needs to be injected in our component via the constructor. We need to import it from the Angular router module.