Let's take a look at Angular now.
Angular is a JavaScript framework created by Google
for building front web applications.
So naturally it also uses HTML and CSS.
But Angular makes our HTML more expressive by adding
features such as if conditions or for loops.
It has a powerful data binding so we can easily display
attributes from our data model into our web pages.
In our architecture, the Angular front-end needs to talk to the Java EE back-end.
This communication is simplified in Angular because it has a built-in
support to integrate with a back-end in a very easy way.
Last but not least, Angular comes with a fantastic ecosystem,
a great community of developers and tools for quickly bootstrapping an
application or generating components or services.
Even if in Angular you can develop directly in JavaScript.
It supports all the languages such as TypeScript.
TypeScript is a free and open-source programming language
developed and maintained by Microsoft.
It is a superset of JavaScript and adds static typing in class
based object-oriented programming to the language.
TypeScript is designed for development of large applications and is transpiled to JavaScript.