So we have Node JS as the JavaScript runtime environment and
Yarn for compiling and building our code.
We could even start coding right away.
But instead we will use Angular CLI to speed up our development.
Angular CLI is a common line interface tool to scaffold and build
Angular applications using the Node JS style.
It gives us a set of commands to initialize,
develop, and even maintain Angular applications.
So we won't need to handle all common tedious
configuration files and directory structures.
The generated code just works out of the box.
Think of it as a Maven architect on steroids.
When you go to the Angular CLI website,
you stumble a bunch of command that we will see later,
such as ng new, ng generate, or ng serve.
Angular CLI being written in JavaScript, we need to use NPM.
If we click on the Getting Started,
we'll have all the instruction to install Angular CLI.
Angular CLI being written in JavaScript,
we need to use NPM to install it globally. As you can see here, you can run npm install -g angular/cli to have access to it.