Let's switch to the IDE and command line and build
these three BookStore components.
We will use the Angular CLI to save us some time and then
type some TypeScript and HTML code.
Remember that we used Twitter Bootstrap so we won't be adding any CSS.
We keep it simple.
Thanks to the feedback loop of Angular we will type code and always see it live.
That's when the Chrome development tools will become handy.
We will be able what's wrong in our code while we type.
So I've split my screen with Chrome on the right and the IDE on the left.
Let's start creating the book-list components with Angular CLI.
So ng generate component book-list --spec false,
so we don't have test classes,
and inline-style so we don't have a separate CSS file.
Brilliant.
Angular CLI has created a book-list directory and inside the book-list.
component.
html and TypeScript.
Okay so here in the HTML there's book-list works!
So let's display that on the right side in Chrome.
For that remember that a component has a selector, a name, bs-book-list.
So we go to the main app.
component and add bs-book-list.
We save the page and here it is, book-list works!
That's actually the content of our HTML page.
Let's change that.
So the title should be lists all the books and then the number of books.
For the number of books, let's do some interpolation.
So let's split the screen so I have the HTML at the
bottom and the TypeScript at the top.
So I'll create a variable called nbBooks and let's
say I'm going to create two books, so = 2.
Now on the HTML template, it's just a matter of using interpolation.
Let's get rid of private so it's easier.
I've saved the page, it compiled, and as you can see on the right,
list of the books - 2.
Now I'm going to iterate through these two books.
So I'm going to add some dummy data, so here I'm creating an array of books,
which is a JSON structure, and as you can see id equals 1,
the title: dummy title 1, description: dummy description 1,
and we display an image, so here I've copied the URL of a real image.
So let's duplicate that so we have two books,
we have a JSON array of 2 books, id equals 2,
dummy title 2, dummy description 2.
So how we display these two books?
Well, with an iteration.
So let's add some HTML and use the ngFor directive.
So here I'm creating a variable book of type books and remember
that books is the array on the TypeScript.
So let's close that and let's use the HTML image tag and bind it to imageURL.
We save the page, it refreshes, so here I have the two images of the two books.
Next to the image we need to display the title of the book and
the title of the book will actually be a link to the detail
component that we will create later.
But for now it's just an empty href.
So book.
title displays and let's finish with a book.
description.
Save the page.
Okay it's not very nice.
Remember that we have Twitter Bootstrap,
so let's use the style sheet of Twitter Bootstrap.
So here I'm using some styles on the list,
let's do media and use the 4 columns, so that's slightly better.
The image, let's create like a thumbnail,
so I'm using img-thumbnail, save the page,
that's nicer.
The title too, let's put, so it displays underneath the description.
Well, that's looking right now.
Okay so now let's create the book detail,
so the idea is when I click on the title of the book I go to the detail.
So again, as you can guess, Angular CLI book-detail,
it creates a new directory with two files,
the HTML template and the TypeScript.
Here it is.
So first thing, let's display this component on our main component.
So let's put it above, bs-book-detail, save the page, book-detail works!
Okay, so let's change the title, so let's use an h2 Detail of a book,
save the page, yes.
So let's create a data structure of a book,
like we did in JSON, but this time it's not an array,
it's just a single book.
So a book has a title, dummy title, a description,
it also has a price, we call it unitCost,
the isbn number, so let's put a random string,
a book has a number of pages, and it's written in a certain language,
so English.
Now that we have the data structure,
let's create some HTML to display nicely the details of the book.
So the title, it's an input text and, as you can see, we used the binding book.
title and it's read only so we use the HTML readonly tag.
Again,
let's use Twitter Bootstrap to make it nicer so we can have in
a single row the title and the text field.
The title will be two columns and because Twitter
Bootstrap uses a 12 column data grid, we will put 10.
So 2 for the label, 2 for the text field.
That's nicer.
Okay so let's duplicate that and do the same thing for the description,
the unit cost, and so on.
Description is longer so let's not use an input field, but a text area.
So let's change input with textarea, let's give it three rows,
so it's not a type text,
and let's get rid of that because a text area we need
to bind inside the tag text area, book.
description, save the page.
Okay we're getting there.
Here is our detail book finished with the two buttons because we
can delete a book and we can go back to the list.
So we've created the book-list, the book-detail,
one component missing, the book-form.
Thanks to Angular CLI we created our two files,
HTML and TypeScript, so the first thing we do is take the name of the component,
bs-book-form and add it to our main component so it displays on the page.
Here it is, book-form works!
So let's change the HTML, put another title,
this forms creates a new book,
and now I'm going to do a little bit of copy/paste
because it's more or less the same thing.
So on the book detail I take the JSON structure and I
copy and I paste it into the book-form.
I'm just adding the imageURL.
Okay so on the TypeScript file I have this book JSON structure.
I'm going to copy a little bit of HTML too so it makes my life easier,
back, let's make a bit of space, and here,
save the page, it displays.
So the difference is the form, it's not read only, so I get rid of read only.
Now I have a text field where I can put data in.
And remember the two way bindings.
So we get rid of the interpolation syntax and we use the two way binding syntax.
So ngModel and bind it to the book.
title.
Here is the form component created.
As you can see, we've created the form, the detail,
and the list books component.
The three components with Angular CLI and a bit of Twitter Bootstrap.
Let's commit our code.
So each component has two files, book-detail, book-form, book-list.
We added three components to the app.
component, which is the main component,
and Angular CLI updated the module behind our back. Let's change the commit message and we are done.