That was a lot of information,
let's go back to our BookStore application and finish coding it.
In this last demo we will use the Swagger CodeGen command line to pass the
JSON contract and generate a TypeScript service and model.
The service acts like a proxy and invokes the Java
EE back-end doing http requests.
Because this service uses the Angular HTTP module,
we will have to use observable in our code.
Okay so let's generate some code from the JSON contract, so the swagger.
json is on bookstore-back,
and do you remember it details all our methods exposed by the book endpoint,
the book data structure,
and we will take that as an input and generate
TypeScript code in a service directory.
So here I'm using Swagger CodeGen, saying as an input take the swagger.
json file, generate TypeScript for Angular 2,
and the output should be src/app/service.
That's quite quick, isn't it?
Here it is, the service directory.
Underneath we find two subdirectories, model where we have the model,
so here the book class, and api, so that's the book.
service.
As you can see, we have the path of our rest endpoint.
It injects the HTTP module in the constructor and if we go down,
we find all our business methods, countBook,
createBook, deleteBook, getBook, and all the methods return an Observable,
here an Observable of Book because it gets a book.
Well, let's use this book service.
Let's start with a book list.
Let's get rid of our mock data, so number of books was equal to 2,
we get rid of that, books is an array of Book,
so now that we have the book model, we can use it,
and this and now we need the book service.
What are we going to do?
Inject in the constructor.
So private, we give it the name bookService of type BookService.
And now we have access to all our business methods,
so let's start with counting the number of books.
So you'll remember, it returns an observable so we need to subscribe to it.
This event will return the number of books,
we call it nbBooks, and we effect nbBooks into this.
books.
And we do the same thing for the list of books,
so we have this method getBooks, we subscribe to it,
this method will return JSON array of books,
we call it books, and we effect that into the variable this.
books.
So let's start our server ng serve, oh wrong directory, sorry, ng serve.
It compiles everything.
Refreshes the browser and it's not working, let's debug that.
So we open the dev Chrome tools and, oh, yes of course, connection refused.
So we haven't started the WildFly.
So let's start WildFly (Scrolling) and now if we refresh, yes it's working.
So we have our 100 books and we have the number 1 under it at the top,
meaning we've done 2 HTTP calls,
1 to get the number of books and the second one to get all the books.
Well that's brilliant.
Now let's go to book-detail, so when we click on the book title,
we want the details of the book.
So again, we get rid of our mock data, we use our Book class,
new Book, so we create a new instance of Book.
As you know now,
we inject the bookService in the constructor and we need
to inject another API from Angular, it's the ActivatedRoute.
This API will give us details of the current route.
What we want from this API is the parameter passed on the URI, the bookId.
So we take the route, the API gives us all the parameters of this route,
but we are only interested in bookId.
So then it returns the id of the book and with this id we
invoke the bookService getBook method, passing the id,
and again, we need to subscribe to it.
So that returns the entire book in the variable book and we set this.
book.
So let's open the terminal, refresh the page, save, and now yes, it's working.
So I'm going back.
As you can see, the URI is 1064 and if I click on this one, 1015.
Now I need to delete a book.
So that's quite easy, we get rid of this command and this.
bookService.
deleteBook and now that we already have the bookId,
it's just a matter of going this.
book.
id.
Once we delete, then we route.
So finally and then we do the routing.
And again, we subscribe to this observable, save, refresh, delete, yes 99 books.
Let's delete another one, 98.
Let's delete another one, 97.
Good.
Now the last thing to implement is creating a book.
So if we go in the book-form, we get rid of our mock data, creating a new book.
So Book new Book.
We inject the bookService,
BookService and we call the createBook method on
the bookService passing the book, and if it succeeds,
then we'll navigate back to the book list.
So we go back to our main page and subscribe to it.
Save, refresh, okay let's click on Create.
So let's create a book about Java EE 8, say that it's the best Java EE book ever.
Let's give it a price, number of pages, I've copied a URL for the image,
it's in English, Create, 98, so we went from 97 to 98 and here it is.
So if I click on it, good.
Creating a book works.
Deleting a book, showing the list of the books, everything works.
So let's commit our code.
So we added Book and bookService in all our components.
Swagger CodeGen created all this code under the API and model,
and it's just a matter of changing the message and we can commit. Our application is finished and works.