The architecture of the BookStore is finally completed.
Thanks to our JSON contract in Swagger CodeGen,
we generated a book service and a book model.
The book service uses the Angular HTTP module to
communicate with our Java EE back-end.
Then it's just a matter of connecting our components to the book
service and we have our application up and running.
We can even get rid of the browser on the Java EE
back-end so the diagram gets clearer.
In this module we've seen what Angular services are and how
they use observables and reactive programming.
Thanks to Swagger CodeGen and the JSON contract,
we've just generated most of the code to invoke our back-end with HTTP.
In the next module we'll revisit the application setup.
We will focus on the anatomy of the BookStore application
throughout the modules since the beginning,
the Java EE back-end, until the end, the Angular front-end. I'll wrap up by giving you a few external references.