We will use this JAX-RS client API for our Arquillian tests.
In module 6 we saw that Arquillian is perfect for integration tests.
It packages the business code as well as the test class into an archive.
Then it deploys it to WildFly and executes the test inside the container.
But that is not the way we will test our REST endpoint.
We need to test it from outside the container.
Arquillian has a specific mode where it doesn't package
the test class inside the archive.
Therefore, the tests are not executed from inside the container,
but from outside through HTTP.
Let's take back our BookEndpoint, it has a GET method returning a single book,
giving its identifier.
This method is accessible through an HTTP GET on /books/123.
Let's test this method with Arquillian.
The BookEndpointTest class still needs an Arquillian runner.
But we need to inform Arquillian that this test
class will run as a remote client.
We still need to package the REST application that
is going to be deploy on WildFly,
but also specify not to package the current test class with testable = false.
Finally we create as many tests as we want.
Being a remote HTTP test,
we ask Arquillian to inject the web target pointing at /books.
With this web target we execute an HTTP GET on /123, the identifier of the book.
Get an HTTP response and check the status code of the response is okay.
Let's see this code in action in an Arquillian test called BookEndpointTest.
This client test is using the JAX-RS Client API to
access remotely the deployed endpoint.
This kind of testing is often called black box testing where we
only access the external API of a component,
not its core code.
So here we are in front of the BookEndpoint.
Let's create an Arquillian test.
I'm using the IntelliJ IDEA wizard again and the first thing I'm
going to do is a copy/paste from BookRepository,
you'll remember all the ShrinkWrap packaging,
so I'm copying that to save a bit of time.
Here it is.
And because I'm testing BookEndpoint,
I need to add BookEndpoint to the archive as well as the JAXRSConfiguration.
And I'm saying testable = false,
so I'm telling ShrinkWrap not to package the test class inside the archive,
and I'm running this as a client.
Now I'm using a nice Arquillian trick, I'm injecting the WebTarget,
so api/books.
This way I have a WebTarget object pointing at api/books.
So first let's test the count, count all.
So what I do is I use the WebTarget to give me a response and then
I will assert that this response is correct.
So counting books is on the URL api/books/count,
that's why I do the path count,
and I'm doing an HTTP GET that returns a response and
remember that the database is empty so that this stage I
should have NO_CONTENT status code.
So let's make it cleaner.
And that is more or less the same thing for the find all,
so let's test the find all or we use the response,
the webTarget,
so this time I'm not using the path because counting all books is on api/books.
I do HTTP GET.
I need JSON, so let's make that cleaner again,
and let's copy/paste the line above because it's the same thing.
And what I'm going to do now is create a book.
So because I like copy pasting, I'm going back to the BookRepository.
here copy/paste the new book, and I'm reusing the webTarget and the response.
This time I am not going to do an HTTP GET,
but a POST, so there's also a post method.
And I'm using a little JAX-RS trick to convert the book into an entity.
Here it is,
I have to say that it's in JSON and this time when I do an HTTP
POST I expect to have a CREATED status code,
not a NO_CONTENT.
So the test looks good now.
Let's execute it.
So WildFly is running and I'm going to run the
BookEndpoint test with this method.
So this is a remote test.
Good.
Great.
Let's commit the code now.
So in this module we've created the BookEndpoint,
the JAXRSConfiguration, remember that we imported some SQL data in the database,
100 books, and we created a BookEndpointTest to have remote testing. Here it is.