Okay, let's quickly check your development environment is set up correctly.
We won't need our database and testing frameworks yet.
So let's just focus on the essential tools for now.
First of all we need a JDK or Java Development Kit.
As I mentioned earlier,
the prerequisites for this course is to have some
knowledge of the Java language,
so I'm assuming that you already have it installed.
Then we need Maven, as we've just seen,
installing Maven is just a matter of downloading a zip file
and then zipping it to your file system.
Same for WildFly, which is our Java EE runtime environment.
So here I've switched to the terminal.
First of all, make sure Java is installed.
So java -version will show you which version of Java is installed,
here it's Java 8, and we'll make sure that Java is in your class path.
Then Maven, we can do the same and go maven -version.
Here it's written in red, I have Apache Maven 3.
5.
Finally, WildFly, you can see I've installed WildFly 10.
1.
The bin directory will have this standalone script,
which bootstrapped the application server,
so if I go standalone, you will see logs going through.
That's when we bootstrap WildFly.
Here it is, WildFly has been started.
To make sure it's up and running, we can go to the browser on port 8080,
that shows you the WildFly home page.
Let's click on the Admin Console.
The admin console tells us that first we need to create an admin user,
running the add-user script.
So let's go back to the terminal.
Here I use another tab and I use the add-user shell script.
What type of user do we need to add?
Management User.
Now let's pick up a username, I use agoncal,
and a password, are you sure your password is correct?
Yes.
Re-enter password.
The groups, let's leave empty.
Do I want to add this user to the management realm?
Yes.
Do I need a remote connection for EJB?
No.
And that's it.
So if I go back to the browser, and go down the page and try again,
now I'm prompted with a username and password,
I connect to it, and here I am in front of the WildFly Administration Console. We will use it in the coming modules.