Let's finish this module by having a higher level view
of our application architecture.
So the book repository is still the one dealing with the book entity,
accessing the database in a transactional way and
using external utility components.
What we did in this module is that we've exposed the
book repository through a REST API.
The book endpoint is a JAX-RS component that deals with HTTP
protocol and delegates the call to the book repository.
The REST API exposes a JSON representation of our books.
This API can be accessed through a browser or
automated through remote Arquillian tests.
In this module we've seen the two sides of JAX-RS,
one is exposing a REST API using annotation,
the other one is being able to consume it with a client API.
JAX-RS allowed us to easily add an HTTP endpoint on top of the book repository.
The book endpoint will actually be the entry point for our Angular application.
We've also added data to the database so the web
application has some data to display.
We also used the JAX-RS client API in an Arquillian test.
Now that we've exposed our book repository through a REST API we could end here
the Java EE part of this course and start the Angular part,
but we won't yet.
In the next module we will document the BookEndpoint API.
I'm not talking about documentation as a Java doc or any kind of text document,
I'm talking about documenting the REST contract.
What HTTP methods are allowed on our REST endpoint,
which parameters to pass, which response is returned and so on.
Thanks to this contract we will then be able to generate Angular services to access our Java EE back-end.