Again, let's take a higher view of the architecture of our BookStore application.
So far we add a Book entity using JPA annotations to be able
to be mapped on a relational database.
Now we've added a Book Repository to persist,
delete, and select books from the database.
This book repository uses the JPA Entity Manager to access the database
and Java Transaction API for transaction demarcation.
In this module we've added a repository facade to handle our books.
We saw that JPA has a very important API called EntityManager
to allow CRUD operation on a single entity,
thus simplifying the way to do an insert,
delete or find by Id with a single line of code.
When finding by identifier is not enough,
JPA comes with a rich query language called Java Persistence Query Language.
The JPQL syntax is similar to SQL, but instead of dealing with tables,
rows, and columns, it manages entities.
Finally, we used Java Transaction API to do transaction demarcation.
A single annotation and we leave the container the deal
with comments and rollbacks on our behalf.
Well,
so far we've typed a few lines of code without being
able to execute our application.
We won't be able to execute it just yet.
Instead, in the next module we will test our code.
We will see the differences between unit tests and
integration tests so we can choose wisely.
We will implement our first test, making sure what we've done so far is valid. We will test our CRUD operations in our queries.