In this module we saw all the tools that we need to
set up our Angular environment.
I'll keep IntelliJ IDEA as the code editor because it gives me
a great Angular support as well as Java EE,
as we've seen in the previous modules.
Node JS is the JavaScript runtime environment we'll be using.
Yarn is the building tool that will help us compile and package our code
as well as dealing with the external dependencies.
In terms of code generation,
we've seen and installed Angular CLI to bootstrap our
Angular application and Swagger CodeGen to generate the
HTTP code to invoke our backend.
To prettify our web application, we've chosen the Twitter Bootstrap framework.
Finally we will use Google Chrome for its dev tool extension.
Now that we've picked up all the tools to develop our Angular frontend,
the next module we'll use them to bootstrap our web application.
We will use the Angular CLI to scaffold an Angular application.
We will check the generated code and then compile it and
execute it with a Yarn building tool. Finally we will see how to configure Bootstrap to have a nicer UI.