Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo in front of us we see the dashboard the beautiful customer
segmentation dashboard that we created in the previous tutorials of course.
And today we're going to be putting this dashboard into a storyline.
So just to remind you what we have here is a map of the United Kingdom and how a certain bank how its
customers are distributed across the different regions of the UK.
Also we have a distribution of the same customers by different balance bands.
So these are 10000 old bands or 10000 pound bands in this case the distribution of the customers by
age so five year bands then we can control the bands here if we like.
And as we click around they adjust and also we've got the gender distribution of our customers and the
job classifications.
And once again this dashboard is fully interactive we can click around we can see what's going on with
the different demographics and that's what's called the customer segmentation dashboard.
So what we're going to do today is as we discuss We're going to put this dashboard into a storyline
and provide some inside a story tell the readers or the viewers that people we're going to be presenting
to tell them a story about this bank and its customers and how they differ from region to region.
However before we proceed with today's tutorial of like to ask you for a quick favor I know you've already
brought this up before and if you have left to review.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
However if you haven't I would really appreciate if you considered leaving a review for this course.
It's very easy to do you just have to click this button up at the top and then in this window you just
select the right number of stars you think the course deserves and perhaps type in some comments.
It would really help me understand how you rate the course and if it has met your expectations and also
it'll help other students who are considering taking this course to understand what to expect inside
and whether it's worth their while or not.
So I would really appreciate if you could do that for me today.
And now is get on.
Back with the show.
So how do we create a storyline.
Well the first thing we need to do is click this button at the bottom which says news story.
So we'll do that.
And now you can see a new type of working space.
So it's not a worksheet it's our dashboard.
It's a storyline.
What you can do here you can create anything inside but you can drag elements in here and like a dashboard
you can drag worksheets and you can also drag dashboards and a storyline but the main difference is
that you can only drag one item you can combine items here souces you drag a second item.
It automatically replaces the previous one.
And so here we can drag our dashboard in here.
You got to pick what you want to drag into the storyline and then once you've added it.
So let's say if I want the map then I can add another point to my storyline.
The gender and then let's say I want the decision by balance that way I can create a story and talk
through these points one by one.
But in our case we will be working all the time with our segmentation dashboard and it will just be
showing different cuts of our member base.
In this storyline.
So let's go ahead and drag the segmentation dashboard in here and right away you can see it underneath
this storyline control panel.
So the first element or storyline will be the overall representation of all customers so it's kind of
our customer base line and we want the user or the viewer to be able to see what the bank looks overall
in the whole of the United Kingdom as here we need to add a caption.
And what are we going to type in is very go to prepare this bank's customer base line.
There we go.
That's done all we want to show our viewer at this stage.
Now we're going to create a new point and we're going to drag the segmentation dashboard in here as
well.
Now what we want to look at is the one of the regions of the U.K. and we're going to start with the
largest region or the region that has most customers for this bank.
It's is it's England.
So we'll just click on England here and as we discussed previously the insight that we want to convey
here is that there's a lot of white collar workers in this region Predominantly they are this region
the customers in this region are presented represented by white collar workers.
Perhaps that has something to do with London being the economic center of Europe.
So we're going to take a new caption and I'll copy it in here and it says England is mostly represented
by white collar workers.
70 percent.
That's all we wanted to show.
So when you do get to this point during a presentation what will happen is you can start drilling into
this dashboard.
If it is required so obviously you're talking about white collar workers who might want to click on
it and then see how the dashboard changes and perhaps look at what other male white collar workers up
to and look at their representation by age bands and then look at their representation by the higher
and balances and so on.
So it's up to you once you get to this point.
But to start with.
To get you started or to create a segue between the previous slide and this slide.
You just need this little caption over here.
So now we're going to update that.
So it's saved.
And instead of treating a blank point we're going to duplicate this chart and that will save us the
trouble of dragging the dashboard.
There we go so we've duplicated the tab and now we will look at Scotland and as we discussed here the
age demographic is completely different.
Much older customers the gender is also different predominantly males.
And the job classification blue collar and other very few white collar workers bank with this bank in
Scotland.
So let's copy the caption and see what it says.
The caption here is larger so if you move away you'll see this scroll box appear.
And now we can read the caption says customers in Scotland are predominantly males in their late 40s
and early 50s late 40s and early 50s representation of white collar workers is low.
OK so that gives us some conversational topics so you might want to click on blue collar workers once
you open up this dashboard you'll see that 95 percent of them are actually male.
And so the other 44 percent these are mostly represented by females.
You might also want to look at the older demographics and see how their balances are distributed like
and so on.
So that is how what are we going to convey for Scotland.
And at this point I'd like to show you another cool feature of Tablo and that is annotations.
Now it is a very simple feature and a lot of the time people get to learn it right away so you might
really know it.
But if you don't.
No not a worry.
We'll look at it now.
It's very easy to use let's say on this chart.
I want to point out something specific that there is a lot of workers or customers in this region.
We're in the early 50s so between 50 and 55 years old.
What I want to do here is right click on this bar click annotate and add in Mark and we'll just keep
the default for now.
So I'll just change the size to 10 because that's a bit too big.
And what you'll see is this arrow up here and this box with text which you can move around and is basically
telling the reader some additional information.
So once you get to this picture to this slide you will see this annotation which I hadn't seen before
and that is very powerful because it attracts their attention and also gives you some cues talking cues
so what are we going to do.
Now we're going to change the text here and we'll say high representation of customers in early 50s
maybe center this.
So that's what we wanted maybe change it a bit so it would fit.
So that attracts attention and gets you can get to talking about this specific element of the customer
segmentation.
So that age groups you can definitely add them for other elements of your position so if you want to
talk about balances or gender or something else something that might not be obvious or something that
you really want to attract people's attention to then feel free free to add annotations.
So I'll just update that and we'll duplicate it again.
So now we're moving on to Wales and in Wales we obviously don't need this anymore so we can delete it.
And as you can see it's stayed here but it's deleted here now.
In Wales our main inside was the balances so here you can see something different to the overall baseline.
And we will see it even better if we change the balance group so we got a justice parameter and change
it to 15000 dollar or pound bands.
And here you can see that it actually increases first and then drops off.
So if unclick whales in the baseline you'll see that it always drops off like that for whales at first
increases.
And so let's type in our inside for whales the inside for whales is going to be daughter for Wales shows
an above average representation of mid-sized balances.
There we go so we can update that and perhaps you can add another caption here so on it and it said
Mark and we'll say above average representation and here will say size 10 and also centering it is a
good idea sometimes.
So that's how we will deal with this region.
And once you're in here you can start kicking around and understanding what else is going on.
If you need to.
So once you click these balances for instance you see that the distribution by age changes so you can
tell how these people were from abnormal or representational balances what they are who they are and
you see that they're mostly in the early thirties.
They're mostly female and the mostly white collar workers.
And finally let's move on to Northern Ireland.
So we're going to update that and we're going to duplicate.
And here we'll get rid of this caption and we will select Northern Ireland right away our inside here
was that early.
Younger age groups and predominantly female So let's copy that into our caption here we typed in Northern
Ireland is mostly presented by female customers in younger age groups.
Update that.
And there we go.
So that's all done.
We can add another annotation here but I will leave that up to you.
Another thing I want to show you is that here the parameters are independent.
So Tatel has thought this through very well.
If you change the parameter control on this element of the storyline then it won't change on this element
so even though it's the same dashboard we're dealing with Ultimately the actual parameter controls are
independent so feel free to change them around and show exactly what you want in every single part of
your of in every single region of the United Kingdom so you might want to show it like this.
In this particular case that is totally up to you.
So there we go.
Now what we see is a storyline.
So when you're presenting you can start with the UK then you can move on to England and Scotland then
Wales make some comments points or move on to Northern Ireland and conclude your presentation.
That is how to create storylines in Tablo very new powerful feature.
Hope you enjoyed this tutorial.
And just as a reminder AOD really appreciate if you could leave a review.
It's very simple to do it will take you 30 seconds and help me out a lot.
Thank you very much.
Alipore see you next time.
And until then happy analyzing.