Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo.
And today we're downloading and connecting to the data set that we require for this section.
So let's go ahead and get started with that.
We're going to need a browser and we're going to go to superdog assigns dot com slash Tablo And if you
scroll down to the bottom here there's Section 6 Tablo calculations more dashboards and storytelling.
And this is where adalah data set sits.
It's called The UK bank customers that's three That's right.
We're back to see as file because it's always good to know how to connect to different data sets and
practice different types of files.
And before we download the file I just wanted to say that there's a small caveat here that today's data
set is dummy data for an imaginary bank operating in the UK.
So you don't have to worry.
This is not real customer data.
This is all mockup data created specifically for the purposes of this exercise.
So let's go ahead and download that save link as I'll just put it into my folder.
And now if I open up the folder.
So I actually already had one so I didn't really need to download.
So there is a file and let's open that up and have a look at what is inside.
So there is Excel.
I'm going to copy the file into their annals just zooming in a bit I don't need the browser anymore.
I'll just zoom in a bit here and make space for these columns.
OK.
So we've got customer id the idea of the customer the name of the customer the surname the gender of
the customer.
Age of the customer or the region in the UK where they're from or where the branch is located.
So it's either England Northern Ireland or Wales or Scotland.
The job classification whether they're white collar blue collar or other the date they joined the bank.
So this is a relatively new bank.
It's only been operating for a year for the year of 2015 from January to December.
So that's when all of these customers joined and the balance on the account of the customer in dollars
or pounds doesn't really matter.
Just some sort of currency.
And now if we go down to the very bottom here you'll see that there's 4000 and 15000 actually 4000 14
because one rose a header.
So not a lot of customers relatively new bank.
And what they want us to do is they want us to analyze how the different regions are presented in this
customer base so basically what the customers look like in the different regions so they can assess
who's interested in the bank in these different areas of the U.K. and how to better service their customers.
So we need to create some visuals a dashboard A and a storyline to actually portray what we want to
tell the executives and explain about the user base so basically all of the findings that we uncover.
So that's our data set.
Let's close this file.
And no we don't want to save changes and we will go ahead and connect Tablo to this file.
So this is no longer an Excel file it's a text file because cxxviii files are deemed text files and
we're going to open up UK bank customers and there we go.
So there is a file at the bottom.
Scroll down will see just to check that everything is OK and the total number of rows is correct.
That's good.
And now we can proceed to creating our visualizations that we will require for our own Alliss.
So that was all for today.
I look forward to seeing you next time when we will start analyzing the customers and creating some
cool charts and maps and stuff like that.
So until next time happy analyzing.