Hello and welcome back to the course in Tablo.
And in today's tutorial we're going to install Tablo onto our computer.
So what do we need to install tablet Well the only thing that it will need is a browser so let's go
ahead and bring that up and where you'll need to proceed to is.
W w w dot Tablo dot com.
Now you have two options here.
You can install Tablo and get a demo version of Tablo.
That's of course if you don't have a full license of tabel already if you have full Les's of Tablo ready
then you can proceed with the first option and then use your license.
Otherwise if you don't have a full lessons you can either use a trial version of Tablo.
They provide a 40 day trial or you can use Tablo public which you can get at public dot Tablo dot com.
So we're going to start with option number one and then I'll explain a bit more about Tablo public.
Now what we need to click is the try and now button up at the top.
Once we click that here we can download our free trial and in order to do that we're going to need to
enter our e-mail.
And let's for argument's sake put an e-mail test 2:59 add G-mail dot com and click download free trial
and now as you can see your Tablo installation has started downloading.
So we're going to cancel this one because I already have Tablo installed on my computer.
And also you will notice that there are a couple of versions so the version has been downloaded is the
one that has been recognized for my computer that's a 64 bit Windows version if you need a 32 bit origin
for when is it going to get here.
Or if you need the Mac version you can get it here as well but normally the website will recognize the
correct version that you need and download that one right away.
So there you go and once you have downloaded the installation package just in Seoul Tablo.
So like the 14 day free trial and proceed with the prompt.
After that you will get an icon on your desktop.
Now if you want to proceed with the Tablo public version then you'll need to go to public dot tablet
dot com and tell the public is absolutely free so it doesn't have any limitations in terms of the amount
of days you can use it for it's a completely free software.
It does have a few slight restrictions for example you cannot create extracts and you cannot save files
directly onto your computer or you'll have to save them onto the public of public server.
But that is not a big hurdle in terms of completing this course you will be able to totally complete
the scores.
I've done it myself.
I've created the most complex visualizations in this course using Tablo public.
And you can totally do that as well.
The public is a very convenient tool.
It is free and it is often used by people like journalists and professions where they're not facing
any sensitive data where they just want to create some really interesting results that they want to
share of the world.
So the public is a great option.
I often get asked what is the best way to take this course.
If the Tablo trial has expired or if somebody decides that the trial is not long enough Tebbel public
is a great option to complete this course so I select one of those to either select Tablo I'll be using
Tablo the full version throughout the course or if you like to follow along exactly then.
So like the tablet full version if your trial has expired or you just want something that doesn't have
a time limitation go public and you'll be able to follow along with 99 percent of this course as well.
And once you've installed Tablo you'll get a desktop I can just like this one so if you double click
it that will bring up Tablo.
And this is what it looks like inside.
And this is where we'll get to the fun stuff and we'll proceed with that in the further tutorials of
this course.
I can't wait to see it next time.
And until then happy analyzing.