Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo.
And in today's tutorial we will discuss how your daughter should look like when you're importing it
into Tablo.
Now we've already touched on this topic briefly before but I think it'll be a worthwhile exercise for
us to discuss this once again and recap on the conclusions that we came up with that time.
So to start off with I'm going to bring up a spreadsheet.
Move some data.
So here you have a spreadsheet that might look familiar because we did talk about it previously in the
course but this is a spreadsheet that tells us about unemployment rates or long term unemployment rates
for different months of the years since 2005 and so on with different genders so for men and for women
and for the different age groups so 16 to 19 years old 20:24 and so on.
And so this started does look like visually appealing to the human eye.
And here we can quickly derive insights if we need to we can scroll further along and find the right
year that we or urin motard we're looking at and we right away know that the left column is meant men
the right columns women and we know which how to select the right age group just because they're nicely
highlighted here.
Also the history has some header information up at the top.
It's got some additional information on the bottom.
Sometimes you might find the species like this will have totals at the bottom as well like we can either
right now.
So here you've got the total and let's just drag got along so well we'll call that total.
So this is not uncommon when there's a total at the bottom of the spreadsheet might be highlighted in
a different color as well so or maybe like light blue or something like that and to as humans we can
understand and comprehend this information quite easily.
But on the other hand it's not the best format for machines so let's have a look at another format that
might be might be used to.
So here is another spreadsheet with the same information and it's got the age groups that period and
here the men and women are split into two separate columns.
And so for that period for that age group you can understand right away what was unemployment for men
or at some point for women.
And once again they might be a total here as well.
So just copy that down.
And as you can see this information is presented in an appealing way to the human eye.
But it is not what machines are used.
It's not what Tablo is used to when you were importing this information.
And for instance this information is best presented in the following way if you are to put it into table
and that format.
Is this where you've got separate columns for every type of dimension that you have for instance the
age which is split into some bags here.
The gender is a separate dimension.
And then you've got the period so period of time the month that you're looking at.
And then finally you've got the measure for which is aggregated at the lowest level of granularity that
you have.
So when you take the age the gender and the period into account you've got that value over here so it's
basically just columns of data rather than some visually appealing formatted data which we had here
and here.
So what you need to make sure when you're putting got into Tablo is that it is formatted as close to
this as possible ideally has to look like this.
And that means that you need to take out all these headers any possible margins that your daughter has.
You have to kind of unpick it the views and put all of these these months into a column and give that
column a name called Month or time period and put the genders into court and to call them also to get
rid of the totals because you don't need the totals and tablet you can get them in trouble if you need
them.
And here what they're only.
All they're doing is they're good for visual analysis but they will confuse you if you bring them into
Tablo that might cause discrepancies in your daughter.
Also sometimes you might find that dot is structured in a way that if a value becomes repeated then
there is no value there.
So for instance it could be like this.
And so that basically means that all of these are January all of these February febrile of these are
March.
Well for Tabeau to understand the data you also need to once again fill in the blank spaces of your
data and you can all do all this in Excel if you need to.
However the good news is Tablo has some advanced features in its daughter import functionality which
will help you do a lot of these things and and actually allow you to do a lot of these automatically.
And so that's what we will be looking at in the next tutorial will be talking about the dot interpreter.
And I look forward to seeing you next.
Until then happy idolising.