A lot.
Welcome back to your favorite course on Tablo.
And today we're finally creating our very first dashboard.
Hooray.
Congrats on getting this far.
It's going to be super super fun and you will see exactly how to create your first dashboard.
It's going to be epic.
So let's get straight to it here we've got two tabs We've got two worksheets that were created.
We've got the customer scatterplot and we've got the map of Europe.
So now how do we put them both together onto one dashboard that when somebody is analyzing he can see
them together.
So to create a dashboard you need to click the second button over here which says new dashboard.
So let's go ahead and do that and right away we've got a dashboard one created.
And as you can see it looks a bit different to a worksheet.
It doesn't have dimensions and measures it's rather got the different worksheets that we have in our
tablet workbook and it's got some layout specific issues that you can choose like you can add images
you can add web pages text different horizontal vertical layouts.
It's got.
You can make objects floating or tiled and it's got some other width and height parameters so it's more
of a visual kind of representation.
We're no longer doing Tata mining or dot investigation and analysis.
We are creating a very pretty powerful tool for somebody to do dot investigation using the dashboards
that or the worksheets that we've created.
So let's go ahead and do that now.
The first thing that we are going to do is we're going to drag our worksheets onto the dashboard.
So let's take the map of Europe and all you do is just drag it on here and right away you can see it's
filling up most of the space.
And basically this dashboard is pretty much identical to our map of Europe.
We can roll a scroll over different states and all show different information.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to add the scatterplot to this dashboard as well and we're
going to drag it.
And as you can see Tablo is giving you some suggestions where you want to put it.
So what we're going to do is we're going to put it here underneath our map and there we go.
So Tablo has put this dashboard under all map.
Now we obviously don't like these scroll around buttons here because they shouldn't be there.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go to the map and we'll make it a little bit smaller so
if you make your map just a bit smaller and you go back to your dashboard you will see that slowly you're
kind of getting rid of those things.
So we still got this vertical one so let's make this smaller and maybe this a bit wider.
And maybe one more time.
So we've still got both that like that.
Then you can just drag it in the dashboard to fix it up.
Finally And there we go.
So we've got the map of Europe and the customers scatterplot both in this dashboard.
So obviously this now we're going to decide on what we want to leave what we don't want to see the sales
kind of size of the bubble.
It doesn't really help us because visually it's very hard to compare this legend to what we actually
see so let's get rid of it.
It's no point in having the profit margin.
Well kind of it's more the red and blue is more to show us kind of positive negatives we don't really
care about how the different like how they compare that.
This blue is exactly zero point 9 and this blue is 0.09 5.
We won't be able to see that before.
And same thing here it's more of an historical thing in this case because we already know that anything
below the horizontal line is actually bad.
So in this case aesthetical thing in this case is just so that our eyes are our attention is drawn towards
the red or the blue so we can quickly separate the good versus the bad and versus like the neutral which
are these gray ones.
So in reality we don't really need this college and so let's get rid of it too.
Of course we do need a year of order date.
And now what I wanted to show you is how to add this filter in case it's not there.
So let's let's assume that the filter wasn't there.
So yeah that's OK.
What happened there was I removed a I removed one of these containers.
So I'll just put it back.
So yeah that's probably another thing that's good.
Good to know you can add these containers so horizontal or vertical and that will help you split up
your dashboard into segments.
So in this case I added a vertical containers so that now I can put things into the container.
So here we've got two dashboards but we don't have that filter.
How do we add that filter in.
Well what we can do is we look at this dropdown for this for the map and here it says quick filters
and you can add the filter we had on your order date and same thing you could have done it through this
way you can go here quick filters and you can just choose a quick filter if you want to add.
So just going to actually close this because it's already create a container for me.
And with this quick filter once again you need to format it.
So just go what did we have single values slider.
And obviously we don't need all customized show all value taken off.
And there you go.
So they have a quick filter.
And as you can see as as you remember because we said for this filter to be applied to all worksheets.
So here you go apply two worksheets all using this data source so it's basically the same as what we've
said on the map of Europe and it's applying it to all what she's using not a source.
So now when you click around you will see that both of these charts or both of these worksheets are
being affected by the filter which is good which is consistent which means that we know that in both
cases we're looking at the same year rather than not knowing what year we're looking at in which of
these two worksheets.
So that's how you create your first dashboard.
That's the concept behind it so drag and drop kind of style of operating in the next tutorial.
We will learn how to reduce some really cool stuff.
We will start doing looking at action filters so how to make each of these dashboards clickable so that
they interact with each other.
I'm making a dashboard interactive and we'll look at some other stuff as well in the section of the
course.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then happy analyzing.