Hello and welcome back so of course in Tablo in the Bruce tutorial we learn how to pivot our daughter.
And today we will look at a feature which was introduced in tablet 9 which is called split.
So this split feature allows you to split one column into multiple calls and to be frank it's not very
applicable in our specific case because our columns look as they should.
But I would just want to show you this feature because I think it can be very handy when you have certain
types of data.
For instance if you have customer data then you might have a column which has their full name but you
want to split it into first name and last name and so that can be easily done.
And we'll just have a look at an example with this call and we'll be using the regions call to perform
this example even though we don't really we actually don't need to do this in this specific data set.
But nevertheless just for argument's sake we'll pretend that this is a name and surname and we will
do what we want to split out the surname out of this data.
So let's assume that the last word so that comes after a space.
In this case America is a surname and everything before that is the first name.
And you just want to split out the last o the surname so in this case would be East.
In this case are Americans on.
So you can really easily do that.
All you have to do is once again click this dropdown select split and then say what.
What's a word you want to split off.
So you want to split off the last one word into a column and use a separator which is in our case is
going to be a space.
Click OK and there you go.
So you got you got the last words separate separated its own into its own column.
So here you've got oh once again if there's only one word you'll take that word.
But in this case has got America.
This case has got East and so on.
So let's one on one more or you can split or you can split what you can do is you can split all words
but find all the words are separated by spaces and you'll find all the words.
So here it is it Europe new members into Europe new members Russia Turkey and other Europe Russia Turkey
and other Europe.
So as you can see that's a very powerful feature.
If your daughter is not prepared in the sense that it's got a name and surname for example in one column
and that can be very useful as well not only will excel files like with Excel it's not that hard to
actually go into Excel and perform that split yourself here but sometimes you might be getting data
from a database or from other locations where you cannot make adjustments so before you if you do want
to make adjustments before you send it into Tablo you would have to exported into Excel or some other
software make the adjustments and then then taken a tablet.
While you don't have to do that anymore now you can just do all of this in Tablo.
So there you go that's how to use the Split function.
And next time we will look at metadata I look forward to seeing you on that tutorial.
And until then happy analyzing.