Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo in today's tutorial we will finally create awesome visualization
and get to that deriving those insights.
But let's take a step back for a moment and look at what we've actually achieved.
So firstly we have been able to connect to a PDA fall a read only static fall and extract the data from
that obtained from an open source data provider.
We have been able to combine that with special data which is not available with Intel blood beach or
pox and get the proper light out of each of these parks in terms of the size they form and also the
distribution around the city.
We've also managed to iron out a couple of data integrity issues which is of paramount importance.
And therefore this was no easy feat and such a valuable skill to have learned.
But let's get back to solving the business case.
All right.
We already have geometry onto our sheet.
Next we'll take the Pawk name and put that into detail.
And the reason for that is at the moment it is just showing one big polygon and we need to actually
break it up so we can see where each of the different shapes starts and end.
So we can just do that by adding it to the detail tab.
Now next we can also just take the incidents and add that color and make sure that that's some of incidence.
And we know we want to just make it give it a bit more punch to it and let's use temperature diverging
take from a green to a red and immediately we can see where the box or the more problematic box.
All I do think that the borders are creating a bit of a you know if effect here which we don't want.
So let's just take the borders off.
And that looks much neater now we could even see that much smaller parks as well.
What we also do is just to take the city of Daraa put that on two fold up and we want to select all
of them because this will allow us if we do show the photo.
And let's just bring it over here.
It's also selected as a single dropdown but this will also allow us to navigate the city borough by
borough.
As you can see as we scroll through them we can see what they're look like now how it works in New York
is that each city borough is funny enough.
Also a county within the state.
So what we could do is we can just use the map layers and also just take the county borders and that
would actually break them up quite nicely into different boroughs.
And on top of that we can select the county names but the county names funny enough is not exactly the
same as the borough names.
So for that reason the bill actually just Antek them.
For instance if you look at Richmond over there that in any case it's actually the Staten Island although
it's called an ADA Staten Island So what we'll do is we'll just to avoid any confusion we'll take off
the county names and we can then just rename these using an alias and we can just update these aliases.
So if we keep areas over there we can take the update to Brooklyn.
Then two men.
Q To Queens on Staten Island.
You know that refers to Richmond and then good old Bronx and hit enter.
OK.
Now we are able to navigate city Barnabei City bar to see which parks have the most incidents.
Now seeing as we are able to navigate to these areas some of these parks have you know obviously that
color is adapted to the number of incidents.
And this is not correct.
We want to keep the same color writing across all of them.
So if we go into color and just edit this we can just fix the start and end because we know the maximum
is six and the minimums zero and we can just hits a plot.
Now if we do go in again you can see that it's not that dog afraid raid that he used to be when we did
it.
The that was updated the color rating was updated for this specific focus or falter.
Let's also just update our sheet them over yet because what we want to cool those is the New York City
parks and we just want to put the borrower name in there so we can just pick it up from there instead
insert option over there with the city borough.
And we can actually just make that bold and weakening to decrease the size to 24 both of these.
And just a plus.
So if we do navigate between now we are able to see which one we are working with to arrive in the title.
So handy stuff as well.
But I also like to do is in our map if you go into map options you're able to see the scale and obviously
want to say this to us as we work in the US.
So now you get a scale over there.
So if you are focusing on a specific area and you can see our changes on Staten Island the scallies
one mile and in Queens It's two miles so obviously depends on the size of your visualization then you're
able to relate on how far and how close each of these sections are.
Each of these talks to each other now you can also navigate the city by not only looking at this specific
borough but but just by zooming in and then immediately you can see even the smaller parks where they
have more of a number of incidents.
So pretty handy stuff indeed.
So pretty cool way to navigate this as well.
And this also answers our brief that we've set out to do and I'm sure Atlanta will be super happy with
what we are delivering now.
That is how you connect and combine PBS special falls in your data import your data ensure data integrity
create custom Geographic polygons using data sources from open source platforms.
Pretty awesome stuff indeed.
And you can be really proud of yourself not in the next tutorial.
We'll be looking at a brand new business case.
And look at some improvements in Tablo relating to how we use to stirps and even look at a brand new
chart type.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.