Hello and welcome back to our course on tabbouleh in today's tutorial we will look at our brand new
business challenge as well as learn how to create a step and jump on charts.
First let's start off by having a look at our business challenge.
So we are looking at the New York state salary analysis.
Now you are required to build a visualization within tabla doing an analysis of average salary across
industries for the state of New York.
The analysis needs to have the following.
Firstly an average annual salary by county which needs to be displayed on a map.
We need to show the top five highest earning industries by county and last include a time series analysis
of the average annual salary per county.
Now the client has some specific requirements and they do not.
They've mentioned that they do not want to see separate graphs on different sheets and also don't want
to work with a dashboard.
So some limitations they not.
They mentioned that they would like all information contained within a single sheet with pop up charts
while the map is being explored so it will have to be innovative here let's have a look at the data
that we are working with.
So if we have a look we can see that the Foglio school the quarterly census of employment and wages
annual data beginning 2000 and this is a C as V fall.
If we have a look at it in Excel we can see that it's got quite a number of rows if we scroll down and
we have information relating to on different levels of granularity.
We are obviously only interested in the average annual salary so we'll be ignoring the the the establishment.
The average employment and total wage we've got Yeah that is for.
So that will help us to build our time series analysis.
And then we have in two fields called the icy Asen in Essie's title.
Now those are the North American industry classification system titles.
So what that means is that it has different levels so for one character is your highest level two characters
like a one and or one would be second level three characters or third level and so forth.
So something that has three characters and starting with one one would be related to agriculture.
These are crop production.
These four or five would be related to that.
So we need to factor this into account when we work with our data to ensure that we work with the right
level.
Another complexity with this data is we've got different area types.
We've got state.
We know we are looking for county we found County and there is a whole bunch of different levels of
granularity that to be worked with.
So we've got our area.
And then the area that that translates to.
So we will have to do a bit of data cleaning once we import this into tabla.
So talking about that let's open Tablo we will connect to this quite easily Luckily this time by just
using the text file because we Noticias V and we will just open it and we can see it Brading properly.
There is nothing strange happening in this fall but now the clean up needs to happen.
Now we know the area outside.
We're looking for is only county so we can just add a data source format by looking at the area top
and saying we only want the county to be included in there.
All right.
And we can just change our area now to be called County and we also know that this is a geographic and
also we can just change it right now and change it to a county not a country but a county.
All right then let's look at the icy roads or the industry.
So I'll just read and there's the industry because that's what we all want in the end of the preparation
of our data.
But we will need to make sure to exclude everything on specific levels.
And for this specific one level two will be more than sufficient so that will be everything with two
numbers.
And actually this change the strings.
It's not really a number.
We want to use this as a number.
So when these two characters in the string we would like to see that level that's agriculture for instance
and utilities and construction we don't really care about the lower levels and we don't want to go up
one level.
But how do we tell to blow to only look at this level.
So we can easily do that by creating a calculated field and that new vehicle just school this level
and then we will use the lane function.
So the main function is for string functions and that's also why we change that to a string.
And if we just look at what Lean does it returns the number of characters in the given string.
So it just basically counts the number that's there.
So for instance that is level 2.
Because it's two characters that's level three because of the three characters.
And that's exactly what we wanted to add another yet another deciles full to one level way we just want
to see level 2 so we can exclude one and we can exclude three.
So just.
And that reduces our information significantly in terms of the number of records.
And we did mention we don't really want these fields we won't really work with him so we can just hide
them and that is what we'll work with.
So we've got our area up which we know is county we've got the county name then also the actual level
of the code which we're not going to use in the visualization but is needed for the data cleanup.
And then also the industry and the average annual salary.
Now let's actually create our first chart as well without further ado.
So if we go into our first sheet we'll be looking at firstly creating the time series analysis.
So for that we know we need to put a year into columns because that we want our time series to run from
left to right and we know we want to have the average annual salary we can put that in rows but not
aggregated to some but aggregate to average.
And we know that we can now see that what the average is over all counties and we will break this down
later on into each specific county.
But for now this is our chart.
But what we know that the client wants is positive detail.
Is this trend over yet and is not it's nice to see the overall trend but it's not easy to distinguish.
You know what exactly the jump has been or the amount of increase or decrease has been or even any decrease
as well.
You know there's one over there.
So in that case we could obviously go into our both and change the line.
And this is where we found our step and our job charts.
So if we look at step for instance you can see it literally creates a resemblance of steps of a building.
So where it's easy to see that where there was an increase in both these years there was a big increase
in 2003.
They was in 2000.
So this works really well for four discrete measures where you want to see the impact and even they
look interesting that is there was a decline and we would not have seen that if I just undo that to
our previous job.
That almost looks like a straight line doesn't look like decreased and the same we can do obviously
with the jump lines.
But in this case I think this will look better for visualization and then we can just call this our
step line chart.
As simple as that.
And in the next to Tauriel we will be building the rest of the visualizations and combining these and
see how we can use to alter IPs to our advantage in answering this brief.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing.