Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo and in the previous tutorials we prepared all the worksheets
for our segmentation dashboard.
So we've got a map we've got gender split in a pie chart.
We've got two distributions one by age and one by balance and we've got a tree map of job because vacations.
And today we're going to put all of this into one dashboard one powerful awesome looking dashboard.
And now that we've got them all prepared it's going to be quite quick and easy to put them all together
into one dashboard.
So let's go ahead and get started on it.
We're going to click this button here.
And new dashboard which brings up a new blank dashboard for us to work with.
Now if we wanted to we could change the size because it is a bit big and we could change to a different
size over here or select our own size.
But instead what I'm going to do is I'm just going to expand this window.
And now we will work with this full space and fill it up with colors.
All right so we'll start by dragging our worksheets into this blank space so I'll take the map we'll
drag it in here then it'll take distribution by let's take balance and put it in here.
The solution by age will put in here as well.
Now as you can see some things that are appearing on the right here are some controls.
Obviously we don't need this one as we discussed we're not going to visually compare the different shades
of green.
Same thing for the blue.
The parameters appeared for us here as well.
Now we're going to take the gender will drag it in underneath this box over here.
Once again we don't need male female because it is very intuitive.
We made it intuitive.
Blue is a male pink is female and we'll get rid of the number of records this color size legend completely
not adding any value here and we'll take a job classification we'll try to get underneath here as well
because we don't need this legend because it is spelt out in our tree map.
OK.
So that's our raw information in our dashboard which we can start working with now.
We're going to quickly make it look much better.
So that's a format that a little bit.
Let's give these guys some more room maybe up to here with the map a bit more room OK.
What else.
The tree map is a bit big.
The pie charts a bit small so if something is a bit smaller it's easy to fix it up here and then you
just go for pie charts specifically you just go to the pie chart and you change the size so it just
fits in your box.
Now we'll go to the tree map job classification and we will make this one small or so that we can work
with it further in Dashboard.
So you just generally always make something smaller first and then you make it bigger.
OK so there we go.
So sometimes you will get these elements that you can't reduce.
You can just go past that and what you need to do is nudge this chart down with the chart above for
instance like this or just kind of reset everything to fit your needs at the bottom over here.
So Also what do we need to do before we format this part of the chart.
Is change the formatting here because you can see it's not in line with everything else it's smaller.
So we're going to format legends and the title we're going to make it 12 and bold and perhaps the font
of the legend doesn't really have to be 12 but at least 10 and also bold.
And now if we do that there we go and you can see these parameters they collapse into this new format
which is good either.
Either way works for us.
So basically if we have the space if we can move our chart a bit down let's say all pie chart.
There we go.
Now we probably need to make the size a little bit smaller so that the percentages are out of the chart
itself.
And now perhaps we can make this one a bit bigger.
There is a bit of like tedious clicking around but eventually you will get there.
There we go.
So that could work.
Probably in this case we need to make these charts a bit smaller again or the other option is fix this
up like this as it was just now.
So there we go probably that's that's a better option because we don't need that much space for our
parameter controls.
So that's how our dashboard looks at the moment.
We just have to look around and see if there's any anything that would like to change perhaps maybe
rotate these labels.
And also you can see that the parameters do control your charts and at the same time the chart shrinks
to fit inside the dashboard which is good.
One more thing is that if your parameter for some reason hasn't been added to the dashboard or you deleted
it it's very easy to bring it back.
So just cancel that and just as you would do for filter you go not quick filter's but go parameters
and you add the parameter back in.
So there we go and your parameters here Sibyls groups is above because submission by balances at the
top age groups is at the bottom.
So put that at the bottom.
That's pretty much it for the first part of the dashboard process in the next tutorial we will make
this dashboard interactive and adjust the colors a little bit for the dashboard to look awesome.
I look forward to seeing you then and until next time I'll be analyzing.