Highs and welcome to this new tutorial and this one which is going to be quick and easy we're going
to create the inverse dictionary of the answers were in dictionary.
Why do we need to do that.
That's because we will need inverse mapping from the integers to the answers words in the implementation
of the sectors like model.
And we actually just need for the answers words in dictionary and not the questions word.
So this will be very quick.
And the other reason why I wanted to make it a separate tutorial is that in Python you have to know
the trick to Inv. a dictionary that is to get the inverse mapping of a dictionary and put that in the
dictionary because you will need to do that a lot whether you are doing deep learning an LP or other
kind of coding.
You need to know the trick to Inv. a dictionary.
And so since we needed here I think that's perfect for you to get the trick.
So let's do it.
It's actually going to take one line of code it's very easy to do once you know the trick.
And we need to start by choosing a name for that dictionary because we're creating a new dictionary
which will be the inverse dictionary of the answers words to in dictionary.
So well you can guess what this name of the dictionary is going to be since we're doing the inverse
mapping we're mapping from the answers integers to the word and therefore we're going to call that dictionary
answers.
And two word.
All right.
That's our new dictionary.
And the trick now to invert a mapping is just to do this.
Dictionaries are always in brackets like that.
But then we're going to make a for loop inside these brackets.
And so what we're going to do is introduce a new variable here which will be one of the loop variables.
Then I'm going to call w underscore II because it corresponds to word integers.
So that's going to be the integers of the word.
In this new dictionary.
So w underscore I call an then W. which will correspond to the word.
And now it's important to understand that w underscore I corresponds to the values of the dictionaries.
And w here corresponds to the key and the fires to this new dictionary.
All right.
And then we need to start to follow up.
So we are here for then we need to take our words again w Cunha R word integers w underscore I and these
guys we're going to take them from our previous dictionary that we're trying to inverse the mapping
and that is the answers words to and dictionaries.
I'm going to take that here.
Copy and paste that here.
Answers words to it but then be careful to make sure we get w that is the words which are the key identifiers
in the previous dictionary and the words integers W. underscore I which are the values of the same Brydges
dictionary.
Well we need to get them by adding that items and parenthesis by adding that items parenthesis we will
get separately the words.
That is the key identifiers and the words integers that is the values of the dictionary are right and
then that said you now know how to inverse the mapping of a dictionary by creating and one which is
the inverse dictionary.
So perfect let's execute this.
There we go.
Executed and now we have our inversed dictionary for the answers we can have a look.
Where is it.
It is actually write here answers in two word will look and perfect this is exactly what we want.
As you can see now the keys are the integers.
And for each of these keys we have different words.
So we clearly have a mapping from unique integers to unique words.
So that's perfect.
We now got where we wanted which will I remind be useful for the implementation of the sectors.
So we're done with this new step.
Now we're going to move on to the next step.
It's almost over we have three or four steps left.
We now need to add the end of string token the iOS that we created in the previous tutorial.
This one here to the end of every answer.
And that's very important because that's for the decoding part of the SEC the SEC and the decoding part
of the SEC the SEC 22 and the decoding with this POS token and the string.
So we need to add this to the end of every answer we'll make a quick follow up for that.
That will be easy.
And then we'll move on to the last two big steps of this data processing part.
And by the way this natural language processing part because we're clearly doing some natural language
processing that will considerably improve the training process.
So we'll do that in the next tutorials.
And until then and the penalty.