Hayes and welcome to this new tutorial and this one we're going to make a function that will convert
the questions that are right now in strings to list of encoding integers and why are we doing this.
That's because we will need that function for this final step right after this to toile to set up the
chat between a chat but and us.
So let's make this function.
We start with def.
We're going to call that function converts Well let's say string to int and that function is going to
take two arguments the first one is the question and the second one is word to int which is a dictionary.
So it can either be the questions word in Dictionary or the answers words to any dictionary.
All right so these two arguments.
And now let's define what it has to do first before making that conversion we're going to clean everything
in the question and we have a nice function for that that we made which is the clean text function.
So that's why I'm going to take my question which is one of my argument and I'm going to clean it.
Thanks to the context function.
And of course this quintic function takes the question as input and now we can make the conversion.
And to make that conversion we'll first we will return directly what we want to return.
That is the question as a list of encoding integers.
And therefore since we want to return a list I'm going to introduce here some square brackets and I'm
going to use this for loop inside the list trick that you know we've done several times in this course.
So there we go for.
And we're going to loop over of course the word in the question.
So for word in question and then remember we need to add that split with some parenthesis to get the
words separately.
And so what are we going to do for each of the words in the question.
Well we are going to convert them and for that we're going to use our word to ant dictionary but we're
going to use a trick which is to get function because the problem is that we filtered out some words
that were not frequent.
You know among the least frequent words we filter them out and therefore they do not exist in the dictionary
but they might exist in the question and we're using just get here to make sure that if this nonfiction
word is not found in the dictionary whether out token ID will be returned remember we made an out token
for each of these non-African words and that's why in this get function we are going to input first
the word that we're dealing with right now.
And if this word doesn't exist in the dictionary.
Well we'll return the word to inte dictionary of the key which is the out token.
All right so that it returns the unique integer encoding outspoken otherwise it will get the unique
integer idea including this word based on the mapping of this dictionary.
All right.
And that's it.
That's just a function we had to make here.
Congratulations.
We are ready to set up the chat so we'll do that in the next tutorial.
And until then Id been on the.