Hello and welcome to this new tutorial and this one we're going to do something very important.
We're going to get the training predictions and the test predictions.
So just to make sure you understand we're not starting the training yet.
There is the whole process of the training and you'll see precisely when it starts that's going to be
from the moment we start the for loop over the epochs.
But now we have to get the training predictions and the desperate actions when fitting the model with
the inputs we loaded in this specific line of code.
So here we loaded the inputs the target which is what we need to feed the to on that work with.
And therefore right now what we need to do is get the training and test predictions when in putting
these inputs and targets and learning rate and keep probability into the neural network.
So let's do this.
The good news you know what the good news is is that we have the perfect function for this that will
directly return what we want and that function is of course the last function we made in part two to
stick to sec model which represents of course the whole sectors like.
But as you can see it's a function that returns in the end the training predictions and the test predictions.
So this is going to be a very good stuff to toile we're just going to use this function and input all
its arguments one by one that we now made ready in the previews to toils.
Indeed we prepared the sequence length.
We have the budget size that was in the hyper parameters and the first code section and this part 3.
We also have to keep probability we have the targets and inputs things to the model inputs function.
We got previously and we also have all these parameters.
Basically we have everything to use this sect to sect model function and return the training prediction
and the test predictions.
So let's do this.
It's going to be very easy we'll just have to enter the arguments that the set to signal function one
by one.
All right so since this function returns to training predictions and desperations very simply we're
going to introduce two new variables that are going to be our training predictions and our test predictions.
All right.
Our training operation in our desperations not to be confused with the local variable in the sector
signal function that we defined this time it's the real variables that we will use later on in the training.
So training breaks and desperations that are going to be returned by our SEC to SEC all function.
And now let's put the arguments one by one.
The first one is the inputs.
However I noticed these are not yet in the right shape.
And if you followed one of our other courses like the machinery course or the deep green course I sometimes
used the reshape function by nuns by to reshape the diamond sions of a tensor or a number array when
working with by to get it in the right shape for the model.
And actually that's what we have to do here.
The inputs so far are not in the right shape.
So we going to use kind of the same thing as the reshape function.
By and by but since were working with tons of flow this function is going to be the reverse function
that is going to take the inputs.
Let's not forget the parenthesis here.
The reverse function that basically reverses the dimensions of a tensor.
All right but then remembering the reshape function by non-bio we have to specify minus 1 and 1 to reverse
dimensions of this tensor shape and intensively.
We do it this way with the second argument here which is going to be in square brackets minus 1.
I will of course give the documentation of both this reverse function by tens of flow and the reshape
function by an umpire.
So there we go with our first argument.
So now let's move onto the second argument which I remind is the target.
All right so there we go.
Targets which were already loaded here by calling our modeling function target.
Then the next argument we have to input is to keep probability which is the probability of keeping the
neuron activated during each iteration of the training.
And we got this key parameter at line.
Two hundred and ninety seven that we will later connect to the keep probability variable that we created
at line two hundred and ninety and that is a specific entity of the tensor flow API.
So we will connect that later.
But what we have to input here in this sector signal function is make sure to understand the key prob
variable returns by the model input function and that's it.
The key probability tens of loci will actually connect them later when running the session with the
run method of our session object and that will be in the big for loop over the epochs of the training.
So keep it up.
Then the next one is the batch size All right always working with batches when doing deep learning.
And we get our budget size here 64 meaning that there are going to be 64 inputs and targets in each
batch batch size then the next one is the sequence length which we just got here.
And then the next argument is going to be the length of our answers.
Words 2 and dictionary.
Then I'm going to copy this because the next argument is going to be the land of the questions words
in the dictionary.
So perfect.
Then the next argument is going to be the encoding embedding size which I remind is the number of columns
in the embeddings matrix.
Each of these columns corresponding to an embedding value.
And then again I'm going to copy this because the next argument after that is going to be the embedding
size.
This time the decoding matrix the decoding embedding size.
All right then the next argument is going to be the Arnon size which we also got here and the hyper
parameters the size of 512.
All right.
And then two more arguments to go the next one is the number of layers.
And that again we got when setting the hyper parameters number of layers equal 3.
Meaning that there are going to be three layers in the cells of our record neural networks both the
one of the encoder and the one of the decoder to numb layers.
And finally the last one which is our dictionary questions words to it.
So basically now we are ready to execute this code section execute to get our training protections in
our test predictions.
Perfect.
So now we're getting closer and closer to the big loop of the training.
But we're not there yet.
We have a few remaining steps to do and we'll do them in the next intervals toils until then Id been
on the.