[Autogenerated] Hi, My name is Kevin Jones,
and this is the securing the application with Spring
Security chapter from the architect ING web application
with spring class from Pluralsight.
So, up until now,
we've built the application using a mixture of
horizontal design on vertical design.
We've added repositories.
We've added services.
We've added tests.
Now what we're going to do is take a look at how it is.
We have security to the application.
We want to add both authentication and a
authorization support to the application.
We'll talk about how they differ in a moment.
We're going to use spring security to do this, so authentication is who are you?
But I logged onto an application to give it some credentials,
such as a username on password.
And given these credentials, these application will know who I am,
and it may assign some roles to me.
Based on who I am on may be based on those roles.
The application will then decide what I'm authorized to do.
So authentication is working out who this user is.
Authorization is allowing the user to do certain things based on that identity.
Spring security is a set of libraries that come with spring.
They allow us to easily and security into an application.
It's a nice library.
It's very extensible and very easy to use. I will use that library in this module.