[Autogenerated] so I'm sure that many of you have come across the idea of
what's known as physical design by physical design.
In this case,
I mean designing the application so it matches the
physical characteristics of the system.
Our system will simply have a database in our code.
We have a section of code, maybe a project dedicated entirely to the database.
And these projects are called repositories.
They will be entities involved in database access.
Well, typically also have a set of services.
These services will wrap up the database access and again,
typically within the application lovey services project on
inside of that services project will place all of the services
that are associated with the database.
So inside here we may have an authentication service.
We may have a blog services.
We may have an article, services, whatever services our application offers,
but they'll follow the physical design.
There will be one project called services on Inside.
This project will contain all of the sources for all of our services.
Then you have a web project.
And a web project will contain all the things to do with the web.
So inside here we have the controllers.
We have the views we'll have.
All the access to the web would structural a source code to follow
this physical structure to follow this architectures.
Do you have a web project?
And I was source code.
We have a services project and I was source code ID going to
database project and I was source code.
So with the logical design,
we break our application down into features on each of
these features would have its own project.
She may have a blog feature we may have an article feature on each of
those would be its own project on each of these would typically consist
off one or maybe more than ___ ___ files.
Now we're going to find we can't always do this.
They're going to be some features across all of the projects.
So, for example, the web here,
we need to deploy a single web project on to one or more
physical pieces of hardware inside the web here.
This will almost certainly create a single web project to hold all
the things that make up the Web application.
Same thing is true for database entities.
If I have a database, I love many entities for their database.
Those entities are going to be related in some way to
love primary keys and foreign keys.
If we try and place each database entity into its own project,
that would end up with many, many cross project relationships.
We may end up with circle dependencies,
so we typically break the entities out into its own
project on We'll see how we evolved on.
We'll see how we evolved to this as you work through the
application that we're going to build here.
So typically what happens with these projects is that the logical projects
cut across the physical tears to create a feature on that feature will have
code that probably runs as part of the web,
part of the services and part of the database.
So each feature is like a horizontal cat across the different services.
So we lay our features onto the tears themselves,
so there are benefits to using the logical design against the physical design. But there are also drawbacks on that's what we'll take a look at now