[Autogenerated] so to manage our database.
On in particular, to manage this schema of the database,
we're going to use something called migrations.
Migrations are snippets.
The change the database schemer we can use the snippets to
create tables and a to altar tables.
Snippets are often written in SQL.
However, they could be written in some of the language.
So depending on the tool you use snippet, you right.
Could be a snippet of SQL that we apply to the database.
Or we could write the snip in some other language.
Maybe Java an API groovy on depending on the language you're using,
we could write a snippet in the language that you're more familiar with,
and that might give you more flexibility in the things you want to do.
It might also make this snippet database independent.
One of the issues you might have a SQL is you might
need to write database specific SQL.
And if you try to support multiple databases,
using some other language for the snippet could help you write the database.
Independent snippets Migrations originally came from the ruby world
in Ruby on Rails pattern called active record.
One of the ways I'm probably the most common way of creating a
managing or database schemers was to use Ruby on Rails,
so other languages were inspired by this on.
Now we have migrations in, for example,
Microsoft .NET environment and certainly have migrations in Java.
And a many tools to do this on the one we're going to
use is something called Flyway.
So here we have a migration and see the at the Migration is written in SQL.
On this migration is going to create a table the tables called articles.
We want to apply that migration to this database.
So when we apply the migration to the database,
we create the table within the database.
So now we have a table.
It's got some columns these columns of types on.
Then we decide the latest stage that this table isn't quite right.
We want to add something else so we can create another migration.
In this case, we're going to alter the table So we can see the at our migrations,
concrete's tables and a schema.
They can alter the schema and can also delete things from the schemer.
We can also add data to the schemer.
Essentially,
anything we can do in SQL we can do us part of our migration
when we add the migration to the database.
Then we update the table.
So now we have another column in the table called Title on the Tables now,
in a state that we'd like it to be so migrations
have pros and cons with migrations.
It's easy to manage database changes.
We write another snippet, we can, then use that snippet to update the database.
It's easy to recreate the database we can simply take all of our
migrations and rerun them against any database that would recreate
the database to the state it should be in.
One great thing about migrations is that they're under source control.
So all of our migration is going to the source
control system and easily versioning.
You can easily pull them out of the source control
and update them when we need to.
They're not managed by DBS.
We don't have a third person involved here to manage our database.
There's no need to go to someone else and say, Can you do this for me?
This is all managed by the team.
We can run multiple independent upgrades of a database,
so we can right snippet to,
uh played small parts of the schemer and then run the
snippets where and when we need to.
In general, these things work across.
Database is so a migration URL library will provide a mechanism so we can apply.
This scheme is too many different types of database.
We don't necessarily need to write SQL for that specific flavor database,
such as my SQL post rows,
SQL SQL Server or whatever it might be now for the cons.
Well, they're not managed by a d B a.
So this could be a good thing.
It can also be a bad thing because the DB A knows all about
database is the diva is a person that knows the best way to
create a database until layout the database.
So leaving this in the hand of a developer might not always be a good thing.
Database is could be difficult diversion as well.
So while the actual snippets are in source control,
the actual state of a database at a given point of time can be harder to manage.
You also often end up with many small files,
so you tend to want to apply small migrations.
To a schemer on this means you have lots and lots of small migration files.
What some places do is after a certain amount of time,
take the migrations and actually put them into a single migration script.
On inside that script, they normalize the migration.
So in our previous example,
where we had to create table followed by an altar table,
what you would do is simply take this to migrations movement to one file,
which would be a single create table with the altar table.
Change may part of this migration,
and you might want to do that at a well known part of the project.
And even though we said these things work across,
database is, this isn't always true,
so that are gonna be occasions where you need to
write database specific migrations.
If you work with more than one database and a again, depending on your organization, this may or may not be an issue for you.