[Autogenerated] we saw previously in the web to we had a controller.
Our article controller and a controller used the repository.
What?
We no longer want to use this repository.
Instead, what we want to use is our jacket article, services.
So let's rename this from repository to service on
rename the Associative variables as well.
So instead of our article repository, we don't use our jacket article services.
We also need to inject that,
so that will be here on now we have access to the
service rather than the repository.
Now we also need to update the methods this was calling Final a.
Now we need to call get or articles on the service instead.
And that returns a list of get jacket article rather than a list of entities.
So here we have our get all articles and get all articles,
returns, a list of jacket article.
So let's use of are here to make this slightly easier.
Then after that, then the code the same.
So the services articles also has a title.
So we get the title out of these service articles we can then pass
the articles back to the page for the page to use.
So in the control we've updated.
We're trying to inject this service,
but we need to tell spring that this services injectable in
the same way that we can inject repository.
So back in my service code, I need to add an annotation to this.
I need to say at service on in the same way that we add at
Repository to tell spring that as well as being named this
thing was a repository on my service.
We add at services on it says this thing as well as being named is a service.
And again, this is a Met annotation.
Once we have that, I should be able to run the project.
If I flip across the Chrome and go to local host 80 81 then sure enough,
we're getting data again.
So again, everything is happy.
But now we're going through a service rather than going through the repository directly