[Autogenerated] So one of the things I mentioned at the start of this
cause was about going through some of my four processes.
For example, here we're using a repository.
We have a jacket repository project.
But if I look in this repository, we have no repository classes.
What we have instead now are just models.
These are just the entities for our project.
That's what I should do is to rename this from
jacket repository to jacket entities.
So even though we're inside idea here, this is all based on a great URL file.
So what I'll do is the renaming through the great
URL file on the file system on, then reimport the project.
So, in the root project, if I open up my settings,
Doc Raedle, it says, jacket repository.
I'm going to change this to jacket entities on then in the bill grade.
URL far for this Everywhere I have a jacket repository.
I'm going to change that to jacket entities.
So we have a dependency here.
We have a reference here.
I'll add a base project entry as well for this.
So having done that and also rename this from jacket
repository to jacket entities on the file system.
So here in the project folder,
we have a jacket repository folder and I'll rename that to jacket entities.
And if I do that on,
go back into idea we can See already ideas found
that the far system has changed,
but it doesn't yet know the jacket entities is a
project because we haven't reimported it.
So I got a grade.
All do a refresh.
And sure enough, it now knows that jacket entities where it should be.
If I run this, sure enough is built on run.
Okay?
And if I go back into Chrome and a refresh, then the date is there a swell?
So this seems sensible.
It seems more realistic here Oven entities project
rather than a repositories project.
When you're building software, naming is really important. So having these names correct seems to be the right thing to do.