Hello everyone and welcome to the art data frames section of this course and this section of the Course
will start off by learning the basics of the data frame how to index and select data from a data frame
and then we'll have a two part series of lectures on an overview of all the data frame operations things
such as selecting rows selecting columns and transformations on a data frame etc..
Data frames are the workhorse of our.
So this is one of the most vital sections in the course to really understand.
Well after we learn how to work with data frames we'll have a data frame training exercise to test your
understanding.
Let's go ahead and get started.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture