Hello everyone and welcome to an introduction to the nearest neighbors lecture and this lecture will
discuss the Kinnear's neighbor's algorithm and how to use it for classification problems to understand
the mathematics behind this algorithm.
Go ahead and finish reading Chapter 4 of an introduction to statistical learning cannoneers neighbors
sometimes known as k and an is a classification algorithm that operates on a very simple principle.
It's actually just best shown through example.
Imagine we have some imaginary data on dogs and horses with heights and weights of these dog and horse
data points.
If we plot them out it looks something like this.
Again this is just imaginary data so don't worry about the weights and the heights.
Obviously you're not going to have a 500 pound dog but here we have red points indicating horses and
blue points the kitting dogs.
This is our training data but we want to know is if we get an animal where we only know the height and
weight we want to predict if that new data point is a horse or a dog.
Again we're just trying to classify this new data point.
Here we can kind of already see that based on where the green point lies in association fits neighboring
points.
It's kind of easy to predict certain points.
For example this top point in green would probably be a horse since all the points around it are red
horse points.
Likewise the points all the way at the bottom left that's green would likely be a dog since the nearest
points to it are all blue points indicating their dogs want to expand on this idea and formalize it
.
That's where K the neighbor's algorithm comes to play.
The training algorithm is very simple.
You simply store all the data and the prediction algorithm for new test points.
Works like this.
You calculate the distance from X to all the points in your data X indicating that particular new data
point.
Then you sort the points in your data by increasing distance from X.
Then you predict the majority label of the K K being a number.
Closest points choosing a k it will affect what class a new point is assigned to.
Let's go ahead and look at another example here.
I've plotted out our training data which is just yellow points in class A.
And purple points in class B.
This red star indicates a few points I want to predict whether this point belongs to class A or class
B.
If I choose k equals 3 then I look at the three nearest neighbors to this new point.
In this case I have two purple ones and one yellow one are a class a so with equal to three I will predict
that this you redstart point belongs to class B purple.
However if I set equal to 6 I will actually have a majority of yellow or class 8 points meaning if I
have capless 6 I would predict that the new point belongs to a class A choosing a K will affect what
class a new point is assigned to.
So if we look back on our horse vs dog we can here see the plotted effects of various k values by choose
cake was to 1 and then actually pick up a lot of noise.
But as I go larger and larger k values you'll notice I smooth out and create more of a bias in my model
or I get a cleaner cut off at the cost of mislabeling some points.
The prose of the cannoneers neighbors algorithm is that it's very simple.
The training is very trivial you just sort your data.
It works if any number of classes.
It's really easy to add more data and it has very few parameters.
The only parameters being that K which is how many points are you going to look at that are next to
your new test point and then whatever distance metric you're using.
If you want to learn more about distance metrics go ahead and finish reading Chapter 4.
But the distance metric is just how you're actually defining mathematically.
The distance between your new test point and the old training points.
The cons of this algorithm is that there's a high prediction cost and it's worse for large data sets
because you're having to sort this entire large dataset.
There's a high prediction cost and testing out what points are closest to this new data point.
It's also not good with high dimensional data as your features increase and you get higher that mentions
year data.
It's going to throw off your ability to measure distances in various dimensions.
Also categorical features don't work well.
K nearest neighbors.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio and begin to explore an example.
Then you're going to have a project to test your understanding of the nearest neighbors algorithm thinks
everyone will see at the next lecture.