Hello everyone and welcome to the our major c section of this course.
Now that you've learned about the basic data types and R and vector basics and then your first basic
training exercise you're ready to expand the level up your knowledge and are and start learning about
are matrices aren't matrices are going to allow us to store data to that mentioned really and they will
be the stepping stone to learning about our data frames.
In this section of course we'll learn how to create a matrix perform operations and arithmetic using
matrices then we'll learn how to select an index data from the Matrix we'll learn how to make matrices
into categorical matrices through the factor function and then finally we'll have a matrix training
exercise.
Let's go ahead and get started.
I'll see at the next lecture