Hello everyone and welcome to an introduction to linear regression in this lecture We'll discuss the
history and background of linear regression.
The basic concept behind the linear regression and will end with showing how models can actually be
built in are.
If you want the mathematical background behind linear regression.
Go ahead and read chapters 2 and 3 of an introduction to statistical learning before actually approaching
this lecture.
Moving along.
Let's go ahead and start the history of linear regression.
This all started in the 1800s of a guy named Francis Galton.
Galton was studying the relationship between parents and their children particular.
He investigated the relationship between the heights of fathers and their sons.
What he discovered was that a man's son tended to be roughly as tall as his father.
However Galton's breakthrough was at the son's height tended to be closer to the overall average height
of all people.
Let's go ahead and take Shaquille O'Neal as an example.
He's a very famous basketball player.
Shaq is really tall seven feet one inch.
Or if you using the metric system that's 2.2 meters ish.
If Shaq has a son chances are the sun's going to be pretty tall too.
However Shaq is such an anomaly or an outlier that there's also a very good chance that his son will
not be as tall as Shaq.
Turns out that is the case.
Shaq's son is pretty tall six feet seven inches but not nearly as tall as his dad.
Galton called this particular phenomenon regression as in a father son's height tends to regress or
drift towards the mean which is the average height.
And that's where the term regression comes from.
Let's go out and take the simplest example possible.
We'll go ahead and calculate a regression with only two data points.
Here I have two little tiny data points on a G-G plot graph.
All we're trying to do when we calculate a regression line is to draw a line that's as close to every
dot as possible.
Here it's very easy because we just have two dots.
Is the simplest example we can do for classically regression or the least squares method that you read
about in the reading in the introduction to us to skal learning you only measure the closeness in the
up and down the reaction.
So how far in the up and down the action or that y axis you are from the line you drew that regression
line to the rest of the points.
Now wouldn't it be great if we could apply this same concept to a graph of more than just two data points
.
More likely our data is going to look something like this on the right here on the y axis we have a
Sun site and on the x axis we have a father site.
By doing this we could actually take multiple men and their sons heights and do things like tell a man
how tall we would expect his son to be before he even has a son who would try to predict that Sun's
height based off of the father's type.
Our goal of linear regression is to minimize that vertical distance between all the data points and
our line.
So in determining the best line we are attempting to minimize the distance between all the points and
their distance to our line.
There's lots of different ways to minimize this sum of squared errors some of absolute errors etc. but
all of these methods have a general goal of minimizing the distance between those points and the regression
line formulas that are take the form why tilde x.
If you see the diagram here below this is how we actually build models in our.
If you want to add more predicter variables you just go ahead and use the plus sign.
Let's go out and break down what's written here all the way on the left.
We have a variable called Model that's the R object.
We're going to save our result and then we have our assignment operator the arrow and we begin by saying
linear regression modeling command.
So that linear regression modeling command is going to be the actual modeling function.
Now we're going to be replacing that actual function depending on what machine learning model for linear
regression will use l m meaning linear model.
Then the first thing we pass is the quantity we want to predict.
In this example they're trying to predict some sort of log quantity but as we'll see later on we can
actually put any quantity or any feature from the variable as what we want to predict.
Then you have the tilt sign and your actual formula.
So you put in the variables that are available to make the prediction.
Then finally you add in data equals and then your data frame to use for training your model.
Once you've trained your model you can predict off your model.
You'll go ahead and Storm Prediction as some sort of new column using the Predict command this predict
function.
All I will do is pass in the linear regression model or later on will see that it can pass in any other
model and then we pass a new data test set the data to use in prediction.
We can also do the same operation on a training data.
Let's go ahead and go to our studio in the next lecture and begin to explore an example.
Then you'll have a project to test your own understanding.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture