Hello everyone and welcome to the introduction to neural networks lecture.
I'm super excited for this lecture because after discussing supervised learning topics and unsupervised
learning topics we're finally at reinforcement learning neural networks is our first stepping stone
to understanding things such as deep learning.
There's no official reading assignment for this lecture but I would still suggest you go ahead and browse
through the Wikipedia articles on neural networks and reinforcement learning before viewing this lecture
.
Let's go ahead and get started.
Your own networks are modeled after biological neural networks and attempt to allow computers to learn
in a similar manner to humans through reinforcement learning.
There's lots of use cases for neural networks.
A few examples would be things like pattern recognition time series predictions.
Signal Processing anomaly detection and later on through the use of neuron that works can even do things
like controlling self-driving vehicles.
The human brain has interconnected neurons with dendrites that received inputs and then based off those
inputs produce an electrical signal output to another neuron and that's the concept we're going to be
trying to recreate through artificial neural networks or a an end.
Let's talk about why we want to even develop neural networks to begin with.
There are problems that are difficult for humans but easy for computers.
Things such as multiplying two large numbers together are easy for computers to solve but difficult
for humans to do in their head.
Then there are problems that are easier for humans but difficult for computers such as recognising pictures
of people or giving an image and describing the image and what's inside that picture.
Neural networks attempt to solve problems that would normally be easy for humans but hard for computers
.
Let's start by looking at the simplest neural network possible.
The Perceptor from a preset truck consists of one or more inputs a processor and a single output.
A perception follows the feed forward model meaning the inputs are sent into the neuron are processed
and then result in an output.
So for this figure below you would read this from left to right.
You have input 0 input 1 going into the preprocessor and then being output it is some sort of result
after being processed.
A perception process follows four main steps.
First you receive the inputs to you put some sort of weights on those inputs three you sum those inputs
and then for you process those inputs and generates some sort of output.
Let's go ahead and walk through the very simple example.
Say we have a perception of two inputs we'll say Input 1 is x 1 equals 12 we'll say Input 1 is x 2 equal
to for each input that is sent into the NIRA must first be weighted which means going to be multiplied
by some value.
Often this value is just between negative 1 and 1 when creating a percent Tron will typically begin
by just assigning random weights.
In this case we'll go ahead and randomly assign weight 0 to 0.5 in weight 1 to negative 1.
That means we take each input and multiply it by it's weights.
That means we'll say input 0 times weight 0 is 12 times zero point by six and input one tempts one is
four times negative one equals negative for the output of a perception is generated by passing that
sum.
There are some sort of activation function.
In the case of a simple binary output that activation function is what tells preset Tron whether to
fire or not.
There are many activation functions to choose from functions and processing such as logistic functions
Trigon to metric functions such as sinusoidal functions or tanh functions step functions etc..
Let's go ahead and make the activation function.
The sign of the sun.
So a very simple activation function.
In other words if the sum is a positive number we'll have the output be 1.
If it's a negative number we'll have the output be negative 1.
One more thing to consider is bias.
Imagine that both inputs were equal to zero.
That means any sum no matter what multiplicative weight you put on it would also be zero that would
cause problems because it would be very common to have a point.
That may just happen to land on x 1 is 0 x 2 0 or X is 0 y is zero etc. in order to solve that problem
we add a bias.
This third input is known as a bias and it starts with a value of 1.
This avoids that zero issue to actually train the percept Tron we use the following steps.
We provide the perception of inputs for which there is a known answer.
We asked the precept trons to guess an answer.
Then we compute the error which is basically asking how far off from the correct answer are we.
We adjust all the weights according to that error and we return to step 1 and just keep repeating this
process.
That means these five steps laid out.
Here is how you actually trained precept Tron and you'll basically layer a bunch of percent trons and
create a neural net.
We repeat that until we reach an error that we're satisfied with and usually set that beforehand.
That is how a single percept trundled work and that or create a neural network.
Again you have to do is link many preset trons together in layers you'll have an input layer and an
output layer any layers in between are known as hidden layers because you don't directly see anything
but the input or output you may have heard of the term deep learning.
That's just a neural network with many hidden layers causing it to be deep.
You may be wondering well how deep is a typical deep learning network.
There's no good answer for how many hidden layers you should use.
But as a quick example Microsoft state of the art vision recognition uses something like 152 layers
.
Let's go ahead and go to our studio and begin to explore for example.
Then finally you'll have a project to test your understanding of creating your own networks.
In our thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture