Hello everyone and welcome to your capstone data project and this project we're going to be learning
how to combine everything you've learned about your our programming skills and your data visualization
as well as data frame operations in order to solve a real historical problem.
And in this case it's going to be the famous Moneyball problem.
Let's go ahead and jump to notebook to give you a little more background on the capstone data project
.
All right.
Here I am at the notebook.
The location of this notebook and all the images and cxxviii files associated with this notebook and
its project is located under the training exercise folder.
You should see another folder called capstone and Data Projects and then there's a folder called capstone
project.
And this actual notebook is called the Moneyball project notebook and it has a sister in a book called
Moneyball project solutions.
So check the solutions first.
Actually try to attempt this project.
Now you may be thinking I don't know anything about baseball or sports.
How can I possibly do this project.
Well don't worry you don't need to know too much about baseball to complete this exercise.
If you're totally unfamiliar of baseball go ahead and check out the useful explanatory video that's
linked in the notebook.
You can just click here and that will take you to this video right here which just very simply explains
the rules of baseball.
And after watching this video it's quite sure it's only eight minutes long.
You should know enough about baseball or actually more than enough to complete this project.
So go ahead and check out this video.
If you don't know anything about baseball.
Once you watch that video or if you already know enough about baseball you can go ahead and start reading
about the background of this project.
The basic premise is that in 2001 the Oakland A's which is a baseball team in Oakland California saw
the departure of three key players which were known as the lost boys and Billy Beane the team's general
manager was able to use statistics in order to create a very good team with a very low salary budget
and this story was made famous because of a book called Moneyball which was written by Michael Lewis
and it was later turned into a movie starring Brad Pitt.
And again the basic premise here as you can see from this chart here and highlighted in red is the Oakland
A's and they have essentially the third lowest salary cap and total salary available for all other players
versus everyone else in the Major League Baseball League.
And what you're going to go out and do is using your skills and your G-G plot 2 skills in everything
you've learned so far is basically help the Oakland A's to recruit undervalued players will be using
data from this Web site right here.
But this is actually already been downloaded for you and you have to see S V files a batting that see
every file and then a salary's that sees the file and you also have a read me 2013 text file and this
text file has a reference if you need to understand what all the acronyms stand for.
You'll go ahead and use are to open up the batting.
Let's see every file.
Then you'll check out the head of batting.
And again notice that some of these columns.
In fact a lot of these columns are just acronyms such as a B R or H and if you don't know what those
acronyms mean you can go ahead and look at the read me 20:13 that text file which is located in the
same folder as this Moneyball notebook and you scroll down you should see a list of acronyms and then
there are definitions.
But the new book will also help you out in understanding which acronyms you need to know.
Then you'll go ahead and check the structure of the data frame you'll call head and there's outputs
here to make sure that everything you're doing is following along correctly.
After that we're going to perform some feature engineering which will learn about in a lot more detail
and we actually cover machine learning but we'll create three more statistics.
And the very first one batting average is actually done for you.
But essentially you're going to click on these links which will take you to Wikipedia page.
Go ahead and do batting average examples already done for you.
You'll click on the batting average which will take you to the Wikipedia page for batting average and
you going to scroll through the page until you can find the formula for batting average and in this
case it's over eight here in this right hand corner HEG equals h divided by a B.
And those acronyms are actually in your batting that see as we file.
I mean you can come back here.
Notice that it's HEG equals h divided by AB and you'll go ahead and call your columns the 8 column off
with the batting data frame divided by the AB column for the batting data frame and set that to a column
called B A which stands for batting average and that way you can create a batting average that's equal
to hits divided by at base.
And you can go ahead and check out the Wikipedia pages because you want more information as to why those
particular statistics are important.
Once you've done that you'll go ahead and create and feature engineer to more statistics.
Fill out that code there.
And the Neutrik structure of your data frame then you're going to merge the salary data with batting
data.
Now we actually haven't discussed too much about merging data frames together and the whole point that
we didn't discuss that is that hopefully uing this project you can discover that on your own and if
not if you're ever confused on anything.
Always feel free to post the Q8 forums but what you can do is join your batting data frame that you
just featured engineered with some salary data and there's a salary's that see as we file in the same
folder.
And eventually what you're going to do is merge these two data frames together and you summary make
sure it matches up to what's shown here in the notebook and then you'll analyze.
Finally the last players and as I previously mentioned the Oakland A's lost three key players which
you could do is find those three key players do some more analysis on them and figure out their particular
statistics such as on base percentage slugging and bet batting average and at bats then what you're
going to do and this is the key to the project is find replacement players.
You have all the information I need.
And your final task is to find replacement players for the key three players shown here that you lost
and you have three constraints.
They should have a total combined salary of no more than 15 million dollars.
The combined number of at bats needs to be equal to or greater than the loss players which is shown
here.
And then there I mean oh BP which is on base percentage which show later or previously calculate has
to be greater than or equal to the mean of the BP to the last players.
And then there's some more instructions on how you should do this as well as some helpful phone sorting
data frames.
All right.
The ending is left intentionally more open ended.
There's lots and lots of different answers as far as finding three players that can successfully replace
these lost boys or lost players something to know.
And it's explained in the notebook what we're doing here is a little unrealistic because we're basically
treating any player that's not already on the Oakland A's as a free agent that we can sign on.
That's not exactly true in real life but we'll go ahead and continue as if that is the case.
Again if you have any questions throughout this project feel free to post the Q&A forums.
Make sure you go ahead and read the descriptions of everything that's provided in the notebook because
most of the steps are laid out pretty clearly here in the notebook free to follow.
All right.
I hope you have a lot of fun with this project.
Keep in mind that this was a real problem in real life than if you had a time machine you could go back
to the year 2001 with your laptop and our studio and make some real money solving these real problems
.
OK.
Again I hope you have a lot of fun in the next lecture will be a full solutions walkthrough of this
project.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture