Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Unlist basics we've already covered vectors matrices and data frames.
Now we're going to learn about our final basic built in our data structure known as the list.
The list is going to allow us to store a variety of data structures under a single variable.
Let's jump to our studio and see how it works.
OK here are studio.
Notice that I have just the console displaying here because that's really all we need for right now
.
I'm going to create a couple of data structures.
First one I'm going to create a basic vector with one two three.
I'm also going to create a matrix using the matrix function and it's just going to be the numbers one
through 10 number of rows equals to two and then finally I'm going to create a data frame and I'm going
to assign it a built in data frame we'll call it empty cars.
So I have three separate data structures.
I have my vector of numerics I have my matrix and then finally I have my data frame.
So what if we wanted to put all of these different data structures into a single variable.
That way I can call a single variable and call things out of that single variable in order to store
a bunch of information.
That's where the list comes in.
The list is going to allow us to combine all these data structures into a single variable.
So we're going to go ahead and create a variable called my dot list in order to create a list.
I just put in the list function and then pass in essentially a list of the different data structures
I want.
So I passed the variable names separated by a comma.
Want my vector the matrix am comma and then finally my data frame the f..
So if we print out my list directly to the consul.
Usually you won't print out an entire list like I'm showing you right now.
But if we just go ahead and do that those who have a ton of information here but we have all the information
we assigned to this list we have the vector the matrix.
And then finally the data frame and the Consul's going to display each item in the list with this double
bracket notation.
So the list is going to show double brackets 1 and then display the first item in your list then double
brackets to the second item in your list which is the matrix in this case double brackets 3.
And the third final item in our list which is this of free.
We can also name these items instead of having the automatically assigned numbers.
Let me go in and clear the consul and show you how to do that.
Well go ahead and make a variable called my name that list will call list and if I want to actually
assign names instead of those automatic variable numbers I can do that when I'm calling or passing in
those data structures into the list function.
So I can say something like sample underscore the E.C equals and then I pass in the variable or data
structure that I'm referring to.
So V in this case will say my dot matrix as the next label call it m and then we can say something like
.
Sample DMF it's up to you how you want to label DS will say the f you can use underscores or dots.
Surely what works best for you.
I'll go ahead and make this all dot.
So it's the same here but that's all there is to it.
So if I say my dog named list now we scroll back up you'll notice we get names off of this list and
they have dollar signs in front of them.
Meaning we can actually call similar to calling a column off of a data frame we can call entire data
structures or objects off of a list.
So this is more of an organizational tool than an actual tool where you're going to be doing operations
like a data frame or a matrix or a vector.
You're going to be using a list to organize your work and organize the various data frames or matrices
or vectors or whatever data structures or objects are working with you'll pass to a list and call them
off the list in order to access them.
So I can say my named list dollar sign and then our studio is going to have since really helpful dropdown
menus that show you oh you have sampled that VEC in this list my matrix and this list sampled the F
in this list and it says a little symbol here denoting what kind of data structure it is and then we
can just call stuff offer a list.
In this fashion.
Now let's briefly discuss how to select objects from a list.
We talked about this dollar sign method sample.
But if you want it you could also use bracket notation.
So if we go back to my list the original list had the numbers we could call using bracket notation the
numbers off of that.
So I can say something like my lists or my that list one inside of the brackets and it returns that
vector.
I can also do the same for the named list and I'll return the first item.
Now notice here the first item actually has a name sample back which I could have also said my name
that list with brackets passed then sampled back the sea.
And that would have returned the exact same thing.
OK.
Now a quick no is the class of this statement going to go in and copy and paste it into the class function
is still a list.
If you actually want to grab those data structures of those objects out of your list so you can manipulate
them or operate with them.
You'll use either two brackets or the dollar sign notation we showed earlier.
So if I take out my named list again and I use dollar sign notation to grab that sample that Visi notice
.
Now we actually get the vector object instead of this list.
Class object showing you the first item the list.
So it's a really important thing to note here.
Again if I use this bracket notation that's just going to return.
Hey you have the sample vector in your list and it's called sampled up the see if I use the dollar sign
notation.
It's actually going to return that vector itself.
So let's go in and confirm that by checking class of this statement and now we get back numeric because
it's a numeric vector versus here we got back a list class object.
And with this sort of notation we can also duplicate it by saying double brackets.
So I say my named list.
One set of brackets and another set of brackets and then say sample visi.
And that's another way to directly grab the object so you can either use the dollar sign notation or
this double bracket notation if you want to get in return.
The actual object that stored in that list if you either just use single brackets with either the name
or the index value you'll get back a class of list.
Meaning I'll tell you the name of the objects in your list but you won't be able to manipulate it like
it was just a vector matrix or they are afraid that you stored in that list.
Finally a quick note.
You can actually combine lists so lists can hold other lists and I'll show you that by using the combined
function I'll make an object called Double list and I will go ahead and assign it the list I created
which was my that named list I'll assign it twice.
So now I have a list which is two instances of my lane list.
So if I called Double list I should get a very large output into the console with things shown twice
.
So there's my sample VEC my matrix sample T.F. second instance and here's the first one again.
So that was my double list just to show you that you can combine lists together.
You have to separate this into a single variable which is just essentially a combination of those two
lists.
The best way to get information about a list is just by using the structure as TR function.
We'll go ahead and pass in my named list and I'll report back how many objects in a list and then what
kind of objects they have.
OK that's really all there is to the list object.
Keep in keep it in mind when you're trying to organize a bunch of different data structures.
But you should also keep in mind that it's mainly used for organizational purposes.
You won't be using a list directly for the purposes of working and trying to manipulate data directly
.
That's better suited for things like data framework matrix or even a vector.
A list is more of an organizational tool.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see the next lecture.