Hello everyone and welcome to the interactive visualizations of plotless section of this course in this
lecture we're going to explain what Platini is and how you can convert your G-G plot to knowledge to
plot Lee and make interactive visualizations without learning any more new material in order to get
started.
Let's start by explaining what plot he is as a company and what the plot the open source library is
in order to do this.
Go ahead and go to this link or just in your your browser type in P L O T L Y.
Or even just google search plotline and it will take you to this web page.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to that page now.
All right.
Here I am at Piel o ot l y plotless the official Web site plotless is a company that maintains and manages
the plotless open source library for interactive visualizations and Laplante allows you to do is create
interactive visualizations in a variety of languages such as Matlab Excel javascript Python and are
.
If you go ahead and click on the link here it will take you to Plata.
Slash are slash getting started partly for R is entirely open source free and self-hosted plumply.
The company makes money with a pro edition where you can go ahead and get support and also have an online
editor.
We won't be using any of that.
We'll just use the free mission which is more than enough for us.
And if you're interested on actually seeing the code since it's open source you can click here and it
will take you to this hobe link where they have all the source and web interactive interface for plot
the code.
Let's go ahead and jump back to the getting started page slightly for our has two options.
There's a basic plotline package which will then download and install the plotline library and you can
call plot underscore l y in order to create these interactive visualizations.
However what's really nice about plotline and they've done a lot of work on this recently is if you
go ahead and click here on G-G plot to there's a plot.
L y as you plot to slash getting started page and this library is really awesome.
Basically plot Lee has a function called G-G plotline which will convert G.G. plot to figures into graphs
drawn directly of plot lead thought JS Which is the interactive javascript library plotless is based
off of you can also just install it if installed up packages politely and it will allow you to quickly
and easily make visualisations interactive using just your Ju-Ju plot to knowledge that you've already
learned.
Let me go ahead and show you how this all works by jumping to our studio.
I'm going to go ahead and jump there now.
All right here we are at our studio where we're going to go ahead and do is install the plot Lee package
.
Go head and go to your counsel and say install packages and in quotes pasan P L O T L Y and then select
enter and Eltis this will do.
It's going to install all the packages and libraries you need in order to run interactive visualisations
in our studio.
Looks like we're all good and installed.
I'm going to go out and clear the console and show you an example of how this all works.
Well we're going to do it in our script call Library.
We'll call G-G plot too and then we'll also call plot blee.
Now we're going to do is create a plot in G-G plot 2 and convert it to an interactive visualization
with the plot Li or Gigia plot Lee library.
Let me go ahead and just show you how this would look.
Normally it's just G.G. plot.
I'm going to say P.L. G.G. plot and let's go ahead and just plot the empty cars dataset that we're really
familiar with and say æsthetics will go in and do mpg versus wait and just make a scatterplot off of
this GM underscore points and then since this is the script I'm going to go ahead and say Prince P.L.
Let's go ahead and run the source
and notice we get the scatterplot out.
I click on this.
Nothing's going to happen.
I can click zoom to get a better view of this or zoom than view but that's it and that's what we're
familiar with G-G plot and G.G. plot 2.
We can go ahead and add more arguments to this change the sizes and shapes etc..
Now we're going to see how we can make this interactive three very simple command of Jiji plot.
Lee will you go ahead and do is say Well go ahead to say GPL.
You call the Gee-Gee plot Leite function and then you just pasand the figure.
In this case I'm just Pesi in this P.L. plot.
Basically what's happened is I'm converting this normal G.G. plot into a plot plot just by calling it
into the function G.G. plot Lee and passing it to the very old bold GPL and now what I'm going to do
is instead of printing P.L. and will print GPL.
Let's go ahead and run this source
and sometimes it takes a little while to load.
It looks like you're ready to go.
Now notice what happens.
My cursor is an interactive cross-hair cursor and now I can actually zoom in highlight over points and
get information off those points and I can double click to zoom back out.
I can use all these tools appear such as Pan or pan around I can use box select in order to select these
points and highlight them.
I can use Lassus selects double click to do that.
These last a select select points manually in that fashion double click to do that and Ill tell you
it has been produced by plotless.
And hopefully now you can see this is a super useful tool to create interactive visualizations with
learning anything new you can take all your G-G plot 2 knowledge and convert it to a plotline library
or plot leave visualization just by calling the G.G. plot command.
And that's pretty awesome.
Let me go ahead and jump back to the documentation page or Ju-Ju plot.
Lee going to go to the web browser now.
All right here I am in my web browser and now I'm at the documentation page for the Gee-Gee plot.
Lee and partly Judy plot to library.
This your L is P L O T L Y.
Slash G-G plot to slash.
And in the next lecture I'll provide all the links for all this information.
Basically if you go to this web page it will show you a few examples of how to use G-G plot really which
you plot to.
But more importantly if you keep scrolling down there's the documentation examples and basically the
entire documentation for G.G. plot 2 has been converted to plot Lee.
In these examples that means if you ever want to know how to create a density plot a scatterplot a histogram
if you go down here to see mystical charts using geometers square histogram stat underscore smooth geometer
square box plots all the G.G. plot two functions that layers that we're familiar with have now been
done in plot lead.
And you can easily look up this documentation in case you ever need any examples of how to do it.
And that's basically all I want to show you.
You already have all the knowledge you need for G-G plot to now through G.G. plotless simple function
.
You can cover all that knowledge to an interactive visualization extremely easily and you can impress
your friends and colleagues with all the charts you can now make.
For example if you want to do it histogram and G.G. plot ly you can go click on the histogram scroll
down here and then see how you could create a histogram and it provides all the code for the examples
.
As you look through this page you'll notice that there's a lot of examples for other things you can
do such as adding lines.
The histogram here adding a facet adding a probability density to your histogram etc. and it's all done
with cheesier plot to code and then just calling G-G plotly at the end.
If you ever want to know in more detail what's been converted from G-G plot 2 to plot line.
You'll see here a link that says see the Gigia plot 2 to partly test tables.
If you click on that and open a new link it will take you to this page which is essentially all the
plot to documentation images been converted to plotless code.
Then you can go ahead and click on any of these if case you want another reference.
Basically anything you could possibly think of referencing the code is here for you in this page.
And again all of this is linked in the next lecture.
All right hopefully you're excited now that all your knowledge of G-d Blut too can be easily converted
to interact plot's.
Thanks everyone I will see you at the next lecture which is just a brief text lecture with the links
and a brief overview of everything we just discussed.