Welcome to the Windows installation procedure to lecture in this lecture we're going to be going over
how to install our in our studio which is the main development environment we're going to be using for
this course.
So let's go ahead and get started by opening up your browser.
OK.
So here I am at a web browser.
Go ahead and go to Google or your favorite search engine and what you going to do is search for our
studio and it should take you to w w w r studio dot com.
So our studio is development environment and user interface for our that we're going to be using.
So we're going to do is go ahead and download our and our studio.
There's a free open source version of our studio in an enterprise version.
We're just going to go ahead and use the free open source.
It's one of the most popular ideas for our.
So you're going to go ahead and do is on the very first page you should see some of that says like download
our studio.
Go ahead and click on that.
We'll take you to this page.
And if you just go ahead and scroll down what we're looking for is the open source EDITION.
We're not going to download the commercial license because that when you have to pay for it.
So we're looking for this free version.
And when you click download our studio desktop right there they'll take you to this new page and this
page is just the download page for our studio so you can go ahead and check with the link here.
It's our studio dot com slash product slash our studio slash download.
And if you'll notice here they'll say our studio requires some sort of version of our.
And what you're going to do since we don't have are yet installed as you can say click here.
So you'll notice at the link you can download it here.
Go ahead and click on that and it should take you to this page.
Now this is the Crann our studio dot com and you'll see here it says download and install our.
Since we're on the Windows installation we'll go ahead and click download are for Windows.
Click on that and then what you're going to do is go ahead and choose the correct subdirectory.
So this is our first time installing our.
We're going to go ahead and do is select the winery's for the base distribution.
And again this is what you want to do to install our For the first time.
So let's go ahead and click on that.
Once you've clicked on that it should take you to a link that looks like this.
And we're just going to go ahead and download our.
OK.
Now I'm going to go ahead and fast forward for the download to finish.
OK so my download is complete.
I'm just going to go ahead and click on the executable file.
You may need to allow it to change things on your PC.
Go ahead and click yes.
Select the language for installation and then basically just follow the setup wizard should be pretty
straightforward.
You can just essentially select all the default.
This should work for you.
And just go ahead and select everything here.
The 32 bit and 64 bit files doesn't really matter it's gonna install both even if you have just a 64
or 32.
Do you want to save a couple of megabytes of space.
You can just choose either 64 or just the 32.
Going to go and do that.
Go ahead and just select the defaults unless you want to customize startup select next go ahead and
just click continue here and select next.
There is some additional tax I'm just going to go ahead and create a desktop icon so I can easily launch
it.
And I'm also going to associate our data of our data files so we'll go ahead and select next.
And that's all there is to it it's pretty quick.
So you can just go ahead and extract the files and wait for it to install.
Go ahead and fast forward through this install process.
OK.
So are is all done stalling going to go ahead and select finish.
So now that we have our Fool installed we can go back and finish installing our studio.
So our is that language that we're going to be developing in.
And the actual environment is our studio.
So let's go ahead and download our studio desktop.
So you'll see here there's a bunch of installers ready for you to use.
I'm just going to go ahead and select the Windows Vista 7 8 or 10.
I'm on Windows 10 right now so I'll go in and click that installer.
And again you should see our studio the executable file being installed.
Go ahead and fast forward for that install or that download to finish excuse me.
All right.
Now that that's finished downloading.
Let's go ahead and click it again.
Go ahead don't allow our studio to make changes on your PC.
It's a relatively simple wizard.
Just go through the defaults install and that's all there is to it.
Let's go ahead and jump to this installation of finishing
and the our studio setup wizard has been finished.
So you can go ahead and click Finish there.
And now you can go ahead and do is search for our studio and make sure that it installed correctly in
order to check the our studio installed correctly you can just simply search for it or ask Cortana depending
on what version of Windows are you using.
And just go ahead and type our studio.
It's so one word.
So our studio there's no space between our studio.
You should see the desktop app pop up go to and click on it it will load.
And this is what our studio looks like.
So just to make sure everything's working correctly and that you installed ours as well you should see
the console for our pop up here later on then couple of next lectures we'll discuss our studio how to
use it.
Give you a little tour about it.
But just to check that everything's working we can do is type print open parentheses and you'll see
an automatic closing print sees also form for you single or double quote and you can say Hello World
.
Go ahead and click enter and then you should see the output print hello world and you've already written
your first line of our code.
OK.
So go ahead and follow those directions to install our in our studio onto your Windows machine.
Should be relatively straightforward.
You can always check out the resources on our studios download page in case you have any questions.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.