Hello everyone and welcome to the basics exercise solutions walk through in this lecture video.
I'm going to be going ahead and walking through and explaining the solutions to the our basic exercise
questions.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio and get started.
OK so here we are our studio.
I want to go ahead and shrink the plots and environment tabs who won't really be using them.
So it's going to push those to the right.
And the first question we want to solve is this what is two to the power of five.
I'll go ahead and copy and paste questions as we go along.
Hopefully you remember from the arithmetic lecture that today the power of five can be solved and are
just using that carrot symbol so to the power of five we get 32 back.
If you don't remember how to do that arithmetic.
Go ahead and review the arithmetic lecture and are moving on to the next question.
We wanted to create a vector called stock prices with the falling points and those points were a 23
27 23:21 et cetera.
Let's go in and see what we can do that.
So I'll make my variable.
Stock up prices.
And then I use the combined function which is C and I enter those integers separated by a comma.
OK great.
So now I have my stock prices vector.
Next thing we had to do was this we wanted to assign names to the price data points relating to the
day of the week starting of Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday etc..
So how do we actually do that.
Well hopefully remember the names function and to use the names function we pass in what we actually
want to name.
So I say stocked up prices and then assign a vector of names.
This case will go ahead and assign.
Monday Tuesday.
Repassing these as strings are characters Thursday and then finally Friday and then if we go ahead and
check stock prices now.
Notice when we print it out we get Monday $23 Tuesdays 27 etc..
So just in our minds the numbers here represent the stock price in dollars.
OK so time for the next question.
Next question was what was the average mean stock price for the week.
So it was this was the average mean stock price for the week.
There was a hint that you may need to reference a built in function and the built in function was mean
.
So using mean what we can do is just pasand stocked up prices in a row return the mean value for the
stock prices which in this case was twenty five point six.
OK.
Next question was this let's go out and put this on two lines.
It was create a vector called over 23 consisting of logicals that correspond to the days where the stock
price was more than $23.
So how do we actually do this.
We'll use a comparison operator on a vector do this.
So I'll say stocked up prices and I'll say greater than 23 and I'm going to show you what this actually
outputs.
So this outputs on a element by element basis which is stock numbers or stock prices were greater than
23.
So if we look back at the original stock prices we can see that Tuesday and Friday are the only two
valleys that are greater than 23.
And if we just go ahead and apply this comparison operator to the entire vector.
So let's go ahead and assign that vector of logicals to that variable.
Over 23.
So say stock prices greater than 23.
And now if I go ahead and check over 23 notice I get back that same vector of logicals.
All right.
I'm going to go ahead and clear my castle now.
So have stock prices and over that 23.
Let's go ahead and continue.
Next answer your next question.
Was this use the over that 23 vector to filter out the stock prices vector and only return that day
in prices where the price was over $23.
So how exactly can we do that.
Well we can remember that we can use stock prices and bracket notation to actually filter out what we
what information want from stock prices.
So if stock prices looks like this I can go ahead and call stock prices.
And then a bracket notation I can pass in that boolean value or a logical value vector it'll return
back the actual days where that was true.
This is exactly the same thing as saying stock up prices bracket and then passing and stock up prices
again over 23.
So this is the exact same thing but we just to simplify information we said over that 23 and we assigned
it this actual conditional statement.
All right.
So that's how you answer that question.
Next question was to use a built in function to find the day the price was the highest.
The built in function for that.
Hopefully you're able to discover was Max.
So then we can just pass in stock prices.
But notice when I use Mac Max I only get the number value 34 that didn't actually tell me what I was
looking for the day the price was the highest.
So there's a couple of ways to do this.
One is knowing that the answer was 34.
I could split this up into a second step and say stocked up prices passing stocked up prices check for
equality with 34 to enter.
And then I get back Friday the name of that value.
That's one way to do this or the better way.
Let me go in and clear this con. is to actually combine those steps saw say stocked up prices and then
pasan stock prices equals equals max on stock prices and we get back the same value.
But now it's in a clean line and this is pretty readable.
I'm looking for where stock prices equals equals Max stock prices checking for equality there.
We could also have taken this and assign a variable.
So if I copy and pastes something like Max that price just like we did over 23 we assign that variable
and then maybe this something like this maybe more readable to you.
If we just pass in max price we get the same answer kind of up to you.
Whichever way you actually want to execute this code.
All right that's it for the exercise in the basics.
Hopefully was pretty straightforward.
Maybe there was a little bit of tricks as far as using this bracket notation for filtering but we'll
get a lot more practice that sort of filtering as the course goes on and we learn about how to use data
frames.
All right thanks everyone.
Go ahead and review the lecturers in case any of this was unclear or you're a little fuzzy on it.
I'll see it the next lecture