Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on C S V input output.
This lecture will discuss how to read a C as we fall into our how to write a sci fi file as output with
our let's go and jump to our studio to get started.
OK.
So here we are our studio C S V stands for comma separated variable and it's one of the most common
ways we'll be working with data throughout this course.
The basic format of the CSP file is the first line indicating the column names and the rest of the rows
or lines being data points separated by commas.
One of the most basic ways to read a c a c file in arm is just to use the read that C as V is actually
built into our.
So go ahead and create a sample c file if you need one or you can actually create one quickly by saying
right.
But C-s the empty cars
file my let's say underscore exampled CACP and don't worry about these warning messages will go ahead
to just clear the cons..
So again if you need to get a sample CXXVI you can either open up Notepad.
So for example if you have Notepad you can go out and search for it for using Windows.
Otherwise you can just use any other sort of basic note or text editor and you can just go out and quickly
make a CC file using your notepad.
So for example I could just copy and paste some information here.
Name comma orders comma date as the header and then John comma 12 orders comma some dates and then just
go in and save file.
Say there's all files in other underscore example that CXXVI.
So you have several options here.
If you're using Windows you can good.
Open up Notepad.
Write something like this.
Your own CSFB file if you want.
Maybe you already have a CACP file you want to work with.
Or if you don't have no Petters and don't want to write your own CXXVI file you can just basically write
this one line of code here and it will make an example cxxviii file for you.
You'll say right doc cxxviii has an empty cars which is that cars data frankly work with a little bit
in the past and say file equals and then whatever your C every file name is.
OK let's go in and clear the council
and begin talking about reading in a CSC file.
We actually just showed a quick example of how to write the CAC file.
We'll go over it more formally later on.
As far as reading a c c as we file it will look something like this.
You'll have a variable name and you're going to say read dot C S V and then you're going to pass in
the whole file path to the C S V file or at the CSP file is already in your working directory.
You can check if it's in your working directory by looking over here in this tab in the files.
So have all my C as the files in my working directory.
You can just pass on the C as the file itself.
And what's nice about our studio is if I begin typing let's say E X I can click tab and it will auto
complete the CC file for me.
Sometimes you may get a warning message and if you get a warning message it's important to go ahead
and check to make sure you actually imported the data correctly.
Here it looks like everything worked out well.
This particular warning just showed up because I had an extra space on my final four Fly-In but there
was actually no data there so it doesn't really matter.
Again this is just a warning message not an error.
If you get a warning message just go ahead and check up the tail and head of whatever the file you just
imported was.
Make sure nothing looks out of order or strange but essentially what we have here now we just go ahead
and check.
Class of x is a day different and everything you learn about data frame all the operations you can work
with on a data frame.
You can now work with your CSP files and do the same thing.
OK let's talk about writing to a C SFE file.
I'm going to go ahead.
Just click control if you want to write to a sci fi file you can just say right dot V passes the name
of the data frame you want to write.
Let's say you want to write the ex-aide of frame we just import it and then you say file equals and
then you just pass in whatever you want the file to be called.
So I will say my underscore new example DOS CXXVI enter and notice if I look over here.
I see my new example of C as V and the date it was saved.
OK.
That's really all there is to it.
As far as reading and writing that CSB files.
So again it's just read dot C S V and then you pass in the complete file path to your file.
Or you just pass in the CAC file.
If it's already in the same directory so it's just.
Example CSP.
You may get a warning message.
Just keep that in mind.
I'm going to go out and try importing another one.
Let's go ahead to say my underscore example CXVII.
Here's another example see as V.
This case is the empty cars data frame that we just saved.
OK so that's it really for the basics of reading and writing as the files.
It's really as simple as that.
Just read that C S V in assign that to a new data free variable or write that C S V and save it as a
file if you need more help on these topics.
You can just say help.
Read C as V enter and you'll have an entire documentation page on data input and you'll be able to notice
they can't specify things like skipping a header.
What your separator is in this case it's denoted by cxxviii solo just say separator equals comma but
you can actually say add an argument Sep equals tab or the pipe operator whatever you happen to be separating
.
Each column in your see is free file or whatever type of text file you actually have.
Again you can always use chukka help.
Read the C S V for more information on this.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.