Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on data frame basics.
We've learned a lot about vectors and their two dimensional counterpart matrices.
Now we're going to learn about data frames.
One of the main tools for data analysis with our matrix inputs we're limited because all data inside
of the matrix to be of the same data type with data frames we're going to be able to organize and mix
data types to create powerful data structures.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio to begin exploring some built in data frames.
All right.
So here in our studio I'm going to go ahead and just push the right hand windows over to the right a
little further.
So we just see the console and the scripting screen.
Let's start off by seeing and exploring some built in data frames.
One of the first ones we're going to check comes from that state data set.
So if you begin typing state into our studio you should see a bunch of pop ups.
Let's go ahead and explore state x 7 7.
And then when you click enter you'll notice a data frame pops up.
This looks similar to a matrix.
But notice how the rows and the columns are names.
Now data frames can also have names rows and columns versus just having the number signifying what number
column or what number row it is.
This sort of labeling is going to be really useful or trying to access our data from this data frame
.
You can begin to think about data frames as sort of an X like an Excel spreadsheet.
It's going to be really useful for working with large amounts of data.
Let's go ahead and explore a few more builtin data frames.
You know go ahead and clear the cons..
And I'm going to import U.S. personal expenditure so this data set consists of United States personal
expenditures in the billions of dollars.
It's a smaller data frame but you can see the same idea.
We have a labeled row and some labeled columns.
Now the label rows or the labeled columns to actually need to have string or character labels that can
be numeric just like a normal index.
So for example in other built in data frame is the women data frame you just begin to type women and
this dataset gives the average height and weights for American women aged 30 to 39 of a small sample
of them.
So if we explore this data frame a little more we noticed we have two columns here height and weight
with various values and each row is just a numeric indexed value.
It doesn't actually have a label.
You might be wondering well how do you get a list of all the available built in data frames that are
in order to do that.
You can just type in data close parentheses on that data function and you should get a new tab to pop
up here.
That will give you a list of all the data sets in the builtin data sets packaged with are.
So if we scroll down here you'll see on the left the name that you need to import and a right description
of it.
So for instance let's say we just scroll down here we want to explore the world's telephone's will we
just type in world phones to see that.
So go ahead and type in world phones enter and so we start seeing some data about the number of phones
in the world separated by columns of the different parts of the world.
Something you've made noticed is that some of the data frames are really big.
If you just want to take a peek at either the top or the bottom of the data frame you can use the head
and tail functions.
So for example remember we had that state DOT X 7:7 data frame which was quite large because it has
all 50 states inside of it.
We can go ahead and call ahead on State DOT x 7 7 and this will just return the first six rows of that
data frame and we can also call tail state x 7 7 or just passing whatever data frame we want in they'll
shoot the last six rows.
Some other useful built in functions for working data frames are SDR and summary.
We can use the TR function to get the structure of a data frame which gives information on the structure
of the data frame and the data it contains such as variable names and data types.
So for example if I call SDR which stands for structure and passing the data frame object.
Let's go ahead and pass in that state X 7:7 click enter.
Notice we begin to get some information about it.
Like what kind of rows it has what kind of columns it has the dimensions etc..
There's another built in function which will give you some nice testicle data called summary.
So summary is just a generic function that's used to produce results summaries of the results of various
model fitting functions or just of objects like a data frame.
So if you pass in your data frame here so summerise thought X 7:7
notice we get a summary for each of the columns in our data frame.
So for example the population summary gives you the minimum value the median value the mean values some
court tile values as well as the maximum value.
Later on in the course we're going to be using summary quite a bit for not just data frames but a whole
host of functions and objects.
So just keep that in mind since we've explored built in data frames.
Let's go ahead and explore how we can create our own data frames now.
OK we'll start off by creating a data frame from some vectors.
Let's go ahead and make up some weather data.
I'll start off by making a vector called days and we'll just have this be the days of the week which
we've used before.
So Monday Tuesday Wednesday
Thursday and Friday we have Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday for the days then we're going to
make a temp sector and you can actually just quickly copy and paste this from the notes and I'm going
to make up some temperatures.
Let's say these are in Celsius now.
OK.
So we have my temperatures there.
And let's make one final vector.
This one's going to be a vector of logical values.
So boolean values will indicate whether or not it rained that day.
So we'll say it drained on Tuesday on Monday.
Did it rain on Wednesday then in Reno Thursday and it rained again on Friday.
Okay so we can go ahead and pass in these vectors into the data dot Frain function so we can go ahead
and say days Tim rain and now we outputted a data frame and let's go ahead and actually save this as
DMF variable data frame and then pass in the vector's days Tim brain.
And then when we check out our data frame we'll notice that the column names have been automatically
set to be the same as the name of the vector variable and by default the rows are just indexed numbers
.
Since we've now Cranor a data frame we can actually go ahead and call structure on it as TR RDF that
will give us some information about the structure of the data in the data frame.
Or we can even call a summary on that data frame.
Okay that's it for the basics of what a data frame is and what it looks like and are the main things
you should have been able to get out of this lecture.
Are the following.
You can type in data to get a output of all the data sets in the package data sets.
You can play around with.
Are these already built in for you.
Also remember you can use SDR and summary to check out data frames whether you create them or they're
built in.
And finally you can create your own data frames for passing and vectors into the data dot frame function
.
OK.
Again that's it for the basics.
Up next we're going to learn about selection and indexing data frame elements.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture