Hello everyone and welcome to the data visualization Project Walk through in the state of visualization
project you wanted to recreate a plot from The Economist publication.
Let's go ahead and check out the plot and then we'll discuss what we're going to do for this actual
lecture video.
All right so here we are at The Economist Web site and this is the plot we're trying to recreate which
is basically a human development index value plotted against a Corruption Perceptions Index value.
So you're essentially trying to see corruption versus human development or human development risk corruption
.
So 10 is the least corrupt countries you can see stuff like Norway New Zealand Singapore and then one
of the most corrupt countries.
Things like Afghanistan and Congo.
This data is from 2011s.
Keep that in mind.
So hopefully we can try to use our new plot to our knowledge in order to recreate this plot.
You can check out the notes or the previous lecture as far as links to the data used for this plot.
But I'm going to go ahead and just walk through the different steps in that project notebook and see
if we can try to get a nice recreation of this plot early relatively close to it.
I'm going to go ahead and jump to our studio now and walk through the solutions to this project.
All right so here in our studio one quick note you'll need to download the Economist's assignment data
CXXVI file in order to actually have the data available for this.
So the first instruction step was to import the Gigia plot to library and also to import the data that
table library you may need to install this library if you haven't installed it yet.
You can do that just by saying install up packages and an in quotes but in data table you don't have
to use data at that table.
It just makes the reading process a little faster using the read command that comes of data table.
So in this case I get a pass in the Economist I'm using tabs autocomplete that and what's nice about
this Elfriede method is I can say drop equals 1 and it will drop the first column which was just a repeat
of the index.
You can also read that C is free to read in the the C as we file as a data frame.
It's really up to you.
I just do this because it's a little more convenient to drop because one but not a whole lot.
Let's go ahead and check the head of that data frame and run the source.
Let's go ahead and say print head of data frame order to see this just to see the data that we're working
with.
Right.
So expanding our consul output looks like we have a country a human development index rank an HDI value
some sort of corruption index and then the actual region.
So this is the data that was used to recreate the Economist plot that we just saw earlier.
Let's go ahead and just start with the basics and see if we can slowly build up step by step the actual
plot.
I'm going to go ahead and show you one more time what we're actually plotting out so we can keep that
in mind.
Now go ahead and jump to it now.
What we're trying to do is recreate this corruption human development so we can already tell.
We should be thinking about some sort of scatterplot So GM point to put on these points maybe using
a title notice that we have different colors by their region such as Asia Central Europe Middle East
et cetera.
So we should already be thinking in our minds how can we color by groupings we should be thinking about
factors of regions that sort of thing.
And then notice we have a nice red line some smooth here.
So we should also be thinking of things like geometer score smoothing as another geometry layer.
And you can also check take a look at this white background.
OK.
Let's go ahead and then get started and go out and minimize this and come back to our studio plot.
So I have my data.
Let's go ahead and start using cheesy plot just to get a very simple scatterplot.
So I'm going to read that as ADF and then I'm going to call G-G plot pass in my data.
And then I need to pass in my æsthetics layer.
So what I'm actually plotting here in this case I'm going to plot CPI for X and then HDI for Y and I
want to set my color as a region
and then let me go ahead and pasand geom underscore points.
Well go ahead and save that as P.L. and then we'll say print P.L.
and then we have to go and click zoom here.
Here we start to begin to see the plot.
And it looks like it has the same trend so looks like we're on the same level as we should have been
as far as that economists plot something you may be wondering is why we said color equals to region
here and that's because we wanted to set the color defined by a certain column or feature in our day
to frame a lot of times.
We've also been doing that in the geometry layer.
So instead of saying color equals region here well we could have also said it's in the geometer score
point layer number we could call this mix called Color equals.
And in this case we want to say factor of region and that's a really similar example to what we've been
doing in the past.
Mageddon is called that a little over its head right so we can see this better called Zoom in the plots
as we call them over.
But this was another way of doing that exact same plot.
So if I run the source click zoom I get the same thing.
Use whatever you feel most comfortable with.
I personally like them both ways.
To me they make sense either way because calling aesthetics on them I remember the aesthetics basically
just determines what I'm actually plotting out of from my data.
OK.
So right now we have an issue as far as trying to get the circles or points to look like the Economist
data member the Economist data had hollow circles so let's go ahead and try to do that.
I want to go ahead and put the color equals region back into the actual G.G. plot come in just because
it'll be a little cleaner.
So say color equals region because I don't need to call us that X again in the geometry layer and now
we want to do is mess around with our geometer score point layer to set the size and shape of these
dots.
So I'm going to wait and say size equals four and shape equals 1.
And so what this allows us to do is you can pass in different number values for the shape and it'll
change the shape of the points that we're going to run.
So we can see what it looks like now.
And now if I click zoom I see a half empty circles.
Now let's go ahead and mess around that shape so we can get a better idea of how it works.
If I Pessin shape because three is the same thing then I get crosshairs as in shape for the same thing
.
Then you get X points or X marks so you can go ahead and just play around with this whatever you prefer
But hopefully you get the idea of just different numbers relate to different shapes and you would just
have to check the documentation to see what was the correct shape that you were looking for.
This case will kind of use these empty star looking circles so shape because one.
Right.
So now that we have that set what we need to do is add a trend line so we can do that by adding the
GM underscore smooth to this.
So what I'm going to go ahead and do is say P.L. 2 and assign it plus GM underscores smooth.
So let's go ahead and do that.
But before we actually run this what we will need to do is decide what do we actually want to pasan
as the trend line.
So what are we at.
What data are you looking at in order to make some sort of smooth curve fit.
So there's a couple options here.
As far as figuring out how to do this you could just go to help and put in geometer score smooth.
Check that out.
And if you're kind of just exploring this documentation you'll notice you have a lot of other arguments
you can pasan things such as mapping data position a formula.
Remove any values etc..
So we're going to go ahead and do is in the actual assignment you're kind of given a lot of what you
should put in here and that's because later on when we actually learn about linear regression we'll
learn what these arguments actually mean.
But in this case I'll start off by just saying in the æsthetics we want group to be equal to 1.
I'm going to go ahead and run the source.
Check out my plots again and I need to say Prince Piel too.
So we actually get the output here.
All right.
And if I click zoom.
This is like the most basic version of what the sexual trend line would look like.
So there's a little line a smooth fit.
And if we notice we had a pasand group equals one space is just assigning it what you're actually plotting
this best fit trend line for.
So don't worry too much about that.
We're going to learn about the sort of adding a smooth trend line a lot more when we talk about linear
regression because that's really what we're doing here we're just adding some sort of linear progression
to this.
So just like the instructions said in the project we're going to add a bunch of more arguments to this
GMAT score smooth sangoma say method equals L.M. which stands for linear model and later on again we're
talking about linear models in general.
We're learn how to actually do this.
But for now just go ahead and put in these same arguments that the instructions told us to.
So add in formula as a log X..
So hopefully you can kind of tell that we're essentially adding a log trend line and that's just so
it looks more like the plot from the Economist Let's say as the argument goes false.
And then I'll make the color red.
And again if you want to learn more about these arguments right now how they work and everything you
can check out the help for GMAT score smooth and then explore what these arguments actually mean.
So for instance the s equals false.
That removes that sort of smooth confidence interval so if we look at the old plot we had some great
out area.
So you have this kind of greyed out smoothing as sequel's false remove that color will make it red.
This formula will set it to be a log and then looks like we're using a linear model method.
Again we'll learn much more about this when we talk about linear regression.
So let's go ahead and Prince peel to now and see if all those changes took effect.
Go ahead and zoom.
And now we're seeing something that looks a lot more like that plot we just saw in the Economist some
sort of logarithmic fit to this scatter point data in order to fit time limits.
We'll continue this in part to