Hello everyone and welcome to the logistic regression with our lecture this lecture we're going to be
learning how to use logistic regression with our.
And we're going to be working with a famous Titanic dataset from Kaggle dot com.
Let's go ahead and get started by jumping to our studio.
OK Miriam our studio.
And like I mentioned earlier we're going to be using the famous Titanic data set.
It's actually really often that the data sets used for a student's first step into machine learning
for classification.
We're going to try to predict is whether someone survives or if this was deceased and the Titanic disaster
.
Let's go ahead and begin by getting the data itself.
These files are on catgirls dot com Web site and there's a link for it in the notebook but it's also
in the repository you download it.
Go ahead and grab the Titanic underscore test that CCV file and the Titanic underscore train that CAC
file.
You can see here it's pretty split for you between testing and training data.
Let's go ahead and move along by actually grabbing those data sets and sending them as data frames.
I was going to use read dot CSV in a nice trick here is just type in the beginning of the file name
press tab and it will auto complete this case.
I just want that train that CFE data and let's go ahead and check out a couple of things.
Let's check out the head of DFI train.
And let's also go ahead and check out the structure of the train and we'll print that out as well
and let's prints some statements or some large blank line here.
OK.
Here we have the head.
We have a passenger ID column that just the past droite the number.
You'll notice it's just like the index.
Then we have a survived column which has a logical value 0 or 1 in the kidding whether or not they survived
.
We have a P class which is a passenger class.
So there's different classes on the Titanic.
First class second class third class.
We have the name of the actual passenger the sex or the gender of the passenger.
Male female the age of the passenger.
And then we have these two features sit S P and P R C H.
This first one S I B S P is the number of siblings or spouses on board.
So it's not a logical even though you only see ones and zeros.
Here it's an actual number of how many siblings or spouses this person had on board.
And then we have P P A R C H which is the number of parents or children aboard.
That way these basically indicate whether or not they had parents or children on board or a sibling
or spouse onboard and how much of a factor that was in their survival is something we're going to look
into later on.
We also get a ticket number a fair.
Meaning how much they paid for the ticket the cabin number.
You have some missing points there and embarked is a code of word.
Actually they got onto the ships of the ports of embarkation where sea is Cherbourg.
Q Is Queenstown and Southampton.
Let's go ahead and continue on to the actual structure of the data.
We have 891 observations of 12 variables passenger IDs survive the class etc..
Notice that the name is a factor of 891 levels that makes sense because they're essentially just all
unique character strings for all unique names.
Eventually we'll see that this is going to be useful to us in trying to predict who survived and who
didn't survive.
But you could maybe do some feature engineering and try to grab titles you may have noticed maybe like
someone's called Mr. Anthony or Dr. Anthony etc. and maybe titles are an important indicator of whether
someone survives or not if they have title of Sir or Madam they might actually be important enough for
being first class indicating they survive.
That's something we want to explore too much here.
But just something to take note of that we have sex is also a factor with two levels.
Female and male and then tickets are also a factor of a bunch of different levels and cabin and embarked
are also levels.
Let's go ahead and continue.
I'm going to go ahead and clear the cons. Let's continue by exploring the actual data through exploratory
data analysis.
What are we going to do first is check how much missing data we have we can use the Emilia package to
do this.
First of all what you're going to have to do is install the Amulya package so go in and say install
that packages and then install the Emilia package.
This package is really useful for exploring and visualizing how much data you're missing in your data
set.
How many of those data points are actually and a values.
The reason it's called the Milia is because it's named after Amelia Earhart who famously disappeared
when flying over the Atlantic Ocean by herself.
Go ahead and install this package.
I won't install it because I actually already have it installed.
So I would just call it instead of say library.
Amelia book X what we're mainly going to be using Amelia for is for something called a missings map
.
So after you've called Library Amelia and install there.
Go ahead and say help and type in Miss math and explore the documentation.
Let me bring this over for the missing this map.
And this basically plots a missing in this map showing where missing ness occurs in the dataset passed
to the Amelia library.
And what they mean by missing this is just how many values are in a or null.
Let's go ahead and use this on our training data we'll call mis map is the function you pass in your
data will say DFI train and in argument you could pass in Maine which is just the main title of your
data or of your visualisation excuse me.
In this case we'll just call it missing map the next argument we want to do is c o l and the argument
is just the a vector of two colors.
The first color is the colour for missing cells and the second color is for observed cells and you'll
get a better idea of what this actually means when we actually see the missing map visualization.
In this case I'll just put in a vector using the combined function that see with yellow as my first
color and black as the second one.
These are usually the most visible and they're the most commonly used for this sort of thing.
And then finally we'll say legend is equal to false.
Let's go ahead and run this.
And there we have our missings map.
So notice that we're missing or have a lot of and a values in age from this we can tell that about roughly
20 percent of the age data is missing.
The proportion of age missings is likely small enough for a reasonable replacement by some form of imputation
.
A lot of times your data you're gonna have to clean it by trying to take care of the missing data here
And that's how we're going to try to do.
Let's go to continue on by visualizing some more of the data of G.G. plot too.
And we'll do a little more exploratory data analysis and probably in part two of this logistic regression
lecture series we will actually fill in some of this data and start to build our model.
Right now we're still doing exploratory data analysis which is always a really important step for data
.
A quick no.
If you had an error when you were running mismatched maybe it said something like Access not big enough
.
You have to make sure for mismatched that you actually extend this plot window big enough before you
actually call the mismatch.
So just keep that in mind.
Let's go ahead and continue.
I'm going to go ahead and clear this.
Again you could always reference notes for all the code that I'm typing out here.
Next we're going to do is call library G-G plot to just explore the data.
Play around afit get a feel for it.
I'm going to say geez you plot D-F train passing the survivors column and I just want to know with a
bar plot how many people survived versus how many people didn't survive.
Let's go ahead and check that out.
And here we have a Barch plot with the count.
Notice that I didn't edit the X-axis So it shows values such as negatives are 0.5 percent 0.5.
But really we're just concerned about the center zero value versus one value zero as people that did
not survive.
One is people that did survive would be interesting is to try to continue this plot of bar plots by
let's say class.
So I'll say G-G plot's again pass my training data.
I'm going to say peak class
pass in geombar And what I'm going to go ahead and do is if I said I'm just passing geometer score bar
NSA aesthetic and say the fill of the bar is by a factor of the P class which essentially I just want
to color this by that P class.
Let's go ahead and run that.
And that allows me to automatically color by class looks like by far there was a lot more third class
passengers than either just second class passengers or first class passengers.
And there's slightly more first class passengers than second class passengers.
Let's go ahead and do the same thing for the gender or sex of the passengers just to get an idea of
there's more men than women on board.
A message going to replace this with sex here and it replace P.E. class with the sex column there.
Let's go ahead and run that.
And here we can also see that there's a lot more males on board versus females on board almost around
double the amount.
Let's go ahead and continue on with a histogram.
I'm going to clear these plot calls just so this is a little cleaner and SAGD plot to the left train
.
And let's go ahead and get a histogram of the ages onboard so say Jiya underscore histogram and I'm
just going to say been 0 to 20 let's make alpha 0.5 and let's also say Phil just so you get a nicer
colors blue.
All right I notice it gives you a warning message.
177 rows containing non-finite values were removed and those were the end values we saw earlier under
the age column.
So checking look at this.
Looks like most people on board were somewhere between the ages of 20 and 40.
We have less older people.
But interestingly enough we actually have quite a few young people and children on board which is interesting
to know.
Going to go ahead and say Gigi.
Let's make a few more visualisations the F train and let's go ahead and take a look at the sibling and
spouse is on board and we'll go to make a bar plot just to get an idea of the sibling count or spouse
count.
Ok looks like the majority of people didn't have any siblings or spouses on board.
So just a bunch of single people on the Titanic which kind of makes sense specially seeing how many
third class men were on board.
A lot of them just single workers on a one way trip on the Titanic.
Probably a little more one way than they would have liked.
Let's go ahead and continue by just doing a quick histogram of the fares paid to might be interesting
to check checkout.
Well say geez you plot the F train.
I'm going to say the it is fair since I want to plot a histogram of fair will say GM underscore histogram
.
Let's go ahead and click enter here.
I'm going to add a little more color to this since.
Just to make it a little more readable I'm going to say Phil is green
and our say color equals black and the color is the outline and the fill is the actual fill value of
the color.
And I'm going to go ahead and say Alfas equal to 0.5.
This will make this plot a little nicer.
OK.
Looks like most people paid a low fare which makes sense because most people were on the third class
and these higher fare values are probably only for the first or second class passengers.
You can go ahead and play the bin amount or the bin with to view this data a little more closely if
you want to.
Well we're going to go ahead and do now is explore data cleaning and trying to fill in that missing
data.
We're going to need to make sure the state is clean and tidy before we actually run it through our logistic
regression model.
If we remember back to the missing map data where we have an issue if we have a bunch of N A value is
in our data for age one way we could get rid of these any values is just drop all the rows the Haven't
any value for age.
However that's just too much data.
Remember those 177 rows of data that was missing out of the around 800 900 total rows.
That's just a little too much for us to comfortably get rid of all that data.
They'll be throwing away a lot of information which you could also do is fill in that data through imputation
.
And one way you could do that is by filling in the average age of all the passengers.
However you can be even smarter than just filling in the average age but actually fill in the average
age by passenger class.
And let me go ahead and show you how we can do this.
Well say P.L. Gigi Plaut the train and I'm going to go ahead and make a bar plot or a box plot excuse
me of class versus age and then let's go ahead and then reassigned people to P.L. Plus GM underscore
box plots and going to head and put in a couple of special arguments here.
I will say group P.E. class I always say Phil is the factor of P.E. class and this is mostly just for
visualization purposes making it look nice.
Now is the alpha equal to zero point for.
And then finally what I'm going to go ahead and do is say P.L. plus scale y continuous and this will
just allow me to set the actual numbers on the Y scale just for readability.
You don't have to do all this but this just makes the plot look a little nicer scale y continuous basically
just allows you to set the numbers on the y axis.
Current system ground zero 100 200 300.
But through this argument you can actually put in the number of breaks you want and the breaks argument
is just a vector.
This case I will use the SE Q function.
The regular sequence generator function.
I'll go ahead and say them in and 0 Max 80 and we'll go ahead and go by two.
And this is the plot we get out.
Kind of nice.
Let's go ahead and make it just a tiny bit nicer by saying theme underscore.
BW My favorite theme.
And there we have it.
Let's zoom in on this.
The reason I made this plot was because I wanted to show you basically a smarter way of actually imputing
those values.
Remember we're missing about 20 percent of our age data.
We could just grab the average age of every passenger and stick it as a replacement for all of that
missing age data.
However what we're going to do is be a little bit smarter and impute the average age by class because
notice that first class passengers are a little older than second class passengers and second class
passengers are a little older than third class passengers.
This intuitively makes a little bit of sense because being in first class requires you to be a little
wealthier and it probably takes a little more time to acquire that sort of wealth versus people in third
class or these younger mostly men passengers who don't have as much money and are much younger than
they are first class counterparts.
So is the average age here.
First class you're looking at about 37 second class around 29.
And third class you're looking at about 24.
So there's definitely a big difference from first class to third class as far as your average age.
Well we're going to do is create a function in order to take that into account when we replaced the
values.
Let's go ahead and quickly make that function and actually going to copy and paste it from the notes
and go through it and that will end part 1 of this lecture and then go ahead and leave those guys.
So we'll call this section
imputation of age based on class.
And I'm going to go ahead and make a function to do that.
Let me walk through it and actually copy and paste it from the notes here and hopefully have the ability
to actually make the sort of function on your own.
It's relatively simple as far as what the logic is doing what this is going to do is it's called imputes
underscore age.
It's a function that takes an age and class and then it has an outs as the age.
So I noticed this doctor's going to be that way.
Sensu are going to do is pass in the age column and the class column and then I'm going to say for I
in one to length of age.
So for every element in the age column I'm going to check if that age is an and a value if it's not
an a value we can go all the way down to the else statement here that lines up that if I'm just going
to say out of I is equal to age.
So I'm using index is and I'm going to eventually just return out here that will be my fixed age if
it is.
And they are going to check the class of that specific passenger which is why musing I hear numbers
saying for I and 1 through length of age essentially is going around indexing and then I'm saying if
class of icicle to one of and a first class than out of I is 37.
If the class of time is equal to second class the person's age going to be 29 the average of that otherwise
it means they're in third class.
So they're 24 years old and that's the way we can impute the average age based off of their class.
And then once we have that function we can just go ahead and do something like this.
I would say fixed dark ages and then call the imputes age function and in the age column as the first
argument and then the class column as the second argument.
All right.
That's it for part 1 of this lecture.
We'll go ahead and start right where we left off in part two.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture