Hello everyone and welcome to the linear regression project solutions walk through for this project
.
What you had to do was explore and create a linear regression model trying to predict bike sharing demand
And it's actually it was a Kaggle or Kaggle challenge project.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio and walk through the solutions.
OK.
So here we are in our studio.
Make sure that you went ahead and downloaded the BikeShare dot CSV file that was included in the notebook
download.
Or you can go ahead and download it directly from Kaggle.
All we had to do was just complete the tasks outlined in The Notebook.
First step was getting the data.
Let's go ahead and do that.
We wanted to read in the BikeShare that CSP file and set it to a data frame called like that's just
saying bike read CSV and bikeshare notice since I already have this bike share that CXXVI in my working
directory which is just here on their files tab.
I just get to say like sure that cxxviii if you have the CSP file somewhere else you'll have to put
in the whole path to the file.
Let's go ahead and just check out the head of the bike file or that data from scootch this over to the
right.
OK.
So we have quite a few variables.
Notice we have a date time which is an hourly date plus a time stamp a season either 1 2 3 or 4 for
spring summer fall and winter a holiday weather day is considered a holiday a working day 0 or 1 weather
days neither a weekend or holiday.
Some weather factor variables such as Clear mist light snow or heavy rain.
Temperature in Celsius a temp which is what it feels like which takes into account things like humidity
and wind.
And we also have humidity and wind here and then casual which is a number of non-registered user rentals
initiated registered which was the number of registered user rentals initiated and count which was the
number of total rentals.
Again you can refer to the notes if you want all the information on each of these variables represents
what we want to do is figure out what is the target we're trying to predict.
You have to check out the Kaggle link and hopefully discover that what you're trying to predict is this
final count column you want to try to predict based off the various features of that particular day
or hour.
How many bikes are actually going to be rented at that time slot.
Let's go at a start off of exploratory data analysis.
The main point of this project was to get you comfortable with EDK or exploratory data analysis.
So this is just such a huge part of performing data science data sets.
You haven't seen before.
Let's go ahead and call library.
You plot to answer the first question was create a scatterplot of count versus temp.
And it was also noted to set a good alpha value.
Let's go ahead and do that.
I'm actually going to run this in the console.
Let me hash tag out that print statements clear the console.
I'm going to call library plot.
And then I going SHC plots Pessin my bike data and I'm going to plot out temperature as my X and count
as my y and then the scatterplot hopefully are able to figure out that you should be calling Geum point
.
Let's go ahead and just call GM point and see what we get when we run this.
Let's hope it's plots like zoom.
All right.
Now they've zoomed in on this plot.
There's a few things I can immediately tell.
One is that it would be good to set an alpha value because they don't really know how many points are
stacked on top of each other.
Are these lower count levels.
It's a little hard to tell.
The other one is that there's clearly a discrete jump when we're actually measuring temperature.
There's no continuous values of temperature.
There are actually things like 10 11 12 etc. which is why we get these sort of lines.
Let's go ahead and try to edit this in order to make it even more clear.
I'm going to go ahead and set an alpha value equal to let's say 0.3 and let's go ahead and run.
That's.
Check out the zoom here.
All right.
Now it's definitely starting to get a little more clear as to the information of where we have a lot
of points stacked on top of each other and where we have just singular points and continue playing around
with this.
Something I did in the solutions which you didn't have to do but makes for a nice pretty graph is to
actually use under GMAT score point aesthetics color equals temp and this will allow us to set the color
based off the temperature.
And then I also added a theme.
BW just it's a little nicer.
Now if we click zoom here now we have a pretty nice plot as far as interpret the results.
I can see here that we have some heavy repeated counts over on the low counts of low temperatures and
then lighter temperatures over here it's 40 degrees for higher count levels.
But you can see the general trend that as you increase in temperature you get an increasing counts and
that's basically all you really need to tell from this plot.
Go ahead and mess around with your cheesy plot skills if you want to further customizes plot.
We'll go ahead and move on to the next assignments or task which was the plot count versus date time
as a scatterplot color gradient based off of temperature you'll need to convert the date time column
into POS IXC t before plotting.
Let's go ahead and do that.
First thing I need to do is convert
to time stamp and go ahead and review the time stamp lecture if you're a little fuzzy on this.
But basically I'm just going to say the date time column of bike as day six city like Date Time.
So go ahead and run.
That's great.
Now for a checkup by day time it should be as this time stamp information which means I can go ahead
and start plotting it out.
Analysts say G-G plots pass in bike and this one I want to plot is date time versus counts here.
So count is on the Y date.
Time is on X and then I want to scatterplot so geometer score point.
It's the instruction I specifically requested that the caller great is based off temperature which means
I'm going to go ahead and say under æsthetics here other GM points color equals temp and then I'll say
Alpha is equal to zero point five.
I'm going to go ahead and set this all to an object call P.L. and then I'm going to go ahead and print
people because it's going to be a few more things I want to do of peel before we finally finished this
.
All right.
What's interesting here is that you can kind of see a little bit of a trend.
You notice a seasonality for the data for winter and summer.
And you also note that bike rental counts are increasing in general.
You kind of see these two modes and one to try to edit the color gradient to make this very clear.
We're going to close this before we completely start analyzing the data.
I'm going to take P.L. and I'm going to add or customize this color scale right now it goes from dark
blue to light blue which is the default.
And I'm going to customize it by using scale color underscore continuous and then with this I can specify
the low value and the high value of the color.
I went ahead and just kind of searched online for some pretty colors.
I'm going to go out and copy them from the notebook but you can choose red or blue or whatever colors
make sense to you.
I played around the colors for a little bit and found that these two hex colors look nice and are clear
to me.
And then I'm going to go and say theme underscore.
BW is one of my favorite themes and cheesy plot just because it makes a nice white background.
Go ahead and call that.
And here we have a new plot which to me is quite a bit more clear than the previous plot.
And here we can definitely notice the two trends we have seasonality to the data for summer in winter
.
If you notice during the winter months we have lower counts versus the subsequent summer months.
So over here we have winter notice that starts in January and as we move towards summer we get an increasing
number of bike rentals again as we go back to winter.
We see a decrease in bike rentals and as we continue on going to summer again you get an increase in
bike rentals.
That's one trend you see the winter summer winter summer.
The other trend is that overall just as time progresses from 2011 to 2013 you see an increase in the
number of bike rentals period.
So the summer of 2011 had less rentals in the summer of 2012.
This may or may not be good for a linear regression model depending how it's actually trying to predict
the new count values.
OK let's keep all of this in mind as we continue on with the solutions what we wanted to know next was
what was the correlation between temperature and counts.
Hopefully you remembered from the lectures that you can use the CEO are or correlation function in order
to grab correlations but you have to figure out what you can actually just pass in columns directly
so you can say something like we're going to clear this C or our bike Khama all rows for the columns
.
And here we can just pass an advocate or columns so capacitor temperature and then counts.
And you can see now the correlation between temperature and count is around 0.4.
We wanted to continue to explore the season data and we wanted to create a box plot with the y axis
in the keening count and the x axis beginning a box for each season.
Let's go ahead and do that.
I'm going to say G-G plot pasand that my data which is bike æsthetics I want to do is season but remember
season is a factor so I want to say Factor Season and then it counts then something a box plot and then
go ahead and say GM underscore box plot and I'm going to go ahead and color
by the season.
Again I have to say Factor season since season is a factor.
One two three or four.
And then after all this I'll just go ahead and add a theme to it.
I really liked the theme.
BW since it's simple.
Go ahead and put it all in.
Check it out.
All right.
And this is what it looks like.
Notice what this says.
That means Slyne can't capture a non-linear relationship and that there's more rentals in winter than
in spring.
We know these issues because of the growth of the rental count.
That's actually due to the season.
And the reason I say that is because if you look at this box plot here it gives the indication that
the most popular seasons to have the highest count of bike rentals are seasons 2 and 3 which are summer
and fall.
But you'll notice that spring is quite a bit lower than winter.
Again that's because if we take a look back at our last plot here whoops.
This one.
The colored version of this.
There is a continual growth and that's going to set off those kind of box plot diagrams because here
we have a strong winter compared to the summer of 2011.
But the summer of 2012 is much stronger as far as count numbers versus those lower winters.
And that's because the trend that bike rental counts are moving up in general.
However if you fall along with your mouse you can still see that there's a seasonality to that data
and that's going to throw off a linear regression analysis as always.
Keep that in mind as you're moving along with your exploratory data analysis of your data.
A lot of times you only to use domain knowledge and experience to engineer create new features.
Let's go ahead and move away from G-G plot for a second and try to perform some feature engineering
.
OK let's go ahead and create in our column that takes the hour from the date time column and you can
do this a variety of ways.
And there are some hints for you in the notebook but the simplest way is just to use an anonymous function
with the Apply or apply method.
I'm going to say bike hour to create a new column bike hour and say a supply bike date time and I want
to create an anonymous function meaning I'm not going to create an entire function.
I'm just going to go ahead and create an anonymous one.
You could have gone ahead and created a function yourself.
But this is a little easier as far as saving space in the way you would have noted this as far as you're
maybe you're asking yourself how would I have known to done this format.
The answer is actually a hint in your notebooks or your notebook actually has my copy and paste it.
It has this as a hint so hopefully you're able to figure out that you could have formatted using this
time stamp.
Large our large h sign capital H.
OK let's go ahead and move along.
That's the feature engineering that's how you can create a bike.
Our column.
So if we go ahead and print the head of bike we should see that now.
All right so now we have an hour column that indicates our from zero to 24.
Let's go ahead and continue on using this information by creating a scatterplot of count versus our
with a color scale based on temperature and also only use bike data.
We're working days equal to one.
I'm going to go ahead and put in a call to the supplier library.
It's going to make that filter just a little more readable to use make believe that print statement
and I'll delete this print statements may clear this up.
And let's start with that scatterplot or go ahead and do this in the script.
I want to say P L is equal to G-G plots and I'm going to filter bike by working day equal to one.
And that's what I'm passing in as my data.
So I'm not just going to pass and bike and then a person the filter of bike or working day is equal
to one meaning.
Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday and then for the aesthetics it's going to be our on the x axis
and count on the y axis.
Let's go ahead and add some more to appeal to musée peoples then equal to P.L. Plus GM underscore points
for the scatterplot and I'm going to add some additional arguments later on.
But let's go ahead and keep it as Geum point right now and I will say Prince P L is going to run this
.
See if it all worked out for us right.
But go ahead and zoom on this.
I get an interesting plot here.
I can see on an average the number of used counts are bike rental counts based on the hour of the day
.
We see here that it's pretty low in the early morning which makes sense.
Lowest is around 3:00 in the morning makes sense.
No one's really out at 3:00 in the morning on their bicycle.
But as the commute hour starts to pick up especially around 7:00 a.m. 9:00 a.m. People are trying to
get to work.
A lot of people need to get to work on their bikes or they go ahead and rent that bike.
Then it dies down again.
A little peak around lunchtime but then a major peak where people are out of off of work and trying
to head home or maybe they're off of work.
I want to go on a bike ride.
And then it slowly dies down towards the evening.
Let's go ahead and try to get some more information out of this plot through the use of skill color
gradients and jitter.
First of all add in scale color gradients.
So I'm going to say P.L. in assign it to people plus a scale underscore color underscore gradients.
And I'm going to go ahead and say gradient n and what gradients and and if you want more information
you can just say helped scale underscore color gradient and but essentially what does is it creates
a two color gradient where you can actually specify the actual color names you want to perform your
gradient.
In this case I'm going to go ahead and just copy the colors from the notebooks it's quite a long list
and the colors I want for my gradient are from dark blue to blue to light blue to light green to yellow
to orange to red.
Let's go ahead and try that out.
Also here I'll say Prince P.L. Let's run this.
And notice I don't get anything out because I forgot to say GM points and said æsthetics color equal
to temperature see MP negatron from see if we get something different.
OK now I can see what I want to see which was color based off of the temperature gradient.
Now that we have some extra space to play around here with between the hours so between 7 and 8 there's
a bunch of empty space.
You can use jitter to actually fill in that space by setting the data points off of their original data
point a little bit.
As far as the hour point I'm going to show you how to do that.
The instructions are in your notebooks.
The answer is actually there but it's just an additional argument.
Go ahead and set just inside of Geum point which you go ahead and do is paste in this line position
equals position jitter and we add a little bit of jitter with the W which is the width.
We don't add any jitter along the y axis height and then what I'm going to go to do finally is add alpha
equal to or 0.5.
Here let's go ahead and run this again.
This is all optional you'd have to actually do any of this as far as the more advanced commands but
it's just a nice way to make a really nice looking plot.
And finally it's actually at a theme to this same principle plus theme underscore B W.
All right.
And now we have a really pretty plot's really indicating the use cases for G-G plot 2.
As far as exploring your data here we can clearly see a trend that the high counts of the morning commute
and then the evening commute as well as some activity during lunch.
What's interesting with this color skill gradient is I can see that there is higher count of bike rentals
when it gets hotter and lower counts of bike rentals when it gets cooled down.
That's really clearly indicated by the cool colors.
All right we're starting to finish up our exploratory data analysis section of this project.
Coming up next we'll do one more plot of the same for non-working days centrally setting this equal
to zero.
And we can actually do it right now if we just plot it out for non-working days.
Zoom in.
Notice that you don't get that morning commute.
And five o'clock exit is just during the day.
This is the weekend Saturday Sunday.
You go ahead and enjoy the day on your bike.
OK.
Coming up next Like I mentioned we're going to focus not any more on exploratory data analysis but actually
building the model itself.
Thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture