Hello everyone and welcome to the neural networks project solutions lecture this lecture.
We're going to go over the solutions for the neural network project and explain the code as we go along
.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio to get started.
OK.
Here in our studio we're going to need to do is read in the data into a data frame.
Go ahead and make sure you are in the right location and the data we're going to be using is the bank
underscore no underscore data that see every file and that's located under the sea as we files for M-L
projects folder may go ahead and read that data.
And then again to check the head of the data frame just make sure everything looks OK and it's looking
good.
We have the image variants the skewness the kurtosis the entropy of the image and then we have the class
which indicates whether or not a bank note is authentic.
We're going to go ahead and do is skip the edia the exploratory data analysis because you by now can
create whatever visualizations you're interested in.
We'll go ahead and skip this step and move on to the train test split.
Hopefully by now you're pretty familiar.
The train split her perform it will just go ahead and review it one last time.
Go ahead and call CAA tools and then if you want your results to match mine as far as the random split
you go out and set the sea to 101 then we'll say split sample that split pass in our data frame and
then we want to pass in a column I always pass in the column that we're going to be predicting which
is the class of our data frame and then go ahead and set the split ratio to 0.7 then we'll go ahead
and do the train test split by calling subset on our data frame and saying split equals true.
And we'll go ahead and say test subset data frame split equals false.
All right.
So that's the train to split.
Let's go ahead and run the source.
We have our trained test now.
Let's go ahead and actually start training our neural net in a push just a little over to the right
and clear the council member we got a call library neural nets and then what I encourage to do is actually
just check out the help documentation for the neural net function.
There's a lot of really good stuff in the documentation and I always recommend taking the time to read
it especially because these sort of topics weren't covered in the introduction to discoloring book.
All right.
Once you went ahead and browsed the documentation Well we'll go ahead and do is train our neural net
and clear this consul and say N-N
neural nets and I'm trying to predict the class based off of the other features which is the image variance
the image skew
the image kurtosis and then the entropy.
And keep in mind you could use that trick that I showed you in the previous lecture in order to create
this formula automatically since there's only four features I went ahead and just did it manually.
I want to pass in my data.
My data is just my training data for now and then we can go ahead and pasan a certain amount of hidden
neurons.
It doesn't it's hard to tell what the correct number of hidden neurons is or if you show multiple levels
.
I'm going to go ahead and just do what we did last time which was five and three.
And then lastly we want to say linear output and in this case since this classification it's not linear
.
So we're going to go ahead and say false.
All right.
Now that's been trained.
Let's go ahead and grab the predictions on the test dataset.
When I say predicted and n values computes
and then I'm just going to pass in the features columns 1 through 4 member column 5 is the actual class
to compute.
And there I have my predictive values.
All right now that we have those predicted values we can go ahead and do is check.
Head of the predicted and n values and then grab the net result which you notice is that they're all
still probabilities.
And this is basically the probability of belonging to the zero class or the one class where we can go
ahead and do is apply the round function to the predicted values.
So you only see zeros and ones is your predicted classes.
Let's go ahead and say predictions and we'll use a supply on the predicted end and values net results
and I'm going to apply the round function.
Now if I check the head of those predictions
we have all zeros and set of these small probabilities.
Something to note here is that we didn't actually scale or normalized our data in this case our data
as far as the actual columns were relatively at the same order of magnitude entropy was a little smaller
but it would still usually around either negative 5 up to 5.
And that means it wasn't a huge deal to not normalizer data you should normalize your data.
However if there's large ranges of min and max values between the column features in this case they
were all relatively similar.
So I didn't actually perform the normalization but I just wanted to make it clear that you should usually
perform some sort of scaling or normalization on your data before putting it into that neural net.
But we're about to see why that wasn't actually a huge deal.
Let's go ahead and use table to essentially create a confusion matrix on a say table
predictions and grab the test class column and you'll notice that we actually predicted perfectly from
the tests that we did extremely well.
And as a data scientist you should always be very suspicious of perfect results.
Now we're going to do now is compare against a random force model just to make sure we're not going
crazy here because one we didn't actually scale normalize the data and we still got perfect results
.
Let's go ahead and create a random forest library or model to compare it to a call the random forest
library.
And then what I'm going to go ahead and do is run the code that's in your notebook and it sets the class
column as a factor column.
And basically I'm going to paste it here.
Again this is from your notebook
and what it does is it takes a factor version of the day of class and then it goes ahead and read redoes
the train test split for that.
And that's going to be for the random forest when you go out and run that we already know that our neural
net predicted perfectly well the test set.
Let's see how our Random forest does when we go ahead and do control L here.
Going to creates the RF model the random force model cholerae in the forest pass in class
and I want to predict off of everything and then say data equals train.
All right our random force has been built and trained.
Let's go ahead and use the Predict function to get the predicted values from our RF model and a call
RF credit for the random force predictions predict pass in my model and then passes the test set.
And now let's call a table
and pass in the actual class.
OK.
What we notice here is that the random forest model performed very well but not perfectly well and that's
a great reality check for us.
It makes sense now that the neural net performed perfectly well because a random force was also able
to perform extremely well with just a little bit of a type 1 error and type 2 error.
All right I hope you enjoy the project and I sincerely hope you enjoy the entire machine learning section
of this course.
What I would suggest doing now is go ahead and go back to the other old projects you've done and compare
the performance of the machine learning algorithm discussed for that project versus a neural net or
maybe even go to the UC Irvine machine learning repository and test out your various skills for machine
learning algorithms on data sets that we haven't discussed yet.
Okay hopefully enjoying the machine learning project.
Thanks so much for completing the section of the course.
Thanks everyone.