Hello everyone.
Now that we've gone over a light theoretical overview of the perception and how to build a neural network
from a group of percept trons we're actually going to learn how to implement a neural network with our
using the neural network package or library for our let's go ahead and jump to our studio to get started
.
OK here we are at our studio.
We got some pretty cool stuff in store for this lecture.
But before we begin we have to actually get our data in this case we're going to use the famous or popular
Boston data set and it's from the mass package with our.
And if you don't have the mass package all you need to do is go to your consul.
And just like in the note book it says you can put in installed packages and capital M S S and that
should give you the mass package.
Once you have the mass package installed and downloaded you just call it library mass and you should
be able to call the head of capital B.
OS Boston let me go ahead and expand the council and scripts for a little bit and enter here and you'll
see we have a bunch of features of houses in Boston.
Keep in mind this housing data is from a publication that's from 1978.
So it's pretty old but it'll do for what we're actually trying to do in this case.
Each of these columns represents some sort of feature of a house for instance.
C R I M is the per capita crime rate per town than we have this r.m which is the average number of rooms
per dwelling in that particular area of Boston.
You have the tax rate the ages of the houses et cetera.
At the very end we have this median value of owner occupied homes in the thousands of dollars.
We're going to be trying to do is essentially almost like a regression problem where we have a bunch
of features and we're going to try to predict a continuous value which is the median value of owner
occupied homes in the thousands of dollars.
If you want more information on what each of these columns actually represents.
Check out the note book where the description of each of the features of this data frame.
Let's check out how large data frame is by calling structure member that's s tr Press in Boston and
it looks like we have 506 observations and there's 14 variables meaning the 13 features and number 14
we have what we're trying to predict which is the median value.
Let's go ahead and just quickly check to make sure we don't have any missing data member the way we
check for missing data and to clear the Consul is by saying NE is dot an A.
And then you pass in your data in this case I'm just going to pass in that Boston and we get false which
means false.
There is no and a value is in Boston meaning we're not missing any information.
So that's all great.
Let's go ahead and clear the console make a variable data and assign Boston to it.
That way we can mess around with data and it's a little more clear than just typing Boston all the time
.
We won't do any exploratory data analysis in this lecture but in your project that's coming after this
lecture you will do a little bit of exploratory data analysis on a dataset you haven't seen before.
For now we're going to focus on actually training a neural net model in order to do this we need to
do two things we need to pre-process our data.
And then you actually need to install the neural net library.
Let's continue on the data path and actually preprocess our data.
Whenever you're training a neural network it's a good practice to normalize your data and we can use
the skill function in order to normalize our data depending on your dataset.
Avoiding normalization may lead to useless results or to a very difficult training process meaning a
lot of times the algorithm won't converge before the number of maximum iterations is allowed.
But you can choose different methods to scale your data such as a min max scale Xen normalization a
bunch of different typical methods for scaling and normalizing your data.
Well I'm going to do is teach you how you can customize your arguments in the skill function and are
in the upcoming project.
I'll just have you use the default arguments for scale and that means it's going to be a lot more straightforward
but I do want you to know how you can actually customize the arguments that we put into our scale function
.
Well we're going to do first is grab the mid and emacs values of each of the columns in our data frame
and we're to do that using apply and we create a variable called Maxxis.
And I'm going to call the Apply function I'm going to apply over my data and I'm going to add a second
argument called margin.
And if you want more information on what that second argument margin does you can just call help on
apply and it should take the documentation apply functions over array margins.
But basically what's going to happen is if you just put in a two it indicates that we want to apply
this over the columns and that's exactly want because I want the maximum value of each of the columns
which is why I'm going to pasan a two here as my margin argument and then I'm going to pass in a function
that I want to apply over the columns.
In this case the function I want to apply is Max let's go ahead and see that analysis checkup Max's
notice now I get the maximum value for each of the columns mean the maximum value for the median value
of a group of houses is $50000.
We're going to do the same thing for the minimum values.
Let's go ahead and say an argument mennes make sure you have an s at the end of Maxxis or mindes that
we don't overwrite the actual max or min built in functions.
We're going to apply over our data.
That's the Boston dataset put into because we want to do this over the columns and then put in min for
the minimum function.
And now let's go ahead and check mins.
And now we have the minimum values for each of the columns.
Now what I'm going to do is use these men's and max values in order to scale my data or normalize my
data may go ahead and clear the con..
And what I want to do is go ahead and call help on the scale function and it should take you to a page
that looks like this in the documentation.
You'll notice that scale is just a generic function whose default method centers and or scales the columns
of a numeric matrix and that tells you two things.
One that it has default arguments and two it's going to return in numeric matrix meaning we have to
transform it back into a data frame.
Notice that these other arguments center and scale can be either logical values or numeric vectors.
In your project you're just going to leave them as the default logical values.
But right now on this show you can actually pass in the min and max values we just calculated in order
to customize your normalization.
What the first center argument is if we're going to pass in a numeric vector for center then each column
of our data has the corresponding value from center.
Subtract that from it meaning I'm going to do this on a cost scale on my data and say Center is equal
to men's and that means each single data point in the column is going to have the minimum value subtracted
from it.
And then we have the second argument which is scale in if we pasand a numeric vector for scale each
value in our dataset is going to be divided by the scale.
And that means I want the scale to be Maxxis minus mindes.
All I'm doing right now is I'm saying get my data in every data point subtract the minimum value of
that column that it's in and then divide it by the maximum value minus the minimum value and that's
going to normalize my data.
Let me go ahead and set this equal to scaled data and a push over the documentation's.
We have a little more room here and I have my scaled data.
Remember this is a matrix and that means I want to actually say scaled or scaled up data and passing
it as a data frame.
Let's say as that data frame and person that matrix and then I can get back head of scaled and notice
everything's been scaled now or normalized and that's exactly how we want it for a neural net.
This is a really important step and you should always make sure you're normalizing your data whenever
you're working with a neural net.
Otherwise you'll get funky results or it just won't converge and they pushed this a little more to the
right.
So we have a little more room to work with.
And if you want to confirm that this is actually scale you can just go ahead and check out the head
of the built in Boston data frame and notice that we actually had different values here.
You can you just check here in the median value.
Notice everything's now between 0 and 1 versus in the original you actually had the real values.
Now that we've standardized our data let's go ahead and split it into a training set and a testing set
.
Now we're already really familiar with this process.
Hopefully you can just do this on your own by now since you've done it for basically every lecture and
every project.
Remember you call CA tools get the variables split call sample dot split and then our scaled data pasan
any column.
I always like passing in or trying to predict in that case it's the median value in our split ratio
is just going to be point 7.
That means 70 percent of the data be for training which means I will say train is a subset of scaled
where the split is equal to true just put in capital-T and then test is the subset were scaled split
is equal to false.
Let's go ahead and run that
it looks like everything's good.
You get a warning message.
But again that just has to do with what version the library is built on.
But if I go ahead and say head of train looks like everything's working out I may go ahead and clear
the con..
Now we're ready to actually train our model.
We're going to need the neural net package in order to do this.
And that means if you don't have it yet go ahead and and your consul say install that packages and in
quotes person that's one word word neural net.
Once you've done that you should be able to call library neural net and have it all come out for you
.
All right.
Now that that's installed Let's go ahead and actually use the neural function from the library to train
a neural network for some odd reasons this neural net function won't accept the formula in the classic
form that we're used to or we just say why and untilled and Dadds it doesn't except that for whatever
reason you have to actually manually put in call 1 column to etc..
Usually we're used to being able to avoid that process by just using the dot.
And this time we're actually gonna have to manually put those all in.
I'm going to go ahead and show you a little trick that will help you avoid that manual labor of having
to type all those out.
Go ahead and ask for the names of the training data set the column names.
That we want to call and we see all the column names and in your note book you have a piece of code
.
I'm going to go ahead and copy and paste it from the notebook.
Now you grab it copy paste.
And what this does is it automatically joins all of these column names together into a formula.
Let me go ahead and just quickly break this down what we're doing is we're just grabbing every single
column name pasting it together with a plus in between.
And then at the at the very beginning we're saying MATV for the median value tilde and then we're going
to go ahead and paste in as long as it's not an MTV and then casting it as that formula.
And that's going to save you some time just using this names function and then using this formula little
cheat code that I put in the note book for you.
And then when you call f you'll see that this formula actually has already been written out for you
and that way you can avoid the process of having to manually type out each of these column names.
Hopefully that's useful to you but that's where you're going to have to do since you can't use the dot
notation for the neural net function.
Let me go ahead and clear the console now and actually train our neural net and create a variable called
an N called in your own that function.
It takes in a formula again and we couldn't do something like this.
We have to type in the whole formula.
In this case RLT save that as f is going to put an F..
I'm just going to train on my training data that Sika arguments that data and then we have an argument
called hidden.
And what the hidden argument does.
It's a vector of integers specifying the number of hidden neurons in each layer.
Go ahead and check out the Wikipedia articles as far as maybe what are reasonable values to choose here
.
But I'm going to go ahead and just choose a first hidden layer of five neurons and a second hidden layer
of three neurons you could keep adding to this.
Right now we'll just leave it at that.
And then since we're not doing classification we're actually doing some sort of continuous value.
Well we're going to go ahead and say is our final argument linear output equals true.
And you would set this to false if you're actually performing a classification problem your neural net
.
Well let's go ahead and train our neural net.
OK.
Now what's really cool here is we're actually going to be able to plot out the neural net that we just
created.
Let me go ahead and show you how you can do that.
I'm going to expand the visualization window a little bit.
Put it all the way out so we can clear when your output nicely.
All right.
And then all you do is say plots and pass the variable that is your neural net and you will see the
plot of your neural nets go in and zoom in on it.
And this is one of the good things and nice things about a neural net.
Basically a neural net you cannot treat it a bit of a black box because it's really hard to interpret
what each of these actual weighted vectors really means in reference to the column values of your data
.
We can see here that the black lines show the connections between each layer and the weights on each
connection and these blue lines that we see showed the bias term added in each step.
Again the bias can be thought almost as the intercept of a linear model.
The net here is essentially a black box.
That means we cannot say that much about the fitting the weights or even the model.
But we can't say is that this training algorithm converged and therefore the models ready to be used
on some sort of testing data.
All right let's go ahead and move on to actually creating predictions with our model.
I'm going to hope you thought this paralyzation was pretty cool.
Even if it's not super interpretable and I go in and close the shed over to the right and time for some
predictions I'll just go ahead and do this all in the con. I'm going to make a variable called predicted
and an values and for the neural net function you just use the compute function and you use compute
and sort of predict.
But we're usually used to you passing your neural net model and then you pass in your test data with
out the labels for it.
And that means columns 1 through 13.
Remember there were 14 variables or features in that column day to frame.
We just want the first 13 of them because we don't want that actual label.
And we compute those values if we check out the structure of what came out of that.
This predicted and end values.
Notice we get back a list a list of two there's neurons in the net result.
Well we actually want is the net result.
But remember we scaled and normalized our data for the training model.
What we have to do is basically undo those operations in order to get the true predictions.
And that means I'm going to make a variable called True predictions and say predicted and end values
net results and I'm going to go ahead and just copy this formula from the notebook and then quickly
explain it.
Remember that we were subtracting from the center value and then dividing by that scale value or performed
our normalization operation.
And basically here we're just inverting that.
Notice that I'm saying instead of dividing by Max minus min of that median value of our data I'm saying
multiply it by the max minus the men and then instead of subtracting from that center value I'm saying
go ahead and add that center value and I'm just grabbing the Maximin from that specific median value
column.
And this will essentially and the scale or get non-skilled predictions let me go ahead and also convert
the test data.
I'm going to go ahead and just copy those.
Going to say testor are in basically doing the exact same thing.
And the reason I'm doing that is in order to actually get some sort of mean squared error from this
and I say mean squared error.
M S E and say and then remember that's the sum of our test minus our true predictions.
And the reason I call that true there should be a minus sign is because these are the non-skilled predictions
.
And then what I'm going to go ahead and do is square this and then divide it by the number of rows in
our test set.
And that's the main square.
Go ahead and call it now and figure out the mean square error.
Well we can also do is visualizes error in G-G plot 2 by actually just graphically showing the true
predictions plotted by the test values.
All right let's go ahead and create a data frame air Dia and i will call the data frame function and
pasan my test values going to call and test R and then my true unskilled predictions.
Let me go ahead and check the head of that error.
D f.
All right.
And this is basically how we have the test value for that particular house.
This was Row 2 row 4.
Notice these aren't sequential because we did that random train test split and then we have these true
predictions.
These are the unskilled predictions of our neural net.
Looks like we're not doing too bad.
Let's go ahead and visualize.
Visualize this by saying the test the test values on the y axis and the true predictions on the X-axis
.
I'm going to call me go to clear the consul here.
When ecology as you plot to which are already very familiar with say G-G plot ere the F Pescara data
and as the æsthetics I'm going to go ahead and say X is the test are and why is those true predictions
.
I want this to be a scatterplot and a go ahead and say GM underscore points
and then I also want to go ahead and Panay that smooth line just to see a little more on the visual
side.
How we did is go ahead and run that.
And that should have been smooth not state smooth Let's cool this plot out and there it is.
Go ahead and click zoom.
Remember that a perfect prediction would just basically be a straight linear line with a slope of one
.
And here is our true predictions meaning Menier unskilled prediction of values versus the actual test
data.
Looks like there were some houses that threw off our model.
But overall it's not looking too bad especially considering all we have to do is normalize our data
.
And we treated the neural net as essentially just a total black box and that means we can conclude a
couple of things that neural networks resemble black boxes a lot explaining their actual outcome and
how they interpret the features is much more difficult than explaining the outcome of a simple simpler
model such as like a linear regression.
Therefore the pending on the kind of application you need.
You may want to take this into account as well.
That means if you're doing something at work or your own project where you need to specifically interpret
the importance of each of the variables a neural network that is little more black boxy may not be as
good as a simpler model.
And then furthermore as you've seen here extra care is needed to fit and neural that work in order to
actually use that data and that means stuff like normalization of your data.
Ok I hope you enjoy this lecture.
Coming up next is your neural network project.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.