Hello everyone and welcome to the Apply lecture in this lecture we're going to learn how to use the
Apply function in order to apply a function over a list or a vector.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio and see how it works.
OK so here we are our studio and to start off I want to go ahead and show you a simple function called
sample first the builtin sample function allows us to just randomly sample objects from a vector.
So this case I can say X is a vector of 1 through 10.
And the second argument is how many actual objects I want to grab from this vector.
So I just want to grab one object from one the source for that.
Nothing actually occurs.
Let's go ahead and print this out.
And you know every time we run this is going to just run it multiple times we get some random number
from X and X is just this a vector of integers 1 through 10.
So if I also changed this to let's say from 1 to 100 then I can change the second parameter to 3 or
just get three random numbers between 1 and 100.
So that's all sampled does.
So you can go and play around with it.
That's a pretty useful function.
And we're going to be using it in just a second.
Now let's get back to our main topic which is apply.
We can use apply in a really practical use case when we want to apply some sort of function over a vector
.
So we are a vector.
Let's go ahead and make a vector one two three four five.
You could also use that one colon or five to make the same vector in.
Now I'm going to make a custom function we'll call it add Rand.
And the reason I wanted to show you the sample function first I'll say at of rand which is going to
just add a random number.
Well say it takes an X and it's going to grab a random number between 1 and 100.
So one in 100 of vectors the first argument and just want to grab one random sample from that and then
I'm going to return the input X plus that random value ran.
And that's my random function.
Let's go ahead and make sure it works.
So I'm going to call Prince on at Rand and I'm going to go ahead and put 10.
See what we get up.
I'm going to clear my console and run this ok.
Notice I get 20 out if I run this again I should get something completely different.
Run it a few more times.
I should get just some random number added to 10 with a round number B being between 1 and 100.
Now let's see how I can use our first apply function to apply this function over a vector What apply
function I can use is l apply and L apply.
The first argument you pass in is the vector and the second argument.
Passen is the function.
Notice I'm not actually calling the function with parentheses.
I'm just passing the function and that's an important difference.
So I'm going to go ahead and say l apply V Adarand and I'm going to just run this.
Let me clear the cons. first.
And what I'm going to go ahead and do is assign this L apply result to some variable called result and
then we can go ahead and say print results and make sure spooled result right here.
Result.
OK let's go and run this.
See it works.
OK so notice will we get back out with L.
Apply we get a list out which is why it's called L apply list apply and all this function does is it
takes some vector and then input functions.
Vector can also technically be a list but it's easiest to use it with a vector and it's going to apply
this function to every single element in this vector.
So in this case we're saying OK go to every single element and add a random number to apply this function
.
Add rinde and in the result it will store each of these separate results as an item in a list which
is why we get this sort of double bracket output.
Each item in a list now a lot of times you won't want a list back.
You want something simpler simpler which is just like a vector or a matrix in order to do that.
You can just use as supply which simplifies process by just returning a vector.
So if I go ahead and run this again noticed we get back a vector of 5 essentially random numbers.
So we took in this vector and apply this Adarand some expand that this ad Rand function to every single
element in that vector.
What's good and clear all of this and show one more example so we can really get an understanding of
how these apply functions work.
I'm going to go out and create a vector just going to be the numbers let's say 1 through 5.
I'm going to create a function called Times 2 and the function accepts some number arguments and it's
going to return that number times to then I'm going to go ahead and say my result is equal to s apply
and I'm going to go ahead and pasan V and then my function times 2 and then I'm going to print.
My result is going to run this.
And notice it took the we go ahead say print's V before we apply anything around this again.
It took V and essentially multiplied every single element in V by two to get two four six eight 10 back
and that's how apply works.
There's actually several apply functions and you can find all of them by just saying help on one of
them for instance as apply just call help here go in and pull up the Help tab.
We apply a function over a list or a vector.
So the base function for all of these apply functions is l apply.
So l apply returns some list.
A lot of times you won't want to list.
So there's other apply functions such as apply which is the one we just showed here.
So user friendly version wrapper of L apply that it defaults to returning a vector or Matrix.
There's also the apply which is similar to supply but it has some pre-specified type of return value
.
So sometimes it can be a little faster to use than as supply.
So you can feel free to use via plier as apply as you see fit.
Then there's some more information on replicate and simplify to array case instead of reading more about
those.
Again the best way to check all of this out is just by calling help on any of the Apply functions.
It'll take you to the main.
Apply a function over a list or vector documentation page.
The main idea here is I'm going to call a supplier.
L apply depending on what I want my output to look like.
I pass in my vector and then second argument I pass and the function again.
No that I'm not actually calling the function.
So I'm not putting parentheses here like that and just passing in the function as an argument not calling
it.
And then I can store the result in print the result or do whatever I want.
In that case.
Now let's talk about anonymous functions in a go ahead and expand the our script and the consul here
and I'm going to clear the consul and let's talk about anonymous functions
.
There we go.
So you notice in one of these last examples we had a rewrites an entire function to apply over the vector
and then involve the process something like this at RAND.
And then we had to call function etc. make some clearly brackets write some code and that can be time
consuming and it can also take up space.
Since you're taking the entire variable name to define your function that's where anonymous functions
will come into play.
If we don't actually want it take all that space and effort to create an entire function.
If you're only going to use it once meaning a lot of times you don't actually want to have to formally
define an entire function.
If you're only going to use a function once in anonymous function is a great tool and our That allows
you to quickly create a function without having to name it.
This is a similar idea to lambda expressions in Python.
Let's go in to show an example of how we can use this.
I'm going to go ahead and create a vector v the numbers 1 through 5 and then I'm going to use s apply
pass in V and instead of passing in a function such as Rand add or etc. I would actually build an anonymous
function as my argument right here and the syntax for an anonymous function looks like this.
You type the keyword function in parentheses.
You type in some variable for the input or go ahead and say numb and then in curly brackets you go ahead
and type what you want to return this case go ahead and return some times too.
And I'm going to go ahead and say this as a result.
And then print the results I could have also just said print on this entire supply statement but this
is a little more readable.
OK.
There we have it.
Two four six eight ten.
So this worked so successfully.
So what are we actually trying to do here with this anonymous function.
We save ourselves the effort of actually labeling this function and naming it.
I'm going to go ahead and build out this function again one last time is a formal function so I can
break down how it looks as an anonymous function.
So I can say a function times to call my function keyword.
I pasan.
And I want to go ahead and return nine times too.
That's what this looks like as a formal function.
And that's what I would pass in here just times too.
If I had a formal function but the anonymous function breaks this down you get rid of this naming or
assignment operator step you get rid of the return call and then you just go ahead and get rid of these
princes and put the curly bracket all in one line.
And that's how an anonymous function can be created from a normal function.
Anonymous functions are really good for very complex tasks or stuff.
But for something simple like this you just want a quick single use function that you don't want to
formally name or define.
This is a great choice.
All right.
That's all I want to show for anonymous functions for now.
Lastly I want to show something really quickly about using a supply or L apply with a function that
takes in more than just a single arguments.
For example let's go in and keeper V.
And let's talk about apply with multiple inputs.
I want to create a function called add underscore choice and the function takes in two arguments numb
and choice.
And what it ends up doing it just returns
your number plus your choice.
So if I call it's going to print this add choice I can pasan a number two.
And then my choice 10 to go ahead and run that 10 plus 2 is equal to 12.
So what if I wanted to apply the add choice function to every single element in my vector v.
Well I would say this this case is a supply.
So I want a vector back I pasand v what I want to actually apply over and then I pass in my function
name add choice except for I just run this.
Let's go out and try this.
We should get an error and you'll see why it says error in fun.
And this is just a general term for a function.
You'll notice this is argument choice is missing with no default meaning it didn't know what to put
for choice here.
It knows what to put in for number because it's using the number for the vector.
However it doesn't know what to put in for the additional arguments.
If we have additional arguments so we need to put in with our function that we're trying to apply we
can add those as more parameters into the Apply function sirra.
Can I just say choice is equal to.
Let's go in and put in 100.
Now if I run this it works just fine.
So keep that in mind or using a supply or apply or apply with functions that take in multiple inputs
.
All you have to do is take the name of the other parameters that you want for your function in your
apply statement and you can go ahead and add them on after you call your function.
So it goes.
Vector function and then any additional arguments with the values you want to put inside of them.
OK so that's it for apply.
What you should have gotten out of this as a quick review is how to create an anonymous function.
I'll show you one more time how to do that.
Imagine we wanted just to say no and create a function called add to this would it look like this as
a normal function taking the number add two to that number for an anonymous function.
We get rid of the assignment operator.
We go ahead and get rid of the return statements and we put this all in one line.
So it looks like this.
This is the anonymous function version of that add to function.
All right.
And the second thing you should have gotten out of this lecture is how to use a supplier l apply by
passing in a vector and passing in a function in order to apply that function to every element in that
vector.
All right that's it for this lecture.
Thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture