This video it's continued from part one.
Right.
So moving on it's starting to look pretty similar.
But there's a couple of things we're still missing.
First off we need to add labels and we've actually never shown how to add labels before.
So the instructions say we can use GMAT score text.
Let's go ahead and just try that going to go ahead and say peel three is peel two plus underscore text
and then for text.
If I go ahead and pass it it helps.
Hopefully you are able to do this by checking out help.
You can say GMAT score text will search for that.
And notice we get some textual annotations.
So basically what this does is adds text directly to the plot.
And part of the project is free to figure out how to do these additional things because there's tons
of plots tight plot types and we're not built to go over all of them in this course.
But what I want you to have is the skills to look these kind of functions up either in the documentation
or what's really helpful is that cheat sheet we showed earlier and figure out how to do this by just
reading the documentation because that's a key skill to using our for programming is being able to search
either Google or stack overflow or the documentation to figure out how to do something that you haven't
actually seen before.
This case we're going to use GM underscore text and what we need to do is add a label to this.
So after reading documentation scrolling down and just seeing these examples hopefully we can begin
to tell that you need to just add some sort of label to this so if we just run this by itself no what
will happen if we just say print all three and we run this.
You'll see that we require the following aesthetics that are missing label.
So we actually say what's the actual label which makes sense.
Otherwise we don't know what we should be plotting.
So I'll say yes label equals.
And in this case if we take a look at our data frame head of the if we have a couple of labels we can
either label things by the country or HDI rank HDI CPI region and the actual text.
I want looking back that economists plot it was the name of the country.
So let's go ahead and put in country as a label.
So this actual argument should feel really similar to when we added things like color by region and
another geometry late layer.
This case we're just assigning the static of the data we're going is this case it's a label for geometers
cortex as the country.
And now if I run this I should get a bunch of country labels.
All right.
So that's good except there are way too many labels and it shows in the instructions that there should
be way too many labels in order to minimize or get rid of some of these labels that we don't need.
We want to select a subset.
I'm going to go ahead and jump quickly to the notebook for this so I can show you on I'm referencing
but if we take a look at the notebook going to bring in screen now notice you actually given the code
in order to grab this subset it's going to go in and copy this.
But I want just to show you what it's actually doing.
This case we created vector of the points to label and this is what would take a long time actually
making this vector name.
So it's already done for you you don't need to waste your time on that and essentially just add them
in as additional arguments to this GM underscore text.
So I set some color this case I said kind of a darker gray.
You can just set it as black if you want and we say data equals and we're using that subset command
.
So we say subset past year data and we're going to use this in operator and the operator looks similar
to a pipe operator.
But what it does is it just checks if a certain value is in a vector.
So in this case I'm going to say this.
I mean go ahead and zoom in so I can fully explain this.
I say GM underscore text where my label is equal to my country.
We've done that so far.
I set the color to just some dark gray and then I say data of this actual labeling is equal to the subset
of my data frame where the country is in these points to label here.
So just checking if it's in there and there's additional argument check underscore overlap because true
will try to automatically make sure that these text points don't overlap with each other.
So I want to go ahead and copy this and then put it into my code.
So the reason that's there in the notebook for you is because it's a lot of typing and it's stuff that
you would just kind of have to take a lot of time to look up which is why I labeled it for you.
So let me go and paste that in.
All right so we have this big ugly vector.
Let me go ahead and expand this.
We can work with this and then will shrink it down again.
All right.
So how many points to label vector which is kind of this large ugly vector.
I'm going to go ahead and cut this and just put it here at the top so we don't really have to worry
about it that much.
And we really want to do is worry about this geom underscored text which is again just adding in that
label because one country and then taking the subset where the country name is in these points to label
.
Right.
And I know we didn't specifically cover this in our previous lectures.
Reason being just kind of this very specific action we have to take to try to make our plot look as
close as we can to The Economist.
So let me go ahead and say print t l 3.
Let me run.
That's an resizes windows.
We can actually see the output of the plot.
So order to resize that make or cancel small so we're not really using it and then control shift as
to run this.
And it looks like we have our plots or plot is starting to look more and more like the actual plot from
the Economist.
OK.
We'll go ahead and continue moving on.
So now that we have that it's still not exactly like the economists plot is almost good enough for the
assignment really.
But what we want to do is just add in some themes.
So in this case I'm going to take advantage of the Gee-Gee themes library we've played with a little
bit earlier.
So G-G themes in I'm going to just run that line so that I can grab the themes later and I'm going to
add a layer to this on a theme underscore and there's actually a white economist theme so that makes
her job a lot easier.
But you can actually just play around with the themes decide what looks best for you but really at this
point it's just playing around this trying to make it look nice you can add a title master of the X
or Y labels et cetera.
But if we just run this line we go something that looks pretty similar to the Economist plot.
So we have a plot that looks very similar to the Economist's plot in what I'm going to do is add one
more argument to change this x axis.
And again you don't have to do this you can pretty much go either as far as little as you want.
In this plotting exercise usually not going to be trying to copy a plot from the Internet.
Hopefully you're going to be making your own original plots.
Let's go ahead and explore how we would just fix the x axis in order to make it go from zero to 10.
Like it did it that economists plot to go ahead and expand this and I'm going to go ahead and say peel
four and assign it to all three.
And I'm going to go ahead and add a co-ordinates lair or some sort of scale layer.
And the argument for this is scale underscore X underscore continuous and these sort of arguments for
additional coordinates are Fassett values etc..
You're pretty much going to have to be looking these up as you go along or referencing that cheat sheet
that we showed earlier.
A lot of the process of using G-G plot beyond just the basics that we've covered as far as that data
layer aesthetics layer geometry layer is just looking things up or looking up examples and maybe some
sort of cookbook which are available on the Internet as well.
And then just seeing what formulas you have to follow this case I looked it up in the documentation
.
And how do you scale underscore X underscore continuous.
This is the sort of thing that I wouldn't expect you to know right off the top of your head unless you
using GZA plot a lot.
So let's go ahead and set our limits equal to in this case.
I want to go from point nine to ten point five.
So a little less than 1 and a little more than ten.
And in that case I can add breaks which just sets the actual breaks.
So where that the dashes actually belong.
So my dash set one two three four five six seven eight nine ten.
And that's the reason why I had to set the limits a little less than one and a little more than 10.
Let me go ahead and then say Prince P.L. for run this zoom on this.
And now we get something that has the same x axis 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10.
OK.
And again I can add a theme to this so I can just say Crantz four plus theme underscore economists why
to try to make it look even more like that economists plot.
All right.
So again just go ahead and play of the solutions.
You can go as like as mentioned before either as little or as far as you want with this sort of plotting
.
The main idea is just to get you used to adding a data unaesthetic Slayer and geometry layers.
Well I would expect you to have been able to do by yourself without really referencing anything.
Is this data layer and knowing geometry underscore or geometer score point layer then I would expect
to you have been able to call GM underscore smooth but maybe not have figured out how to do this method
of formula.
E color this stuff is more related to linear regression in general not the actual plotting the vice
.
So as long as you are able to figure out hey I can make a data and layer I can add my points and I can
add a smooth fit curve.
Then you should have been more than enough good as far as this project is concerned.
The rest of this is just icing to make it look as similar as possible to that economists plot.
All right.
Hopefully that was interesting for everyone being able to recreate a plot you see on the Internet just
using G-G plot.
And the main idea of this project is to reiterate just how powerful G-G plot is and its customization
abilities.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture