This video it's continued from part one.
Next one up we want to learn about is select going to go ahead and clear this data frame so often you
want to work with large data sets that have a lot of columns like the ones we're working with but only
a few of the columns are actually interesting to you at a certain period of your analysis.
The select function allows you to quickly zoom in on a useful subset using operations that will usually
only work for numeric variable positions.
So for example I'm going to pass and heads only get the first six rows.
I'm going to go ahead and say select you passing your data and then just pass in the column you want
.
So for instance I want to just select carrier and there is the first four six rows of my carrier column
So I want to do this with more than one column.
I could just continue adding those in as additional parameters in that select function.
So we can say select the carrier column and the arrival time column.
And there you have it you can also keep adding columns as you wish.
Please.
OK.
So that's it for the select.
It's just an easier way to quickly grab your data and then just in the columns you want to select from
it.
Moving on we have the rename function the rename function allows us to quickly rename columns.
So for example note and clear this.
Let's say I want to rename that Harrier column to airline carrier just so it's a little more clear.
I'll go ahead and just ask for the head we pasand the rename function first argument for pretty much
all of these functions that we've been working with.
Is your data.
And then the syntax is the new column name you want.
So for instance I want airline carrier to be in my new column name equals and then your old column name
.
In this case the original column was called carrier.
So all rename does is you pass in your data and then as parameters are functions arguments into this
rename function you in the new column name you want equal to the old column name.
And if I go ahead and check this out.
Notice we get airline carrier as the new column name and carrier is no longer showed here and that's
it for the basics of renaming a column using renamed function.
Now let's talk about the state which is another really useful function with the player.
So the distinct function is going to allow us to select the distinct values or unique values in a column
or table.
So I'm going to go ahead and just say distinct in this case I don't actually have to call ahead since
I'm not going to get a huge number back so I'm just asking for distinct.
And then we'll go ahead and say let's just get the distinct carriers in our flights dataset.
So say flights here and there we have it we have the 16 distinct airlines.
So what is actually going on here.
Well first I say select flights carrier and if you remember back to how the select function works for
the plier you passing your data first and then the actual column you want to select or list of columns
you want to select.
So this internal command is just the same thing as saying flights dollar sign carrier and then passing
that into distinct were returned the unique values in the results which is this case all the unique
airline names.
And that's a really useful way to use distinct.
So it's really common to use distinct along with some select function in order to grab all sync values
of a particular column.
All right so we learned about distinct.
Now let's learn about mutate.
So besides selecting sets of existing columns it's often useful to add new columns that are functions
of existing columns and this is where the job of mutate comes into play.
So you pass in mutates again.
First argument is always the data you're working with.
And then what you go ahead and do is say new call or whatever your new column name sort of like when
you were using the rename function.
But in this case instead of just passing a single column like we didn't rename with mutate you can actually
make a new column that's a function of existing columns.
So for example let's say I wanted to create this new column that was equal to the arrival.
Whoops delay minus the the partridge Dilley So if muet say I can actually pass in these sort of functions
of the existing columns and assign them to a new column and I'm going to going to go ahead or just call
head of this so we don't get a huge output and notice all the way over here I get new column.
Great and this new column is going to be the resulting of a rival delay column minus departure delay
.
So this is kind of a nice quick way to create new columns that are not just renamed versions of old
columns but are actually built off with some sort of formula of the old columns in your data frame.
So we could have also done something like Time's departure delay even though it doesn't really make
sense.
But you still can create new columns that way and this mutate function is related to the transmit function
.
If you only want the new columns that you created back you just use transmutes instead of mutate.
So for example we just go ahead and copy paste this.
If I only want this new column back instead of calling me I'd say you call transmute
trans mute.
And there are the first six rows of that new column.
Again the only difference here being mutate will return the entire data frame along with that new column
you created and transmute will only return the new column you created.
So they're related and the same functionality on what happens inside the function.
They just differ in what you actually get in return.
OK we just have a few functions left to talk about.
Summarize sample and sample frac.
It's good and clear the cons. And quickly discuss those.
So summarize allows us to quickly collapse data frames into single rows using some sort of function
that aggregates a result.
This is really similar to the built in aggregate function in our or something like a group by statements
in a sequel like language.
So for instance we can say summarize past and the data we want comma and the name of your new column
.
I'm going to go in and say average air time I'll say equals two.
And then I need some sort of aggregate function.
So for instance I can take mean which is the average and I'll go ahead and pass in the airtime column
that's already existed in my data frame and I'll add one more argument and a dot r m equals true.
And that's an argument for the mean function which is built into our in order to just remove any values
.
Since in my data frame not every single row has a value for every time.
So if I say any that remove it will just go ahead and remove those values.
But that's part of the mean function not to summarize function.
So if I go in and show this we get one Roback And that's basically how summerize works.
It should be some sort of group by function or some sort of aggregate function that allows us to get
our data passed in the column we want back as the new name and then some sort of aggregate function
.
So we could then say something like lips.
Let's say we wanted total air time by all the flights.
We could then say something like total underscore time is equal to some of the air time column and that's
the total time spent in the air.
But all these planes again you should only really be getting one row back when you're using summerize
because it's an aggregate of all the data.
You're quickly collapsing that data.
Finally we have two functions left which are related to each other sample underscore n and sample underscore
frac.
And basically what these do is allow you to take a random number of rows or a random fraction of rows
.
So for instance I can say sample let me go in and clear the con. I can say sample underscore and pass
in my data frame.
In this case its flights and pass in the number of rows I want to randomly sample from my data frame
.
So this returns 10 random rows.
So this isn't like head or tail which returns the top or the bottom 10.
This returns a random n number of rows so just a random sample of.
In this case I just set 10 rows if you want to do it by percentage.
You can use sample underscore frac in order to receive a fraction of the rows.
So again you just pass in flights whatever your data is and the fraction you want back.
So if I wanted back 10 percent of my rows you would just point point 1 in there.
OK.
So that's it for the plier.
Hopefully you can see how it really simplifies the syntax and makes rereading your old code a lot easier
.
Go ahead and check out the notes for this lecture.
In case you want to ever refresh on how to use any of these functions later on we'll have an exercise
that will show you and re-affirm you're learning on how to actually use all of these.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture