Hello everyone and welcome to the logistic regression project solutions part to lecture in part one
the previous lecture we went ahead and got the data and then we also transformed feature variables with
a lot of factor levels and we reduced the number of levels in those factor variables.
Let's go ahead now and explore the missing data using the Amelia package do worked with previously and
to jump to our studio to get started.
OK here we are our studio and I'm going to go ahead and clear the console.
Here we have our script with all the transformations.
Let's go ahead and clear this structure print statement out and start a new section or code.
We'll go ahead and call it missing data.
OK first thing going to do is call the Amulya package.
Go ahead and install the Amulya package if you haven't done so already.
That's basically a package that allows us to create missing maps.
The next step you had to do was convert any cell with a question mark to an end a value.
There's lots of ways to do this but one of the simplest ways is just to do this transformation by saying
adults and you'll say it we're adult is equal to the character question mark.
Go ahead and transform that to an end a value.
That's the easiest way to do this.
You can also do like an is and a check or apply that to a data frame.
But this is probably the easiest way to do that.
That's just going to cover all the question mark or that character question marks in the data set to
any value.
So we actually get missing data instead of just a question mark character.
Then what we're going to do is use table on a column and a values should now display not those any values
but just see a zero for question mark levels.
Let me go ahead and show you what I mean by that.
I'm going to say print's the table let's go and explore type employer.
If you remember from part one when we explore a type employer we went ahead and grouped the type of
employment's to self-employed.
Federal government state and local government and then private and unemployed.
And I will say that question mark call him let's go and explore this by running this after running this
line.
I have a few other print statements that are running Here's our table print statement.
Notice that now I have a question mark as to zero which means what we want to do is actually refactor
or apply that factor to all those columns again.
I'm going to go ahead and grab this factor code.
Let's go ahead and grab the label as well and do it after we do this transformation going to go ahead
and paste it here.
That way we don't have these questionmark levels anymore.
OK something else that is going to delete this print statement.
And like I mentioned earlier you can actually just supply factor.
You say the factor of this column instead of saying a supply but that's totally up to you than what
we're going to do is go ahead and just to make sure it works.
Check table of adults.
We'll go ahead and say type employer.
Run this code.
And there you have it.
We no longer have this questionmark level notice that any values just won't show up.
Perfect.
That's our table.
We want to do now is play around with the mismatched function from the Amelia package.
Hopefully you can kind of play with it and start to figure it out.
If you just say mismatched adults after calling the Amulya package what you want to do is expand your
plot's window called mismeasure adults and you'll notice you'll get a missing map or a missing this
map but it looks kind of ugly.
It will show you lines the missing values and the observed values but then you also have a bunch of
crap there for the labels.
What you want to do is note that this is basically a heat map pointing out missing values and it gives
you a quick glance at how much data is missing.
In this case it's not a whole lot.
Relatively speaking you probably also notice that there's a bunch of white labels and you can get rid
of them through the following command.
And this one is actually in the notebook.
And we go out and copy and paste it.
If you run this code instead where you say Why Dot labels is equal to a vector of a single empty string
.
And you also say why x is equal to this vector of 1 and you can set the colors for a missing versus
observe.
This will actually produce a cleaner looking Messina's map perfect this is a lot cleaner.
It won't actually show the white label data points of who is missing data from those actual index values
.
It's a lot easier to interpret than the kind of previous uglier plot.
OK.
Hopefully you're able to create that plot.
Now we want to do is think about how we can deal with this missing data.
We could just pass an average values we did something like that for the Titanic dataset.
However no occupation and type employer both of them are not numeric values so we can't just say OK
impute the average employer type or we're going to go ahead and do is it's not so much of our data.
We're just going to drop it.
And the way you can drop it is by using an 8. omits.
Now let's go ahead and start a new section called Drop missing data
and the command that just any omits adults or Belisa adults to get rid of its missing data going to
go out and run this
nation is quickly note that this line depending on how fast your computer is it may take a little longer
to actually compute.
Looks like it's done.
Let's go ahead and copy this line and redo our missing this map.
Hopefully now we won't see any actual yellow lines here.
Perfect.
That means we observe every value and we have no missing values and everything is black.
Looks like that works.
Now that we've cleaned the data dropped any any values.
We are ready to actually explore this data through visualization.
Let's go ahead and call G-G plot to called the plier library and mess around with the data actually
plotted out and visualize it.
I'm going to go ahead and call library cheesy plot too.
And I'm also going to call the deployer library just in case.
I haven't actually imported it yet.
Going to clear the plots is missing the maps and get started.
Let me push this over a little bit so you get a nice balance here.
First thing we want you to do is create a histogram of ages colored by income and we're under the FDA
section of the project now the exploratory data analysis.
I'm going to pass in my adult data frame that's already been cleaned and had the missing data or Moogs
.
I'm going to put in the aesthetic of age and that's my XT histogram and then I'm going to say geometer
score histogram and I want the fill color to be by the income and also what I'm going to do is say color
is equal to black.
This is my personal preference.
I like having that borderline of black.
You don't have to do it if you don't want to.
And then I'm also going to say been with is equal to one.
And finally I'm going to add my favorite thing which is just a simple theme underscore B.W. and there
we have let's go and zoom in.
OK.
So here's a histogram of the ages colored by income.
You'll notice that basically if you're younger than 25 remember this state is from like around 1996
.
But according to this data set they were younger than 25.
There's very few people that are making more than 50 K when they're below 25 years of age.
And as you get older the amount with people percentage wise for that particular age group that are making
more than the 50 case starts to grow.
But then after a certain age people start retiring they receive less income both just the actual data
points begins to decrease but also the amount of people making 50 proportional to their age group begins
to decrease.
All right.
Hopefully that's pretty useful information as far as from an exploratory data analysis framework.
Let's go ahead and plot a histogram of the hours worked per week.
Osages you adults will go ahead and say our underscore her underscore week.
It was just H.R. underscore and then I'm going to say history.
Let me go ahead and finally add that theme.
Let's play that out.
And here we go.
All right.
Since the United States 40 hours per week is the standard.
We notice that there is such a high it counts of 40 hours per week as far as the occurrences go that
you may want to consider creating a nother right feature by feature engineering saying something like
less than 40 hours per week 40 hours per week or above 40 hours per week.
Right now we'll go ahead and leave it as is and continue on through the project assignment.
The next task you have to do is rename the country column to region column to better reflect the factor
levels.
Take a look at the head of the adult data frame right now.
Those we still have a country column but the country column These aren't really countries North America
is an a country and South America isn't a country.
They're more actually regions.
Let's go ahead and rename that country to regt. column.
There's lots of ways to do this.
I like to use the plier to do this sort of operation because as a really simple rename function and
we go out and see adults and then I'm going to say rename and rename is really easy just pass in the
data.
So you say rename the adult data frame and then you Pessin your new column name equals and then the
old column name and that's all you have to do.
And I want to go ahead and just put a print statement here to make sure it works.
So print head of adults.
Once you've done that we're going to go ahead and create a bar plot of the region with the fill color
line by income class.
Okay perfect.
If we take a look at this head we have region as the output versus previously we had country has the
output on the go ahead and clear that print statement clear the consul and get working on this marplot
.
Again I want to create a bar plot of region with full color defined by income class.
I'm going to go ahead and say G-G plot pass in my adult data frame and say the aesthetic is region and
I want this to be a bar plot.
We're actually going to be doing quite a few additional layers to this.
So I want to go ahead and sign this to P.L. and then I'm going to say geometers score bar and static
feel equal to income.
Color is equal to black
plus theme.
Underscore B.-W.
And if we just show what looks like for right now we'll get this result.
We go ahead and zoom in on it.
We get this nice output of the income levels for coloring and then the actual bar plots.
Notice most of our data is actually from North America and North America seems to have quite the highest
amount of people making over $50000 even if you look at it proportionally it's still a much higher percentage
in North America than other countries.
Maybe Asia's a little competitive there.
OK.
So that concludes our exploratory data analysis in our data cleaning.
Let's go ahead and just briefly get an overview of everything we've done in part 1 and Part 2.
And in the final part 3 of this lecture series we're going to build a logistic regression model and
split it into a training a test set for data etc..
Let's just review quickly what we've done so far the things we've done so far is we read in our data
.
We called the player library to quickly unselect that extra index column and then we spent a lot of
time cleaning our data.
Here's a saying in data science where 80 to 90 percent of your time is going to be spent cleaning data
and then 20 to 10 percent of time is going to be spent actually creating models.
And that's definitely true in real life.
So it's good to practice data cleaning in general.
Here we practice data cleaning by combining features that had a lot of factor levels.
We went ahead and did this for the job or any type of employer feature.
We grouped them by self-employed state and local government.
We also did this for the marital status not married never married married.
And we just do this by creating a function and then applying a function.
This is the easiest way to do it and it give you the most control.
Then we went ahead and did the same for the country column data by splitting it up into regions and
later on we went ahead and use the operator as a little trick with these vectors to do that.
And again we just apply it.
Then we took care of missing data by exploring it a little bit.
We use the Amulya library a great library for working with and trying to visualize or missing data.
We went ahead and put a question of Mark data to add a values.
Then we used factor to apply a new factor level in order to make sure the old factory levels that it
have that question mark inside of it.
We checked out the missing data dropped all the missing data since it wasn't that much checking out
the missing this maps.
Then we explored our data through a few visualization plots such as bar plots histograms such as hours
per week.
Then we also did this age for counts are plot and you can check or a histogram excuse me and you could
check out your own visualizations if you want to.
Then the final thing we did was just rename the country column to the region column using the plyers
rename function.
Ok that's it for part 2 and part 3.
We will end the fire exploratory data analysis and move on to building the logistic regression model
to try to classify people into two groups above or below 50 k in salary.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture