Hello everyone and welcome to logistic regression with our part two in the previous part one of this
lecture series we went ahead and explored the data use Jiyu plot to visualize it.
And we explored how we could replace the missing age values with an imputed age value based on the average
age of the passengers class.
Let's go ahead and continue on right where we left off and then jump to our studio now.
All right.
This is where we left off last time we created this imputes underscore age function which took in the
age and class vectors and then basically created an output vector which is the fixed ages.
Let's make sure this works by re-assigning the train age to the fixed ages
and then what we're going to go ahead and do is use that mismatch function again again to do that.
I'm just going to say this map pasand my data the if that train the main it's just the title here.
We'll go ahead and say imputation check.
As the title and C O L stands for the color vector first color is what you want.
Missing values to be or any values second colors what you want absurd variables to be elements.
Call it black and then we'll say legend is equal to false.
If you say legend is equal to true you get kind of a super large legend that takes too much room and
then we'll go ahead and print this out.
Let me expand this window before I actually run the script so we have enough room to see the plot.
All right let me go and I can run this control ship us.
OK we have an amputation check.
Everything is black which means we no longer have any.
And a data in our data frame looks like it work.
Let's go ahead and continue.
By building up our model so that it's time to build our model or we're going to go ahead and do is begin
by doing a final clean up of raw data by removing the features we won't be using and making sure that
the features are of the correct data type.
If we get quickly check here under structure I'm going to go ahead and remove all the plots I've been
using.
Let me clear the console.
Move this over to the rights to won't be visualizing.
For now I'm going to check the structure of DFI thought train.
And if you notice here we have some variables or features that we're not going to use the ones we're
not going to use.
Our passenger ID the name of the passenger the ticket of the passenger and the cabin of the passenger
because it just have way too many levels and factors.
You'd have to do some feature engineering to actually make use of these.
Something you could do fichu engineering.
For instance the name we actually already mentioned you can try to grab titles as a feature and something
else you could do is from cabin.
Try to grab the actual cabin level.
I noticed that a lot of these cabins start off a letter.
You could just try to grab that letter and use the cabin level as a feature.
This case we won't bother using any of those.
We'll just go ahead and remove those features.
I'm going to call to the plier library to remove these features.
All right so we've have the the plier library ready to go.
I'm going to say DMF train and I'll use the select function from the plier and for the select function
function you pasan DFA train and we have two choices here either passen all the features or column names
that you want to keep or put a negative sign and passing all the features variables or columns that
it don't want to keep this case.
I'll do it the negative way.
I'm not going to keep passenger ID.
I'm not going to keep name ID I want to get rid of ticket ID or a ticket and then want to get rid of
carbon.
So we're getting rid of passenger ID name ticket cabin and we could do that with a negative sign using
the select from the train.
Let's go ahead and check out the head of the train make sure it works.
And it worked out perfect.
This is exactly what we want what I'm going to go ahead and do is not check the structure of the train
Note that I'm kind of hopping back and forth between the script and the cons. You should be careful
if you're doing this to make sure you're using the same DFI train.
I would suggest that you actually type this all out through steps to create our script and organize
it.
I'm doing this so that it's easier to show step by step or actually doing that we have the structure
of the frame I want to make sure that survive is not an integer.
It should be a factor so class.
It's also not an integer.
And we saw from our visualizations that sibling spouse these are low enough numbers that let's go ahead
and group these as a factor instead of putting it as a continuous variable.
This is a choice you can make and you can also choose to not make it since it is a continuous value
of number of siblings or spouses from 0 to technically infinite siblings.
But I'm going to go ahead and group these because it makes sense given the small actual amounts of siblings
or spouses or parents or children.
So let's go ahead and say survives as a factor P class as a factor this sibling spouse is a factor and
this parent child is a factor.
I'm going to go ahead and copy and paste the code for the note book that allows us to do this.
In this case it's just these four lines Central just calling each of those four columns and then re-assigning
that with a factor in a run that knowledge check the structure of the train one more time.
Note that I don't have to type in Prince because I'm right in the con..
It looks like we were able to convert those all to factors perfect.
Something to note here is that embarked actually has four levels a blank string.
C q and s.
That's OK.
Basically you can just treat this blank as an unknown and that may be an important feature if they don't
even know what court they embarked on.
It may or may not be but it shouldn't affect the model too much to just leave it like that.
That's something that you may or may not want to take care of when you're actually clean in that data
.
Let's go to continue on by training the model.
I'm going to go ahead and say Lagat model and to use a logistic regression model in our you say G L
M which stands for generalized linear model you pass in the formula.
In this case I want to predict these survived column based off of everything or every feature every
column in my data frame.
I'll go ahead and write period to do that.
And then what you have to denote is family and family is basically a description of the earth distribution
of we're going to be using this case will say Binomial and we'll say link equals logic.
And this basically just says use the logistic regression function and we'll go in and say data DFT train
.
Again when you're using generalized linear models function here in order to perform a logistic regression
you just pass in your formula like we did for linear regression earlier but you also pass in this argument
.
Family equals binomial link.
Watch it.
You can go ahead explore help on Jhelum to see what other families you can use this case for using TLM
for logistic regression.
Let's go ahead and train the model.
Now it's going a summary of that log model.
OK.
Note that we have a bunch coefficients and a bunch of data here to interpret just like in the summary
results for linear regression we can use D-Star notation to see what has a low probability of not being
significant.
Basically three stars you can kind of interpret this as important features unsurprisingly second class
and third class are very important features and so is the age and sex of the passenger especially the
fact that if they were a male or not male seems to be extremely important.
Now I say extremely important but the correct statistical way of saying this is that it's very likely
to not be important.
But we'll just go ahead and use the terminology for semantics here.
I'm just saying that this is a pretty significant feature age.
What else was significant having either three or four siblings.
A little bit but definitely not as much as the age sex or class.
And those were the most important ones.
Intuitively this makes sense.
Maybe you've seen the movie Titanic where it kind of gives the impression that everyone in third class
died but really the most important thing was whether you were a male or not.
OK go ahead and check out help on summary for logistic regression if you want more information.
Everything that we've done here or check the previous notebooks for more information on how to actually
interpret this summary what I'm going to go ahead and do is start with predictions.
Let's go ahead and try to predict off of test data as an exercise for you to finish off this lecture
.
I'm going to go ahead and leave it as an exercise for you to use the Titanic underscore test that C
S V file in order to predict new survived or not survived.
Classes offer that test that cxxviii file.
That's an assignment for you because I want you to practice everything we just did here because you're
going to have to clean it the same way we cleaned the training data.
You're going to have to impute the age and the average age based off a class.
Now I want to leave that for practice for you so we won't do it in this lecture and said what we'll
do is split up our larger training set into a kind of a mini test mini train dataset and redo the models
that way.
Again go ahead.
And as an exercise after this lecture to make sure you fully understood everything we just did try to
predict off Titanic underscored tests that C S V.
For now let's go ahead and splits by making tests out of our training set.
NASA library s.a.a tools.
And this is also good because it's always great to practice using this going to set seed to 100 once
you get the same random splits I do.
And then a set split to sample that split and say DFI train pass in a column you can pass in any column
.
But like I mentioned earlier I like to pass in the column that we're trying to predict.
We're trying to predict whether they survived or not and that I'm going to go ahead and say split ratio
.
And also at the 0.7
then I'm going to say final train as the subset of the train where split is equal to true.
And then we'll say final the first sequel to subset the if the train splits equal to false.
All right.
Now let's rerun our model using only this final training set and then we'll test it using this final
test set.
Again I'm not using the Titanic underscore test CSP file that's for you to work out as an additional
exercise just to make sure you understood that basically the imputation of age based off of class.
That's what I really wanted to test out so you can test that out on the test.
Continuing on what we're going to do is say final log that model will say G L M pasan a formula which
is parodic survive off of all the columns say family loops is equal to binomial and we'll say link equals
logic for logistic regression.
And then finally we'll passenger data and our data is equal to final the train now.
And let's call a summary of the final the log model since it's already been trained.
And here again we see that third class extremely important predictors.
If they were male.
Also very important and their age is important.
Let's go ahead and practice predicting values off of this.
We have a final test if we scroll back up here.
Notice we have the final thought.
Let's try to predict using our final dot log model.
I can go ahead and say fitted the probabilities you go in and clear this so it shows up in the middle
we'll say fitted the probabilities
and we'll call the Predict function.
Remember for the Predict function you pass and your model will say final that Lague model you pasan
your new data.
In this case it's final thought test.
And since we're actually doing a classification problem or trying to predict declasse 0 or 1 as to whether
or not they survived.
But you end up typing here as type equals response.
And now we can calculate from the predicted values.
So when I say fitted that results
and what you're going to do is one quick way to do this is put in if else passen fitted up probabilities
greater than 0.5 Kamo 1 comma zero.
And this is just a very shorthand way instead of having to write a whole function to do this.
This is essentially a shortcut way of saying OK if my fitted probability is greater than 0.5 set it
equal to 1 meaning they had a greater than 50 percent probability of surviving I will set it equal to
1.
Otherwise I will set it equal to zero.
This sort of if else kind of shorthand function is just shorthand and sort of having to write a whole
function with if else statement in it.
Right.
And you can type in help if else if you need more information on that.
Now let's go ahead and get my misclassification air or say Mis classification.
We'll just call it miss class error
and that's going to be the mean or the average of the fitted the results that are not equal to the actual
results and the actual results are in final test survived.
Colum let's make sure we have that.
Go ahead and print that one minus
MS Glasser.
There you go.
And that is your accuracy.
Let's go in and break this down real quick will we actually just did we use the Predict function past
then our logistic regression model passed in our test data not case it was the final test data we split
from our training set and we put in type equals response because we're trying to predict an actual class
response 0 or 1.
Then we use this little if else shortcut.
And this is kind of a trick for you for future reference when you're doing logistic regression that
we can just say if the fitted probabilities are greater than 0.5 Stethem equal to 1 otherwise equal
to zero.
And we say that as the fitted results so that's just a vector of zeros and ones that we want in the
misclassification air.
So we want to the number or average amount of fit adult results not equal to their actual test values
which was final that test survived.
Kala we grabbed the meat of that and then one minus the misclassification ere is your accuracy.
So we got an accuracy of about 80 percent.
So we have 80 percent accuracy in what we can do here is actually create a confusion matrix A confusion
matrix is basically going to be your main standard of evaluating your model because you can get specificity
or recall or precision or accuracy.
Don't just use accuracy as a score of your model use all the different rates that we learn about in
the logistic regression overview lecture.
What I'm going to go ahead and do is show you how to create this confusion matrix.
Let me go type in confusion matrix
as a comments and use a table function to actually create this confusion matrix.
You put in a table and you pass in your actual data.
So I'll say final test survive and then you just pass in fit it probabilities that are greater than
0.5.
And here we have our confusion matrix.
OK.
I hope that was help for you.
That's basically the end of this assignment.
What I want you to do as an exercise to just as it's optional you can go ahead and not do it but it
would be nice to really test your understanding by using the Titanic underscore the underscore Tessy
a city in order to actually test your model against this totally unknown test that see c file if you
want it can even try submitting your results to Kaggle competition Web site by their submission by their
online submission.
OK thanks everyone.
Hope you find that useful and I'll see you at the next lecture