Hello everyone and welcome to the overview of data frame operations data frames are the workhorse of
our.
So in this lecture we're going to basically be going over all the common operations use of data frames
and our this is going to be a very useful lecture.
We're going to be going over material we've already covered since it's so vital to know data frames
very well in order to save yourself time in the future.
Let's go ahead and open up our studio and get started.
OK so here our studio and you can see here in this the script I have listed a basically a list of topics
we're going to be going over we're going to start off with creating data frames importing exporting
data all the way down until we can get to how to deal of missing data and selecting multiple rows multiple
columns.
So we're going to take this one line slash topic at a time.
You can always reference the notes from this lecture in case you interview anything we go over.
We're going to go ahead and make the console larger and most of what we're going to be doing isn't in
the con..
Let's go ahead and start with creating data frames.
I in and clear the console of control here.
OK.
So if we want to just create a basic data frame just an empty data frame we can do something like this
.
You can say empty and data that frame is going to be the main function you can see our studios already
completing it for us.
And that's the way you can make just a basic empty data frame.
Now let's go ahead and make a data frame from Vector we can say something like this.
C1 which is going to be our first column is going to be just a vector of integers 1 through 10 reason
that colon rotations quickly create that vector of integers and in other key trick to R is if you just
type in letters letters is basically a vector of the alphabet that's built into our.
You can quickly reference for letters A through Z.
So what I'm going to go ahead and do is say C-2 and assign letters 1 through 10.
Enough I check out C-One Anssi too.
I have two columns that are available for me.
Let's go ahead and combine those columns and make them part of a data frame.
Then I go out and make an object called DSF.
Use my keyword data frame data frame.
That's going to be the function that allows me to build these data frames.
I'll start off with call that name that one is equal to see one call not name that two is equal to C2
.
And then we can go ahead and check out this data frame if we can see here we have a rows and or two
columns.
So let's break down the state of frame function just pretty quickly.
It's data frame and then it's the parameters that you pass in or the column names.
And you can actually just create these call names you can make them up.
They don't have to be a reference to something.
And then you say equal and then what we actually want to pasan as the data for that column.
So again I'm saying call that name too.
So I want that to be the second column equals and then I pass in the data.
If you don't pass in these variable names you're kind of making up for the column names.
What are you going to do it's going to automatically name your columns for the variable names of whatever
the data you were putting into it.
All right now let's briefly go over importing and exporting data.
There's a lot more lectures on imprinting exporting data to specific formats.
Here we're just going to go have a brief overview of how to import and export from CSP files.
Let's go at in clear a con..
To read a C as we filed the command the just read that C S V.
That's going to be the most common command throughout the course as far as reading our information.
They can say I've read that C S V and then you just pasan whatever your file name is you can say some
file does CXXVI and this will go ahead and read that into a different if you want to writes to a C S
V.
You can just use write thought C S V passing your data.
So for instance I can pass in the data frame we just made if and then the second argument is file and
you pass in the file you want.
So we can say something like Saved f not sci fi.
So let's go ahead and read that CXXVI.
So say DFI to read the CXXVIII.
We'll go ahead and pass in the file name.
So if we look at this it was saved underscore that CXXVI and I can actually press tab and it should
auto complete to the filename you know we have DFI too which is the same thing as the if.
But the thing to notice here is when you're saving it as a C S V with just these two parameters your
index will also be saved as a column into that CAC file.
So you'll notice that when we read that cxxviii file it's a Ze'ev too.
We've got an extra column called X and the X column is just the index of that data frame that you saved
at CAC.
After reading this CACP you can either drop it keep it doesn't really matter what you do with it but
just keep in mind that it's also going to save that index information.
And the reason for that is because a lot of times in your data frames your index isn't just going to
be numbers are actually going to be string names such as names of states or people cetera.
So it's good to say that information when you're writing to see every file when you're reading it you
can go ahead and either delete drop or do whatever you want that information.
All right.
Now let's go ahead and move on to our third topic getting information about the data frame going to
go ahead and clear the con..
And we have our data frame Dia.
Let's who wanted to know the row and column counts.
There's a couple of ways to do this but the most direct way is the NRO function that's all lowercase
.
And then you just go ahead and pass in your data frame.
And I'll tell you back how many rows you have and you can also say and cnl for end columns passing data
frame it'll tell you how many columns you have.
Back again this doesn't include the actual index just the columns that have names.
If you actually want to get those names you can use the call names function so that C O L names and
then just call on any data frame and all or turnback a vector of the column names.
You can do the same with forenames.
However we should probably be careful of this because we have a very large data frame.
This output will be really large.
So just keep that in mind.
And in this case where that data frame just has an index it's not super useful to have the road names
.
Couple of other ways to get information but data frame is the SDR function which returns the structure
of the data frame.
So here are the math here I'll tell you how many observations you have of how many variables which are
the same as just those columns will tell you the column names.
So you kind of the data type is in those columns so integers or a factor of 10 levels etc..
That's one way of getting information off the data frame.
The other way is with summary and this will give you a statistical summary of what's going on in your
data frame.
Some of these don't make too much sense if you're looking at it from a statistical standpoint such as
a column name to the column name one.
If we check a look it's just a bunch of integers.
So here we get statistical information on the median.
The mean the max value cetera recall him to since it was a bunch of string values what you're going
to get in return instead of the sort of statistical information it's just a count of the terms how many
times they show up.
ABC the.
Cetera.
And if there's too many values here they'll eventually say other and give you another count.
Otherwise this would be a really long output.
OK.
That's it for getting information about a data frame.
Our next topic.
Topic number four is going to be referencing cells.
So now we're going to learn how to reference a particular cell off a data frame and go out and clear
this.
Check out our data from DIA.
And there it is the most basic way to reference a single cell in a data frame is by using two sets of
brackets with index numbers.
For example you could say if your first set of brackets.
And then inside a second set of brackets you'll pasan a row comma column value.
So imagine you wanted to get the value at row number five on column two or I could say something like
this 5 which is the row column too.
So if I look at that I get back e as well of some more information on the levels where the levels is
basically just unique values in this case of column name too.
So it's actually going on here.
We checked that row five value in column two which is.
Now this isn't going to be super useful because a lot of times you want to reference the actual column
name not the column number.
So the way you do that is really similar pasan a set of brackets.
Again the row you want in this case it's five.
You can also pass on that index name and in the string you can pass in the column name instead of the
column number.
So call name 2 here and we get back the same value.
You're probably going to be using this sort of reference usually instead of memorizing what positions
the columns are in and we can use this sort of syntax to actually reassign single cell values.
So for instance let's say I wanted to change this to into a number like nine thousand nine hundred ninety
nine.
I would say DMF has a second set of brackets.
That too is in rote too and it's in call that name one and I'm going to head and use a assignments to
pass in a number there.
So let's go in and say nine thousand nine hundred ninety nine that does the assignment.
So if I take a look at.
Notice now that value is nine thousand nine hundred ninety nine.
So I can call that single cell value and then pass an assignment to it.
So that's an important feature to know that you can use when you're referencing single cells.
All right.
Let's go ahead and move on to referencing rows so Rose is going to be similar except without that double
bracket notation going to go and clear this in order to return a row which you can do is something like
this.
You can say DSF racquet pass in the number or index value of the row you want comma nothing.
Now we should be pretty familiar with this sort of format from our study of Meecher season.
And there it is.
That's the row.
And it returns a data frame not a vector.
So it's something to keep in mind.
You'll still have information of those two column names.
If for some reason you actually didn't want that data frame information you just wanted a straight vector
of those values which you could do is something like an as numeric call to try to convert that row to
a vector.
But again the easiest way to get back a row is just called data frame a single set of brackets.
The row you want comma nothing and then close that bracket.
Let's talk about referencing columns which is going to be kind of similar except our placement is going
to be a little different.
Let's go ahead and play around with the empty cars state a frame that comes built into our.
So the empty car as we take a look at it again it's a bunch of cars and then a bunch of columns with
their difference.
Are there stats like MPG number cylinders horsepower etc..
Let me go ahead and change to suggest looking at the whips.
The head of cars.
All right.
So that's a little more manageable and a control.
I'll do that one more time.
So we have a cleaner screen.
OK we're looking at the head of Indy cars.
There's lots of different ways to actually get a column.
Let's go ahead and talk about four main ways.
One way is just to get a vector back so I can say cars or excuse me empty cars dollar sign and then
the name of my column says one of the most common ways to grab columns as a vector of values.
And you'll notice this is common enough since our studio will actually have a nice little dropdown menu
of all the columns available for you.
So we'll go on to say NPG and then we get back a vector of all the values.
One other way to do this is going to be similar to the way we reference the row.
It's just essentially going to be backwards so you can say nothing comma and then pass in mpg and you'll
get back a vector of those values.
You could have also passed in the number of that column.
So MPG is the first column.
So if I pass then a comma one there I would have also gone back mpg.
And finally a little less common.
But another way we could add this is passing in two sets of brackets like this with a single column
name such as mpg.
OK so those are four different ways you can get back a vector of those column values so empty cars mpg
just with the dollar sign a comma with nothing in front of it.
First comma and then either the name of the column you want or it's position in relation to the other
columns.
Or you can just use a double set of brackets of the column name.
Now something to quickly note here is this were methods of just returning the vectors if we wanted to
actually return a data frame.
So keep this car information here is the MPG with it.
We would just use two other methods so that we could say empty cars single set of brackets mpg and that's
going to return a data frame instead of just a vector of the values.
So note the difference here between these two methods using two sets of brackets is going to return
that vector of values.
If we just use a single set of brackets they'll return a data frame with just that column back.
Now we could have also instead of having to say mpg if we knew the order of the columns we could always
just replace this with an integer value for that column which in this case is one that said use the
first column.
So keep in mind you have this method available to you if you want to add data frame with that column
back.
Let's go ahead and clear the con..
And last thing I want to talk about before we move on from referencing columns is how to get multiple
columns back as a data frame.
So if we wanted to for instance get empty cars this would just return the MPG column who want multiple
columns we could pass any vector of column names such as MPG and cylinders.
Let's say that I'm going to go ahead and type and head at the beginning of all this.
So you only see the first six rows.
Whoops forgot to close off the vector.
There it is.
OK.
So again empty cars instead of just passing MPG to get a single column back as the data frame.
Can pass on a vector of column values you want and you can also pass them back in in whatever order
you want.
They don't have to be in the same order they are in that original data frame.
All right.
So you've gone over creating data frames importing exporting data from a CNC file getting information
about the data frame referencing cells rows and columns.
We'll go ahead and stop here.
And then the next lecture will have a part two to this lecture we'll all go over adding rows adding
columns setting column names or multiple rows or multiple columns and then dealing with missing data
.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture which is just going to be part two of
overview data frame operations