Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on Matrix selection and indexing.
So just like with doctors we're going to be able to use the square bracket notation to select elements
from a matrix.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio to see how this works.
OK.
So here are studio and let's go ahead and get a quick reminder of how we can use indexing for a vector
.
Imagine had a vector V of the elements 1 2 3 4 5 index and number two I would simply use square brackets
and then put the index position where the element I want back.
Or it could also put in the name if the vector was named.
Now for matrices since we're dealing of two them mentions we'll need to use a comma to separate or indexing
for each dimension.
So let's go ahead and show you what this looks like.
First off we'll start by making a matrix called Matt.
The matrix function as a numeric sequential vector 1 through 50.
We'll say by RHO is equal to false.
Actually true excuse me and I'll specify the number of rows to be equal to 5.
So it's going to take a look at that matrix real quick.
So because my font's a little larger here it's going to be split into two parts but it is all just one
matrix that's a 5 by 10 matrix so there's five rows with 10 columns here.
You'll notice here that there's a square bracket index notation for the columns and the rows and that's
the same kind of rotation we're going to be using when we select from this matrix.
So let's go ahead and get started.
The men really wanted to grab the first row.
So for Matrix indexing notation what you're going to do for the square brackets is your first going
to pass in the rows you want to if I just want the first row I'll put in one then you put a comma and
then you pass in the columns you want if you want everything you just leave it blank.
So if I want the first row that's going to return that first row for me.
Let's go ahead and see what that looks like one more time.
So I notice the first row was the numbers 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 and 10.
So if I say first one comma nothing then I'm going to return all the columns for the first row.
Great.
Let's go ahead and see how I can grab the first column.
So the first column is going to be nothing.
Comma 1.
Now what this means is grab everything all the rows from the first column so that in return will bring
back the first column.
So in general we can think of this.
If I just go and take this in our script as something that looks like this we'll have some matrix and
then we specify which rose we want.
If a comma and then we specify specify which columns we want.
So it goes Rose comma column within the square brackets.
And if you want all the rows or all the columns you're just going to go ahead and leave that blank.
So let's go ahead and see what else we can do here.
Imagine you wanted to grab the first three rows of a matrix.
Well we would just say Matrix name but the square brackets in there.
And here we can use this slicing notation.
So one colon three that's going to return 1 2 and 3 for the rows and then I'm going to leave a comma
there because I want all the values for those rows every column value for those three rows and then
we can see that it gets returned those three rows for all 10 columns.
All right great.
So let's go ahead and take a look at our matrix one more time.
So we have this matrix Matt.
It's 10 columns by five rows.
Imagine I want it to grab let's say just the top left right rectangle So that's going to be let's say
just want to grab one two three and 11 12 13.
I would actually do that.
So I'm going to say Matt square brackets.
I want to go ahead and grab that left top left rectangle.
So it's going to be looks like the first two rows.
So it's I want one two three and 11 12 13.
So gonna go ahead and put in the first two rows.
So that's one goal and two for that slice of the first two rows.
And I also want the first three columns.
One two three.
So that's going to be one comma three.
And there you have it.
We have that rectangle back that top left rectangle.
OK let's go ahead and just show two more quick examples.
Imagine I wanted to grab the last two columns.
I could do Matt since I want just columns.
That means I want all the rows for it.
So going to put a comma and I'm going to go to specify columns 9 through 10.
So those are the last two columns.
And there you have it.
We have the last two columns there.
Let's show one more example of this.
Go ahead and see what the map looks like.
Imagine you want it to grab let's say just a center square.
So I want 15 16 and 25 26.
I want this square in the matrix when I go ahead and say mats and let's see we're going to need the
rows for 15 16 25 26 will need two and three are going to go and slice rows two for three comma.
Then I'm going to do the columns in this case looks like it's five through six and you can notice.
Now hopefully this notation starts to make sense as to why our studios are reporting it as blank.
Comma 5 because this stands for all the rows in column 5.
Likewise for the rows.
It's going to be the row comma blank because it's all the columns for the first row.
So if I go ahead and run this it returns back that square from the Matrix.
OK.
So that's it as far as the general syntax for grabbing chunks from the Matrix.
But I encourage you to do is just go ahead and pick out with your eyes some gen's rectangles or rows
or columns from our general matrix here and see if you can index them correctly.
So maybe try grabbing the rectangle here 33 through 35 and 43 for 45.
See if you can grab that rectangle.
How would you do it.
Just go ahead and practice.
Choose some rectangles or squares in the matrix and see if you can index them out.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.