Hello everyone and welcome to the player training exercise lecture and this lecture we're going to give
a brief overview of the plier training exercise and how to approach it and what to expect.
Let's go ahead and jump to the note book for the player training exercise.
All right.
Here I am at the notebook or this notebook which just going to use the empty car's data frame that's
built into our and you're going to use your library to perform a series of tests on which space is going
to review all the operations.
We went over in the guide to using the plier lecture and at the end we'll also go over at the pipe operator
.
Keep in mind that these tasks be done without the player library.
But for the specific training exercise you should only be using the player library functions listed
here.
All right you should also keep in mind that this should be a relatively straightforward assignment since
the whole purpose of the player is to make your life easier by simplifying all these functions and operations
.
All right.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&A forum or just watch the next lecture where we have
a full solutions walkthrough for this training exercise.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture