Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on factor in categorical matrices this lecture we're going
to look at how to create factor in categorical matrices in our.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio to get started.
All right so here here our studio.
And in this lecture we're mainly going to be discussing the factor function and it's used for creating
categorical matrices.
This specific function will become really useful when we begin to apply data analysis and machine learning
techniques to our data.
This is also sometimes and then is creating dummy variables.
So you may be familiar with it in that context.
So let's go to start by show an example of why and how we can build a sort of matrix.
I want to go ahead and create a vector called Animal Nalut just go ahead and pretend that where have
some sort of animal sanctuary.
And there's dogs and cats in it.
So we'll go ahead and just label this the C for cat D for dog.
Let's go ahead and put another dog in there and then we'll start with two more cats.
All right.
So we have our animal vector where C is for cat D is for dog.
And so we're trying to represent some sort of animal sanctuary and let's say each of these specific
animals also has a corresponding ID number.
So we'll go ahead and make an ID number vector.
Know let's just go ahead and say One two three four five.
All right so we have our animals in Adie's and we want to convert the animal vector into information
that an algorithm or equation can understand more easily meaning we want to begin to check how many
categories or factor levels are actually in our character vector.
So we can do is we can pass the vector through the factor function like this.
So we're going to go in and say factor.
And so then notice I'm going to go ahead and pass an animal.
And so what you get back is this vector that also notice that it has these levels attached to it C and
D.
So I'm going to go ahead and assign this factor of animal and I'll assign it to let's just go ahead
and say fact Annie as some variable name for this.
So we're going to save that factor.
All right.
So we can see that we have two levels D-N.C. for dog and cat.
So in our There's going to be two distinct types of categorical variables.
There's going to be ordinal categorical variables in nominal categorical variables.
So the nominal categorical variables let me go in and type this out.
You can also reference the notes for this.
So right now we're talking about nominal must go ahead and make that a little brighter by not putting
it as a comment.
So the nominal categorical variables don't have any order.
So you can imagine that dogs and cats.
There's no order to them.
Well some people may prefer dogs for cats but in reality there's no order to them versus ordinal categorical
variables as the name implies.
Do have some sort of order so we can think of nominal there's no order versus let's go ahead and say
ordinal there is an order.
So nominal an example that is what we have here.
This animal so there's no order versus dogs and cats but something that could be ordinal of order could
be something like temperatures so we could have something like or Dohm cat with let's say cold
medium and hot.
So this is a ordinal categorical variable because even though we're dealing with strings here and different
categories.
So cold is a category medium is a category of temperature hot as category temperature.
You can see that there's an order to them.
It should be cold medium hot versus dogs and cats.
So Dog is a category C is a category for cat.
There's no order of dogs before cats are cast before dogs.
OK.
So if you actually want to assign an order to these variables you would be able to do that while using
the factor function.
And you can actually pass in an argument with ordered equals true and pass in the levels argument as
well.
So we're going to show you how we can do that.
So let's say we have a vector temp's and it's going to be called Medium a high bigger than just copy
and paste this.
And we're also going to put in a couple of more instances so I'll say there's another instance of hot
.
Another instance of Ha we'll say there's another axis of cold.
And finally one more instance of median.
Right.
So we have our attempts vector here.
So it's caught cold medium hot ha hot cold medium.
Right.
So we have these three categories.
Let's go ahead and pass this into a variable using factor and let me just bring this back up by clearing
that I'm going to go ahead and say temp's is that vector of cold medium hot et cetera.
Various instances and I'll say the factored version of this called The Factor function pass in my temps
vector.
I'm going to say ordered is equal to true.
Remember I didn't do this for the dogs and cats vector because there was no order that made sense for
dogs and cats in this case.
There is an order that makes sense.
It should be cold medium that hot.
You could also do hot medium cold depending on which way you want it to think about it.
This case will say cold comes first then medium than hot so I'll go ahead and add in the level's argument
and the levels argument is going to take in a vector and you just pasan a vector of the order you want
needs to be ordered it's going to say cold medium and then hot
right.
So we've assigned that factored version of that.
Dr. chanels go ahead and see an idea of what this looks like by calling fact that temp.
So notice the levels actually have an order to them and you can see it by the comparison operator in
between the terms so cold is less than medium and medium is less than hot.
OK so that's pretty useful and it's going to be really useful when we end up using the summary function
to call a summary on that object.
So I'll go ahead and tell us cold medium and hot and the various counts of how many times those appear
and we can show you a summary of the original temps as well to show the difference between the factored
version of that vector versus the summary of the original.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture.
Don't stress out too much about understanding everything you've gone over here during this lecture.
We're not going to touch back on this until quite a while from now.
I just wanted you to be aware of it since it fits in well with the ideas of vectors and matrices.
So the only thing you should be aware of are the use of the factor function as a possibility for you
to use.
And then the difference between a nominal category set versus an ordinal category set.
OK so the nominal you have those cats and dogs are the order ordinal as the name implies there is an
order to it.
And you can specify that order using the factor function by saying order equals true and then specifying
the levels as a vector and you just pasand the vector of the terms in indexed order that you want.
OK that's it for this lecture.
Thanks everyone.
I'll see at the next lecture.