Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on coordinates and fasting learning how to deal coordinates will
allow us to resize or plots correctly and fasting will allow us to place several plots next to each
other.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio to see how this all works.
OK so here we are our studio.
And before we begin adding the coordinates layer and the fastening layers to our grammar graphics model
let's go and just start off by building a very simple plot.
So we're going to say library Gigia plot 2.
And then we'll say gee plot function pass in the MPG dataset which comes with Jiyu plot.
And then for the aesthetics we'll go ahead and say X is displacement in y as highway then we'll go ahead
and add G underscore point to create a very basic scatterplot will assign that's the variable P.L. or
we'll go ahead and print P.L. and run that source and see what we get.
So we get this scatterplot if we go ahead and just zoom on it we can check out that we have a highway
which essentially mpg.
And then the displacement of whatever the engine is.
So let's go ahead now and play around with coordinates in order to set x and y limits.
One nice way to do this is by we go out and say people we can add the argument Kord underscore Cartesian
and then inside of that function we can pass x slim and whilom these both accept vectors as arguments
where the first number in the vector is your lower limit and your higher and your next number is your
higher limit.
So for example we want the X limit to go from let's say 1 to 4.
We can pass in X Lim and then with the combined function pasan a vector 1 come 4 and we can do the same
thing for whilom.
Let's go ahead and limit this one to with a vector let's say 15 to 30 15 Khama 30 will assign that P.L.
to and then we'll just go ahead imprints heal too.
So it's from the source.
Now make sure this all worked.
And now we can see the difference between the first two plots.
So our first plot looks like this but with the ability to use chord Cartesian we were able to set the
x and y element.
So if you take a look at the actual plot that we just output it it looks like this.
Then you can resize this window you want to resize the plot.
But here we can see that we go from one to four just as we indicated in the chord underscore Cartesian
function and then it goes from 15 to 30.
Again as we said with why limit.
All right let's go to continue.
Notice as I was zoomed in on that plot I could automatically resize this to set aspect ratios.
We can actually see the aspect ratio is from the very beginning before we even play around with this
plot zoom.
We can do that by adding an argument Kord underscore fixed.
Let's go in and show how we can do that.
So the undelete the CT underscore Cartesian argument and instead add corde underscore fixed and we can
use this argument to change the aspect ratio of the plot by default.
It's one one sort appears in the square but in this court underscore fixed function we can pasan a ratio
parameter and the ratio première is expressed as y to x.
So for example we can have a ratio of 1 to 3.
Run the source and you can see a ratio of white X is 1 to 3 meaning if we zoom in here let's go in and
zoom a little further.
Notice how the aspect ratio no longer actually changes.
When I zoom in and out it stays the same.
So it takes 3 x units to create the length of the bin of one white units.
As far as the grid lines go and we can do that by again saying CT underscore fixed and setting the ratio
by default it's 1 1.
All right.
That's the basics for dealing with coordinates.
The most important one was that Kord underscore Cartesian to fixture x and y limits.
Let's go ahead and discuss facets.
So the best way to set up a Fassett grid which is essentially just multiple plots is to use the Fassett
underscore grid function there's a lot to Fassett grid.
So I would definitely recommend calling Help facets underscore grid and checking out the documentation
page.
This documentation page is great and instruction on how to lay out panels in a grid using the Fassett
underscore grid argument.
It has tons of examples to follow and input into year either our script or con..
So definitely check that out.
The syntax for using Fassett grid may appear strange at first so will show several examples to hopefully
try to clarify what the syntax is actually trying to say.
First let's go ahead and see what our normal plot looks like.
So going to go out and say Prince P.L.
run that source chicken plot.
So we have our normal plot here.
Let's go ahead and try to separate this into four facets based off of number of cylinders.
Each of these cars have has.
So I can do that by saying plus Fassett underscore grid.
And then the Fassett I want to do is cylinder.
I'm going to go ahead and continue by saying dots till the see why else cylinders.
So if we take a quick look at the head of NPG notice we have a cylinder column similar to our empty
cars column where just four six one of these cars has five cylinders and one of them a few of them have
eight cylinders.
So we're going to try to create four separate plots for each number of cylinder types.
So what this actually shows is the following.
We say Fassett grid.
And then we use a dot till the symbol and then the actual column we want to separate by for Fassett
grids.
Let me go in and show you this.
So hopefully try to explain this maybe strange syntax.
All right so if you notice what we get back out is the cylinders separated along the x x.
So the syntax for a Fassett grid will be what you want to Fassett by on the y axis till the symbol.
And then what you want to Fassett by on the x axis.
So let's go ahead and show another example of this by saying for instance we have to drive the drive
type column.
So we're going to Fassett our scatterplot by Dr cild symbol.
And then what the dot represents is just everything else.
So essentially you're not trying to Fassett by two variables you're just fascinated by one says the
most common approach.
Either X or Y on the pending side of till the stand on and then a period or dot on the other side.
Let's go ahead and run so you can see what this looks like.
Checkout zoom here.
Now you notice I'm on the y axis as far as the drive type.
So I have four wheel drive front wheel drive and a rear wheel drive.
And that's because the column name came first before that Tilda sign.
And then I have my period.
So what happens if I don't have a period here.
I go ahead and put in another column.
So let's say Fassett by Dr type and number of cylinders.
Well then I'll get basically two dimensional facets so we get basically blocks that look like this.
Where along my x axis I've separated things but a type of cylinder and a long y y axis I've separated
the scatter plots by type of drive for four wheel drive front wheel drive real rear wheel drive etc.
.
And that's the way you can use Fassett grid.
The syntax is a little strange to get used to but essentially you can remember it as just call Fassett
grid.
The column you want to Fassett by this till the symbol and then a dot.
So that's the most basic way to fasten it in or give something that looks like this.
If you wanted it to be faceted along the another dimension then just reverse this.
So you'll say then that's still the and then the name you want to Fassett Biles go to say drive type
again and then you'll notice it's Fassett along the other dimension.
So as long as you remember this basic pattern of a dots that till the symbol and then the column you
want you should be good to go because you can just reverse these to the period and the column name in
case you accidently switch the actual dimensions or axes.
You watch your fastening to occur in if you want to Fassett by two columns then you just add in the
other column and you can switch these columns around.
In case you want to switch which axis belongs to which column and that's the basics of using Fassett
grid this sort of expression syntax wise may look a little strange will appear to look a lot more common
when you do things like machine learning in are way you'll end up using this sort of tilde symbol with
a daughter period.
A lot more.
But as far as using Fassett grin hopefully now you understand the basics of just passing a column name
till the symbol and then either a period or dot.
If you're only doing one dimensional fastening.
OK hopefully that was useful to you.
You can go check the documentation for more information by just checking help and then looking up Fassett
grid here.
All right that's it for this lecture.
Hope you found that useful.
I'll see you at the next one.