Hello everyone and welcome to lecture on comparison operators in this lecture we're going to learn how
to use comparison operators to compare variables that return logical values.
Let's go ahead and see some examples by jumping to our studio.
All right let's start off by just going through each of the comparison operators.
You're pretty self-explanatory.
So we'll just use simple integers to explain them for us.
Let's say you wanted to get a comparison of five is greater than six.
This should return a logical value.
In this case false to 1 do less then it's just going to be the reverse less sense so 5 less than six
.
True.
Now you can also do greater than or equal to or less than or equal to.
By using something that looks like this or something that looks like this looks for greater than or
equal to.
So you just tack on an equal sign to the less than or greater than sign.
Now you can also do comparisons for equality or inequality.
You can do that with equality for two equal sides so if you want to check let's say if two was equals
equals to three that's going to be a CheckFree quality in this case it's false.
If you just use one equal sign you should get some sort of error because you're basically trying to
do some sort of assignment here.
Is getting it to.
Just remember it's two equal signs for equality.
Do you want to test for any.
You use an exclamation points or exclamation mark with an equal sign so as to not equal to four.
That's true is to not equal to two.
That's false.
And again for equality just two equal signs.
All right.
Something they should pay close attention to is your spacing out when comparing numbers.
Because if you remember correctly the assignments operator for R is this arrow symbol.
So let's say I want to assign 2 to V.
That's how it works.
But let's say I actually have the equal to 2 and I want to compare V.
I want to ask if the is less than negative 1.
Notice here how the spacing is going to play a major role here.
Here I am saying is be less than negative 1 and the answer is false.
If I'm not paying close attention to my spacing and do something like this you're actually going to
do a reassignments of the so that you'll save the.
A sign one value.
So notice the difference here.
This is kind of important otherwise you may mess up your code later on if you have some variable name
.
Just go ahead and put in.
Let's say my VCR and you're trying to do a comparison to a negative number.
Make sure your spacing makes sense for that.
So you always want to make it very clear that you're comparing to a negative number.
Or if you're trying to do some sort of reassignments
so please pay close attention here to the differences of the reassignments versus the comparisons.
OK so that's just a little hiccup.
You may find in the future.
These should probably be paying attention to if you're ever doing some sort of less than comparison
with negative numbers living on.
I want to show you now how you can use comparison operators with vectors.
So when you use a vector with a comparison operator instead of returning just a single logical true
or false value.
It's actually to return an entire vector of logical values.
Let's go ahead and show this.
By creating a vector We'll start by just using the combined function to create a vector of 1 2 3 4 5
.
Now let's say I wanted to compare the less than 2.
What's this going to do.
It's going to do.
Elements by elements comparison.
So it's going to compare all those elements and then return a vector of logical values with the index
referring to the comparison.
So was one less than two.
That's true.
Was 2 less than 2.
That's false false false etc..
So let's say I wanted to check for equality.
I can do this and it's actually going to return a vector of logical values.
Later on we're going to see how we can Easy's vector comparisons to actually select parts of the vector
.
Which is why we're explaining them now.
OK so that's really all there is.
As far as comparison operators should be pretty straightforward and self-explanatory.
You just have the greater than sign.
You have the less than sign you have greater than or equal to less than or equal to now.
Checks for equality of two equal signs checks for inequality of an exclamation sign with an equal sign
.
And then you can also use the same comparison operators on entire vectors against a single number.
All right last thing I want to mention is that you can actually do element by element comparisons for
multiple vectors.
So let's say I want to compare vector against another vector.
So I have my first vector.
The let's go ahead and assign the two use combined function.
Now let's go ahead and make 10 20 30 40 50 so I can actually compare the one on an element by element
basis to the two.
So I say go ahead and say it is whereas V less than the two.
So you get all five trues which makes sense.
The in every single index location when you compare it on an element bilat basis to be 2 is always less
than the two.
So one is less than 10.
Two is less than 20.
Cetera.
So just like when you compare it to a single value.
A vector by vector comparison operation.
Basically also works the same way in returning a vector full of logical boolean values.
Ok that's it for this lecture.
Again just a quick reminder make sure you pay attention if you're ever doing a comparison that's something
similar to less than a negative number so you're not actually doing a reassignments.
All right thanks everyone.
I'll see you at the next lecture