Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on four loops for loops will allow us to iterate over an object
to perform and execute blocks of codes for every loop we go through.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio and see how they work.
All right.
So here we are our studio.
And in order to show what a for loop syntax looks like in case you're already familiar of programming
I'm going to go ahead and create a vector real quick.
Keep in mind this is just for people that are already familiar for the for loop is adjusting the syntax
will break down how to construct a for loop.
No more basic manner right after this.
So the syntax is for.
And then if you just go ahead and click tab and enter you should see our studio complete it for you
.
So you can say for variable in vector and then you'll go ahead and have your curly brackets and execute
some block of code.
So for example if we just call this vector the sun sets one already looking for we say for variable
in v we'll go ahead and just say grants that variable you shouldn't usually call variables just the
straight term variable but this is for demonstration purposes and there when you run the source you
see 1 2 and 3 that's all there is for the syntax of a for loop in our.
Now for those of you who are new to programming Let's go ahead and break this down and see how to create
this.
All right.
So what is a for loop.
A for loop again allows us to iterate over an object.
In this case which is a vector and then we can perform an execute blocks of code for every loop we go
through.
So let's go ahead and show a simple example with a vector.
Here we have a vector one two three.
Let's go ahead and add a few more elements to it for five and I'm going to say four.
And in parentheses The syntax is going to be some temporary variable name or some variable name you
create.
So I'm going to go ahead and say TNP Diyar.
So for TNP that V.R. and then you have a keyword in and then whatever the object you're iterating over
.
For example the which is a vector that we just created.
You're going to have some curly brackets and then inside these curly brackets you're going to execute
some code.
But what's different about a for loop vs a while loop is that you're going to execute this code for
every temporary variable annuity.
So for every temp the are in the end what you mean by temp.
The are some temporary variable name that's just going to be the variable name and you can make this
up.
Doesn't have to be temped up V.R. and it's going to be every variable inside of this iterable object
which in this case is that vector b.
So we could do a say print like we should earlier the temporary variable.
So if I go ahead and run this source I get one two three four five.
So for example if I also just say a print statement so prints hello.
Even though this doesn't have anything to do with the temporary variable.
This lock of code inside this curly brackets is going to execute every single variable inside of this
object.
The.
Which is a vector.
So we should see prints hello five times.
Now if I go ahead and run the source I see 5 Hello's here and that's really all there is.
As far as for loops go that's the basic idea of a for loop.
You say for an imprint sees some variable name that you choose.
The keyword in in the object you're iterating through an in curly brackets.
You go ahead and execute some code for every single variable in that object.
So usually throughout this block of code you're probably going to be using the temporary variable in
some way or in some manner.
Let's go ahead and show another example of how we could do this.
We could say something like this will have a result.
Objects Nells say that's equal to the R plus one.
Now we're going to have to print statements or prints the VR.
What's the temp.
The are plus 1 is equal to colon and then right below.
I'm just going to go in and prints that result.
So let's go in and see what we have here.
So I'm running the source and I get the temp var plus one is equal to 2 then to 3 to 4 to 5 to 6.
So it's actually going on for a loop.
I'm saying for each of these variable are these temporary V.R. variables in this vector v.
I'm assigning results to tempt V.R. plus one.
I print the line and then I print that result and this executes for every single element in that vector
.
It can use for loops for not just vectors which can be used for loops for a list or a Matrix or other
objects.
Well let's go to an example of a list with a for loop.
Now can I just show that easily by just saying list here.
So here's a list of let's say we'll put in a vector one to three in our list.
We'll put in a data frame.
Let's go out and say empty cars on our list.
Al put in just the number 12 on our list.
We'll call this my list now.
Now I can just say let's say for item in my list and in curly brackets I'm just going to go ahead and
print the item.
So if I run the source here scroll all the way up.
You'll notice we get one to three which was that first vector that gets printed.
Then we print an entire data frame over here and then all the way at the end we print the single integer
12.
The key thing to note here is that this variable name that you choose as you iterate through this object
is totally up to you.
So you're really going to want to take advantage of this and name it's something that makes sense to
you.
Now let's go ahead and show an example of using a for loop with the Matrix.
I'm going to go ahead and delete this.
Say M-80 or matrix call my matrix function pass in one call and 25 a label number of rows equal to 5
in that matrix.
Let's go ahead and just see with that matrix looks like real quick.
So going to good in WIPs need to save Prince Max.
And here is what my matrix looks like.
Just one two three four five and it's filled out by columns.
They go in and clear out the consul and see what we can do with this.
So instead of just print to them I'm going to iterate through it.
So we're going to say four.
Let's just go ahead and say for numb in mats and all I'm going to do is print that numb to it it looks
like I should just get a single stream of all those numbers in that matrix printed out.
So again my matrix looks like this.
And what I'm going to do is go ahead and run this source and notice I just get a single stream of that
printed out for all those elements in that matrix.
So it's important to note here is that for the matrix what it's going to do when you iterate through
this matrix it's going to go by columns is going to the first column then the second column then the
third caudal column etc. that's where we get 1 2 3 4 5 6 instead of 1 6 11 16 21.
So it's going to iterate through the columns first.
OK.
Now let's briefly discuss nested for loops so you can actually nest for loops inside of one another
and I'll show you an example of that.
Let me go to delete this.
Prince NUMP statement and a set of that statement.
I'm going to create another for loop in and you'll notice that our studio kind of says 4 and then highlights
for you.
You go ahead and just click that will automatically fill in the default values for a for loop some variable
in a vector.
This case I'm also going to say just fill in there for a little bit and I'm going to say C L loops.
OK so we're going to do here is iterate with a nested for loop and I'll show you an example of how we
can do this.
Now let's say for row in and I'm actually going to make a vector one column and row math.
So what does this actually stand for this and colon and romance.
Well if I put it into the con. You go in and clear the console and just put this in one colon and romance
.
That's just a vector of one.
All the way to the number of rows of that matrix.
So and Rahmat is just five scissors five rows in that matrix.
If I do one call and five I get this sequence of integers so that's all this line is doing just give
me the number of rows.
So I'm saying for row 1 and row that then I'm going to say for a call.
And similarly one colon and see a well of Matt.
Now I need to add that second set of parentheses the right balance everything.
What I'm going to go ahead and do is put a print statement here and I'll add in a paste.
And in this case I'm going to put in a string that says the elements row
and then I'm going to go ahead and put in row since that's what the temporary variable here is.
And then I'll say and call Khama see well put is comma.
And then finally I'm going to call that object off match.
So say RHO comma see.
Well let's go ahead and run this mixture.
We put everything in correctly and then break it down.
So for I the source knows what happens here.
I say the elements at row 1 column one is one the elements at row 1 column 2 is six in a row 1 column
3 is 11 etc. etc..
And if we take a look at our map again one more time.
Sure matrix.
Let's go ahead and check out.
Let's say this one the El-Amir row 5 and column for is 20.
So the element at row 5 and column 4.
That's correct.
It is 20.
So it does for a loop actually doing well if we look at Rho.
It says For row in 1 through 5.
So it's basically just the numbers 1 through five.
And then we have a nested for loop inside of it as well.
Let's say for a call in number of columns which in this case it's the square matrix was also five and
say so were actually saying here is four row in the number of rows in the Matrix.
And then for column from one to the number of columns that matrix.
Go ahead and imprints this Pace's statement where we said the element that row number and the column
at that column number is equal to.
And then we're just using these temporary variables row column a column in order to actually call that
particular value here.
So in this case we can actually add some more print statements if we wanted to to get a clear right
understanding of what's going on.
So we can say something like this current paste the selected row is and then we could just put in row
like that.
So if we go ahead and run this well say the selected rows 5.
And notice how it keeps saying 5 for every column in that matrix.
And likewise I'll say for row four for recall them in the matrix row three for column matrix etc..
So each of those numbers will show up essentially five times as far as this particular print statement
the selected row is all right.
So go ahead and review the notes and review this code in case it's still unclear for you.
But this pretty basic example of a nested for loop should look like.
That's it for for loops.
Again just a quick review of what a for loop is a for loop allows you to iterate over an object such
as a vector into the most basic case and then you can perform and execute blocks of codes for every
loop that you go through.
All right thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture