Hello everyone and welcome to the functions lecture in this lecture we're going to explain what a function
is an art and how to create one functions will be our main building blocks when we construct larger
and larger amounts of code to solve problems.
Let's go ahead and jump to our studio.
OK so here we are studio.
Before we explain in more detail how to construct functions and what a function is and are in case you're
already familiar with functions from a different programming language and just want to quickly get the
syntax I'm going to go over the syntax quickly now.
So function the syntax of a function are looks like this.
You have the name of your function in assignment operator and then the keyword function corrent sees
the inputs.
You want to take.
Separated by a comma.
If you want an input to have a default for instance the input stream has a default use an equal sign
and then some so have a default value then you have curly brackets.
Whatever code you want to execute and then finally if you want to return something from that function
you'll use the return keyword or the return function statement and then just return whatever result
you want back from whatever code you had here.
For instance something like this would be a really simple summation function.
Ok that's a very basic syntax of a function.
Or you can go ahead and check up the notes.
This is only for people that are already familiar functions from a different programming language.
Now I want to get a quick write down what the actual syntax looks like and are going to go ahead and
clear all of this now and discuss functions as if you've never programmed before and never seen them
before.
For people who are new to programming and are going unclear this and discuss functions in a little more
detail.
OK so what is a function.
Formally a function is just a useful device.
The groups together are a set of statements so that they can be run more than once.
They can also let us specify parameters that can serve as inputs to the functions.
We've actually seen a lot of built in functions.
For example the SUM function.
We've actually already experienced it.
So I could sum all the elements in a vector like so and then I could also call help on my function such
as help some and I get this nice helpful pop out here.
For instance some vector elements or description usage etc..
So in a really fundamental level functions basically allow us to not have to repeatedly write the same
code again and again.
We can store blocks of code as a function and then we can just call a singular function instead of having
to rewrite that code over and over again if we want to use the same sort of functionality of that code
.
Let's go ahead and show a couple of examples and build up in complexity of just examples of functions
and are going to go ahead and push it to the right.
So we're just dealing with the.
Script or here.
First thing I'm going to do may push this a little more to the right so it's a little cleaner.
OK first thing to do is create a very simple function that takes no inputs.
For example this sum function took an input of a vector.
In our case we're going to create a very simple function that doesn't take any inputs.
The syntax goes like this.
We create some sort of function name.
In this case we'll call her function.
Hello.
The assignment operator and then the keyword function and then Apprentice's we're going to have input
.
In this case we're starting off simple so it has no inputs.
Then curly brackets and the block of code that we want to execute when we actually call hello.
In this case I'm just going to have it be a simple function that says Hello.
All right that's our Hello function so we can go ahead and call hello.
Like so hello close parentheses in front of it since it doesn't take any other inputs.
So you go ahead and run the source here.
Well notice we get low as an output again.
Hello is a function that takes no inputs which is why there's nothing in the parentheses and then just
prints hello.
If I were to call hello with no parentheses there I wouldn't get anything out.
It's basically just saying oh is a function but you didn't actually call the function.
You'll need parentheses to call the function.
Most functions take in some sort of input so will be more obvious to use the parentheses.
Let's now create a function.
Building off our Hello function that actually takes in it.
So when you want your function to take taken inputs for example the sum function took an input of a
vector.
You'll say here inside your function some sort of temporary variable name for the input you want.
In this case we'll just say name it so I'm going to say print and I'll use paste
and I'll say hello.
Comma name parentheses so now you'll notice we can pass on a name and say hello.
So we'll go ahead and say Sammy.
So if we go ahead and run this code notice the output is.
Hello Sammy.
So what's actually going on line by line is we have hello as our name for a function the function keyword
we pass in name as an argument or parameter into the function.
And you're free to call these whatever you want.
Just be careful not to overwrite some default function.
So for example probably wouldn't be a good idea to call some here since some is already a function.
Likewise you wouldn't want to say summary etc..
You want to just have some unique thing name.
In this case is simple enough that we'll just go ahead and use it.
So we pass in our first arguments or parameter into the function and then we can play around with it
or use it inside the function itself.
So this is going to be code that executes when the function is called.
And below here we call the function using parentheses.
If we accidentally didn't pass anything into the function and just left the empty we'll get an error
in else say error and paste Osei argument name is missing with no default and that no default is basically
saying hey this name was missing and you didn't have a default here for it.
What a default means is a default value for these variables inside of your function in case you're not
actually passed.
Now we can assign them using an equal sign.
So I'll go ahead and say a default name is Frank.
So now if I run hello with no arguments I'll say hello Frank.
However I can overwrite the default by passing in Cmin And now when I run it I'll say hello Samie.
So this equal sign notation along your parameters or whatever inputs you want is a nice way to set defaults
.
In case you don't expect the user to have to put in the argument every single time.
And a lot of the built in functions we use have some sort of default parameter for other arguments or
parameters inside of that function.
Let's go ahead and show a totally different example of building a function want to create a very simple
function called add underscore or make my keyword function and my functional taken two arguments number
one.
Number two with no defaults here.
Notice separate arguments are separated by a comma.
When I'm calling them into the function and what I want to go ahead and do is print out number one plus
number two.
Now let's go ahead and call and underscore and pasand two numbers let's say four or five.
And if I run this from the source notice I get output printed for plus 5 which is 9.
Let's go ahead and clear the console so we can keep working on some more examples.
Something to notice is that in all or previous examples that we've shown so far we've been printing
the actual result to the function where we actually usually want to do is return the result so we can
store as a variable and you can do that by using the return keyword and this return keyword is essentially
a built in function that will return the result of whatever you're doing inside of your function.
So for example have something like this will say my some and I'll say that's number one class number
two.
And then we're going to return my that sum.
And with this return statement or we're going to be able to do is assign the output of the function
what it returns to a variable.
Let's go ahead and run the source and then break it down.
Notice when I run that source I don't actually see Nine come out because I'm never printing nine.
I'm just returning it and then storing it as this variable result.
So I'm saying Adnams is this function that takes an number one.
Number two I go ahead and add them together so I get my that sum back and then I'm going to return my
that sum and this return function statement allows me to then store that whatever was in that return
function to a variable result then I can later on if I wanted to print that result so I could print
the result that sales going to print it twice.
So if I run courtesy 9:9.
So the result of this add underscore function was returned and then saved as this variable result and
then I can play around it do whatever I want it etc..
So keep that in mind if you're working the functions and creating and building your own functions you're
probably usually going to want to use return instead of just printing out the value.
Otherwise you'll be storing a print statement when you do something like this instead of the actual
summation or whatever value or whatever output you want your function to really use.
All right.
So we've learned the syntax to use for functions when we want to pass arguments to them or set default
arguments and then get some sort of result in return.
Now let's discuss scope scope is the term we're going to use to describe how objects and variables get
defined within our When discussing scope with functions as a general rule.
We can say that if a variable is defined only inside a function then its scope is limited to that function
.
Let's go ahead and show this through some examples.
Are good and clear the con. and clear my scripts imagine we create a function called times 5.
We'll put in our keyword function and let's say it takes in some value and then it's going to go ahead
and return now.
Times five.
And then we'll just go and say print times 5.
This is a very basic function.
That's what it looks like.
Times five.
So what I'm going to go do is now pass in 20.
So now we should get the results 20 times five.
When I run this which is 100 note the first time I was just asking print out the function so I was calling
it without any prints is there.
So it prints it out.
Oh this is what your function looks like.
Second time actually asked that print out the result of times 5.
Just input 20 which is then 20 times five 100.
All right.
Now imagine I wrote that function like this.
I said for instance my thought result and I assigned the numb
times 5 and I'm going to go ahead and return my result for the function and then going to continue by
assigning the result of times 5 to some variable.
We'll go ahead and call it my the output and assign it times 5.
We'll go ahead and put in 100.
And then finally we'll go ahead and say print my output let's clear the console and run the source.
OK so we get out 500.
Everything everything's good.
So even here in the console if we say my the output call it we get five hundred.
Everything's looking great.
Now what if I call my dart result notice we get object my result not found.
You may find that strange because you can see it here and your script might not result in looks to you
like you've defined it.
This is where scope comes into play scope indicates that these variables are only defined inside the
scope of this function here.
So variables defined inside of a function are only defined or perhaps redefined inside of that function
.
However variables are assigned outside of the function are known as global variables and the function
will have access to them due to their scope.
Let's go ahead and show an example of a global variable and a function being able to access it in order
to show this properly.
I'm going to go ahead and just clear my environment workspace by clicking on this broom.
And now my environment is empty.
I would suggest you go ahead and do the same.
Now let's clear the console and let's work on a simple function to show scope and then we create some
variable v and it's going to be a string called I Am a global variable and then we're going to go ahead
and say another variable stuff and we'll go ahead and say I'm global stuff.
So these are going to be two global variables because in their scope they're not defined within any
function.
They're on a global scope.
Then I'm going to create a function called Fun my function we'll taken we'll say stuff it's going to
go ahead and print the
will take stuff and we're actually going to say re-assign stuff inside of this function fun and then
I'm going to go ahead and add whip's one more line where I go ahead and just print stuff.
Finally I'm going to go ahead and call sun on stuff.
Take a moment to think what this should output when you run the source.
Or let's go ahead and run this and we get I'm a global variable and then we also get reassigned stuff
inside of this function fun.
So it actually happened here.
We called at the very bottom Passons stuff which starts off as I'm global stuff.
And then inside that function call we have a print statement.
The notice we never pass the V into the function fun which means the function will now look into the
global namespace over here which is v is a global variable.
And if you want an idea of your global namespace you come over here to your global environment.
Notice Hertz's global environment.
It will show you the variables you have such as stuff in V.
It'll tell you what they actually are and then also report functions fun.
So now that we know what values we have globally the function can actually look for stuff that's in
this global environment.
So if we didn't assign V inside of this function we'll look for it in the global namespace and we have
it right here.
Then we reassign stuff inside of the function fun and then we print stuff.
So we get a global variable and we reassign stuff instead of this function fun.
Now here comes the tricky part.
What if right after I call fun stuff I say print stuff.
Take a moment and try to think what you expect to show here after we say fun stuff we know.
I'm a global variable re-assign stuff inside of this function.
Fun but what's going to happen on line 11 where we say print stuff.
Will it be this line or line number two.
Let's go ahead and run it and find out.
OK.
We get I'm a global variable re-assign stuff inside is function fun but notice when you say print stuff
outside of this function you still get I'm global stuff and that's because stuff has been defined as
a global variable in the global environment which means the reassignments of that stuff.
Term only affects the scope of the stuff variable inside of the function meaning lines 4 through 8.
It won't affect anything outside of the function.
So that fun function does is it first checks to see if for instance this V is defined at the function
scope.
So it it's not.
Which is this case.
We then search the global scope over here for a variable v and then that leads us to saying Oh I'm a
global variable and we go ahead and print that out on the next line.
We do the re-assignment And then when we say print stuff it looks for the stuff term in the scope of
the function and it finds its rate here.
If it didn't find that here it would then look for it in I'm global stuff.
Now in line 11 we say print stuff we're first going to search the global very environment for stuff
it will never actually find the scope of things inside of function.
Since again this reassignment is limited to the scope of only being inside the function.
All right.
So that's it for this lecture on functions.
Go ahead and check out the notes.
If you want more examples of this topic of scope the scope is a really important topic to understand
.
Otherwise you'll be expecting things to be affected inside of your function when you're actually only
limited to the scope of that function.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture