Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on our matrix exercise solutions.
Walk through in this lecture video.
I'm going to be going over the solutions for the Art Matrix exercises and explaining as we go along
.
Let's jump to our studio and get started.
OK.
So here we are our studio.
I want to hit him just showing the scripting and the cons. windows.
The first question or exercise we had to perform was to create two vectors and B were A's 1 2 3 and
B is 4 5 6.
Those vectors we had to use the C binder are Byne functions create a two by three Matrix from the vectors
and we'll need to figure out which of these binding functions is the correct choice.
Let's go ahead and get started.
Well go ahead and assign a and we use the combined function that's the lowercase c and we'll do a similar
process for creating B 4 5 6.
And then what we had to do is figure out whether to use C bind or bind.
So what's the actual difference here number that see Byne will bind columns together.
So if we did see binds we would have a result that is a three by two Matrix and the instructions asked
for a two by three.
I mean the correct answer was to use our bind AB.
And here we have our matrix.
Let's go ahead and move on to exercise.
Question number two.
Exercise 2 was to create a three by three matrix consisting of the numbers 1 through 9.
We had to create this met matrix using the shortcut.
One call and nine is by specifying the n row argument in the matrix function call.
Let's assign this matrix the variable M-80.
Matt when you go ahead and clear the con..
So just a quick reminder of what the actual shortcut looks like.
This one Colan nine that creates a sequence of integers.
So for example instead of having to write the combined function one two three for a continuous sequence
of integers I can just say one colon three.
And the syntax is your starting integer colon to your ending last in the integer.
So how do we actually use this with the Matrix call or we're going to say matrix function will pass
in one call in nine and then we're going to say by RHO equals true and we'll say number of rows is equal
to 3.
In order to have it be a three by three it's go to check to make sure that looks correct.
One two three four five six seven eight nine.
Everything's looking good.
Let's go in and save that to the variable M-80.
So I'll take that same command and I will sign it to the variable Max.
And that's how we answer that question.
A quick note.
If you didn't specify by rote the equal true that's OK as well.
So if he did something like this and ran that that would give you filled out by the columns which is
also an acceptable answer doesn't really matter.
You don't do by RHO true since it wasn't specified for this particular question.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next question.
All right.
Question number three was to confirm that M-80 variable is a matrix.
Using is dot matrix.
Let me go and explain how that is that Matrix actually works.
I'm going to say is dots.
And you'll notice our studio will actually have a huge drop down menu of all the things we can check
.
So the is the methods are really useful if you're trying to check what data type data structure you're
working with.
Then in this case we're going to go ahead and check if something is a matrix.
So you end up doing is say is that matrix and you pass in the variable you want to check and it'll return
true because the M-80 variable is a matrix and you can actually use the same sort of operation for any
data type.
So if I go in and clear the console and say Is dots we can check if something is an array.
So we can go ahead and pass in MIT and we get true in this case because Matrix's do count as a form
of an array.
Notice an array is not the same as a vector.
You can think of a matrix as just a two dimensional array.
But if we do something like check is dot for instance data frame which will learn about in more detail
later we pass and met we get false because a matrix and a data frame aren't the same thing.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next question.
Number four exercise for was to create a five by five matrix consisting of the numbers 1 through 25
and assign it to the variable M-80 2 and the top row should be the numbers 1 through 5.
So we're going to do this really Similarly it's how we just did the last Matrix.
I'm going to go ahead and say Matt 2 for my variable name and then I will pass in the matrix function
.
I'll use that shortcut to quickly create a vector one through 325.
Notice it said the top row should be the numbers 1 through 5 meaning I want to fill this out by rows
not by columns.
So since my columns is the default meaning by rows is false.
And I go ahead and say by row capital-T for true.
And then finally I want this to be a five by five matrix.
So I want the number of rows to be five.
Let's go ahead and check that too.
It looks like everything worked well.
We have a five by five Matrix and we have one two three four five.
OK moving on to the next question using indexing notation.
Grab a subsection of Matt 2 from the previous exercise that looks like this 7 comma 8 12 comma 13.
All right let's go ahead and do that.
So let's go in and locate where 7 8 12 13 would be in or M8 to are meant to object.
Looks like it's 78 right here in columns 2 and 3 wrote 2.
And then we also have in the same columns 2 and 3 but row 3 total 13.
So essentially want to grab this square chunk out of our matrix.
Let's go ahead and do that well you use bracket notation.
Or the indexing notation that we learned earlier.
First thing I want to do is pass in the rows that I want in this case I want rows two through three
.
So one way I can do that is just by using that colon rotation rows two three three and actually want
this exact same columns.
So say comma exactly mutation and if I run that we get that result 7 8 12 13 to enter two times it goes
up a bit.
But here it is.
So this is the correct way that index for that.
Let's move on to the next exercise which is also an index notation exercise and for this exercise we
want it to again grab a subsection that now looks like this 19 20 and 24 25.
Looking again at our math to object we have 19 20 and 24 25 looks like that's a two by two subsection
in rows and columns 4 5 and 4 5.
So how do we do this.
Well again it's going to be really similar.
Hopefully if he did the last one you'll be able to answer this one as well.
We're going in clear the councils we have in a Froom.
I'll say I'm at 2 again so you can see it.
I want 19 20 and 24 25.
So again pass met to a pass in the rows that I want which is rows 4 through 5.
And then I pass the columns I want which again is Aurthur 5.
And there we have that subsection in the matrix.
As mentioned during the matrix lectures it's really useful if you're struggling with this concept of
rows common columns to just in your mind grab subsections of the matrix and then try to index them.
So do a quick example of this.
In case you're struggling this concept let's say I wanted to grab seven eight nine ten and then 12 13
14 15.
So a rectangular Matrix.
Well I just identify the rows that I want so two three and it passes into Colon three and then identify
the columns I want which is two three four five.
So let's to call in five and I get this answer as a result.
Again that's not an actual exercise question in this case.
Just an example of how you can break this problem down.
So if you're struggling with this make sure you practice it a lot just by choosing subsections and trying
to get them out.
Let's go to move on to the next exercise which was exercise 7.
The question was What is the sum of all the elements in Mat 2.
How do we actually do that.
Well you can clear the console and we just use the sum function so we can say some math too.
So hopefully to discover that if you just say some math to it will sum all the elements.
Quick side note if you're looking to some just the columns or just the rows you can add additional arguments
like call some's or sum up the column so we can go in and say I met two and then row sums.
Works for the rows.
All right.
So those are just quick side notes.
But in this case if you want to do all the elements shust normal some moving on we have one more exercise
.
And it was this.
Find out how to use run I if this function to create a four by five matrix consisting of 20 random numbers
four times five is equal to 20.
All right let's go ahead and see how he would do this.
First thing I'm going to assume that you've never actually seen this function before run.
So I want to find out how to use it.
Meaning I want to help on this.
I'll say help.
And pasan.
Ron I-F and then boom we have a nice help tab here and we see what the arguments look like and what
we should actually do.
So what actually is run I.
Well it's a uniform distribution.
And what that means is these functions essentially provide information with the uniform distribution
from the interval from min to Max.
So how do we actually do this.
We look here and notice we have a few uniform distribution functions.
But the last one here is run.
The one we referred to is a little small so hopefully you can call as far as font size.
You can call help here and that spoiler's yourself.
But if I just go in and copy this so we can see what it's actually saying in the documentation it says
run a f n comma min equals zero Max equals 1.
So those are the parameters or arguments we have to pass into this function and if we check out the
documentation for what it is it says and is a number of observations.
All right so we know we want 20 random numbers.
So that means I want to draw 20.
If I go yes go ahead and say run I if I pass in 20 and looks like it returns a vector of 20 random numbers
.
Perfect.
Now I can also specify min and max value.
So for instance right now I'm just doing random numbers.
Frean the defaults and the defaults were 0 and 1.
But if I go ahead and say run I if it's a random uniform distribution pass in 20 values I can also specify
what I want the min value to be and the Max might be.
So if I wanted to pick numbers tween 0 and 100 I could say many equals zero.
And I could change my max to be 100.
And now I get 25 or 20 random numbers between 0 and 100 in the solutions notebook I show putting in
the men and the max.
You don't actually have to do that.
You could have just run run f 20.
Let's go ahead and go with min and max settings.
So how do we actually perform this.
As far as creating this matrix of a four by five consisting of these when he ran the numbers will you
just say matrix and then we pass in run I f 20
and we wants four rows who want a four by five matrix and there is our matrix.
And notice here even though it's printing out like this is a four by five.
I'm going to go ahead and do is expand the window a bit.
You can always check by what the index locations are the dimensions of your matrix.
But if I run this again then we can see for sure that it's a four by five matrix.
All right mixture of the notebook in case you're confused on anything but remember the main point of
this last question was to get you used to reading help on functions that you don't know about and learning
how to use them.
All right.
Hopefully that wasn't too bad.
Make sure review the matrix lectures in case you're unsure of anything we just covered.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture