Hello everyone and welcome to the lecture on getting help with our in this brief lecture.
We're just going to discuss a couple of useful ways to get help.
When you're programming of our let's go ahead and hop over to our studio.
OK.
So here we are our studio and I'm just going to show you a few ways you can get help with our the main
way you can get help for it just by using a help function.
So for example let's see you wanted to get help with doctors.
You could say something like this.
Help open parentheses and then just pass on the topic.
So again it's past and the topic doctor and you should see here on the Help tab of the lower right hand
panel a help documents for the documentation will show up describing vectors telling you your usage
for them.
The arguments details and even examples of vectors at the bottom.
So there's a really useful way of using our documentation directly from the our programming environment
.
In other way you can get help is by using two sets of question marks.
So for example you could type in a question mark question mark vector and you would get the same result
.
So let me go ahead and show that and another word cxi the change.
Let's say I wanted to know more about gnumeric.
I clicked enter.
I get search results for numeric then America is actually quite a general term so you get a lot of results
here and help.
If you actually want to specifically search for help you can do help search and then search whatever
terms you were curious about.
So let's say you are curious a little more about vectors and you just wanted to search for vectors that
go directly to the help page for that particular data type.
So you did it just a basic search for help in the R for vectors in the documentation.
All right.
So that's really all there is to it.
As far as getting help within are of course doing a good google search or checking out Stack Overflow
for your questions is another great way to find help when you're programming.
Our thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.