Hello and welcome to the part of the course on visualization.
I hope you are enjoying intro to data science so far and in this part we're going to have quite an exciting
time.
We're going to get some hands on experience with physical zation in order for us to get a better feel
for what it's like to be a data scientist and visualizing things and actually how much per hour that
can give to age in a sense the whole concept of Israel lising data or seeing your data how powerful
that is.
And this part we're going to be using a tool called Tablo.
I personally really like tabloid think it's very you are very user friendly and well-thought through
tool for zation and in fact they actually have a free version which called tabel public and that's why
we're going to use it here.
So let's have a look to find tabel public.
We're going to need to type in Tablo public.
There it is.
And that will open up the page if we can actually go and check out Tablo the Web site itself.
So here you can see the Tabeau Web site.
They talk about you know data in brilliance out.
It's quite a cool company in general they have a good division I think and also they have a very large
community so that's one of the powerful tools of type 1.
One of the advantages of Tablo the community they have because you can always ask questions and people
can help you.
So there's lots of things you can exploit as a gallery here if you'd like to see some examples.
But for now just if you type in your e-mail here it will allow you to download that.
Now don't worry you don't have to give away your personal information you can type in a temporary email.
You you have or something else.
So for instance I've already downloaded it but I just wanted to see what it looks like I'll show you
what it looks like.
Would say as I type in test 2:59 Visi test test test at gmail dot com.
Maybe add some symbols in case somebody has a me already.
So if you put in your information or some information you'll see that it's started downloading automatically.
They have a version for Windows and for Mac.
So that's good.
So once it's downloaded I'm just going to cancel this because I already have it.
Once it's on your computer and you launch it you'll get a screen like this.
And here you just continue the installation.
So I don't have it installed yet and doing this along together a few.
So let's have a look.
There's always the license agreement so make sure you are aware of it and you agreed to it if you agreed
to it.
It tells you how much space will take and then it's going to ask you for your password.
And as you can see it's installing now.
It lets you in a few seconds takes about a minute.
So while it's in storage sort of say that tabbouleh I've been using for quite a while now so probably
since 2000 12 was it.
Yeah they were both finished and I don't even have time telling or what.
So I was using Tablo I first learned about it at the word and I fell in love with that tool.
They're asking me to move to trash the installation file that's just how Macs work.
Yes.
Yeah and I think you will actually enjoy the two as well.
Once we get to know everybody here so tool is ready how do we how relaunch should we go.
Whoops trouble.
So I need tabel public not tablet desktop because I have no power at all.
And so if you search for Tabeau public on your Mac I pressed Connard comments space to bring up the
search menu.
And then you type in of public on Windows you will have it in the start menu.
So if you wanted to reach which screen is it going to launch on or away have to drag it or there is
less room.
Other screens.
I'll try to get over in a second.
So there it is there is tablet public and you're all successfully installed.
So we'll learn how to use the software.
And in fact we'll start using it from the next Toral.
And I look forward to seeing it.
Until then enjoy the asides.