It all goes back to the interesting data science course we're in the visualization part.
And right now we're looking at the month variable and whether or not there is some correlation between
in which month we contacted people and their likelihood to take up our term deposit offer.
We already create this recession in the previous tutorial but we haven't discussed it yet.
And plus you had some homework to grade the following three variables housing day a week and the outcome.
So we really got them created here and we'll look at them in a second but for now let's discuss month.
So what's the first thing that stands out.
First thing that should have stood out when you were looking at this election is that somehow we only
have 10 months January and February completely dropped out of this election.
They're not here.
So first thing we look at is filters.
There are no filters on so that means they're probably not even in the database or in the data set.
And so what's in a proper entend data science project we do at this stage is we would actually go back
to the original data source and make sure that we haven't lost any data along the way because it's quite
strange that January-February are here and so don't worry a very double check.
I checked the original data source and data set and we truly don't have January and February in there.
And so now we just have to try to understand why.
So the next thing is we discussed that we're not going to look at December because it looks like it's
not really statistically significant.
It's about 89 93 here compared to you know like we've got a lot more variables in other ones.
And so this could be a random effect that it's like almost you know half the people we contacted in
December decided to take up the trial because it could be a random effect because it's not a statistically
significant result most likely and therefore we're not going to look at it.
And again this illustrates the importance of statistics or just basic understanding of statistics in
data centers.
And this actually gives us a clue as to why January February might not be available either.
The thing is that people spend a lot of money on Christmas New Year's and other holiday presents during
the December festive season and that's why in December they're kind of like saving up money in order
to spend it on the presents and then in general if they simply don't have that money until they get
paid.
Several times from their job.
So they get paid for January and then they have to pay off their credit cards.
February is usually the worst month for retail and you you get to see that in practice as you do.
There are science projects in the retail industry you see that a huge dip in February in terms of sales
because people are still paying off their credit from December.
And maybe that's exactly the reason why this bank is not proposing these products to their customers
in January and February simply because a term deposit requires a customer to put it away put money into
the bank for six months or 12 months or 24 months for a fixed period of time.
And then which they cannot touch the money in that time.
In exchange they get good.
In exchange they get a good interest rate.
And so maybe the bank has already figured it out.
That said Janet Hembree I really not the best months to contact people.
And as you can see maybe they've also thought the same about December that there's quiet.
You know that's why they didn't do a lot of contacts.
And so that that could be one that could be the reason why Jennifer Bernardin here.
And now let's have a look at the other months.
What did you discover here about the other months.
Well we can see that the sell the term deposits in March are quite high although people who took up
the offer was probably the highest month maybe the reason here is that people actually got paid and
now they have some money they've saved up.
They have been buying presents and so on and they're willing to invest it in to make some interest and
then make some interest what else we can see that April kind of drops off.
Maybe it's because a lot of people invested in March and others is they don't have enough money to do
that again.
May I'm not really sure about May.
Why so low.
June July August outside is probably because of the summer holidays and people maybe in May.
People are saving up to go for a trip in the summer holidays and that's why it's low.
And then summer holidays.
June July August people are just not at home or that's not what they're really worrying about they're
spending time with the family if the kids are going somewhere and then it goes back up in September
because everybody's back and now they're you know kind of like starting a new educational year in terms
of school.
But like the adults the parents bring their kids back and you know maybe they're rethinking their finances
October.
Again similar on kind of like in that sense.
But then November drop's.
Why would a member drop Well similar to this situation that they're probably setting up for December
to spend money there.
Again we're not looking at this at all.
So they probably spring up for December and also in November we have Black Friday right.
So in Black Friday people spend a bit of money and that's another reason.
So there you go.
That's as an example of how interesting designs can be like we're looking at a picture but we're applying
so much other knowledge right away to assess why this is happening.
And the other thing I wanted to point out here as well is that these effects they are not like they
are not secluded right.
So there's also other variables and the combination what we're seeing here are people taking up this
term deposit is also affected by the variables and you know Carol that nobody is guaranteed that for
instance I don't know the marital status of people we're contacting is consistently the percentage of
you know married versus divorced versus single.
It's consistent across the months maybe in March.
We just contacted more single people for some reason.
So there might be some correlation between the variables and that can be affecting these outcomes so
that's just something else to keep in mind we're not going to delve into that.
Just wanted to put that caveat out there that there are other things to consider.
And that comes with like additional statistical information knowledge or when you apply machine learning
but through basic visual analysis you can already get some valuable insights that's you know like you
can really say that some months like March September or October are most likely better than the other
ones.
All right.
So let's have a look at these other variables so housing you probably if you did this very well you
probably saw that there's not much effect here.
Nothing to talk about day of week.
Similar.
Not much effect.
The 2 percent difference even though you know eight hundred and nine hundred fifty three The difference
is so little it's only 2 percent.
And the number of people like in order to for that to be statistically significant.
I'll just give you like a quick quick insight into the world of stats for that to be statistically significant
between 2 and 10 percent.
The number would have to be in observations in each of these cases would have to be much greater than
it is now.
So even though they are high they are not high enough to prove that this 2 percent difference is that
this is significant.
So what we would conclude from here would say that there's not enough evidence to suggest anything about
about day of week.
So basically hour any day of the week you contact them.
They're same there's the same likelihood of getting that term deposit and the outcome.
So here we've got an interesting example right so here we've got a huge difference.
Right.
So if if we if we contacted them before and it was a successful campaign IPO outcome is what is the
outcome outcome of the previous marketing campaign.
So if it was a successful marketing campaign previously then this time they are more likely to subscribe
to take that term deposit.
Sixty five percent chance that they will take.
So that's a huge gold nugget we found in there is kind of expected.
Right so if a person already said yes to our product or a product before then they kind of like maybe
they're loyal to us.
They they like our bank and so on.
So they are probably going to say yes again.
So it was expected but this percentage really high 65 percent so that's really good.
So something to point out if and then this one is interesting if we didn't contact them before if we
didn't even approach them at all then the percentage is 9 percent.
But if we contacted them and we failed and they didn't take up the offer the percentage is 14 percent
and the numbers are quite high.
Six hundred and so there can be something going on here.
And so that's very interesting because I would expect the opposite.
I would expect if you failed to contact if you failed to sell them something before then you're not
likely to sell them something again this time and maybe people who you haven't approached at all then
you're more likely there but in reality as we can see is actually it's better to contact people who
we've failed to sell something to before then people we haven't contacted at all.
So basically you would contact them and this or you would contact people who you've successfully sold
to before then you'd contact people who you unsuccessfully sold to before and then only you would spend
your time and resources and energy contacting people who you haven't contacted yet before.
Interesting insights so this was expected this was probably unexpected.
You always obviously check test the statistical significance there.
But again we're not going to go into that looks looks kind of OK.
But obviously before presenting this to an executive you would make sure that it's statistically significant.
It's just a very simple calculation that has to be done.
So there we go.
That's that's some insights into some of the other variables.
All right so hopefully you had similar results and we're going to stop this tutorial here because there
was quite a lot of information.
And yeah and also on the next.
Until then enjoy that sense.