Local printing.
Now Microsoft has always been a bit persnickety,
if you don't mind the five-dollar word, about their terminology with printing.
In the Microsoft context,
a print device refers to the physical device that produces output.
This could be a laser printer, maybe in older shops a dot matrix printer,
or commonly in the home you might find an inkjet printer,
it's the actual device.
The printer port can be a physical or virtual interface.
We'll cover what both of those mean upcoming later in this module.
The printer in Microsoft nomenclature is the software
representation of a print device.
This should make sense.
When you go to print a document by doing a File,
Print, you select the software printer,
and then you go to the physical print device to retrieve the output.
A printer driver is a piece of software that serves
as an interface between Windows, the operating system,
and the physical print device.
You know that we need drivers for any hardware in Windows,
printer driver it's no different.
In fact,
we have bit more to say about printer drivers and their behavior in Windows 10.
But first though,
let's take a trip through memory lane and examine the
various common printer interfaces.
When I use the term interface,
I'm referring to a hardware interconnect between the print device on one
side and a matching port on your computer on the other.
If you've ever heard of the old parallel port,
that's what you see in this picture,
when I got into the IT industry full time in the '90s,
that was a pretty standard interface.
They're very slow, they're not compatible with Plug and Play.
If you make a configuration change,
you'll likely have to power cycle the printer,
but you'll be surprised to see how many legacy shops,
and when I say legacy I'm referring to a business
that's still using hardware that's many,
many years old, you may run across a parallel port printer nowadays,
but to be honest,
if you want to connect a parallel port printer to
any current generation computer,
you're going to have to purchase a matching interface card
and install it in the chassis first.
The Small Computer Systems Interface, or SCSI standard, has come a long way.
It's generally considered faster, by all accounts than parallel,
but parallel SCSI even has gone the way of the dodo in favor of
faster and more reliable printer interfaces,
like the Universal Serial Bus.
Each successive version of USB, we're up to version 3 now,
gets faster and more reliable,
and there are a number of form factors for those plugs.
Now you don't have to worry about the interface plug types for this exam,
but if you're interested,
I would encourage you to check the Pluralsight library for
my CompTIA A+ training because I go into great detail on how
these various interfaces work.
As far as wireless printing goes, you have infrared,
which is a line-of-sight printing you see in this small picture on an old flip
phone using infrared to print from the phone to the printer.
The line-of-sight really weakens IR's practicality though.
Bluetooth is a longer-range wireless technology,
30-40 feet that does not require line of sight.
Wi-Fi and Ethernet are by far the most common approaches.
Well, for a true local printer it would be USB,
and as far as wireless access goes,
it would be traditional Wi-Fi or in a wired network context, Ethernet.