System Restore.
System Restore is an often misunderstood service in Windows, I found.
It's been in the Windows Client OS for a long time.
It's called System Protection formally,
so when you see references in Windows 10 to System Protection you
know that we're really talking about System Restore.
What this service does, it snapshots "system files",
and I put that in quotation marks.
System files comprise stuff like your registry configuration,
device drivers, applications,
but in practice System Restore doesn't technically back up entire applications,
it looks for specific file types or file extensions,
many of which do happen to be executable.
Note that System Restore is not an antimalware product.
There's a common conception, and in some cases it might work,
where if your system becomes infected by malware you can roll back to a
system restore point from before when you were infected,
but I wouldn't depend upon that 100%.
System Restore is also not a file recovery product.
A common misconception is that System Restore touches your document files.
Now there are some potential gotchas that could result in data loss,
but those are fairly edge cases.
Look in the exercise files, and I give you a pointer to read further on that.
Specifically, System Restore is intended to help in the following cases,
number 1,
you install a program that conflicts with other
software or drivers on your system.
Yes, you could go to Programs and Features and remove the program,
but you can also consider running a system restore point back to
before the application was on the machine.
You, in a sense,
can roll back the configuration of your system to a previous point in time.
Device Drivers,
this is what I find to be the most commonly used case for System Restore.
You update a driver, or maybe Windows Update updates a driver,
and it breaks functionality, you want to go back to the previous version driver.
Well,
as long as you have a valid system restore point that was
taken before that driver installation, this is an option.
Third, your system develops a stability problem.
Maybe another user who uses the system installed a piece of software,
or a driver,
or made a registry system configuration change
that's introduced some instability,
all of these are valid use cases for System Restore.
Now you're probably wondering, if you've never used System Restore,
do System Restore points just happen automatically?
Is System Restore turned on by default?
The answer to those questions are, number 1, it depends.
As I'll show you in the upcoming demo,
you do have control over the System Restore Protection Service.
And also,
it depends upon whether the applications that you
install are System Restore aware, that is to say,
you can write in your application installation code an instruction to take a
System Restore snapshot automatically before you proceed.
There is recovery software.
There is a third-party piece of software called Revo Uninstaller,
and that's an application that allows you to perform a deeper and
more comprehensive uninstallation of software.
It will, by default,
take a System Restore point before going further in an uninstallation,
such that you can roll back your changes if you decide that
that uninstallation was not a good idea. Let's hop into a demo, because this is best experienced live in person.