First we'll examine network connectivity options in Windows 10.
Before I do the demo,
I wanted to go through a user interface tour to show you some of the major
touch points in configuring network connectivity in Windows 10.
One option is to click the appropriate network icon in the notification area.
What you see here is the icon that Microsoft uses
for a wired ethernet connection.
There's also a similar one that looks like Wi-Fi
radio waves for Wi-Fi connections.
So if you click the ethernet or Wi-Fi link,
you'll get a notification pop-up, like you see here,
that gives you a list of available networks that you're either connected to,
or can connect to, in the case of Wi-Fi.
That's one way to get to your physical network connectivity in Windows 10.
If you need to do some more profound configuration,
no surprise, we can go to the Windows 10 Settings application.
Specifically,
under Network and Internet we have Status that gives you just a
general run of what your current network connection is.
Now you'll see below Status there's an Ethernet entry.
Some other entries may show up in this list if you have
other physical network connectivity means,
namely,
if you have a Wi-Fi adapter in your computer you'll have an entry
in this settings list for Wi-Fi connections.
You should see in the right side of this page several features that
by now you should have good familiarity with,
particularly the HomeGroup and Windows Firewall.
VPN, or virtual private network,
refers to creating a secure connection over the public internet,
which is anything but secure,
such that you can work as if you are local to your business,
but you may be in a remote location, home,
hotel, remote office, whatever the case may be.
The VPN connections, or as I sometimes call them,
connectoids, are stored and configured under this setting.
Because I've been with Windows since the very beginning,
I reflexively type ncpa.
cpl to open the Network Connections window that you see in the background.
This is going to have an icon that represents every
physical connection you have, in some case,
virtual network connections.
What do I mean by that?
Well, the text is probably too small for you to see on your screen,
but there's an entry called vEthernet Default Switch.
That is a virtual network interface that is managed by Hyper-V.
The other three entries are, in fact, physical cards I have on my system.
You can rename those connections.
I have two connections on this machine that I'm using,
one for internal connectivity and one for external.
When you look at the properties of an Ethernet connection,
you have, well, the property sheet.
I'm going to go through this in more detail in the demo,
but if you're not familiar with this workflow then
you've got some remediation to do,
because for our purposes here we have to assume a baseline
familiarity with Ethernet and TCP/IP.
As usual,
at the end of this module I'll give you some
Pluralsight course links if you do realize, hey, I need some more general purpose grounding in networking.