In this demonstration, we'll look at System Restore in Windows 10,
and I have us here at the Microsoft Development Network or MSDN website.
I gave you the URL in the exercise files.
Remember I mentioned that System Restore technically looks at file extensions.
A file extension, you might recall, is normally a three letter,
an alphanumeric string,
a three-character suffix to files that serve as an association
point between that file type and an application.
Oftentimes files can be handled by multiple applications, like HTML files.
But anyway, this is a pretty comprehensive list,
a lot of executable code here that gets picked up,
a lot of files with extensions that might be unfamiliar to you,
it's a pretty big list, but anyway,
I just wanted to show you that for completeness.
The end user experience to System Restore, let's get this show on the road.
I'm going to do a Windows key + Q to open up Cortana and type system restore.
It wants to open up the Create a restore point in the classic Control Panel.
This technically opens the System Control Panel to the System Protection tab.
Now the System Restore button will actually start the System Restore wizard.
Down below, though, you first have to make sure that you're protecting a disk.
Normally for System Restore this is going to be your system disk, your C drive.
You can toggle protection from off to on just by
selecting the volume and clicking configure.
I have my system drive already turned on, so I'll click Configure.
This is where you can turn System Protection on or off and adjust
the disk space used for those restore points.
Now in some troubleshooting cases, when a machine has been compromised,
say, with malware for a long time,
you might just want to delete all previously created restore
points for the drive and then start over.
In my case, I'm allocating about 2.
5 GB max usage for the system restore points on that volume.
You can manually create a restore point here by clicking Create.
It asks you to give it a name.
I'll call this PreWinZip.
Now there's a reason why I'm saying PreWinZip.
It says Creating a restore point.
So it's snapshotting the system,
remember it's monitoring a whole bunch of extensions,
it's not picking up any user files.
The restore point was created successfully, awesome.
What I'm going to do is go out to Edge,
and I'm going to download the WINZIP extraction utility.
I'm going to run it in place, quickly get this application installed,
let me close out of System Restore.
I'll be darned,
it looks like the smart screen filter is not allowing this
installation to complete because it says the file contains a
virus or potentially unwanted software.
That's one of the problems that you find with freeware and shareware,
is that oftentimes in order to make money the software vendor will
include or inject money-making software in there.
I mean, I don't know anymore details about this,
I'm not knocking WINZIP specifically, but you saw what just happened,
and I'm glad it happened,
because it looks like we have some WINZIP remnants in our system.
there's a shortcut created on our desktop,
and this would be a good case where we want to rollback using System Restore.
So, again, I'll use win key + Q, system restore Enter,
and this time I'll launch the System Restore tool,
and let's step through here.
It gives us a list of restore points.
I have my PreWinZip one that was a manually created one.
Notice that an automatic restore point took place a coulee days ago,
that was snapshotted by the system.
I'm going to, actually this is kind of cool,
Scan for affected programs, let's click that.
This is a good sanity check before just blindly rushing
forth with a System Restore restore,
and it hasn't detected any possible breakages if we remove any files.
Programs and drivers that will be deleted, None detected.
Well, didn't, was it more than just that shortcut that WinZip gave us?
Maybe not, maybe it was just the desktop app.
Let me run a little test here.
I'm going to create a text file called text.
txt,
and I'm going to put some junk text in here just to prove and
demonstrate that we're not going to lose any user data here.
Let's select PreWinZip and actually I just realized,
I want to show you, I'm sorry about all of the actuallies here.
What I'm thinking as I'm going through here,
I don't use a script as an instructor because I think my training
is much more effective when it's spontaneous,
but I realized there's three days between this initial restore point,
and wonder if there's been anything that will show up in the affected programs
and drivers list if we choose to go back in time 2 days,
instead of just 2 minutes.
Nope, this has been a pretty quiet system, I must admit.
So, anyway, we'll select PreWinZip and click Next, and Finish.
It tells us that once started you can't interrupt it,
are you sure you want to do that?
I'll say Yes.
Preparing to restore your system.
It's going to force a restart here,
so I'll let that take place and we'll log in together.
System Restore is initializing, okay.
Okay, we've restarted, time to log onto the system.
System Restore completed successfully.
The system has been restored to this particular date and time.
Your documents have not been affected.
Right, so that text.
txt file is still here untouched,
but that stub loader that we saw from WINZIP is conspicuously absent.
Now the good thing about System Restore is,
as long as you take a restore point before you roll back any restores,
you can move forward in time as well.
You would Start + Q, System Restore, step through the wizard again,
and actually even better than that it looks like the wizard
detected that we just ran a System Restore,
and we can undo it directly or we can choose a different restore point. Very handy indeed.