In this demonstration, we'll work with file systems,
and specifically I'm going to walk through how to initialize a new disk,
create partitions, format them, so forth.
We do this through the Disk Management Console.
Couple different ways to do that.
We can just do a search for disk management.
That brings us to Control panel, Create and format hard disk partitions.
Huh, weird.
Yeah, it's one way to do it.
Another way, my favorite way,
is to get to a run prompt or a command prompt and type diskmgmt.
msc.
That's the specific file name for the Disk
Management Microsoft Management Console.
I have it open here, so I'll close out of the Run box.
Now, because I mounted a new, uninitialized disk,
we're prompted right off the top, do you want to initialize it?
I'm actually going to cross out of that,
or X out of that, and we'll maximize our Disk Management interface.
Up on the top, we have a list of volumes.
Remember, a volume is a formatted partition,
and a volume does not necessarily mean that you're
occupying all space on a physical device.
This machine has one, two, three fixed disks,
internal disks, and one optical drive,
on which it looks like I have a DVD mounted.
Its volume label is right there.
I happen to know that's the Windows 10 Professional DVD.
We can see up on top in the summary,
we see what kind of file systems we're using.
It looks NTFS, except for the DVD that uses the UDF file system.
The status, let me stretch this out.
Actually,
I'll double left-click the right side of each of these
column headers to autosize them.
They're all healthy, and that's good,
but you see on my Disk 0 I have my System Reserved partition.
That's 500 MB.
Windows creates that for its own use.
My boot volume is my drive C, NTFS, as you can see.
And then I have a Recovery Partition for my recovery environment that also,
neither it nor the System Reserved have a drive letter
because we don't need to interact with them.
I have a D drive that's called DATA.
That's using NTFS.
I have a new uninitialized disk that I've told you about
that we saw the pop-up for a moment ago.
And then we have our DVD.
If we open up File Explorer, and we navigate to This PC,
there's our C drive, there's our D drive,
and there's our optical disk.
To initialize a new disk,
we'll right-click its header and choose Initialize Disk from the shortcut menu.
Normally, for most purposes, MBR or Master Boot Record is fine.
GPT is a newer partition management format.
I'm going to leave MBR here.
And once the disk is marked Online, we can start to carve it up.
Now this is a 60 GB unallocated space block.
If I right-click and choose New Simple Volume, it kicks off the wizard.
We can step through this.
I'm going to create a 20 GB by specifying 20000 MB.
Next, assign the following letter, it picks up the next available one by default,
that's fine, and then here's where we format that volume.
In this case, it's giving us the choice of only FAT32 or NTFS,
not ReFs, which we would see in Windows Server systems.
The Allocation unit size, default is normally fine to let Windows choose.
This is the size of the clusters that'll be used on that system.
Normally it's 4K.
And then for Volume label, we can always change that later.
I'll call it DATA2, just for now, and we can enable compression right here,
or we can do it later.
That again is a feature of the NTFS file system.
Didn't take long at all for that to work,
and if I click the notification balloon,
I can open the folder and I can start to store data on this drive all day long.
Now you can do things in here that are kind of cool.
You can extend volume, shrink volumes.
Of course, you can delete it.
You can change the drive letter.
If we're not happy with F,
we can change it to another available one in the alphabet.
I have to do that from time to time on systems.
But basically,
the distinction between the top and the bottom is the
top is a summary view and down here,
the graphical map allows you to work directly on each volume.
And then as far as making changes go in the future,
if we needed this to use a different file system for whatever reason,
we could right-click and go to Format,
and you have an opportunity to choose another file system.
There's REFS.
We can change the volume label if we want to.
I'll call it REFSVOL and perform a quick format.
Of course, if I had any data on this disk,
it's going to be gone,
so you want to be extraordinarily careful when you're performing a format.
And that is an administrative action.
I'm logged onto the system as a member of the local administrators group, as you would expect.