Now I mentioned that these settings and Control Panel items modify the Registry.
How do we open the Registry?
Well I would suggest that you right-click the Start button,
go to Run, and type regedit, R-E-G-E-D-I-T.
Now you have to be an administrator to run this tool.
If you're logged on with standard user permissions,
then you'll be prompted to supply an administrative username and password.
If you're already logged on that machine as a local administrator,
then you're prompted for consent, which you see here,
and I'm going to grant that consent.
Here is the Registry editor, as I mentioned before.
There is a lot we could do here and there is a lot of important Registry keys.
One that I've used so much when working with customers over the
years are the autostart keys because malware,
malicious software,
normally will create values in your autostart paths
such that as you would expect,
the malware will autostart every time the system is rebooted.
Now there is four different paths.
Check the exercise files for details,
but the main one I'll go to is under the machine
configuration HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE, Software,
Microsoft, Windows, scroll down,
I have quite a bit of software installed on this system
and there is a lot of Windows options,
I just want plain old garden variety Windows,
current version, and then scroll down again,
Run.
Now this is a pretty clean virtual machine so there is really not too much here.
It is a virtual machine,
so you'll notice I have a setting called VMware User
process and if I double left-click that,
it's a string value and basically this means that
every time I start the computer,
VMware will start this little agent program that you see
running down in my notification area.
Specifically,
this Windows 10 box is running as a virtual machine under VMware workstation.
I'm just trying to get you to the point here of understanding
the basics of working with the Registry.
Remember,
I mentioned that there is no undo functionality so this means
that when you're doing surgery on the Registry,
it's important for you to take a backup.
Now you can backup the entire Registry or you can just backup a part of it.
Now what you back up depends upon where you are in the hierarchy.
If I just want to backup the contents of the Run key,
I can right-click and select Export from the shortcut menu.
I'm going to browse to my desktop and I'm going to save this as RunKey.
Now notice that it's saved as a.
reg file,
that's important to know because you want to be careful when you're browsing
the web and downloading a reg file and just opening it up.
That could have potentially disastrous consequences.
Now here is a trivia question or a learning question from the previous module.
You'll notice that I don't see the.
reg on this RunKey, how can we force it to display.
What do you think?
Well it's going to involve the Settings/Control Panel system isn't it,
and specifically what I showed you in the previous module is
that you can open a File Explorer window,
go to the View tab, and under Options,
you can do a change folder and search options,
and in there, you can come over to View,
scroll down a bit and uncheck Hide extensions for known file types.
I'll apply that change and we can see that it's taken place immediately.
Click OK to dismiss folder options.
Now I mentioned that's the way I showed you in the previous module.
One of my goals is, remember, to show you how to be a Windows 10 power user.
You can also press the Windows key and just type your search,
folder options, for instance, and look what it does.
It actually attempts or asks us if we want to open the
File Explorer Options Control Panel.
This one happens to use the classic interface as you can see,
but it's the same set of options, and if we scroll down,
we can see hide extensions for known file types is
still deselected as we expected.
Now to look at the contents of this,
let's say actually let's come back to the Registry and let's say we're
living dangerously and we don't want this to autostart.
Now note that many times you don't have to come down to the
level of the Registry to remove something.
Oftentimes,
you can do it through Control Panel or through the application itself,
but let's just say you were reading a support article and
it instructs you to delete this value.
I'm going to right-click and delete it.
We do see a scary-looking confirmed value delete dialog that says
that this action can cause system instability.
Are you sure you want to do it?
I'm going to click Yes and there is no undo.
Sometimes Registry changes go into effect immediately.
Other times, you'll have to log off and log back on,
and other ones, specifically, ones that effect the entire system,
you have to restart to see that change.
Now if we decided that we did in fact need that value,
remember, we took a backup of the RunKey.
Check this out.
Right-click, come down to Open with and you can force this guy to open,
not with Registry editor, but with another app.
I'm going to choose a plain text editor.
Notepad has been in Windows for many years, I think that's fine.
We'll click OK, and although it kind of looks like gobbledygook,
specifically, we see a bunch of hexadecimal values.
I'm going to go to Format,
Font and boost the font a little bit to make it easier for you to see.
It shows you the path that you backed up and then the values and the
value data of every value that's in that backup.
Now if you back up the entire Registry, that's going to be big reg file.
Here,
I just backed up those two values and this is actually the one that we deleted,
this VMware user process.
To merge this back into the registry, we can double left-click it.
You do have to be an administrator to do a registry
merge as I think is a good idea.
And it says, are you sure you want to do this.
I'm going to click Yes,
and it tells us that the keys and values contained in this file
have been successfully added to the Registry.
Let's come back to the Registry editor and there is that
value that we deleted a moment ago.
Finally,
I'm going to very quickly show you Group Policy just in case you were
interested and where to find that in Windows 10.
We can right-click the Start and go to Run again,
and this time, we type gpedit,
that stands for Group Policy editor,. msc and the msc file type
denotes that this is a Microsoft Management Console,
or MMC file.
We'll see more about MMC consoles a bit later in this course.
Just like we saw in the Registry, there is the computer,
the HKey local machine, and then the users HKey users and HKey current user.
Current user is whoever is currently logged onto the machine.
The Registry settings that you can control in Group Policy
editor are similarly split along those axes,
and note,
it doesn't take too much clicking for you to begin to appreciate just
how much power you have over a system in Group Policy.
So there is plenty of training in the Pluralsight library if
you're interested in learning more about it, but I think that we'll call this demo done for now.