In this demonstration,
we'll focus on the Windows 10 desktop environment specifically the Start menu,
the taskbar, and the notifications area.
You can open the Start menu in a number of different ways,
of course, left-clicking it with the mouse,
you can also press the Start button on your keyboard,
that's the button a couple to the left of your Space
bar that looks like the Windows flag.
Now I showed you a screenshot of this so I don't
need to give a full explanation.
I'll just get right to some of the useful shortcuts.
Notice that we can expand or contract the left side of the Start menu
that gives you access to your user account settings.
If you click your user account, you can change your settings,
lock the computer, or sign out potentially as a different user.
We have File Explorer which we'll look at shortly,
Settings we cover in the next module, and then Power allows you to sleep,
shutdown, or restart the system.
I'm going to collapse that left side.
The middle part gives you a scrollable list that's alphabetized
that has all of your different programs in it.
Now there is different things you can do with these programs.
What do I mean by that?
Well I'd like to encourage you that I know I'm going to eventually
sound like a broken record album saying this,
but I want to encourage you to get into the habit of
right-clicking everything in Windows 10 because you're going to
find that there is almost always a context sensitive shortcut menu
from which you can do advanced options.
So Google Chrome, if this is something that I use a lot,
I may want to pin it to start and notice that when I pin it to start,
it shows up on the third side,
the right side of our apps which give you your tiles.
Now sometimes I'll post static icons like Chrome,
but things really light up once you get into more
dynamic applications like weather, for instance.
Now you probably think well what just happened there Tim.
Now let me start over again.
Press the Windows flag and just simply start to type.
I find that I very rarely have to scroll through those programs.
If I know any part of the name,
I can simply start to type and I'm off and running.
If I right-click Weather, I can pin it to the Start menu,
I can pin it to the taskbar, and then there is some social media options,
and I can even uninstall it.
Well I'm going to pin it to Start, and then if I reopen the Start menu,
I now have the weather icon.
Now I need to actually, let me right-click,
you can resize it into different sizes, right-click again,
go to More, Turn Live Tile on.
Ah-ha, once again,
this is something that you may not get to if you don't have
the habit of right-clicking on everything.
If I turn it on,
then it's going to actually try to connect to the
internet and display the weather.
Now I'm going to left-click to open the application
because I haven't actually set it yet.
I'm going to set it where I live in Nashville,
Tennessee and click Start, and here is my current temperature.
Yes, it's November and it's 61 and sunny,
and yes, I've very grateful for that, thank you very much.
We close that application and come back to Start and there we go.
So this is a good example of the live tile and notice that you can group these.
Now notice if you hover above a live tile,
you can create a group and actually place multiple tiles in that group.
You see that I've gotten rid of the other tiles that I have on this screen,
once again, you can do that by right-clicking and selecting Unpin from Start.
If you're wondering how to get to Start menu options,
it's as easy as opening settings.
I'll come back down to the lower left corner of the Start
menu and open the settings application.
In the Find a setting, I'll type Start menu and press Enter.
This gives us a whole bunch of specific options,
choosing which folders appear on Start, whether you want to do the full screen,
Start, I mentioned that to you earlier actually.
I'll go to Start settings and let's see if there's anything that jumps out.
Well like I said,
here's Use Start full screen and the other ones look like just
whether you want to show the apps list on or off,
if you want recently added apps to be highlighted,
if you want recently opened items in jump lists on the start or on the taskbar.
Speaking of which, this preference pane for Start is pretty handy,
it's part of the personalization settings group and you'll notice that
you can adjust things like the desktop background,
the color scheme, what you have on the Lock screen,
Start, and then of course, there's Taskbar.
Taskbar has options like whether you want to hide the taskbar,
I've never been a fan of that honestly.
You notice that there is separate options for hiding the
taskbar in desktop or tablet mode.
We'll talk about continuum a little later on in the course.
That's where if you're using a two-in-one device like a Surface Pro tablet,
you can get a slightly different UI depending upon
whether the keyboard is attached or not.
Now notice this,
it says replace command prompt with Windows PowerShell in the menu when I
right-click the Start button or press Windows key+X.
That's a pretty useful preference come to think of it and I'm glad that
reminded me of it because this is definitely a power user thing.
It's one thing to open the honest-to-goodness Start menu,
I'll do that occasionally if I can't remember a program's name
or if I'm not sure the program is installed.
Oftentimes, as I said before,
I'll use the Windows key and just start to type to get answers,
and you'll notice that those results come back not only with local resources,
but sometimes resources in the Windows store or on the web.
But anyway,
where I was going with this suggestion was right-clicking the Start menu,
this is really cool.
This is what I call the Power User's Start menu and it gives you one-click
access to all of your most important administrative options.
We'll be getting into a lot of these administrative tools like Event Viewer,
System, Power Options as we go along,
but this is just a gradual unfolding and I don't want to overwhelm us too early.
Some of you who have worked with earlier versions of
Windows wonders where the old Run box went.
Notice that you can get to it, like I said,
by right-clicking the Start button and selecting R.
This is useful if you want to open up a command if you know its name,
for instance, like ncpa.
cpl is a file name that I'll always remember.
That's a shortcut way to open up the network
connections available on that computer.
Now the keyboard shortcut is Windows key+X.
Windows key+X will give you this and it also has the ability to sign out, sleep, shut down, or restart, so that's a useful tip like I said.