Let me right-click my PowerShell icon and choose Run as Administrator.
I want to open an elevated PowerShell prompt.
Now although this is PowerShell, and not the CMD environment,
we still can use certain old-school executables with no problem.
So, for instance, we can use ipconfig with no other options,
and it gives you brief results for each of your interfaces.
I want to pay particular attention to my internal one,
which is my business network, and we see that we have the IPv4 static assignment,
and a subnet address, and its default gateway,
but we're not able to see additional addresses that might be relevant,
specifically, is this machine a member of an Active Directory domain?
Can we communicate with the Domain Name System,
or DNS server, you see what I mean?
So let me clear the screen with cls,
up arrow twice to bring back the ipconfig command,
and I'm going to do /all.
And this gives a lot more information.
So let's go back to Internal, and see if there's anything more here.
While we have our DNS server, that's true,
if we were using DHCP, we would have a separate entry for DHCP.
Here it has some DHCPv6.
That's because IPv6 will auto-generate unique addresses.
It functions much differently with DHCP than how IPv4 does.
As a matter of fact, let me scroll down to my public interface,
and that has what I'm talking about here.
We have multiple DNS servers two of them using IPv6,
that's what the 2001:558 business is, and we have an IPv4 DHCP Server,
and it looks like we also have a Default Gateway
that's using both IPv6 and IPv4.
It's actually good to see so much IPv6 here,
because it truly is the way that the internet,
and even local area connectivity is going to go.
It's going to be many years since we have IPv6 only.
We're going to be running in what's called a dual stack
configuration for the foreseeable future,
but I'm pretty proud of my internet service provider,
Comcast, because they've definitely embraced IPv6 quite robustly indeed.
Now, let me cls again to clear the screen, and try some commands, like hostname.
If this were a member of a domain, I could see that.
Actually another command that's useful for testing domain membership is whoami.
Now you notice the syntax here,
it's going to be computer or domain name backslash the username.
Hostname tells me that this machine is called devbox.
Devox\tim means that I'm logged on as a local user,
and I'm not a member of a domain.
Of course, I can always verify that by looking at the System Control Panel.
Let me type control to open the classic Control Panel.
You notice that I'm studiously avoiding that Settings app.
Let me go to System, here we go, and we can see right here under Computer name,
domain, and Workgroup settings, that we're in a workgroup,
we're in a non-domain environment.
If we want to change that, we can use User Account control to do so.
We can go to Change here, not only to edit the computer name,
but also, as I said, to join a domain, and my domain is called company.
pri.
And assuming that you have DNS connectivity to the
domain and everything goes right,
we're prompted for an account that has the permission to join the domain.
And in some environments, very few I've worked with,
users have that ability to rejoin their computer to the domain,
but that requires more tech skills than I would consider many end users to have.
Let me authenticate with domain admin credentials.
The network path was not found.
That's a weird error.
Well, let's do some live troubleshooting together.
Let's come back here and let me do a ping -4.
That ensures that we're going to use IPv4.
The name of my domain controller is dc1.
Now ipconfig has a lot of other things involved,
that is,
you can do things like releasing and renewing your
IP address if you're using DHCP.
You can also flush your DNS Cache.
DNS, if you don't know, I would assume you know,
but if you don't,
Domain Name System is simply a directory of hostnames and IP addresses
so that you can communicate with other machines using hostnames rather
than having to know and type IP addresses.
But look here, you can re-register yourself with DNS.
Let me do that.
Ipconfig registerdns, it'll take a moment to do this,
my DNS server is my dc1 domain controller,
by the way, and so now let me do a ping -4,
but this time let me try the fully-qualified name of that server,
dc1.
company.
pri.
Well, I have connectivity thanks to ping.
Ping, in Windows anyway,
sends out four internet control message protocol ICMP echoes,
echo requests, and the idea is that number one,
you want to get four replies back, that's the first thing,
and the second thing is you want to look at the time.
I have a super-duper fast connection to dc1 because the
response time is less than 1 millisecond,
so it's certainly not a question of latency.
Let's try this again.
I'll authenticate.
This time I'm going to do company, I'm going to choose a different account.
I guess the second or third time is the charm,
this is what we want to see, Welcome to the company.
pri domain,
and we're going to have to restart in order to put this into practice.
Alternatively, let me bring up PowerShell one more time,
we could use Add-Computer.
Let me run get-help against Add-Computer,
not Get-Computer, and look at examples.
Programmatically, this is the way to go.
And the tersest, if that's a word, command would be this one,
Add-Computer to the specified DomainName,
Restart.
When you run that, you'll get the authentication prompt,
and then the Restart flag will automatically restart
after you've joined to the domain, but I'm going to choose Restart now,
and then I'll show you the logon and we'll call this demo finished.
Here we are at our logon screen, and I want to come down to Other user,
because I'm not using my local account anymore.
That can be a point of confusion among many now.
This Tim Warner account you see here is a local machine on this devbox machine.
No, we want to go to Other user, and it defaults to Sign in to: COMPANY.
Now you can override that, for instance.
Let's say, for instance, I still wanted to log onto the local computer,
I would have to know the computer's name,
and it's devbox, it's devbox1.
And if I do devbox1\,
notice that it now says sign onto DEVBOX1 and I
could specify a local credential.
Otherwise, if I'm domain-joined it's going to go to the domain by default,
so I'm going to authenticate with my trainer account, and here we go, I've got myself a desktop.