Windows Defender.
First, a history lesson.
Microsoft and Antimalware Antivirus.
There's a lot of good history here,
and if you're relatively new to IT you'll want to pay attention.
Microsoft bought a company in 2004 called GIANT Antispyware,
and I was pleased with that because at that time I was using GIANT Antispyware,
and I thought it was a fantastic tool.
Around that time, in the early 2000's,
there was a proliferation of adware and spyware,
just people trying to get paid by tricking you into visiting
websites where you'd see a cascade of pop-up windows,
and each pop-up advertisement is going to wind up ca-ching,
ca-ching, giving somebody a few pennies.
You see what I mean?
And the idea that software could be hijacked with
components that phone home from your system,
in other words, they silently in the background,
sometimes using a service, a Windows service like we talked about earlier,
to go out from your computer without your consent.
You see, that's the big problem with malware, with malicious software.
It's code that executes without your explicit consent.
So anyway, Microsoft bought GIANT,
and initially they rebranded it as Microsoft Antispyware,
then it became for a while Microsoft Security Essentials,
and now we know it as Microsoft Windows Defender,
and it used to be that you'd have to install it yourself.
I remember a standard part of my builds when I worked in industry around
the time that Security Essentials were released we'd want to make sure as
part of our preparation process to install that.
You might ask, well,
is there an advantage to using a Microsoft
antimalware as opposed to a third-party?
All I can say is that in my professional experience I haven't had to use
another antimalware on the systems that I've managed over time.
The Microsoft one is fantastic.
So now, as I said, we have Windows Defender,
and it's actually built-in to Windows 10.
You don't have to do anything about it.
It's already there.
Endpoint Protection.
That is a potential point of confusion.
We've referenced the Microsoft System Center line of datacenter management
products a few times over the course of this course.
In there you have System Center Configuration Manager,
and one of the many things that the System Center Tools
can do is centralize antimalware,
and the client that you can deploy through System
Center is called Endpoint Protection, but it's essentially just Windows Defender,
and as I said,
nowadays in Windows 10 you already have the bits installed on the machine,
so you really don't need to do a separate
installation unless you really want to.
Going further,
Windows 10 Defender bits can function just fine on their own on a one-by-one,
each computer is an island unto itself basis,
or you can centralize using Windows Defender Advanced Threat Protection or ATP.
Now this is a cloud service that's part of Microsoft's Office 365 portfolio,
and what happens is you onboard your Windows 10 clients
and point them to your ATP instance,
and the ATP is able to generate a lot of behavioral analysis based
on what your users are doing on their systems,
and you can get a much more tailored, personalized antimalware strategy going.
Windows Defender Features.
Well, you have the antivirus component.
I like to use the term antimalware because you may know that a virus
is just one of several types of malicious software.
Adware, spyware, junkware, crapware, all of those are synonymous terms.
There's viruses, worms, Trojan horses.
The antivirus engine in Defender hits all of those
pieces with real-time protection, so yes,
we're working with a service running in the background.
You can control Windows Defender through the Security Center,
and I'll show you that in the next demo actually.
The Windows Defender Security Center was added in the Windows 10 1703 update,
and remember, 1703 means March of 2017, and it was expanded in the 1709 update,
that's September 2017,
such that the Security Center will actually work with
third-party antivirus and firewall apps.
You can control the Defender with PowerShell,
Group Policy, or Microsoft Intune, and of course,
there's ATP, Advanced Threat Protection.
There's System Center Endpoint Protection, as I mentioned in a previous slide.
The Security Center is a roll up.
It used to be the Windows Security Center.
If you remember in 8.
1 and Windows 7 there was the Action Center,
and the Security Center,
and now we have the Windows Defender Security Center that's
a conflation of those different tools.
Windows Defender was the name of the antimalware.
Security Center was meant to be a one-stop shop for
firewall settings and so forth, and then Action Center is a notification hub.
You have all of that stuff build in to this GUI called
the Windows Defender Security Center. It's a pretty nifty tool actually.