In this demonstration, we'll work with network printing,
and I'm going to do the back-end work here in Windows Server 2016.
Now the Print Management app is available on Windows 10, you can install it.
In fact,
you can get all of the Windows Server 2016 management
tools on the client by downloading what's called the
Remote Server Administration Tools, or RSAT tools,
but I'm going to do this natively on my Windows Server machine.
I'm going to open Start and type print management,
and you can see right here, Print Management Desktop app.
It's an old school Microsoft Management console,
and you'll notice it has some sections here.
We've got Print Management, and if we right-click this,
we can go to Add/Remove Servers.
Now dc1 is my local box.
The idea here is that you can actually load in all of your
organizational print server devices,
these would be Windows Server machines that are hosting
at least one network print queue, and manage them all in a single interface.
The Print Management console is a must-use utility if you're
doing network printing in a Windows context,
in particular in the context of an Active Directory domain.
The filters are useful when you have a lot of print
servers and a lot of printers, you can create custom view filters,
but I just have a single print server,
so I'm going to open it up and you can see there
are separate buckets for drivers, forms,
which are essentially paper types,
paper sizes that are supported by those printers.
The drivers is going to be for any print devices
that are installed on this system.
It gives you the specific driver version,
it doesn't tell you type 4 necessarily.
Then we have printers,
and on this server I just have the Microsoft Print to
PDF and the XPS Document Writer.
I'm going to create a synthetic, or fake,
printer by right-clicking here and choosing Add Printer.
We can either search the network or add what's called a TCP/IP port.
That's what I'm going to do.
This is going to be a TCP-based printer,
its IP address is going to be,
I'm not even sure what this machine's IP address is.
Let me open an elevated PowerShell console really quickly and type ipconfig, 10.
0.
1.
So my fake printer will be 10.
0.
100,
and I'm going to deselect Auto detect because there is no
printer that's on the network at that IP address.
Now what it would have in the real world,
or what I would have I should say,
is that I would have the device out plugged into a
switch and available on the network,
and I would ensure that it gets this IP address,
either by statically assigning it on the printer using
the printer's physical interface,
or I could create what's called an IP address reservation on my DHCP server,
Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol.
It stills tries to detect, even if you tell it not to,
and of course it's going to fail.
Of course it wasn't able to find that device,
so we can override it by specifying a particular standalone
Print Server or just a Generic Network Card.
Next, we're asked to identify a printer driver,
and the only option that's available in this case is to install a new driver,
and we'll do so manually.
This dialog's been around for a long, long time.
Now you'll notice that these are generic Class Drivers.
It says so right in the definition.
If you check the exercise files,
I point you out to some documentation where you can store
manufacturer's device-specific drivers in the driver store
where Windows can get to them.
But in this case, I'm just going to choose, at random, a Color LaserJet.
If you have a device driver already on your server,
that's what the Have Disk option is all about.
And again, that dialog box is so old it's amazing that it's still around.
I'm going to call this laserjet1,
and you can actually share it directly from here,
which I'll do, Laserjet1, and I'll say Second floor lobby,
click Next, and then Next, and of course we can't print a test page,
so I'll leave that alone, and we'll click Finish.
So now we have a new shared printer here.
What can we do with it?
Well if we right-click that printer we can look at its queue,
same dialog we looked at in the previous demo.
We can manage sharing,
which will bring you to the Sharing tab of its Properties sheet,
but if you want to get specific,
you'll want to go to the Security tab and set NTFS-level permissions.
Notice that these permissions are different from
what we saw with files and folders, and that's as it should be.
You've got Print, that's the baseline permission,
Mange this printer, Manage the document queue,
or Special permissions.
Your ordinary users should always have just Print.
If there's a brave soul who volunteers to manage the printer,
the print queue, that's awesome.
You can him, or her, or their group and allow for that permission as well.
Now as far as deployment goes, check this out.
You can directly from Print Management, Deploy with Group Policy.
Now I'm not going to step through this whole wizard because we
haven't formally treated the subject of Group Policy,
but suffice to say,
this wizard will allow you to either create an existing Group Policy Object,
or GPO, that includes this printer definition in it,
or you could add it to an existing GPO,
and then scope the Group Policy to hit only the users and
computers that need access to that printer.
Isn't that convenient?
During the next GPO refresh for your users,
which normally be within 90 minutes,
they'll receive a new printer in their printer
folder of this network print queue.
Just easy peasy.
Now if you do need to manually intervene,
what we can do on the client side is again open up that printer's wizard again,
Printers and scanners, and go to The printer that I want isn't listed,
this is just one of several ways to do it,
please understand that, and we can Select a shared printer by name,
\dc1, and then it actually fills in the print queues through auto complete.
I'll just choose laserjet1 from the list, click Next, it's going to connect.
Now depending upon what type driver this is,
if it's type 3 or type 4, we'll either be downloading the driver from the server,
or just installing it locally from this computer's driver store,
or potentially through Windows Update, and this is a class driver actually.
I just saw a notice of that.
So now I have this connection to this shared printer.
I shouldn't be able to manage it unless I'm an administrator.
Come to think of it, my currently logged-on user,
who is, expand the Start menu here, trainer,
is in fact a domain administrator.
So I do have full permissions on this network printer.
And if I wanted to remove the connection,
I can simply click Remove device, and without any confirmation, it's gone.