Finally, we have Windows Mobility Center.
The historical perspective here is around 2006 or so,
Microsoft gave us the Vista operating system and there were
quite a few advancements in that version,
one of which was the Windows Mobility Center.
By this time, in information technology,
Microsoft saw that many of their customers were beginning to rely upon their
laptop computers for business use or even not for business use,
maybe just for every day use out and about in different environments.
So what Microsoft has done is give us this tool
that looks like a bunch of tiles, doesn't it,
in fact, this one shows six tiles with room for two more.
This is actually an extensible application and you may find
that your original equipment manufacturer,
OEM, for instance, if it's a Dell laptop or an HP laptop,
they may have extra items tucked into mobility center,
so it's going to depend upon the make and model of your
PC and how Windows 10 was installed.
The mobility center options really haven't changed all that much all the
way up to Windows 10 as you'll see in the next demo,
but basically, you can mute the volume very easily and quickly,
you can check your battery status and change your power profile,
this can be useful if you have to be on the battery for a while.
You can adjust your Wi-Fi connectivity,
you can connect to an external display and work with a projector,
now that's something I do all the time being a trainer.
And then Sync Center is an opportunity for you to force a sync if
you're using a feature called offline files.
Offline files is a business-oriented feature where you can take
files that you normally access across the network and have copies of
them available locally on your laptop that you can access even when
you're away from your business.
Now what if you don't have a laptop,
but you still want to use that Mobility Center because it
does have some pretty cool options, the ability to easily mute the volume,
for instance.
The bottom line is that Registry that we've been dealing with stores a
whole lot of data about your computer including a sub repository called
the common information model or SIM repository.
That's also sometimes called Windows Management Instrumentation,
or WMI repo, but all we need to know about that,
SIM or WMI,
is that Windows can tell whether you're running on a desktop or a
laptop computer based on that SIM repository data,
and if Windows detects that you're on a laptop,
you'll get Mobility Center.
If Windows detects that you're on a desktop computer,
you won't, but we can tap in to the Registry,
specifically going into HKey Current User,
Software, Microsoft, Mobile PC Mobility Center.
We may need to create one or more of those subkeys,
by the way, for instance,
you might not have a mobile PC or a Mobility Center
subkey so you would add those, one inside the other,
and then inside the Mobility Center subkey,
you would create a new D word or double word value called run on desktop.
Now when you're creating new values in the Registry,
you're going to want to watch your case,
your upper and lowercase, and you're definitely going to watch spaces,
there is no spaces here, and you want to get the data type correct as well.
And then depending upon whether you have the value either deleted,
which is disabled, or if you set it to one,
that would enable Windows Mobility Center even on a desktop computer. There you have it, some Registry work in action.