In this demo we're going to take a look at the Windows Defender Security Center,
which is really a roll up of a whole lot of Defender antimalware features,
and because I didn't show you the SmartScreen filter in the previous module,
or it might have been the module before,
I thought that it was more appropriate to place that demo here,
okay?
So what we have in the notification area,
if we hover over the shield it has a little x on my system,
and it says, Actions needed.
As I said, I clicked that by the way,
that opens the Windows Defender Security Center,
and so this consolidates the functions of the old Action Center and the old
Security Center interfaces into a single unified interface.
We have Your device is being protected.
Now if you were to disable or if you had malware
infecting your system that turned off, say,
virus and threat protection, this would turn into a warning.
We also see metadata on the last time a definition update took place,
when a last threat scan or health scan took place on this machine.
Just like we say in systems administration that a good backup is only
as good as its ability to be successfully restored,
Antimalware Scanner is only as good as the recency that it's been updated,
so make sure that you have your system configured to update,
and I'm going to expand the left hand menu that allows us to go through
the five components of the Defender Security Center.
There's virus and threat protection,
from which you can start a quick or advanced scan,
and then there's some additional metadata.
Device performance and health.
This is going to give us issues related to Windows Update,
okay, it looks like we must have updates that need application,
Storage capacity, and Device drivers.
So that's what Device performance and health is.
Firewall and network protection gives you some metadata on your
firewall based on your location profiles,
as well as which one is active.
I am joined to an Active Directory domain,
which is why the domain profile takes precedence,
and you have some additional links down here.
App and browser control is where you can turn on or
turn off the SmartScreen filter.
You see Check apps and files,
Windows Defender SmartScreen helps protect your device by checking
for unrecognized apps and files from the web.
Remember that this SmartScreen filter does a hash
calculation on your apps and files,
compares them to online copies in its threat intelligence database,
and let's you know if there's a disparity.
SmartScreen, whether you want it --- how you want it to behave in Edge to Block,
Warn, or Off.
Warn is the default setting.
SmartScreen is also integrated in the Windows Store,
and it could be set to Warn or Off,
and then there's a whole lot of exploit protections.
Now if you already have experience in Windows,
if you're already a power user, you might remember the EMET tool,
E-M-E-T.
This was a tool that Microsoft made, free tool,
free download, that contained remediations for specific,
I'm not going to say Edge case vulnerabilities,
but problems with certain applications,
like Adobe Acrobat that could present security problems,
Adobe Flash.
Here we have a lot of that stuff build in to the Exploit protection.
There's System settings and Program settings.
It really gets beyond our scope because that gets more
into the enterprise control stuff, and then we have some information,
some options regarding family settings.
We're working with business in this course,
so we won't work with that either,
but you'll notice that it's not obvious how to turn off virus
and threat protection through this interface.
There is a hyperlink for virus and threat protection settings,
and here you can, in fact, toggle from on to off,
but you want to be very careful with that.
You may think, well I'm a private person,
and I don't want sample files sent to Microsoft,
even though that will help them.
Notice that that's a User Account Control protected action.
I'm going to choose No here and leave that on.
You could add exclusions files that you don't want to be included in a scan.
That's all typical bread and butter stuff that you
see in any antimalware scanner,
and then what kind of notification robustness you want to see.
A lot of those notifications will be pop-ups in the
notification area or we have the notifications panel,
which is really quite helpful.
If you remember Windows 8, for instance,
they had what was called the charms bar that was somewhat similar to
this in terms of you could get to your settings and,
you know, some other utility type commands,
but it was difficult to invoke.
It involved hovering over a certain part of the screen.
It was quite awful.
Now you have this notifications balloon that you can bring back,
and do a lot of cool things,
not the least of which get to your Settings and Network Preferences very conveniently.