Now let's fire up PowerShell.
I'm going to open up the PowerShell ISE,
and I'm going to right-click this and go to Run as Administrator.
This is a built-in utility for running PowerShell interactively,
but also for creating scripts.
So I'm going to create a script.
I'll save it on my D drive here.
I'll just type D: and press Enter, and I'll call this module17.
What I wanted to do is walk you through some of these networking cmdlets.
Let me do a cd \ to go to the root of Drive C, and cls to clear the screen.
Let's see what happens if we run Get-NetIPConfiguration.
What kind of output do we see back?
Well it looks like for each connection we have the alias,
which is the friendly name, right here, we have a unique index number.
It's basically a lot of the ipconfig info with some hardware stuff thrown in.
You might wonder, well, isn't it just as easy to do ipconfig?
Well, in a way, but if you needed to, for instance,
gather these statistics for a number of computers,
Windows 10, could be Windows 8.
1, could be Windows Server, it's a lot easier to do that with Windows PowerShell.
Just for grins, let me try this.
We're on Windows 10, the administrative workstation, right?
I'm going to do Invoke-Command -ComputerName dc1.
Alright, so let me walk you through this code,
let me put it on its own line here.
Invoke-Command is one command we use in PowerShell to send a PowerShell
command or an entire script to one or more remote machines.
So what I'm saying here is invoke a PowerShell command on my dc1 server,
and in this case,
I'm just going to pass raw PowerShell as what's called a ScriptBlock,
and that ScriptBlock is placed within curly braces.
I'm just going to pass Get-NetIPConfiguration.
Now there's the question of credentials.
I'm logged onto this machine as a domain administrator,
so I should be okay, and it looks like I am.
So it looks like that server has only an external and an internal,
and its internal IP address is 10.
0.
1.
Let me go over to that server, and let me bring up Run and do ncpa.
cpl.
Here is our Internal and External.
We'll go Internal, Details, 10.
0.
1, so that was right on the money, wasn't it?
That is called PowerShell remoting, and we could have n number of computers,
or we could pass in a file containing a list of computers and
send that command across all those machines.
I hope that shows you a little bit about how powerful PowerShell is.
What we're doing on line 4 is looking for NetIPAddresses,
let me clear the screen in the console,
and then we can get all of that information back and
sort it according to properties.
So we're going to sort on InterfaceIndex number,
and we want the data to be formatted as a table and have the following columns.
Now what's cool about these properties is that they get automagically filled in.
Notice I'm pressing Tab here.
One of the things that the ISE does that you sometimes,
well most of the time you get in the ordinary PowerShell console,
is auto-completion, so you don't have to know,
necessarily, the specific names and spellings of those properties,
some of which can be kind of arcane.
So let's put our cursor there,
and it instantly gives us back a table based on InterfaceIndex,
the alias name, the AddressFamily, and the IPAddress.
And it's showing both IPv6 and IPv4 addresses,
so we have multiple entries per adapter.
Now what I've done in the next bit of code here,
let me put some space between these commands,
is Get-NetIPAddress is where the AddressFamily is IPv4,
and format that table in such a way that all of the columns are
auto-sized to accommodate the largest entry beneath them.
So I'll select this.
And it says we're missing a curly brace,
well that makes sense,
our Where-Object expression needs to be enclosed in curly braces,
there we go.
And so here we have, like I said,
actually let's just click this Hide Script Pane and look at all of the results.
Wow, it's going through each one that has an AddressFamily of IPv4,
and because I'm just doing Format-Table -AutoSize,
it's showing all other information.
I actually want to customize this output to make it easier to see.
That's one of the fine skills that you'll develop after
you hit your initial PowerShell learning curve of just
understanding the basic syntax.
Your first challenge is to figure out which cmdlet or
pipeline gives you the results you want,
and then your next challenge is to format that result set in such
a way that you can quickly isolate what you need and not see the
information that you don't need, signal to noise ratio, in other words.