In this final demo of the module, I want to work with Windows Mobility Center.
Now I happen to know just obviously and intuitively that this
virtual machine is considered a desktop machine.
I can test that actually by right-clicking the Start button,
going to Run, and trying to start the Mobility Center executable,
which for trivia's sake is mblctr.
exe, and it says Windows Mobility Center is available only on laptops,
but we know that we can override that.
This is going to give us a chance to practice the
Registry and also to work with websites.
This is a well-known site, vistasx64.
com.
I link to this page in the exercise files.
And a site like this is intended,
their goal is to make it easier for you to implement a
Registry change by giving you the Reg file.
So here, it allows us to Enable_Desktop_WMC.
zip.
So I'm downloading this zip file and I'm going to extract it to my desktop,
but I'm not going to double left-click it.
We want to be really careful.
Scan the file with your antimalware tool.
I'm going to right-click and go to Open with Notepad,
again, I have to be an administrator to do this,
and this will tell you exactly what it's going to do and it
looks like it's going to add some paths.
If we don't have a mobile PC folder under HKEY_CURRENT_USER\Software\Microsoft,
it will add one,
and it's going to add a value called SkipBatteryCheck with a value of 1 and that
makes sense that we would need to disable the batteryCheck because a battery is
only going to be relevant for a laptop computer,
and then we're adding a value called RunOnDesktop 1,
which means true, which means enable.
So I'm actually okay with merging this.
Again,
have to be an administrator and we have to go through the
process of confirming that we want to do that.
Now I'm imagining we have to restart.
We shouldn't be able to start the executable directly.
Oh, we sure were.
Great!
Well, it's one of those things, sometimes you have to log off,
sometimes you have to restart, sometimes it just works.
In this case, it just works.
So what do we have here.
Well there is no battery option, of course, as we said earlier.
We can adjust display, brightness, there is not much we can do.
There is presentation, turn on or turn off.
It's kind of limited because some of these options really
are geared toward a laptop computer.
And then there is sync settings,
which I said before provide a way for you to synchronize with network
files that are configured for offline access and it looks like Sync Center is in fact part of the classic Control Panel.