We'll finish with special-purpose printing.
Now when I first got into the industry,
the concept of print to file was something that you never wanted to mess with.
What you're doing here is instead of printing to a
local or network-based printer, you're creating a more intermediary format,
a PRN file, a spool file basically, that you can then,
at least in theory, bring to another device.
Maybe you're on a computer and you're having connection problems
actually getting the network print job to work,
you could print out to a PRN,
bring the PRN to another machine that does have a valid
connection to that network printer,
and then feed that PRN file directly to the printer.
Very clunky actually.
Nowadays in the 21st century when we talk about print to file,
it's almost always taking a print job and producing an
Adobe Acrobat Portable Document Format, or PDF file.
And Windows 10, finally at long last, has the capability in the print dialog,
the System Print dialog box, to do a print to PDF.
There was a while there for a few years where Microsoft tried to compete
with PDF by developing their own document specification,
the XPS format if you've ever heard of that,
but I think everybody understands now that PDF is a very universal,
and works perfectly fine, as a universal output format.
Now if you don't like the Windows PDF printer,
Adobe Acrobat, if you install that on a system,
it will have its own software printer, and as you would expect,
it's very much the difference between a class
driver and a device specific driver.
The Windows 10 built-in PDF driver is very basic and bare bones,
that's analogous to a class driver.
If you install Adobe Acrobat and use their PDF printer,
that's going to have all sorts of rendering options that's
tailored specifically to the Adobe PDF format.
Internet printing,
yet again this is a case where several years ago it
was just basically a novelty.
The idea of using the Internet Printing Protocol,
IPP, along with the Hypertext Transfer Protocol,
HTTP or HTTPS, to print to a remote printer that could be on your LAN,
could be at another branch office, or could be across the internet.
You could be on vacation, for instance,
and submit a print job from where you are on one side of the world,
and have it come out on a print device back at your
office on the other side of the world.
Now why would you want to do that is one question?
Well, there's some reasons,
enough to where I want to tell you that the internet printing protocol
does require some special firewall configuration.
The default port that it uses is TCP 631,
that's ordinarily blocked on any firewall worth its salt.
So in order to do internet printing,
you have to identify the use case and is this important enough
to where you want to expand your home or business network's
attack surface just a little bit.
In general practice,
IPP may be useful because instead of doing network discovery
where you're clicking through the network control panel in
Windows 10 trying to search for a printer,
you can simply run the Add Printer wizard and provide an
HTTP path to a shared print queue.
And because you're specifying HTTP or HTTPS,
Windows 10 has the internet printing protocol driver already installed,
and it can, again, be a nice convenience for setting up printers.
There's some other ways to do internet printing if you've ever
heard of Google Cloud Print or Apple AirPrint,
these are methods for,
as long as your printer supports either or both of those technologies,
to make it easier to print.
I've used those, for instance,
to print something from my phone wirelessly to the
Inkjet printer that we have at our home.
If you're using a VPN connection to your corporate
network when you're working remotely,
you're essentially at the corporate network from the perspective of the network,
so you can just do a regular print there. You don't have to worry about IPP.