Offline Files.
The Offline Files use case is a user takes her work laptop home and
wants to continue working network-based files,
and let me say, in the absence of a virtual private network,
or VPN connection.
Is this possible?
Well, sure.
Offline Files has been around for a long, long time.
It relies upon caching.
A user connects through, say, a mapped drive letter to network-based files.
He or she goes home and can still get in work on those files when
they're not connected to the corporate network.
When they plug into the corporate network the next day,
a synchronization takes place, the server copies are updated,
and you're back in business.
That's the general use case for Offline Files.
It's meant to be a convenient method to access network-based
resources when you're not in the network.
And I'm going to explain the rest of it through a demo.
In this brief demo,
I want to show you how Offline Files work in Windows Server 2016 and Windows 10.
We're on a Windows Server 2016 server here,
and I've created a folder called reports that
contains a bunch of sample text files.
And I've already shared this resource out on the network.
Let me right-click the folder, go to Properties,
go to Sharing, go to Advanced Sharing, go to Caching,
I know it's a lot of clicking,
but this brings you to the Offline Settings dialog.
And you see, by default,
only the files and programs that users specify are available offline.
And in my experience in the business world, that almost never happens.
Users have no idea what offline files are, and they don't care.
But if you want to allow this capability,
you can choose All files and programs that users open from the
shared folder are automatically available offline,
and you can optimize that cache for performance.
So you selectively enable offline files on the server,
and then on the client, let's switch over to my Windows 10 client,
we can just do a search for offline files.
And that's not bringing us anywhere.
How about if we do Cortana?
That does give us a match here for Manage,
I should say, offline files in Control Panel.
Okay, so this takes us to the old school Control Panel.
You can enable or disable offline files here.
Then you can open a tool called Sync Center that we'll take a look at.
I'll open it right now and then minimize it just to keep it down there,
and then you can view your offline files cache.
Cool.
So I'm all ready now as a user.
We can pretend that, say, I'm a laptop user, and I'm connecting to the network.
Now how do you do that?
Well,
one fast way as an administrator is to use what's
called universal naming convention, or UNC paths.
Once again, I'll right-click Start, go to Run.
Instead of a drive letter, we can do \\,
and then if we know the name of the server,
which I do, dc1, I'll type that.
I'm in a domain,
so I can establish a connection to shared resources that I have access to,
and I do have access to this reports share.
I can open these files directly from here and work on them all day long.
I opened up that one.
I opened up this one, fine,
or I could make the folder available on my system to show up as a drive letter.
That's what's called a mapped network drive.
You see I have drive Z mapped to my vmware-host.
Then I have my local drives that we've been working with thus far.
Let me step back in File Explorer a couple steps.
We right-click the shared folder.
We can come down to Map network drive.
You can choose a drive letter.
If this folder's called reports, why don't I see if I can get drive R.
Yep, I can.
Reconnect at sign-in, connect using different credentials.
Nope, this is fine, so I'll click Finish.
And now I have this resource permanently mapped as drive R,
and I can get to I all day long in that way from this PC.
Here it is, see?
Now I've opened a couple of those files.
Let me open one more for good measure.
I don't know why I'm having a problem opening up a doc file here,
but anyway, let me open this Series Guidelines one more time,
okay.
So I've done some file opening, and let's cut the connection to the network,
and let's look at our offline cache.
Certainly, if we're not connected to the network,
we're not going to have access to that hard drive anymore.
This is going to involve some user training by the way.
If we open the Offline Files Control Panel,
View your offline files, we can see that I have trainer,
we can see Mapped network Drives, we have Offline Files Folder,
and we can browse into Computers, dc1, reports,
and then here are some of the files that I opened.
Anything I do to these files offline,
those changes are going to be synced back to the server
when I'm reconnected to the domain.
Windows 10 includes a new tool called Sync Center.
It's available only, unfortunately, through the classic Control Panel,
as you see here, Sync Center.
And we have what's called a sync partnership happening.
The purpose of Sync Center is to give the user,
the end user, and potentially the administrator or the help desk person,
whomever, some more visibility in what's happening.
For instance, it says network files available offline,
and you can force a synchronization event.
This is basically a troubleshooting step.
The synchronization should happen automatically,
but we can force a synchronization if we need to.
And this also is important from a troubleshooting standpoint because
what if you and your colleague have both worked with the same file
while you were disconnected from the network,
and you both attempted to sync at the same time?
You see what I mean?
This may be a case where an administrator may need
to be brought into the equation.
So that's a little bit on Offline Files and Sync Center.
The takeaway here is that you need to manage these
using the old school Control Panel, and this will, in all likelihood, involve some end user training to get this going.