This is where we get our user profiles,
and I'm holding down my control key while I'm mouse
rolling to get bigger icons here.
Each user of a system will get his or her own folder.
I'm logged on as Tim, so I'm going to go in the Tim folder.
By default,
only that user has permission and administrators have
permissions to the users folder.
You can always customize permissions, but that goes beyond our scope.
The idea here is that my personal settings here,
my preferences, my desktop wallpaper,
any custom sounds I've attached will show up here.
Certainly, my documents show up here, our searches get saved here,
my Start menu shortcuts, and of course,
you can add whatever you want yourself to your home folder.
Down below, we see a bunch of things called ntuser.
These deal with what's called the Windows Registry that
we'll learn more about in a little bit.
But for now, just suffice it to say that each user gets their own profile folder.
If multiple users are sharing a computer,
then they will not be able to access each other's folder
without an administrator granting special permissions and
that's to preserve privacy.
Note also that in a network environment where users
go from computer to computer,
I've found that's not as common nowadays as it used to be.
You can have your profiles also copied up to a network folder
location and they will be roamed with the user.
So if you log onto another computer at your business campus,
you'll download your settings from the server and they will be
populated in your C Users profile subfolder.
The final thing I want to mention here is how does Windows get the defaults,
like if I create a new user account now and log on as that person,
I'm going to see a default environment.
Well what happens is we have a special folder called default user and
notice that because I'm logged on as an ordinary user,
I get that access is denied message.
The default profile is the template that defines the
starting environment for all users.
Now that's useful for IT administrators because for businesses that
have policies where users need to see say the corporate desktop and
have their environment standardized,
then what the administrators will do is customize the
default profile and then any new user will pick up a copy of all of those settings by default.