Microsoft Edge.
Microsoft Edge is the default web browser in Windows 10.
In the Microsoft documentation, oftentimes,
they just refer to it as Edge, it's a marketing term more than anything else.
We contrast edge with what was previously the default browser for many,
many years, Internet Explorer.
This screenshot is from Internet Explorer v3 that shipped with
Windows 95 and if it looks kind of archaic,
that's because the web was pretty archaic back in those days.
I, myself, have used Internet Explorer since version 2,
so I've seen the product grow as the world wide web and internet
connectivity have grown over the past couple dozen years or so.
I think it's instructive to compare and contrast IE with Edge because
you're going to find that in Windows 10 IE still exists,
even though, officially, it's a deprecated web browser.
Internet Explorer 11 is the version that ships with Windows 10.
I don't believe we're ever going to see a 12 because as I said,
Microsoft has officially deprecated it.
Basically,
Internet Explorer 11 is included in Windows 10 for backward compatibility only.
As I said before, the browser has been around since the mid-90s,
whereas, Microsoft Edge is a brand-new project,
officially it was forked from Internet Explorer 11 and
basically what forked means is that you take the source
code from Internet Explorer 11, create a copy of that code base,
and then they rearchitected the browser from Scratch.
So Edge is not Internet Explorer 11+ so to speak,
it's a new browser that has minimal to do with or very little to do,
to use more correct English, with Internet Explorer 11,
other than it was originally forked from the project.
A web browser what has what's called a rendering or layout engine,
actually there is several engines that exist within a web browser,
but the one that handles most of your page rendering
and layout is called just that,
the rendering and layout engine and Trident is the code name for the layout
engine that's historically been in Internet Explorer.
EdgeHTML is a brand-new rendering and layout engine in Edge.
The idea here is that with 21st century internet and web standards becoming
truly standardized across different vendors and platforms,
EdgeHTML plays much better in the current web than Trident has.
For instance, this is a good example here.
Historically,
as the internet and the world wide web developed and we got
later and later versions of Internet Explorer,
Microsoft still took a rather proprietary tact in the way that you would
add or should I say developers would add functionality to Internet Explorer
and how web designers could add interactivity on their sites is to create
code objects using the ActiveX technology and these code objects are called
Browser Helper Objects, or BHOs.
These represent a big security problem because it is executable code that
gets downloaded to the user's computer and run locally.
And if you know much about information security,
you really want to control every bit of executable code
that executes on a user's system, so those are really not desirable.
Microsoft Edge actually does not support ActiveX Browser Helper Objects.
Instead,
Edge uses the same model that you see in other leading web
browsers like Google Chrome and Mozilla Firefox,
namely extensions.
These are basically JavaScript modules that run locally on the user's computer,
but in a much more sandboxed and secure environment and provide a
lot of the same kind of additional functionality that you used to
try to get with BHOs years ago.
As I said,
Internet Explorer started and spent most of its
life as a proprietary technology, so as a web developer,
you typically had to develop your websites for compatibility
with IE and pretty much all the other browsers.
Browsers like Chrome and Firefox have historically
cleaved much more closely to web standards,
whereas IE always historically has had its own
little proprietary hooks thrown in.
The great news is that in more recent years,
specifically since Satya Nadella took over Microsoft,
Microsoft is much more willing to embrace standards
and Edge is a good example of this.
The idea with Edge is that it should play perfectly well with
HTML5 and all the current accepted web standards.
Another thing, Internet Explorer 11 has a slow update cycle.
As a matter of fact, the update cycle is gone now.
Internet Explorer 11 is deprecated,
which means that Microsoft is no longer investing
resources in adding new features.
It will, Microsoft will release security updates for IE 11, but that's it.
Now by contrast, as I said, Microsoft Edge was designed initially for two things,
for compatibility with web standards and speed.
Finally, on Internet Explorer 11,
you normally would have a different experience on different devices
if you're running Internet Explorer on Windows.
For a while, there was IE on Mac,
then there was the various mobile operating systems,
Windows CE if you remember that from many years ago.
Microsoft tried to give a generally similar feel,
but they were different products from the ground up.
By contrast,
Microsoft Edge to go back to the update cycle has a
much more agile update cycle.
This reflects current security trends where you have
exploits being taken advantage of immediately,
in most cases,
where Microsoft needs to respond and patch their
software as quickly as they possible can.
And then as far as the different experience goes,
besides speed and besides compatibility with web standards,
I'll throw in a third design goal of the Edge browser and that is to have a
consistent behavior and experience across different devices,
and believe it or not,
Microsoft is even developing Edge for Apple iOS devices and Google Android devices.