Windows Updates.
The first thing I want to do here is differentiate the three
types of update that Microsoft publishes.
Now these are code fixes.
They could be bug fixes that fix just performance-related
code flaws in the Windows code base.
Most often they have to do with some kind of security
vulnerability that's been published,
but we have feature updates at this point coming out twice a year,
the creator's updates, spring and fall.
Those are formally called by Microsoft feature updates,
and this is basically the equivalent, if not a bit more than the equivalent,
of the service pack that used to be the standard with Windows Client,
and even Windows Server over time.
You would have the base operating system,
the generally available, or GA copy, and then in a year or so,
whenever Microsoft had enough updates rolled up together,
and maybe some new features that have come through the pike,
they would be added to a service pack.
Well now in Windows, Windows Client,
we have these semi-annual big releases that add new functionality,
as well as rolling up changes that you might not have picked up
through the ordinary Windows Update process.
Quality updates are the normal Windows updates that are
delivered the second Tuesday of every month,
what we systems administrators call Patch Tuesday.
And the reason Microsoft does these quality updates on a schedule is
to give configuration managers an opportunity to plan ahead because
doubtless they'll want to test these updates on some lab systems to
make sure that an update doesn't inadvertently break functionality
elsewhere on the system.
Non-deferrable updates are updates that you have no choice
but to receive when Microsoft sends them,
and those are things like definition updates for Windows Defender.
I mentioned earlier when we covered antimalware that it's
utterly crucial that you A) have an antimalware product
installed on your system at all times,
and B) you ensure to update its definition so that the software
can remediate against the latest threats.
The same thing happens with Windows Update.
If you're not regularly applying updates from Microsoft,
then you may be leaving vulnerabilities open that could result in
catastrophic data loss in the case of ransomware, and/or the possibility of things like identity theft and financial loss.