We have count them, four different account types supported in Windows 10.
First we have the local account.
That screenshot I just showed you from Windows NT showed
local accounts that were resident in the Security Accounts
Manager database of that system.
Same thing exists in Windows 10.
These accounts are defined and usable only on the local system.
We have an important distinction between a standard user and an administrator.
An administrator would be someone who belongs to the administrators local
group and has full spectrum access to that local machine.
A standard user has a moderate amount of user rights
and privileges out of the box,
and then it's your task as a systems administrator to find the
balance of what's called least privilege security,
where your users have enough privileges to do their jobs,
but nothing more.
A Microsoft account is an online identity that doesn't
have to be a Microsoft owned email Id.
It can be just about anything; Gmail, Hotmail, which is Microsoft, Yahoo.
com.
These Microsoft accounts are cool because the account
settings will synchronize across devices.
The chief advantage of using a Microsoft account in our
consumer environment is that you can get to,
for instance, your OneDrive files seamlessly on your Windows 10 desktop.
If you have an iPad you can install OneDrive there and get to your files.
If you use an Xbox you can use OneDrive.
Same thing, it's a universal account.
It's really convenient.
Now the waters get a little muddy when we get into
business and enterprise environments.
That's what we're going to talk about next.
Things like Office 365,
which is Microsoft's online collaboration and productivity platform.
Office 365, to use that as an example,
uses Azure Active Directory in those accounts.
These Azure AD accounts are often used in business nowadays in what's
called a hybrid cloud in which on-premises identities,
ones that are defined in, say, and Active Directory domain,
are synchronized up into an Azure AD tenant,
and then the accounts that are synchronized can then
transparently access services online, like Office 365 and many,
many others.
A Standard AD account is an on-premises Active Directory Identity.
In a Microsoft network the domain is the fundamental
unit of connection and administration,
and normally in a domain environment a user will never touch any of the
local identities defined on his or her Windows system.
They will log on strictly with their domain account and go from there.
Least privilege, as I mentioned a moment ago,
is an IT security principle that, formally defined,
is a principle in which every process, user,
or application must be able to access only the information and
resources that are necessary for their legitimate purpose.
This is a good description here,
especially the reference to processes and applications.
User accounts, group accounts,
and applications are all what are called security principles,
or security Ids, or security assets.
Those are the objects,
the principles that are granted or denied access to network resources,
and once again, least privilege is critical because if you,
for instance,
out of convenience make your ordinary domain users and business
members of the administrators group on their system,
so they see fewer permission denied errors,
that gives the user more convenience,
but it dramatically reduces the security of the system.
So the best practice guidance is for everybody,
and I'm not talking just Joe and Jane end user,
but even you as a systems administrator should log on
to your system with a standard, local, or domain identity,
and then use something like the run as capability that I'll show you in a demo
to elevate your privileges when you feel that's necessary.
As I said,
that question of privilege splits between the administrator or the super user,
as it's sometimes called, and the standard user.
In Windows 10 in the local accounts database members of the
built-in Users group are considered standard users.
There's no guest account in Windows 10.
Microsoft found that most customers never used the account,
so it just presents a security hazard.
Administrative actions are going to require UAC elevation.
That means that the user's going to either have to ask an
administrator to put in their credentials or through scripting
automation it's done automatically over the network,
but you do have to authenticate as an honest to
goodness administrator to do that task.
As I already said, the best practice is to run everybody as standard user,
and then elevate only when necessary.
An administrator has complete control over the computer.
There's a built-in Administrator Identity on Windows systems,
as well as an administrators group.
That is to say, any account that's placed in that administrators group becomes,
by inheritance, and administrator of that local system.
As far as the built-in Administrator account,
the best practice is to rename it to something non-intuitive like Joe
Shmoe because Administrator is a known quantity,
and any attacker is first going to try to breach a system by
attempting that as the username thinking,
well, I know that account exists.
If it's been renamed, then you've made the attackers work harder to do.
Certainly,
you haven't stopped them because there's other reasons why it's pretty
trivial to find out which is the administrator identity,
but renaming it is certainly better than nothing.
Perhaps better is to disable it, and enable it only when you need it.
Administrative actions as an administrator require User Account Control
consent instead of actually having to put in credentials.
Now that's default behavior. We'll talk more about UAC momentarily.