Configuring Windows features.
The historical perspective here is that Microsoft
goes back a long way in Windows.
This is a screenshot from Windows 3.
1 that shows you how you can add or subtract optional features.
These are built-in programs, in many cases,
many programs, and back in those days actually,
back in Windows 3.
1 space may indeed have been a factor that would lead you to dump,
say games, wallpapers, screensavers.
Maybe you didn't have enough RAM or CPU power to do it,
and disk space was certainly at a premium back then,
so even Windows 3.
1 had this capability.
We still have it today in 2018.
I submit that now the reason why you would want to adjust which default or
built-in programs you have installed in your Windows 10 deals with
performance and security rather than disk space.
This is the Graphical User Interface in Windows 10.
It's the Windows Features dialog.
Notice that it gives you a graphical view that looks much like File
Explorer where you can expand and contract components.
For instance, look about 1/3 of the way down the screen, Hyper-V.
Client-side Hyper-V you can click to select the root node that'll select
all subcomponents or you can expand and be selective.
Hyper-V, for instance, includes both the actual client-side engine,
as well as the management tools.
If you don't want the GUI tool you don't have to install it.
This is a good thing.
From a security perspective it's called reducing the
attack surface of your system.
Here's the idea.
If a built-in Windows component has a software bug or a vulnerability in
it that can be exploited there's no way that your system will be
vulnerable if you don't have that feature enabled.
You see what I mean?
So this speaks to what's called least service.
If you don't need an application or service on your machine uninstall it.
If you change your mind later you can always come back,
circle back and reinstall, but once again,
by not installing components you don't need you're giving
your system potentially a performance boost,
as well as importantly reducing the attack surface area of that machine.
Windows Features.
You can manipulate these at the command line as well.
Command line I want you to always think in terms of larger environments,
and when I say larger I'm not necessarily talking
fleets of thousands of computers.
You may be a tech who does maybe four or five systems a day.
Even there when you're doing the same repetitive action over and over again,
that's a candidate for automation,
so I want you to keep that in mind as we're going on.
We have the DISM tools.
DISM is a command line tool.
DISM stands for Deployment Image Servicing and Management,
and it ships with Windows by default.
It allows you to do both online and offline servicing.
Now what the heck does that mean Tim, right?
This is not a deployment course.
Keep having to remind myself over and over again.
You can, even on a standalone Windows 10 machine,
use DISM to view, install, and uninstall optional features,
but it becomes powerful in an Enterprise context because you can
run a DISM script against n number of machines.
Online means that you're actually operating on a Windows 10
box that's powered up and functional.
Offline means that you're working on, in the case of a virtual machine,
you'd be working on the virtual hard disk of that system while it's powered off.
PowerShell is an automation engine, command line only,
although you can build GUI front ends, as we saw in the previous module.
You can get GUI front ends for DISM, as well as many PowerShell functions.
PowerShell has three cmdlets that are relevant here.
Get, Enable, and Disable are the verbs, WindowsOptionalFeature is the noun.
I'm not going to say anything more about this now because I'm going to do a demonstration on it momentarily.