Now then,
let's run through a quick comparison of the major differentiating
features between the different Windows 10 editions.
First of all,
it's important to understand that we have the home SKU that's
intended for non-business environments where you have
presumably less networking going on, and you still have an emphasis on security,
but not mass enterprise level security across dozens,
hundreds, thousands, or tens of thousands of machines.
Both home and pro give you the Cortana digital voice assistant.
You can to Tablet mode, also called Continuum.
We have the Edge browser, Mobile Device Management,
which means that you can enroll Windows 10 home or pro in Microsoft Intune.
I know it's not exactly a misnomer, but a bit confusing.
I normally think of MDM as pertaining to tablets and phones,
but of course, Windows 10 can indeed run on a tablet computer,
and you can, in fact,
enroll desktop and laptop computers running 10 in Microsoft Intune as well.
That's all under the MDM umbrella.
Trusted Boot is a secure way to start a computer and prevent
malware from injecting itself into the boot process.
Windows Hello is a Multifactor Authentication scheme where you can log on using
biometrics in addition or instead of just a simple password.
Now the pro only SKU, again,
we're thinking more in terms of business and not necessarily just enterprise,
500 users and above, but even the mid-market and potentially the small office,
home office.
You've got BitLocker whole disk encryption,
Group Policy for centralized desktop management,
the ability to join an active directory domain services
domain or an Azure Active Directory domain.
Once again, the point or the theme there is centralized management.
Remote Desktop, client-side Hyper-Virtual,
and a more robust Windows Store experience where,
for instance,
the administrator can control which Windows Store
applications are available for their employees,
and Windows Update for Business where network administrators,
systems administrators can more granularly control how
updates are delivered to their managed devices.
Then we have a second layer of distinction.
This is purely for business environments.
You have the Windows 10 Pro verses the Windows 10 Enterprise SKUs.
Both Pro and Enterprise offer Windows Information Protection,
Windows Hello, Windows Store.
We've seen some of these in the previous slide.
By the way,
Windows Information Protection or WIP is the client-side component
that's used in the system center environment or perhaps if you're
using Office 365 and Azure AD that provides data loss prevention or
DLP protection where you have, for instance,
business documents that may contain social security numbers,
credit card numbers,
and you want to make sure that your employees aren't forwarding
those to external addresses in this kind of thing.
Mobile Application Management is mobile device management,
but SKUed specifically towards applications.
The Enterprise only SKUs give features like BranchCache,
which is where you can give remote offices faster access to files by
keeping local copies or cached copies of those files in the remote office
where the main copy exists in headquarters over,
say, a Wide Area Network connection.
MDOP stands for Microsoft Desktop Optimization Pack.
This has a number of enterprise tools.
One in particular that's kind of cool is BitLocker management.
Device and Credential Guard, ways to really lock down a system.
Maybe your company has some kiosk PCs that public access or
visitor or guest access is allowed on.
Think of a hotel, that would be a good example,
where they have a couple kiosk computers where
customers can print their flight tickets.
Well,
you want to be absolutely sure that only allowed code can run on those machines.
Device Guard, Credential Guard fit into that.
DirectAccess is a way to do virtual private networking
without the overhead of a VPN device,
and Cortana Management is a way to centrally manage Cortana.
App-V and UE-V are ways to virtualize desktops or applications.
We don't want to get too far off track here because the purpose of
this course is specifically on the Windows 10 client.
Those are a lot of buzzwords I just threw at you.
Now don't expect on your exam that you're going to see
detailed questions about any of it.
If anything, it's just going to be a recognition thing,
where you recognize a feature and say, oh yeah,
that's Enterprise only, or this over here is available in home,
this kind of stuff.
To sum up these two slides,
home you have much less emphasis on centralized control. Pro and enterprise increasing and maximized emphasis on centralized control.