Now let's look at the 98-349 exam in greater detail.
The Microsoft Windows Operating System Essentials
certification exam has the exam ID 98-349.
Every Microsoft certification exam has a unique identifier.
The number will stay the same over the course of years
and over the course of exam revisions.
Occasionally Microsoft will retire an exam and replace it with a new number,
or it'll just retire it and it will disappear.
This exam was published in April of 2011,
so as of this recording in 2018 that's a good number of years back.
It's most recently been updated August of 2016.
Now, there's lots of inconsistent information on the web about this exam.
You'll find references to Microsoft learning posts
where this is listed as a retired exam,
and then when you try to investigate the reference it 404s,
which means that the page has been taken offline.
As you see in the left, the graphic there,
that says 2017, so the certification is still alive,
is still around as of this recording, even though,
like I said,
it's not particularly well-documented and there's lots
of rumors about it disappearing.
That having been said, I want you to focus on your technical skills.
The certification is great, the certification may definitely be on your radar,
but the most important thing I want you to take away from this course
are a bunch of new skills on supporting Windows 10,
and how you can apply those skills on the job and even in
your personal life helping those around you.
As far as understanding the certification process,
if you've never studied for a certification,
if you've never taken a computer-based exam,
if you're not sure how to register for Microsoft exams,
I'm not going to spend any time here explaining it,
because I've already done so.
Look at the URL at the bottom of this screen, timw.
info/mvac.
That'll take you to the Microsoft Virtual Academy website.
I put together two courses there.
The first one is of particular import.
It's called Mastering Microsoft Certification Exam Prep.
You study that,
I guarantee you'll come out with a crystal clear understanding of what
goes into studying for a Microsoft certification exam,
how to register, the whole workflow, I cover it in great detail.
And then Building an IT Certification Study Lab is
really nice guidance on how you can, for fun and for free,
develop a hands-on learning environment at home with minimal cost.
I've developed an approach to studying for certification exams.
I haven't trademarked this, maybe I should.
I call it my certificate Study Pyramid, because I strongly believe,
after having taken it's got to be over 100 certification exams over the years,
that we have three elements that are all interdependent and need
to be present in order for you to succeed.
First we have content knowledge.
This is understanding the theory of the learning domain,
and the learning domain in this course, of course,
is Windows 10.
I covered a lot of features, a lot of capabilities,
and I also gave you real-world examples of how those
features come into play in business.
That's your theoretical content knowledge.
Now, if you're working in IT already,
you may have already applied a lot of that knowledge,
practical application,
where you can take what you know about Windows theoretically and
see how it actually behaves in the real work.
If you're not yet working in that industry,
then you have some additional work to do,
like I said a moment ago, building a home study lab network is a good idea.
You really need to have both of these elements in place by the
time you sit for any certification exam,
the hands-on and the theory.
The third element of my study pyramid is test-taking strategy.
I know many people over the years, sadly,
who went into their exam session with lots of content knowledge,
even practical application,
but because they weren't expecting a computer-based test,
and they weren't accustomed to how Microsoft wants to ask
those questions and test your knowledge,
they didn't pass.
So there what I recommend you do is choose a good reputable,
legal exam simulation.
Measureup.
com is a company that is an official practice exam provider for Microsoft.
There are others that I recommend, like Transcender and Boson.
I have links to all of those companies in the exercise files.
If you're part of an enterprise subscription with Pluralsight,
you do have access to Transcender certification exams.
so you do have the test-taking strategy element in place.
Let's take a moment to consider learning styles.
What is your preferred way to learn new concepts?
It's crucial that you do some reflection and
determine how you best learn new stuff.
For instance, are you a visual learner?
This would be somebody who learns really well with books or watching
computer-based training like you have here with Pluralsight.
Here you're visual, you like images, you like to see spatial relationships,
you maybe work cognitively using mind maps,
if you're familiar with those.
An auditory learner is big on listening and discussion and repetition.
If you're faced with memorizing protocols and ports,
you might develop mnemonic devices.
It's the sound and shape of the words that helps you understand,
and also dialoging with peers, with your instructor,
etc.
Kinesthetic is hands-on, you learn best by experiencing.
You don't necessarily want to talk about it,
you don't want to watch movies on it, you want to do discovery and make mistakes.
Now, you may fit mostly in one of these three categories,
or you might be like me where I'm fairly divided across all three.
But the way you determine, or should I say,
when you determine your learning style,
that's going to take you down in your cert study to
rely more or less heavily on, say, video prerecorded training like Pluralsight,
technical instruction books or websites,
or the practical aspect, hands-on labs and real-world experience.
I don't want to belabor this,
because from a student's perspective it's got to get pretty tedious,
but I have a few slides that I've taken screen
captures from the exam 98-349 blueprint.
As I said at the end of the previous module,
I structured this course according to the blueprint,
so we cover every topic.
And actually it's good to go through this as a sanity check to
make sure that we've learned all this stuff,
and also it's good as far as recognition,
patting yourself on the back like, wow,
I know a heck of a lot more than I did before I started this training.
So we have the blueprint divided into objective domains, or ODs.
These are top-level categories.
This first one is called operating system configurations.
And notice that Microsoft gives you an estimated
percentage of the overall question pool.
We started with control panel, with administrative tools.
We've done a lot with classic Control Panel and the Windows 10 Settings ap.
We've looked and worked with File Explorer a great deal.
Desktop settings, we certainly looked at the desktop environment,
the Start menu, the taskbar, toolbars.
Native applications, we used Edge and Cortana,
client Hyper-V, MSCONFIG, Task Manager, the computer management console.
For mobility, we did Sync Center and the Windows Mobility Center,
we did RDP, that's Remote Desktop Protocol.
For management tools, we spent a lot of time in Microsoft management consoles,
and I also tried to inject as much PowerShell and
PowerShell ISE into the course as I could.
The next objective domain is installing and upgrading,
and we began with looking at system requirements and Windows editions.
We did upgrades and application compatibility.
We did installation types, clean installation,
using Windows Update, network installations.
We worked with operating system architecture, 64-bit, 32-bit, all that.
In the applications objective domain,
we looked at applications from a number of different lenses,
didn't we?
Network and local applications, Windows Store apps versus desktop apps,
the SmartScreen filter, user account control and how that fits into security,
Windows Defender Security Center, the Malicious Software Removal Tool.
For services we looked through PowerShell and the Service Control Manager,
how to control service behavior.
In the files and folders objective domain,
we covered file systems, we did a lot on networking and file sharing,
NTFS, and Share Permissions, HomeGroup, printers,
shared folders, etc., BitLocker and Encrypting File System.
We did more with File Explorer, with libraries, remember that?
Offline files would be another subject.
For managing devices, we looked at plug-and-play and printer installation,
and device driver management, all sorts of local and remote storage options,
quite a bit with OneDrive and how that functions,
printing devices, both local and remote,
installation management, internet printing,
print-to-file, system devices, understanding Device Manager. Ah, enough with these lists, let's get into a demo to break up the monotony.