In this demonstration,
we'll take a look at some of the built-in
troubleshooting utilities in Windows 10.
We'll start with troubleshooters,
so let me open the Start menu and type the word troubleshoot.
It looks like we want to open up System Settings.
Sure enough, it takes us under Update & Security to the Troubleshoot area,
and let's just scroll through the list here.
We have what Microsoft probably receives their most support requests on,
Internet Connectivity, Audio, Printers, and Windows Update,
Blue Screen, Bluetooth, I'm not going to read these,
but it's a nice significant list, as you can see here.
Search and Indexing,
well what if the user is experiencing problems searching for files.
Maybe they receive a message like indexing is disabled on this drive,
and you want to dig into that a little bit more.
Well let's run that troubleshooter and see what happens.
Notice that a detection process first happens,
and then depending upon whether the troubleshooter actually
finds the problem straightaway or not,
you may be led through a question and answer or interview process.
Let's just say that Files don't appear in search results and click Next.
And in this case it looks like we have to elevate,
or we can give feedback,
which is just a standard end question that Microsoft has.
Well this one is going to require elevation,
and I am logged on as an administrator so I was able to do that,
and it now asks us the question again, files don't appear in search results.
And it's going through quite a few processes that a fix for
which would require administrative privilege,
and in this case it looks like the troubleshooter actually found that I had
permissions set incorrectly on some Windows search directories,
and it says Fixed, green arrow.
That's a good deal.
And we can close the troubleshooter, give feedback or view detailed information.
And this is cool just from an informational standpoint,
because it looks specifically on the subsystems of Windows Search that
could have gone wrong and whether the issue was present.
So it looks like permissions on Windows Search data
directories needed to be adjusted.
Cool, I'm going to cancel out of here,
and that's basically how to use the troubleshooter,
it's no more complicated than that.
Let's do another search.
This time let's look at error reports.
If we type error reports or problem reports we'll be
prompted to open the classic Control Panel.
On this system there's no reports to view,
but I have another system that does have reports,
let me bring that on screen, here we go.
I'm actually overlaying this window from my Windows 10 host computer.
And we have some Adobe Acrobat updates problems,
we have an Odyssey2 emulator that stopped working.
Some things we can easily recognize, some aren't so obvious, right?
What about this bad_module_info?
what the heck is that?
If you double left-click it, it gives you a detailed screen here,
and it looks like bad_module_info, the package is Microsoft.
Windows.
Cortana, okay, and then we get a Bucket globally unique identifier.
So this might be enough.
The report was sent anonymously to Microsoft based on my sharing settings,
but we have some specific stuff that we can do a search on.
We could open Google or Bing window.
Actually, why don't we just do that.
Let me open up an instance of Edge, have that in the background running.
Bad_module_info, let me see if I can copy just this guy,
and then I'll do a quoted search.
Oh, and it looks like we have some search suggestions here,
and it looks like there is an answers.
microfost.
com result here.
Ah, this one is talking about steam games, maybe if I add cortana.
So we're seeing some live troubleshooting here.
Cortana has stopped working, okay.
So you see where I'm going here.
You could put on your detective hat and just start troubleshooting
based on quoted strings that you pull from here.
You can copy the whole report to a clipboard,
and then send that to your vendor, or Microsoft or whomever.
Again,
this is part of the Security and Maintenance Control
Panel that we've looked at before.
Next let's look at Feedback Hub. If we type feedback in Start