Okay, here we are on a Windows 7 desktop computer.
You see on the taskbar I have Microsoft Office installed.
That's a Microsoft application,
so I'm not particularly concerned about it working.
You'll see I have some freeware or shareware installed.
I have Auslogics Disk Defrag, and I've got WinZip,
so I've installed some software to simulate,
in a weak way, what a typical home or business system might look like.
Windows Explorer, we'll go into documents, and I have some ping files.
So this is just to set the stage.
Our goal is to upgrade to Windows 10.
We know that Windows 7 can be directly upgraded to Windows 10,
so we have a few different ways of doing that.
We used to have the Windows update free upgrade approach,
but that window has passed.
So a couple things you can do,
you can download the media creation tool for Windows 10.
That's a fee download.
Check the exercise files for the link if you want it.
You also can procure a physical DVD or the Windows 10
media or an electronic version, and ISO image file.
If I go to my computer you see I actually have one
mounted in this virtual machine.
If I right-click it I can fire off AutoPlay to kick off the upgrade,
but I suggest strongly that you disable AutoPlay.
There's a number of security reasons for that,
not the least of which if you're given an infected USB
stick and you have AutoPlay enabled, then any executable code,
boom, you're done, you see?
I don't like AutoPlay anymore, but if we just open it you see we have a setup.
exe file.
Cool.
Well, we need to know some things, first of all,
and by things what are we talking about?
Well how about what edition we're currently running.
Let me open the Start menu here, go over to Computer,
right-click, go to Properties, and we see that I'm running Windows 7 Pro.
So that means I'm going to have some problems if I'm using
Windows 10 or if I want to use Windows 10 Home I'm going to
want to go to at least Windows 10 Pro.
The ISO I have is, in fact, Windows 10 Professional edition.
The Media Creation Tool, if you download that,
that's going to automagically determine which edition
matches the one that you currently have.
Now if we decided afterwards that we didn't want to do Pro,
but we wanted to move up to Enterprise you can always do that.
Now as I started the Media Creation Tool it looks like I've got a problem here.
We weren't able to download all the files.
I'll bet I have a network connection problem,
and sure enough, if I hover over my networking icon it says,
No internet access.
So I'm going to pause the video.
This is a good learning example for us.
We want to sort this stuff out before we kick off the upgrade.
Okay, that's fine, and if you're wondering,
Tim, how did you resolve that networking problem?
Let me ask you instead to search the Pluralsight library in the CompTIA A+
or the Network+ training and look for troubleshooting,
and I'll teach you all about it there,
but if I hover over the icon we see that we now have internet access.
Why is internet access required for the Media Creation Tool?
Well, this Media Creation Tool executable is actually quite tiny.
What this will do is actually download the ISO disk
image from Microsoft directly.
You see what I mean?
You have to accept the end user license agreement,
which I will do, and then after a few moments we're asked what you want to do.
Do you want to do an upgrade or do you want to create installation media,
USB flash, DVD, or just a straight ahead ISO for another PC?
If I choose Upgrade this PC now it's going to download,
which is going to take a while,
it's going to perform some preliminary compatibility checks,
and then it's going to continue.
I'm going to bomb out of this.
I wanted to show you at least a couple different ways
to perform this in-place upgrade.
If you have access to the DVD for Windows 10 or the ISO
image you can just simply kick off set up.
Now we're going to talk about user Account Control
in greater detail in a moment.
Because I'm logged on to the system as an administrator,
and you absolutely do need to be logged on to your system as
an administrator to perform an upgrade, I hope that almost goes without saying.
That User Account Control is asking, are you sure you want to do this?
And I have to explicitly answer yes to kick off that process.
Now I'll talk more about some pre-flight checks after this demo,
and I have a reason for doing it that way,
but one of the things to check besides the editions,
besides whether you're logged on as an administrator,
make sure your system is fully up to date with Windows Update.
This is a Windows 7 box that's completely up to date.
Nonetheless,
notice that the Windows 10 setup from the ISO
volunteers to download and install updates,
and that's recommended.
I know I did that, so I can bypass this in this window.
Another thing that you'll want to do is make sure that
your anti-malware scanner is turned off.
An upgrade is much different from just installing,
say, Microsoft office on your system.
Here you're modifying the system files and the boot files.
Now if you're running a Windows anti-malware client it's less important.
I have defender, for instance.
So if I start Windows Defender on this machine and go to Tools,
and then go to Options,
I can turn off automatic scanning and real-time protection and disable it.
Perhaps even go into Services and turn off the service,
but like I said,
because it's a Microsoft product it's aware of what's
going on here in the execution world, so I'll click Next.
Again,
we have the preliminary check that takes place that
gives us some user friendly text.
And again, I have to laugh how friendly and conversational the interface is.
If you date back, like I do, to several versions of Windows,
back in Windows NT days for instance,
it was a user interface that even the strongest
propeller head would find objectionable.
Okay, now this Windows 10 DVD has multiple editions on it.
Looks like it has Education, Enterprise, and Pro.
Want to make sure that I'm in the correct region, English US.
En is code for a European version.
The European versions have all the base features,
but they don't have Windows Media Player and other stuff.
There's some legal reasons for that.
Now because we know that I'm running Windows 7 Pro I'm going
to do a direct upgrade to Windows 10 Pro,
so I'll select that image from the list,
and click Next.
Again, we're asked about license terms.
Depending upon how your licensing works,
by the way, and that's another whole subject that's really beyond our scope,
we can reuse the existing key for the previous version,
and activate Windows 10 automatically over the web or you'll
have to have a Windows 10 activation key,
a valid one, ready to supply in order to activate Windows 10.
The set up routine has given us a driver warning here saying that
this video driver is not compatible with Windows 10,
and we have to confirm that incompatibility before we go along,
and that's fine in this case.
It's nice that you get those flags,
but in an enterprise business if you're going to do this across dozens
or hundreds of machines you want to make sure to test all this before
you're actually upgrading a user's computer.
We're ready to install, and notice that it says, keep personal files and apps.
This is an in-place upgrade.
If we click Change what to keep we can choose to keep personal files and apps,
that's the default setting, just the files and nuke the applications,
or nothing, which is almost a clean installation,
except you still get to keep your user account.
I'm going to go back, accept the terms,
make sure that keep personal files and apps is selected,
and we'll go Next.
Okay,
once we're happy with our settings we can click
Install to initiate the upgrade process.
We're warned that the PC will restart several times,
and the process might take a while.
Now it's been several minutes, and we're 39% of the way there thus far.
We haven't had a restart yet, but I'm expecting it.
I'm just sipping my coffee and eating some cheddar rice cakes.
Pardon the weird resolution, but we're coming back from a restart.
I think Windows 10 is attempting to figure out the proper resolution.
Actually, we saw that there was that error regarding the video driver earlier.
Hmm.
We'll keep monitoring it.
After a couple more restarts and updates we're here.
We're working with low resolution of course,
that's why you're seeing the black at the side of your display,
but we can correct that quickly enough.
I'm going to click Next to verify that I want to logon as my current account.
We'll accept the license agreement,
and we're now given what I guess you could call a mini setup
wizard that's asking us a number of questions,
how much we want to opt in to things like location identification,
Cortana and speech recognition allowing anonymous
diagnostics being sent to Microsoft to help them,
relevant ads.
I'm certainly going to turn that off.
I don't like ads at all, but I'll leave the others on for now,
and I will use Cortana.
Remember, we saw this earlier in the course that Cortana is really great,
but first you have to give her, I hate to use her,
give it proper permissions.
We have the ability to choose default applications
here for media and web browser.
I'll click Next, and lastly we're presented with the Windows 10 log on screen.
I'll provide my password and authenticate.
We're notified that some updates are here for our PC.
Okay, so we're going to have to sit through a run of Windows Update,
this time for Windows 10.
Alright, and finally we have a desktop.
Now the in-place upgrade made a couple changes.
One is that it replaced the Pluralsight desktop wallpaper that I had
previously with this that's the default Windows 10 wallpaper.
As far as preserving my applications the short cuts are certainly still there.
I had opened up Auslogics disk defrag in Windows 7.
Let's open it now.
The User Account Control dialog is Windows 10 as opposed to Windows 7,
obviously.
There it is.
That's fine, and then Windows Explorer or File Explorer,
as it's called nowadays.
We'll go to Documents.
There's those ping files that I had before.
So there you have it.
An in-place upgrade from Windows 7 to Windows 10.
Pretty painless, but of course, I have a relatively simple system.
The more highly customized your system is with hardware and software the
more potential for something going wrong there is. So due diligence is your watch word okay?