Let's compare and contrast on one side the concept of the
physical or logical disk versus the virtual disk.
I want to make sure you're clear on this.
A physical or logical disk refers to hardware,
an actual piece of hardware that you can touch with your
hands and install either inside the chassis of a computer
or plug into it externally.
Now a logical disk is where you partition a physical disk.
We've gone through that earlier in this course, so I hope you remember that.
In Windows 10 we can use, for instance,
the Disk Management MMC console to divide space on a physical disk.
You might, for instance, have a partition for your Windows operating system,
and another partition for your applications.
And one benefit there is if you have a catastrophic OS error that
requires you to reformat drive C and reinstall Windows,
all of your user data will remain safe on a separate partition.
Now normally the physical disks are inconvenient as portable storage,
unless, of course, it's an external drive.
In helping customers over the years,
if they're moving to a new computer and they want to be
able to switch all their files over, migration scenario,
again we talked about that earlier in this course as well,
I'll sometimes open the customer's computer case using a screwdriver,
remove the hard drive from the person's original computer,
place it into an external drive enclosure,
you can buy those quite easily,
and then mount that using USB as removable storage on the user's new computer,
and then you could just simply tap in and copy off
all the data that you want to.
Now a virtual disk,
that term virtual sometimes causes confusion among newcomers to IT,
it's not imaginary so much as it is software.
A virtual disk is a file that resides on a physical disk.
It's not a file you can open up with, say,
Microsoft Word or Notepad, it's a binary file.
In the Microsoft context,
it's going to have either VHD or VHDX as its file extension.
That will associate that virtual disk with hypervisor software.
Hypervisor software is software that allows you to
create and manage virtual machines,
which are software representations of physical computers.
Hyper-V, as you probably already know, is Microsoft's own hypervisor product.
Business SKUs of Windows 10 include client-side Hyper-V as a feature.
Now when you use a virtual disk in Hyper-V,
the virtual disk from the perspective of the VM appears to be a physical disk.
You actually can use the same tools in Windows 10,
like for instance,
the Disk Management console that we've talked about and used in the past,
just the same way you would on real bare metal.
Another thing that differentiates virtual disks from physical disks is
that virtual disks are normally dynamically expanding.
That is, you may create a 60 GB virtual disk and attach it to your VM,
but it will only occupy as much space on the hardware,
on the host's hardware, as you're using,
you see, and that's a good thing.
It is possible to do what's called thick provisioning and create a virtual
disk and allocate the full amount of space on the front end,
but it's generally best practice to let it dynamically expand so that you're
consuming less space on the hardware host's physical disk.
Last thing I want to say about these virtual disks used with virtual
machines and hypervisors is that you can use tools like PowerShell to
easily convert files for use with different hypervisors.
Many times, for instance,
you can use a VHD or VHDX with very minor modification with,
say, a VMware infrastructure.
Hyper-V is Microsoft's world-class hypervisor.
VMware has vSphere.
My friend and Pluralsight colleague, Greg Shields,
and my friend and colleague, Dave Davis,
both have a lot of great VMware content in the Pluralsight library,
but know that you can in fact use these VHDs in an eminently portable way. In fact, that's one of the great beauties of virtualization.