Now Windows Update for Business is not what you might think.
In the previous module when we looked at OneDrive,
I know for a fact that some of my students have said,
I always thought that OneDrive and OneDrive for Business
were two totally separate products.
And they are in many ways, but they're both accomplishing the same goal,
it's just that the focus is different.
Similarly in Windows Update, you have the Windows Update Control Panel,
or setting technically,
in Windows 10 that the consumer manages himself or herself,
and Windows Update for Business is aimed towards
centralized management of Windows Update.
Now we're going to talk about Windows Server Update services in a moment,
that's been around for a long time,
but what you're looking at at this slide is essentially
a couple new Group Policy settings.
In the local or domain Group Policy editor,
the path is Computer Configuration, Administrative Templates,
Windows Components, Windows Update, Windows Update for Business.
And essentially,
these policies allow an administrator to defer certain type of updates,
and also potentially opt into preview builds.
Now you certainly wouldn't want to roll pre-release Windows Client versions to
your users who need their systems to do their work each day,
but most configuration managers I know do belong to the Windows Insider program,
and do have preview builds on at least a couple test or demo test dev
workstations in order to test new functionality and see how that new version
interoperates with your line of business software.
You might be underwhelmed with this Windows Update for Business.
You mean it's just a few Group Policy settings?
How would we, for instance, schedule Windows Update across our enterprise?
How could we approve or block certain Windows updates that
we know we want to green light or block for performance
reasons or stability reasons?
Well that brings us to the subject of WSUS, or as some people call it, WSUS.
Windows Server Update Services has been around for many,
many Windows Server versions.
Understand that this is what you install in Windows Server.
It's a built-in server role.
If you want to go into the Pluralsight library,
we have plenty of training on it,
but what I will say is that WSUS allows an organization to take
full control over the Windows Update lifecycle.
As you can see, its interface here is a little bit cluttered,
but basically you have managed computers in your Active Directory environment,
those computers may be running different versions of Windows,
you may, in an international organization,
may have users running non, whatever your native language is,
other languages besides that.
And you can corral updates across many different Microsoft products,
many different product versions, and even languages,
and run your tests and approve or block updates as you see fit.
There's also performance advantages of this.
Instead of 500 client devices going out over the internet and
downloading a whole bunch of files from Microsoft's website,
you can download them just once into your local LAN,
stage them on your WSUS server,
and your client computers will pull from WSUS as opposed to Microsoft Update.
Now how do they do that?
That's a little bit more of Group Policy magic, pointing your users to WSUS.
That gets beyond our scope though. I've covered what you need to know in our context right now.