In this demonstration,
we'll start with Cortana and how it integrates with Microsoft Edge.
So getting started in my Windows 10 machine,
Cortana is enabled by default and if you've noticed thus far that
your taskbar looks a bit different from mine,
I intentionally hid some items to make things more compact.
If we right-click an empty area of the taskbar and come up to Cortana,
you notice that you can hide or show Cortana by selecting
Cortana hidden yes or no and then you can choose,
I'm going to unselect hidden there, and come back again,
you can show just the Cortana icon which looks like a little
circle or right-click Cortana show the search box,
type here to search and you can actually use your microphone
for what's called Hey Cortana functionality.
If you click in that search box, once again,
depending upon how you have Cortana set up,
you could simply speak or type Nashville weather let's say and you'll notice
that the results show up immediately over on the right.
It looks like it's giving us from Bing which is Microsoft's own
search engine current conditions in Nashville,
TN.
Let me right-click, come up to Cortana,
and just show the icon because I want to step you
through how to configure Cortana.
So we'll open the icon up,
it gets basically the same interface that we saw before.
Notice that you can filter specifically on various filters like apps,
documents, and web, and then there is this Cortana can do much more.
If you open that and you haven't yet consented to Cortana data collection,
you're asked to do so,
and the way that you need to do that first is by
signing in with your Microsoft account.
I trust you have a Microsoft account.
If you don't, I'd suggest you create one, they're free to create.
I give you some links in the exercise files to get you started with that.
I'm going to click Sign in.
I've already used a particular account and I'm going to
reuse and associate with Cortana now.
Now if we open the bottom drop-down,
we're asked would we like Cortana to work across devices.
Remember earlier,
I mentioned that the Edge browser is intended to be a unified interface
across different devices and one of the benefits actually of your
Microsoft account and signing into Windows 10 with your Microsoft account
is that you can share many of your preferences and settings and even
applications across computers, so your home computer,
your work computer,
all these machines can enjoy the same search results
and environment thanks to this.
And what this is asking us here is would we like
Cortana to work on our mobile device, and as you see,
we have links for the Google Play and the Apple iOS App store.
So yes, Cortana can and does work in mobile environments as well.
I'm going to select not now here and it looks like
Cortana wants to give us some news here.
And again, specifically,
all of the data that Cortana gives you over time is going to be
customized based on the information you give to her.
For instance, Get traffic updates for your commute,
I need your work address to do that.
And then in order to specify that,
we need to customize the data collection for Cortana.
So we'll click Settings here and we're taken into the settings app
that I introduced you to in the previous module.
It looks like I have location services turned off on this
device so I would turn that on as one option.
This would allow Microsoft and Cortana to understand where I am in the world,
and then I can set a default location if I want to that Cortana will use if
it's unable to determine what my current location is.
Okay, I'm going to answer yes to this question,
it looks like the maps application is opened up.
As you see here,
you can just step through the wizard to specify your default location.
If you're concerned about security,
notice that you can at any time clear the location history.
You may have a laptop computer that you travel with and you may have
quite a few locations associated with Cortana.
Again, that can be a great convenience.
I, myself, go to the Microsoft campus in Redmond,
Washington a lot and it's really nice that Cortana functions and gives me
personalized results for my searches and what I do there.
And then when I'm home here in Nashville, it's the same thing.
Now if we come back home,
you'll notice that the root level of the settings app actually has an
entire category related to Cortana so let's select that.
Now you can calibrate your microphone and have Cortana respond to your
voice by checking the status of your microphone.
I don't have a mic on this computer so I can't do that.
And then once you've associated your microphone that Windows
knows that you have one and that it's working,
you can let Cortana respond to hey Cortana.
This allows Cortana literally at any point in time
you can say hey Cortana and it, she, I use she,
personification,
but it will respond to your query and again check the exercise files if
you're wondering the kind of things that you can have her do,
set reminders, open applications, perform a web search,
etc.
Let's see anything else.
Use Cortana even when your device is locked.
Let Cortana access additional data including calendar,
email, messages, and power BI data when your data is locked,
what language you want Cortana to use.
It's defaulting to my home region, English United States.
Now if you plan to use that hey Cortana feature or if you just prefer to
be able to use your voice from the context of search,
you're going to want to train or have Cortana train to learn your voice.
Let me close out of settings and open Cortana again.
I mentioned in the slides portion of this lesson that
Cortana has what's called a notebook.
Let me expand this left part here and you notice that there is a devices
option where you can again calibrate your microphone and looks like there is
an advertisement to buy a Microsoft Cortana speaker.
Huh, I learn something new every day.
I'm learning this along with you.
Although, frankly by the time you're watching this lesson,
you may already own a Cortana speaker.
I don't.
I'm actually learning of its existence right now.
Oh yes.
I think I've seen the news on this.
Harman/Kardon has a product called Invoke that uses Cortana.
That would compete directly with, for instance,
that Google Home appliance or Amazon's Echo device.
But anyway, come back to Cortana and if we go to the Notebook option,
this is where you get your Cortana specific configuration info,
and depending upon how generous you are with your data,
you can have Cortana call you by a particular name,
know your favorite geographic locations,
lists and reminders that you instruct her to create,
link to music accounts.
I, myself, use Spotify.
This is particularly very helpful to me actually
because I use Spotify every single day.
So I'm making a note to myself that after I finish recording this demo,
I'm going to configure this integration so I can more easily control Spotify.
Skills is something that Cortana has recently added that I
should say Microsoft has recently added.
I have a,
well my wife and I should say technically have an Amazon Echo device
at home and Alexa is the name of that assistant,
and skills are cool because they're third-party plugins that extend
the functionality of the device and it looks like we've got skills
coming to Cortana platform as well.
To configure the voice training, go into Notebook,
and as long as you have a microphone that's enabled,
you can enable hey Cortana and there'll be a settings option here.
I don't have it because, as I've said before,
I don't have a microphone available in this virtual machine,
but in the Settings Panel, you'll be able to run a voice training,
in fact,
I'll put an overlay on this demo so you can see what it
looks like at lest on your screen, and by training Cortana on your voice,
you can teach her not only to pronounce your name,
but also to be able to respond better to the commands that you give.
Pretty cool, isn't it.
Now I mentioned the Edge, the Edge browser integrates with Cortana,
that's certainly true, and what that means is you can,
for instance, find a word of phrase that's interesting like here is CGI,
whoops, you can select a word or phrase.
I know CGI in this context refers to a business name,
but CGI also is a technical term.
You can right-click to ask Cortana about that and Cortana brings up a pane
that you can open as you see here that will define the word,
give you additional information depending upon what
it is that you're looking for.
Isn't that cool?
And then it says here,
it asks us to start a wizard to create a more
personalized experience and it looks like here,
okay, let Cortana collect and use your browsing history.
So the pattern you've seen here, I hope,
is that as you begin to use Cortana in different contexts,
you'll be prompted to consent to that type of data collection.
So there is voice level data collection,
there is the email and context integration,
contacts I should say, integration,
and then in Edge when you're integrating with Cortana,
it's a similar thing where you're asked to allow to share your browsing history in Edge with Microsoft.