The HomeGroup is a simplified method for file sharing.
When Microsoft introduced this, well before this time,
Apple really hadn't had a good, solid grasp on the consumer market.
Nowadays, Apple likes to advertise its products as just working together,
and that's largely true.
On my home iMac system, for instance,
I can load a movie into iTunes and then stream it immediately across my
network onto my Apple TV and then onto my high-definition TV.
I can do the same thing with my other Apple devices without
having to worry at all about IP addresses,
sharing protocols, and the like.
In Windows,
that's typically what you have to get into the weeds
with to do simple media sharing on, say,
a consumer home network or perhaps even the smallest of business networks.
So the idea of a HomeGroup,
it's a simplified interface for a system to share some or all of its resources.
As you can see, this is a screenshot from the Create a Homegroup wizard,
and you can share out your pictures, videos,
music, documents libraries,
or even printers or other hardware devices like an external hard drive.
You can selectively share those and then protect them with a simple password.
On other systems that you want to connect to from,
you would simply browse through in File Explorer any available HomeGroups.
If you're on the same local area network,
you should see that advertised HomeGroup,
and them supply the password to join it,
and you're in.
So that is the basic use case for home and small,
small business environments who need to do file and
media sharing in a simplified way.
Now if it sounds like I'm not going into detail on HomeGroup,
that's because HomeGroup is officially deprecated.
This is a screenshot from one of the Windows Client blogs.
If you're not a fan of really simple syndication,
or RSS, I suggest that you do so.
My favorite RSS aggregator is Feedly, but there's plenty of them around,
and you'll want to keep up to date with the different Windows blogs,
the major ones.
The Windows Client blog is one.
I have the attribution link in the lower left.
But this announcement that centers on the Fall 2017 Creators Update,
the 1709 update, tells us that we're going to start to retire,
Microsoft, that is, is going to begin retiring the HomeGroup service,
and in a future update, that is probably Spring 2018,
the HomeGroup service will no longer be operational.
So in the real world, you don't want to use HomeGroup,
and if you have customers, clients who are using it,
you want to wean them off HomeGroup into a different media sharing mechanism.
Now the Microsoft Certification Exams sometimes lag
behind what's happening in the field, so on your MTA exam,
you may see a question or so referencing HomeGroup.
I've given you essentially what you need to know to
answer those questions successfully.
Instead,
the reason why Microsoft has deprecated HomeGroup is that
it's really not necessary anymore because cloud storage is
manifested in software as a service, or SaaS applications,
like Microsoft's own OneDrive.
There are other popular ones like Dropbox and Box.
This is ubiquitous storage where you can install the
client application on your game console,
on your set-top box, on all of your computers,
on your phones, on your tablets,
and you have immediate access to any data that's in that account.
You see what I mean? So there's really no market need anymore for HomeGroup.