Remote Desktop.
It used to be, a number of years ago, the 1980s,
for instance, is when a third-party Symantec published their PC anywhere program.
It used to be rather problematic if you were a systems
administrator and you needed to touch systems remotely.
Now you could be a business user, an end user,
and you want to be able to get to your work PC from home let's say.
Well certainly in the 80s,
this was before the world wide web and before the adoption of TCP/IP is the
standard protocol suite not only for the public internet,
but also for business specific local area networks.
So anyway,
I guess what I'm saying from a historical point is that this remote
access concept started with third-party tools like pcANYWHERE where you
would install the pcANYWHERE program on all of your machines that you
wanted to not only be remotely accessible,
but also from which you wanted to connect to remote
machines and it worked like a charm.
I first was introduced to pcANYWHERE around the time I got into IT
in the late 90s and this functionality has been entirely replaced
by a number of other technologies including Windows Remote Desktop
that we're covering now.
Remote Desktop, as I've said, is a built-in service.
It's going to depend upon the Windows 10 version,
your home version is not going to have remote desktop,
but the Business edition certainly do.
And the use case here is that you want to establish a
connection to a remote computer running Windows.
Now it doesn't have to run Windows 10 necessarily,
in fact, in a business world, if you're an administrator,
you would be working from your Windows 10 machine and you would
establish a connection to one or more Windows Servers boxes that could
exist in your local campus and your data center,
maybe in another campus,
or maybe even the internet into the Amazon or Microsoft public clouds.
Remote Desktop has client and server components.
As you see here,
we have in the settings program in Windows 10 a simple
slider to enable or disable remote desktop,
and under that, you see user accounts.
You can pick which users can remotely access this PC.
The server is what hosts that remote connectivity.
Now if you're a home user, you certainly would want to keep this turned off.
This is in most cases the server piece that is,
something that you would have in a business environment.
And to tie in what we learned a bit earlier,
remember we've been flirting around a bit with Group Policy,
you absolutely want to centrally manage remote desktop capability
across your business by setting those in Group Policy.
The client-side component of remote desktop is called the Remote
Desktop Connection tool as you see here and this allows you to
specify the remote computer name and also the credentials that will
be used for authentication and then you can specify how big you want
the remote Windows to be,
whether you want to share the clipboard between the client and the server,
and basically all of the parameters around that connection.
Once again, Remote Desktop is a fantastic go-to tool.
Any Windows Systems administrator will likely use this tool every day.
Now from a networking standpoint,
I'm not sure where you are as far as your skills with TCP/IP,
but I do want to say that the default protocol and port that remote desktop
uses is called TCP 3389 and you can look at a port number as a mailbox address
such that when your client computer goes across the network using Remote
Desktop Connection to connect to a remote machine that's running the Remote
Desktop Server Service it's going to,
the client is going to knock on the server's door
so to speak at address TCP 3389. This is a well-known port for what's called the Remote Desktop Protocol, or RDP.