Reliability Monitor.
The Windows 10 Reliability Monitor is really the engine from
which your automatic maintenance pushes its data.
Remember when we dealt with the automatic Windows maintenance,
and you might be wondering, well,
as the maintenance goes through its tasks and looks at
services and looks at uptime values, where is the data being stored?
Well much of it goes into the Windows Event Manager.
If you've ever heard of the Event Viewer and Event Log System,
that's where a lot of the data goes,
and it also goes to this Reliability Monitor tool where you can check
out your system's uptime and availability over time.
You can spot application failures, failures in the Windows components themselves,
peripheral device failures, warnings, or just changes,
change notifications.
Now I've mentioned System Center Configuration Manager quite a bit, or SCCM.
There's a sister product called System Center Operations Manager,
S-C-O-M, or believe it or not, SCOM, and this is an enterprise monitoring tool,
and what it can do is centralize all of this data that you could see on a
one-off basis using the Windows 10 Reliability Monitor,
and you can spot trends across multiple workstations.
But when you're working on a one-off system,
the Reliability Monitor's a really helpful tool for diagnosing
potential bottlenecks or slowdowns in system performance,
and potentially spot you to software that you didn't
know was running and available.
In this demonstration, we'll look at Reliability Monitor.
Now if we right-click an empty area of the taskbar, we have Task Manager.
Of course there's many ways to use this tool.
It defaults to fewer details, but as a power user,
you should get accustomed to always having more details exposed
so you can have access to all of these tabs.
And you should also get accustomed to, for instance,
in the process list, doing an inverse sort on these properties in order to see,
for instance, which processes are consuming the most CPU and memory.
Now you'll notice that it actually does,
and by it I mean Task Manager,
will expand a process if it is in fact a parent process
that has one or more child processes, they will show up here.
How do we go further?
Specifically, Task Manager's great for giving us right here,
right now performance data,
but what if we want to see over the life of the machine?
Well as long as you have those Automatic Maintenance tasks running,
which of course you do, Microsoft makes it difficult to turn off,
you can fire up Reliability Monitor.
And if I type reliability, we get View reliability history.
And notice that this takes us A) into classic Control Panel,
and B) under Security and Maintenance, Reliability Monitor.
And it looks like we're viewing by day from the end of 2017
into the first week and change of 2018.
Now you'll notice here I was working really
high-level of efficiency through December,
and you notice the arrows here.
You can move back and forth through this timeline,
but I'm just going to keep it here because this is the most recent couple weeks.
I took a big hit here on January 2nd as you'll notice.
You see the X show up here.
The I is an informational item, and we can see those details down below.
Let me stretch out these columns.
So on this day when we took this dive, AZLOG.
exe stopped working.
Well what the heck is AZLOG?
And as far as informational events are concerned,
it looks like on that particular day, wow,
I applied a whole bunch of updates.
I wonder if January 2nd was --- well it's definitely
not the second Tuesday of the month,
so perhaps I ran Windows Update manually and
installed a whole bunch of software.
But anyway, I want to know more about this AZLOG.
So let's click View technical details and see if it
gives us any more information.
So the Faulting application is AZLOG, the Faulting module is KERNELBASE.
dll, gives us specific versions.
Does it give us a path?
Yes, C:\Program Files\Microsoft Azure Log Integration\AZLOG.
Okay, so this deals with my Microsoft Azure client-side bits.
That had a problem.
Well this is enough info to where we can turn to our trusty
knowledge repository called Bing or Google,
and you can look up some of these specific errors.
If there's an exception code, yup there sure is,
there's a specific code and so forth.
There's even a globally-unique Report Id for this event that you
possibly could share with Microsoft support.
Let's take a look further on because it looks like since that day,
January 2nd, we're gradually getting better with our reliability,
and then we take another hit on the 14th.
It's that dadgum AZLOG.
I'm going to want to look much closer at that file.
In fact, does it continue?
Yup, it sure does, right up until today.
We've still got problems with that.
That happened --- today is the 19th, and it's about 2 hours past 1 p.
m.
so this is still giving problems that I'm going to
definitely want to investigate.
So that's Reliability Monitor.
Pretty cool tool, isn't it? I learned something new about my system just now.