In this demonstration,
I'm going to walk you through a clean installation of Windows 10.
Clean installation means 1 of 2 things,
either your installing Windows 10 on a hard disk that is empty,
that it's formatted, it's ready for use,
but it does not currently have an OS on it.
It can also mean reinstalling Windows where you reformat your C drive,
your system drive,
and lay down the operating system as if the disk is empty and brand new.
Have you ever heard the term don't mind the person behind the curtain?
Well I'm about to take you behind the curtain a little bit
and show you what I've got going on here.
My chosen hypervisor most of the time is VMware workstation.
Hyper-V is Microsoft's built-in one, I could use that if I wanted to,
that's true,
but my preference is to use VMware and it's the same basic
stuff because we're dealing with VMs,
so the same ideas here in VMware are exactly the same as they are in Hyper-V.
I've created a new empty virtual machine and you notice I'm
allocating it 2 GB of RAM from my hardware host.
I've created a 60 GB software file that represents the hard drive,
and again, that's the maximum size,
it's not going to be that size unless and until I actually consume it.
I'm using the NAT network adapter type and so this will put
this virtual machine on my local network and allow me to go
out onto the internet if I want to.
You can customize these settings all day long by clicking Edit.
So Floppy, that's not something I want so I'm going to actually remove that.
I don't want sound necessarily, so I'm going to remove that capability.
Now this is a heck of a lot more convenient than
working with a real physical computer, wouldn't you agree.
Wow.
Now if we go to CD/DVD, you see that I'm already using an ISO image file.
I downloaded a file win10-creators.
iso from the Evaluation Center and I'm going to boot this
computer from that DVD and that should be just as easy now as
powering on the virtual machine, clicking inside of it to capture my mouse,
and then letting the system boot from the DVD into
the installation setup program.
Now I apologize for the wacky what happened graphically there
because I run my virtual machines at 720p resolution,
but you'll notice that here we're down to a 640x480 screen
because we are in fact in a setup environment.
Now whereas you used to have no mouse all text screen booting off floppies,
now you can take it for granted that you've got mouse access.
Chances are very good that the Windows 10 installer has already loaded a
driver for my network card so I have internet capabilities.
All I need to do here is verify my language,
my time, and my keyboard input, and click Next.
Notice that there is a repair capability built into the Windows 10 setup,
that's a useful thing to know about.
But we're going to go to install now.
Now again,
it wasn't too long ago where setting up an operating system by hand
meant answering a whole bunch of different questions.
It's amazing that really the only question we're going to be asked
here is first of all do we accept the license terms,
I will agree to those.
Are we going to upgrade or do a fresh install?
I did a fresh install by click Custom.
It allows you to choose which disk you want to install
Windows on and notice the commands.
You can format, you can delete,
you can customize the layout of your disks from this screen.
I have on this virtual machine an empty 60 GB software hard disk,
so I'm just going to use that, in fact,
it's the only choice and we'll click Next.
That's all there is to it.
We're going to be asked some basic setup questions after it's installed,
but this is all there is to the actual installation.
As you see, it's getting files ready for installation,
it's going to go through this process, and it's going to restart at least once,
and then when we come back, like I said,
there'll be some final setup questions and we're off and running.
Here we're being asked to begin with for our home
region which I'll verify and click Yes.
We're asked to verify the keyboard layout.
Now you remember we were asked these questions at the very beginning.
I believe that it's added here at the end because of the
human tendency to just click Next, Next,
Next and blow past a dialog when they might realize,
the user might realize afterwards oh actually I wanted
to use a different keyboard layout.
Of course, you can always change that once you're in Windows.
I'm not going to add a second keyboard layout, that's fine.
It says we're connected and they'll check for any updates.
Let Windows do this.
I can't stress this enough.
It's critically important that you keep your
Windows 10 machine always up-to-date.
Yes, it can be inconvenient from time to time, but so worth it.
And you'll notice that the text here, found some,
hang tight while we get them installed was written intentionally to
make these messages as user friendly as possible.
Alright, this is an important question.
Are you going to sign into the computer using a Microsoft
account or are you going to do a local account?
That's what this domain join instead means.
Microsoft really wants you to sign in with your Microsoft account because it
conveys so many advantages with regard to synchronization,
and you know what, I actually agree with that.
So this could be a Microsoft account that you created for your own home use,
or if you're in business and your company uses Office 365,
you can also sign in using your Office 365 account and actually
that's what I'm going to need to do here.
I put the wrong account in there.
Let me put in my Office 365 account and click Next, pop in my password.
Notice that it says please wait while we set up your device.
You may be doing this on a full-fledged laptop or desktop computer,
but nowadays, the installer doesn't assume that.
You very well could be on a tablet computer.
If something goes wrong, which it looks like,
in this case, I'm going to choose offline account.
This is actually a good learning moment because the other
alternative you could either use a Microsoft account or an
account that's defined locally on the PC,
and if you go the local route, which I'm going to do now,
you supply a friendly name for that account.
This is going to be an administrator super user account.
What's your password, confirm said password,
add a hint, do we want to use Cortana or not.
Normally, I tend to say no, but you know what,
I really have to say I like Cortana.
You want to be careful with this here.
Again, especially if you're concerned with privacy.
Geolocation diagnostics adds speech recognition,
you can turn off the things that you don't want.
Accept to proceed.
Again,
you always can come back and make override choices later once you're in Windows.
We're just setting up initial defaults for this user.
It's working through the last step of setup.
It's basically creating,
Windows is creating my profile and preparing my desktop environment.
Here we go.
Now notice it says searching for display driver.
I've mentioned the term driver a lot.
This is the software that powers your installed hardware and Windows 10 has a
very current and robust library of device drivers so you should find that
regardless of who makes your hardware components,
including keyboard, mouse, etc,
Windows should do a pretty good job of finding the proper driver.
If that's not the case, then you can always go to the vendor's website,
look up the hardware,
and download the Windows 10 driver that way to give it support.
We're going to cover post installation tasks in the third and final demo of this module.