In this demonstration, we'll look at drive optimization,
built-in ones, in Windows 10.
Let me open the Start menu and type automatic maintenance,
and we can choose the Change Automatic Maintenance
settings to bring up the dialog.
This is classic Control Panel, as you can see,
and it tells us here that Windows will automatically
run the scheduled maintenance.
The only options you have, notice there's no on/off,
is to change when the maintenance tasks run,
I have mine set to 2:00 AM,
and whether to allow the scheduled maintenance to wake up
your computer at the scheduled time.
Well first of all, let me just read a bit of this explanatory text.
The Automatic Maintenance is stuff like running Windows Update,
running an antimalware scan, system diagnostics.
If we come back to Security and Maintenance,
it gives us this interface, and of course they're divided into two sections,
Security, which allows you to check whether you've got your firewall,
virus protection, browser security, and User Account Control enabled.
And then under Maintenance, we can open up the reliability monitor,
we'll look at that later in the course, we can start a maintenance activity,
or we can change maintenance settings in Automatic Maintenance.
The changing settings brings us back to where we started.
Let me expand this again.
Start maintenance will actually kick off the process.
And User Account Control, this is obviously an administrator task,
so let me authenticate as such,
and we don't see any obvious indication that it's going on.
I'm opening up the notification area here and looking for an indication.
If we right-click and go into Task Manager,
once again running as a standard user means that you'll be typing in
your password more often than you would otherwise.
And let's look at our processes.
I'll do an inverse sort by CPU.
It looks like it's running an antimalware scan right now.
So all this is happening in the background.
While that's happening,
let's continue our trolley ride through maintenance tools.
I'm going to open Start and type optimize,
and this allows us to open Defragment and Optimize Drives.
This is a desktop application,
and you'll notice if you've used Disk Defragmenter
in previous versions of Windows, now it's called Optimize Drives,
and the reason for that is if it's an HDD drive,
you can choose to run a defragment operation.
If it's a solid-state drive, what it will do is perform a trim operation.
Trim is effectively a method where Windows will examine your solid-state
drive on all of the pages that have data and those that are not necessary
any more that data is still being held on,
and it will free up that area of the disk.
The advantage of running trim is instead of doing individual
operations on individual blocks that consume the number of
read/write cycles that an SDD has in its lifetime,
it can do a mass clearing all at once.
As far as how we can change the settings,
again we have a User Account Control protected setting.
The default schedule is to run this weekly and to notify you if
three consecutive scheduled runs are missed.
And you can also choose which disks you want
involved in this optimization process.
So it's a basic control surface.
It's nice to have this enabled and scheduled to run.
The automatic maintenance is a nice sanity check where you don't have to
worry about running your antimalware scanner on a schedule.
Let's return to Start and type Disk Cleanup.
Again, this is a desktop app.
It functions the same way it always has over years.
It asks you which drive you want to clean up,
I'll choose drive C, and you'll see the categories of data that it inspects.
Downloaded Program Files, Temporary Internet Files,
Delivery Optimization Files,
that's where you're using Windows Update and the
Windows Update Delivery Optimization,
that's where you can download updates from other computers in a
peer-to-peer fashion to speed up update delivery.
Recycle Bin, Temp files, and Thumbnails.
And then there's a protected option for cleaning up system files as well.
Now there's third-party products.
You might have heard of CCleaner, and Defraggler, and Auslogics Disk Defrag.
I'm a big fan of the Diskeeper products.
They have an SSD keeper for SSD drives, and Diskeeper for HDD drives,
but I'm limiting myself to what's in-box in Windows 10,
and as a Windows 10 support professional/power user, it's important that you know where those tools are and how to use them.