Okay, it's time for us to examine diagnostic startup in Windows.
Remember I mentioned there are several ways to do it.
As long as you can do it from within Windows,
the easiest way I've found is to open the Start button,
click the Power button, hold down Shift,
remember, hold down Shift, not Ctrl, not Option,
but Shift, and with your Shift key held down,
click Restart.
That's going to force a restart of the system,
and it'll reboot into the Windows Recovery Environment,
which you see right here.
Now,
these screens are a review of what I showed you in the slides just a moment ago,
so we can proceed right to the details.
Let's go to Troubleshoot.
We're asked to Reset or go to Advanced options.
I want Advanced options.
Let's test some of these out.
We go to System Restore,
it's going to restart the computer again using 640 x 480 resolution,
at least to begin with,
so that's why the display might look a little wonky in your viewer.
It asks us to authenticate,
and I'm going to authenticate with my local administrator account,
supply my password, press Enter.
And because Windows RE is really a stripped-down version of Windows,
I do have access to the mouse, and we do have this graphical environment,
don't we?
And then we can see all of the restore points available on the system,
and we can work our way from there.
I'm going to cancel out, and now we're asked again to choose an option.
We can do a regular boot into Windows 10 or go the troubleshoot route.
We're going to go back to Advanced option.
System Image Recovery assumes that you used the Windows 7 tools to do an image,
and I did, in fact, create a system image backup.
It's stored on my F drive, and that's the latest one,
but if you have more than one or one in an alternate
location that Windows can't see right now,
we could choose select a system image.
And if I click Next,
we have the ability to inject custom drivers if we know
that they're not included in that image.
If we go to Advanced,
Automatically restart this computer after the restore is complete,
Automatically check the integrity of the disks.
So we're not going to go any further,
but this is going to set the entire system back in time
to the point at which this was taken,
and it tells us the most recently available is on January 23 at 9:27 AM.
Well that's two days ago, I don't want to do that.
So I'll cancel again, we'll go back to Troubleshoot,
go back to Advanced options, and we have Startup Repair,
Fix problems that keep Windows from loading.
This is going to run a low-level diagnostic and attempt a repair.
As you can see right on your screen, the system restarts,
comes back again, 640 x 480 resolution.
I don't think it's going to find anything to fix,
because my system is behaving okay.
So it's asking me to log back onto the system.
No problem, I'll re-authenticate.
And now we'll go back into diagnostic startup one more time,
but this time we'll do it through the Settings application.
In Windows Settings, I'll type restart and choose advanced startup options.
This brings us to Update & Security Recovery,
and under Advanced startup we'll click Restart now.
Again, those assume that we're already in Windows.
You may be in a troubleshooting situation where Windows won't start.
In that case,
you'll want to do a similar action by using your Recovery Drive USB stick,
the Windows 10 installation media,
or another method that you're using in your corporation.
Let's come back in Windows RE to Troubleshoot,
Advanced options, and our final stop on this journey is Startup Settings,
Restart to change these Windows options,
we'll restart, and here is the Advanced options menu.
And notice that there are three Safe Mode options.
Why would you want to do Safe Mode with networking?
Well,
one thing you might want to do is you're doing
low-level troubleshooting on the system,
and you want to make sure that minimal drivers are installed,
minimum services are started, but you still need networking access,
maybe to retrieve files from a local server,
download definition files from the internet,
and so forth.
If your system may be infected with malware,
don't choose that option because you don't want your system
communicating with the LAN or the internet.
I'm going to choose 4, which is regular garden variety Safe Mode,
and I'll authenticate using my local administrator account.
And, as I already showed you, we have our Safe Mode banners,
actually you're not seeing the taskbar,
it's being cut off in the screen recording,
I apologize about that.
Let me open the Run box and type services.
msc.
And if we sort by status, we see that very few services are running,
just the bare-bones what Windows needs to get running.
Anything else is not loaded, so this is great.
If you have a service that was set to automatic startup,
and it was causing your system to crash,
hang, or otherwise malfunction, this is your opportunity to come into that,
and perhaps set it to Disabled,
and make sure that it won't start the next time you start your system.
It allows you to come in to Add/Remove programs.
If you have software that's giving you problems or Windows
Updates that are giving you problems that are preventing
you from getting into Windows, you can come in and uninstall those.
And then if we just do a normal restart by using the power button restart,
the next startup will be normal boot,
and we'll be able to log into Windows normally, and hopefully everything is all fine and all ducky.