Cloud Storage.
I'm such a huge fan of cloud storage.
Yes, on one hand it's going to require some trust on your side.
You have to trust the cloud provider with your data,
but on the other hand,
I think Microsoft has done a good job of demonstrating how and
why they're a good steward of your data.
In point of fact,
check out the exercise files because I give you a link to
the Microsoft Trust Center website.
I give Microsoft strong kudos on their transparency.
They tell you right off the top that your data is yours and not theirs,
but nonetheless, they offer you enormous availability numbers,
the N number of 9s, 99.
99% availability, whatever it is,
and they also support a number of different regulations,
compliant certifications around the world.
Anyway,
the purpose of this slide is to differentiate
OneDrive and OneDrive for Business, which can be confusing for some.
Now OneDrive is a standalone service, cloud storage service,
that's aimed at the individual consumer.
It's directly competing with services like Dropbox,
if you're familiar with that, or box.
com.
It's a type of service where you can install the
client on just about any device, and have ubiquitous access to your data.
That's why I love it so much.
As I said, OneDrive for a consumer is individually managed,
and it's just general Software as a Service cloud storage.
The capacity is you get 5 GB for free,
and you can then purchase a subscription to go up to 50 GB of storage.
So you see, 50 GB it seems like a lot of data,
and to many people it is,
but it's not going to work in some business environments.
And in those cases, Microsoft wants you to consider OneDrive for Business.
And you can, in fact, use OneDrive for Business as an individual consumer,
but generally speaking,
OneDrive for Business is aimed at corporate clients who need central management.
The management hub here is Office 365.
Why do I say that?
Because OneDrive for Business,
instead of just being a generally abstracted SaaS cloud storage
where you put your files in your OneDrive and they just
automagically get replicated in the background.
OneDrive for Business will actually use a SharePoint
site as your OneDrive repository.
So it's natively tied into Office 365.
The storage capacities are much larger, 1 TB to start, up to 5 TB per user.
OneDrive universality.
I get a kick out of that word because if you look at this slide quickly,
if you look away from your screen and then look back at the slide,
it might say OneDrive university, or it might say OneDrive universe.
Anyway, I guess I'm easily amused.
This slide starts with a screenshot of File Explorer,
and you can see in the navigation pane that I've installed the OneDrive client,
in particular I'm using OneDrive for Business,
it says OneDrive - Office 365, and then you can store whatever you want in it.
As you see here, I'm not storing very much,
but it's addressable through Windows, just like any other local disk.
And any data that you save here is going to be replicated to Microsoft and
available anywhere else you can get to the OneDrive Client.
Of course the web interface is super ubiquitous.
You can get to it from anywhere.
Again,
this would be you'd log in with your Microsoft account if
you were just an ordinary OneDrive user.
If you are part of OneDrive for Business,
an Office 365 implementation, you would log into OneDrive via that,
via O 365, and if you look at the interface here,
and if you have familiarity with SharePoint,
it's meant to look like that because under the hood this is a
document library in your My Site as it's called,
in a SharePoint site collection.
Even more to the point,
Microsoft has OneDrive and OneDrive for Business
clients for iOS and Google Android,
and you can interact with your files same way, same song and dance.