Windows 10 Post-Installation Tasks.
Now I mentioned that you'll need to choose your edition when you
install Windows and you may not have had a choice,
like I said,
your original equipment manufacturer may have given you Windows 10
Home and then later you realize that you want to do some homework from
work and you need a professional edition,
how do you do that?
Well, it's nice that we have this anytime upgrade feature.
Again, we talk about upgrade later in the course,
so I don't want to spill too much now,
but I'll show you in the demo how to change the product
key and unlock different edition levels.
Common point of confusion for many,
even those in IT is understanding Windows 10 versions,
builds, and update branches.
Here's the deal, you look on the left side of the screen,
there are various servicing options.
This is used in business.
For a consumer user,
they're just going to use Windows update normally and you're off and running.
All I want to say about that is that when you're working with your friends,
colleagues, family, your customers,
make sure to encourage them to always keep Windows update on and functioning.
So much devastating malware,
ransomware comes to mind comes through unpatched operating systems.
I know that some people are resistant to doing updates.
Consumer customers of mine, for instance,
their main complaint is I don't want to install an update
that's going to change how I do my work.
In the business world,
administrators tend to resist update sometimes because they're
afraid of a failure of regression testing,
in other words,
this update may break line of business services that
are working just fine right now.
Thank you.
That's another discussion for another time,
but what I want you to know is that Microsoft when
they deployed Windows 10 to us, when they gave it to us,
there were a number of update branches that you could
associate with for a lack of a better term.
The Windows inside our channel is still around today
and this is for those brave souls,
both business and consumer customers who want to evaluate the latest
and greatest non-release versions of Windows 10 and the tradeoff
there is that you're asked to give feedback to Microsoft and it helps
them build the product better.
You see in the first column, all of these things,
long-term servicing branch, current branch for business is really confusing.
Fortunately now, we have basically three ways to update or service Windows 10.
In business, there is the Windows insider, which is not for production use.
You would do that only in your testing environment.
Semi-annual or targeted is the most common one and this is what customers,
what consumer customers have on their systems where Microsoft does
monthly patches second Tuesday of every month,
so-called Patch Tuesday, but twice a month,
you can expect in the Spring and in the Fall,
Microsoft will release a big update.
The Fall updates, for instance, are normally called the creator's updates,
at least they have for the last year or so.
And this allows IT administrators to budget time and testing resources
before they update all of the computers on their network.
The other way to go is the long-term servicing branch that you see down
at the bottom and that's for specialized devices.
That's not for ordinary desktop or laptop computers.
This is where you really could hose up something important
like a medical device by updating and then having a bug or
a problem rear its head.
So it allows you to get away with updating as infrequently as possible.
So just looking at that row there, the semi-annual channel row,
notice the version number, 1709, that actually is meaningful.
That means September 2017, the 17 is 2017, 9 is September.
So the previous big update this year, 2017, was in March 1703.
So that's the version,
that number will tell you how up-to-date your Windows 10 is.
The OS builds are less important for most people.
This is the specific detailed release that you're running.
That might be useful if you're doing troubleshooting and you've asked Microsoft for support.