In this demonstration,
I'm going to show you Device Manager and the basics
of hardware device management.
I'm going to open Start and type device manager.
This is a classic Control Panel utility,
and the interface is exactly the same as it's been ever since Windows 95.
We have all detected hardware, and in the case of undetected hardware,
it will show up at the bottom of the list.
And the idea here is you can expand the appropriate
sections to see what's going on,
double left-click an entry to determine whether the
device is in a problem state,
although there'll be icons that represent an exclamation mark or question mark,
there'll be --- or an X for that matter,
it'll show the state directly in the Device Manager tree.
You can inspect the specific driver that's being used here.
Go to Driver Details, it gives you the actual file name.
You can update the driver for a device, search automatically,
or browser your computer if you've downloaded the driver manually.
This is something that you'll use on a fairly regular
basis if you're doing PC support.
With troubleshooting,
sometimes it's a good idea to disable a device that
you suspect is causing problems, you can do that from here,
and then restart and use the system for a while,
and if the problem doesn't recur,
you can be pretty confident that the problem is related to that disabled device.
So there's not much more to say about Device Manager.
It is what it is.
It's a handy tool that also shows up in your Computer
Management administrative tool, compmgmt.
msc.
This in Windows 10 is a really nice rollup of several handy dandy tools
including the Task Scheduler for automatic tasks.
A lot of your Automatic Maintenance tasks actually will show up here.
If you look in the Task Scheduler library,
we have Device Manager right here as I said,
we have the Service Control Manager, which we've looked at earlier,
and we have Disk Management.
And for that matter, we have Local Users and Groups.
So we've used quite a few of these MMC consoles over the course of time.
If you feel that computer management is something that
you'll be returning to for a while,
perhaps you can pin it to your Start menu and make it easier to find.
Let me come back to PowerShell,
and I'm going to show you a command line tool called driverquery,
and let's do /?
in order to see its help.
This is simply a scriptable command line method for
displaying a list of installed device drivers.
It's as simple as that.
And we have a similar syntax here that we saw in the
previous demo with the systeminfo.
exe tool.
So as you saw, if you watched the previous demo,
I kind of bombed that demo because I'm not familiar with these switches.
I don't use them an awful lot.
And quite honestly, thanks to PowerShell, you don't have to memorize this.
You know,
if you're not convinced that PowerShell is really the way
to go for administrative automation,
let me just say that PowerShell has a consistent syntax that
once you learn the basic rules of the language,
you can apply it to any domain at all,
whether it's configuration management or whatever.
By contrast,
these old command line tools all have their own unique sets of parameters.
In this case, it's just coincidence that we have some repetition,
some of the parameters are the same as systeminfo.
exe, but just as likely, they're totally different.
So you wind up having to learn separate parameter sets,
many of which are unintuitive, per tool.
It's just not a scalable way to work.
Let me run driverquery with no other parameters,
and you can see if we do that,
it just gives us an alphabetized list of drivers that are
available from the driver store on this machine.
And you'll notice you'll see different categories,
File System drivers, that are relevant to the user equation,
what the user's interfacing with.
Many of these drivers operate at the Kernel mode,
which is where the operating system has permission to interact with the driver,
but the user doesn't.
There's a fundamental boundary line between what's called Kernel space,
or protected operating system space, and user mode,
which is where the end user can get involved. Just thought I'd give you that little bit of trivia, FYI.