So let's click OK here and Close and come back to our Windows 10 workstation.
I'm going to log on as someone who I know is only a member of domain users.
So let me open up the Start menu, come down to my user control, and do Sign out.
And I'm going to sign in as Liz.
I'm going to choose Other user, Liz, authenticate as her,
get her desktop, and we can browse to the server.
The server name is dc1.
There's plenty of ways that we can get to that server.
One direct way that you'll use as a systems administrator all
the time is universal naming convention,
backslash, backslash, server name.
That'll make a network connection across the domain to that controller.
So here we have the reports folder.
In a previous module,
I showed you that you can map a network drive by adding this shared
folder as a local or logical drive letter on this system,
but for now, I'm just going to browse into the folder.
And let's open up a DOC file,
and I'll choose More apps and choose to open it up in WordPad.
I don't have the Office Suite installed for this user.
Yikes, looks like we have some encoding problems.
Never mind the man behind the curtain.
What I'm trying to do is test the limits of Liz's permissions.
So what we're going to do is choose a part of the document,
randomly, it doesn't matter, delete it, and then see if we can make the change.
Now, actually,
let's do one more sanity check before we do that
because if we come back to the server,
look at the properties of the folder again,
remember right-click, Properties, go to Security.
We want to be absolutely sure that domain users only have read.
Now if you were, rewind your video and check it again.
You might notice that originally, I cut them down to read,
but I still had write enabled.
This is the view list of the access control list.
We want to go to Edit to actually make changes.
And if you scroll through the list here,
it's very easy if you want to just give read access,
to leave that write enabled.
So I actually deselected that and saved that change and then OK'd out.
Now behind the scenes where you don't see where I
stopped the recording and fixed things,
I had to log Liz Noto off and log her back on.
That's an important point for you to remember in the field.
When you make changes to access control lists,
the user will have to refresh his or her token.
They don't have to restart, but they have to log off and log back on again.
So after I made that change and after I logged Liz back on,
reconnected to the reports folder, opened up this file,
I'm going to make a change, click Save, and we see what we should see,
an access denied message.
So I want to finish this demo by again coming back to the
shared folder properties Security tab.
We go to Edit to make changes to the existing DACL.
If we go to Advanced, this unlocks a bigger interface where we can see four tabs,
Permissions, Share, Auditing, and Effective Access.
Now there's a lot more here than we have time to go over.
If you're having problems with inheritance,
you can come to, say, the subfolder level,
open this advanced view,
and you can see explicitly which security principles have been given which
access level and where the inheritance has taken place.
You see what I mean?
Now because I made changes to the domain users,
notice that it says Inherited from None,
because I made an override of that permissions inheritance.
This SYSTEM, trainer, and administrator's identities I did not add.
Those were all inherited from the parent object.
And if we look at the path here,
the parent object of reports is going to be my desktop folder,
which is C:\\Users\trainer\Desktop.
Ultimately, it all comes to the root of the volume,
which is drive C, so that's where you can make adjustments,
and disable inheritance, and replace.
Those are important troubleshooting steps.
But what I want to do is take us over to Effective Access because this is
where you can test what level of access a user has.
And what you do is you select a user.
I'll select Liz Noto.
I'll check her name to resolve it, bring it in.
To include additional group memberships besides the
one that she's already a member of, you can do that.
I'm not going to do that.
You can actually add permissions to computers as well,
so you have the ability to look for her computer.
I happen to know it's called ps1.
At least I think it's called ps1.
Let me go to Object Types and make sure we're looking at computers.
Yes, we are.
And we are looking at the domain.
Oh, it's not ps1; it's devbox; that's right.
So let me check that name and resolve that.
And then if we go to View effective access,
it gives us a run of specifically what she has.
And in this case, it looks like any changes to effective access,
the full control, for instance,
that comes from the shared folder is being limited by the NTFS file permissions.
She is able to list the folder and read the data and the file attributes,
but that's all.
She's got explicit read permission. This is a very useful tool that you'll use all the time in practice.