In summary, what have we learned in this module?
Well, first of all, just again, congratulations on completing this long,
in-depth journey.
I shake my head in amazement, and I taught it to you, this material.
I hope that you can answer this question with a rousing yes.
Are you more comfortable with Windows 10 now than you were when you began?
I encourage you to take a Skill IQ test in Windows 10,
and just demonstrate for yourself, not to mention your employer,
how your skills have evolved.
If you want to contact me,
you know how to do so based on the demo through the Pluralsight website,
but you can reach me via my work email address,
which is timothy-warner@Pluralsight.
com.
Please follow me on Twitter.
I post several times a day, always IT related, good, up-to-date current links.
That Twitter handle is TechTrainerTim.
And that's about it.
Thank you, one last time, for joining me on this journey.
I wish you all the best in your professional endeavors. Take good care.