Windows Defender SmartScreen.
Specifically,
Windows Defender is the anti-malware client that's built-in to Windows 10.
It's a very robust product now.
SmartScreen is a component of it.
Specifically, the defender family in Windows 10 is called,
well it's put under the parent application,
Windows Defender Security Center, and what SmartScreen does,
it's a live check against applications and files that you
attempt to download from the internet through,
say, Microsoft Edge, and compares those against known bad versions.
So a SmartScreen is screening your file downloads and your
application launches against its own database.
So this is going to require an internet connection to work,
obviously, and it's going to require that you turn this on,
and that you're okay with your files, you download file attempts,
and your application starts to be sent to Microsoft.
What's sent is only a hash, not any more information than that.
So maybe you're downloading WinZip, but you're not downloading it from winzip.
com, which is the official company site that owns that product.
It could be that you're downloading it from a rogue website that's
modified the WinZip installer to contain malware.
Well when you run a hashing algorithm, that is you apply,
say, a file, a binary file like the WinZip installer,
to an algorithm like MD5 it comes out with a certain result,
a hash let's call it, an alpha numeric string.
If you change one bit of that file and rerun the hash algorithm it's going
to have a totally different hash value or digest value,
so these hash functions are useful to detect changes.
What will happen is you go to download the rogue WinZip,
SmartScreen Database Online knows what the correct hash value should be,
if it differs you're going to get flagged and say,
wait a minute now.
This file does not match what it's supposed to.
Once again,
we have that issue of end-user training and helping them
not be numb to these kind of responses,
and there's also additional tools in the Windows Defender family,
particularly up in Office 365 where you can actually take
auto-remediation steps when SmartScreen flags something as
a possible security hazard,
but for our purposes today in Windows 10 we have
SmartScreen running in Edge to protect your device against
malicious website visits and downloads.
SmartScreen also runs behind the scenes in Windows Store
to check content used by your app.
So if you download or purchase a Windows Store app and it
wants to go out onto the internet to fetch a file
SmartScreen will capture that request, and once again, warn you if there's something that you might want to be concerned with.