[Autogenerated] Who are you and what do you need to know to for these calls?
Well, this is a cause about the Java I ve.
So of course you need to know little about Java.
It is mostly life coding and step by step demos.
My goal with this course is really to show you how to find your way
in this complex software that is called Eclipse.
Beside that, you need to have a fair knowledge off the javelin wage.
You need to be able to write a legal job application.
You need to know how is a job application organized?
What is a pack age?
What is a source?
File the combine and run a process.
You need to know little about what the job over to mission is.
What by code is the difference between the Java
development kit on the Java runtime environment.
Basically, in a nutshell.
In a Java development kit, you have all the tools to create job applications,
whereas in the j.
R E Java runtime environment, you don't have them.
A. And the difference between Java Standard Edition and Java Enterprise additions