[Autogenerated] And now let us jumping the demo off this Majola let
us create riel maven projects within Eclipse.
We will first create Defour projects using artifacts.
And then we will study the relationships between several maven
project within the same eclipse workspace.
We will see how to download the source code off maven
dependencies as longer they are available old,
and we will also run maven goals.
So we are now back in the eclipse i d e.
And before we see how to create maven projects,
let us check the maven configuration of eclipse.
It takes place in the window.
Menu preferences.
Options are it is open this painter more here,
we can filter on May Berna and we have all the options Maybourne has to offer.
The first we want to check in the installations a configuration
in which we can see that these version of eclipse comes with an
embedded version off May Virna,
version 339 If we check the user settings are we can see that the default
repository where Megan is going to re called all the artifact dependent
Caesar on Braganza is this Wallner hidden dot m two slash repository
within a you personal home directory.
Now these configuration works perfectly,
Wailer, as you can use it for this Majola.
But I am going to show you how to change it.
First, I am going to declare a custom version off.
May Virna Letters Adah this version A click directory here and directly
go to the right directory Which is this Warner click?
Ok, here we have a 350 version off.
May even installed a Let us click finish and select this
version as the one we want to use.
Click Apply.
It was go to the user settings.
Now change the settings that XML that we want.
Maybe 12 user.
So letters browser.
Let us go here in the cough directory.
I have my own setting that xml that I won't maven to use.
Let us open this.
You can click the update Settings are if you wish,
But now you can see that the local repository that is used
by this installation of Megan is deep.
Megan Repository, where I stole all the artifacts begins on the like.
It is quite important to do that,
especially if you're in a company environment where those repositories are
most of the time in standard places on development machines.
Let us apply in close, and now we have a properly configured maven installation within eclipse.