[Autogenerated] let us see all this in action.
A letters first, create projects in eclipse and configure git toe.
Handle the source code of those projects.
Then we are going to create commits on play with them.
We are then going to push a local repository to remote git
repository in give Herber and create a project from an
existing remote git repository.
So let us begin.
We have here a simple java, a C eight project that we want to share with get.
We want to control the source code of this project using it.
We are going to begin by configure this project and then create
some content in it and create comets using it.
The first thing we might want to do is go to the preferences of get so
window preferences are Let us make this little bigger filter on get here
and we have here a set off configuration option forgets there is one
that we're going to use right now.
This configuration here I am going to add the user that name with my name and
user dot emailer with my mail address on those two values are going to be used
by gate automatically to feeling the author on the email address under the two
inch Come it let us playing closer.
Now is the second step.
Let us create a git repository with this project.
We can do that with the pop up menu off the project.
The team option Here, choose a share project here.
If your local eclipse installation has a support for
other source control management system,
then get you will have an intermediate pain with for
instance as viene CVS Fear case, etcetera.
Here we have only get so let us create this repository in the parent folder.
Select the project here.
Click Create,
Repository finish And then we are done and we can see that visually speaking,
the appearance of the project in the package Explorer has changed the burial.
Now I have this greater than a sign in front of the project Icona.
And there is this little golden sitting there on this project
Icon to that shows that this project is handled. Bag it