[Autogenerated] so the first step is to connect Eclipse Toe,
an application server,
and the application server we are going to use as an
example is the Tomcat application server.
A clips needs a plug in for each application server
around and sometimes a different play gin for each
version of such an application server.
Now the good news is that eclipse for Java E developments
comes with already installed a Ginza, so we will not have to download those.
If this is the case,
If you're using special application server not supported by default by Cliffs,
then you need to go to the marketplace and download the right plug in.
Once this is Donna,
a connection to an existing server instance toe on existing
server installation must be established.
Let us see the big picture of the eclipse on the
application server organization.
As you remember, A Cliffs works with a special folder called The Workspace,
in which all our project folders are going to be stored.
In that folder,
there is a special dot meta data he didn't folder in which the different
connections to the well known application servers are is to order.
And once this is done,
each project can be connected to a given instance of an application server,
so the organization is exactly the same as the jail BBC organization we saw in the previous module.