[Autogenerated] let us now see how to create a simple maven project.
We are in the Java Sea perspective.
You can check it out at the top right off this interface.
And we're going to use the package explorer of you here and a pop up menu.
And you project we're going here to select project instead off Java project.
Since what we want to do is to create a maven project From
here we can filter May Virna to suggest the maven options
offered by the new project with ______.
And we have three options are take out existing married
project from source control management,
create a maven module or creative maven project,
and this is what we're going to click next.
We are going to skip the archetype selection A.
So just create a simple project.
Next.
As you know, a maven project is known by three elements.
A group i d.
An artifact 80 and version A.
So let us die.
Pena, A group i d an artifact i d, which is also the name of the Java project.
A loose Aries.
And let us simplify the version.
Number 20 that one letters creek finish and now the a Cliff Smith Virna,
begin as created Ello service project which has this form.
I just kept the message service plain java is he
project opened to see the difference.
A typical maven project as a four folders are two for the source code and the
test code and two for the resource is are both main and test resource is this
is the first difference but there is another one.
The default maven project is created depending on double fiver.
Java five has been released in 2000 for and there is very
little chance that this is what you want to do.
So we'll first need to change that.
And at last we have the bomb. That example five that has bean created for us.