[Autogenerated] EC lives, they find that several notions.
The first notion it defines is the notion of workspace in a jail.
Er workspace is a directory on your disk.
They can be as many workspaces as you want at a given time.
Only one instance of Eclipse works in a workspace,
and one instance of a cleaves can only work in a single
workspace a workspace can contain and can handle.
Several projects on those projects are going to share common
properties defined at the workspace level.
So one workspace is one folder, and one project is one sub folder in a workspace.
Suppose we have a workspace gold workspace.
Inside these workspace, there is a hidden subdirectories called dot meta data,
which contains a version dot any configuration filer.
It also contains the dot log file with the messages
Eclipse rights in case of errors, and there is also a dot log fire.
They can be also many subdirectories in these dot meta data directories
created by Eclipse itself or by one of its many plug ins and then the other
subdirectories For the Projects Project Wall Project to project three product
for and insider projects of directories.
There is one subdirectories called the dot sittings subdirectories,
which is a hidden subdirectories and 25 dot class,
path and DOT project.
Those elements contains a project level configuration.
We are not going to open them. Usually you do not need to change or edit those files or subdirectories by hand.