[Autogenerated] Okay, Let us close this window.
May Virna add dependency.
Look for the J Unit artifacts.
The one we're looking for begins with dear Unit.
And it is just this Warner.
We have all the details off the different versions of this artifact.
And since it is J unit, we have quite a lot of them.
The scope is the test scope because J unit is a test framework.
So let us other This dependency here it appears a directly in the palm filer.
We can also add a the Assert J dependency.
The one we're looking for is the Assert J.
Cole.
Let us grab the last version of it in the test scoop.
Adah, This dependency here, there's get rid of this bundle, er, sub element.
And here we have these Asser Jiko added automatically toe our project.
We can check that those dependencies have been added A by
opening the Maybourne dependency node here.
J unit has been downloader Gah er say Jay also,
and since Asa J depends on him,
Crest ham Crist has also bean downloaded automatically by maven.
If we open the J unit,
no doubt we can see that all the classes are off J unit are
excessive boulder through this interface.
But if we double click on it, the salsa off this base that's run a class,
for instance is not present.
Now the maven pra gehna is able to automatically download this
source code for us on This is the reason why we now see the
source code appearing automatically.
And if we check precisely the icon used to represent
the J unit for the 12 the job filer,
we can see that there is this little detailer in front of this white job
which tells us that the source code has also bean downloaded.
It is not the case for him, Crist or as a J,
but we do not needed to open a class off those dependencies
toe automatically download the source code.
We can do that directly through the interface.
With the pop up menu off this dependency May Virna download So Sousa it will
automatically download the source and the same for as a J.
We can see the Progress bar currently downloading the source Soza.
And once it is down, it will refresh the interface automatically.
We can do the same for the documentation.
Ana may Virna download Javad ACC.
Now we have both the source code on the documentation of those dependencies.
Now that we have properly configured our dependent Caesar,
our test class is compiling properly.
The Assertions class has been founder, and by the way,
we can control click on it to check it.
So Skoda on the same for the test annotation which comes from Jay in it.
And we can runner I with this class run has a Jay any test.
It is a maven project and still an eclipse project.
So all the functionalities provided by Eclipse are still working in this kind of project.