[Autogenerated] let us add a, for instance,
to string method to our use a class by using the card generator
utilities from Eclipse Let us commit this modification A added to
string method a come it and you can say in the Serie that this commit
is automatically added to the list.
Now suppose we want to check out this commit in particular you know that it is
not a good habit when using gate to check out directly commit you better create
a branch on that commit and check out the branch.
So let us do this Wrong finger take out and you see
that a cliffs is giving us a warning.
It does is that by doing that we went in the detached head state.
It means that we are not on the local branch.
So if we want to do some modification and check them in, we will have trouble.
We might lose our commits.
So how can we go back one step?
How can we find a the last commit we had previously?
The problem is that by default this history view only shows the
current commit on the previews commits of the resource we have
selected And even if we see like the project itself,
it does not show us the commits.
After the comet we have checked out to see all the comets on all the branches
are we need to check this button on the Easter review show.
Old branches and tags are.
Let us do that.
And there we can see the commit.
We are honor under commits after that so we can go
back to the master branch here, check out this and we are back to the correct state.