[Autogenerated] Let us see now how we can push this
repository to a gettable repository.
That is a cloud repository.
Basically, what we're going to do and what I'm going to show you,
is the same as pushing toe any repository get.
UB is a well known and popular repository for open source projects.
So I think it's interesting to see this example will get help.
So for that, I'm going to open my get up account, create a new repository.
Let us call it sample, Get for oversight.
This is a simple repository for my Prue oversight
cause eclipse for Java developers.
A.
Of course, it is a public repository.
I do not want to initialize it with a read me because I
am going to push some content to it.
And creating a read may would create a first comet in this repository
which will create problems with this push operation.
So let me create this repository.
It's pretty fast, and I am going on this page to copy paste this u R l which is an http s Euro