[Autogenerated] So first let us create a first class in this project.
We can open it like that to create a class we can see like the
SLC Fuller knew and class from the pop up menu.
Or,
if you prefer to use the tool bar a new class from
these button from the toolbar.
The result is of course, the same.
We are going to put our class in a package A because using the default
package or the empty back agia is not recommended in Java.
In fact, you should not be doing that, especially in Java.
Naina and we are going to create an L A world class.
Let us ask Eclipse to create a main method for us.
Click finish. And now, in the middle of you, we have our class opened in the Java Editor.