[Autogenerated] In order for this to work, we need to other too dependent.
Cesar to the pom xml off our Maybourne descriptor.
The first Warner is the devil e dependency from the Djebbour X back Agia
Here it is on the one we need is the Java e web a p i.
Since we are only using the web profile of the E.
And the second dependency we want to add a is the J S T
Ella Java server tag labor library,
which is either this one on the two or even the Java X that
several it one do not use the JST l a dash a p I because this
is not the one we want to use.
Okay, Once we've done that,
we can create our jsp filer users a dash least dot jsp there is click finish.
Let us check that these users dash list The jsp is indeed a the
fight to which we are forwarding the request,
which is the case.
We are going to other first tag labor Here, take labour.
The prefix is the standard one c and the your eye.
Eser.
Http java dot Sana that comma slash jsp slash j STL slash
call If you make a mistake in typing this,
you arrive for instance You forget the e u will have an error
message from the Js people again of eclipse telling you that this
year I is not recognised So this is Ah, I were uses list.
It's too uses list is the full winger We are going to use the
forage tagger from the standard tag laborer Reza,
let us take a user As of our on items are will be request scope that user
list And for each user we are going just to display the user that name
Karam User that age our Jsp is now correct.
If we want to runner our project, we can also drag and drop it on the Tomcat.
Noda from the servers view Launch Tomcat by clicking on this but IRNA
the console should tell us that everything is fine.
Then go back to our Crume application A make a request on
user Dutch list and here we have the list of the users of
that has been sent by the separate.
We can just check that this is correct.
Let us go back to the Sublette modifier.
The ages.
For instance, 22 here, When you modify or serve, let Tomcat has to be restarted.
Republishing the web is not enough.
So let us do that.
Restart the server by clicking this button.
This is Donna.
Go back to Chroma Refresh. And indeed, the ages have been updated.