[Autogenerated] let us add some more content to our user class.
We are going to add a a constructor and shift s generate
constructor using the name and age fielder.
And we are also going to keep the empty constructor.
Since we do not want to make hibernates Onda like fail, let us come in.
This added the constructors are income it And it turns out that having to
enter a password every time we want to push stuff toe our git repository is
quite annoying And for some security reasons,
we do not want to record.
I will use the name and password inside the Eclipse configuration fight.
There is another solution to provide credentials to get Herber on other git
remote repositories which is to come with a key and use Ssh!
So let us do that.
We are going to delay the push configuration we just created a we already
have configured in our get up settings are an ssh key And what we are
going to do on this repository interface is,
for instance, click the cloner or download button here,
select here user is his age and copy to clip board the SS age.
You are I for this repository.
Let us go back to eclipse First are we need to.
Terry Cliffs were to find our private key.
This is Donna in the preferences of here.
Siddiq Tina is this age as message to add the private key here?
My private key is there.
Open it now.
It has been added to the list of the known of private keys by eclipse.
By the way, if you want to generate a private and public key pair,
you can do that from within eclipse, using the optional apply and closer.
And now we need to configure push once again,
change A The s s age stuff appears here automatically.
Here, you need to select the ssh Protocol.
If it is not correctly configured by default,
you do not need to enter any password here.
Click finish advanced and we are presented with the same
configure push window that we already saw letters at old
ranches and at old tags here.
And click finish.
If your key is configured er to be protected by your password,
a cliff's would have asked you toe enter that password previously.
Let us say that Bush here is the report for the push Operation A.
Let us close this and check on the project The commits for
the master branch the other the constructors commit has been
properly added to the repository.
So this is much moral easy to user.
You can just Freedy push and fetch and walking to see the fetch
operation in just a minute without having to enter password.
Since the eclipse get pro Ginna is able to Delia with private and public key pairs are on the SS age protocol.