[Autogenerated] we still have two elements to cover,
which are the same but in two different context which
consists in a fetching repository.
Locally, when we have no code locally.
So here I just closed the the sample get project.
I will still be using this simple get project from Get Herber on.
What I want to do is to import it locally so that I can go
in the package Explorer pop up menu,
select the import options here that is open this or
it'll I have This gets no doubt there.
So I can imported projects from a git repository.
I am going to use a cloner.
You are I here I am presented with the same kind of window as the fetch window.
We already so the u airai is the get your IRA using ssh
that does he liked SS age protocol Here.
Click next.
Since we have already configured eclipse to connect to get eclipses able
to query this git repository to get everything here,
let us click next.
We are going to create this project locally in sample,
get for poorer sight and automatically get will register this
remote repository as the origin repository keeping you this
configuration it is Click next and we are going to import this
project as a general project.
The name of this project will be the same as the repository Letters Click
Finish on Now we have this project created here for us.
The problem is that this project as search is not seen as a Java project.
Why?
Because we decided not to push the dot project on the dot class path
Eclipse configuration Pfizer to get Herber so Eclipse could not
recognize this project as a Java project.
Once we've done that,
we need to tell Eclipse that this project is a Java project.
So select the project.
Pop up menu properties.
Oh,
here we are going to select the project Facets from this property
windows convert to faceted former Just select java here,
select a run time here which is a Java eight,
her playing closer and we are down.
We now have a proper Jeff project.
So those steps other steps you want to follow when you want to import an
existing Java project from a remote repository locally.
By the way, if we check the git repositories er of you,
we can see that in the remotes.
Noda, the guitar repository, has been automatically configured with proper push and fetch operations