[Autogenerated] Now what we would like to do is go to the next
level and create an enterprise level application.
So let us create a second project Nujoma Project.
We are going to use the same Jaedicke 88 version of this project and call
this project message service eclipses warning us because by default we're
still using a Java nine compiler for that.
In fact, the Javan nine compiler is still set up at the workspace level.
So all the Java projects we are creating in this workspace are going to inherit
this property that has finished this open message service.
Open the properties of it.
Check the compiler and shake here enable the project.
Specific settings are click on the gun figure project settings.
And now from here we can select Java eight.
Eclipse is giving us another warning because by default it is going to use
a Java nine a virtual machina to create our project.
We can also override this by selecting here jk eight instead of J d.
K.
Nine.
Let us apply in close.
We will go through a full rebuild, of course. And now things are configured, Jeff eight at the workspace level.