[Autogenerated] Now what we want to do here is Creator,
the class message service.
You know, back a job order tomorrow.
Service finish.
And in this class,
we will have a single method public ________ that get Miss Ager return head.
Oh, well, the and what we would like to do,
of course, is used this service in our area.
Well,
class message service message service equals new message service
and replace this string here by message service.
That good message?
Of course it doesn't work.
Why?
Because message services declared in another project,
then the first project where the other world class is.
What we need to tell Eclipse is that these first project
is depending on the message service.
To do that, we can see, like the properties of this project.
But in the bill path Adah,
the project message surveys as a dependency to the
first project we just created.
Now, First project knows message service.
So if I ask you cliffs to fix the imports of this
class by using control shift Oh, as a shortcut,
it will be able to import message service.
And if I runner the year world class by clicking on
this button it will work properly.
So this is how you can declare dependencies between your Java project.
Go to the properties of a project on the bill path here, project Abba, you just add the project you need as dependencies to this project.