[Autogenerated] So for the last step of this life coaching session,
I would like to generate an executable jar off our little project.
For that, we need to go to the pop up menu of the project.
Chose the export option here,
select the Java Noda from this list and the jar file here.
So what we're going to do is export our project in a
jar file and make it executable.
Notice that you also have a rentable jar file as an option.
And this is not the option we are going to choose like
next from this panel we can select.
The resource is we want to export.
So what we want to export is of course,
the classes from the aga dot Omar package off first project.
We do not want to export the dot class path on the DOT project.
We will see those fires later in his calls and from the message service.
Since this is a dependency,
we want this package the or dot Come out that service package.
Of course,
we do not want the SLC dash test package in which we put our test classes.
We are going to export this in this jar file here.
First dash project slash jobs slash first project dot Jaw compressed
the content of the job fighter All this is correct.
Pick next here.
All the default options are correct.
We are not going to launch the construction of the job
fighter if we have compiled errors anyway.
And we want to say the description of the job in our first project
here First project and put it as first dash project.
OK, eclipse as the job desk extension to this fire automatically click next.
Indeed, we want to generate a manifest for this job.
Feiler The manifest is the file inside the jar fire that is
going to describe the content off the job.
Filer, if you want to seal this job, you can also choose this option here.
And we are going to select a main class to make this jaw rentable.
Okay.
Here.
The main class will be declared in the manifest for us letters.
Click Finish.
Eclipse is going to create this location for us automatically.
Let us refresh this project.
Eclipse has created this job folder inside the project with
the first project dot job fire in it.
We can open it using a win ra in it.
We have indeed the order from our l A world class and
service message service that class.
So we have all the classes we need for my to project
first project and message service.
And if we check in meter dash in, if we have the manifest that MF class,
that is you it and inside the main class as being a properly declared,
let us check the properties of the job with the ELT enter short cat.
Here we have a butternut that would show this job in a system explorer.
We can then open a common Tuller.
Let us run, eat Java dash jar first project the job and indeed this file is correctly run.