[Autogenerated] for the moment, these database instance is empty.
There is no table it.
So what I want to do first is to connect to these
databases and create the right table.
For that,
we're going to use a special view available in Eclipse Window Show view,
other, which is the data source Explorer.
Let us open the view.
These you could appear anywhere on the perspective.
So if you want to drag and drop it from one place to another,
you can just do it like that as usual.
And by the way, if you are using the Java e perspective of Eclipse,
the data source Explorer is already opened.
In this perspective, let us switch back to the Java.
Is he perspective?
For the moment, this data source explora is empty.
What we're going to do is create a database connection
from this node here Buffet menu new.
What we want to create is a connection to my sequel server.
And we are going to call this my sequel Connection profile max equal per site.
Click.
Next.
There is no driver available here.
This drop down list is empty.
So let us click on this button to create a new driver definition.
What we want to create is a J BBC driver to the 5.1 version of my Sequera.
So let us create this one.
Switch to the journalist here.
There is just a placeholder telling us the name of the fight we are looking for.
So at this point, you need to know where.
For instance, in your maven repository,
your my sequel Jdb see driver he's located.
It is located here, so I can just open it.
I can get rid of this Warner switch to the properties of this driver.
The connection your Ella will be to local host slash per site.
The database name is per site.
The user i d is also parasites.
And by the way, the password is also parasite.
Let us click.
Okay?
We are going to save the past Werder in the eclipse configuration file,
which is not necessarily very safe.
And we can test the connection here.
The connection is okay.
Meaning that eclipse has found the right driver
that the database is open running.
The your ella is correct.
Database name is correct and the user and password are also correct.
Let us click next.
We can review here.
The different properties we set up, they are all correct.
So let us click.
Finish here.
Now we have a database connection in a available here.
And if we open the parasite Noda, we see this key Mazza, the parasite user as access to and see that there is no table in this database.