Hello everyone.
In this lesson we will create our own modal or overlay.
This feature is also sometimes referred to as a light box just so you and I are on the same page.
Here's a bit of preview footage of the finished product.
All right.
So now we know what we need to build.
Let's get started and make it happen.
Here's a quick overview or roadmap for the lesson.
First we will take care of our get branches.
Next we will set up the h t AML and C Ss for the overlay.
We won't worry about hiding it yet.
We will just let it always display during this phase.
And finally we will use javascript to hide the overlay initially and only reveal it if an appropriate
button is clicked.
All right let's start up at the top.
Number one and take care of our get branches.
So over in the command line we can see that we currently have the sticky header branch checked out and
in our previous lesson we completed the sticky header behavior.
So now let's go ahead and merge this branch back in the master.
And then once we've done that we can create a new branch for our modal or overlay.
Let's begin by running get status to see what files have changed recently.
All of these changes look good to me so I'm going to add everything to my staging area.
So get add dash uppercase a for all.
And then we just want to commit everything that's in the staging area.
So get commit.
Let's include dash M so we can include a message.
And let's say completed sticky header functionality.
All right.
So now that we've made a commit we've saved those changes into gets history.
So this means we can safely switch back over to the master branch so we can say get check out master
and now that we've checked out the master branch we just want to merge the sticky header branch into
it.
So let's say get merge sticky header All right.
So now our master branch is up to date at this point.
Let's create a new branch for this lesson's modal or overlay.
So get check out dash be for branch and then the name of the new branch that we want to create.
Let's call it create modal.
All right.
So at this point we've got our new branch.
Let's get to work.
Let's jump over to our text editor and within our app folder let's open up index thought H TMM.
If we scroll down to the very bottom of this file right above the closing body tag and our script tag
we see commented out each TMM All right.
Here's the closing comment.
This is the end of the modal reference HDMI and if you scroll up a few lines you'll see the opening
comment it reads.
Leave this comment it out HDMI here until you need it for an upcoming modal lesson.
So this is that lesson.
So go ahead and get rid of this top comment line.
So just select this entire line.
Get rid of that and then go ahead and get rid of this bottom comment line.
This entire line.
Okay.
And if we save this back in the browser down at the very bottom of the page we see get in touch and
we will have an online order system in place soon.
So on and so forth.
Now clearly this does not look like a full screen modal.
Right now it's just the raw each demo.
So now let's write the CSA s to make this area look visually or stylistically like a modal.
Once we have the design or styling taken care of then we can set things up so it's hidden by default.
And then when you click on the get in touch button it reveals this full screen area.
So let's set up a new CSX file to style the model so in our text editor in app assets styles let's create
a new file in the modules folder let's name the new file underscore modal dot see ISIS before we forget
let's jump into our main style sheet and import in this new model file so open up your main styles dot
CSX down at the very bottom.
Let's just say X symbol import modules and grab the file named underscore modal semicolon.
Let's give that a save and then jump back into our new modal CSX file.
Let's create our baseline selector.
So dot modal OK now let's begin by making this modal area take up the entire screen and be a bit transparent.
So let's say position fixed.
So this way even if you scroll the modal still takes up your entire screen.
Since we're using fixed positioning to make the model take up the entire screen we can just set its
top bottom left and right values all to zero right the extreme edges so top zero bottom 0 left 0 right.
0.
Okay let's give it a slightly transparent white background color so background color RGA to create white
you max out the red green and blues 255 255 255 and let's set its opacity to ninety four percent right.
So it's 6 percent see through.
So my colon.
Let's also set its z index to 5.
So it sits on top of all the other content on our page.
Okay.
Let's save this and see what it looks like so far cool.
So notice as we scroll.
It doesn't matter.
This section still takes up the entire screen.
It is layered on top of everything.
It's looking good.
Next.
Let's set things up so that this content is centered vertically within the height of the browser viewport
involve we're at it we can also set this X. It's a bit small right now but you can see this X that you
would click on to close the modal let's position it so it sits in the very top right corner so back
in our CSX within our baseline rule here.
I want to set it to use flex box to display flex.
You'll see why we're setting this up in just a moment.
Now within this rule let's dropdown and let's target the inner wrapper div so ampersand which will give
us dot modal and then we want to add on underscore underscore inner curly brackets.
Let's set this to use all the available space.
So flex one semicolon and then if we say margin auto.
Well this in combination with Flex box will center it.
Okay.
After this inner rule let's dropdown and target that close or that x button that you would click on.
So use our baseline selector underscore underscore.
Close curly brackets and let's just position it to be in the top right corner so position absolute.
Let's have it come down from the very top 15 pixels.
Let's also have it come in from the right 15 pixels right.
15 pics.
Let's go ahead and save and see what this looks like.
Cool.
So the actual content is now centered vertically.
The X icon is positioned where it should be next.
Let's adjust the text or font styling of this message here.
So back in our CSX it doesn't matter where but maybe right after the inner rule we can create a new
rule Ampersand underscore underscore description and let's center it horizontally.
So text align center let's increase the font size a bit font size maybe one point three ram let's make
sure the font isn't too thick so font weight three hundred and let's bump up the line height a bit so.
Line height.
One point six five.
Let's see what that looks like.
Go ahead and save.
Okay.
This text styling looks good but the spacing looks off.
So first of all there's too much vertical space between the headline and this text and then also I wouldn't
want this text to be able to use up this much width.
I think it should be constrained to the center portion of the screen like this.
Now to make these changes let's actually jump into our each PML instead of our CSA s at first towards
the bottom of our HDL file.
I want you to find the modal div now a few lines into the modal code you'll see a heading Level 2 that
is reusing our section title.
But notice it has a modifier class of section title dash dash less margin.
Also we have this extra wrapper div id it has a modifier of dash dash narrow.
So I've already written this HDMI for us but if we go add these modifier classes for wrapper and section
title that will take care of these issues that I was just describing.
Let's start with the section title Let me show you what I mean within our CSA as modules folder jump
into our section titled dot CSX file.
So down around line 14 we have a blue rule maybe right below the blue rule.
Let's create a less margin modifier class so Ampersand dash dash less margin curly brackets and let's
just set margin bottom to only be one point three ram and let's set margin top to zero.
Let's give that to save.
Cool.
So now there's a bit less spacing in between these two elements.
Next up let's work on the narrow wrapper.
So within your CSF modules jump into the file named underscore wrapper dot CSX.
We already have a modifier rule four dash dash medium so maybe right below that.
Let's just say Ampersand dash dash narrow.
Instead it's Max with two maybe four hundred and seventy pixels.
Let's give that to save cool.
I think this text looks a lot better when it's constrained to the middle portion of the screen like
this.
Next let's fine tune the styling of the X close icon right.
It should be a bit larger or easier to see.
So back in our modal dot CSX file if we scroll down a bit.
We already have a rule for the clothes icon so within that rule we can just increase the font size to
to ram let's also make it blue color.
And we can use our variable dollar sign main blue give that save cool.
Now I think it would look even better if it was stretched a bit.
So it was wider and not as tall.
Right.
So that it actually looked like a close X and not just the letter X from the alphabet.
Right if we squished it it was a bit wider to do that.
We can just say trans form and use the scale X function within these parentheses a value of one will
keep it the exact same size but if we say one point two well we are stretching it on its x access to
be a bit larger.
Sure include a semicolon here.
Now before I save this I do want to point out that I want to increase the width from the top right corner
as its pivot point because I want to maintain the perfectly spaced out 15 pixels of margin from the
top right corner.
So I want the element to grow in this direction right starting here and moving out like this.
So to do that we just want to set the transform origin point to 100 percent to mean the far right corner
and then zero to mean the top upper corner.
So my colon.
And while we're at it let's also set the cursor to be a pointer so that it looks like a link or something
you're supposed to click on when you hover over it.
Give that save.
Cool.
That looks a lot better and if you hover over it it looks like something you should be able to click
on.
If we wanted to we could even set up a hover rule so when you hover it it turns orange as well.
So right after this color line we can say Ampersand colon hover and just set the color to main orange
perfect.
Okay.
At this point we just need to style these social media icons that should sit right about here.
Now they already exist in the HDMI L.
We just can't see them because they are white icons sitting on a mostly white background.
So we have Facebook Twitter Instagram and YouTube links here.
Now instead of writing all the styling for those links within our modal file let's create an entirely
separate file just for the social icons.
So within our CSF modules folder let's create a brand new file and let's name it underscore social icons
dot CSX.
And before we forget let's include this file within our main style sheet.
So at the bottom of styles dot CSX say import modules underscore social icons semicolon.
Let's give that a save.
OK now back and social icons.
Let's create our baseline selector.
So dot social icons.
Let's begin by centering everything so text align center.
OK.
And then each of the four icons write the Facebook Instagram the YouTube and the Twitter.
Each one of those has a selector of underscore underscore icon right or social icons underscore underscore
icon.
So let's say Ampersand underscore underscore icon.
Let's begin by giving them a background color so we can actually see them.
So they're not a white icon on a white background.
So background color.
Let's go a dollar sign.
Main orange.
Let's set their display to be inline block.
Let's set their width to be 72 pixels their height to be 72 pixels.
Let's give them a bit of margin around each one.
So zero top margin five pixels to the right five pixels to the bottom and five pixels to the left.
OK.
And still inside this same rule or selector lets just drop down and with a descendant selector let's
select the image inside each one of these.
So just I AMG let's tell it to be a block and let's position it so it's centered within the orange background
area so position absolute.
If we're setting this to be position absolute we should set the parent to be relative.
So position relative and then back in this new rule come down from the top halfway.
50 percent come in from the left 50 percent and then we want to pull it back up into the left half of
its own size.
So transform translate negative 50 percent comma negative 50 percent.
So both vertically and horizontally.
Let's give this a save and see what it looks like.
Cool.
So for larger screens this looks great but for smaller screens I think we should adjust things so that
exactly two icons fit Perot.
So let me show you how I would do that back in our social icons file within our icon rule maybe right
after position relative I would use our Mixon named at small.
So super tiny screens will receive the baseline styles while screens that are at least small or larger
will receive these styles.
So in here we can say with 72 pixels but within our tiny baseline styles let's change the width so that
it's no longer 72 pixels and instead is 33 percent.
Let's give that a save cool.
So now for mobile or tiny screens we get exactly to Perot but for larger screens we still have the four
wide grid and that's going to bring this video but not this lesson to a close in our next video we will
begin writing javascript to interact with our CSX so that when you first come to the page this full
screen modal is hidden and then only once you click the get in touch button this will gradually fade
or zoom into view.
Right.
And we'll also set things up so that when you click on the X icon the model goes away.
There should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next video.