Hello everyone in this lesson we will get back to writing C Ss to be more specific.
We will clean up the styling for this large hero block down at the mobile small screen view and also
for all screen sizes.
We will begin working on this intro section if we look at our design file.
We see that that section is supposed to look like this.
All right so let's get started.
The first thing that I want to work on is cleaning up the mobile styles for this section.
So the first problem that I noticed aside from these font sizes needing a bit of attention is the fact
that this text is pushed up against the very far left and right edges of the device.
And from a design perspective that is something that you want to avoid at all costs.
So let's work on adding a bit of spacing or padding on the left and right sides.
So let's jump into our text editor and make that happen.
Now our first instinct might be to open up the large hero CSSA file since that is the block that we
are looking at.
However we need to ask ourselves is wanting content to not push up against the very edges of the screen
unique to this block or is that a pattern that we could use again and again throughout the page.
Well I think we can answer that by moving our eyes down the page about 100 pixels to this section.
We don't want this content to push up against the far edges either.
So clearly this is a design pattern that we're dealing with.
So because this isn't unique to the large hero block instead of writing CSSA in this large high profile
Let's go ahead and create a new module.
Let's name this new file underscore wrapper dot CSX.
Let's create a class named wrapper and let's give it a bit of padding on the left let's say 18 pixels.
And let's also give it a bit of padding on the right so we can save this file and be sure to go into
our main styles does CSSA file and include an import that points towards the new wrapper file.
So go into the modules folder and grab underscore wrapper.
Go ahead and save this file.
And now we can use this new wrapper class in our HMO.
So let's open up our index that each TNL file.
Let's scroll down a bit to find the large heroes section.
Here it is.
So where do we want to add that new wrapper class to add left and right padding.
Well we know that we want the picture itself to be full width so we don't want to apply any padding
to this main parent element.
We only want to apply the padding to the text content so down here this div that houses all of the text
content.
Let's go ahead and wrap these elements.
So starting with the H one and ending with the paragraph.
Let's wrap these within a new div an extra div.
So right before the H-1 and create a new div and give it a class of room for and then right after this
paragraph add the closing DIV tag.
And then let's be sure to select from the paragraph to the age 1 and indent just to stay organised.
So go ahead and say this.
And if we check the browser We now have the spacing that we wanted.
Next let's fine tune the font sizes for these elements.
So to do that let's open up the large hero does CSSA file and I'm going to resize my text editor so
we can see the browser in the background.
So let's begin by fine tuning the font size for this your clarity element.
Here is the CSA as rule for that element.
So right now it has a baseline font size of 1.1 Renn and that is clearly too small.
I think we can afford to have a larger font size even at the Mobile view.
So let's try to round let's increase that just a little bit with 2.4.
Looks good to me.
And we can obviously afford to use a larger font size for larger screens.
Now in an earlier lesson we set up three media queries for this element because we were really trying
to drive home the point of how to use a mixin but in reality I think this is overkill.
I think as soon as the screen gets to this at small size we can begin to use the full 4.8 size.
So let's change this to four point eight RAM and let's just delete this at medium.
And this at large mixing.
All right.
Next I think we can afford to bump up the font size of this one chip away element.
So here is the rule for that element.
Let's change the font size from 1.1 to 1.5.
Looks good.
Next let's shrink this font size quite a bit.
But scroll down.
In our CSSA file here is the rule for that element.
Now we want to leave this font size in place for desktop large screens but we do want to set a smaller
baseline font size.
So let's copy this line down here.
Let's use a mix in mix in as small.
So once a browser window is large enough to at least be considered small instead of microscopic or tiny
which is our baseline then we can use a font size of 1.8 But let's lower the baseline to something like
1.1 that looks a lot better.
Next let's lower the font size of this button for small screens.
So the CSSA for this button element lives in the modules folder in the button CSSA file.
And if we look in our HVM DML to find that button so I can search for get started today.
Here is that element and we see that it is using a ben modifier class of button dash dash large.
So back in the button file we want to edit this rule.
So I think this font size is OK for larger screens.
So let's create a mix in and say at small.
Go ahead and use that font size but for smaller screens or for our line I don't think we even need to
define a font size at all.
So that will just default to one run.
I think that looks a bit better.
All right so at this point I think the large hero block looks excellent on a smartphone and all of our
styles that target larger screens are still in place.
Let's check the design files to see if we forgot anything for this block.
I think the only thing we're missing is this blue bar that runs along the bottom.
So let's add that in really quickly in our large hero does CSSA file that scroll to the very top.
And within this main large hero role puts out a new line and we can create this bar by using the border
property.
So let's say border bottom.
How thick should the border be.
Let's see.
That looks like about 10 pixels to me.
So it's a border bottom 10 pixels solid and what color do we want to be.
We can just use our main blue variable.
Let me open the browser in the background and then save this CSSA file and we see that the blue bar
was added but there's this tiny white gap in between the image and the blue bar.
And we don't want that gap.
The reason this gap exists is because our image element is an in line level element instead of a block
level element.
I will explain what that means in just a moment but first let's switch the image to be a block level
element so we can get rid of the gap.
So in our C Ss for the large block we don't currently have a rule that targets the image file.
So in our each T.M. how let's scroll up a bit here is the picture element and we want to add a class
on this image element that it contains so that we can select it with RC SS.
So let's give it a class of large hero because that is the block that it belongs to.
And using the Bembe system to signify that this is an element we use to underscores and let's name this
element image.
All right.
Now back in our CSSA file we can select the image by creating a new rule.
And let's just tell it to be a block level element.
So as soon as I save this file the gap will disappear.
And there you have it.
Now if you're wondering how this works.
Here's a quick explanation by default web browsers treat image elements as line level elements.
What does that mean.
What is an inline level element.
Well it basically means that the browser thinks the image is similar to a line of text.
Right so if we change this to in line the gap comes back and that's because when the browser thinks
that this might be a line of text it wants to leave a little bit of room for the bottom part of certain
letters that hang below the rule.
So if you think of a G or a Y you get the idea.
So by declaring that the image should be a block level element we are telling the web browser that it
should treat the image almost as a div right so it treats it as a rectangle that can align perfectly
without worrying about leaving any room for bottom parts of letters.
All right let's change gears.
So at this point our large hero block is complete.
Now let's move on and begin styling this intro area.
If we check out the design once again we see that that section should look like this.
So the question becomes where do we begin.
How do we begin to transform this into this.
Well let's just work our way down from the top to the bottom.
So the first piece of the design that I see is this empty space this white space here.
So if we look in the browser that space doesn't exist now to create the vertical spacing that we want.
Our first instinct might be to add bottom margin to the large block or to add top margin to this heading.
But before we do either of those things I think we need to stop and ask ourselves a question is wanting
vertical spacing between sections of the page unique to this area of content or is that a design pattern
that we could reuse throughout the entire page.
Well if we look at the design file we already noticed the spacing here.
And if we scroll down a bit the next big section of the page is this our features area and it also features
a fair amount of top padding or vertical spacing.
And if we scroll down further the next big section of the page is this testimonials area and it also
includes a fair bit of top padding or spacing.
So I think it's fair to say that this is a design pattern.
So to create spacing between the large block and this content let's create a new block.
So in our text editor within the modules folder let's create a new file.
Let's name this file underscore page dash section CSX.
So let's create a class named page section and if we look at our design file this new class will have
the responsibility of adding top padding and bottom padding for each section on the page so we can just
say padding.
Let's try four and a half rim space zero.
So this is C-s a shorthand this value will be used for the top and bottom padding values and we don't
want any horizontal padding so we add a zero for the left and right values.
So let's say this and let's be sure to open up our main styles that CSSA file and import in this new
page section module.
So modules folder underscore page section.
So let's save this.
And now we can use the new page section class in our HVM.
So scroll down and are h DML.
We see that there is already a div that is wrapped around all of the content that begins here.
It ends here right before the our features section begins.
So this is the perfect div to add our page section class too.
So let's save this and check out the browser.
And there is our vertical spacing.
All right the next thing that I think we should address is the fact that this content is pushed up against
the very far left edge of the screen.
Now earlier in the lesson we already created a block named wrapper that can help us out here.
So in our age TNL within the div that we just added a class of page section to let's create another
inner div with a class of wrapper let's indent all of this content
and after it be sure to include a closing div tag.
So if we save this in the browser we see that the content is no longer flush against the left edge.
Now while I think that's enough on a smartphone or a small screen I think we need to take things one
step further.
For large screens.
So for example if we look at the design file we see that throughout the design there seems to be a max
width of about twelve hundred pixels.
So back in the browser We don't want the content to be as wide as the screen because if I had a 30 inch
monitor in my browser window was full screen it would result in text lines that are way too long for
the human eye to comfortably read.
So lets do this within our.
SS in the wrapper of CSSA file.
Let's add a max width of twelve hundred pixels.
So we see that that creates a maximum width but we want it to be horizontally centered in the screen.
So let's also say margin left.
Auto.
Margin right.
Audio.
There we have it.
Now I know we are supposed to be focusing on this section of content but really quickly I want to show
you an example of why it's worth our energy and effort to think of our design in terms of reusable blocks
and repeatable design patterns.
So for example let's look at the design file and let's scroll down a bit and change gears and look at
the our features section watch how far we can get styling this section by simply reusing existing blocks.
Let's find this content in our each TNL.
So if I search for our features we see that there is already a div with an idea of features.
Let's give this div a class of page section so in the browser we see that that creates the vertical
padding above and below our feature section.
Next let's give the section a blue background.
Let's go ahead and give this section a modifier class named page section dash dash blue.
And then in our page section CSSA file.
Let's create a new rule that targets that blue modifier class and we can just say background color mean
blue variable and let's make the text white.
So now in the browser We now have a full with blue background section just like the design file and
we can use the wrapper class to limit the content to this middle.
Twelve hundred pixels instead of using the full screen.
So in our HVM out within this div Let's create another inner div give it a class of wrapper let's indent
all of this content
and close out that div that we began and in the browser we have now centered the content.
All right.
So hopefully that gives you an idea of just how useful it can be to identify patterns and create reusable
blocks.
Now let's shift our focus back up to the content that we were working on earlier.
This will actually bring this particular lesson to a close but in our next lesson we will pick up right
where we left off.
Let's keep rolling along and I will see you in the next lesson.