Hello everyone.
In this lesson we are going to learn about code splitting within web back before we worry about what
code splitting is.
We just need to remember that our overall goal is to have the visitors of our Web site download as little
data as possible so that things load as quickly as possible for them.
So with that in mind when someone first visits our Web site immediately they have no need for the javascript
that powers the modal.
Now in our specific case.
Yes the modal javascript is only 58 lines of code so it's not like that's a ton of extra data for someone
to download.
But that's not the point.
So in this lesson I want you to use your imagination and picture that our modal javascript was 200 or
300 lines of code.
So imagine you have this sizable bit of code that the user doesn't need to download right away.
In that scenario there's no sense in including that code in the main javascript bundle that the user
downloads right away.
So here's what we're going to do in this lesson.
I want you to jump into our main or overall app dot J.S. JavaScript file.
So this is the main entry point.
That web pack looks at.
Right.
And Web pack is bundling up everything that we are importing end up at the top.
We are indeed importing our modal JavaScript file.
Now again imagine that our modal was powered by three hundred lines of JavaScript and we wanted to prevent
the user from having to download that right away.
Well do this with me right now within our app dot J.S. I want you to delete this line completely.
Where we are importing the modal class and then I also want you to delete the line where we are creating
a new instance of the modal class OK.
Now if I save this obviously back in the browser if I refresh the modal feature no longer works.
So now let's set things up within this main app dot J.S. file so that when you click on one of the buttons.
Well then on demand or on the fly we load in the modal JavaScript file.
That way they only download it if they need it.
So back in app dot J.S. maybe below all of these lines where we are creating new instances of classes
right below that let's set up the code that loads in the modal code at just the right moment.
So first we're going to need to handle the Click event.
When you click on one of the buttons that should open the modal.
So let's just say document got query selector all.
Any element that has a class of open modal.
Now this is going to return a collection or multiple elements.
So then we want to call for each on that.
And then let's give this an arrow function with exactly one parameter.
Let's say E L for element arrow function for each one of those elements.
Let's add an event listener.
The type of event we're listening for is a click comma.
And then let's also give that an arrow function with one parameter.
Let's have the parameter be called E for event.
So we can prevent the default behavior and then arrow symbol curly brackets.
So first let's say e dot prevent default so that way when you click on one of the links it doesn't actually
try to take you to a u r allocation of hash tag and then below this we can actually load in the modal
file so we can use the import method inside these parentheses we give it a path to quotes dot forward
slash modules slash modal.
Now this is going to return a promise.
Meaning we don't know how long this is going to take to complete but once it does finish loading that
file then we want to actually use it to create a new instance of the class.
So at the very end of this line since this is a promise we can say dot then and then after that we can
say dot catch.
Now if this is your first time ever working with a promise.
Essentially we provide functions in both the then parentheses and the catch parentheses.
The idea is that we don't know how long it's going to take to load this file.
It could take 10 milliseconds or it could take a thousand milliseconds but when it is successfully retrieved
right if things go as planned then whenever that happens the function we provide and then is going to
get called or if there is a problem in the file never loads and for some reason there's an error then
whatever function we provide and catch will be called.
So let's actually start with the catch.
For now we can just provide an arrow function and just log a message to the console that says there
was a problem.
OK.
But if things go as planned the then function is going to run.
So within the then parentheses let's give this an arrow function with exactly one parameter.
Let's use a parameter name of x.
So X and then a space and then the arrow function symbol and then let's add curly brackets and in-between
them let's dropdown the X represents the file that we just imported or loaded.
So we want to use this to create a new instance of the modal class.
So on this line we can just say create a new instance of X and then due to the way web packed imports
the file in this situation we do need to say X dot default parentheses.
So this will create a new instance of our modal class.
Now we don't just want that new instance sitting in outer space we want to save it to a variable so
we can reference it later on.
However we don't want to create a variable using the word left here because it would only be available
within this current scope down here.
So let's do this maybe right below these lines where we're creating new instances of classes.
Let's write a brand new line and we can just say let lowercase modal and that's it.
That's the entire line of code.
This is just creating a variable with this name in the global scope.
So now down here when we're saying create a new instance of X dot default at the start of this line
we can just say lowercase modal equals and just for organization this line of code should be indented.
Okay.
I do want to point out though that it's not as if every single time you click an open modal button we
would want to try to load or import the file.
For example what if you opened the model once and then closed the modal and then click the button to
open it again.
Right that second time you click it.
We don't need to load the file again the browser already would have that modal code in memory.
So let's do this.
I want you to select these three lines of code.
So starting from import and then down until the end of the catch line like this let's cut this into
our clipboard
OK and let's write an if statement to determine if the modal file has already been downloaded or not.
So we can say if parentheses curly brackets after the closing curly bracket.
Let's also set up an else block.
Else curly brackets.
Now for the condition in these parentheses only if type of modal double equal sign to check for equality.
Only if that equals undefined.
So to review we are first creating a variable named modal.
And at first its type is going to be undefined.
Now if that's the case then within the curly brackets for this if statement this is where we can paste
back in our clipboard.
So go ahead and paste so on demand we are loading in that file that we need and we are updating the
value of that modal variable right to be a new instance of our class.
So then the next time you would click on open modal button this would evaluate to false.
Right.
Because now modal is an object not undefined.
So within the else block this is where we would just open the modal.
We don't need to load in the file again.
We can just say lowercase modal dot and call its method named open the modal.
Now we would also want to open the modal within our if block.
So right below this line where we're creating a new instance of it only in this situation we would probably
want to give the browser a few milliseconds to create the object before we try to do something.
So I would actually set a time out set time out.
This allows you to give it a function that you want to run but also then tell it how many milliseconds
to wait before you do that.
So first I would give it an arrow function where I call modal dot open the modal after that comma.
I would just want to wait maybe 20 milliseconds.
Right.
Just to let the browser create that new object and inject the HDMI all into the Dom and just be ready
at this point let's go ahead and save this file.
But before we jump right into the browser let's be sure to jump into our modal file and update things
a bit because now our main JavaScript file is handling the on click event.
So up in our constructor we no longer need to select the open modal buttons we can get rid of this line
and within our events method we also no longer need this.
Listen for open click event so we can delete all of that.
And finally I want you to go down and find our open the modal method and we no longer need to worry
about preventing the default behavior.
Right.
That's being handled in our main JavaScript file.
So within the parentheses for this method we don't need the E parameter and we definitely do not need
this line where we say prevent default.
Ok let's go ahead and save this and back in the browser go ahead and perform a refresh.
So we're dealing with all new event handlers OK.
And if I try to open the modal perfect but to illustrate what's really going on and why this is impressive
we need to use our developer tools in our web browser.
So I want you to do this go ahead and perform one more manual refresh.
So at this current state the browser has not loaded the modal code and what I want you to do is right
click anywhere and choose inspect right that will open your developer tools and then instead of clicking
on elements or console we're actually interested in the network tab.
If you don't see network you might just need to click on the arrows it might be hidden under the other
options.
But we are looking for the network tab and your developer tools.
OK.
Now if you refresh the page with this network tab open.
So on P.C. that's control are on Mac.
That's command are you will see a list of every asset that your browser downloaded.
Right.
So every CSX file every J Pag every JavaScript file.
Now at this point I want you to click on this clear icon.
It looks like a circle with an X through it.
You didn't have to do that but it makes it easier to see if any new files are downloaded.
Now at this point go ahead and click the button that will open your modal and now back in your developer
tools Network tab.
If you're like me you've resized this window to be quite small you might need to close the bottom console
draw but notice the list of files that our browser has downloaded is updated.
So as soon as we actually opened the modal in the browser it fetched a new JavaScript file named zero
dash bundle the J S and it also obviously loaded the SPG icons that the modal displays.
This is great.
This proves that the browser is not downloading the extra modal code until we actually click on that.
Now if he didn't want that separate JavaScript file to be named Zero dash bundled let me show you what
you can do back in app dot.
J.S. when we call import and give it a file path right at the start of this.
So in the parentheses but before the quotes you can actually write a comment.
So slash asterisk and then space asterisk slash to close out the comment inside the comment.
We can say Web Park uppercase chunk uppercase name colon quotes and then you can give it whatever name
you want let's call it modal OK.
Let's save this file.
But in order for this change to actually take place we need to restart our web pack task.
So in the command line just press control C and then just fire it up again.
So NPM run Dev
OK.
Now back in the web browser.
Be sure to perform a manual refresh.
And let's check our network tab.
We do not see the modal file or any of its SPG icons in this list of files but if we clear that out
using this icon and then open the modal back in our developer tools perfect we see that new file using
our custom name mode old Dot bundle that dot J Yes.
Now before we bring this lesson to a close I want to review.
So yes in this particular instance our mobile file is not a very large file so we technically don't
really need to do this but it's important that you have this tool in your tool box.
If you have a large and complex javascript module that you don't need right away.
The idea is that you can load it on the fly so that when the visitor first comes to your Web site everything
loads very quickly.
And one final additional note before we close out this video.
If we jump back into app dot J.S. in our previous video I promised I would explain when we need to store
a new instance of an object into a variable or not.
Well as we learned in this lesson you do want to save a new instance of a class into a variable.
If you're going to need to access it or call its methods later on right in this case any time the user
clicks on one of those open buttons we are actually running the objects open the modal method.
So in this case we absolutely wanted to save that new instance of a class into a variable but for everything
else in our example application for example the sticky header that does not need to live in a variable
so we can get rid of that first part of this line in the same thing is true of our mobile menu.
We don't need to store that in a variable.
So I can save this and nothing on our Web site is going to break.
However you would want to get in the habit of storing these into variables if your different modules
would need to interact with each other.
Now for our travel Web site that's not the case but if in another project you are building something
rather complex where different modules should trigger other events inside of other modules.
Well I would encourage you to look up a package on NPM named event emitter.
You can see just in the last week it was downloaded two point three million times.
And the idea here is that inside one of your modules.
Right.
So for example inside our modal module if something happens right.
If a certain event happens you can emit an event back to your main JavaScript file and then when your
main JavaScript file detects that event it could call a method on another object.
This way your individual modules don't need to import or even be aware of the other modules.
Right.
Each module self-contained.
But your main JavaScript file is sort of the puppeteer you can broadcast certain events to it.
And then if you've been storing your objects in variables as we saw here it's very easy to begin working
with that and then call a certain method.
Again we don't need that sort of complexity for our travel Web site.
So going to delete that.
But that's just a tip for your future projects anyways.
That's going to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson we are going to learn about lazy loading
our images.
We are getting very close to pushing our Web site up onto the Web to share with our friends and family.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.