Hello everyone.
In this lesson we will make a few enhancements to our Web sites header for larger screens.
But before we dive into that let's first take care of our get repository.
So over in the command line we see that we currently have a branch named reveal on scroll checked out.
And in our previous lesson we completed this branch's functionality.
So let's go ahead and commit any recent changes and then merge this branch back into master.
So let's run a get status to see what has changed recently.
All of these changes look good.
They all look related to the reveal on scroll functionality.
So I'm going to add everything to my staging area get add dash a.
All right.
And now we can commit that staging area.
So get commit.
Let's include a message.
So dash am open up quotes completed the reveal on scroll behavior.
All right.
So we've saved and committed our changes.
Now we can switch back to our master branch get check out master.
And now we just want to merge the reveal on scroll branch back into the master branch.
So we just say get merge reveal on scroll all right.
So at this point our master branch has our latest code.
So now we want to create a new branch off of it where we can work on the desktop sticky header features.
So to create a new branch let's say get check out dash B.
And then the name of the branch.
Let's call this new branch sticky header.
All right.
So we are now working within the new branch.
Let's get started.
So in this lesson we want to make this top header sticky for larger screens.
So that means that as we scroll down the page we want that header to stick to the top of the viewport.
So let's make that happen.
Let's write a bit of CSX so over in our text editor let's open up app assets styles modules and let's
jump into the site header CSX file so here we see that we already have a media query targeting screens
that are at least medium or larger.
So within this media query let's just say position fixed.
This will lock the element to the top of the screen even as we scroll.
So let's save this and test it out in the browser.
So now even as we scroll we see that our header stays locked to the top but I'm noticing a design problem.
So the semi transparent blue background of our header works well when it's positioned here overlapping
the top of this blue sky photo.
But once we scroll down a bit and it's overlapping a white background the header bar is just too transparent
it's too light and it's making these links really difficult to read.
So what I think we should do is let the header bar use that transparent light blue color when we are
scrolled to the very top of the page.
But once we've scrolled down a bit maybe this far let's transition and fade the headers background color
to use a much darker less transparent blue.
Now in order to modify the page on the fly like that we are going to need to use javascript.
So let's jump over to our text editor and create a new javascript module file.
So within app assets scripts modules let's create a new file let's name this new file sticky header
dot J.S. let's begin with a class and let's name it sticky header and then down below this class we
know that we need to export this so we can use it in another file so let's say export default and then
the name of the class sticky header let's go ahead and save this file and before we forget let's include
it or import it within our main app J.S. file so within our scripts folder here is app J.S. let's go
ahead and import that new file so let's drop down to a new line and say import sticky header from so
dot slash to go into the modules folder and then grab the file named sticky header.
All right.
So we've imported the file.
Now we just need to create a new instance of that class.
So down here let's drop down to a new line.
Let's create a new variable and name it sticky header.
This instance of the class or this variable this object will begin with a lowercase s and we will say
that it equals a new instance of the sticky header class.
Let's save this file and then jump back into our new sticky header module so within our class we know
that we are going to need a constructor function.
So let's say constructor and let's stop for a second to think about what we actually need to do.
So back in the browser once we scroll down about this far we want to target the site header and give
it a modifier.
Class that makes it darker.
So why don't we begin by creating a property that points towards the site header DOM element.
So back in our constructor function let's say this dot and let's name the property site header and let's
set that to equal document dot query selector and it has a class.
So a dot of site dash header.
All right.
Now let's ask ourselves how are we going to add a modifier class to this element at precisely the right
moment.
Well we can just listen to the web browser scroll event and once the user has scrolled down let's say
about 60 pixels from the top.
Well at that point we can add the dark modifier class to the header and then if they ever scroll back
up so that they are less than 60 pixels scrolled from the top we can remove that dark modifier class.
Let me show you how we would do that.
So below our constructor but still within our class let's create a method named events and up in our
constructor let's be sure to call the events method right away.
So this dot events.
OK.
Now within our events method let's target the overall window browser object and we want to add an event
listener.
So dot add event listener type of event we want to listen for is a scroll event after the quotes we
include a comma and then this is a function that should run in response to this event.
But as we've learned we should care about performance or efficiency.
Remember that as we scroll the web browser is going to call the scroll event many many times.
So why don't we use the load Ash throttle tool here because we don't need to know the browser scroll
position every millisecond or after every single pixel that's scrolled.
We really only need to know its value maybe every 200 milliseconds so up at the very top of this file.
Let's import in the load Ash throttle feature so let's say import throttle from quotes and we want to
use the low dash package and then look inside it just for the throttle tool.
OK.
Now for the second argument here after this comma we can just say throttle parentheses inside those
parentheses first we give it a function let's actually give it an arrow function so that the this keyword
doesn't change.
So another set of parentheses after that an arrow symbol so equal saying greater than and then we haven't
created this method yet but let's imagine that we have a method named run on scroll so to call it you
would just say this dot run on scroll in parentheses to call that method.
OK.
Now after that most recent set of parentheses add a comma and then the second argument is how many milliseconds
we want to wait before this function can be called again.
I'm going to go with 200 milliseconds OK.
Now we'd better go ahead and create a method with this matching name so right below the events method
let's say run on scroll and let's just set up an if statement that checks to see if the user has scrolled
down 60 pixels or not so we can say if parentheses curly brackets right after the closing curly bracket
for the if let's also add in else block so else curly brackets OK.
And for the if condition we can just say if window dot scroll why this is a property that the browser
makes available to us.
It's how many pixels you've scrolled down from the very top so we can just say if that value is greater
than and I'm just choosing this number you can tweak this number a bit but I'm going to say 60 pixels
if that's the case.
If they've scroll down that far or farther than we would want to add the CSF modifier class that makes
this top bar a darker or less see through shade of blue.
So this dot site header dot class list dot ad and let's give it a modifier.
Class site header dash dash dark.
OK.
And then for the else block if the user has scrolled and the number is not larger than 60 we would want
to do the opposite of this.
Right.
We would want to remove the dark modifier class so to save some typing we can just copy this line into
our clipboard and then in the else block pasted in and just change add here to instead be remove.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
But before we jump to the browser I want to first hop into our CSX and create a new rule that targets
are dark modifier class.
So back within sight header CSX within this media query that targets medium screens and larger.
Let's create a new rule.
Let's use the ampersand symbol which will give us dot site header and then let's add dash dash.
Dark.
And from here it's as simple as adjusting the background color.
Let's use RGA.
So it's still a little bit transparent and instead of using our main blue color I'm actually going to
use a darker blue.
So let's try 23 for the Red 51 for the green seventy two for the blue and let's try.
Eighty five percent transparency.
Let's save this file and jump over to the browser and if we start scrolling down perfect we see that
the header transitions to the darker background.
But if we scroll back up the header reverts to its normal style.
Perfect.
Now before we bring this lesson to a close there's one final detail that I want to work on.
I think it would look nice if when the dark header is being used if we also shrunk this top left logo
to be small enough so that it could fit within the header bar that way as we scroll down the page the
logo isn't using up any precious real estate.
Now all we need to do to make this happen is to jump back to our text editor and hop into our site header
CSX file and we are looking for the logo rule.
So if we scroll down a bit here is the logo rule and we already have a media query that's only targeting
screens that are medium or larger.
So within this media query let's create a new rule.
Let's target the site header class when it's using the dark modifier out of space to create a descendant
selector and then just use the ampersand symbol which will give us the selector for the logo element.
So this selector will target the logo only when the dark header is being used.
So let's open up curly brackets and let's shrink the element by using the transform property and then
using the scale function.
So if one is the elements natural size let's try.
Point five seven.
Let's go ahead and save this file and check out the browser.
So if I scroll down a bit cool you can see the logo shrinks but it's just a little bit too tall.
It would be nice if it vertically fit within the blue bar.
So let's reduce that a bit instead of point five seven let's try.
Point five six still doesn't fit perfectly.
Let's try reducing it down to point five five perfect for scroll back up to the very top.
It's back to its original styling but I think this could be even better if the logo animated or transitioned
did size change.
So back within our CSX within the baseline rule for the logo let's just add a transition property and
say that the transform value should transition smoothly over the course of about a third of a second.
And let's use the ease out transition style so let's save this.
And check out the browser.
And now when we scroll down we see that the logo size smoothly changes perfect and that's actually going
to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson we will learn how to highlight links in the header
to correspond with the section of the page that we are currently viewing or that we've currently scrolled
to.
This feature should be a lot of fun to set up.
I think it has the potential to really improve the user experience of our site.
Let's keep rolling along and I will see you in the next lesson.