Hello everyone.
In this lesson we are going to learn how to integrate react into our project or I should say into our
web pack powered workflow.
If you've never heard of react that's OK.
It is an incredibly popular front end library.
Now we're not going to actually learn react that is completely outside the scope of this course.
React really deserves its own course dedicated to react.
This lesson is just about integrating react into a typical workflow that already exists.
If you read a few react tutorials you'll quickly find out that they almost all tell you to just use
a package called Create react app.
Now there's nothing wrong with this package.
I think it's a phenomenal tool.
However in the real world you're not always going to get to start from scratch.
Oftentimes you'll want to integrate react into a workflow that you've already set up.
So that's exactly what we're going to learn how to do in this video.
Now even if you've never heard of react before this video and you have no idea what it's used for.
I still want you to follow along with this lesson.
So right now all you need to know is that React is incredibly popular.
It's incredibly in demand and it can make our life a lot easier when it comes to writing front end javascript.
If by the end of this video you're even 1 percent impressed or interested or intrigued by react.
Then I encourage you to seek out other learning materials on react cool.
Without further ado let's get started.
So we're going to add react into our existing travel Web site and workflow to begin.
Let's jump over to our command line and we want to install two packages to run this command with me
npm install react space because we want a second package named react dash Dom react is the core of the
library and react.
Dom is specifically for the web browser environment.
We don't need to include dash dash save Dev because these are direct dependencies that we want our visitors
to actually download.
Go ahead and press enter OK.
Now let's go leverage those packages.
So right now I want you to jump into your main JavaScript file that lives in app assets scripts and
is named app got J.S. maybe below these first several lines where we import packages in we could even
write a comment to ourselves and say react related code goes here.
OK let's import the overall react library so import react from quotes the lowercase NPM package name.
We also want to import react Dom's import react Dom from the NPM name of react dash Dom.
OK.
And now to actually output a react powered component onto our Web site we need to add an empty div somewhere
within our each team e-mail.
So do this with me.
Let's open up indexed on HDMI all which lives in our app folder.
You can add an empty div anywhere but in my case I'm going to scroll down to the very bottom and maybe
right before the footer I will add a new div.
So do this with me div closing div tag.
We just want it to be empty.
You can give this a really unique class name where we could even just give it an I.D..
So I.D. equals let's say my react example.
OK.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
Now let's jump back into our main JavaScript file and right below these to react lines let's add another
line and type this in with me.
React Dom dot render.
So we're using the render method of the react on package within these parentheses.
We provide two arguments so we could say a comma B as place holders.
The first argument is a component that you want to render to the page in react.
Everything really boils down to the idea of components.
For now you can just think of a component as a reusable feature.
Again we're not actually learning react in this course.
That's outside of our scope.
I just want to show you how to integrate react into our project or our workflow or technology stack.
OK.
So this first argument should be a component we haven't created a component yet but we will in about
30 seconds from now.
So instead of a placeholder type this in with me less than symbol and let's say my amazing component
space forward slash greater than symbol.
OK.
And then for the second argument instead of this b place holder this is the element on the page that
you want to render to.
In other words that empty div that we just added to our H T.M. L so instead of the B type this in with
me document dot query selector inside these parentheses we say quotes to select an element based on
its I.D. we just say hash tag and remember we gave it an I.D. of my dash react dash example.
OK now you might notice that this almost looks like an H T.M. l tag that's sort of the whole idea.
So instead of a heading level three tag or a paragraph tag we can create a component with its own custom
name and custom features custom behavior.
So let's do this right above this line right here.
Let's create a function with this matching name.
So let's say your function.
My amazing component parentheses curly brackets.
Obviously you could chose any name here.
I just made this name up.
Okay.
Now within the body of this function let's say we want to return parentheses.
Here's where things get interesting in between these two parentheses I want you to drop down and now
even though we're not within quotes or back ticks we can actually start writing what would seemingly
look like h tmr.
So let's create an overall wrapper div and inside that div we could create a heading Level 1.
This is my amazing react component below that but still within our overall div we could create a paragraph
and say react is great.
Sky is blue grass is green okay.
Now this might look like each CML but it's not.
It's something called J S x.
Now again since we're not actually going to learn react in this course unfortunately we can't dive into
the details of JSA X for now.
All we really need to know is that the web browser would be tremendously confused by J as X and not
only the web browser but our web packed workflow would probably throw an error message if our dev task
was watching and we tried to save this file.
However luckily for us we already have a tool at our disposal that can look at javascript analyze it
and then convert it or trans pilot.
Remember we used a tool named babble to look at our javascript and turn it into something that is backwards
compatible with older browsers.
Well even though web browsers would not be able to understand J.S. X we can just download a babble tool
that is specifically designed for react and the J.S. X syntax.
Then whenever web pack bundles up our code it will convert this into something that does make sense
to JavaScript interpreters and web browsers in general so do this with me we can save this file but
go into your command line and we need to install just one more package so let's run npm install in the
name of the packages at Symbol babble forward slash preset dash react and this time we do want to include
dash dash save Dev because the visitors of our site do not need to download this.
This is just for our workflow.
As the developer of the site let's go ahead and push enter okay into leverage that package.
We just need to jump into our web pack dot config dot J.S. file now previously we set things up so that
only our built task but not our dev task leveraged babble.
This made sense because you and I are always going to have the latest version of our web browser so
we didn't need to transpire.
Our code locally but we did want to convert it to be backwards compatible before pushing it up onto
the Web.
However we want to apply the react babble tool to both our dev and build workflows.
So let's go find the babble code that's down in our build task.
So for me it's around line number sixty seven.
We see if current task equals build right and then we said config dot module dot rules dot push.
Here's what I want you to do inside that parentheses for push.
I want you to begin selecting this curly bracket down to this closing curly bracket.
Okay.
And then go ahead and cut this into your clipboard.
You'll know that you cut the right code if it now just looks like this an empty push call.
So we can delete this line entirely.
Okay.
Now I want you to scroll back up to our common config object right.
This is the shared config that is the same between both our dev and build tasks.
Well all we need to do within the module and then rules within this array.
Right after C Ss config you can just add a comma dropdown and then just paste in your clipboard.
OK so we've added a rule that is only for JavaScript files.
We're using the Babbage loader and we were already using this preset that will make our code a bit more
backwards compatible.
Well this is an array that can have multiple presets so let's just add the react preset to the beginning
of this.
So add a pair of quotes add a comma in between and in these quotes say at Symbol babble forward slash
preset dash react cool let's go ahead and save this and again make sure your main app dot J.S. file
has been saved and let's fire up our NPM run dev and VM run Dev
OK.
If we jump back over to the Web browser just to be safe go ahead and perform a manual refresh and then
if we scroll down to where we added that empty div awesome you can see that our ReACT component rendered
into that div.
Now even though we're not going to actually learn react or J.S. X in this lesson I do want to show you
a few tips.
So back in our code within our function for my amazing component we need to remember that this might
look like h TMF But it's not HDMI.
So imagine I wanted to add a class to this heading to make it blue and large and centered so I could
say class equals S. dash title S. dashed title dash dash blue.
Well this code would make sense in HMO but this will break JSA X since JSA X is actually just JavaScript.
We need to realize that the word class is reserved in javascript.
So when we want to apply a C Ss class to one of our elements here we need to say class name and capitalized
the N in name.
Okay let's go ahead and save this then back in the browser.
Cool.
We don't need to refresh our web PAC just injects the newest version of our code can see it's blue and
it's large.
OK another quick JSF ex tip is that you can only have one route or top level element.
It doesn't need to be a div.
You could use something called a react fragment.
But again we're not going to get into that because we're not actually learning react here.
Essentially I just want to let you know that if you tried to have this top level div and then if I tried
to add another element down here this would break everything.
This is not valid JSA ex.
You can only have one top level or root level element.
OK before we bring this lesson to a close I want to show you how you could tuck this component code
away into its own separate file right.
So that way our main JavaScript file stays super clean.
We import the files we need and that's it.
So do this with me within our scripts modules folder.
Let's create a new file let's name it.
My amazing component Doc J.
Yes.
OK.
Back in app Doc J ust just copy this entire function for my amazing component.
Let's cut that into our clipboard back in our new empty file we can just paste it in and then down at
the very bottom here say export default my amazing component right.
So that if any file tries to import this file that's what we want the official export to be before we
save this file though up at the very very top.
We do need to import in the core react library so import react from react.
Don't worry it's not like including react both here and in the main file is going to bloat the bundle.
Westpac is super efficient and it just points towards the same instance.
OK at this point we can save this file and then back in our main act J.S. Right below when we imported
react and react.
Dom we can just import our component file.
We could even write a comment to ourselves.
Stay organized.
Import react components that we created.
Then we can just say import my amazing components from.
Give it a file path dot slash into the modules folder my amazing components.
Okay.
And then this line will be able to access that component or that function.
Let's go ahead and also save this file and then to prove that things are working now that we've split
it into its own file we could go into that file and just change any of the text so I'll change this
paragraph to just say react is great with three exclamations.
I save that back in the browser we see that change reflected.
Okay.
And then finally I do want to let you know that it's not as if react Dom dot render is the only thing
that can list a component using this HDMI tag style.
So for example in our component file within our J OSX here below this paragraph we could say my cool
photo box and then we could create a functioning component with this matching name in a separate file
just like we did with this component.
Let me go ahead and delete this example.
Now I realize we didn't do anything truly interesting or exciting with react in this lesson.
That wasn't the point of this lesson.
I'm not here to advertise or to quote sell you on react.
However it's such a popular library that I felt like I'd be doing you a disservice if I didn't show
you how to integrate it into our existing workflow if react has piqued your interest at all.
I strongly strongly encourage you to continue learning about react.
In particular I'd encourage you to research the reactive topics of props.
Once the idea of props makes sense then I would encourage you to research hooks and specifically the
use state hook.
Anyways big picture.
Do a bit of react research and if it excites you at all.
Dive into it because I can't overstate how popular and in demand react is right now in the industry.
Anyways that's going to bring this lesson and our coverage of react in this particular course to a close.
Now in our next lesson we will pretend we are working with a team of other developers to keep this site
updated.
We will learn how to handle something called a get merge conflict.
We'll learn why it's nothing to be afraid of.
And more importantly we'll learn how to avoid as many conflicts as possible in the first place.
We've come a long way in this course and we've almost reached the end where I will begin to share some
big picture tips with you.
Let's keep rolling along and I will see you in the next lesson.