Hello everyone.
In this video we will talk about job interviews.
This video has two main components to it.
First we'll learn how to get more interviews and then secondly once you've gotten the interview we'll
learn how to interview well.
Now I've personally been on both sides of developer job interviews the applicant side and the hiring
side.
So I'm going to share my top tips.
These are things that worked for me when I was job hunting and these are also things that I was looking
for an applicants when I was on the hiring side.
So without further ado let's dive right in and let's learn how to get more interviews.
My first tip is to consider working remotely.
This will allow you to simply cast a wider net.
This tip may seem obvious but believe it or not I see a lot of people who are job hunting who make the
mistake of only looking for jobs in their local area.
This isn't 1950.
You're a developer you work on a computer you can work from anywhere you are throwing away countless
amazing opportunities.
If you refuse to work remotely.
Now if you happen to live somewhere where there is a wealth of local opportunities that's fantastic.
But if you live somewhere where there isn't as much going on locally you really need to ask yourself
would you rather work for a disappointing local company or a thriving fun supportive company that just
happens to be across the country.
To me the choice is obvious.
Working remotely is an attractive option.
Now you might be wondering where to look to find remote jobs.
Well Web sites change over time so I won't mention any specific site names in this video.
But in the text discussion for this video I'll include a few links to the top remote developer job board
sites.
My next tip is don't limit yourself to officially listed openings only sometimes you can create an opening.
So if you see a company that you like and you honestly think that you would bring value to their team
reach out to them.
A lot of companies are always on the lookout for talented new team members and many will have a career
page on their company Web site that says they are accepting applicants even though they haven't necessarily
posted any openings on official job board sites.
So the point is don't wait for an opening.
Sometimes you can create an opening.
My next tip can be referred to as call their bluff meaning you need to be able to tell when a job description
is lying.
Now when I say lying here's what I'm referring to.
Sometimes a job posting will include a description of who they're looking for and they will basically
describe a non-human genius alien with superpowers that knows everything about everything.
Well I'm here to tell you that that person doesn't exist.
So we need to call their bluff.
So even if you don't have everything that the job description mentioned as long as you have the majority
of the things they list I want you to go ahead and apply.
So for an example a lot of companies will mentioned that they're looking for a full stack developer.
Now while some of these companies are indeed actually looking for a senior level well-rounded developer
who can do it all a lot of companies use that phrase full stack developer pretty lightly.
They might not actually be looking for a full blown genius phenomenon.
They might just be looking for someone who is at least familiar with several different aspects of development.
So trust your gut you know you'll have a general feeling of whether you're qualified or not for the
job.
But I would say to try and error on the side of overestimating yourself instead of underestimating yourself.
Don't let the job descriptions intimidate you.
Basically don't pre reject yourself.
It never hurts to try.
The great Michael Scott once quoted the great Wayne Gretzky and said You miss 100 percent of the shots
that you don't take.
So in your gut if you think you even got a small chance I want you to apply.
My next tip is to customize your message for each job that you apply to.
When I say your message I'm referring to your cover letter or the email you send or the little text
box message that the job site lets you include.
Notice I'm not saying I want you to completely rewrite the message for each job but just make minor
adjustments to it.
So after you read a job description and you research the company even just for three to five minutes
you'll get a feel for what specific qualities and experiences they're looking for and you'll get a feel
for what traits they value in people.
And I want you to highlight those skills experiences and traits in your message.
Now I don't want you to lie or make stuff up.
I want you to be honest but think about how you align with what they've said they're looking for.
So for example if a company mentions a certain piece of software they use and you have experience with
that software mention that in your message.
Basically I just don't want you to copy and paste a generic cookie cutter cover letter and use it for
every single application.
Don't do that.
It only takes a couple of minutes to customize your message for each job.
My next tip is to keep that message relatively short but not so short that you don't look interested.
This is about finding that happy middle ground so no one wants to read a novel but you do want to write
enough that you wet their appetite.
So as a general guideline I'd say begin with a sentence where you introduce yourself and then no more
than one medium length paragraph where you talk about your experience and your strengths.
After that no more than one or two sentences about why you like the sound of their company and why you
think you'd be valuable and that's it.
Anything longer than that and you run the risk of sounding self-important or like you're compensating
for something.
So basically keep your message short and sweet.
My next tip is to create a personal website for yourself that you can linked to in your job applications.
There's no excuse for you to not do this.
Now that you know how to use GitHub pages for free and even if you don't have a portfolio of real world
projects to show off that's OK.
Just create a site that simply has a paragraph about yourself.
Maybe a photo and a list of things you're interested in.
Why is this so important.
Because your website is a chance for the company to see your code to see that you understand best practices.
The website itself the HMO CSX the javascript that is your portfolio they can check it out.
They can ask themselves Is it responsive.
Is it mobile first.
Does it load quickly.
Does this applicant stay current.
I know this tip sounds super obvious but you'd be surprised how many applicants I've seen that don't
have a Web site.
So again don't worry so much about your personal site's content.
The content only needs to be one step above law met some dummy content but just treat your site as a
design exercise as a coding exercise to show people what you can do.
My next tip is don't use bootstrap on your personal site.
Now I'm not saying that bootstrap is bad and I'm not saying that it's never the right tool for a job.
I'm just saying don't use it on your personal site.
It would be like if someone was applying to be the lead chef for a five star restaurant and in their
resume.
They said that they make dinners from boxed Rice mixes and they make desserts from boxed cake mixes
using Bootstrap makes you look like the opposite of an artisan craftsman who takes pride in building
Web sites bootstrap makes you look like you just wanted to finish the site in the most economical rushed
way possible.
So again this is an antique bootstrap propaganda.
I'm not saying it's not the right tool for certain jobs but I am saying for your personal site it's
a no no.
And here's my final tip for getting more interviews.
Find a way to demonstrate that you stay current.
There are a ton of different ways to do this.
On Twitter you can tweet about new things that you're learning or start a blog and post about what you're
excited to learn next.
Or even just mentioned new technologies that you're interested in on your Web site.
I know that Staying current is important in any industry but in ours it's even more important because
technology moves so quickly you immediately become an applicant that is at least worth considering.
If you can present yourself as someone who makes an effort to stay current.
All right now let's change gears let's say that you've landed an interview and now you want to be sure
to interview well.
So here are a few tips.
Tip number one is that it's OK to be nervous if you're nervous or stressed out about an interview.
That just means that you're human.
The interviewers know that everyone gets nervous and they aren't going to judge you for it.
Also even though you think you might look super nervous it probably isn't as bad as you think it is.
As far as they can tell you probably seem at least relatively calm.
My next tip is to prime yourself before the interview.
Again it's normal to be nervous or stressed out but you don't want to be so nervous that it robs you
of your personality.
So try to prime yourself before the interview to be in a somewhat playful mood.
Watch a few videos that make you laugh or listen to your favorite music.
You want to do something that keeps you grounded in your personality.
That way you can own your nervousness instead of it owning you.
My next tip is to remember that an interview is a two way street and this might help you feel less nervous.
So an interview isn't just you trying to convince them to hire you don't feel like all of the pressure
is on you.
You are also finding out if you like them they are in the hot seat to you are finding out if you would
even want to work for them.
So don't mentally give away all of your power before you go into an interview.
Don't think of it as a meeting where you need to convince someone that you're good enough you are good
enough.
Just think of it as a meeting where you want to see if you can be friends.
So what would you do in a social situation.
Well you'd want to give off a positive vibe.
You'd want to be kind.
You want to be humble.
You want to speak confidently about the things you're good at and that interest you try to approach
it like that.
My next tip is don't try to make yourself seems super intelligent.
It's more important that you seem likeable.
The best way for me to describe this tip is to just share one of my own personal experiences.
So we were interviewing applicants for a mid-level developer position and we ran into a candidate who
is the smartest most talented developer by far.
It wasn't even close.
He was a genius.
But during the entire interview he didn't laugh even once he barely smiled and he didn't say anything
positive about anyone or anything other than himself.
Now again even though he was the most skilled person we interviewed by far he just wasn't likeable.
And because of that we did not pursue him as a candidate.
So smile laugh.
Employers want positive likeable people someone who is positive instantly seems like someone with leadership
potential.
So in a nutshell being likeable is more important than being super intelligent.
My next tip is to try and convey enthusiasm in this industry things change super quickly.
So the best developers are the ones that love what they do because this leads to them spending the time
to stay current.
You don't want to seem like this is quote just a job to you.
You want to seem passionate you've got to remember that we have the luxury of working in an area that
we are interested in that engages us that challenges us in a good way.
Millions of people would love to be mentally stimulated by their work the way that developers are.
So be thankful for the field you're in and let that gratitude and enthusiasm come across in your interview.
My next tip is don't be afraid to present yourself as a specialist.
Don't be afraid to admit that you don't know something.
So for me it's a turnoff.
When an applicant tries to act like they know everything about everything because I know they're lying.
If someone really was that proficient at that many different things they wouldn't even need the job
that they're applying for.
They would have already invented the next Facebook.
So I'm much more impressed when an applicant presents themselves in a realistic light.
They talk about the things they're strong at and they also open up and maybe be a little bit vulnerable
and talk about the things that they are still working on improving.
My next tip is that even though you don't need to know everything about everything.
Building up your vocabulary as much as possible is always a good idea.
You want to familiarize yourself with as many different technologies as possible.
Notice I'm not saying you need to learn as many technologies as possible just become familiar with them.
Just being able to use a technology word in a sentence correctly and talk about how what you do know
interfaces with the technology in question shows that you're a valuable candidate.
So for example maybe you don't know how to use Mongo D.B. in javascript to save data to a database but
just knowing that Mongo D.B. is a database system is helpful.
So basically you don't need to know everything but building up your tech vocabulary certainly helps.
And my final tips interview well is to prepare a custom question beforehand.
What I mean by this is that most interviewers will ask you if you have any questions for them.
You want to have at least one question preferably multiple questions that show you are picturing yourself
working there.
Your questions show that you are genuinely interested and engaged and can imagine yourself in the job
in a perfect world we would be able to think of a question on the fly about something in the interview
but thinking on your feet like that can be tricky.
So why don't you come into the interview with a semi canned question in your pocket now don't have a
completely generic cookie cutter question that you ask in every interview.
Instead research the employer before the interview check out their Web site and their social media and
create a question about something you saw that interests you that way.
If you can think on your feet and come up with the perfect question in the heat of the moment great.
But if you can't you know that you have a solid question in your back pocket all right before we bring
this video to a close.
I've saved the most important big picture tip for last and that is that most likely the biggest challenge
you'll run into during your job search is running out of patience because finding the right developer
job can take a surprising amount of time.
I know personally the last time I was job hunting it took me longer than I thought it would and I have
a close friend who even with a degree in computer science from a good school still took longer than
you might think to land the job that he wanted.
So don't be so hard on yourself.
This doesn't happen overnight for anyone you might think it's taking you quote too long to find a job
that there's something wrong with you that you aren't good enough and that's why you haven't found a
job yet.
Stop.
It's normal to have those thoughts.
If you're having those thoughts it just means you're human.
But deep down you know those thoughts are not true.
You are more than good enough.
You know it.
I know it.
I know it because you've made it through my five million hours of rambling in this course and that alone
proves that you're driven you have ambition and that you're going to get what you want.
The only problem is that you've ran out of patience.
You think the job search is taking too long.
And so now your mind is trying to punish and attack you.
So let me try and help you strengthen your patience.
First of all know that it's normal for a job search to take what feels like an eternity.
Secondly maybe none of the jobs you've interviewed for so far were the right one for you so personally
during my last job hunt I had met with several companies and just didn't click with any of the people.
So obviously I didn't get the jobs and started to bring me down.
When you have multiple interviews in a row where you don't get the job it's normal human behavior to
feel discouraged but then I had an interview with a company that I had a good feeling about.
The interviewer was friendly and someone that I immediately gelled with the job needed a certain skillset
that I was strong in so my weaknesses weren't a big deal.
And by the end of the interview I was convinced that this would be a really good fit and I really wanted
the job.
And it made me stop and think that I was glad the previous few companies had passed on me.
I stopped feeling bad about those rejections because if any of those companies had hired me I wouldn't
have ever interviewed with this amazing company and the amazing company would actually go on to hire
me and it would become the best job that I ever had.
So long story short the job search can take a lot longer than you thought it would.
And you've got to stay patient.
I don't want you to let anyone including yourself tell you that you can't get the job that you want.
You know fully well that there are things you are downright amazing at and you would add so much value
to so many teams out there.
You can contribute to a project through get you right clean HDMI all super organized CSX modular object
oriented javascript.
You're a beast.
You understand what no JSA is and how to leverage NPM and build tools like web pack and babble.
I am not exaggerating when I say that there are tons and tons and tons of companies out there looking
for the exact skill set that you now possess.
All you need to do is keep your patients stay positive and sooner or later you will walk into an amazing
opportunity.
If you need to come back in a month or two and re listen to this last part of the video to remind yourself
what a catch you are go for it.
I'll be here waiting.
That's going to bring this video to a close in our next lesson.
We'll look at next steps you can take and we'll talk about career progression should be interesting.
Let's keep rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.