Hello everyone.
In this lesson we are going to get started with net flying.
So right now I want you to follow along with me.
Our first step is to sign up for a completely free Net lift account.
We don't even need to enter a credit card so you can visit.
Net Lafite dot com or you can just google for net LA fi by the end of this video you'll understand what
net LA Fi is.
But for now all you need to know is that it's sort of an alternative to traditional web hosting right.
They host our Web site files for us and make our Web site available to the public.
Anyways right now all we need to know is that we are interested in their completely free plan so you
can either click on sign up or use the.
Get started for free button.
Now you are free to sign up with your GitHub get lab or bit bucket account but if you're like me you
usually just sign up with a traditional email registration.
So that's what I'm going to click on email.
OK.
And then obviously just pause this video lesson while you're entering your new email and password to
sign up once you submit that form you should see a screen saying that net lo fi is e-mailing you.
So just go to your email inbox.
You might need to check your spam folder but there will be an e-mail from nettled fi with a link that
you click on to activate or verify your account.
Once you click on that link you should be taken to a screen that looks something like this.
I'm going to close this quick start guide.
OK.
And from here we have a few different ways to create our first site with net lo fi.
So one way would be to literally just drag and drop a folder from your computer into this area of the
screen.
We're not going to do that because that's not a very powerful workflow.
Instead we want to create a new site from get so click this new site from get button from the screen.
You can choose where your repo lives.
So you need to already have an account with either get hub get lab or bit bucket.
Now if you've made it this far in the course you already have a get hub account.
So let's click on get hub that should open a new pop up window.
So make sure that your browser didn't automatically block the pop up window but essentially this window
is GitHub dot com and it's asking us Do we really want to give net low fi access to our github account.
We absolutely do.
So you have a couple of options.
You can grant Nettlefold access to all repositories in your get up account or you can just select specific
repos.
So I'll leave that up to you.
But if you do select these specific repo option be sure to choose the travel site repo that you just
pushed to in the previous lesson.
OK.
Down at the very bottom of this pop up I'm going to click the install button cool.
So back in this net lift window or net the fly account now has permission to talk to and get data from
our get hub account for this new project we're setting up a net lift.
We need to choose which GitHub repo it's associated with.
So for me that is the travel site repo.
So I will click on that OK.
We can leave these options the way they are.
You are the owner and we want to work with our master branch
this is where things get interesting basic build settings.
So we see there is a field here titled Build the command click into this field and type NPM run build.
We also see published directory.
So in this field go ahead and type in Docs a little bit later in the video we will circle back to why
this is so cool and powerful.
But for now all you need to know is that if net lift is aware of our build command that can create some
very powerful automation anyways we can circle back to that later for now.
Go ahead and click the deploy site button
so this is a randomly generated name.
Yours will be different but you should see site deploy in progress.
Now through the magic of video editing and post-production I actually just sat here and waited maybe
20 to 40 seconds and this turned into a link that is ready to be clicked on again your name will be
different.
This is randomly generated.
But go ahead and click on your link or open it in a new tab.
Awesome and there is our Web site and you can share this link with anyone in the world your friends
your family your colleagues.
Now you might be thinking to yourself didn't we already set this up with GitHub pages.
Right.
You already had a public GitHub pages linked that you could share with the world.
Well yes that's true.
But our net lo fi powered site has so many extra features.
So right now let's circle back and I want to show you one of the biggest reasons I'm a huge fan of net
lo fi and that is automated builds.
Now before we worry about what that means or how it works let's first give ourselves a goal.
Let's imagine that our goal is to update our public Web site so that this headline ends with an exclamation
point.
So let's make that happen.
We know that we would need to jump back to our text editor and within our app folder jump and index
on HDMI all.
For me it's around line number 47.
So I will add an exclamation point right here.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
However before we commit this into get and push it to get hub I first want to do something that might
seem a bit extreme.
So not only am I not going to run NPM run build I'm also going to delete the entire docs folder.
I want you to do this as well so you can either delete it within your text editor or just within your
computer's file explorer going to travel site and delete this entire public docs folder so I'm just
moving it to the trash.
OK now let's commit those changes.
So if I run get status here are all of the changes.
So yes I modified the index on each to AML.
But you can see I also deleted every single file that was in the docs folder.
So I want to stage all of those changes so type this in with me get add dash uppercase a OK then let's
commit that so get commit.
Let's leave a message.
So dash a lowercase M and then space in quotes let's say changed headline and deleted docs folder as
net lo fi will now take care of bills.
Be sure to end that with a quote.
Let's push enter.
OK.
And then let's push our repo up to get hub.
So get push origin master now.
Here's the cool part.
If we go back into our net lo fi control panel or just the overview screen for this project I just had
to manually refresh the screen usually I don't think you need to manually refresh but now you can see
net lo fi detected that we pushed a new change to our github and net lo fi has published the newest
version of our site.
So if I go back to the net defy U.R.L. and refresh awesome.
There we see that exclamation point.
Now this is pretty cool.
This means that when we push our latest changes to our github repo not only does net lift I detect that
change but net lo fi also runs the NPM run build task for us right that task that optimizes our files
to be delivered to the public so whenever net Lafite detects that we push a change to get hub net lift
I will see our package dot Jason File and the net lo fi hardware actually downloads all of the NPM dependencies.
Once it's done then it actually runs the NPM run build task on their net lifting hardware.
And since we told Nettlefold that our public directory is the docs directory it all just works flawlessly.
Big picture this means that our workflow is now super smooth so locally on your computer you can run
NPM run dev to spin up your local web packet dev server right so you get on the fly live reloads for
CSX as javascript and HDMI out once you're done working you just commit your changes to get push that
up to get hub and that's it.
Net LA Fi will copy your files and run your build task for you.
And it goes without saying MetLife I also hosts those files for you.
So net lo fi is like a web hosting company that actually understands modern web development.
Now I will point out that because we deleted our docs folder from our repo our github pages site will
no longer work right.
So if I go back into GitHub and click on settings for this repo down in the github pages area it says
your side is having trouble building because there is no docs folder that's fine if you want to use
get up pages instead of net lift by then obviously just don't delete your docs folder but if you're
like me and you want to use Net LA fi we could even take things one step further.
So back in our text editor even though net LA I will take care of builds for us there may come a time
in the future where we need to adjust our build process.
So imagine if we had to go into web page config and update or change the way that our site was being
generated.
In that case we would want to test the build process locally to make sure that it works as we'd expect.
However and this is just personal preference for organization reasons.
But I still wouldn't want that docs folder to be committed into the get repo.
I really only want my source code in the repository so here's what I would do I would go into our get
ignore file and it doesn't matter where in the get ignore file but you can see we're already ignoring
node modules folder.
So I would just add a new line and ignore the docs folder.
Go ahead and save that.
So now even if I did make changes to my Web patch config and I wanted to test my build process locally
I could say NPM run build
and yes that generates the docs folder however get isn't going to pay attention to that.
So if I say get status the only change that it notices is that I modified get ignore.
Cool.
This way our get repository that's hosted on GitHub stays clean it only contains the actual source code.
We don't even need to worry about the docs or the public folder because Nettlefold takes care of all
of that before I commit and push this get ignore change.
Why don't we also set this back to end with a period instead of an exclamation point.
So back in index dot HD demo I will just change that back to a period save it if I run get status once
again.
Cool.
Those are the only two changes that I want in the repository.
I indeed do want to ignore my local copy of docs folder so get add dash a git commit changed headline
and ignored the docs folder.
Let's push that up to get up get push origin master we can jump back over to the net the fi Web site
and if you click on the deploys tab you can actually see real time updates so you can see it's in the
process of building right now as I'm watching this right.
We see that commit message changed headline and ignored the docs folder and again through the magic
of video editing I just sat here and waited maybe 20 seconds but you can see in real time it's updated
to say published.
So back at my net lo fi websites you are Elif I refresh.
This is back to a period awesome if you want to try to make a minor CSX or JavaScript change just to
make sure that things are working that's OK.
But at this point we can rest assured that our workflow is now silky smooth.
Now this automated build feature is just one of two main reasons I'm a huge fan of net lo fi and we're
going to learn about reason number two in our very next lesson.
I'll give you a hint.
Net low fi makes it incredibly easy to begin working with cloud functions or we might call them a W.S.
lambda functions.
This next lesson is going to open up so many possibilities.
We're going to be able to add backend or server side functionality to our otherwise static or front
end based Web site.
This is going to be a lot of fun.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.