Hello everyone.
In this section of the course we will learn how to write highly organized javascript.
We will kick things off in this lesson by familiarizing ourselves with something called Object Oriented
Programming.
So let's begin with a question what in the world is object oriented programming.
Well I think the best way to answer that is for you and I.
To jump into our text editors together and begin writing a bit of JavaScript together.
OK.
So I want you to jump into our main JavaScript file to refresh your memory.
It lives in the app folder and then in assets and then in scripts and it's named app dot J Yes.
So far we just have this bit of code in the file and I absolutely want you to keep these lines of code
in just a moment from now.
This lesson will appear as if I'm typing in an empty JavaScript file but I do not want you to delete
these lines right.
This line adds in our CSX and this line enables hot module replacement.
So why don't we do this maybe at the very bottom of this file lets out a comment and say lesson example
code below this line.
OK.
And then right here where my cursor is blinking.
This is where you can follow along with the remainder of this video lesson and let's begin by simply
logging a test message to the console so we can say console dot log quotes.
This is a test.
Now if we save this and jumped to the browser we can view our web browsers console by right clicking
anywhere on the page and clicking inspect which will open up your developer tools.
And from here you can simply click on console.
And here we see this is a test.
All right.
And now let's jump back to our text editor and try something a bit more interesting.
Let's log another message to the console that reads.
Hello my name is John Doe and my favorite color is blue.
And then let's actually copy and paste this entire line and in the second copy let's change the name
to Jane Smith and let's change her favorite color to green.
Now if we save this and then back in the browser no surprises here.
This is exactly what we would expect.
But as a developer as a programmer this code should drive you insane because it is very repetitive.
The only unique aspects of each line are the named values and the color values.
Everything else is part of a pattern that we can define once and then recycle.
So let's delete all of this code and let's create a function that we can use.
Time and time again.
So let's give this new function a name of person.
And what do we want this function to actually do.
We want to log a message to the console that reads.
Hello my name is blank and my favorite color is blank.
And we want to include a closing period and we want to end this line with a semicolon.
OK.
Now we can simply call this function once for John and once for Jane.
So down on a new line let's call the person function that we just created.
Let's fill in this first blank value by passing an argument of John Doe and then we can fill in the
next blank by including a comma and passing an argument of blue let's add a semicolon here and now let's
call the person function again for Jane.
So the first argument is her name Jane Smith.
And the second argument will be her favorite color green.
So if each time we are calling the person function we are passing it to arguments a name and a color
we better make sure that up in our function definition we include two parameters to receive those incoming
two arguments.
Let's call the first one name and let's call the second one fave color.
OK.
Now within the actual body of our function we can access the argument values that are being passed in
by replacing these blanks with the name of our parameters.
There is no magical variable named blank.
I only added that temporarily as a placeholder.
So let's replace this first blank with our name parameter and let's replace the second blank with our
fave color parameter.
So if I save this and then back in the browser we see that nothing changes the exact same two sentences
are being output but behind the scenes we know that our code is less repetitive.
Let's go ahead and take things a step further and continue to improve our code.
So within this hypothetical application we can imagine that maybe in the future we would need to reference
John's name again or his favorite color again now because we didn't store these values anywhere if we
wanted to reference these values outside of this function we would have to manually type out John Doe
again and we would have to manually type out blue again and that would be repetitive.
Now one way around that would be to create individual variables.
So for example we could say let John name equal John Doe and then we could create another variable.
So say let John fave color equal blue and then we can use these variables throughout our entire application.
So for example when we call the person function for John instead of actually spelling out any values
we can simply pass in those variable names as arguments.
So we could say John name comma John fave color and if I save this and then back in the browser we see
the exact same result.
So our code is technically working we are storing data about John within these variables and then we
are accessing that data later on but we can do better.
This code just feels a bit sloppy or disorganized to me because you and I know that these two variables
are intrinsically related to each other.
They are both about John but currently we don't see that relationship reflected in our code.
So the question becomes how do we add structure to our data.
Well remember that this is a lesson on object oriented programming.
So surprise surprise the thing that is going to save us here is an object.
So let's delete these two individual variables and instead create an object for John so we can say let
John equal and a pair of curly brackets will create an object.
Now within this single object we can add anything and everything that has to do with John so we can
give this John object a property of name and we can give it a value of John Doe and we can give this
object another property named favorite color and give it a value of blue.
So now all of our data about John lives within a single unified John object and accessing these object
properties is a piece of cake.
So for example down within this function call these variables no longer exist.
So we want to replace these with references to the object properties.
So if we want to access John's name we can reference this property by simply typing John dot and then
the name of the property that we want.
So name.
All right.
And we can access the favorite color property by simply typing the name of the object.
John dot favorite color.
So if I save this and then back in the browser once again we see the exact same result.
Now at this point you might be wondering why there's a big fuss over objects.
What's the big deal.
I mean yeah it's nice that we added a bit of structure to our data but this doesn't feel earth shattering.
You might be thinking that object oriented programming is a bit overhyped.
But what if I told you that we can store more than just simple properties or variables like this within
an object.
What if I told you that we can also store functions within an object.
So this is where things get a bit exciting.
Let's go ahead and delete this function that we've been working on and let's also delete these two calls
to that function and let's go ahead and add a function within this John object.
So at the end of this line let's add a comma.
Let's create a new piece of this object named greet and greet is not going to contain data like these
two lines.
Gary is going to contain behavior so Gary will be a function as a quick example let's make this function
log out a bit of text to the console console log.
Oh hello.
Now if I save this we will not see that.
Oh hello message in the console.
And that's because we defined the function but we never called the function.
Now just like we access these properties by typing John dot name or John dot favorite color we can call
this function by simply typing John dot greet.
So if we save this and check out the browser we see oh hello.
This means that one variable or object can contain all of the data and behavior that it needs to operate.
So object oriented programming is about getting into a mindset where you stop thinking in terms of individual
loose variables and functions and you begin thinking in terms of cohesive self-sufficient objects and
an object is just an entity that has data and behavior.
Or another way of thinking about it is that it's an entity that has nouns and verbs.
So in our example John is the object name is a noun favorite color as a noun GRI is a verb it's an action
it's a behavior we use the function to make something happen.
Now just a really quick vocabulary note in the programming world when we have a function that belongs
to an object like this we no longer refer to it as a function but instead we call it a method and we
could add as many different methods to this object as we wanted.
So John as a person what sort of things can a person do.
We could add a walk method or a run method or a jump method.
You get the idea.
So now that we have a general understanding of what an object is let's go ahead and complete the agreed
method because we didn't just wanted to say Oh hello we wanted it to say hello my name is John Dot.
Name and my favorite color is John dot favorite color and then add in a closing period and if we save
this and then back in the browser we see our same old trusted sentence.
That's great.
But remember we didn't just have John whose favorite color is blue.
We also had Jane Smith whose favorite color is green.
So how do we want to create a new object for Jane.
Well I mean we could just copy and paste this so copy paste and then within this new copy we could just
change the variable name to Jane and fill in these values.
So Jane Smith favorite color green you get the idea we could update all of this for Jane but let's not
do that.
It would be very repetitive because the Greek method for both John and Jane is identical and there's
no good reason to spell out functionality like that more than once.
So this was a bad idea.
Let's delete it.
Now there are several different ways to create an object the way that we created the John object gets
the job done but it isn't the most efficient tool for the job when we want to create multiple objects
that are very similar to each other.
So let's actually delete everything that we have and try something new.
Let's create a reusable blueprint or recipe that spells out what a person objects should be in JavaScript.
We can create a reusable blueprint like that by leveraging something called a constructor function.
So let's create a new function let's name it person and in the programming world.
It's a common convention to begin our blueprint name with a capital letter.
We don't have to do this.
It's just a stylistic thing that will make our code easier to understand for other developers.
Now you might be thinking that this looks like a regular function.
What makes it a constructor function.
Well it all depends on the way that we actually use the function.
So check this out.
We know that we are going to want to create an object named John but instead of opening up a pair of
curly brackets and listing all of the properties and methods that we want we can simply say new person
the word new in Javascript is an operator that will create a new instance of our person object type
or in other words.
This will create a new object using our person blueprint.
This means that our John object will contain anything that we list within this constructor function.
So let's say that all person objects should have a method named greet within this constructor function.
We can simply say this dot Gary we will learn what the keyword this means in just a moment.
But for now let's complete this method equals and then create a function as a quick example let's just
log out a bit of text to the console that says Hello there.
Now because we added this method to our blueprint or recipe this means that our John object now has
a method named Gary.
So let's test it out.
Let's take it for a spin.
Let's say John dot Gary.
So if we save.
And then back in the browser.
Hello there.
So we know that we are also going to want to create a Jain object.
So let's say var Jain equals new person.
And we can rest assured that Jain also has a method named Gary.
So if I save this we see Hello there once from John and once from Jane.
Now just a moment ago I promised that we would learn what the this keyword means.
The this keyword is what allows our blueprint function to be flexible to be recyclable.
The value of this changes depending on how when and where this function is called.
So let's walk through an example when we create the John object and we call the constructor function
in that particular instance.
The this keyword refers to our John object but when we call this function again to create the Jain object
in that instance when this function runs the keyword this has a value of the gene object.
So I think you get the idea we can use the this keyword to refer to whichever object is currently being
created.
All right.
Now let's get back to the task at hand because our work is not complete yet.
Remember that we also wanted each person object to store the person's full name and their favorite color.
So let's add a couple of properties to our blueprint in order to store that data so we can add a new
line.
Let's begin with their name.
So this dot name equals and we can't just type John Doe because we want our blueprint to be recyclable.
We want this to make sense for all objects not just the John object.
So what we can do instead is include each person's full name as an argument.
When we call our person constructor function.
So down on this line for John we can include an argument with his full name John Doe and let's do the
same thing for Jane Jane Smith and then within the signature for our constructor function we can add
a parameter to receive that incoming name.
We could name the parameter anything we'd like.
Let's just go with full name.
And then within this function on this line we can just say this dot name equals full name.
All right.
Now let's also store each person's favorite color.
So down here when we call the constructor function once for each object let's include another argument
with their favorite color.
So John's is blue and Jane's favorite color is green.
Let's add a second parameter to our person function to receive that income and color value.
Let's call it fave color.
All right.
And then let's add a property for each object named favorite color and it should simply equal the color
that is getting passed in.
So fave color.
All right.
Now at this point anywhere within our application if we wanted to access John's name we could simply
type John dot name or if we wanted to access Jane's favorite color we could simply type Jane dot favorite
color but we don't need to do that.
What we do need to do is update our grief method to use our old trusted text so we didn't just want
this to say hello there.
We wanted it to say hello my name is this dot.
Name
and my favorite color is this dot favorite color and then add a closing period.
So if we save this and then back in the browser we see the two sentences that we were hoping to see
only this time our code is object oriented.
So now that we have these clean objects with these useful methods our code down here feels squeaky clean.
It's very easy to read and immediately understand what's going on.
And now that this code is complete we don't really need to look at it or think about it.
Now really quickly I want to point out that in other programming languages like C++ or Java this thing
that I've been referring to as a blueprint would actually be called a class but technically javascript
doesn't have classes anyways long story short it would be nice if we could tuck this class code away
into a separate file so that it's out of sight out of mind.
And that way our main JavaScript file would be squeaky clean.
And that is exactly what we are going to learn how to do in our next lesson.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you then.