Hello everyone.
In this lesson we will learn how to reveal an element when it's been scrolled to.
Why don't I share my screen so we can make sure that we're on the same page.
So here's what I'm referring to.
If we scroll down our page a bit down within this our features section in this lesson we are going to
initially hide these four items and as a user scrolls down the page once they scroll down to the point
that just the very top of these items would begin to display at that point.
These two items will gradually fade into view and once a user scrolls down about this far then these
two items will gradually fade into view.
This is a very popular effect that I'm sure you've seen on many Web sites before and believe it or not
it's pretty simple to set up.
All right.
So now we know what our goal for this lesson is.
Without further ado let's get started.
The first thing we should do is create a new get branch for this functionality.
So let's jump over to the command line and before we create a new branch let's first take care of the
branch that we currently have checked out which is the header branch in our previous lesson.
We completed the header of our website which means this branch is ready to be merged back into master
before we perform the merge.
Let's check for any uncommitted changes so let's run get status.
All right.
So quite a few files have been changed since my last comment.
All of these changes look good.
They all look header related so I will add everything to my staging area.
So get add dash uppercase a.
All right.
So if we run get status again all of the changes have been added to our staging area.
We are now ready to commit this so we can just type get commit.
Let's include a message so dash M and then quotes let's say completed desktop and mobile header styles.
And the quote push enter.
And now if we run get status once again we see working directory clean.
So at this point we can now jump back to our master branch so we can say get check out master.
Now with the master branch checked out if we look at the browser we see that none of our header changes
are in place.
So we want to go ahead and merge the header branch into the master branch.
So we simply type get merge header and now if we look at the browser we see that our master branch has
been updated to include our header and this makes me think that now is a good time to push our repo
up to get hub that way even if our computer blows up tonight we won't lose any of our website's progress.
So over in the command line let's type git and what do we want to do.
We want to push and where do we want to push our repo to.
We want to push it to get hub which we've saved as a remote named origin.
And just to be safe let's spell out which branch we want to push.
Master let's go ahead and press enter and now if we pull up our github repo page in a browser here we
see the latest commit completed desktop and mobile header styles.
This means we can rest easy knowing that our files have been backed up on github.
So at this point let's get back to the task at hand.
We want to create a new get branch for our Reveal on scroll feature so to create a new branch Let's
type get check out dash B and then the name of the branch we want to create let's call it reveal on
scroll.
Let's press enter and now we've checked out a new branch.
So we're good to go.
Let's begin working on this new feature by jumping to the text editor and let's create a new module
file where we can write the javascript to bring this feature to life.
So within our app Assets Scripts modules folder let's create a new file let's name this new file reveal
on scroll dot J.S. let's begin by creating a class and let's name the class reveal on scroll.
Open up a pair of curly brackets and below this class let's add a line down here at the very bottom
and let's go ahead and export this class.
So export default.
And then the name of the class reveal on scroll.
All right let's go ahead and save this file.
And before we forget let's include or import this file within our main JavaScript file.
So within our app assets scripts folder let's open up app dot J.S. after the second line of code.
Let's create a new line and say import reveal on scroll from open a pair of quotes dot forward slash
so we can point into a folder.
Let's go into the modules folder and then let's point towards that new file we just created.
So reveal on scroll all right.
Our next step is to create an object that is a new instance of this class.
So down on a new line let's create an object and name it reveal on scroll.
Notice we are beginning this with a lower case r and let's say that this equals a new instance of the
reveal on scroll class or blueprint.
Let's go ahead and save this file and then jump back into our Reveal on scroll module.
And within this class we know that we are going to need a constructor function.
So let's say constructor and let's begin by selecting the elements that we want to reveal.
So let's create a property within this object and name it items to reveal.
And this property should equal or point to the DOM elements that we want to reveal.
And just to refresh your memory the elements that we want to reveal are down here within the hour feature
section.
These four items and each of these items has a class of feature item.
So back in the text editor our items to reveal properties should equal.
Document dot query selector quotes and then to select the class it's a dot and then feature item however
query selector will only select the first element that matches this.
If we want to select multiple elements well we want to use a method named query selector all.
So right after the are here after selector just add in all just like this.
So we've selected the elements that we want to reveal once they are scrolled to.
But let me point out that you can't reveal that which isn't hidden.
So our first step is to actually go ahead and hide these elements initially.
So within our code let's actually create a new method.
So below the constructor function let's create a method named hide initially and let's begin by referencing
the property that points towards our elements.
So this dot items to reveal however this property is not a single dom element it's a collection of multiple
elements.
So at the end of this line let's include a dot for each and then within these parentheses we can provide
a function that will run once for each of the elements in this collection.
Let's start with a traditional anonymous functions function parentheses curly brackets.
Let's dropdown within these parentheses.
Let's include a parameter of l.
This will stand for element.
We could have chose any name.
And then within the body of this function we will just take that current element that's been looped
to say element dot class list dot add and let's give the element a class of reveal dash item.
All right.
Now this is a traditional anonymous function.
Let's turn it into an arrow function.
So our code feels a bit cleaner to do that we can get rid of the word function and since we have exactly
one parameter we don't need the parentheses around this parameter so we can get rid of this opening
parentheses and this closing parentheses.
All right.
And now after our parameter let's include the arrow symbol.
So that's equal sign greater than.
And since our function only has one line we can actually get rid of the whitespace so it sits on a single
line like this.
And if you only have one statement in your function you don't need the curly brackets either.
So we can get rid of this opening curly bracket here and also get rid of this closing curly bracket
here.
All right.
And we want this method to run as soon as the page loads.
So within our constructor function let's actually call or run the method.
So this dot Hyde initially let's go ahead and save this file and next let's create a new CSF file where
we can setup the styling for this new reveal item class that should hide the elements.
So within our app assets styles folder within the modules folder let's create a new file let's name
this new file underscore revealed dash item dot c SS All right.
And before we forget let's jump in to our main styles Doc CSX file and down at the bottom.
Let's import in the brand new CSX file.
So import go into the modules folder and look for the file underscore reveal item.
Let's save this and then jump back into the new CSX file and let's begin with a class selector.
So reveal item and let's hide the element initially by setting its opacity to 0.
So if we go ahead and save this file and jump over to the browser our four items are now hidden.
And while we still have our CSX file open why don't we go ahead and create the modifier class that we
can add to the elements to reveal them.
So within this rule let's create a new rule.
Let's begin with the ampersand symbol which will give us dot reveal item.
And then we can just add on a modifier Dash Dash is visible.
So within this class let's go ahead and set the opacity to 1 or fully visible.
And remember when we reveal an element we don't want it to go from completely hidden to completely revealed
in one millisecond.
We want it to gradually fade in so within the baseline rule.
Let's set the transition and say that the opacity property should gradually change over the course of
one and a half seconds.
And let's use the ease out transition style.
Now at this point we just need to use javascript to programmatically add this is visible class to the
hidden elements at precisely the right moment when they're scrolled to.
So let's go ahead and save this file and then jump into our Reveal on scroll JavaScript file and let's
begin listening for the scroll event in the browser.
So below our constructor and above our height initially method let's create a new method named events
OK.
And we know that we want our events method to fire right away.
So within our constructor let's just be sure to call it.
So this dot events.
OK.
Now in our events method let's begin listening on the window or the overall browser element so window
dot and then let's add an event listener and the type of event that we want to listen for is a scroll
event.
So whenever the user scrolls then still within these parentheses but after the quotes comma and let's
include a function let's start with a simple arrow function.
So empty set of parentheses.
And then the equal greater than arrow symbol and then pair of curly brackets.
Let's dropdown.
And now as we are scrolling we want to check to see if any of our four item to review elements have
been scrolled to yet.
So we'd want to run a calculation once for each of those items.
So let's start working with those four items.
This dot items to reveal dot and let's do something once for each of them.
So dot for each within the parentheses let's give it an arrow function that just has exactly one parameter.
So let's go the parameter name of L. short for the current element we've looped to.
And then the arrow symbol and then curly brackets let's dropdown inside these curly brackets now instead
of trying to calculate if the current element has been scrolled to right here.
Well why don't we include that logic in a separate method and just call that method here.
Let me show you what I mean.
So let's pretend we have a method named calculate if scrolled to so let's call it this dot calculate
if scrolled to parentheses to call it and now within these parentheses let's pass it the current element
that we've looped to.
So now let's go create a method with this matching name maybe right above height initially calculate
if sprawled to parentheses curly brackets within these parentheses let's received that incoming argument
with a parameter.
OK.
And now in the body of this function try this out with me.
Let's log a message to the console console dot log and we know that we can say E L to work with the
current element and let's say dot get bounding client rect parentheses to call that.
And then finally at the end of it say dot why.
So this is a property that all modern web browsers make available to us.
We will see firsthand what it does in just a couple of seconds.
Let's go ahead and save this file and jump into the browser you can pull up your console and resize
your window so you can see the console as you scroll but notice that as I begin scrolling we see all
sorts of values being output to the console.
So the question becomes what in the world does this get bounding client wrecked.
And then it's why property.
What in the world does that mean.
What are these numbers that we're seeing.
Well we know they're in some way tied to the.
Our feature elements that are currently hidden.
So let's scroll down to where those elements would live.
So the first one would be about right here.
And notice that as I scroll to where the top of that element would hit the top of our browser viewport
so right about here.
Notice that the number again there are four numbers because there are four our feature Divs.
But the first one is now very close to being zero.
So to answer the question of what is this value what is get bounding client rect and then in particular
the why property.
Well it's a measure of how far the top edge of an element is from the top edge of the current bounding
rectangle in this case the browser's viewport.
So if I scrolled to where the top edge of this hidden element was perfectly hitting the edge of our
viewport Well that would be zero.
Now the value is measured in pixels.
So if we just barely scroll to where the first item would be touching the bottom of the browser's viewport
well then the value would be the height of our browser window in pixels.
So with those numbers in mind we can now get a bit creative and come up with a solution.
Let me show you what I have in mind.
And again remember we want to reveal the items.
Once you've scrolled to them a bit let's say maybe once the top of an item has been scrolled into the
bottom 25 percent of our browser screen.
Then we would want to slowly faded into view.
Right.
So back in our text editor within our calculate method let's get rid of this current line and start
fresh.
Let's create a variable and let's call it scroll percent and let's set it to equal.
And then we're going to perform a bit of math.
I'm going to open up with a bit of parentheses because I want what I'm going to place in here to happen
first and then I want to multiply that by a hundred.
OK.
Now within these parentheses what I want to do is take that bounding rectangle number and then divide
it by the height of the browser window.
So let's do this within the parentheses we can say element dot get bounding client rect parentheses
to call that and then after those parentheses dot y and then we want to divide that so forward slash
divided by the web browsers height so window dot inner height.
OK.
Now altogether this is going to give us how far into the browser viewport the element has been scrolled
to.
So for example imagine if our first item lives here.
So I'm scrolling I'm scrolling I haven't saved yet.
So these numbers still don't make sense yet but if I scroll to about here our number would be about
75 percent or just seventy five because this is about 25 percent of the browsers height.
So let's do this right after our new line of code here.
Let's drop down and say if parentheses curly brackets for our if condition let's say if scroll percent
is less then and we can tweak this value later but for now let's just say seventy five.
Only if that's the case then let's reveal the item.
Let's make it visible.
So yell to work with the element and then let's say dot class list dot add and we give it a class of
reveal item Dash Dash is visible.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And now I know web pack inserts the new javascript on the fly but let's actually perform a refresh because
we don't want our old event handler still firing after you refresh.
If we scroll down and scroll very slowly just so we can see this in action noticed that as the item
crosses the 75 or depending on how you're looking at it the 25 percent threshold of our viewport it
slowly fades into view.
However even though the feature is up and running it is far from complete because as of this moment
the code that we have written is terribly horrendously inefficient.
So in our next lesson we are going to make our code much more efficient so it doesn't waste the computing
horsepower of the browser.
Also we will learn how to make our module recyclable so that we can use it to reveal the testimonials
once they are scrolled to.
It should be a lot of fun to set up so let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.