Hello everyone.
In this lesson we will resume styling our travel Web site to be specific.
We will work on the our features section.
Let's dive right in and get started.
So here we are in the browser.
If we scroll down a bit in this lesson we want to transform this our features section into what we see
in the design file which is this.
All right.
So the first thing that I want to work on is the main title to this section.
So this element which is supposed to look like this.
Let's begin by finding this element in our H2 PML.
So over in the text editor let's open up the HDMI file.
We can find that element by searching for our features.
Here it is.
And I actually want to create a brand new block for this element.
So let's go ahead and give this a class of section title.
All right let's save this file.
And now let's create a new CSX module file for this new class.
So within app assets styles and within the modules folder.
Let's go ahead and create a new file.
Let's name this new file underscore section dash title dot CSX.
All right.
And let's create a new class section titled save this file.
And before we free it let's open up our main styles dot CSX file and import this new file.
So import modules underscore section title save this file and let's jump back to our brand new section
title file.
All right.
So what CSX Should we write.
Well if we compare this to the design file the first thing that I notice is that we need a much larger
font size.
So if I measure from the top of these letters down to where a letter has a dissenter like the letter
Q or why would be.
That looks like about 60 pixels tall.
We want that in RAM.
So sixty divided by 16.
Three and three quarters let's copy that to our clipboard.
Font Size pasted in Ren.
That looks better.
I also noticed in the design file that the entire title should not be bold.
Only the word features should be bold.
So let's lower the font weight a bit font weight 300 and then within our HMO let's wrap the word features
in a strong tag.
It looks to me like there's not enough difference between not bold and bold.
So let's do this within our CSX file.
Let's say that any strong tags nested within this class should have a font weight of 500.
I think that looks better.
We also want this title to be centered horizontally.
So let's say text align center.
And we also want these star icon to be positioned next to the title.
So within our HMO let's just cut and paste the image that is right above the title into the H2 element
right before the text it's right here.
I'm just going to paste
looks good.
Let's give this image element a class so we can give it a bit of right margin and increase the space
between the icon and the text.
So here is that element.
Let's just go ahead and give it a class of section title because that is the block that it belongs to
underscore underscore to indicate that this is an element of a block and let's name it icon.
So then back in our CSX let's create a new rule icon and let's say margin right.
Let's give it just a little bit.
Let's go with half of a ram.
See how that looks.
All right.
So that was subtle but I think it looks good.
So our title element is complete.
If we look at the design file I think the next thing we should work on is creating this two column layout.
So over in our h t UML underneath the heading level two element that we were just working on let's create
a new div and let's leverage the row class that we created earlier in the course.
If you think back to several lessons ago we created a roadblock or a row class to create this two column
layout.
So let's go ahead and use it again here to create a two column layout.
Once again so within this new dig that has a class of row.
We want to create two columns that each take up half of the available width.
So if we think in terms of each 12 column grid that means that each column should take up six of the
12 column grid bars.
So let's create a column that has a class of row underscore underscore medium 6 and let's go ahead and
copy and paste that.
So there are two of them.
And then let's simply move half of the content into one column and the other half of the content into
the other column.
So let's take this block of code in this block of code.
Let's cut that and paste it into this first column and then let's take this section in this section.
Cut it and pasted into this second column.
And let's be sure to get rid of these empty spaces and save this file.
And then within our CSF modules folder let's open up the road at CSX file.
So currently this road block supports a two column split of the one third and two thirds.
Now we want to go ahead and allow it to support the two columns that are equal width.
So in our CSX file Let's just scroll down a bit.
Here is the medium for rule which creates a column that is about one third of the available width right
below this.
Let's create a new rule medium dash 6 and we will just float it to the left and give it a width of 50
percent so we see that that gives us a two column layout.
However we need a bit of margin or gutter between the two columns.
Now earlier in the course when we originally created the row block we created a modified class that
we can place on the row element of row dash dash gutters which does indeed create a margin between the
two columns.
But if we look at the design file I think that this our features section calls for an extra wide gutter.
So why don't we just go ahead and create a new modifier class of row dash dash gutters dash large and
then over in our CSX for the row block towards the top right after this original gutters modifier.
Let's just create a new one gutters dash large and if our regular gutters are sixty five pixels let's
make the extra wide gutters or the large gutters about 100 pixels.
So for those gutters large modifier margin right.
Negative 100 pixels.
And also underneath this next rule let's create a new corresponding one for our gutters large modifier
class so any direct children that are a div.
So in other words all of the columns instead of padding write of 65 pixels.
Let's give it 100 pixels.
So let's save that.
And check out the browser looking good.
If we check out our design file I think the next thing we should work on is creating a block for this
style.
Right.
So this layout where the icon sits to the left and the corresponding text sits to the right.
So let's create a new block and apply it only to this first feature item to begin with.
And once we have things looking good then we can apply that block to the other three feature items.
So over in our h t demo here is the first feature item consists of the icon the heading in the paragraph.
So let's just go ahead and wrap that in a new div that has a class of feature item.
Go ahead and close that div and let's indent this content just to stay organized next let's create a
new CSX file for our new feature item class.
So in our CSX modules folder let's create a new file.
Let's name the file underscore feature item dot CSX.
Let's create a new class feature item save this file and then let's go into our main styles that CSX
file and import this new file.
So modules underscore feature item.
All right.
So back in the feature item file.
Let's write a bit of CSX that will position this text to sit side by side with the icon.
Now there are probably 50 different ways that we can achieve that with CSX the way that I'm going to
do it is begin by giving the image element a class so we can target it with our CSX.
So here is the image element.
Let's go ahead and give it a class of feature item underscore underscore icon now in our CSX.
Let's try this.
Let's give the overall parent item the feature item class.
Let's give it a bit of padding left.
How much should we give it.
Well if we check out the design file if I measure from this left edge of the icon to where the content
begins.
Looks like about ninety four pixels.
So let's say padding left ninety four pixels.
All right.
So that pushes all of the content in.
Now we can just position the icon.
Absolutely to sit in the top left corner.
So let's select that icon
position absolute left zero.
And because we want the icon to be positioned in relation to its parent let's be sure to give the parent
element position relative.
So let's save this.
And check out the browser.
And there we have the layout.
The next thing I think we should work on is the styling for this title or heading.
So in our HMO let's give that element a class so we can target it with CSX.
Let's give it a class of feature item underscore underscore title.
Let's head over to our CSX file and create a rule title let's start with font size.
So if we check the design file for measure from the top of this letter down to the bottom of the Y in
the P looks like about 30 pixels to me in terms of ran 30 divided by 16 gives us this let's copy that
to our clipboard.
Pasted in ran.
And while we at it in the design file I noticed that this does not look like a bold font weight.
So let's go ahead and also adjust the font weight to 300 I think that looks good.
Next why don't we focus on the paragraph text.
I think it should use a slightly larger font size and a significantly higher line height.
Now if you think back to several lessons ago we actually created a reusable class named generic content
container and that is how we created the styling for these paragraph elements so we can apply that same
font size in line height to the our features section by heading over to our HD GMO and on the main road
div for the outer feature section.
Let's just give it a class of generic content container
that looks a lot better but I'm noticing that the font weight for these paragraphs looks a bit high.
So why don't we go ahead and open the CSX file for the generic content container block and within the
rule that selects paragraphs.
Why don't we just say font weight.
Three hundred.
It's a subtle change but I think it matches the design.
Next let's reduce the space between the title and the paragraph so to do that.
Let's take two steps.
First let's adjust our generic content container until paragraphs to not have any top margin.
So within this margin line let's just add a couple of zeros.
This is CSF shorthand and it works in a clockwise fashion.
So top right bottom left.
So in other words we are zeroing out all of the margins except for the bottom margin on our generic
content container paragraphs.
So with that change in place we are now free to reduce the bottom margin of this title.
So within our feature item CSF file within these selector for the title element let's say margin bottom
point eight Ram
perfect that spacing matches the design.
All right.
So I think the styling for this block is good to go.
Let's go ahead and apply that same each T.A. pattern to the other three features.
So in our HDMI file let's wrap this image heading in paragraph in a div it has a class of feature item.
Here's the closing div tag.
Let's indent these.
Let's scroll down a bit.
Let's do the same thing for these three elements.
So did with a class of feature item closing div tag indent.
Let's just go ahead and copy this so we can paste it once again for this section of content.
So let's paste that let's wrap the closing div and let's indent the content.
If we scroll back up to our first feature item we will remember that we added a class to the image element.
So let's just go ahead and copy this and then paste it onto these other three images.
So here here and here.
And if we scroll back up we also want to do the same thing for the heading Level 3 element.
So we want to copy this class and then go ahead and paste it here here and here.
So let's save that.
And check out the browser
and everything starts to fall into place.
Now if we go ahead and compare this with the design file the biggest thing that I notice is that we
need to add a bit of vertical spacing between the items currently our items in the browser are too close
together.
So let's jump over to our feature item CSX file and within the main rule let's just add a bit of padding
bottom.
So let's say padding bottom.
Let's go with three and three quarters REM that looks like a bit too much vertical spacing.
Let's reduce that to two and a half Ram.
I think that matches the design nicely.
And at this point we've actually completed the styling for this section or at least for larger screens.
Why don't we see how things look on a smaller screen I see several things that I would like to adjust
for mobile.
The first would be that I think this title should use a smaller font size.
So let's jump over to the CSX file for our section titled block why don't we copy and paste this current
font size into a media query mix in some mix in at small paste that in and let's lower the baseline
font size to two point five five RAM.
That looks better.
Next let's position things so that this star sits on its own line.
So back in our CSX within the selector for the icon element let's tell our baseline styles to make that
element a block level element which will drop the text after it onto a new line.
And now that it's a block level element let's make sure that it stays horizontally centered by saying
margin left auto margin right.
Auto.
Now obviously these will conflict with this previous property that we had but we only want this right
margin to apply if screens are certain size or larger.
So let's cut this line and begin a media query Mixon.
So mix in at small pace that right margin back in.
Let's also offset that left margin that we set for small screen.
So let's say margin left 0.
Let's also tell the icon to be an inline block level element so that on larger screens it won't drop
the text down to a new line.
So let's save this.
That's a step in the right direction but I think it could benefit with a bit of margin vertically in
between the icon and the text.
So why don't we say within our baseline Stiles margin bottom go is just a little over half of a ramp
so point six Ram.
And then we want to undo that for larger screen.
So margin bottom 0 within the mix in.
Let's save that think that looks nice for small screens and that will actually bring part 1 of this
two part lesson to a close in part 2.
We will finish optimizing this layout for small screens and we will also learn about an alternative
way to merge our get branch back into Master.
Let's keep rolling along.
And I will see you in part to.