Hello everyone.
In this next section of the course we will learn about a couple of new tools named node dot J.S. and
NPM.
Let's not worry about the names of these tools for now and instead let's begin with a few questions.
So the first question that you might have is are all of these tools really necessary.
Why are we not writing H TMX CSX in JavaScript yet.
Why can't we just get started building the actual Web site.
That's a fair question.
I know that it's one I personally asked when I first heard about these other tools.
And here is the answer.
Here is why we need a few other tools.
It's because while we build the site we want automation and organization automation will save us time
and organization will save us from pulling our hair out.
So let me elaborate on those two terms a bit.
Automation just means to take a task and make it automatic.
Make the computer be able to do it for us.
So when we are building a Web site if there is a small task that we find ourselves performing again
and again and again even if it only takes a few seconds imagine how much time we can save throughout
the course of a day.
If we can find a way to make the computer perform that task for us automatically.
Let me give you a few real world examples.
So whenever we save a change to one of our HDMI LCROSS or JavaScript files we then want to see what
those changes look like in the web browser.
Now instead of hopping into your browser and hitting control R or command R or hitting the refresh button
wouldn't it be nice if your computer could detect that you had saved changes to a file and then automatically
trigger a refresh in the browser for you.
Your computer definitely can do that for you.
And that is an example of automation.
For another example of automation we could setup something called CSX auto prefix or now.
In recent years we don't need to use CSX vendor prefixes as much as we used to.
But for certain properties they are still necessary.
Now instead of wasting the time of typing out all of these messy vendor prefix names or even wasting
the time of trying to memorize which properties need prefixes and which don't we can set up our computer
to watch for any saved changes to a CSX file and then it will automatically trigger a filter to run
on our CSX files and the computer is intelligent enough to know which properties need to be prefixed
and it will automatically add those prefixes to our CSX.
That will save us a lot of headache that will save us a lot of time.
And it's another example of automation.
So that's automation in a nutshell.
There are a lot of different tasks that we can automate using Node J.S. and NPM that will save us a
ton of time on a daily basis.
Next let's talk a little bit about organization and how no doubt J.S. and NPM can help us stay organized.
Let's begin with CSX organization as we write the CSX for our Web site.
We don't want to place all of the code within one single huge CSX file.
Instead we want to stay organized by keeping our CSX separated in multiple bite sized files.
So for example any CSX code related to the header of the Web site would go in its own file named header
dot CSX.
Any styles related to the footage of the Web site would go in a file named footer dot CSX.
This way if we need to revisit and update the Web site six months or even a year down the road we will
know exactly where to find that little bit of CSX that we want to update.
Having said all of that we still don't want to litter the head section of our Web site with calls to
40 different CSX files even though we as the developer want to work with multiple bite sized CSX files
at the end of the day we still want to serve the web browser and the visitors of our Web site.
One single CSX file.
The good news is that we can have the best of both worlds.
And this ties back into automation we can setup our computer to watch for any saved changes to any of
our multiple bite sized CSX files and when a save is detected the computer will automatically in the
matter of a few milliseconds combine all of our little CSX files into the one single file that we can
serve to the browser while still leaving all of our little CSX files intact.
This way our Web site will load quickly and we as the developer can still stay organized.
So that's one example of CSX organization.
We will learn about many others throughout this course but for the time being before we bring this lesson
to an end.
There's one final type of project or code organization that I want to talk about and that is package
management.
We will learn about package management in detail throughout the course.
But for now I want to keep things really simple.
So what is package management.
Well if you've created a Web site in the last few years odds are that you used bootstrap or maybe low
dash or maybe you used the popular CSI as reset named normalized CSX.
Now what do those three things have in common.
The answer is you didn't write or create any of them.
They are pieces of code or packages that someone else maintains and you might use 5 10 or 20 different
packages on a Web site that you create.
Now as you're going to Google and searching for load ash or going to Google and searching for bootstrap
to get the files to download if you've ever thought to yourself there's got to be a better way of doing
this.
There's got to be a faster more automated way of getting access to all of these different files.
Well if you've ever thought that you were absolutely correct there is a better faster way of getting
all of those files.
And it's called package management.
We will learn all about package management in the next few lessons.
But for now this lesson has come to a close.
Let's review what we've covered.
We learned that when we build a Web site we want automation an organization now that we know what's
possible.
Now that we know that we can configure our computer to do all of these neat automatic things for us.
It's just a matter of learning how to make the computer do all of that.
The key to turning your computer into your own little robot assistant is learning a few tools named
node J.S. and NPM in our next lesson we will learn what in the world no dot J.S. even is.
You will get your hands dirty.
I will help you install node on your computer and we will walk through a few code examples together
step by step.
It's going to be a lot of fun.
And I will see you in the next lesson.