Hello everyone.
In this lesson we're going to learn about web pack web pack is at the center of all of the automation
that we're going to be setting up in the course.
Let's begin by asking ourselves what exactly is web back.
Well if we take a look at the official web pack Web site we see that it says bundle your assets bundle
your scripts bundle your images and bundle your styles.
So Web backed bundles things that means that it's a bundler.
But what in the world does that mean.
What's a bundler.
Well to completely oversimplify things.
Remember how we were able to use the NPM install command to pull in packages from the NPM grocery store.
Well web PAC can help us bundle up those packages that our Web site depends on in a way that is easy
for visitors of our Web site to download and consume.
Now granted that's just one of about 5000 different things that web pack can do for us.
But it is an important one.
Now before we move on any further I want to let you know that if you're anything like me during the
next few chapters web pack might seem overly complicated or like it's not worth the effort but trust
me by the end of the course you'll be wondering how you ever lived as a web developer without web back
and you don't need to take my word for it.
So here on the NPM page for the web back package we can see that just in the last week web Park has
been downloaded over eight point three million times.
This lets you know that web pack is absolutely an industry standard and not just an obscure tool that
I'm a big fan of.
All right.
Now at this point in order to understand what web pack actually does.
Let's get our hands dirty.
So first let's make sure that we have something worth bundling.
So I want you to jump into your text editor and open up the travel site folder that we set up in a previous
lesson.
So in my case I have this folder on my desktop named sites and then I have the travel site folder.
So go ahead and drag this onto your V.S. code or within V.S. code you can click file and then open or
open folder and just choose that directory.
So within the travel site folder we have a folder named app.
And within this app folder let's create something that we would want web pack to bundle for us.
Now web back can work with all sorts of different file types.
But out of the box without any extra configuration web pack only understands JavaScript files.
So right now let's create a new JavaScript file that we would want web pack to process for us.
So to stay organized within our app folder let's jump into the assets folder.
Currently we just have the images folder.
Let's close that.
And within the assets folder let's create a brand new folder just for JavaScript files.
So right click on assets and choose New Folder we could name anything but just so you and I are on the
same page.
Let's name this new folder scripts OK.
And let's create a new JavaScript file within this new scripts folder.
So right click on scripts choose new file.
Again we could name anything but let's name it uppercase a let's call it app dot J S OK.
Now within this new empty javascript file let's write a bit of test or example code so just for a quick
test maybe let's create an annoying alert pop up in the web browser.
So to do that we can just say alert in parentheses in those parentheses.
Let's say quotes and then hello.
This is just a test.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
Now this code is so simple that we don't actually need web back.
Right.
We didn't split our code into multiple files to stay organized nor are we leveraging any packages from
NPM but that's not the point.
That complexity will come later in the course.
For now we just want a javascript file no matter how simple or complex it is so that we can practice
telling web pack to look at it process it and bundle it.
So the question becomes how do we begin actually using Web pack.
And the answer is we go to our command line.
If you're using V.S. code you can open your command line by just clicking on the View menu and then
selecting terminal or for a keyboard shortcut.
And this works on both windows in Mac.
You can just hold down the control key and then simultaneously press the tilde key which is the key
to the left of the number one or right above the tab key.
And that will toggle your command line.
OK.
Within your command line I want you to run the following command with me.
So type this out npm install and we want to install two packages the first package is named Web pack
as you might have guessed at a space in the second package we want to install is named Web pack Dash.
S.L. I CLIA stands for command line interface.
And finally at the end of the command enter a space and then dash dash save dash Dev after you've typed
in this entire command.
Go ahead and press enter now even if you're using a very fast computer and internet connection this
installation could take upwards of 30 seconds or so.
So be patient.
But once it completes this means we now have web pack within our local project.
So now the question becomes how do we actually use or leverage web pack.
And the answer is that we want to create a configuration file within the route of our folder.
So not even within our app folder just within the root of our travel site folder I want you to right
click and choose new file.
Now the name of this file absolutely matters.
It needs to be lowercase web Park dot config dot J Yes go ahead and press enter.
Now web PAC will know to look for a file with this exact name and within this new file we essentially
tell Web PAC what we want it to do.
And in order to do that we will begin by typing a pair of curly brackets.
So we're creating a javascript object and we give it different properties to tell web packed what to
do to create this character you just hold down the shift key and press the key to the right of your
peaky.
OK.
Within these two curly brackets let's dropdown just to stay organized and to start out we only needed
to find one property and its name is entry.
So type in entry colon and then a pair of quotes.
And now this is where we type a path that points towards our JavaScript file that we want to bundle.
Right.
So we want to point towards this file app dot J Yes.
The file we created a few moments ago.
So it lives within the app folder and then assets and then scripts.
So for our file path here within these quotes let's say dot slash.
To start with the current root directory and then go into the app folder Slash.
And then go into the assets folder slash.
And then go into the scripts folder slash and then look for the file that is named uppercase app dot
yes right.
So we're saying the entry point to our javascript application or we're saying the file that we want
web pack to watch and process and bundle lives at this path.
All right.
Now for the time being this is the only property we need to setup.
So now the question becomes how do we actually tell web pack to use this file as its instructions and
actually run actually process and bundle our file.
Well first up at the very top of this file on the very first line of code even right before the opening
curly bracket I want you to type out module dot exports equals OK.
And now we can go ahead and save this file.
So this just sets things up so that when Web packet loads this file it knows that there's javascript
object we just created is what should be exported and used.
All right.
Now we're on to the final step to get web pack to actually run what we need to do now is jump into our
package dot Jason File within this package dot JS on file we have properties such as name version dependencies
Deb dependencies.
And right now we're looking for a section or property named scrips you will likely already have a property
name scripts but if you don't have one you can just add one like this.
So after maybe version or name right after the comma you can just drop down to a new line and say quotes
Scripps colon and then curly brackets and then right after those curly brackets add a comma OK and then
within those curly brackets we can create as many different NPM scripts as we want to essentially and
NPM script is a command that we will be able to run from the command line.
Now your package got Jason File probably already contained something like this a test script within
the pre-existing scripts section.
That's OK.
What we can do maybe right above that line but still within these scripts objects are just like this.
We can create a new script and we can give it any name we want.
Let's name it dev so quote dev and then a colon and then quotes and all we need within the quotes is
simply Web pack and then be sure to include a comma after those quotes.
Cool.
The reason we needed to do this is because we don't want to have to install web pack globally on our
computer.
So if we just went to the command line and tried to run Web PAC directly from the command line our computer
would have no idea what we mean.
However if we create an NPM script like this well it will have no trouble looking within our node modules
folder and finding the web pack package.
So check this out go ahead and save this current file that we're in and then open up your command line.
Now check this out if we want to run this script that we just created named Dev we can just say in the
command line NPM run and then the name of the script.
So that's dev and then go ahead and press enter cool.
So notice in your sidebar that just created a brand new folder named dist and within that folder there's
a new file named Main dot J.
Yes.
So Web pack looked at our app dot J.S. file and it processed it and bundled it and created this new
main J.S. file.
This is great.
But what if we don't want the new generated file to be named Main dot J S what if we want to control
what it's named and also what if we don't want it to go into this disk folder.
What if we just wanted the newly generated or bundled file to live within our app folder.
Well let's set that up right now.
So jump back into your web Park dot config dot J.S. file and right at the end of this entry line let's
add a comma and then we can drop down after the comma to a new line and let's add a property named output
so output colon and then curly brackets to create a javascript object in between then we can dropdown
first lets out a property named file name so file name called in quotes and then this is where we can
control what the bundled file should be named just so you and I are on the same page.
Let's name it bundled Dot.
J Yes.
Okay.
And then in order to control where the newly generated file is placed.
So if we didn't want it to be in this disk folder we can just say comma at the end of this line and
then say part colon and imagine we want the bundled copy to sit in the app folder directly.
So sitting side by side our index start each PML file.
So to do that we'd say path colon and then type this out with me path dot resolve parentheses underscore
underscored dir name short for directory name comma and then quotes and then add.
If you're wondering why this path looks like a different syntax from this path it's because web pact
requires an absolute path for the output.
Now in order for this code to work we do need to manually import or require in the know J.S. path package.
So up at the very top of this file up at the start of Line 1 Let's press enter and create a new line
up here and just say const path equals and then require parentheses within these parentheses.
Let's just say quotes.
Path.
We do not need to npm install path.
This is just part of the node library.
This makes sure that no matter what operating system you're on Windows Mac or Linux it will be able
to generate an absolute path to the correct folder.
Okay.
And finally while we're at it let's make sure we address this annoying warning message that we see in
the command line.
So it's just warning us that we didn't set the mode of web back.
So to fix that maybe right after the output property so right after this inner closing curly bracket
you can say comma and then let's add a property named mode call in quotes and let's set the mode to
development right because we're just still developing things we're not ready to deliver these files
to the public or up to a live web host yet.
So go ahead and save this file if you need to pause the video to make sure that your web page config
file looks like mine that's OK.
Now before we test this out again let's be sure to delete the disk folder in the left hand sidebar.
Right we didn't want the bundled file to be output there any longer.
So I'm just going to right click on dist and choose Delete OK and then down in our command line let's
tell Webb pack to run again.
So we just run NPM run Dev go ahead and press enter cool.
So notice now within the route of our app folder right alongside index the HMO we have the brand new
generated bundled dot J.S. file.
Let's actually jump into our HD PML file and load or import in the javascript file.
So jump in the index dot HDMI L and scroll down to the very bottom of this file down at the very bottom
right above this closing body tag type this in with me.
So let's create a new line and let's say.
Script tag your text editor should automatically create the closing script tag.
Now on the opening script tag let's just point towards that new bundled file so S.R. C equals quotes
in the name of the file is bundled dot J yes OK go ahead and save this file.
And now let's go load or preview this HD AML file in our web browser.
So here's my web browser.
And then if I go find that HD PML file on my computer.
So Sites Travel site app there is index dot HDMI I'll just go ahead and drag out on top of your web
browser.
Cool.
We see that annoying alert pop up from our app that J.S. file.
Right.
Hello.
This is just a test.
Let's practice updating this pop up message and having Web pack generate the bundle again.
So in our text editor jump into app dot J yes let's change this so that it ends with three exclamation
marks instead of a period.
So go ahead and save that.
And now if you refresh in the browser you will not see that change.
So we need to tell web pack to generate the bundle again.
To do that we would just jump back into our command line and run NPM run Dev.
So that will run Web pack once again.
And now if we refresh in the browser we do see the latest message right.
We see those three exclamation marks.
Now you might be thinking that's really inconvenient.
I don't want to have to jump to my command line every time I make a change to a file.
Well luckily for us we don't need to.
So check this out jump back into your web pack config dot J.S. file and maybe right underneath this
mode line let's add a comma at the end of that line then dropdown and if we just say watch colon and
set it to true and then save this file.
Check this out.
Now if we run our web pack task so in the command line if you run NPM run Dev well because we set the
watch option to true Web pack will stay running and it will watch and detect any time we save a change
to our source file or our entry file.
So check this out if we go back into app that yes and maybe if I remove these exclamations entirely
and then save the file that triggers a fresh rebuild or re bundle.
So if we go back to the web browser refresh you see the updated text or if we go back and change this
text entirely.
The sky is blue and hit save web pack is actively watching us.
So we don't need to run the command manually again and again if we go back and refresh we can see that
Web pack has already bundled it for us now because we told web pack to watch our files for us it's going
to continue to run in the command line until we tell it to stop.
So when we are ready for the web pack task to stop watching us in your command line you just press the
control key and then simultaneously press the C key.
So control C and it stops now.
I will be the first one to admit that this specific example is not impressive at all but that's only
because our update J.S. file is so simple.
Right.
We just have the annoying alert.
If we were actually doing something complex in this file then Westpac would be a lifesaver because now
every time we save a change to this file we have an automated workflow tool that magically makes everything
happen in a matter of milliseconds.
In other words now that we have Westpac watching and processing and bundling this file for us we can
start to build our project and Web site and gradually add complexity and new features as needed and
Westpac will be along for the ride with us in our very next lesson.
Things are going to get very real and concrete and useful because we're going to be implementing CSX
into our web pack workflow.
It should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling.
I'll see you then.