Hello everyone.
In this lesson we're going to take our web pack automation to another level.
Here's an overview of what we're going to set up.
First we will adjust things so that whenever we save a change to see SS or JavaScript files that code
is automatically updated or injected into the browser's memory without a full reload even being necessary.
After that we will set things up so web pack reloads the browser for us automatically when we save a
change to our H CML file.
And finally we will learn how to view our development site on any device connected to the same Wi-Fi
network as the computer we're working on.
This is great for testing your Web site on a small screen like a phone or a tablet.
Now there's one piece of technology that's going to make all three of these things possible.
And that's a package named Web pack dev server.
Just so you were aware web pack dev server is not an obscure package that I'm just a big fan of.
Here on the NPM page for this package we can see that just in the last week it has five point three
million downloads so it's definitely an industry standard.
So right now let me show you how to begin using it.
So first we need to jump into our command line and run the following command with me npm install the
name of the packages web pack dash Dev dash server after that.
Be sure to include dash dash save dash dev and then press enter
OK.
Now that we've installed the package we need to leverage it.
So to do that we go into our web pack dot config dot J.S. file so down within this area where we have
module dot exports equals and then we have different properties like entry output mode watch.
We want to add a new property.
So maybe right after the comma for this output area let's drop down and lets out a new property named
Dev and then uppercase server.
So all one word that's the property name dev server colon and then it's going to be an object.
So a pair of curly brackets and then right after that include a comma.
Okay.
Within these curly brackets let's dropdown to stay organized.
Let's give it a property named content uppercase base.
So content base colon.
And now this is where we point towards the folder or directory that we want web pack to serve up.
So in our case that would be the app folder.
Right.
Because the app folder is where our index the HDL file lives right and that's what you would want to
visit in the web browser.
So we just want to point towards our app folder.
So for content base after the colon let's say path dot join parentheses and then say underscore underscore
Dern name comma and then quotes and then app at the very end of this line after the parentheses.
Let's include a comma dropdown.
Let's add another property named hot and set it to true.
Let's add a comma.
Let's add one more property named port.
And set it to three thousand.
So for a bit of an explanation for these two properties port is what's going to allow Web pack to inject
our new sea SS and JavaScript into the browser's memory on the fly without even needing a reload or
refresh.
Westpac calls that hot module replacement or hot for short and then port.
This would have a value of 80 80 by default but we're setting it to 3000 just because I think it's a
bit easier to remember.
You'll see where this number comes into play in just a moment.
OK.
For the time being that takes care of the dev server object but I do want you to look down just one
or two lines and find our watch property.
So right now it's set to watch true.
Well the dev server is going to be watching for changes so we no longer need this watch property.
So I would just delete this entire watch coal and true line like this.
OK at this point let's go ahead and save this file.
And right now I need you to jump into our package dot Jason File with me within package dot Jason I
want you to find the scripts area.
Remember we have this NPM script named Dev.
Well we just want to change what it actually runs.
So instead of calling Web back we want it to call Web pack dev server now.
So within these quotes or after the K for web practice a dash Dev dash server.
OK.
Let's go ahead and save this file and now we just need to make one more change before we can test things
out.
Right now we need to go into our main JavaScript file and tell it to accept hot module replacements
right or to accept updates on the fly.
So let's dig into our app folder and then assets and then scripts and then jump into the file named
app dot J.S. down at the bottom was add a new line and let's say if parentheses within the parentheses
will say module dot hot after those parentheses curly brackets drop down in between say module dot hot
dot except in parentheses to call the accept method.
So essentially we're just saying except the hot updates if it makes sense to accept them.
Let's go ahead and save this file and now we can test everything out.
So just like before to tell Webb back to begin running or watching us we just go to the command line
and type in the following command NPM run Dev go ahead and press enter.
OK.
And now to check things out in the web browser we do need to visit a different U.R.L. so go up into
your address bar and completely clear it out and type this in with me load goal host colon.
And then this is the port number.
So after the colon it's just three thousand.
Go ahead and press enter cool.
So we see our Web site.
But what's the big deal.
What have we been working on for the last five or six minutes.
Well to refresh your memory if we look at the overview for this lesson again remember our first task
was to set things up so that when you save changes to a SS or JavaScript file it updates in the browser
without a full page reload.
So right now let's ask ourselves what is a full page reload.
Well in your browser if you click this refresh icon here or if you press control are on a P.C. or command
are on a Mac it reloads the page.
Now a full page reload like that is very expensive in terms of performance or speed.
It forces the web browser to completely reload and re render and repaint the entire page.
So anytime we can avoid a full reload that's great.
Just a quick tip so you can see if your browser is reloading or not if you select a bit of text right.
If you click and drag on a headline.
Well as soon as you reload the page that text selection that highlighted it is going to be lost.
Right.
So if I press command are it's gone.
So now let's test things out to make sure web PAC can actually update our code without a full page reload.
So go ahead and select a bit of text.
Why don't you go ahead and click and drag and select this your clarity headline.
OK.
And let's go into our CSX file and change the font size for this headline to something ridiculous.
So within our styles folder and then within our modules folder let's jump into large hero dot CSX.
So here is that title selector right now font size is set to four point eight REM.
Let's set it to something crazy like nine point eight REM.
Now as soon as we hit save.
Back in the browser we don't need to refresh and you can see the web browser itself didn't even refresh
because our text selection is still in place.
This proves to us that web pack is doing its job and doing it very well.
It's bundling up our code and then it's injecting that latest code into the browser's memory on the
fly.
Not only is this fast but it's also convenient when we begin working with JavaScript and for example
maybe you click something and it opens a menu.
Well it will be nice to be able to change the CSX for that menu without having to refresh and keep closing
and reopening that menu each time.
Right.
If we can keep the browsers current state and just inject our new code into memory that's going to save
us a lot of trouble down the road.
Cool.
Let's go ahead and put this font size back to normal.
So instead of nine point eight just put it back to four point eight hit save.
We don't even need to refresh.
It's just updated on the fly.
Perfect.
At this point let's change gears.
So if we look at our lesson overview item number two is to set things up so that whenever we save a
change to our each TMM file the browser reloads on its own to set that up.
We just need to jump back into our web pack dot config dot J.S. file go ahead and find your dev server
object within it.
We have properties like content base hot in Port.
So we just want to add one more property inside dev server named before.
So before colon and we're actually going to give it a function.
So as a function parentheses curly brackets now right after those curly brackets.
Be sure to add a comma.
OK.
Now within the parentheses for our function let's give it two parameters app comma server.
And then within our curly brackets or the body of our function we can dropdown and let's say server
dot.
And then there's a method named underscore watch within these parentheses.
Let's give it quotes and let's tell it to watch for any file that ends with DOT HDMI out.
So I would say dot slash look in the app folder slash and then asterisk asterisk will look for any sub
folder if necessary slash and then asterisk any file that ends with DOT HDMI out.
OK.
At this point let's go ahead and save this file if you need to pause the video while you type this out.
That's OK but let's test this out.
So in our command line let's press control C to stop the old instance of web pack control C and then
let's fire up a new instance of web pack that will use our latest web patch config code.
So just NPM run Dev.
OK.
Back in the web browser I will give it a refresh.
Now that we're using a new configuration and let's test something out.
Let's do this.
Let's go into our HDMI file and edit this headline to end with an exclamation point instead of a period.
So within our app folder jump into index dot each CML for me it's around line number 26.
So if I change the period add an exclamation point and then save this file back in the browser.
Cool.
I did not have to refresh it refreshed for me now just a quick note when it comes to our HDMI oil it
is performing a full page reload.
So if I select this text just as an example and if I put this back to a period and save.
Notice that back in the browser my text selection or highlight is gone.
That's OK.
It does need to load the new HDMI page so a full reload is to be expected.
Let's make sure that our CSF is still working without a full reload though.
So if we select this go into our large hero.
Change the font size.
Cool.
So that is still working without a reload.
Let me put that back to four point eight.
Perfect.
At this point let's look at our overview again because we are ready to move on to our third and final
task.
We want to be able to view our website on any device connected to our Wi-Fi or our network this way.
It's really simple to test our website on a small screen like a smartphone or tablet.
Let me show you how we can set this up.
So back in our text editor jump into our web pack config dot J.S. file within our dev server object
maybe right below the port line lets out a comma at that line add a new line and we just need to give
it a property of host colon and let's give it a value of quotes and then 0 dot 0 0 0 so for 0 separated
with periods in between.
This will allow devices on the same network to be able to access the web packed dev server from this
computer.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And then since we have a new Web Pad configuration let's restart the web pack task.
So in the command line press control C and then fire it up again.
So NPM run Dev.
OK now from the current computer you're working on you'll still be able to visit your Web site from
local host.
Colon three thousand however this address is not going to work on another device on your network.
So for example the question becomes if you have a smartphone ready right now what address when you type
in the smartphones web browser address bar to visit this site.
Well in order to answer that question we need to find the local IP address of the computer you're working
on.
Now that's not the public IP address that a malicious user could take advantage of.
We want the local IP address so unfortunately we can't just go to Google and type in what is my IP because
that would give you your public IP to find your local IP address.
It's a bit different depending on whether you're using Mac or Windows.
Let's cover both.
So if you're on Mac just go into your system preferences and then click on the network icon and then
towards the top of the right hand column you should see a bit of text and it will say which network
you're on and it will also include an IP address that's your local IP.
It should begin with 1 9 2 dot 1 6 8 and then two other sets of numbers and they're all separated by
periods.
So remember that number take note of that number.
OK.
If you're on Windows to find your local IP address go to the command line and run the following command
IP config.
Press enter the command line will output a bunch of text you're looking for the one that's called IP
V for address to the right of that you'll see an IP and again it should begin with 1 9 2 1 6 8 and then
a number separated by a period and another number.
Okay at this point whether you're using Windows or Mac you should have your computer's local IP address
so on your smartphone type that IP address number that we just found into the address bar and at the
end of it add in Colon three thousand right because that's the port number that our dev server is running
on call once you type in that address and push enter.
You can now view your website on your smartphone on your tablet on another computer whatever you wish.
Not only is this great for seeing what things will look like on a small screen but it can also boost
your productivity.
For example if you have a tablet you can now basically use it as a second screen right like a second
monitor during your development workflow so you can set your text editor to take up the full screen
on your main computer and then you could position your tablet to the side of your screen and have the
tablet with your website pulled up and it will show you the changes in real time right.
So as soon as you save a CSF change just a few milliseconds later you will see the website update without
a reload on the tablet or smartphone.
OK so we've completed the third and final task for this lesson.
But before we bring things to an end there is one thing I want to point out.
So do this with me within your text editor or I should say within our project folder.
Remember that web Park is creating this bundled dot J.S. file that lives within our app folder.
Well check this out.
Do this with me right now.
I want you to delete this file.
So right click on bundled J.S. and choose Delete
now you might think that if we go to the web browser and refresh it wouldn't be able to load that code
but you'll see that everything is still OK and even if we make a change to one of our CSF files right.
So even if I go in and change the font size to something crazy and save it successfully bundles and
injects into the browser and you'll notice in our folder structure that it did not regenerate a new
file named bundled Dot.
J Yes this is because web pack dev server does not actually output the bundled file to our file disk.
The dev server actually just keeps the bundled file in RAM or in memory so it's super fast.
In other words the dev server makes the file available from our address.
So local host calling three thousand and then slash bundled dot J.S. so the file can be accessed from
this U.R.L. but it doesn't actually exist on our hard drive.
Anyways I just wanted to point that out to save you a bit of frustration if you're wondering what's
going on now.
Don't worry in the future when we're ready to actually push our files up onto the web so that other
people from the public can view our Web site.
We will set things up in a way where the bundled file actually is output to file disk.
But for now let's not worry about it because this is the optimal workflow while we're building and creating
a Web site really quick.
Let's just set our font size back down from nine point eight to four point eight and go ahead and save.
And that's going to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson we're going to start a new chapter
on responsive web design should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep things rolling.
I'll see you then.