Hello everyone.
In this video we will pick up right where we left off our goal in this video is to write JavaScript
to make this modal come to life.
Let's begin by thinking about the HD PML that powers this.
So back in our text editor if you open up your index start each demo and take a look at the modal HD
PML.
It's just my own personal preference but I actually want to move this HD PML that powers the model to
live inside javascript because if we think about it the modal is going to be hidden when you first come
to the page.
And the only way to see it is if you use javascript to make it appear.
So if for whatever reason javascript is disabled on a user's device there's no point in even sending
them this HDMI all at all.
So to get started let's do this towards the bottom of your HD CML file.
I want you to select the entire overall modal div so it's an opening div with a class of modal and then
just select down until the closing div and let's cut all of this into our clipboard
okay.
You can save your HDMI file.
And now let's go create a new JavaScript file for our modal.
So within app assets scripts let's right click on modules and create a new file let's name it uppercase
modal dot J.S. let's create a class named modal and then outside of that class at the very bottom let's
say export default modal and before we forget.
Let's save this file and go import it within our main JavaScript file.
So within scripts go into your main app.
Got J.S. towards the top here that's imported in so import modal from quotes dot forward slash modules
slash modal.
And then on a new line let's just create a new instance of the modal class.
Don't worry.
By the very end of this lesson I will explain when we do and when we don't need to save the new instance
of a class to a variable.
But for now before we get to that explanation we can just have a new instance of modal.
Let's save this.
Now at the moment in the browser the modal is not visible right because we removed it from our H PML
file.
However with it's still in our clipboard let's jump back into our modal dot J.S. and let's do this within
our class.
Let's set up a constructor and blow the constructor but still within our class let's create a method
named inject h t Gemmell inject HDMI all parentheses curly brackets.
OK.
And then within our constructor let's be sure to call this method right away as soon as an object is
created.
So within the constructor just this dot inject H T.A. In parentheses to execute it.
Now within this actual method let's just add a bit of H PML towards the bottom of the document.
So to do that we can say document and then we can begin working with the bodies or document dump body
dot insert adjacent H CML.
This is a method the browser makes available to us.
We give it to arguments.
The first argument is where in relation to this element do you want to insert your new H TMM let's say
quotes before.
And so all the letters here are lowercase even the E and end after these quotes we have a comma.
Now the second argument is the H T AML that you want to add or insert.
Now we could use quotes however instead of quotes here.
Let's use to back ticks.
So again this is the character to the left of the one key or right above your tab key.
The cool thing about back ticks is that it creates a template literal and the cool thing about a template
literal is that we can drop down in between the two back ticks whereas you cannot drop down in between
two quotes that will break javascript but with tactics we can do this just to stay organized and as
you might have guessed this is where you can paste back in your clipboard to just paste OK.
And if we go ahead and save this file over in the browser we see our model again.
Great except we don't want the model to be visible when you first come to the page.
So let's write a bit of CSX so that the modal is hidden by default.
So in our Ed go into app assets styles modules and open up the modal dot CSX file within the baseline
rule up at the top here.
Let's add a few new properties.
So by default let's set the opacity to 0.
Let's also set visibility to hidden.
Let's also set its scale to be a bit larger than its natural size.
So this way when we reveal it it looks like it's sort of doing a zoom out or zoom in scale effect.
So it's say transform and usually scale function and let's put it to one point two.
So it's 20 percent larger than its normal size semicolon.
And then let's tell the browser to gradually transition these values.
So it looks like it's animating in once we actually reveal it.
So transition.
So I want to transition all properties over the course of point three seconds and I will use ease out.
OK.
Now while we're in this file let's go ahead and create the CSX modifier class that would make the modal
visible.
So still within the baseline rule.
But maybe right below this flex property that's dropdown and say Ampersand dash dash.
And let's make up a modifier name of is visible within this rule.
Let's just say opacity should be one fully visible.
Let's set visibility to visible and let's set it scale or size back to normal.
So transform used the scale function and give it a value of 1.
Be sure to end that with a semicolon.
OK.
Let's go ahead and save this cool.
So it's hidden by default.
Now we just need to write a bit of JavaScript so that when you click this button or this button the
modal gets that is visible modifier class.
So let's jump back into our JavaScript file modal dot J.S. and right below the constructor let's create
an events method.
So events parentheses curly brackets within the constructor let's be sure to call it this dot events
and the ordering of these lines matters in the sense that we need to inject the H2 PML before any of
our other javascript can interact with that HDMI out.
Okay.
Now within our events method we would want to listen for two things.
So we can even write comments to ourselves so first we would want to listen for the open modal button
being clicked on so we could say slash slash listen for open click and then we could write another comment
because we also want to listen for the closing click right.
When you click the top right exe to close the modal so listen for close click and while we're at it
let's listen for a third event and that is if the user presses the escape key that should close the
modal.
For now let's just write a comment that says pushes any key okay.
At this point let's work on the opening the modal feature so let's begin by selecting the open button
that you would click on From the DOM to up in the constructor we can create a property let's name it
this dot let's call it open modal button and let's set it to equal.
Document dot query selector all all is important here because there are multiple buttons you could click
on and let's give it quotes dot open dash modal now at the moment I don't believe there are any elements
in our HD PML file with this class so let's fix that right now.
So in your HDL file up at the very top.
For me it's around line number 23.
Here is that top right.
Get in touch button.
So in addition to just the class of B10 let's also give it a second class of open modal okay.
And then let's also find this orange button and give it a class of open modal.
So for me that's around line number 50.
Here it is button.
Button orange button large.
So I'll just give it another class of open modal.
And then finally remember we have a button in our footer that also says get in touch.
So down at the very bottom of our HDMI well.
For me it's around line 166 at the end of this line instead of just button button orange.
Let's also add open modal.
Let's go ahead and save that.
Okay now back in our javascript.
Now we have this collection of all of the buttons that can get clicked on to open the modal so down
in our events.
We can say begin working with that collection.
This doc open modal button.
Actually why don't we make this name plural so adding S buttons and then down your open model buttons
dot and we want to do something once for each item in the collection.
So for each let's give it an arrow function with exactly one parameter some element and then the arrow
symbol and then what we want to do is just add an event listener to that element.
So l dot add event listener the type of event we're listening for is a click event after the quotes
comma.
This is what we want to do in response to a click.
Let's give it an arrow function with exactly one parameter.
This time the parameters E.
I just made up this name it's short for event.
You'll see how we're going to use that in just a minute but e.
Arrow symbol.
And then we haven't created this method yet but we will in just a moment.
So let's call a method named open the modal.
So this dot open the modal in parentheses to call it.
Now in these parentheses when we're calling it let's pass it e for event.
Okay now let's go create a method with this matching name.
So right below our events method and right above this inject H TMM method we can say open the modal
parentheses curly brackets within these parentheses let's receive that incoming parameter of E and then
in the body of this method what we want to do is prevent the default behavior.
So these buttons are a elements right links and they have h ref values.
So currently if we clicked on one of these you'll see the hash tag appears at the end of the address
bar and in a draft value of hash tag we'll also scroll you up to the very top of the page.
So if I click the link in the footer notice it scrolls to the top.
So that's not what we want.
So we're going to prevent that default behavior.
So within our open the modal we can just say e that is the current event that just happened the Click
event and we want to say dot prevent default.
We want to call that prevent default method.
OK.
Once that's been taken care of.
Now we just want to actually open the modal.
So we want to give that overall modal div the class that makes it visible.
So within our constructor let's select the overall modal div so we can save it into property.
This modal equals document query selector just dot modal is the selector.
Okay then in our open the modal method we can just say this dot modal dot class list dot ad and remember
our CSF modifier class.
That makes it appear is modal Dash Dash is visible let's go ahead and save this and test it out.
It's back in the browser.
I will refresh just to make sure that any experimental event listeners are gone and if I click the button
perfect next let's set things up so that you can click on the exe icon to close the modal.
So first up in the constructor let's create a property that points towards that close icon.
So we can say this dot closed icon equals document query selector and it has a class of modal underscore
underscore close.
OK.
Now in the events area we already have this comment.
Listen for close click.
We can just say this dot closed icon.
We want to add event listeners or dot add event listener.
We're listening for a click event comma.
And let's just give it an arrow function so parentheses arrow symbol.
And then we haven't created the method yet but let's imagine it's called close the modal.
So this dot close the modal parentheses to call it.
And our HDL is set up so that this is not an A element or a link with an H ref.
So we don't need to worry about preventing the default behavior.
So we can just go create a method with this name closed the modal right here close the modal parentheses
curly brackets and we can actually just copy and paste this line to save a bit of typing.
Only now instead of adding this CSX class we would want to remove it.
So let's copy this paste it into closed the model and just change add to remove let's save and test
it out.
I will refresh though just so our add event listeners aren't doubling up and having multiple handlers
so I can open the model if I click this cool I can close the modal mean try the button in the footer
perfect.
Finally let's set things up so that if the motel is open you can close it by pressing the escape key
on your keyboard instead of only being able to click the close icon.
So back in our code within our events method we already have this comment pushes any key.
So in this event listener we're not going to listen for the escape key because that's not the way the
browser works.
First you just need to listen for any key up or key down event.
So I would say document right.
So the overall page and then add event listener the type of event we are listening for is a key up event.
So once someone presses a key and then releases it up what do we want to do in response.
Well let's provide it.
An arrow function with exactly one parameter the parameter will be e short for event.
This will contain information about the event that just occurred in this case it contains which key
was pressed.
So in just a moment we're going to want to check this to see if it was the escape key that was pressed
but let's include the arrow symbol and then let's call a method that doesn't exist yet but one that
we can create in just a moment.
So I would say this dot key press handler parentheses to call it.
And when we call it be sure to give it that E.
OK.
Now let's create a method with this matching name so key press handler within these parentheses.
Be sure to receive that incoming argument and then we can just write an if statement.
So only if the key that was pressed was the escape key only in that situation would we want to close
the modal if any other key was pressed.
We can just ignore it.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition if e dot key code double equal sign to check for
equality.
If that equals twenty seven so every key on the keyboard has a numeric value associated with it.
And I just know from memory that the escape keys key code is twenty seven.
So only if that's the case then in the if block just closed the modal.
So this dot close the modal parentheses to call it.
Let's go ahead and save this.
Back in the browser I will refresh.
So I have fresh event listeners and if I open up the model and then press escape on my keyboard.
Perfect.
At this point the user experience of our modal feature is complete.
However if we think about it when the user first comes to the page there's a decent chance they might
never open the modal.
So with that in mind does it really make sense to force the visitor to download all of the modal javascript
if they're never even going to click on the button to see the modal.
I think it would be better for performance if the modal javascript lived in a separate file that's not
part of our overall bundle and then only if someone clicks on a button to open the modal well then it
will just take a few milliseconds to load that JavaScript in and then we can open the modal.
Well what I just described splitting code out like that that is made possible by Web pack.
In my opinion it's actually one of the coolest and most powerful features that web park offers to us
and it's relatively simple to set up considering the huge performance benefits it can offer us.
I'm very excited to set this up with you and it's exactly what we're going to work on in the next lesson.
So let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.