Hello everyone and this video will talk about the next steps you can take.
This video has two main components to it.
First we'll talk about what you can learn next.
So we've finished learning new skills in this course.
And now you might be wondering what's the next logical step.
What should I learn now.
So we'll cover that.
And then secondly we'll also talk about career progression.
So let's say you get a job that's fantastic.
It's definitely something that's worth going out and buying a cake to celebrate.
But you don't want to stay at that exact job or position for the rest of your life.
You want to be able to grow and continually see progress.
So we'll talk about a few things that can help you in that area.
But first let's talk about what you can learn next.
I want to start out by saying that with everything you've learned in this course I think you'd be valuable
to just about any dev team out there right now with what you currently know.
But the developer spirit is to never stop learning to always be moving forward.
So with that in mind here are my recommendations on what to learn next.
Really it's as simple as JavaScript javascript and more Javascript.
It's still a plus to know server side languages like HP or Ruby but honestly at this point in time I'd
say there are more companies that will value javascript.
This is because javascript is now completely ubiquitous.
It's on the front end it's on the back end.
It's in simple brochure type websites.
It's in complex web apps it's in device native apps it's everywhere.
So a developer who knows javascript is incredibly in demand right now.
Now we definitely learned about javascript in this course but I would still jump at any opportunity
to learn more about javascript.
Keep practicing keep building new things with it.
I'll include a few links in this video description where you can read more about javascript news and
resources and best practices because really anything you do to advance your understanding of javascript
is going to propel your career forward tenfold.
Now my advice is always to learn what interests you the most your natural curiosity is the best motivator
and teacher.
So I'd say whatever interests you the most just pursue that from a javascript angle.
So if you say that design or front end or user experience interests you the most.
Try to learn a single page application library like react react to super popular right now and learning
it will open all sorts of doors for you.
You can find introduction to react to Tauriel is on YouTube and across Google and if it looks like something
that interests you at all.
I wholeheartedly recommend you sink your teeth into it.
Re-act is a great tool to know right now.
It's very in demand.
Or if you say that back and interests you the most.
So dealing with data and actually making things happen.
Try learning more about no.
J.S..
So remember way back in the course when we wrote no js code to programmatically go out onto the Internet
and save the photo of a dog to our hard drive.
You can do stuff like that only ten thousand times more advanced.
You can learn how to use node to serve up an API or even an entire website.
You can learn how to talk directly to a database with node and if you use a database system like Mongo
D-B your actual requests for the database themselves can be written in Javascript.
So long story short you can do anything with Knode and no developers are incredibly in demand right
now.
So again if data and back end tasks are what excite you.
I recommend staying in the know J.S. ecosystem instead of sinking your teeth into something like BHP
or Ruby.
All right so those are my recommendations on what to learn next.
At this point let's change gears and now let's talk about career progression.
The first topic I want to cover is how important it is to know yourself.
So we all have our own unique blend of strengths and weaknesses.
And if you want your career to grow you need to align your decisions to leverage your strengths.
Here are a few examples of what I'm talking about.
So some people are super intelligent programming just comes a little bit easier to these people than
it does for others.
Their minds seem to learn a little bit quicker than others and they can train themselves to see the
most elegant solution with code.
Their minds are just built that way.
But that same person might not be a very good leader.
They might lack charisma they might lack the ability to bring out the best in others.
They might not be very good at seeing the bigger picture.
Maybe they tend to focus on smaller technical details.
So for this person maybe their career progression doesn't involve staying with a mid-level company for
a long time and moving up to a management or executive position.
Considering this person's strengths and weaknesses maybe their best career move would be to try to become
the absolute best developer or programmer they can be and to keep getting developer jobs at bigger and
better companies.
But let's take a look at a different person.
So some people are good programmers but they're not great or amazing but maybe they do possess leadership
qualities.
Maybe they are good at keeping a level head no matter what.
Maybe they have the ability to inspire people and they can get a group of people working together in
harmony to complete a huge project.
Maybe they can see the bigger picture for a project and know when to make a judgment call.
So for this person considering their strengths and weaknesses maybe their best bet is to get their foot
in the door at a company as a developer and then stay with that company and work their way up to a management
or executive position.
Now those are just two examples.
There are billions of people on the planet.
So there are billions of different types of people but the general idea is that we are all good at different
things.
We all have unique gifts.
And the trick is to aim your career so that you're in a position where you get to use your gifts on
a daily basis because if you try to progress in a career path that uses your strengths you will still
be met with many challenges but because you are aligned with your natural gifts you will remain energized.
When we do something we're good at it makes us feel good.
We feel like we are useful and like we're helping others.
So the analogy here is when your career is aligned with your gifts it's like running on a flat surface.
Running is still difficult and taxing but it's doable and it's rewarding.
On the other hand if you try to progress in a career path that ignores your strengths and overing gauges
your weaknesses you will become burnt out and probably end up stagnating when your career isn't aligned
with your gifts.
The person in the mirror knows that it's a waste of your gifts.
You're going to feel like you're not giving all that you can give and that's going to take its toll
on you.
So the analogy here is when your career isn't aligned with your natural strengths.
It's like running uphill nonstop for 50 years.
It's not sustainable.
So long story short get to know yourself.
Let's move on to my final tip and this is a tip that will help you progress in your career.
Whether that's through promotions at a job or seeing growth in a business you on that tip is to follow
these two rules.
Limit your complaining and try not to dodge responsibility.
Now I think you'd be surprised even if you aren't the best developer in the world.
Just following these two rules will make people want to promote you or it will make people want to work
with you.
Now I know these things sound cliche and are easier said than done.
And unfortunately this isn't a personal development course it's a web development course so I can't
give you effective ways to actually follow these rules but I can tell you that these things are super
important to career progression and that it's definitely worth your time to google how to improve in
these areas.
All right that brings this video to an end.
And actually that brings this course to an end.
Thank you so much for coming on this journey with me.
I hope you feel like you learned something.
And don't be a stranger.
Reach out to me in the course discussion area let me know how things are going.
Anyways here's my final message for the course.
Don't put your dreams or goals on hold while you quote learn even more.
There's always going to be something else to learn.
And being a developer means learning on the fly as you go and not waiting for that perfect moment.
When you quote know enough and only then jumping in.
You already know what time you already have the skill set and knowledge to go out and make crazy things
happen.
I guarantee you are underestimating your skills talents and knowledge.
So do not wait.
Make something happen now.
You are enough right now today.
So until the next time we meet in a course I wish you the very best of luck and take care.