Hello everyone.
In this video we're going to pick up right where we left off.
So we're creating a copy of our Web site that we're going to send to a web host for the public to download
and view so far within this automatically generated disk folder.
We've set up our build task to output our bundled code in a few minutes from now we will set things
up to extract our CSX from this big bundled file into its own separate traditional CSX file.
However before we get to that I first want to enable a feature in web back only for our build task that
will help our visitors download less data in the long run.
Let me show you what I mean.
So right now do this with me within our web pack config file.
Let's find the if statement for our build task right.
So if current task equals build maybe right after this config mode equals production we can just drop
down and let's say config dot optimization.
So this should equal an object within this object let's say split chunks.
Colon and that should be set to an object itself.
And let's just give it one property named chunks.
Colon and then give it a value of quotes all.
So all in all I just added these three highlighted lines of code.
If you need to pause the video to type this in.
That's OK.
But once we're ready let's go ahead and save this and let's run our NPM run build task again.
So in the command line let's test out our build process so NPM run build.
Let's see what's different this time around.
So if we go back into our disk folder instead of only two files we now have three.
So this is our main overall bundle.
This is the modal javascript module that should be loaded on the fly.
And this brand new file.
This is our vendor code.
In this case vendor just means code that we didn't write.
So for example the load Ash throttle and d bounce functions and also the lazy sizes javascript.
Why would we want these in a separate file.
Well imagine the scenario where the code that we write ourselves write our sticky header our Reveal
on scroll.
Imagine that that code is going to change very frequently so the visitors of our Web site would need
to be continually downloading a new copy of this file.
However if the load ash does bounce and throttle and if the lazy sizes packages if that code that we
didn't write doesn't get updated very often there's no sense in forcing our visitors to re download
that every time we want them to read download the code that we write in the long run.
This can save our visitors from downloading quite a bit of unnecessary data.
OK.
Now with this in mind we need to think about the way that web browsers handle caching of files.
So imagine we make a change to our Reveal on scrawl J.S. file and then we need to create a new bundle.
Well we'd probably want that new bundle there generated file to in some way have a slightly different
file name.
So the web browser would know that it's different that it's changed and that it should read download
the file from the server instead of using its own local cached copy.
So let me show you what we can do.
Back in our web packet config within the if statement for our build the task I want you to find the
config dot output area.
So instead of the file name just being bundled dot J.
Yes.
Well let's hollow out these quotes and instead type this in with me square brackets inside the square
brackets type name and then dot after the square brackets new set of square brackets and inside these
say chunk hash and then after the square brackets say dot J Yes.
OK.
Now at the very end of this line Let's go ahead and create a new line and let's say chunk file name
colon quotes and at the end of the quotes at the very end of this line while we're at it.
Be sure to include a comma.
OK.
Now within these quotes we can just use the exact same value that we used on this line.
So you can just copy within these quotes and then paste that within these quotes.
OK.
Let's go ahead and save this.
But before we run our build task in the command line I want you to go into your dist folder and go ahead
and manually delete these three files just moving to the trash OK.
Now back in our command line let's test things out.
Let's run our build process so NPM run build
OK.
And then let's go check out our disk folder.
Perfect.
So we see two new changes instead of every file having just the basic name of bundled bundled one bundled
two.
Now we actually see their names right.
Main modal the vendor's file for the main file.
And then after that name we also see a string of characters that is the chunk hash.
What in the world is a chunk cache.
Well if we ran NPM run build once again these seemingly randomly generated strings of characters would
stay exactly the same because none of our actual files changed.
However do this with me if we go into our main app dot J.S. and just write an alert that says testing
and we save that and we run NPM run build once again
well.
Notice now that I have a new copy of that main bundled file with a different chunk cash right.
So its main dot and then the chunk cash string.
So this is a new one.
However nothing in these two files actually changed.
So they have the identical or same chunk hash.
This is great.
This allows us to perform cash busting for the web browser visitors web browsers will see that the file
has a new name and know that hey.
Something must have changed in that file.
I need to download the newest version of the file.
However we obviously don't want to have two copies of the same file.
So right now let's set things up so that every time we run our build process it begins by completely
deleting this folder so that then only the most recent latest copies of each file exist.
I would have thought that this is a feature that web pack includes by default.
But as of today we actually need to go download a plug in to do this with me in your command line run
the following command npm install in the name of the package is clean dash web pack dash plug in and
be sure to include dash dash save Dev
OK within our Web pack config file let's leverage that new plug in up at the very top.
I will say contest let's say curly brackets clean web pack plug in let's set that to equal.
And then just require it and so require in the exact name of the package was lowercase clean dash web
pack dash plug in.
OK.
Now we can go leverage this within our build process.
So let's find the if statement.
So if current task equals build and then maybe below this configure optimization we can just say config
dot plugins equals.
And this should be an array so you can have multiple plugins if you'd like to.
For now we can just have one item in this array so we would just create a new instance of.
And then the name we gave it is clean web path plug in and instead of parentheses.
OK.
Let's give this a save and then to really test it out.
Let's make another random change in our main JavaScript file so that it will have a new chunk cache.
So you could just add a few random strings in this alert message just so it's different.
Save that.
And now let's run a fresh build process.
So in the command line NPM run build
cool so on my screen we saw there was an old copy of Maine and then it got deleted.
Actually all the files were deleted but these two were instantly replaced.
They still have the exact same chunk hash because they didn't actually change.
And here we see the brand new latest copy of our main bundle with a new chunk cash value at this point
let's change gears a bit and let's work on extracting the CSX out of this main bundle.
And have it instead live in its own separate traditional CSX file.
That way if we make a change to our CSX it doesn't force our visitors to have to download the entire
bundle again.
They could just re download the CSX file so let's go download the industry standard package to make
that possible jump back into your command line and run this with me.
Let's say npm install the package name is mini dash C S S dash extract dash plugin.
Let's be sure to include dash dash saved EV and this package is great.
Just in the last week alone it's been downloaded over 5 million times.
So go ahead and press enter OK and then back in our web pack config file up at the very top.
Let's import in that new package so contest mini C Ss extract plug in should equal.
And then just require it in or require mini dash SSD dash track dash plug in.
Okay.
Now we actually need to leverage this plug in in two different locations in this config file.
So first within our generic or shared configuration within the module property we see rules and then
we have a rule that only applies to C Ss files and it's using the style loader and the CSX loader in
the post CSX loader.
Well we want to use a loader that that new extract plug in offers to us.
However we only want to use it for our build task not for our dev task.
Also we only want to use this style loader for dev but not for build so to handle the different situations
here's what I would do.
We can see that rules is an array right.
The square brackets now.
Right now there's only one rule the rule for our CSX files but what we can do is make this a variable
and then modify it in the if statements for Dev and build accordingly.
So here's what I would do within this array.
The square bracket.
Select the one rule that we have.
So from Curly bracket to curly bracket like this and cut this into your clipboard in its place.
Say C Ss config.
Okay now we just need to create a variable with this matching name so maybe right above config we can
say left CSX config equal and then paste in our clipboard.
OK now in the code that we just pasted in.
Be sure to delete style loader like this.
OK now we can just modify this within the dev if statement to add style loader back in and also modify
it within the build if statement to add in the C Ss extract plug we just download it.
So first let's go into our if statement for the dev task and maybe write inside the curly brackets for
that if statement we can just say C Ss config dot use.
Remember that is an array so we can say dot on shift to add an item to the beginning of the array.
So for the dev task we can just say quotes style dash loader OK and then let's scroll down to the if
statement for our build task.
If current task equals build right inside there we can just say C S S config doc.
Use dot on shift and in this case we want to use the loader that came with that package we just downloaded
from NPM so many CSX extract plug in dot loader.
Okay that takes care of the loader situation.
Now we just need to actually add this as a plug in.
Luckily for us down here we already have config dot plug ins equals.
So right now we just have one item in this array of plugins but right after we call the clean web back
right here we can say comma.
And then just create a new instance of mini CSX extract plug in parentheses at the end.
Now inside these parentheses we want to give it an object so curly brackets and we just need to give
it one option and that is file name so file name colon because I want to have fine grained control over
the name of the CSX file that gets generated.
So let's say quotes.
So inside these quotes let's say styles dot and then square brackets inside the square brackets let's
say chunk hash after the square brackets a dot CSX.
OK let's go ahead and save this and test out our new build process so in the command line just run NPM
run build
OK.
Let's go check our dist folder.
Perfect.
Here we see a separate traditional CSX SS file now by default it will not be compressed or mystified.
So if I check the file size currently it's about 21 kilobytes.
Let me show you how we can set things up so this file is modified or compressed back in our command
line.
I want you to install one more post CSF plug in with me to run this command npm install C S S nano.
Be sure to include dash dash save Dev OK.
Now we only want to run this nano package that will compress our C Ss within our bill the task not our
dev task.
So within if current task equals build maybe right below that C Ss config line we just wrote We can
just say post CSX plug ins.
Remember at the very top of this file we have a collection of plug ins with this name so we can just
say dot push to add an item onto the end of this array of post plug ins and within these parentheses
what we want to add is that CSX nano package so we can just say require quotes C S S nano.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And now let's run our build process again and see how many kilobytes we saved on that CSX file.
So NPM run build and if I inspect the newest CSX file.
Cool.
Now it's only 13 kilobytes now.
Sure if you open up this generated file in a text editor there is zero white spacing.
And this is impossible for humans to read but that doesn't matter.
This is not our source code.
This is just for the web browser to download and apply cool.
That's going to bring this video but not this lesson to a close in the next video.
We will set things up so that our disk folder also copies over our h t AML files as well as our images
or photographs.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.