Hello everyone.
In this lesson we will begin styling one of the most important areas of our site the header.
So in this lesson we will be transforming this very top section of content into what we see in the design
file which is this.
Now before we begin working on setting up the logo or the transparent blue bar or the navigation why
don't we first make sure that we are working within a new get branch dedicated to this header effort.
So over in the command line we can't create a brand new branch and switch to it in one move by typing
get check out dash B and let's name this new branch simply header.
All right and if you haven't already make sure that NPM run dev is running in one of your command lines.
OK.
At this point we have a new get branch and our Web packed dev server is up and running.
Let's go ahead and begin styling this content.
So let's jump into our text editor and within our each team e-mail file.
Let's look for the header content.
So right underneath the opening body tag.
Here we see the header.
Let's go ahead and give this header element a class so we can target it with our CSX.
Let's give it a class name of site dash header.
All right let's save this file.
And now let's create a brand new CSX file dedicated to this new class name.
So within our app assets styles modules folder let's create a new file let's name it underscore site
dash header dot CSX let's create these selector for that class so dot site header let's save this file
and before we forget let's go into our main style sheet and import in the new file.
So import modules underscore site header let's save this and then jump back to our brand new site header
file.
All right.
And what's the first bit of CSX that we should write.
Well if we look at the design file the first thing that I notice is that the header content is overlapping
or is overlaid on top of the large hero section.
And currently in the browser our header section is occupying its own space.
And then the large hero section begins.
So it's almost as if we need to take the header out of the normal flow of the page so that the large
hero section can slide up underneath it.
We can do that by telling the site header to be positioned absolutely so position absolute.
So let's save this and check the browser.
All right.
So it appears that our header has disappeared but really it's layered underneath the large hero section.
This is because by default when two HDMI elements are positioned in a way where they will overlap the
element that comes later in the HMO will sit on top.
It will be the top layer.
However we can customize which piece of content will sit on top by using z index.
So on site header we can simply say z index to the large hero block that is currently overlapping our
site header doesn't have a z index value at all.
And whichever element has a higher z index value will be placed on top.
So if we save this we see that our z index value brought the site header to the front.
I think the next thing we should work on is the transparent blue background that we see in the design
file.
So over in our CSX let's give our site header a background color because we want the color to be transparent.
We will use RGA.
Now I know that the red green blue values for our main blue variable are actually 47 85 114.
And in terms of Alpha transparency let's set this to be only 30 percent visible.
So let's check this out in the browser we see that the transparent blue is being applied successfully
but really quickly I want to address a question you might have.
You might be wondering how you were supposed to figure out the red green and blue values of a color.
So for example in our styles base folder within variables that CSX we know that our main blue color
has a hexadecimal color code of this value.
But how do we find the RG B equivalent of this color.
Well you could paste this value into an app like photoshop or illustrator or sketch but what if you
don't have access to an app like that.
Well let me show you another way.
So back in our site headed up CSX.
Wouldn't it be nice if instead of listing the RG B values we could simply include a hexadecimal color
code here so we could say main blue and make it only 30 percent visible.
Now this is not valid.
CSX the web browser would have no idea how to interpret this but post CSX can save the day.
We can install a post CSX plug in that will automatically convert hexadecimal color codes inside an
RGA parentheses into the corresponding red green and blue values.
So then we can write code like this.
So in order to download and install a new post CSX plug in let's jump to the command line in this one
where we're running our web pack task.
You can just press control see.
All right.
And what we want to do is install a package from NPM.
So npm install packages post CSX dash hacks r g b a.
And then at the end be sure to include dash dash save dash death.
All right.
Now that we have that package let's go leverage it.
So to do that jump into your web pack dot config dot J.S. file towards the top.
We have this array named post CSX plug ins maybe right before the final auto prefix or lines right above
that line with a new one and say require parentheses quotes and its name was post CSX dash hacks.
RG B.A..
Be sure to include a comma at the very end of that new line.
All right let's go ahead and save this file and then back in the command line.
Let's tell Webb pack to begin running again.
So NPM run Dev.
All right.
That will allow us to preview the site in the web browser once again.
And now if we jump back to our site header dot CSX file.
Let's take this code syntax for a spin.
So let's just test it out and say that it should be 95 percent visible.
Looks like it's working.
So we can try 50 percent and we can put it back to 30 percent.
So I know that was a bit of a tangent about RGA and hex colors but hopefully you find this syntax useful
and you can even use it in future projects.
All right.
So back to the task at hand.
The next thing that we should probably work on is making our site header.
Use the full available width.
Currently we see that it's only using this much horizontal space.
And this is because when an element is positioned absolutely by default it will try to shrink wrap and
only use as much space as it needs to fit its content.
We can adjust this in our CSX by simply telling this element to have a width of 100 percent.
All right.
Next why don't we adjust things so that this content doesn't sit up against the very far left edge.
Why don't we go ahead and leverage our wrapper class so that way our header will use the same universal
margin we've been using throughout the design.
So over in our H2 CML we want to wrap all of this content within a new div.
So let's cut this to our clipboard and create a div that has a class of wrapper and then we can simply
paste the content back in all right.
If we check out the design file again the next thing that I notice is that the get in touch button should
be positioned against the right edge of the header and currently in the browser it is positioned here.
So let's do this.
Let's jump over to our h t demo.
Here is the get in touch button.
Let's actually wrap it in its own div.
Let's give that div a class of site header underscore underscore button container.
Let's close out that div.
Let's indent the button.
Let's save this.
And then over in our site header CSX file.
Let's create a new rule that targets that element.
So button container and let's simply float it to the right.
All right.
So we see that that change is in place next.
Let's go ahead and position these navigation links so that they sit here.
Let's jump into our HMO here is the NAV element for those navigation links.
Let's give this element a class so we can target it with our CSX.
Now we could consider this nav an element that belongs to the site header block.
But remember that in Bem it's OK to nest one block inside another block.
And if we look at the design file to me this link styling feels very generic.
It feels like a design pattern that might be used in the future on another page.
Right.
Because having links in an unordered list and wanting them to be displayed horizontally like this is
a pretty common occurrence in web design.
So I'm going to consider that it's own block and let's name it.
Primary nav let's save this file and next let's create a brand new CSX file dedicated to this class.
So within our styles modules folder let's create a new file.
Let's name it underscore.
Primary nav dot CSX let's create the selector for that class of DOT primary nav.
Let's save that.
And before we forget let's jump into our main styles dot CSX file and import that new file.
So modules underscore.
Primary nav.
And let's jump back to the new primary now file.
So what's the first bit of CSX that we want to write.
Well if we check out the browser we want to go ahead and float this content to the right so that it's
positioned here.
However because we are trying to create a reusable block for this navigation I don't want the baseline
styling to be floated to the right.
So I'm actually going to give that element in our HDD CML a modified class of primary nav dash dash
pull.
Right.
Let's save that.
And now back in primary nav CSX let's create a modifier rule so dash dash pull.
Right.
And we can simply tell it to float to the right next.
Why don't we adjust the default margin and padding and bulleted list styling of these elements.
So if we check our HMO we want to remove the default padding and margin on this unordered list and then
we want to tell the list items to no longer have a bullet.
Now if I was going to follow the Bem philosophy 100 percent I would give a class to this element named
primary nav underscore underscore list and I would give each list item element a class of primary nav
underscore underscore item and I would even give each link a class like primary nav underscore underscore
the link.
However this is one area where I actually disagree with the best methodology.
Our primary nav block has a very specific purpose to styled lists of navigation links so I can't imagine
a situation where we don't use this exact H TMM pattern or in other words I fail to see how using generic
type selectors and descendants selectors in this situation would have any undesired side effects.
So I'm just going to jump to our primary nav file and I'm going to say that any unordered lists that
live within the primary nav should have zero margin and zero padding.
And then I'm going to say that any list items within primary nav should have list style none to remove
the bullets.
And I also want them to be floated to the left so that they will all sit on one line.
And because I floated all of them I want the parent element the unordered list to use our clear fix.
So I can say mix in clear fix.
Let's check this out in the browser.
Let's go ahead and add horizontal spacing in between each of these links.
So within our CSX for each list item I'm just going to say padding right 20 pixels.
That looks better.
Let's go ahead and make these links white instead of orange.
And let's also remove their underline so we can create a new rule that targets any links within primary
nav color should be white and we can say text decoration.
None.
Let's save this the font for these links actually looks a bit too bold to me.
So let's reduce that let's say font weight 300 that looks better.
We can fine tune the vertical positioning of these links in just a moment but for now I want to check
out the design file and I want to point out that the height of this transparent blue bar is determined
by the height of this content not of the logo but in the browser.
We see that because our logo is taller than any of this content.
The transparent blue bar is expanding vertically to fit the logo.
So I think what we need to do if we check out the design file again is remove the logo from the natural
flow of the page.
That way the containing element that gives us the transparent blue background won't even be aware that
the logo exists.
So in order to do that let's go ahead and target this logo area in our HDMI URL.
Here is the logo graphic.
Let's go ahead and wrap it in a new div and let's give that new div a class of site header underscore
underscore logo.
Let's close out that new div and indent the image.
Let's go ahead and save this and then jump into our site header CSX file.
Let's create a new rule that targets the logo.
And in order to take it out of the natural flow of the page like this let's just tell it to be positioned.
Absolutely perfect.
So now the height of the transparent blue bar is being determined by this content.
Let's finish styling the logo area.
So if we check out the design file we want to give that area a blue background.
This looks like our main blue color.
So back in our CSX within the logo rule let's say background color should use our main blue variable
all right so that gave us the background color but now we need to add a bit of padding around the logo
image.
So let's say padding if we check the design file.
This looks like about 25 pixels of vertical padding and about 36 pixels of horizontal padding.
So we can just say 25 pixels and 36 pixels looks good.
Next let's work on the vertical spacing above and below this content.
If we reference the design file above and below the get in touch button it looks like there is about
10 pixels of vertical spacing.
So in order to add that spacing in the browser let's simply give our main site header rule a bit of
vertical padding.
So 10 pixels.
And it doesn't need any horizontal padding.
So we can say zero.
All right.
So that gave us the vertical spacing we wanted in terms of this button but it also pushed our logo down
10 pixels.
Now we can fix the positioning of this logo by jumping into the logo rule and simply saying that its
top position should be zero.
Perfect.
The next thing that I notice is that we should adjust the vertical positioning of these links.
We want the links to appear as if they are vertically centered within the available transparent blue
height we can achieve that by simply giving the links a bit of vertical padding.
So within our CSX we are interested in the primary nav file and within the rule that targets links we
want to add a bit of vertical padding.
Let's say five pixels.
And we don't need any horizontal padding.
All right.
So that five pixels clearly wasn't enough.
Now in situations like this where it's difficult to guess and fine tune the padding value.
What I like to do is right click on one of these links and click inspect that will open your developer
tools.
And with that link selected in the right hand section of the screen we see all of the CSX being applied
to the element we can actually click on this padding declaration.
And if we place our text cursor on that five pixel value we can actually use the arrow keys on our keyboard
to increase or decrease that value.
And you can see that the links are being adjusted in real time so you can use this to find that perfect
sweet spot value.
So to me it looks like twelve is the perfect value so we can just go back into our text editor and adjust
that to twelve
perfect and that will actually bring part one of this lesson to a close at this point.
Our hairstyles look good on a large screen so you might have guessed that in part two of the lesson
we will test our header on a small screen and make any design adjustments that are necessary.
It should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep rolling along and I will see you in part to.