Hello everyone.
In this lesson we will continue to write highly organized CSX to be more specific.
We will complete the text styles for the large hero block and we will also begin and complete the button
styles that are used throughout the design.
This should be a lot of fun.
Let's get started.
All right to begin let's make sure that we have our index start.
Each TMI file open within a web browser.
To do that you just navigate to the project folder drill into the app folder and then drag index start
each Timo on top of the browser.
All right let's write some CSX.
Let's jump over to our text editor and let's open up the CSX file that's dedicated to the large hero
block.
So that file lives in the app folder and then the assets folder styles folder and then the modules folder.
There it is large hero.
So the first thing that I want to do is to eliminate this spacing or margin between the different text
elements.
So let's completely remove that margin.
So on this title element let's just say margin zero.
Let's copy and paste that to the subtitle element as well.
Go ahead and save this.
That looks better.
Let's compare what we have to the design file.
So I think the next thing we should work on is making this text white and using a larger font size than
what we currently have.
So let's go ahead and locate this element in our H2 UML file our index start HMO file lives in the root
of the app folder.
Let's find the large hero block.
Here it is.
So here is the element in question.
Let's go ahead and give it a bam class.
So this element belongs to the large hero block to indicate that this is an element of that block we
use to underscores.
And now we can come up with any name we want for this element.
Let's go with description.
Let's save this.
And jump over to our large hero dot CSX file and underneath the subtitle rule let's just create a brand
new rule.
Let's begin these selector with the ampersand because we are nested within the main large hero block
rule the ampersand will actually be converted to large hero.
So let's begin with Ampersand underscore underscore description and if you remember we want to make
the text white and use a larger font size.
So let's say color should be f f f for white and let's bump up the font size to maybe one point five
REM.
Let's see how that looks.
It doesn't look terrible but it doesn't look quite right either.
I think we need to fine tune the font size a bit which is the perfect segue way into talking about REM
in this course.
Whenever we declare a font size or a padding or margin value we want to do so in terms of RAM instead
of pixels or percentages or E M we want to use Ram.
So the question is what in the world is REM when we use Ram.
Everything is relative to the root of the page and the root of any web page is always the h t AML element.
So when we say one point five ram the browser will take whatever the font size of this main each TMM
element is and multiply it by one point five.
Most web browsers will have a default font size on the HDMI element of about the equivalent of 16 pixels.
So when we say one point five let's get out our calculators 16 pixels time's one point five.
In this specific instance this is really similar to saying font size of 24 pixels.
So if I save this and refresh watch the white text it doesn't change at all.
So you might be asking yourself why would we go through all that trouble of using REMS.
Why wouldn't we just say 24 pixels.
Well that's because not everyone in the world has their web browser configured exactly the same.
So for example on my computer and maybe on your computer this HDMI font size is set to 16 pixels but
for someone else who might be nearsighted or farsighted or maybe just wants to avoid eye strain their
web browser might be configured to use a font size of 20 or 25 or even 30 pixels.
And as a good web designer and developer we want to honor the users font size preferences and if we
use ram for font size and padding and margin our entire web design and all of the whitespace and balance
will scale accordingly to the user's font size preference.
Whereas if we used pixels for everything our design would kind of be set in stone.
And if a user had a larger default font size the text might feel too big for the layout surrounding
it but we won't need to worry about that because in this course we will use rim.
All right that's enough on RIM for now.
Next let's focus on fine tuning this font size.
So if we compare this to the design file it looks to me like we will need to increase this value of
one point five a bit.
So the question becomes how do we eliminate guesswork.
How can we find out the exact value that this should be.
Well normally we would just open this design file in a program like Photoshop or sketch or illustrator.
But to keep things moving right along I will just say that the designer told me this text should be
30 pixels.
So over in our text editor let's change this from one point five.
And what should we change it to.
Well let's get out our calculator.
So if we want a font size of 30 pixels and most browsers will use a default font size of 16 we just
divide 30 by 16.
And that gives us a value of one point eight seven five.
So let's use one point eight seven five REM save that.
That looks better next.
Let's go ahead and edit this text to use a really thin font weight.
Let's set the font way to 100.
All right let's compare this to the design file.
If we look really closely I see a super subtle shadow on this white text.
So let's try.
Text shadow square with a really small one.
Just a two pixel offset zero blur.
And what color should it be.
Let's use a black.
But a really transparent black.
So we only want the black to be 10 percent visible.
Let's save this.
See how it looks.
That looks good to me.
If we compare this with the design file I think our last bit of business with this white headline is
to make it drop to a second line after the word journeys.
There are probably 500 different ways to achieve that.
With each Allen CSX.
Let me show you the way that I would do that.
I would measure this and I would say that this has a width of about four hundred and eighty pixels as
we can see here.
So if we go into our CSX and give this element a max width of 480 pixels we see that that breaks the
text onto a second line just like we wanted it to.
And the text is still center aligned within that 480 pixel paragraph.
But now we also want that four hundred and eighty pixel paragraph to be aligned center within the entire
block.
So to do that we can use margin.
We can say margin left auto margin right.
Auto.
And there you have it now 480 pixels is the width that perfectly breaks this onto a second line.
But if a user has customized their browser to use a larger than default font setting 480 pixels won't
work.
So instead of using pixels here Let's convert this to REM.
So let's get out our calculator.
Let's take 480 and divide it by 16.
Gives us 30.
So let's replace this with 30 REM excellent for the time being.
Let's change gears let's transition from working on the large hero block to working on the button block.
So if we look at the design file we see that there is a button style that is being used here here and
in the very bottom in the footer being used here let's scroll back up to the top let's say that this
medium sized blue button is the default state for the button block.
So let's begin with it.
So that element back in browser lives right here let's find this in our HDMI out in the HDMI file only
a couple lines down from the opening body tag we see this link that reads get in touch.
Let's go ahead and give this element a class so we can target it with our C Ss let's give it a class
of B10 short for button let's save this file and then let's create a brand new C Ss file just for this
button block so within our app folder and then the assets folder and then within these styles folder
and within the modules folder let's create a new file.
Let's begin the button rule and let's save this file let's name this file underscore t n dot CSX.
If we look back at the design file the first thing we want to do is give the button a blue background
and make it use white text so let's say a background color.
Let's use a nice blue shade
color should be white.
Now if we save this file and refresh in the browser we won't see any change to this element and that
is because we need to include or import this button block file into our main style sheet.
So within app assets styles let's open up the main style sheet and let's add a new line where we import
in the new button file that we just created.
Save that refresh the browser there's a bit of progress and I'm thinking that this blue color that we
are using as the background for the button is the exact same blue color we are using for this text.
We don't want to have to keep remembering and typing out the hexadecimal code for that blue.
So instead let's create a variable for this blue color that we can reuse in all of our blocks.
So let's do this.
Let's copy the code for this blue color and up at the top.
We can create a variable named Main blue and it should equal that color code.
So now we can replace this with main blue except there's no sense in keeping this variable definition
in this button block file.
Instead let's create a brand new file in these styles base folder that has the single responsibility
of holding our variables.
So within that styles base folder let's create a new file let's name this new file underscore variables
dot CSX and let's just go ahead and cut this line where we defined the main blue variable and let's
paste it into the new variables dot CSX file.
Let's be sure to go into our main CSX file and import in that new variables file that we just created.
So import go into the base folder and then grab the variables file.
Excellent.
So if we save and refresh.
Nothing changes just like we were hoping.
Now really quickly let's go back into our large hero block and update the rules for these two headings
to use that blue variable back in the large hero block.
Here is the rule for the large title.
Let's change the color to main blue.
Let's change it for the subtitle element as well.
Perfect.
Let's get back to styling the button.
Let's go ahead and remove the text underline and also give the button a bit of spacing or padding.
So in the text editor within the button file let's say text declaration.
None that will remove the underline.
Let's give it a bit of padding.
Let's try one point two RAM and because we are giving it padding.
Let's also make sure that we set it to be an inline block level element.
That way it's parent and surrounding elements will be aware of its vertical padding.
So let's save this I'm not seeing the change when I refresh.
Let's check the command line.
So I will actually leave this mistake of mine in the lesson so you can learn from it.
I must have hit command s to save this button file before we had created and saved the new variables
file.
So the command line is complaining and saying that that variable is undefined.
It's unknown.
So now that we have the variable file in place and it definitely does exist we can just press control
C to stop the old web pack task and then run NPM run Dev once again and go back to the button or actually
any CSX file and save the file to trigger a rebuild or re bundle.
And now let's go back to the browser and there are changes so if we compare what we have to the design
file I think that our horizontal padding looks good.
But I think we have too much vertical padding.
So in our CSX we can use CSX shorthand.
So first we provide a vertical value.
So if one point to ram was too much let's try.
Point seven five RAM.
This will be used as the top and bottom padding.
And this will be used as the left and right padding that looks better.
So at this point I think our default state for the button block is good to go.
Let's work on some of the other instances of the button.
So if we scroll down to the very bottom of the design file we see that in the footer the button is orange
instead of blue.
Let's find that footer button in the web browser.
So if we scroll down there is the get in touch link.
Let's find that in our h t AML file.
Here we are.
Let's scroll down here is that link.
Let's give it a class of button so if we save this file and refresh it receives the button style.
Now we just want to make it orange instead of blue.
So back in the H T memo.
Let's leave that button class intact but let's give it a second class.
That begins with the button block and we want to use a bam modifier to indicate a modifier and bam we
use two dashes and then the name of the modifier.
So let's go with button dash dash orange let's jump over to our button CSX file and create that modifier
rule.
So we will nested within the main button block rule ampersand is dash dash orange background color.
Here is the orange color that we will use throughout the design.
But you know the drill.
We want to save this color as a variable.
So let me actually cut this and let's head over to our variables dot CSX file.
Let's create a brand new variable named Main orange.
And then let's paste in that color code.
OK let's save this file and then back in buttoned up CSX we can just say background color should be
main orange.
Let's test this out in the browser looks good.
Let's scroll back up to the top of the page and let's work on this button.
So we know from the design file that that should be orange and it should be quite a bit bigger than
the buttons in the header in the footer.
So let's find this element in our HDMI code.
Then the large hero block here it is.
So let's give it a class of button.
Let's give it another class of button dash dash orange so just recycling those classes gets us half
the way there.
Now let's add on another modifier button dash dash and let's create a new one named large.
Let's jump into our button dot CSX file and create a new modifier rule for large in this large version.
Let's do two things.
Let's bump up the font size and let's give it extra padding.
So let's go with the font size of one point two five ram or in other words a font that is 25 percent
larger than the pages default font.
And let's bump up the padding a bit so if the normal button has point seven five vertical padding.
Let's try one point one Ram.
Vertical padding on this large version and for horizontal padding with bump it up from one point to
ram to maybe one point nine Ram looks good.
Now in future lessons we can fine tune these buttons dials a bit maybe add a super subtle text shadow
or even a subtle hint of a gradient on hover.
But for the time being that will bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson.
We will take a quick web pack time out.
We will learn how to configure web back to automatically refresh the browser for us when we save a change
to our H T AML file.
And beyond that when we save a change to a CSX file Westpac won't even need to refresh the browser at
all.
It will just auto inject the new CSX code into the browser's memory completely on the fly.
This should be a lot of fun to set up and it should also provide us with a nice productivity or speed
boost.
So let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.