Hello everyone.
In this video we're going to pick up right where we left off.
So as of this moment we know how to visit the U.R.L. for our cloud function but just doing this isn't
very useful.
We need to learn how to send data along with our request to this you are out because a bit later in
this lesson we're going to set things up so that when the user submits this form we programmed the web
browser to send a request to this U.R.L. but also send along with it whatever value the user typed into
this field.
Now before we worry about learning how to program the web browser to send a request like that let's
first learn how to make our cloud function work with any incoming data.
Now when it comes to experimenting with sending requests to different you are ELLs and sending along
different data with those requests.
There is no better tool than postman if you've never heard of postman.
That's OK.
But if you don't already have postman installed on your computer please pause this video and you can
either visit get postman dot com or just google for postman so we can download this tool completely
free.
We don't need to register or sign up or enter any payment information.
It's a completely free download.
Go ahead and pause this video while you download and install post man.
But at this point I'm going to assume moving forward that everyone has postman on their computer.
OK.
So here is the postman application running on my computer.
So we just want to click this button here to create a new tab for a new request.
If you can't see this button it might be because your sidebar is open and if your screen is small the
sidebar would cover that up.
So you can click view and then toggle sidebar to hide the sidebar if your screen is small.
But we just want to click this icon to create a new tab for a request.
OK.
So we're going to use postmen to simulate a web browser sending a request to a U.R.L..
So first of all instead of a get request let's send a post request because we want to post or send a
bit of data along with the request.
So click on this.
Change it from get to post and then in terms of the actual U.R.L..
This is where you can just copy and paste your cloud function you are now.
So this you are all that at the moment is just saying Welcome to the supersecret area.
Copy the actual you are L into your clipboard and back and postman paste that in here.
OK.
But we also want to send along a bit of data with the request.
So in this area click on body from this selection.
We want to choose raw and then we can begin typing in this area.
So let's just send a bit of Jason data.
So curly brackets inside the curly brackets.
In Jason you want to wrap your property names in quotes.
So for example we could have a property named Sky color and give it a value of blue comma and then we
could have a property named grass color and give it a value of green.
So this Jason format is a very common way to send data along with your request.
But in this case we don't actually want sky color and grass color.
We would want a property name that makes sense for this value whatever the user typed in as the secret
password or passphrase.
So in postman why don't we do this.
Let's get rid of these two example properties inside our curly brackets.
Let's just have one property quotes and let's name it password quotes colon.
And for a test let's just give it a value of 1 2 3.
ABC doesn't matter.
You can type anything here within these quotes.
OK.
And now let's actually send this request to just click this send button and then down at the very bottom
of post man.
If your screen is small you might need to scroll down the overall screen.
But here we see the response from the server.
Now at the moment our cloud function is programmed to always send this as the response.
So right now let's jump into our text editor and let's learn how to send a different response depending
on what password value the user sends along.
Right.
So let's imagine that the correct password should be a value of JavaScript.
Any other string of text is considered the incorrect password.
So I'll let you know that the event parameter contains information about the incoming request so we
can use this parameter to extract the data that the user sent along.
So right above this line where we call callback but still within the function.
Let's do this.
Let's create a variable let's name it body.
And for now we don't need to set it to equal anything.
We're just declaring this name in this scope.
OK.
And then below this let's write an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets after those brackets let's also add in else block before we worry about
the password value.
Let's first make sure that the incoming request has any body data whatsoever.
So for the condition I would say if event dot body if that even exists.
Well then I would want to pass that data as Jason data.
In other words event dot body is going to be the literal text characters that the visitor sent along.
So the actual Curly rackets and the quotations and the semicolon we don't want that.
We want to understand it as if it's actual javascript not just a literal string of text.
So what we can do is say a body should now equal and then javascript environments have access to all
uppercase Jason dot because that has a method named pass within these parentheses we give it a string
of text and it's going to pass it or convert it into actual javascript.
Right.
A javascript object so we can just say event dot body else.
Otherwise if there is no incoming body data on the request let's just set body to equal an empty object.
OK.
Now below all of this we can actually now pay attention to the password value.
So do this with me.
Let's have one more if statement after that.
Let's also have an else block and within the condition let's say only if body dot password double equals
sign to check for equality.
Only if that equals javascript.
So now if this evaluates to true we can send the user the supersecret content else.
Otherwise we can say sorry that password is incorrect.
So let's just do this.
Let's cut this callback call to just select these four lines of code.
Cut that in your clipboard in the F block.
Just paste it in in the else block pasted in once again only this time if they typed the incorrect password
let's change the status code from 200 which means success to maybe for a 1 which means unauthorized.
And since we're sending a failed status code we actually don't even need a message here.
So we can get rid of the body property and this comma after for a one as well.
OK.
Now if they send the correct password while we're at it instead of this just welcome to the super secret
area.
Let's include the HDMI all that you saw in my finished product example.
You could just type a bunch of HDMI all right here but to stay organized we could also go up to the
very top of this file and maybe right above.
When we say let body we can say contest secret content equals and then back ticks two of them in between
the two back ticks we can drop down and begin typing each CML.
So for example maybe we want a heading level three that says Welcome to the secret area and then maybe
a paragraph below that.
Here we can tell you that the sky is blue and two plus two equals four.
And just to really drive home the fact that we're sending each t AML maybe we want the word blue to
be bold so we can wrap that in a strong tag.
You don't have to have your server send back HDMI all you could just send back raw data or Jason data
and then have the front end or the web browser pass that Jason data to create its own HDMI.
There's a million different ways we could do this but this is just a quick example.
OK.
So now we can leverage this secret content variable.
If the password is correct instead of body being this string we can just replace this with secret content.
OK let's go ahead and save this.
But before we push this to get hub I do want to let you know that you should probably go make your GitHub
repo private because even though net lo fi and Amazon Web Services will keep our code private and safe.
Well if you're get a hub repository as public then obviously the secret password value will be leaked
to the public.
And that's not net lo fi or Amazon's fault.
Now luckily for us as of the beginning of 2019 even free get hub accounts can make a repo private.
So just go to the overview screen for your GitHub repo.
Click on settings and then down towards the very bottom you'll see an option to make that particular
repo private cool.
Now in this case it doesn't really matter because it's not like Javascript is an actually secure password
anyways but you get the idea.
You wouldn't want to leak your secret password value to the entire world.
OK with this file saved let's push it up to get hub.
So in the command line I will add everything to the staging area get add dash uppercase a.
Then I will commit
updated cloud function to check password and then push it up to get up.
So get push origin master OK if we jump back over to the net lo fi overview screen for this project
we can click on deploys you can see in real time it's still building OK.
I just waited maybe 20 or 30 seconds and now it's published.
So let's jump back over to postman and test it out again.
So currently our test request is going to send a password value of 1 to 3 ABC which is obviously incorrect.
So if we send out again click on send cool so we don't see response body text but we can't see that
the status is for a one unauthorized however if we go up and change this password value to be Java script
and then send that off again check the response from the server.
Awesome.
There's that successful H TMF message.
So at this point our cloud function is up and running now that we know that it works as we would expect.
We are ready to begin programming the browser the front end to actually send along the data of this
form.
When you submit it now I realize we have not actually added this form to our page yet.
This is the example of the finished product.
Right.
As of right now our Web site still has just the bottom footer.
So in our very next lesson we are going to work on the H all CSX and front end javascript to begin powering
this secret client area.
It should be fun to see all of the different puzzle pieces come together.
Let's keep things rolling and I'll see you then.