Hello everyone in this lesson we will build a re-usable block that we can use to create column layouts
throughout our page.
Let's dive right in and get started.
So in this lesson we want to focus on this content.
If we look at our design file we see that that content you use a two column layout.
So basically we want this content here to be placed next to the image.
And what do these two columns belong to.
They belong to a row right.
So if we think of a spreadsheet.
This would be Column A.
This would be column B and they're grouped together in a row.
So in our TMI.
Let's wrap all of this content in a new div that has a class of row we can find that content in our
each team all by searching for how we got started.
OK so here is that image.
Let's open our div and give it a class of row and then if we scroll down a bit after this paragraph
let's close that divide that we just opened and let's be sure to indent all of the content within that
new div next.
Let's go ahead and create a new CSSA file for our row class.
So in our assets styles and then modules.
Let's create a new file name this new file underscore row Ducey assets.
Let's create a new class and then go ahead and save this file.
And before we forget let's go into our main styles not CSSA file and import this new file underscore
row.
Go ahead and say that next.
Let's wrap each section of content that we want to be a call them in their own device.
So in our age team out within a row let's create two new divs.
Let's cut and paste the image into the first div and let's cut and paste from the heading level to down
to this paragraph into the second div.
Paste it in and be sure to get rid of these empty lines.
All right so now the question becomes what should the class name be for these two new divs that we just
created.
We know that they belong to the road block.
So their class names should begin with row and then underscore underscore.
But what do we actually want to name each of these column elements.
Well let's look at our design file for just a moment.
Why don't we go ahead and think of our row in terms of a 12 column grid.
So this image for our first column looks like it's taking up about one third of the width of the row.
Or to put that in the context of the 12 column grid.
What is one third of 12.
The answer is 4 and it just so happens that it looks like this image column is taking up four of the
12 column grid bars.
Our second column looks like it's taking up about two thirds of the available with.
And what is two thirds of 12.
The answer is 8.
And it looks like this column is taking up eight of our 12 column grid bars so we could call this layout
a 4 8 split.
So over an hour each time.
Now why don't we just give this element a class of row underscore underscore for end and give this column
a class of row underscore underscore 8.
Let's go ahead and save this file and jump over to our row does CSSA file and write a bit of CSSA to
make the call them lay out come to life.
So let's begin with the underscore underscore for class.
Let's tell it to float to the left let's give it a width and let's actually open our calculators if
we think of our rows available with as 100 percent and then divide that up amongst our 12 column grid.
So 100 divided by 12 that means that each one of our 12 grid bars is eight and a third percent.
So for our for class we can just take that in a third and multiply it by four.
And no surprise that gives us thirty three point three three which is what we expect.
Considering we wanted this class to take up a third of the available with.
So let's go with thirty three point three three percent.
All right let's create the rule for our underscore underscore a class floated to the left give it a.
And we don't need a calculator.
If this is one third and we know that two thirds would be sixty six point six six percent.
Let's save this file and check the browser so we do see two columns this content and the image are now
side by side but we also see a problem.
The blue background feature section has moved up and is now sitting behind our content.
This is because we forgot to clear our floats when we float an element.
We take it out of the normal flow of the page.
And in this instance our road div only has two direct children.
The two columns and if both of these elements have been taken out of the flow of the page it's almost
as if our main road div has no idea how tall it should be because as far as it's concerned in terms
of sizing and styling it thinks that it's empty.
So for example we can tell the main road give to have a background color of yellow and if we save this
and check the browser We don't even see one pixel of yellow anywhere.
Now there are several different ways to fix this.
Let's look at the sloppy not ideal way first.
So in our HTL right before the main road div ends we can create another element and give it a class
of clear me.
The key here is that this element comes after all of it's floated siblings.
So let's save this file and jump into CSX.
Let's create a rule that targets that element and let's say Clear left or clear both.
So if we say this and check the browser we see that that got the job done.
The main parent road div now knows how tall it should be because all of its floated children have been
cleared.
Now the reason I called that the sloppy or not ideal way of clearing our floats is because we added
an empty element to our markup and whenever possible you should avoid empty elements that only exist
for styling purposes.
So let's delete this save this file and jump back into our CSSA file and delete this clear me rule and
let me show you a more ideal way of clearing our floats.
So up at the top of this row rule let's create a new selector.
We can say calling Cohen after to create a bit of pseudo or fake content with CSX.
So let's say content double quotes with nothing in between the quotes and then let's tell this empty
fake space to be set to clear both for a bit of added extra browser support.
We can also just a display table.
So this VSS selector will add this blank space after all of the content in the main road div or in other
words it will create that content right where we used to have our empty div..
So if we go ahead and save this and check the browser we see that our floats are still cleared and we
got to keep our HMO clean.
Now let's clean up a little bit.
So we didn't actually want the background color to be yellow.
Delete that and this code that we used to clear the floats should probably be moved into a mix and so
we can easily reuse this code whenever we want.
So let's go ahead and cut this code into our clipboard and within app assets styles and then the base
folder.
Let's open up mixdowns CSX.
Let's go to the bottom and say at symbol the fine mixin and let's call this mix in clear fix and then
just go ahead and paste your clipboard.
All right looks good.
Let's save this mixdowns file and back and wrote up CSSA.
Now we can just say mix in clear fix what saved this file and check the browser.
Looks good but now I'm noticing that the two columns but up directly against each other.
And I think it would look a lot better if there was a gutter or margin between the two.
And if we look at the design file we see that there is indeed supposed to be a margin.
Now there might be situations where we do want our columns to touch like this.
So I think the best way to handle this is to go into our each team and go in on our main road give give
it a modifier class of road dash dash gutters.
So by default we will not have gutters or margins if we want them we just add this modifier class next.
Let's write a bit of CSSA so that if this modifier class is used a bit of horizontal padding will be
added to all of the columns and that will create the margin or Gunnar's effect that we are looking for.
So in our CSX let's create a rule for that gutters modifier.
But we don't want to select or style the actual parent row div.
We want to select all of its direct children or in other words all of the columns so we can use the
greater than symbol to select all direct children that use a tag of div and then we can just say padding
right 65 pixels.
So let's save this and check the browser.
Now there's no need to panic but we see that our column layout broke.
So our second column is now getting pushed to a second line.
And this is because the padding values that we just added upset the arithmetic that we set up earlier.
We cannot let the combined with of our columns be more than 100 percent otherwise they won't be able
to both fit on a single line.
Now by default web browsers calculate the true with an element by taking the declared width and then
adding on any padding or borders.
So clearly this value plus this value plus an extra 130 pixels is more than 100 percent of the available
horizontal space.
However we can change the way that web browsers calculate the true with of elements.
If we say box sizing border box web browsers will actually honor our declared with values our padding
will still be applied but it won't affect the calculated width values.
So let's go ahead and say this and check out the browser.
And we're back in business now I don't know about you but this box sizing border box way of calculating
values makes sense to me.
I prefer it over the browser default.
Now in recent years something that a lot of web developers have been doing is applying this globally
to all elements on the page.
So for example let's delete this line.
And within app assets styles and in the base form there let's open up global does CSX create a new rule
where the selector is the star or asterisk meaning we want to select every single element on the page
and let's say box sizing bordered box.
Go ahead and save.
So with that in place managing our with values just got a lot easier.
We set that property once in the global file and we can forget about it at this point.
Our column layout is shaping up nicely.
There are just a few more things that I want to fine tune.
So for example there is currently a margin or gutter here and here.
Now you might not be able to notice the one that I'm currently highlighting.
So let me make it obvious by jumping into our text editor in road of SS and giving the main parent road
div a background color of yellow.
So we obviously want a margin or gutter between the two columns but we definitely do not need a gutter
or margin on this far right edge.
That's a waste of space.
Now we created these margins or gutters by applying padding right to each column.
We did this so even if we have a row that has three or four or five columns there will automatically
be a gutter between each of them.
So the question becomes how do we remove this final gutter on the end.
Our first instinct might be to select the last column in a row and tell it to have zero padding but
doing that would actually affect the ratio of our columns.
Right.
So currently this column is exactly one third of the available width and this column is exactly two
thirds.
But if we told the final call them to not have any padding it would no longer be exactly two thirds.
So let me show you how I like to handle this situation.
We can counteract this padding rate by selecting the main parent row with a modifier class of gutters
and giving it a negative right margin that matches the padding value.
So we can say negative 65 pixels.
The second column still has the gutter or margin that we need to get rid of.
So clearly we are not done yet.
However the negative margin has made the row in general 65 pixels wider than it should be.
What do I mean by that.
Well the row is supposed to be constrained by the width of our wrapper div right.
So for example if we open up wrapper got CSX and give it a background color of green
you can see that the yellow of our rogue element is protruding outside the right edge of the wrapper
and this is thanks to the negative right margin.
So now within wrapper does CSSA we can simply say overflow.
Hidden.
Go ahead and say this.
And the negative margin still exists.
It's where the padding or gutter for this second column is.
But because we told the wrapper to have overflow hidden we can't see it.
So in other words we can remove the silly background colors that we were using for demonstration purposes
and we now have a very clean column laya.
Now before we bring this lesson to a close let's see how things look on a mobile or small screen.
Let me scroll up a little bit.
And we see that the column layout looks very odd on a small screen.
There just isn't enough horizontal space to have multiple columns sit side by side.
Let's go ahead and adjust this so that small screens use a single column layout.
So on small screens we want each section to use the full available width and simply stack on top of
each other vertically.
But we do want to maintain the multiple call lay up on larger screens.
So why don't we do this over an hour each.
TMF.
Let's adjust the class names on our column elements.
So for example we don't want this element to use four of our 12 column grid bars for all screen sizes
on a small screen.
We want this element to use the full available horizontal wit.
So why don't we do this.
Why don't we adjust this name to say row underscore underscore medium for.
And this way we will adjust our CSSA to use media queries.
So only if a screen is considered medium or larger will we apply the width and tell it to float to the
left but do the same thing to this element so medium 8 and then over in our road of CSSA file.
Let's simply change the name for these two rules and then wrap them in a media query.
So let's change this to medium for an medium 8.
And now we can use a mediacorp mixin so we can say mix in at medium.
So only when a screen is medium or larger Do we want these rules to be applied.
So let's just cut and paste these into that mix in.
Let's go ahead and save this file and check out the browser.
Looks good.
So on the small screen the image takes up the full available window and so does the section below it.
And we still maintain that to call them lay out on larger screens and that will bring this lesson to
a close in our next lesson.
We will adjust this topography to match the design file.
We will also add a bit of much needed vertical spacing between these two images and we will also convert
both of these images to become responsive images.
Let's keep rolling along and I will see you in the next lesson.