So let's save this file and then jump in to app assets.
Scripps modules sticky header.
All right.
Let's write some javascript.
So the first thing we should do within our constructor is to create a new property that is a collection
of all of our actual page section elements.
So for example back in our HDMI all all of the actual page section divs have a class of page section.
So within our javascript let's create a new property and name it page sections.
And it should equal.
Document doc query selector all.
Be sure to include the all here because we want to select multiple elements parentheses quotes and dot
because it has a class of page dash section.
OK.
So now we have this collection of all of our page sections.
Now within our run on scroll method every time we scroll we just want to run a calculation once for
each of those page sections to see if it has been scrolled to or not.
So after the if else but still within the run on scroll method let's just start working with that collection
of elements of this dot page sections and we want to do something once for each of them.
So dot for each and let's give it an arrow function with exactly one parameter parameter of L short
for element arrow symbol.
And then this method doesn't exist yet but we can create it in just a moment.
Let's say this dot calc section parentheses to call that method.
I just made up this method name.
The idea is we're going to calculate if the current page section has been scrolled to.
Now when we call this method within the parentheses we want to pass it the current element so e l All
right.
Now let's go create a method with this matching name.
So after our run on scroll method but still within our class.
So right here let's create a new method with that name calc section parentheses curly brackets within
these parentheses.
Let's be sure to include a parameter to receive that argument.
So you know short for element and within the body of this method before we even perform any extra calculations
let's begin with an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets and only if the following conditions are met do we need to perform
any other calculations so the condition for this if statement will be only if the user has scrolled
down far enough so that a section has entered into the viewport at all.
And only if they have not scrolled down so far that the bottom edge of a section is now not in the browser's
viewport at all.
In other words if the section isn't in the browser's viewport at all we don't need to worry about any
other calculations.
So for the condition it will be if window dot scroll y plus window dot inner height.
If those two combined are greater than the current elements offset top right.
So if you scroll down far enough so you can at least see the very top edge of the section and so double
Ampersand to include another condition that must be true.
And I'm actually going to temporarily decrease the font size so this will all fit on a single line for
the sake of this video.
I know this font size might be difficult to read but at least it will all fit on the screen.
And if you need to pause the video and magnify it or zoom in or get really close to the screen that's
OK but Ampersand Ampersand for the second condition window dot scroll.
Why should be less than the bottom edge of the current element.
Now the web browser doesn't have a simple easy property that stores the bottom edge position but what
we can do is grab the elements top position so l dot offset top plus the height of that element.
So element dot offset height.
OK so that is our long winded condition to make sure the element is on the screen at least if you need
to pause the video.
Go ahead.
But in just a second I'm going to zoom back in the font size so it's easy to read.
OK.
Now within the curly brackets for the if statement we want to calculate how far down an element has
been scrolled to.
So for example let's take the transition as you're scrolling from our beginning and you're scrolling
down into our features when we're about here we would want our beginning to still be selected as the
current section but maybe once you scroll until about this threshold then we would want to select our
features as the yellow or selected item.
So we need to be aware of how tall the browser window is and what percent or how far you've scrolled
the element into view.
So this calculation is going to be a bit similar to what we set up when we were deciding when to reveal
an item.
So back in our Ed in the if statement let's create a variable let's name it scroll percent and set it
to equal.
And this is the same formula we used in our previous lesson.
So the current element and then you'd get bounding client rect call it and then we want the Y property
and then we want to divide that by the height of the web browser window dot enter height and then we
want to multiply that by 100.
So it seems like a percentage instead of a decimal.
Now in a previous lesson we learned that if we can avoid asking the browser for information it's a good
idea.
Right.
So instead of asking the browser how tall it is.
That's something that we can store in memory and then we only need to update that if the user resize
is the browser window.
So before we move forward and actually use this value let's do this let's scroll up to the top of our
file and in our constructor let's create a property named browser height.
So this thought browser type and let's set that to equal window dot inner height and then we do need
to babysit this property.
Right.
So when the user resize is the browser window we need to update this.
Now in order to save a bunch of typing we can actually just copy and paste that function from our previous
file write our Reveal on scroll file so within your app assets scripts modules folder jump in to reveal
on scroll and down in the events method.
Remember we have this area where we added an event listener to the window object for the V size event
so you can just select these four lines of code that I've selected here.
Copy them into your clipboard and then back in sticky header dot J.S. well within its events method.
Right after this line just paste in your clipboard we don't need this console dot log line for testing
purposes and in order for this to work we need to make sure that this file or module has access to D
bounds so up at the top of this file we just need to import that it we've already imported throttle
so you can just copy that line pasted in change throttle to D bounce then within load asked to change
this to D bounce.
OK so now down within our calculation instead of using window to enter height we can just use our property.
Right.
This dot browser hiked do the same thing here as well.
So instead of window to enter height this dot browser right.
OK.
Now we can actually use this scroll percent value to determine if you've scrolled down far enough that
a section should be considered the current or highlighted yellow section.
So right below this line let's begin another if statement if it sees curly brackets this time for the
condition let's say if scroll percent is less than 18 and so double Ampersand and scroll percent is
greater than negative zero point one.
Now these are values that I've already experimented and these numbers seem to work for me.
But you're free to tweak these values a bit to your liking.
So once a section has been scrolled into this sweet spot we want to consider it the current or highlighted
yellow links section.
So within the body of this if statement let's begin by giving a dom reference to the matching link that
corresponds with the section that's been scrolled to.
Let me show you what I mean.
So let's create a variable and call it matching link and set it to equal.
And then we can work with the current page section element so yell and then say dot get attributes.
And remember earlier in this lesson in the HDL file we gave it a custom data attribute named data dash
matching link.
OK.
So this value is going to be a CSX like selector.
Right.
A hash tag and then an I.D. and that will be able to select an element or the link up in the header.
So now right below this that's the element that we want to select and give it a CSX modifier class to
make it yellow.
So we can just say document dot query selector.
We don't need quotes.
We want our selector to literally just be this value.
So matching link and then we want to work with its class list.
So dot class list dot add and let's give it a CSX modifier.
Class of is current link.
OK.
However if you scrolled through the entire page that would eventually make all three links yellow.
Right.
By the time you scroll down to the bottom instead we only want the current link to be yellow.
So anytime we make a new link the active link we want to remove that active yellow class from the other
links.
So right above this line that we just wrote.
Let's remove this class from any of the site header links that are not the current matching link.
So to do that we can just say document dot query selector all the all is important here because we're
selecting multiple elements and instead of quotes here let's actually use to back ticks.
So this character is to the left or the one key or right above the tab key.
And let's say dot primary nav space for a descendant selector any element colon any element that is
not.
And then parentheses and then dollar sign signed curly brackets matching link.
Okay.
So that will give us a collection of elements that at the very end of this line we want to loop through
them.
So dot for each within these parentheses will give it an arrow function with one parameter.
So element arrow symbol and then we'd want to work with that current element.
Work with its class list and remove a class of is current link.
OK.
Now this code makes sense if you're scrolling down the page but we need to realize that the calculations
should be different if you're scrolling back in the direction of up.
So really quick let's adjust our code to be able to determine if you're scrolling up or if you're scrolling
down within our run on scroll method right at the very start of the body of this method.
Let's just call a method that doesn't exist yet but we will create in just a moment.
So this dot determine scroll direction.
Okay.
Now let's just go create a method with this matching name so brand new method determine scroll direction
to determine if you're scrolling up or down.
We just need to compare the current scroll y value with the previous scroll y value.
So here's what I would do up in the constructor.
Let's take note of the initial scroll y value.
So in the constructor before we call the events let's just create the properties so this dot and let's
call it previous scroll Y instead it's equal window dot scroll y.
Okay then down in our determined scroll direction method we can just start and if statements.
So if let's also have an LS block for the condition if window dots scroll Y is greater than the previous
value.
So this dot previous scroll y if it's greater then that means you're scrolling down so we can store
a new property on our overall object named scroll direction and set it to down.
This dot scroll direction equals down else otherwise this dot scroll direction equals up.
And then after the else block but still within this method let's update the previous value.
So this dot previous scroll y should now equal the current window dot scroll on.
Cool.
Now let me show you how we're going to use this value down within our calculation for the if statement
when we said scroll percent must be between 18 and negative zero point one right after that one.
I want you to say.
And so Ampersand Ampersand we're going to say and the scroll direction must be down.
So this dot scroll direction double equals sign down then let's say or so right after the quotes four
down will say pipe pipe to say or if we're scrolling back up we want to use different threshold values
to determine if you've scrolled to the sweet spot.
So let's say scroll percent should be less than thirty three and double ampersand.
This is only if the scroll direction is up.
So this dot scroll direction double equals sign up all right.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
But before we test things out in the browser let's first write a bit of CSX so that this is current
link class actually makes the links yellow or orange.
So within app assets styles modules let's open up.
Primary nav CSX if we scroll down to the very bottom here is the rule targeting the link elements.
And remember that our sticky NAV is only for medium screens and larger and it just so happens that we
already have a media query here.
So within this media query let's create a new rule and use the ampersand which will give us this selector
and then we can simply say only if it has a class of is current link and we just want to give the currently
a color.
Here's a value for a nice light orange.
So F A B B 6 9.
Let's go ahead and save this and check things out in the browser.
So if I refresh up at the top notice none of the links are yellow.
But as I start scrolling down once the hour beginning section is in the viewport it becomes highlighted
and as soon as a scroll down until the features area is taking up the majority of the screen you see
it becomes highlighted.
Perfect.
If I keep scrolling down until testimonials is the main focus.
Awesome.
All right now before we bring this lesson to a close.
There's one final feature that I want to implement.
So currently if we actually click on these header links we are immediately within the course of one
millisecond taken to the appropriate section.
But I think the cherry on top for this page would be smooth scrolling so that way when we click on features
the browser automatically smoothly scrolls to that section.
Implementing this feature is a lot easier than you might think.
So do this with me within our text editor.
Within your styles folder look in the base folder for global dot see SS and up at the very top even
above our body selector lets select the H CML element and we just need to give it one property which
is scroll behavior colon and just set it to smooth.
Let's go ahead and save this.
Back in the browser I refresh and go up to the top when I click on our beginning.
Perfect it smoothly scrolls to the destination instead of just instantly teleporting you perfect and
that's actually going to bring this lesson to a close in our next lesson we will learn how to create
our own modal or lightbox or overlay.
If our visitors click the get in touch button in the header and overlay will appear that they can close
out of and we will also open up that overlay if they click get started today in the large hero or if
they click on get in touch in the footer.
This should be a lot of fun.
Let's keep rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.