Hello everyone in this lesson we will learn about node.
J.S. This lesson has three main parts to it.
Number one we will answer the question what is node.
J.S. Number two I will help you install a node on your computer.
And number three we will have a hands on demo.
You and I will get to see node in action.
We will write a bit of code together step by step should be a lot of fun.
So lets start at the top.
Number one what is node to answer that.
Lets talk about javascript first and then circle back to node.
So what is javascript we traditionally think of javascript as a language that only runs within the web
browser which means Javascript can only do web browser ish things things like opening a modal window
or a lightbox on a web page or opening or closing a toggle menu on a page or adding new content to a
page without a hard refresh.
Those are all very web browser ish tasks.
We might call them front end tasks but what about less browser ish tasks and more computer ish or server
ish tasks things we might call back end things like creating new folders and files on a computer or
servers harddrive things like interacting directly with a database or triggering a server to send an
e-mail traditionally to do any of those things you would need to use a language like THP or Ruby or
Python.
You would need a language that can run on a computer and not just run within a web browser which means
javascript can't do any of these things until one day node J.S. came along and said hey javascript Yeah
do you want to grow up and where are your big boy pants.
Yes.
Yes I'd like that.
Great because you are a legitimate programming language just like any other.
There's no reason you need to be limited to the browser.
Do you agree.
I agree.
Cool.
My name's Noad.
I just took the javascript guts out of Google Chrome and I used those guts to build a new playground
for you that is located on the computer or server itself and not in a web browser.
Within this new playground you can do whatever you want.
You have access to the file system you can create files delete files.
You can talk directly to databases you can send e-mails.
You can create and serve up your own API.
You can do whatever you want.
Sweet thinking node.
So that's what no genius is.
It is a javascript runtime that lets us do just about anything with javascript.
Now you can do a lot of different things with Knode but I would say most things fall into one of two
camps.
The first camp is when you install node on a server.
In this case when the users of your website or app request a bit of data node is what's actually taking
that incoming request and then maybe hitting up a database or hitting up an API somewhere retrieving
the data and then sending it back to the user.
So in this case node is what is actually powering and serving up your public facing web site or app.
The second camp or the other super popular usage of node is to install it on your own personal computer.
In this case we are not using node to serve up anything.
Instead we're just using node as a development tool.
We are using it to basically create our own little robot assistant.
We are using node to automate all sorts of web development tasks that can save us a ton of time.
And in this course that is the way that we will leverage node.
All right so now we know what node is.
We know why we want to use it.
Now we can go ahead and install it on our computers.
So let's get started search for the Web site Noad J.S. dot org.
You should see a few download links we are interested in the one that ends with L ts.
We don't necessarily want the newest and most cutting edge version of Noad.
We want the most stable version of node.
So go ahead and click that.
Begin the download.
And once the download finishes whether you are on Windows or Mac just go ahead and double click the
downloaded file.
The installation process is self-explanatory you can just click next next next.
Through the installer all of the default options are A-OK.
Once the installer completes let's make sure that everything was set up correctly to do that I want
you to open up your command line.
Type in the following command node space and then dash V.
Hit enter.
Now your numbers may not match what you see here exactly but as long as you see V and then a few numbers
everything's great you are in business.
If instead your command line replies with a known command or command not found.
Don't panic.
That just means we might need to troubleshoot your node installation a bit.
If that's the case for you go ahead and pause this video and check out the text description for this
lesson.
I've included a few common pitfalls and solutions.
All right I will assume that anyone moving past this point in the lesson has Knode successfully installed.
So at this point we can now move on to the exciting part of the lesson.
The third part where we get to see node interaction and we write a bit of code together.
So the first thing I want you to do is to navigate to the generic sites or projects folder that you
created a few lessons ago and within that folder create a new folder and name it.
Node experiment or something similar doesn't have to be exactly this name but once you create a new
folder I want you to navigate to the new folder in your command line.
So I'm just going to type CD space and then I'm going to drag that new folder on top of the command
line and hit enter.
Next we want to create a new empty javascript file where we can write a bit of code and then have node
run that file.
So you can use your favorite text editor to create a new javascript file in the new folder or since
we have already navigated to that folder in the command line you could just type touch and then the
name of the file.
So let's create a new file named test.
J.S..
There it is.
So now go ahead and open up this new empty file in your favorite text editor.
And let's begin with a simple hello world example.
So type Konsole log in parentheses quotes hello world at a semi-colon.
Go ahead and save the file.
Ok now we want to run this file through node we want node to run the file.
So in our command line type node space and then if you are truly lazy you could drag this file on top
of your command line.
But since we know we are already in the right directory you can literally just type test.
J.S. So this will force node to run that file that we just created and there we go.
So the console replies with Hello world.
Let's try something a little bit more exciting so clear out your text file and let's try instead.
Console log.
Parentheses two plus two.
Riveting right.
So go ahead and add the semi-colon.
Hit save back in the command line.
Just run the exact same command node test.
J.S..
You might be wondering why seeing the number 4 here is supposed to be exciting.
Here's why.
It's because it means that whatever we write in this file isn't merely getting repeated or echoed out
to the command line but instead it means that node is actually interpreting and evaluating our Javascript
code.
Right so node actually ran the expression two plus two and it concluded that that equals four.
So that's a nerdy way of saying that we can do whatever we want in this file.
So let's try something a bit more exciting.
Let's write a bit of code to programmatically have node create a new HTL file in this folder for us
out of the box.
Knode comes with a bunch of modules that can do things for us.
So since we want to create a file we want to leverage the node module named FS which stands for file
system.
So let's create a variable and we can name it whatever we want.
I will call it fs just to make sense but you could name it unicorn or pizza the name of the variable
does not matter.
Let's just say EF-S though and then we set it to equal and then we can say require.
And then this is where the name does matter.
So in quotes I will say FS and this is the name of a node module or package.
OK so a semi-colon here and now on a new line we can access all of the tools and methods that live within
this file system package.
By just saying FS This is now referencing our variable name that we created.
So FS Daut and then it contains a method named right file and we want to get this right file method
3 things.
So just as placeholders we could say a comma B comma C right.
So we want to give this method three arguments.
Now back to the task at hand.
Remember we want to create in each DML file within our folder.
Now the first argument is the location on your computer where you want to create the new file.
So instead of a let's say underscore underscore Der. name which stands for directory name.
This will tell node to look within the current folder and then right after Derg name we can add on and
then quotes and then within the quotes.
Let's say forward slash and then the name of the file that we want to create.
So maybe index dot each TNL.
OK so this is the first argument.
The second argument is what you want to live within the file.
So instead of this placeholder B I will provide a string of text so quotes and then let's imagine we
want to create in each DML headline so heading level one close out the tagging within the tags.
Let's just say each DML is great.
OK and then finally for the third argument instead of this placeholder see we want to include a function
that will run once our write file action has either succeeded or failed.
This is commonly referred to as a callback function.
So at the end where are placeholder C was let's say function and it gets its own set of parentheses
and then right after those curly brackets within the curly brackets Let's drop down and let's write
an IF statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets.
Let's say if there is an error so if something goes wrong and for some reason our file cannot be created
if that's the case then within these curly brackets we can say return Konsole dot log parentheses error.
So if there's a problem this way we can see the problem in the command line and then right after the
closing curly bracket for our if statement we can say else otherwise if there's not a problem within
these Charitha brackets we can just say return Konsole dot log and then quotes for a string of text
and let's say contracts meaning everything worked perfectly and your file was created.
And finally before we save this file if we're going to be referencing a potential error that occurred
we want to be sure to include that as a parameter when we first say function.
So within these parentheses let's include error as a parameter.
And now let's save this file and test it out.
So over in the command line node test dot J.S. contracts.
And if I check my folder sitting alongside or test J.S. we now see index dot h DMO.
And if I open it up in my text editor cool we can see that it contains our content.
Now let's change gears and try one more note example before we bring this lesson to a close.
So up next let's make it our goal to use node to programmatically download and save an image from the
Internet.
So for example we need a RL for an image that lives on the Internet.
So if you want to follow along with me you can visit get hub dot com slash learn web code.
Slash welcome dash to Dagget.
And I'm just going to dig within this images folder and then click on dogs a pig and this you r l will
not work because this is still a web page.
But if you right click on the dog photograph and choose view image this is the type of you rl I'm looking
for.
Now you do not need to use this exact photo of a dog.
Any image you Arel on the Internet will work just fine.
So go ahead and copy an image you are l into your clipboard and let's say that our goal is to use node
to programmatically save this file to live within our folder.
So back in our code back in our test dodgiest file in order to send out a request onto the Internet
I'm going to want to include another node module or package.
So up towards the top let's create a new variable we can name it whatever we want but just to make sense
I will name it.
H t t p s and set it to equal and then I want to require in or include in parentheses quotes a node
module named H TTP s and just a quick note on semi colons in javascript.
99 percent of the time they are not necessary but a lot of developers consider it just a best practice
to be consistent and include them at the end of a statement.
It's a bit of a personal preference because some developers hardly ever use semi-colons.
But if you're going to use them you should probably be consistent.
So you'll notice that on this line I forgot to include one at the end.
Nothing breaks without it.
It's just something you want to be consistent with and technically you can include one at the end of
this line as well.
OK.
Back to the task at hand.
We want to leverage this HTP module to download and save this dog photo.
So down at the bottom of our code now at the very bottom let's add a new line and let's say HTP s to
leverage that new module and look inside it with a dot and it contains a tool or method named get.
We want to give this method to things.
So within the parentheses as a placeholder we could say a and b.
Right.
Two arguments the first argument is that you Arel that you want to work with.
So technically we could include quotes here and then paste in our clipboard but R U R L is so long that
it would take up almost the entire screen.
So instead why don't we do this right before this line.
We could create a variable.
The name doesn't matter.
But I'm going to name it my photo location and set that to equal and then quotes and now paste in your
clipboard.
Cool.
So you can see that that path is really long.
And just to keep this line of code clean.
Now instead of the placeholder a we can just say my photo location right that variable will pull in
the photo you Aro and then the second argument for this get method instead of the placeholder B.
We want to include a function where we say what we want to actually do with the photo data.
So let's say function parentheses curly brackets within those brackets.
Let's drop down and this good method is going to pass along any data that lives that are you Arel into
our function.
So it within our parentheses lets out a parameter we can name it anything.
But why don't we call it response.
And now on this line within the body of our function we can do whatever we want with that data.
So let's say response and then we want to pipe it or send it somewhere.
So Dot pipe and what do we want to do with it.
Well we just want to save it onto our computer within this same folder.
So within these parentheses let's say EF-S to use the file system and then a dot to look inside it.
And let's use a method named create.
Right.
Stream it gets its own set of parentheses and within the parentheses we just want to provide a path
to where we want to create the file.
So I will say underscore underscore dirth name to point at the current folder and then add on a string
of text and save forward slash and then you can name the file whatever you want to name it.
So I would just name it my dog die.
JP cool.
OK so now we can go ahead and save this file.
And back in our command line let's run node test dot J.S. push enter.
And if we go and check our folder cool there is our my dog photo.
And if you open it up perfect and that marks the end of this hands on no demo we didn't do anything
earth shattering with node but hopefully you can see the potential if node can access our file system
and if node can go onto the Internet and grab files for us that means we can automate all sorts of things.
And the good news is that we don't need to write a bunch of code to create that automation.
We wrote code in this lesson just because I wanted you to see how Knode works at its most basic level
but writing code for very basic tasks like we did here is not an efficient use of our time on Earth.
Instead we can leverage code that other super intelligent people have already written and have already
shared with the world.
Which brings us to the topic of our next lesson.
This is exactly where NPM comes into play.
And in our next lesson we will learn what NPM is and how to get started using it.
It's going to be a lot of fun and I will see you in the next lesson.