Hello everyone.
In this lesson we are going to improve our Reveal on scroll feature.
First let's improve its performance.
Or in other words we want to use as little web browser or computer processing horsepower as possible.
I want to begin by showing you an example of how our current code is super inefficient.
So right now do this with me within your reveal on scroll dot J.S. file within our events method.
When we add an event listener for scroll on the window object.
Well we see this line ends with an opening curly bracket right below that lets drop down and create
a brand new line and just say console dot log and let's log out a message that says scroll function
ran.
Let's go ahead and save this and then back in the browser.
Be sure to perform a manual refresh.
Now watch this as we begin scrolling in the browser's console we see that message scroll function ran.
And this number next to it is how many times that message has appeared.
So you can see as I scroll that number is just climbing.
This means the web browser is calling our function for every single pixel We scroll.
Well every web browser is a bit different so maybe not every single pixel but you get the idea it is
calling our function way too often.
And we are wasting a lot of web browser or processing horsepower.
Now you might be thinking to yourself Does this really matter.
Who cares.
There are actually several reasons why we should care.
I would ask you Have you ever felt your laptop or smartphone feel hot to the touch especially on a smartphone
if you visit a simple or well coded Web site.
Your phone is not going to feel hot in the palm of your hand but if you visit a Web site where there's
a lot going on or it's coded terribly inefficiently you will feel the heat from your phone in the palm
of your hand because your phone is having to work too hard.
The Web site is really stressing the processor in your device.
In my opinion that reflects poorly on a Web site and a brand.
It makes it seem like the people who created the Web site don't know what they're doing.
So that's reason number one why we would want to avoid terribly inefficient code.
Reason number two is a bit more timeless.
So let's imagine where in the future 5 10 20 years where processors are super powerful and no matter
how hard you stress them they really don't generate that much heat.
So the end user would never know that your code is inefficient.
Well even in that scenario we still don't want to write inefficient code why you might ask well it's
just sort of the way programmers are built as a programmer you are always striving to write the most
efficient well thought out code.
For example imagine we were writing code that's going to run on the server side instead of the browser
or client side.
In that case the programmer that can write more efficient code is going to save the company money.
Big picture it's just a good idea to get used to writing efficient code.
So hopefully that covers the why.
Now let's get into the how how can we make this code more efficient.
Well in terms of this scrolling action what we want to do is throttle the scroll call.
So instead of letting the web browser call our scroll function as many times as it wants to as we scroll
we want to throttle it so that it's only called maybe every 100 milliseconds as we scroll or every 200
milliseconds as we scroll.
Now we could write our own throttle function that sets up that limitation but there's already an industry
standard we're going to use a package from NPM named lo dash.
So here on the NPM page for load Ash you can see that just in the last week it was downloaded over 25
million times.
So that lets you know that load ash is not some obscure library that I like but rather it's an industry
standard.
So right now let's jump into our text editor let's open up our command line.
If you're like me and your Web pack task is running go ahead and press control see and let's install
load ash.
So type this command in with me npm install low dash this time around we do not need the dash dash save
dash death.
This is because load ash is not a package that makes our workflow or development process easier.
Rather it's a package that we actually want to send along to our visitors.
It's an actual direct dependency of our application.
So let's go ahead and run this command
OK.
And then we can tell Webb pack to begin running again.
So NPM run Dev OK.
And now back in our JavaScript file let's leverage low dash up at the very top of this file.
We are interested in importing the throttle functionality of low dash.
So let's do this.
Let's say import throttle from and then inside these quotes we just say low dash the name of the package.
And then we don't need to import the entire load Ash library.
We can just say slash throttle.
So now we have this function named throttle.
That's very easy to leverage.
You just give it to arguments.
The first argument is a function that you want to run.
The second argument is how many milliseconds you want to have to wait before that function can run again.
Now we could absolutely go ahead and use the throttle function directly in our ad event listener call.
Right.
So the type of event we're listening for is scroll in the second argument here is a function.
So instead of this aero function we could just use the throttle function.
However I want to give our ad event listener a named function.
My reasoning for this has nothing to do with throttle but has to do with a bit of performance savings
we're going to set up later in the lesson.
Essentially once you've scrolled so that all hidden elements are now revealed.
Well I don't want there to be a scroll handler attached to the window object at all.
I want to be able to remove this listener completely and in order to do that we need this to be a named
function that we can reference.
So even though that has nothing directly to do with throttling let me show you how I would set all of
this up within our constructor.
Right above this line where we call events.
So right here I would create a new property you can name it anything but I'm going to name it scroll
throttle and say that it should equal.
And then I'm going to use the low dash throttle tool and this method doesn't exist yet.
But we will create it in just a moment.
So I'm going to say this dot calc caller that's the function I want to run comma.
The second argument is how many milliseconds you want to wait before this can be called again.
So I would say 200 milliseconds.
So this way for every one second that the user scrolls the page we know that our function is only going
to be called five times at the most at the very end of this line.
I will add dot bind with the value of this.
This will make sure that no matter how this function is called the this keyword will still be pointing
towards our overall object.
Now within our events area I want you to cut and paste these four lines of code here.
So from console dot log and then these three lines that power our for each.
So with these four lines highlighted go ahead and cut them into your clipboard and let's create a brand
new method with this name calc caller.
So right below events or right above this calculator scroll to method create a brand new method named
calc caller parentheses curly brackets inside the curly brackets you can paste in your clipboard OK.
And now back in the events method let's get rid of this arrow function.
So this line of code should look like this.
We're adding an event listener to window and we need to give it to arguments.
We just have the one argument of scroll comma and now we're ready to give it the second argument.
So this is where we will use our property named scroll throttle.
We can say this dot scroll throttle if the last couple of minutes didn't make perfect sense.
That's OK.
I think studying this line of code and working backwards will allow things to make sense essentially
every time the browser detects a scroll event.
It's going to call this function.
We set that up so that that function uses the low dash throttle tool which is only going to allow this
to run once every 200 milliseconds.
And then remember we set up calc caller to be the code that actually runs our calculations to see if
the elements have been scrolled to yet.
So let's go ahead and save this and then back in the browser.
Let's perform a manual refresh.
So our old event handlers are gone and now as I begin scrolling you can see it's not as if hundreds
and hundreds of the same event are being fired for every one second that I scroll the function is only
being called about five times.
And if I scroll down to the hidden elements
perfect.
So our code is still working.
And now it's not as if our calculations are being called hundreds and hundreds of times but we can still
do better.
Let's set things up so that once an item is revealed we don't continue to calculate if it should be
revealed any longer before we set up this solution.
Let's first add a console dot log line so that we can see when our calculation is actually running back
in our text editor.
I want you to find the method that is named calculate if scrolled to within the body of this function.
Let's just add a line and say console dot log let's say element was calculated.
Let's go ahead and save and then be sure to manually refresh in the browser and you'll notice that even
once I scroll and reveal all of my items if I continue to scroll in the console you can see that that
message keeps appearing since it's just the same exact message over and over again it's hard to see
if it's actually being called you'll know that it's being called because you can see the scroll bar
for the console keeps getting smaller and smaller.
Or if you selected and highlighted one of these and then scroll your browser you can see it move up
out of you.
So for performance reasons once we've revealed an item we don't need to continue to calculate for it
so let me show you how I would set things up.
Back in our text editor I want you to scroll down and find our hide initially method.
We've already written a bit of code that loops through the collection of items.
And for each item it adds a class.
Well if we're already doing something once for each item why don't we create a property on each item
named is revealed.
And by default it's set to false.
But then once we actually calculate that it should be visible we can set it to true.
That way we can set up an if statement so that we only bother calculating an item if it hasn't already
been revealed.
Let me show you what I mean.
Let's adjust our arrow function down here to have curly brackets so we can have more than one statement.
So right after the arrow symbol we can add an opening curly bracket here and dropdown and then in between
these two closing parentheses here we can add a closing curly bracket right before that closing curly
bracket we can drop to a new line.
OK.
Now within the body of this function or within these curly brackets after this line of code let's add
a new line and we can just say the current element that's been looped to and Dot.
Let's add a new property to it named is revealed in just by default.
Set it to false.
OK.
Now up in this function calculate if scrolled to if this is true and we add the class that makes it
visible.
Well then we can also just set that property to True.
So E L dot is revealed equals true.
OK.
Now let's scroll up to our calc column method and within this for each we have this line that calls
the calculation method.
And this is going to run once for each element in the collection.
So just select this line and let's cut it into our clipboard and we're essentially wrapping it in an
if statement.
So say if parentheses curly brackets for the condition say if the current element if it's property of
is revealed double equal sign to check for equality.
Only if it equals false.
Only if that's the case then inside the if curly brackets just paste back in your clipboard.
Now you might be thinking Did we really need this is revealed property couldn't we have just checked
to see if it didn't have the CSX class that makes it revealed.
Well yes absolutely we could have done that instead.
But I'm quite certain that checking if a single value is true or false is going to be a good deal faster
than seeing if an array of CSX classes contains a certain string match or not.
Anyways let's go ahead and save this and back in the browser.
Be sure to perform a manual refresh.
So all of your old event listeners are gone.
Now as I scroll down you'll see this element was calculated message keeps appearing.
But once I scroll down so that all of them have been revealed.
Now when I continue to scroll we no longer see element was calculated.
We only see our generic scroll function Rand perfect.
So now let's take things one step further.
Once the final item that needs to be revealed has been revealed.
Let's completely remove the scroll event listener.
So back in the text editor first we need to be able to determine once every single item has been revealed.
There are a hundred different ways you could set this up.
But here's what I'm going to do within our hide initially method after this for each loop.
So right after this closing parentheses here I would drop down and say this dot items to reveal.
So this will give me the collection of items.
And then if we use square brackets we can select a particular element from this collection.
So we want the very last or final element in the collection.
So we could put a number here but we don't want a hard code this to a number.
So instead what we can do is grab the overall length of this collection.
So this dot items to reveal dot length so length will be a count of how many items are in the collection.
And then just subtract one because arrays are zero based.
So this will give us the final item in the collection.
Once we've got that element we can just tack on and add a property to it named is last item and set
it to true.
OK.
Now up within our calculate if scrolled to method if we've calculated an item should be revealed.
Well then after this line but still within the curly brackets from the if we can dropdown and let's
set up another if statement so if parentheses curly brackets for the if condition if the current element
dot is.
Last item only if that's true then we would want to remove the scroll event listener.
So the overall browser window object and instead of add event listener we can use remove event listener.
So the type of event we're trying to remove is scroll comma and this is why earlier we gave add event
listener a named function that we can point towards or reference because we want to reference it again
to remove it.
So it was this dot scroll throttle.
Let's give this a save.
Back in the browser manually refresh.
So as I scroll we are seeing both element was calculated and scroll function ran but as soon as I reveal
all of the items.
Now when I continue to scroll we don't see anything in the console.
You can prove this by maybe selecting a few.
And then if I continue to scroll in the browser console doesn't change.
Perfect.
That's going to bring this video but not this lesson to a close in the next video we'll continue this
lesson Don't worry we are ninety five percent done with our performance or efficiency improvements we
just have five more percent to go on that effort and then we can change gears and learn how to make
our Reveal on scroll module recyclable so that we can also use it to hide and reveal these testimonials.
Let's keep things rolling and I will see you in the next video.