Hello everyone in this lesson I will show you a few quick tips that can help you when you are experimenting
with responsive images.
Let's dive right in.
So for the first tip let's use the large hero image as an example.
Let's imagine you are resizing your browser window to test the responsive image and make sure it behaves
the way you expect it to.
Now if you resize your browser window very slowly it's not too difficult to see when the image snaps
and switches to a new image but other times it's not so clear.
And sometimes you want to remove all guesswork from the equation and you want to be able to identify
exactly which image file you are currently looking at.
Well if you open the project folder for the travel site and go into the app folder and then the assets
folder in the images folder you will notice that for every image file for example hero dash dash large.
There is a corresponding hero dash dash large dash.
So every image in this folder has a counterpart that ends in dash II.
I chose I to stand for information but that's not important.
I created these dash I copies of each image for you so you can clearly see when an image is being used.
So for example in our HMO within the source element for the large crop right before the end of the file
name before the dot JPA let's add a dash II.
So if I save this and check out the browser and expand the browser window to use the large crop we see
that the dash i version of the image file has a transparent black overlay and in white text we see the
dimensions of the image.
So 19:20 wide by 6:54 tall and we could go ahead and add the dash II to the medium crop as well.
So now when we resize our browser we see those numbers change.
So it is abundantly clear when the two images are swapping back and forth.
And this is not limited to the large block image I've created dash I versions of every image we are
going to use.
So that's the first quick tip throughout the rest of the course.
Feel free to use that dash version of images when you are experimenting and testing things out.
But for now let's move on to another tip.
The next tip that I will cover has to do with the topic of simulating and testing different pixel densities.
So for example we are currently seeing the large crop of this image which is included here in our HMO.
This image is about 2000 pixels wide but you will remember in our previous lesson we also included a
high speed version.
There is almost 4000 pixels wide.
Now my web browser Google Chrome is intelligent enough to know that based on my monitor's pixel density
I don't need the Heidi API version.
The version that is almost 2000 pixels will result in a crisp photo on my monitor.
That's great.
But as a developer I want to be able to test all of the images I want to see.
The Heidi API version in action to make sure that I didn't include a typo in its filename.
So the question becomes how can I test out the high DPMI version.
How can I see that image in my browser here.
If the actual monitor I'm using isn't Heidy API or your situation might be the opposite.
If your screen is Heidy API then you would want to be able to test this image to make sure that you
didn't include a typo in the file name.
Well luckily the Google Chrome web browser has a developer tool that can help us.
Now if you've been using a different browser that's OK.
Everyone is entitled to their own preference.
There's no such thing as the quote best web browser but I do think it's fair to say that Google Chrome
has its fair share of amazing developer tools and if you're not already using Chrome I think it's worth
a try.
So check this out and Google Chrome anywhere on the page.
We can right click and choose inspect that will open a developer tools window and now I want you to
click this icon.
The icon that looks like a couple of devices.
Now if I click back to the main chrome window we see a few options towards the top of the screen.
So right now Chrome is emulating a Galaxy S 5.
We could set this to an iPhone 5 or an iPhone 6 you get the idea.
But in this situation what we want to do is set it to responsive.
And now I can drag to simulate any size that I want let me drive this a bit further to full screen and
remember our goal was to simulate different pixel densities.
So to do that you might need to click these three dots in the top right corner and be sure to check
the show device pixel ratio option so once that option is checked we now see this option.
And before I change this value from one to two.
Let me jump to my HMO and make sure that both versions of this large crop are using the dash version
so we can easily distinguish between the two.
So let's say this.
All right.
So we are currently using a device pixel ratio of 1 which is what my monitor actually is and we see
the version of the image that is almost 2000 pixels.
Let's go ahead and simulate a device that has a higher pixel density.
So it's bumped this up to two.
And if I refresh the browser realizes that it now needs the version of the image that is almost 4000
pixels wide.
And more importantly the fact that this image is displaying it all means I can rest assured that I didn't
include a typo in this file name which was the entire point of this tip.
So just be aware that Chrome can help you when you are testing different characteristics of devices.
All right so now that we've tested these images and we know they are working correctly.
Let's go ahead and remove the dash.
I
perfect that will actually bring this lesson to a close.
I hope you now feel a bit more empowered in terms of experimenting with responsive images.
Now in our next lesson we are going to fine tune the mobile styles for this large here block and we
will also begin styling this intro section.
We now have all of the tools necessary to basically build out the entire design.
We are going to start making a lot of progress very quickly.
It's going to be a lot of fun and I will see you in the next lesson.