Hello everyone in this lesson we are going to work on our attention to detail.
Let's get started and dive right in.
So in our next lesson we are going to begin tackling this blew our features section.
But before we do that in this lesson let's work on perfecting this content.
Let's make our first task to add a bit of vertical spacing or margin between these two images.
Now we know that this first image lives within its own wrapper div.
So why don't we just add a bit of bottom margin to that element.
So over in our HTL mail we can find that element by searching for ever since.
So you can press Command F or control f and type ever since.
All right so for reference there is that heading.
So we know that the very next element is the image.
Let's add the bottom margin to this wrapper div.
So let's just add another modifier class to the wrapper div.
Let's say a wrapper dash dash B for bottom margin.
What save this.
And then within our CSL modules folder Let's open up wrapper got c.
Let's create a new rule for that modifier Class B margin margin bottom.
So how large do we think the margins should be.
Well if we look at our design file that looks like 62 pixels to me but we want that in terms of REM
so we can take 62 pixels and divide it by 16.
That gives us three point eight seven five.
So let's copy that to our clipboard paste it in and type Renn.
Let's go ahead and save this.
And check out the browser.
Looks good.
Let's see how this looks on a small screen.
All right.
So on a small screen that looks like way too much vertical spacing.
So why don't we do this.
Why don't we wrap this amount in a media query mix in a mix in at small use that amount that we specified.
But our baseline margin bottom should be much smaller.
Let's just try one round.
Let's see how that looks in the browser.
This looks much better for small screens.
All right.
The next thing that I want to work on is I want to fine tune the exact with values of these two columns.
So for example in our previous lesson we set up this column to be exactly thirty three point three three
percent of the available width.
However if we compare this to our design file our image in the browser looks a bit smaller or squished
compared to the design file.
This is because in the design file this image is technically a little bit wider than Exactly 33 percent
of the available width.
So let's create a few modifier classes to adjust the width distribution of these columns a bit.
We want this column to be a little bit larger and we want this column to be a little bit smaller.
So over in our HMO Here is our road block.
Let's add a modifier to the first column of row underscore underscore medium for dash dash larger.
Let's also add a modifier class to the second column row underscore underscore medium a dash dash smaller.
Let's save this and within our modules CSSA folder Let's open up road up CSX.
So after our normal medium for Roulettes create a new rule medium for dash dash larger.
And let's just increase the width from thirty three point three three to 37 percent.
Let's also create a new rule underneath this regular medium eight on eight dash dash smaller instead
of sixty six point six six.
Let's go with 63 percent.
Before I say this let me resize my text editor so we can see the browser in the background and we can
see the change in real time.
So I'm going to save it right now.
It was a subtle change but I think it looks a lot better.
Now the reason we used a modifier classes instead of just adjusting 33 percent and 66 percent is because
later on in our design file down here in the testimonial section These truly are exactly 33 percent
each.
So we do want to keep that rule in place.
And I wanted to show you that it's OK to override your column grid when necessary.
I'm not a fan of completely locking yourself into a completely rigid inflexible grid if you need to
adjust things a bit here and there to match the design.
I say go for it.
In fact in my opinion that's one of the things that separates a good developer from a great developer.
We don't want our website to look like a program or created it.
We don't want things to feel overly rigid and locked in place.
We want it to feel like a designer created it and sometimes that means going the extra mile to customize
things.
All right.
So let's jump back to the browser and continue to make improvements.
So the next thing that I want to address is the max width value that we gave to our wrapper element.
So in our text editor in our wrapper CSSA file several lessons ago we gave this element a max width
of twelve hundred pixels.
Now since then we applied box sizing border box globally to all elements on the page.
And when we did that we actually decreased the max width of this wrapper element by 36 pixels.
Right so that's the padding left plus the padding right.
So to keep up our attention to detail what's account for that change and what's add 36 pixels to this
max width value.
So let's say this so we saw that that was a subtle change but it gave our design a little bit extra
room to breathe.
All right.
I think our next task should be to make this image responsive.
So this cropping and aspect ratio worked well for this.
To call them lay out on a large screen.
But if we look at a small screen or mobile device I think it would look better if this image wasn't
as tall.
I think it would look better if it was landscape instead of portrait.
So over in our HDMI.
Let's find that image.
Here it is.
And let's actually just delete this image line and start fresh with a picture element within the picture
element.
Let's begin with the smallest image first.
So we'll just use the traditional image element will say image source look inside our assets folder
and then the images folder.
And let's actually pull open that folder to see which images we can choose from.
So here is the travel site app assets images.
So we're looking for a file that begins with our start.
So here is our start slash landscape so let's type our start landscape.
Jay peg and let's give this image an alt value of our founder Jane Doe.
All right so let's say this and check out the browser.
I think that looks a lot better on smartphones.
However on larger screens it definitely looks odd.
To fix that within our picture element we can just add a new source element and create a media query
that says if a screen is larger than 800 pixels use a different image source.
So then we can just say or set assets images our star got dot pig.
Let's save that.
So now the image looks great on large screens and on tiny screens.
But what about medium sized screens.
So for example if I shrink this browser window a bit we see the column start shrinking to fit within
the browser with and things start to look a bit awkward are single column lead doesn't kick in until
there.
So for this screen size the image aspect ratio looks a bit odd on a medium sized screen like this.
I think it would look nice if the image was narrower and taller and if we look in our images folder
we see a file named our start portrait which just happens to be cropped that way.
So in each T.M. home.
Let's go ahead and duplicate this source line that we just created.
And within the top source element let's change its media query to be 1020 pixels and we will leave that
source to continue pointing towards this image.
However on this second source element let's change that file to the our star portrait that J.
Peg and we will leave this media query at 800 pixels.
So if we save this and check out the browser we see the new portrait image that is narrower and taller.
And if we make our screen a bit larger here we see the traditional image and we still receive the landscape
image on mobile screens.
So this responsive image is almost complete.
The one final thing that I want to do is add high DPMI copies for each cropping.
So let's start on this top source and work our way down.
We can just select the name of the file in the path to the file and copy it and then add a comma and
paste it in.
And right before the dot J page just add.
Hi DPMI.
You will remember that I've created IDBI copies for all of our images in the image folder and if we
remember back to our responsive images lesson we need to tell the browser the size of each of these
images so it knows which one to use.
So this regular image has a width of 404 pixels so we say 404 w.
And the Hy-Vee API copy is double that 808.
Now you might think that we are done with this source element but we're not.
I have a bit of a confession back in our original responsive image lesson.
I was able to oversimplify things a bit because I knew that the image we were dealing with back in that
lesson we were dealing with this image.
I knew that it was always going to be full browser window with.
However the image that we are currently dealing with this image is only full browser window with on
small tiny devices.
Why does this matter.
Well before I tried to explain it in words let me just show you visually.
So if we add the dash I to both these images and save we see that this is the Heidy API copy 808 pixels
wide.
However I am not using a Heidy monitor so I only want to have to download the image that is 404 pixels
So why is the browser trying to send me the high API copy.
The answer is because web browsers.
Unless we tell them otherwise assume that all responsive images need to take up the entire browser window
width so if Google Chrome thinks that this image needs to be this wide it's obviously going to reach
for the largest copy of the image.
It's up to us as the developer to tell the web browser Hey Chrome this particular source of the image
is never going to display larger than 404 pixels.
Thanks to RC SS Right the web browser is not intelligent enough to figure that out on its own.
We can tell the web browser what size the image will be rendered at.
By doing this in our HTL on this source element we can simply say sizes equals 404 pixels.
So let's save this and check out the browser.
Now we still see the Heidy API copy but that's because Chrome has that copy cached so behind the scenes
really quickly let me clear my cache.
All right so now we are using the standard image.
Next let's add a hide the API copy for the next source of the image.
This source is used for screens that are a bit smaller.
Like this for example.
So we can just copy and paste the file name and file path a comma pasted in and right before the dot
J page.
Hi DPMI.
Next we want to tell the browser the size of each of these images.
So the standard copy is 382 pixels wide.
So W in the hi DP I copy is double the 764 for testing purposes why don't we go ahead and add the dash
II to the end of both filenames so we can easily see which copy is being used in the browser.
And we see that the high API copy is being used.
So practice makes perfect.
We need to tell the browser that this image is not going to be displayed at the full width of the browser
window.
So we need to find out what is the widest that this source of the image will ever need to be displayed
at.
So let's resize our browser window to right before this break point occurs.
Which is right about here.
And let's measure this image so thanks to our CSSA column grid laya.
It looks to me like this source of the image will never need to be wider than about 320 pixels.
So over in our HVM melt on this source we can simply say sizes equals 320 pixels.
Save that.
And if I clear my cache we see the standard copy of the image which makes sense from my monitor's DPMI.
All right.
Next let's move on to adding the Heidy API copy for this crop.
So the first thing we want to do is change this from source to source set so we can add on an additional
image.
So let's copy this Atacama paste and then right for the DOT JPEG add.
Hi DPA.
Let's tell the browser the sizes of both these images.
So the standard copy is 100 pixels wide.
The Heidi API copy is double that at sixteen hundred.
Let's say this and check out the browser.
We don't need to worry about the sizes attribute on this crop of the image because this crop is only
used when the layout collapses to a single column view which means in this instance it's OK that the
browser assumes that the image needs to take up the full width of the browser.
All right.
So we have completed this responsive image really quickly.
Let's move on and make this image responsive.
So back in our HMO we look up just a few lines.
We see that image here.
And if we look in our projects image folder the name of this image is first trip so it looks like we
have a standard version A Heidi API version and a low res version for smaller screens and all three
of these are cropped exactly the same.
They are just different resolutions.
So in our HMO we do not need the picture element because we only need to switch resolutions.
So let's change this from a source to a source set and let's copy and paste the path to the image a
few times.
Comma paste comma paste.
Let's change this first file to the low rez copy.
It has a width of 565.
We can leave this next file name untouched.
But we can specify that it's width is 976 and what's changed.
This third mention of the image to first trip.
Hi GPI.
And it has a width of 1952.
Let's go ahead and add the dash I before the dot J page to all three image files so we can clearly see
in the browser which one is being used.
Let's save this.
Check out the browser.
So far these are the image sizes that I would expect to see.
But if I make this browser window larger we see that even though my monitor is not high API I'm being
served the high DPMI copy.
We know how to address this within this image element.
We can simply give it the size attribute and let the browser know that this image needs to be about
976 pixels wide instead of full screen.
And if I clear my cache we now see the standard version of the image.
However if we look at things on a smartphone we see that the sizes attribute we just added forces even
tiny smart phones to download the medium sized image instead of the low rez copy.
This is because this code is telling the browser that all screen sizes need to display the image at
this size and this is not what we want.
So instead check this out.
We can add a media query and we can say only for screens that are 970 pixels or larger.
Does the image need to be 976 pixels comma otherwise for screens that are smaller than this.
The image just needs to be 100 percent of the device with 100 VW which stands for viewport width.
So for example if a small screen is only 360 pixels wide.
This is our way of saying that this image only needs to be 360 pixels wide.
So if we save this and clear our cash we see that the low rez copy is successfully being sent to small
screens which means this responsive image is now complete and that's actually going to bring.
Part 1 of this two part lesson to a close in part two.
We will work on fine tuning the type Griffy for this content.
Let's keep rolling along and I will see you in part 2.