Hello everyone.
In this video we are going to pick up right where we left off.
We just have a few more details to take care of in terms of improving the performance or efficiency
of our Reveal on scroll feature.
Right now let's set things up so that if you're nowhere near an item that needs to be revealed.
So if I'm way up at the top of the page here and an item that needs to be revealed if it's top edge
has not even crossed the bottom edge of the browser's viewport yet.
Well if that hasn't happened yet then let's not bother wasting resources calculating anything else.
Let me show you what I mean.
Back in our text editor.
Find your calculator if scroll to method.
And I want you to select or highlight the entire contents of this method.
I want us to go ahead and cut this into our clipboard.
So right now we've just got a completely empty calculated scroll to method and in the body of it.
Let's set up an if statement.
So if parentheses curly brackets for the condition let's say only if window dot scroll y.
So this is measured in pixels and it's how far down you've scrolled from the very top of the page.
Only if that plus window dot inner height.
Only if these two combined are greater than the current elements top edge and we're talking about its
top edge not in relation to the viewport but in relation to the total page height.
So we would not use get bounding client rect here.
Instead we can just say element offset top.
So only if this is true then in the if curly brackets just paste back in your clipboard OK.
Let's go ahead and save this and then back in the browser.
Be sure to manually refresh now notice as I'm scrolling.
We do see scroll function ran but we don't see any element was calculated messages.
However once we scroll to the point where the top edge of an element has crossed the very bottom threshold
of the browser but is not up high enough to actually be revealed yet.
Well once that happens then you can see we are calculating if it should be revealed or not.
Right.
We see these element was calculated messages so we can continue to scroll until it's revealed perfect
at this point we only have one more efficiency improvement that I want to make back in our text editor.
I want to draw your attention to window dot inner height so this measures the height of the current
browser viewport in pixels at this point.
Not only are we using it twice within this function but remember this function runs every time we calculate
an individual item.
So it's probably not the most efficient thing to continually ask the browser how tall are you how tall
are you how tall are you right.
Instead we can save its answer in memory with one of our own properties.
So here's what I would do up at the very top of our file within our constructor.
I would just add a new line let's say this stock browser height and I would just set it to equal window
dot inner height.
Now down in our calculate curve we can just reference our property here.
This way we're not continually asking the browser or the DOM for that extra little bit of information
to back down in calculating scrolled to.
Let's replace this first instance of window dot inner height instead with this dot browser typed.
And then here as well let's replace window to enter height with this dot browser.
Right.
Let's go ahead and save this.
I will refresh in the browser let's test to make sure things are still working.
So things still work properly.
However now that we're not asking the browser for its height in real time if I refresh and then make
the browser window a lot shorter you'll notice that our calculations should be off yes see other items
are already revealed we can easily get around this issue.
So if we're going to reference our property instead of actually asking the browser for its height we
just need to babysit this property a bit.
Let me show you what I would do within our events method.
Let's just set up a new event that listens for when the browser window gets resized.
So after this line within our events method I would just say window dot ad event listener type of event
that we're listening for is resize comma.
Now we could include an anonymous or aero function right here.
However I do want to let you know that as you resize your web browser window your web browser is not
very efficient about it.
It's going to fire this resize event many many times every web browser is slightly different but it
seems like it almost calls it every pixel or every few milliseconds as you're dragging and resizing.
This is not what we want right.
We really only need to update our browser height value at the end of your resizing action.
Just that one time.
So luckily load dash can save the day here.
Now instead of using throttle we're going to use a load Ash tool named D bounce up at the very top of
our file.
Do this with me say import D bounce from quotes and then it's in the low dash library slash D bounce.
So what in the world is d bounce.
It's similar to throttle but there's an important difference.
So with throttle we wanted to run our function every 200 milliseconds continually right.
As we're scrolling so throttling makes sense for scrolling.
However when we are resizing the browser window we don't need to do anything during the middle of this
action.
We only need to do something once after we've finally stopped resizing so that's what D bounce lets
us do.
We can give it a value maybe 200 milliseconds or 300 milliseconds and the browser is only going to call
our function once.
After that many milliseconds have passed from your last iteration of performing that.
So if I'm resizing I'm resizing and then I stop.
But I only wait 50 milliseconds and keep resizing the browser is not going to actually call our function
r d bounced function until you stop resizing and wait that many milliseconds.
This is excellent for performance.
So within our events method for resize for the second argument let's just say D bounce parentheses to
call it.
We're gonna give it to arguments for the first argument let's give it an arrow function so parentheses
arrow symbol curly brackets let's drop down just as a test we can say console dot log resize just ran.
So that's just for testing purposes.
What we actually want to do is babysit this browser hype property so we can just say this dot browser
height equals and we just want to update it so we can grab window dot inner height.
OK.
This is important after this closing curly bracket here for our arrow function we need to add a comma
right because we want to give the balance a second argument.
This is how many milliseconds we want to wait.
Totally up to you.
But why don't we wait.
Three hundred and thirty three milliseconds.
So let's go ahead and save this.
And now back in the browser I will refresh.
Now as I'm resizing my browser if I never stop resizing if I just continue resizing it nothing ever
happens I'm not fast enough but if I stopped resizing for only 50 milliseconds nothing would happen
but if I actually stopped resizing and then wait three hundred and thirty three milliseconds perfect
only then do we see in the console resize just ran.
So this way I can start out with the browser windows super small let me refresh but if I resize it
and then test out our reveal and scroll functionality you can see our calculations are still correct.
Only now we're not bothering to ask the browser for its height.
Over and over and over again.
Now before we switch gears and learn how to make our Reveal on scroll module recyclable so that we can
use it on our testimonials as well.
I first want to mention that technically we could improve the efficiency of our Reveal feature even
further by storing our elements top offset in memory right.
Instead of asking the browser for their position each and every scroll.
However we would need to do quite a bit of babysitting of those values.
For example if any javascript added new content to the page well that could push everything down further
and then we would need to update their offset values or if we lazy loaded in images or if anything happened
that changed the height of the page and pushed things down.
You would need to continually babysit these values.
So yes you could improve performance even further.
The idea is anytime you can avoid asking the browser for fresh data that's a performance win.
But in this case I think that would require a lot of attention to detail to make sure that the offsets
were always updated and correct.
So overall I am happy with our current setup and its performance and efficiency OK.
At this point let's go ahead and make our review module recyclable and apply it to these testimonials
as well.
Right so we would want them to be invisible and then maybe once you scroll down this far then they would
gradually fade into view.
Let me show you how I would set that up.
So back in our text editor.
Currently we are in our Reveal on scroll file but I want you to jump into our main app dot J S file.
Write the file that imports all of our other files.
So this is where we import the reveal on scroll class and then we've created a new instance of it.
Well let's actually create two new instances.
You could make a new variable names but in this case we don't need to store this in a variable so we
can get rid of the equal sign in the left hand side like this.
So let's create one new instance of the reveal on scroll class and in these parentheses.
Let's give it a dom selector.
Let's give it a selector that selects these feature items and then we can create another new instance
of that same class and give it a selector that selects these.
Then we just need to go into the class and make it flexible.
Let me show you what I'm talking about.
So within these parentheses I would say document dot query selector.
All quotes and then select the class.
So a dot of feature item.
Okay.
And then let's just copy and paste and duplicate this line of code.
And then on this copy we want the CSF selector that would grab these three testimonial boxes.
So just change the selector to dot testimonial.
Okay let's go ahead and save this file and now we just need to go into our Reveal on scroll module and
in the constructor constructor has parentheses where we can have a parameter to receive that incoming
argument we can name our parameter anything but let's name it ls short for elements.
Okay then our first line in the constructor items to reveal instead of setting this to equal a selector.
This is where we would just set it to equal that parameter.
The incoming argument value let's go ahead and save this and then back in the browser
our feature still work and now the testimonials work while we're at it let's make our module even more
flexible.
So down here within our calculate if scrolled to method remember we set the threshold to seventy five.
To refresh your memory we can think of this number as a percentage and it means that once an element
has been scrolled to so it crosses the bottom 25 percent of the browser viewport well that's when the
element should begin to fade or appear in.
So if you set it to 60 percent then the element wouldn't appear until you'd scrolled to maybe right
here.
Obviously if you set it to 50 percent then you would have to scroll an element halfway through your
viewport height.
So let's do this.
Let's set things up so that back in app dot J.S. you could give 1 threshold number to feature item and
then another threshold for testimonials.
So on this first line for feature items in between the two closing parentheses you can add a comma and
we can just have a second argument.
So let's say for feature items we want it to be 75 but for testimonials maybe we want it to be 60.
Let's save this and then back in reveal on scroll up in the constructor.
We can just add a second parameter so comma after ls and then let's call it thresh hold percent.
OK.
Then within the body of the constructor let's save that as a property.
This dot threshold percent equals the incoming value.
So just thresh hold percent.
Okay.
And then down within our calculate if scrolled to method just remove the hardcoded 75 with this dot
threshold.
Percent let's save this.
I will perform a manual refresh.
Okay.
So now the feature item should still fade in at the same time as before but testimonials should wait
a little bit longer as you scroll to become visible.
Cool.
Hopefully at this point if we jump back into app dot J.S. you can see the benefit of creating a reusable
class a blueprint.
It allows you to set up your logic and functionality once but then you can leverage it multiple times
and in different ways in different situations.
Cool.
Now before we bring this lesson to a close I do want to add one CSX effect.
So instead of just fading in the opacity I think it would be cool if the elements sort of zoomed in
or zoomed out right.
If they sort of changed their size or scale as they faded into view.
So let me show you how I would set that up.
All we need to do is jump into our SS file that is named revealed dash item dot c SS and within the
baseline styles here lets out a new property named transform and say that the scale should be 1 point
1 5 by default.
But then once an element is visible we can set it back to its natural size of just one transform scale
1 and then to make sure that that value actually animates or transitions on this line we can just add
a comma before the ending semicolon and say we also want to transition v transform property over the
course of one and a half seconds and E's apt cool if you need to pause the video to type this out that's
OK but let's go ahead and save this.
And then again I will perform a manual refresh so that elements can fade in again.
And let's test it out.
Cool.
Notice how they start out a bit larger and then they sort of zoom out into view.
I think that looks nice and that's actually going to bring this lesson to a close.
Looking ahead to our next lesson we will be changing gears a bit.
We will be making a few enhancements to our header for larger screens right now.
I will overlay footage of the finished product so you can see what I have in mind.
But basically we will learn how to make our header bar sticky for desktop users and we will also learn
how to highlight links in the header to correspond with the current section that is scrolled to and
in view.
These features should be a lot of fun to set up.
Let's keep rolling along and I will see you in the next lesson.