Welcome back everyone.
In part three of this three part lesson we will pick up right where we left off in part two.
Let's dive in and get right back to the action.
So at this point our testimonials section is complete both for large and small screens.
But what about medium sized screens.
So for example if I make my browser window smaller the layout still looks good.
Even now it still looks good.
But eventually there just won't be enough horizontal space for this three column layout to fit comfortably.
Now if I keep shrinking the window eventually we will see it switch to a single column view but the
question is Where is that breakpoint occurring.
Currently we have set up the testimonial section to only apply a three column layout if a screen is
large enough to be considered medium.
Now in my opinion this does not look good.
These columns are too narrow and there just isn't enough space for three of them to fit comfortably.
So I think instead of applying this layout for screens that are medium or larger I think we should only
apply the three column layout for screens that we consider large or larger.
Now when I use those keywords of medium and large let me refresh your memory in terms of what I'm actually
referring to.
So in our text editor within app assets styles and then the base folder go ahead and open mix ins dot
CSX.
So many lessons ago we created these three mix ins at small at medium and at large and currently the
testimonial section is using the medium breakpoint which is 800 pixels.
And it turns out that that just isn't wide enough to comfortably fit three columns.
So let's adjust the testimonial section to not implement a three column layout until these large break
point.
And I think that twelve hundred might actually be overkill.
Let's adjust this to 1010 pixels.
Let's save this file and then jump over to our h t demo and within our testimonial section let's begin
adjusting these medium breakpoints to use large instead.
So on the main testimonials div let's change this modifier.
Class that says no bottom padding until medium.
Let's change that too until large.
And let's go into the page section CSX file to create a new modifier that targets the large breakpoint.
So page section CSX.
Now we don't want to delete or replace this medium rule because even though we want to use large in
this particular instance there might be another section or another page in the future where we will
want to use this medium breakpoint.
So let's leave this intact but let's copy and paste it.
And then within this new copy let's change this to large and let's change the media query to at large.
All right let's save that and jump back to our HDMI out.
The next instance of medium is on the wrapper div no padding until medium.
Let's change that to large and let's jump into the wrapper CSX file to create the large version of this
rule.
Now again we don't want to delete or replace this medium version.
We want to leave it intact in case we need it in the future.
But let's go ahead and copy and paste it.
All right.
And within this duplicated copy what's changed this to large and change the breakpoint to at large.
Let's save that and jump back to our H2 CML file.
The next instance of the medium breakpoint is on the row element.
So let's change this row equal height at medium to large and then let's jump into our road CSX file
the equal height rules or at the very bottom.
So let's scroll down.
Let's go ahead and copy and paste this.
And then within the new copy.
Change this to at large and change the mix in breakpoint to large as well.
Save this jumped back to our H TMI file.
All right.
Now the only remaining instances of the medium breakpoint are the classes that we added to each of the
three columns.
So on these three column divs let's just change this to large.
So that's the first column.
Here's the second column and here's the third column.
Now let's jump back into our row CSX file to make sure that this new class name exists so if we scroll
up a bit
this at medium media query contains all of our different call them widths for example medium for takes
up a third of the width.
Medium 6 takes up half of the width we can actually just go ahead and copy and paste this entire at
medium media query in all of its contents.
So let's begin here.
And let's copy all the way down to here and then just paste it to create a duplicate.
And then on this duplicate copy let's change the media query to at large and then within all of these
class names let's just change them to large.
I'm going to copy the word large into my clipboard so I don't have to keep typing it.
So let's change that
here.
Scroll down a bit to change this and this.
Now if we save this file and check out the browser we see a three column layout because our screen is
quite large but if we shrink the screen
it looks like we forgot to change one of the breakpoints in our testimonial block.
So really quickly in testimonial that CSX let's change this breakpoint to at large let's also change
our page section rule so that this background image isn't used until the large break point.
So within page section dot CSX we scroll down a bit here is the testimonials modifier.
Let's change this breakpoint to at large.
Perfect.
So now our testimonial section uses a single column layout for small screens.
And it doesn't use a three column layout until our screen becomes quite large.
So we see there's the threshold there is the break point.
This is the narrowest that the three columns will ever be.
And I can live with this.
That means that our testimonial section is now complete for every screen size.
Good job.
Go ahead and give yourself a pat on the back.
But before we bring this lesson to a close.
There are just a few more things that I want to take care of.
So first why don't we add in hi DP.
Copies for each of the three testimonial images.
And once we've done that let's go ahead and merge this branch back into master.
So let's get started on adding the high DP copies.
Let's jump into our HDMI file.
Let's find the first column.
Here it is.
Here is the image.
Let's begin by giving it an all to value.
We can simply use the person's name Jane Doe.
All right.
So let's begin by changing the source attribute to source set.
And after we list this first image let's add a comma and then we can just copy and paste the path to
the image.
And on this duplicate copy at the very end before dot j peg just add high DP.
Now we want to tell the browser the size of each of these images so it knows which one to choose based
on the devices screen size and pixel density for the base image has a width of 160 and the high DP copy
is double that at three hundred and twenty.
And remember that by default web browsers assume that responsive images need to take up the entire browser
window width.
We need to manually tell the browser that this image will only ever need to display at a maximum width
of one hundred and sixty pixels so we can use the sizes attribute and specify one hundred and sixty
pixels.
All right let's go ahead and do the same thing for the other two images.
So here's the image in the second column.
Let's give it an all to value.
John Smith.
Change source to source set.
That's duplicate this path to the image comma separating the two.
The first image is one hundred and sixty pixels wide.
Let's change this second image to end in dash.
Hi DPA.
And it is three hundred and twenty pixels wide.
And we also want to tell the browser that it only needs the display at one hundred and sixty pixels.
Let's do the same thing for the third image.
Give it an all value Cat kitty.
Change source to source said let's duplicate this image.
The second copy should use dash Heidi API.
First copy is one hundred and sixty pixels why the second copy is three hundred and twenty pixels wide
and tell the browser that it only needs to be displayed at 160 pixels.
Now before we save this we can make sure that things are set up correctly by adding a dash eye at the
end of both of these.
Let's save this and we see 160 by 160 which is what I would expect because I am using a normal monitor
instead of a high DP or high pixel density screen.
Perfect.
We can go ahead and get rid of that dash eye on both instances
and we have now 100 percent completed this section now because the testimonial section is no longer
a work in progress.
We can now merge the testimonials branch into master.
So let's go ahead and jump over to the command line.
Let's run a get status to see what has changed all of these changes look good to me.
So I'm going to add everything to the staging area get add dash uppercase a.
I'm ready to go ahead and commit things so get commit.
Let's add a message completed the testimonials section.
All right.
So now that we made a commit those testimonial changes are safe.
Been locked away and it gets history.
We can now go ahead and check out the master branch or switch back to the master branch so get check
out master.
And now back in the browser if I refresh while my web pack task is still running in a different command
line we will see that none of our testimonial changes are in place because they only live in the testimonials
branch and we are currently on the master branch.
Let's go ahead and merge the testimonials branch into the master branch get merge and then the name
of the branch we want to merge in testimonials.
All right.
So we still have the master branch checked out but if I check the browser now our testimonial changes
are in place and we're in business.
Now just in case my computer blows up I want all of this code to be safe.
So I'm going to push this up to get hub.
So to push our master branch we can just say get push origin master.
All right.
Now get hub servers have the latest copy of my project.
We can let out a sigh of relief and we have officially completed the testimonials feature in our next
lesson.
We'll change gears and begin styling the footer of our Web site.
Let's keep our momentum rolling and I will see you in the next lesson.