Hello everyone.
Welcome to part two of our two part lesson on attention to detail.
Let's pick up right where we left off and get straight to the action in part 2.
Let's fine tune this type polygraphy So the first thing that I would like to adjust is removing this
vertical gap at the top of this column.
If we look at our design file we see that the top of this heading should be aligned with the top of
this image.
Now back in the browser this vertical gap is being created by the top margin on this headline.
So let's go ahead and find this headline in our H.T. email so we can add a modifier class to it.
We can find this element by searching for how we got started in our text editor within an hour each
TNL file command for control of how we got started.
All right.
So here is that element.
Let's go ahead and give it a modifier.
Class of headline dash dash.
No T for top margin but save that.
And then within our modules CSSA folder.
Let's open up head blind us CSX.
But scroll to the bottom and create a new modifier rule no t margin.
And then we can just say margin top zero.
So let's save this.
And check out the browser.
I think that looks a lot better.
Next let's focus on fine tuning the typographic for these paragraphs.
So if we compare what we see here in the browser to our design file we see that there is quite a bit
of difference.
So let's go ahead and find these paragraphs in our H.T. IMO.
Here they are and we need a way to target these elements with our CSX.
Now so far in the course we've more or less been following the Bamm methodology and the best way of
doing things would be to create a new class and to add it to each of these three paragraphs.
However this is one instance where Personally I completely disagree with Ben when it comes to something
as generic and repeatable as a paragraph.
I don't want to have to apply a class to each and every one of them because it's really common on a
Web site to have a block of text that might have five 10 20 or even 30 paragraphs.
So in this specific instance let's forget about doing things the Benway and let's do this let's wrap
the heading in these three paragraphs in a new div so each two and these three paragraphs Let's cut
this into a clipboard and let's create a new div with a class of generic content container and then
within that new div go ahead and paste back in that content.
Now technically we could have added this class name to this existing column div but from a philosophical
standpoint in the future there might be some other type of content in this column content that we don't
want to be affected by our generic content container styles.
So by setting up a new div for this class we are keeping our column flexible and future proof.
All right but let's not split hairs.
Our next bit of business is to create a new CSSA file for this new class name.
So within our modules CSSA folder.
Let's create a new file.
Let's name it underscore generic content container.
CSX was created rule generic content container.
Let's go ahead and save this file.
And before we forget let's go into our main styles does CSSA file and import this new file import modules
underscore generic content container.
And then let's jump back to that new CSSA file and let's create a rule that selects any paragraph elements
that are nested within this element.
All right.
And how do we want to style those paragraphs.
Well if we look at our design file this looks like a larger than normal line height meaning there's
more space in between each line.
So let's say line high.
One point six five line height is one of the few properties that doesn't require a unit of measurement.
So we don't need to say pixels or REM.
You can just include this number and hit save.
I think that looks a lot better.
Let's also give these paragraphs a slightly larger font size.
So currently they're using the browser default which is 16 pixels.
Why don't we go ahead and bump them up to 18 pixels.
But we want to specify that in terms of REM so we can just say 18 divided by 16 let's copy that to our
clipboard paste it in and then say REM looks good next.
I think we should increase the margin between the paragraphs.
So let's say margin let's bump up the vertical margin to 1.8 RAM and have the horizontal margins stay
at zero.
I think that extra bit of space looks good.
If we compare this with our design file the next thing that I see is that links within a paragraph should
be bold.
So for example this element.
So in our CSX we could nest a rule within this rule and select any link elements like this.
But personally I don't like to nest more than one layer deep in my CSX.
So instead I will do this I'll create a new rule and create a descendant selector like this.
So any links that live within a paragraph within this class should use a bold font weight.
So let's go with the font weight of 700.
By the way a font weight of 400 is considered normal or standard.
So if I want something to be extra bold we can go with 700.
That looks better.
And we also saw in the design file that the link should be orange.
Now instead of defining that orange color within this rule I think we are safe to actually define it
globally as a fallback for all links on the page.
So within our CSSA base folder Let's go ahead and open up a global dossier.
Let's create a new rule that targets all links on the page and gives them a color of our main orange
variable.
All right so I'm not seeing that change take place.
I'm going to check the command line to see if something went wrong.
And it looks like we have an error message that main orange is undefined.
This is because in our main styles does CSSA file we are importing the global file before we've imported
the variables file.
And this is where the main orange value lives.
So to fix the error.
Let's just go ahead and cut the global line and move it after variables and mix in.
So pasted in here.
Go ahead and save that.
And we're back in business.
Now you might be curious as to why I chose to set up all links on the page globally to be orange.
But when it came to making this link bold we defined that only within our generic content container
rule.
Well my thought process behind that is that I know for a fact we are never ever ever going to want to
use the web browser default color of blue for any link on the page.
So setting a baseline link color of orange doesn't feel like it's hurting us in any way because that
default shade of blue was never going to be used anyways.
But when it comes to font weight there are plenty of links on the page that shouldn't be bold.
So we want to leave that browser default of links being not bold intact.
This will save us extra work later on we won't have to tell the links in the header to not be bold.
They just won't be bold because that's the browser default.
All right so I promise I will end this tangent soon.
But the point that I'm trying to drive home here is that I want you to be very selective over what makes
the cut into your global CSSA file.
We don't want to make the mistake of polluting our global CSSA scope which is really one of the big
ideas behind the big methodology.
So the reason that the Benway would have had us out of class to each individual one of these paragraphs
is because styling elements directly like that avoids descendant selectors or generic type selectors
which really just means we are trying to avoid the cascade from surprising us or drowning us in 12 layers
of inheritance and overrides and specificity wars.
So we did go against the philosophy of bit by setting up this generic content container and using descendant
type selectors but in our defense we did keep the style scoped to this class and we will only apply
this class to elements if we are OK with all of their descendants being styled a specific way.
My personal rule of thumb is that if a piece of content looks like it might have been copied and pasted
from a word doc or if down the road our Web site is powered by a content management system or a blog
platform.
We can't expect every element of the content to be output with a class on it.
So basically for unique parts of our page where we as the developer are writing the HMO.
Sure.
Let's go ahead and add classes to each element.
The Benway but four sections where the content is a bit more generic and streamlined and might come
from automated sources.
I think it's OK to use a setup like we have here.
All right.
So tangent officially over.
Let's jump back to the browser.
We've completed our fine tuning of the typography for this section.
But before we bring this lesson to a close let's see what things look like on a small screen.
Let me scroll up a bit.
All right so the first thing that I see is that we should probably add a bit of vertical margin for
small screens between this image and this heading.
This is an interesting situation because on larger screens we definitely do not need to add bottom margin
to this image but because our two call them lay up stacks to single call them on smaller screens.
We do want to add a bit of bottom margin here.
So here's how I would handle that situation over in our HMO.
Let's find that first column where that image lives.
Here it is.
I would just add an extra class to this first column let's call it row underscore underscore B for bottom
margin until medium.
Let's say this.
And then within our modules CSSA folder.
Let's open up road of CSX right above this line that uses the media equerry mixin.
Let's create a new rule that targets our new class name.
So it was underscore underscore be Marjan until medium.
So my thinking with this class name is that when a screen is really small Let's give it bottom margin.
So margin bottom go with one rim until medium.
So at this margin until a screen is large enough to be considered medium.
So now within this media inquiry Mixon that is targeting medium sized screens we can just say this class
name that we just created.
Copy that paste it in margin bottom should be reset to zero.
So let's save this perfect.
So now we have a bit of vertical spacing on small screens and we didn't create any unnecessary spacing
on larger screens.
I think the only other thing that I would change for small screens is that the font size for our generic
content container paragraphs looks a little bit large.
So why don't we do this in our generic content container file.
Why don't we take this font size cut it to our clipboard and use a media or a mix in say mix in at small
once the screen is large enough to be considered small instead of tiny or microscopic.
Go ahead and use that size.
And our baseline style doesn't even need a font size at all because it will just default to one REM.
So let's save that.
And I think that looks a bit better on mobile.
All right so I think that concludes our fine tuning of this type holography on a random note.
Behind the scenes I'm going to remove the dash I from all of these images just so things look a bit
better during these lessons.
I won't bore you by filming that but I encourage you to remove the dash eyes as well.
Or you can always just download the source code that is included in each lesson referencing those files
can be a great tool if you get a bit off track.
All right so I just took care of that.
One other thing that I want to point out is that in an earlier lesson for one of our images I forgot
to include a W after I specified how white it is.
So let's add that up.
You can find the specific image that I'm referring to by running a command F or control f and searching
for our star landscape.
And this was on the Heidy API copy and that will bring this lesson to a close in the next section of
our course.
We will take a good time out.
We're going to learn about one of the most powerful features of get and that is branches.
We will learn what get branches are and how to begin using them because we are going to leverage branches
as we begin to work on the next section of our site.
The our features section and don't worry styling This section will not be as tedious as it was to style
this section.
I'm fully aware that the last several lessons where we've been styling this content probably weren't
the most exciting lessons in the world but the good news is that we made it through and in the process.
I feel like we've taken our CSSA organization skills to the next level and now you and I speak some
of the same language and think some of the same thoughts in terms of how CSSA should be structured.
So that means that when it comes time to style the remaining sections of the site I think things will
feel a bit easier a bit more natural.
Not to mention all of the reusable blocks we've created so far that we can continue to leverage again
and again.
So I'm excited to jump into the next section with you.
This is definitely one of the times in the course where I feel like we are shifting into a higher gear.
It's going to be a lot of fun let's keep rolling along and I will see you in the next lesson.