Hello everyone.
In this lesson on gift you will finally get your hands dirty.
This is the lesson where I want you to start following along step by step on your computer.
We are going to do a few things in this lesson.
Number one I will help you make sure that gate is installed on your computer.
Number two I will help you find the command line on your computer.
Yes I do actually want you to use the command line.
That program that reminds you of computers from the 80s using the command line will give you a stronger
understanding of how it works.
A lot of jobs will expect or even require you to use get from the command line and a lot of the other
technologies that we will be learning about in this course.
Things like node NPM web pack all of these things use the command line as well.
Now there's nothing to be afraid of the command line is way less intimidating than it might seem at
first.
And we are going to get our feet wet and walk through things step by step together.
And number three we will try out a few get commands together.
All right let's get started.
Now this process of installing get and finding the command line is a bit different depending on whether
you are using a Windows based computer or if you're using a Mac.
Either way this lesson has got you covered.
Let's begin with the Windows side of things and then we'll hop over onto the Mac side.
If you are using a Mac you don't need to download anything so please ignore the following windows instructions.
So if you are running Windows open up a web browser and head over to get dash SVM dot com.
If you perform a Google search for simply get this should be the first result.
Here's what the Web site looks like and what you want to do is come down to this teal colored computer
and there will be a download button.
Now I'm on a Mac so it says downloads for Mac but on your computer it should say download for windows
or something similar to that.
Go ahead and begin the download.
And when it finishes open the installer file from here it's very self-explanatory so you can pause this
video right now and just click next.
Next Next through the installer all of the default options are a ok.
Once the installation is complete come back to this video and on posit OK.
Welcome back.
I will assume that if you're watching this part of the video you've installed get the next step is to
click onto your start menu or wherever your full list of programs is.
And look forget but more importantly I want you to look for the program named get bash.
This is the command line that I want you to use throughout this course.
So whenever you hear me say command line I want you to think get bash the Get Back program.
So right now go ahead and open the gate bash.
And once you've done that pat yourself on the back you have installed it and you have found a working
command line for all of you Windows users you can now skip ahead a bit in this video because right now
we are going to take a look at the Mac side of things.
OK so on your Mac you are looking for an application named Terminal One of the simplest ways to find
this app is to go in the top right corner of your screen and click the magnifying glass and then start
typing the word terminal.
Go ahead and hit enter or return and there's your command line.
Now your terminal might not look exactly like my terminal visually but rest assured you've got all of
the functionality that you need.
If you do want to customize the color scheme and appearance of your terminal check out the description
for this lesson I will include a link to a guide on that but let's not worry about appearances right
now.
Instead let's focus on making sure that gate is installed on your Mac.
There's a very good chance that it is already installed and to make sure.
Just type in this command at your command line.
Get dash dash version and hit enter as long as you see something along the lines of Get version to dot.
No no you are in business you're good to go.
If instead you get a response of command not found or Unknown command that means that gate is not installed
and you'll just want to go to the get dash SC and dot com Web site and just like we did for Windows
earlier you want to download gate for Mac.
So go ahead and pause this video if you need to install get on your Mac and then come back and resume
the video once you're good to go.
All right.
So at this point in the lesson now everyone watching whether you are on a Windows computer or a Mac
has get installed and you have opened the command line.
This means we are all on the same page.
We are all on even footing.
So now we can walk through a few get steps together.
All right let's begin by personalizing a few of your guest settings when get tracks your changes.
It also tracks who is making those changes.
So we want to let get know about your name and your e-mail.
So type this in.
Get config dash dash global user dot name and then quotes and you would type in your name but I'll type
in my name.
Hit enter next we want to do the exact same thing but with our email address instead of our name.
So the command is very similar.
Get config dash dash global user dot email and then just type in your email address your email address
dot com but you'd put in yours.
Hit enter.
All right.
So now your copy of get is all set up and ready to go.
Now we can have get actually do something.
So the first thing I want you to do is create a new folder on your computer somewhere.
Can be anywhere can be on your desktop or folder of your choosing.
But I want you to name this new folder something generic like projects or sites once you've created
a new folder.
Our next step is to navigate to that folder from within the command line the command line is always
working in or pointing towards a directory or folder on your computer.
And we can change where your command line is pointing very freely.
We can see where the command line is currently pointing towards by typing P WD this means print the
working directory.
So it looks like my command line is currently pointing towards the user's Brad directory.
But I want it to be pointing towards this new sites folder we just created.
So what I'm going to do is type C D this stands for change directory and then I enter the space and
instead of trying to type out the location for this folder what you can do is actually just drag the
folder that you just created a moment ago on top of your command line.
I will hit enter and now I can try P WD again to print the current working directory.
You don't have to run P.W. D I do it just to make sure I'm in the right place which I am.
All right.
So once you've navigated your command line to the folder that you created just a moment ago we want
to create another folder for a particular imaginary project.
Now we can create a folder from the command line by typing M.K. Diaw stands for make directory space
quotes and then I'm going to title this new project.
Hello dash world hit enter.
OK so all that did is within the folder we created a moment ago it created a new folder named hello
world.
Let's begin.
An imaginary get repository within this hello world folder.
So first we want to navigate in to the hello world folder.
So to do that.
Seeds for change directory.
And then hello world.
Or another way of navigating to that hello world folder it would be the type C.D. space.
And then do what we did earlier which is just drag that hello world folder onto your command body.
So that's the same exact thing.
Now here is the moment of truth.
Here is what we've all been waiting for.
Let's tell get to begin tracking.
Anything that happens within this hello world folder or in other words let's create a brand new repository.
All we do once we've navigated to the folder that we like typing get in it stands for get initialize
hit enter.
And you've just created your first repo.
Let's test it out.
Let's make sure that it's tracking changes.
So let's create a super simple each TMM file.
We can actually create new empty files from the command line by typing touch and then the name of the
file that we want to create.
So let's try.
Touch index start each T.A. hit enter.
If we navigate to Hello world there it is.
So go ahead and open this new file with your favorite text editor.
We don't really need anything in this file but just to prove a point I will create an H1 and say hello
world.
Go ahead and hit save.
Now back in the command line if we type get status get tells us that I've made two changes to the folder.
This is a system file on Mac and we will learn in the future how to tell get to ignore that completely.
But we see that the only other file that's changed is the index that each team mail file that we just
created.
So we want to add this to the staging area so that we can commit it.
So I will type get add and then the name of the file that I want to add to the staging area.
So get add index that each team so we can try to get status again to see how things are looking changes
to be committed.
Yes.
This is the only thing that I want to commit.
So this staging area looks good.
So I will type get commit I will include a message my first commit hit enter and congratulations you
just made your first commit to a repo.
Now let's really drive home the point of why that's cool.
Which is because now no matter what happens to your files you can always revert to the way that files
were when you just made this comment.
So for example maybe your cat walks on your laptop and hit save.
Or maybe that file simply gets deleted entirely.
Now all we need to do to restore our files back to that comet or back to the last comment would be to
type.
Get check out dash dash space and then a period hit enter and that's all that it takes to restore the
files back to the way they were when we made our commit to index that each team ls back.
And it's without that line of cat gibberish at the bottom.
Excellent.
Okay now this lesson is almost complete but there's one small fun section at the very end here.
But before we get to it I want to recap what we've learned so far.
So far we've installed get on our computer.
We've opened the command line.
We learned how to navigate to a particular folder and create a brand new repo.
And we made our first commit now really quickly I want to point out that we created a brand new repo
from scratch.
And while that can be useful I think more often than not what you'll do instead is you'll want to clone
an existing repo from a server to your hard drive.
So for example let's imagine that you and I are co-workers and I've been working on a Web site and I
want you to help me so the website already exists so you wouldn't create a brand new repo.
Instead you would want to take the existing repo that already exists on a server somewhere and clone
it or copy it to your computer.
And that is exactly what we are going to do in this last section of the lesson.
It's super simple.
So back in the command line I want you to navigate to not the hello world folder but to the main sites
or projects folder that you created in the beginning of this lesson.
So I will take CDE space and then I will drag this site's folder onto my command line hit enter and
now we can pull down an existing repo with one command.
We just type get clone.
And then here's an address that you can type in H TTP s colon forward slash forward slash get hub dot
com forward slash learn web code forward slash welcome dash to dash get dot get hit enter
and now if you look within the sites or projects folder that you created in the beginning of the lesson
you will see a new folder named welcome to get you just clone this from the server.
So go ahead and try to open up the index dot h t AML file in your browser to do that you can just drag
this file on top of an open Chrome or Firefox or Internet Explorer or Safari window.
There will be a friendly surprise waiting for you and that's where this lesson will come to a close
in our next lesson.
I will help you create a free github account and we will get started on the real meat and potatoes of
this course we will begin building the mobile first Web site together and you will be able to commit
and push your progress at the end of every lesson up to your own personal GitHub repo.
It's gonna be a lot of fun.
This is where things really start to take off.
I will see you in the next lesson.