So what is AWS CodeDeploy?
CodeDeploy is a managed to AWS service that automates application
deployment to different AWS compute services.
With CodeDeploy, you can have multiple different deployment destinations.
You can deploy your code to things like Amazon EC2 virtual machines.
You can also send it to on‑premise instances,
for example,
if you have your own data centers that you'd like to
deploy your applications into.
Additionally,
you can deploy your code to AWS Lambda functions or
even to Amazon ECS and Fargate.
So what can you deploy throughout AWS?
Well, you can deploy your code.
You can deploy serverless functions, like we mentioned with Lambda.
You can also deploy configuration files or different kinds of packages,
even executables.
And if you're deploying things that require changes to media files,
you can deploy those, too.
So what are some of the benefits we get from using CodeDeploy?
Well, it can help us to automate our deployments,
and we can automate these deployments to multiple different locations,
like I discussed earlier, between Amazon EC2,
Lambda, and to other places.
We can also make customizations to each deployment,
so we don't have to have a single standard type of deployment.
But we can customize it based on where and when we want to deploy to,
as well as some of the conditions we want to deploy under.
For example, if we need to run a bunch of tests.
CodeDeploy will also help us improve the speed of our
deployments by minimizing or eliminating the downtime that our
services have when we're deploying them,
and also by allowing us to run concurrent deployments if we need
to deploy multiple things at the same time.
In addition to these benefits,
it will help us to avoid errors in our deployment process by standardizing
our deployments through a single deployment pipeline,
and also allowing us to configure different tests and rollbacks.
This will also help us to eliminate manual deployment errors
that might happen when you have an engineer deploying something
using buttons in the AWS console,
or maybe making manual configuration changes inside of a configuration file.
So with CodeDeploy, we can do a lot better.
Now,
there are a lot of other deployment tools that we could use in
AWS and throughout our development process.
CodeDeploy will really help us in a specific
scenario when we're deploying to EC2, on‑premises locations,
with AWS Lambda, or with ECS and Fargate.
However, if we want to use something to deploy other pieces of infrastructure,
we might rely on something like CloudFormation or the AWS Cloud
Development Kit to help us deploy pieces of infrastructure that
don't fall into this category.
For example,
particular AWS cloud resources or configuration
changes to those resources. Now also,
if we wanted to use other tools like AWS's CodePipeline,
which we'll look at in the next module,
this will help us build more complex build pipelines with discrete steps.
Whereas CodeDeploy will help us in very niche use cases,
deploying to particular compute services.
So hopefully this helps clarify where all these different services
really fit within the broader picture of infrastructure management and deployment of our code inside of AWS.