In this demo, we'll be Git‑ing started with Git.
We'll start by installing it on our machines, if we haven't
already had it installed on our machine by default.
And then we'll look at how we can initialize a repository with
a new command that I haven't mentioned yet.
And we'll look at creating and adding files using those
previous commands that I talked about earlier,
and how to commit them to our repository locally.
Finally, after we've made a few commits,
we'll see how we can use another new command to review our Git
history and the series of commits that we've made.
Now, throughout this,
I'll be taking you through some of the options that
you can use with these commands,
so get ready to learn a few more things about Git.
If you don't already have Git on your machine,
you can download it by going to git‑scm.com/download and downloading the
appropriate Git version for your operating system.
Now it's pretty likely that, depending on your machine,
you might already have it.
You can check by typing in git ‑‑version, and then seeing
if you get a responding version number.
In my case, I have git version 2.28.0. Now,
if we want to start working with Git,
the first thing we'll need to do is either to initialize a
repository with an empty folder or initialize a repository
with some files already inside of it.
If I clear the screen here and ls the contents of this project directory,
you'll notice that there's nothing in it right now. So we could go
over to the project directory and add a new file.
Let's call this file1.txt, and we'll just put a little bit of content in it,
like hello. Let's save this, and then let's go back to our terminal here and ls
again to make sure we have it in the right directory.
Now from here we can initialize a Git repository with a new
command called git init, for initialize.
Once we've done this,
you'll notice that some of the styling for my terminal has changed a little bit.
This is because my terminal automatically supports Git and gives me more
information about the repository that I'm working with.
So now that we've initialized this,
let's clear the screen. If we run the git status command,
you'll notice that we have one untracked file that could
be added to the staging environment.
This is file1.txt.
If we wanted to add it,
we could use the git add command, and then we'd have to specify the name of
the file that we wanted to add, in this case, file1.txt.
Now, if we had multiple files in here and we wanted to add them all,
we could also use git add dot, or git add period.
Now,
this would add every single file to the staging environment.
And you'll notice if I do git status again, we now have a
file that's ready to be committed, so let's go ahead and commit it.
We'll use git commit, and then we'll pass a git message with a ‑m flag.
This will allow us to specify the message that's associated with
this file. And if we're making specific changes,
this will let developers know what's happening inside of the file
and why you're making changes. In this case, we'll just call this
first commit. Now that we've done this, we'll have a commit history
for our local repository, and we could make more changes and
continue to iterate.
So, for example,
if we wanted this text to be fixed and be a little bit more
formal, we could type out Hello and Welcome Everyone! And then we
could save this file, and we could go through this process again.
Go back to the command line, git status to see what's going on.
Currently,
we have to add file1.txt to our staging environment because it hasn't been
added yet, and then we could commit it with git commit ‑m.
In this case, our message might be something like Formalize the greeting.
Now, this is going to allow us to tell what we're changing inside of Git history.
So let me clear this screen here, and let's use a new command called git log.
This will log out all the commits for our repository.
You'll notice if I make this section of the screen a little bit
bigger, then it's going to tell us every commit we've committed
in this repository. It will also give them a unique hash for
each of those commits.
So, we have our first commit and then where we formalize the greeting. Later on,
when working with Git,
we could go back to earlier versions that contain the changes that we want. In
order to get out of the git log, you can press Q for quit.
And now that you're out of the git log,
you've just used Git for the first time successfully. We'll be using
all of these basic skills in later demos when we work with all the developer tools that we'll need in this course.