Let's look at two more concepts related to Git, forks and branches.
There's a few common use cases when we're using forks,
which are essentially just copies of our repository that
we control instead of somebody else.
Now these commonly come up using GitHub when you're
working with open‑source projects,
and GitHub is just a place where you store a lot of your code.
You can propose changes using forks without any
permissions on the original repository,
and this can be very helpful when you want to propose
changes using something called pull requests.
It integrates pretty effectively when you have projects you
don't want to give permissions to everybody on,
to change or to do specific actions on,
but you still want to allow people to see it,
to copy your code, and make their own changes and eventually integrate them.
And you can sync your forks with the original remote repository.
Now there's two different names when it comes to forks
that'll come up pretty frequently.
The first is upstream.
Now usually when you're dealing with forks,
upstream is the original remote repository; then there's also origin,
which is usually the fork that you yourself are working on that you own
inside of your own account on something like GitHub.
Now you can have other names for forks,
but these are two of the most common ones you'll see.
Let's look at a forking workflow.
Imagine you have an upstream remote repository,
which has all the code that we want to work with.
The first thing you'd do is you'd fork that repository and create
your own version of that upstream repository.
Usually,
this will eventually be called origin on your local file
system when you're working with Git.
Then you'd clone the origin repository to your development environment,
and you'd start working with it the same way you would before,
adding files in your working directory, Git adding them to the staging area,
Git committing them to your local repository,
and then Git pushing them up to the origin when you're done making changes.
Now this process will have one additional step.
Once you've pushed your changes to the origin,
you'll open up something called a pull request to the upstream
repository to integrate your changes there.
This will allow the maintainers of the upstream repository to take
a look at all the proposals that you're making and integrate them
or ask for some additional changes.
So let's look at pull requests a little bit more.
These will be integrated with repository hosting
tools like CodeCommit and GitHub,
and they can trigger things like automated builds,
test code, and report results.
They're also going to allow you to do things like converse
about the code that you're proposing,
and review each line of code potentially with inline comments to talk
back and forth about the benefits or the drawbacks of specific things
that you're doing inside of your code.
We'll be using pull requests later on in order to do a lot
of these things here with AWS CodeCommit.
Another important concept we'll need to understand is working with branches.
Now it's common that you'll have a remote repository and a
branch that's the default branch that you're merging the code
into on that remote repository.
And you'll see this frequently called either main or master,
though main is becoming the normal convention nowadays.
Now you'll do the exact same things you were doing before where
you'll clone the code from the remote repository.
The only difference is I kind of skimmed over the details of using branches.
In all the previous examples,
we only really had one branch that we were working with,
and I obscured it behind the scenes.
However,
you could also use multiple branches to make sure that all the changes
that you're working on are discrete from one another,
and that you're not stomping on other people's toes
when you're merging code around.
So, for example, after you've cloned your local repository,
you might then take it from main and change it to a new branch.
You can do this using a command called checkout or checkout ‑b,
which would create a new branch at the same time as
you're actually switching to it.
So in this case, we're checking out a new branch called my‑feature,
and we'd have the exact same code on both branches,
but we'd then be able to work on it independently of the main branch.
So if we wanted to add files to our working directory,
we could do this,
and then we could add them to the staging area again, and then add
them by committing them to the my‑feature branch.
Now, later on,
we could push this feature up into a remote repository with git push
origin my‑feature, and this would allow us to have this feature
branch be then merged into the main branch,
thus keeping any specific changes we did for a particular feature separate
from other changes others might be working on. Now this would look a little
bit different from the fork workflow we had before,
because there's only one remote, but we have two different branches.
We could still have a pull request,
then merge the changes from my‑feature to main, and then those
files would be present on that same main branch.
After we merge the changes in, the pull request will typically close,
and then we can also remove the feature branch from the remote repository,
because we've already merged those changes into the main branch.
Similarly,
we might then take the code from the main branch and git pull it down from the
main branch to update the files we have on our local main branch, and because we
already merged all the changes from my feature, we then also delete that local
branch on our development environment.
So while this seems a bit complicated,
let's look at some of the benefits we get from feature branching.
One of the first ones is that the history of changes are
now tied to a specific new feature.
So we see that pull request from us merging in those changes,
and it's tied to a specific feature name that might have a
particular project or set of tickets tracking the work that
we're doing in there, associated with it.
We can also then squash commits to make a clean commit history.
Now this means that we kind of fudge all the work that we've
been doing, if we've been making multiple iterative commits on a
feature branch. Say it took us 16 commits to get the code where
we wanted it to go, well,
we could then have all of the code in that state on the feature branch
be merged into the main branch with just one commit.
Additionally, pull requests can be focused on those new features this way,
and this will allow us to merge everything into
main all at once for that feature,
rather than every single step we took to get there.
Later on, we'll be using feature branching as we integrate it with our developer tools.