In this demo, we'll look at deploying ECS applications using AWS CodeDeploy.
We'll start by creating the entire AWS network infrastructure that we need
to support ECS applications and also to make sure that we don't step on any
toes of anything already in our AWS accounts.
After that,
we'll look at creating an the ECS cluster by
leveraging some of those network resources,
and then we'll configure our cluster with CodeDeploy so we can
deploy our applications to that cluster.
After that, we'll try out two different deployment strategies,
first using an all‑at‑once deployment for our first deployment with CodeDeploy.
And then we'll use a second deployment to deploy linearly to
CodeDeploy by shifting traffic piece by piece.
So now that we know what we're up to in this demo,
let's jump over to our code in the AWS console and get started.
Over here in my code editor,
I've downloaded all the materials for this module of the course.
There's only one demo that we're working with called
demo1‑ecs‑applications‑codedeploy,
and I'll break this up into a few different parts,
as we'll need to do a lot of networking and ECS
setup before we can use CodeDeploy.
So in order to use these files in this demo,
we'll be going through step by step from p1 through p11.
And in this output_values section,
we'll be adding different values that we'll need
throughout the rest of this demo,
so make sure to follow along and copy and paste the
values that you get from the outputs of some of these
different steps and their commands.
And you paste them into the output_values.txt file so you can use them later,
as we'll definitely be needing them throughout many of the following steps.
So I'm going to go over some of these pretty quickly.
But the first step we'll need to do is hop into the commands section and
scroll the top of the file and use this first command.
Now I'm going to need to copy it and also make sure I'm inside the
p1‑service‑role‑setup folder because it's going to be referencing the
trust‑policy that you see right here in this folder.
I can paste this into the console and hit Enter here,
and if you get an error, don't worry.
That probably just means that the role itself has already been created.
So let's copy this second command here,
and this will be attaching a policy to this role.
Now, when we created the role initially, we used this trust‑policy.
Basically,
this trust‑policy says that the role we're creating can be used by
CodeDeploy and by ECS to take actions on different services.
In the role we actually created, we then associated an AWS‑managed policy,
which gives a bunch of permissions on ECS and its subsequent services.
So that means that we now have a role that
CodeDeploy can use to interact with ECS.
So let's get the ARN of that role, because we'll need the ARN value later.
I have copied this command from the section in the commands.txt file
because it'll just give us the role value that we need.
So let's copy that value and then go to output_values.txt,
and let's start pasting in values that we're getting,
in this case, the ROLE_ARN.
You can tell there'll be a few different values that we'll need to set this up,
but this is only really one time you need to do it,
as you'll get everything for ECS set up once and then use
CodeDeploy to continue deploying application versions as you
iterate on everything inside of your application.
Next, let's go to the alb‑setup section,
and let's go to the commands section here and let's start by creating a new VPC.
The reason I'm doing this is because this'll help us create a completely
fresh slate without having to worry about any other configuration that's
in your AWS account or having to worry about anything you're doing to
other applications in your AWS account.
You'll be creating all the networking resources and ECS
resources you need to have a fresh cluster that we can
then work with using CodeDeploy.
So let's get started.
The first thing we'll do is, like I said,
create a VPC, and then with this VPC we'll need to go up and grab the VpcId here.
We'll grab this value and then go over to output_values.txt and
we can paste it in here right below VPC_ID.
I don't need the quotes for most of what I'm doing so I'll leave those off.
In the next section,
we're going to need to paste the VPC_ID in here to the vpc‑id section
where it has the two alligators brackets that contain it.
And whenever you see those, you can basically say,
oh, I already have this value, I'm going to paste that over it,
and we can do this throughout the rest of the commands.
You'll see there's another command down here with VPC_ID,
another one here, and I'll go through the rest of the file and do that.
And this will save you some time from copying and pasting later.
Now that we've pasted the VPC ID throughout everything else,
let's use the next two commands.
These are to create two subnets inside of the VPC,
so let's paste those into our command line here,
and they should run one after the other and give us two different results.
We could copy the subnet IDs,
but instead I've written a command that's pretty nifty that
will help you deal with that instead.
And it requires you to paste the VPC ID in here that you just created if you
haven't done that already. So let's paste that in there and you'll see now we
get our subnets and their availability zones.
So let me copy the first subnet, which is related to us‑east‑1a,
and let's put that in here at the top, right next to us‑east‑1a.
And then we'll do the second one, which is related to us‑east‑1b,
and we'll paste it back in here as well.
The next step will be to create an internet gateway.
In order to create an internet gateway we can run this
pretty simple command here to create one,
and we'll be attaching that internet gateway to the VPC we created.
But first,
let's take that internet gateway value and pop it into our
output_values.txt file and save that.
Then let's go through the rest of this and make sure we paste the
internet gateway ID anywhere that we see INTERNET_GATEWAY_ID
inside of those alligators brackets.
Now that I've pasted the internet gateway throughout this file,
let's go ahead and attach the internet gateway to our VPC
using the VPC ID and the internet gateway ID.
Now that this is attached,
we can create a route table using the VPC ID we had from before,
and then we're going to populate this route table with some routes.
But in order to do this,
we'll need to grab the route table ID and then paste it into
our file here in the ROUTE_TABEL_ID section.
And you're getting the hang on this now,
so basically every time you see me put a new value
into the output_values.txt section,
just know that I'll probably be pasting it somewhere else,
either in these commands or later throughout.
So now that we've done this we can scroll back down and we can
create a new route inside of our route table.
So let's paste that here.
What this command does is,
allows us to tell where the traffic that's coming from
our ECS service needs to be routed to.
In this case,
it allows traffic to come in and out of the actual internet
rather than internal networks in AWS.
So let's skip ahead here to the next command,
which is to associate the route table with our subnets.
After pasting all the relevant values in,
I can run this command to associate the route table with my first subnet,
subnet A, and then I can associate the route with my second subnet,
subject B.
I don't need to copy these association IDs down.
After this we can run this command for subnet 1A to make sure that the subnets
will have public IPs if anything's launched inside of them,
basically making sure that the open internet would be
able to make requests to these IPs, rather than only things inside of our VPC.
Once these commands have been run we can jump down and
create a security group for the VPC.
Let's copy this entire command here, paste it in,
and now we have a security group ID here.
So you know the drill.
We'll put this into output_values, and then we'll end up
using it later throughout our commands.
Now that we've created the security group,
we need to add some rules to it to control how traffic flows through it.
By default, it's going to allow traffic to go out on any port to any direction.
But we're going to need to see how we authorized the traffic coming in,
or the ingress traffic.
So let's copy this first rule and paste it in here.
What this is doing is allowing traffic from the
protocol of TCP going to port 443, anything coming from the CIDR of 0.0.0.0/0,
meaning any IPs.
What this will allow us to do is allow any HTTPS traffic,
and it's going to be more relevant if you're adding SSL certificates to your
ECS service or other applications that are working with this.
However, in our case, we're going to need to use this second command here,
which is the typical port for HTTP traffic,
so let's paste that in here and make sure we add that rule too.
And now in this last step,
we can create the applications load balancer that'll route
traffic back and forth between different versions of our
application that we're deploying.
So once we've done this,
let's make sure to scroll up and get the ARN value for this load balancer.
It should look something like this here.
Let's go back to the output_values and make sure we save that ALB_ARN
because we're definitely going to need to use it later.
All right, so that was a lot of setup, but trust me,
this is going to help you avoid potential issues that you might face
when working inside of AWS accounts that have more network configuration
than you might otherwise want to deal with.
In the next section we'll be creating resources related to our ECS cluster.
And after that, we'll be setting up everything to work with CodeDeploy. So let's get to it.