Welcome back. In this section, we'll create a bunch of other
infrastructure that our ECS cluster will use to help determine where
we're sending traffic between versions of our application.
We'll start by creating the target groups that we'll need
in order to target traffic between one version and another
version of our application.
Now, remember,
we have this output_values.txt file and we have some values in
here that we need to replace with it so go ahead and do that now.
I'm going to use some magic to do mine.
Poof! There we go.
Now let's copy this first command and let's get the first target group that we
need and we'll scroll up and get the target group ARN, this we'll need to copy
and put into the output_values.txt file along with the second target group ARN
that we'll be creating with this second command, so make sure you copy both and
put them both into that file.
With both these values copied,
we can go to the next step in p4. In here, we'll be creating a listener
that we configure with our application load balancer and our target groups
so make sure to copy the values from the output value section into this
file too. Poof! I did my magic again.
Alright,
so now that we pasted in the ARN for the load balancer and the target
group ARN, let's copy this command and let's paste it in here too. What
this will be doing is it'll be creating a listener to listen for traffic
with the protocol of HTTP on Port 80.
So let's grab the ARN for this listener and let's paste it into our
output_values.txt file as well because we'll be using this later on to
configure other application infrastructure.
So now that we've finished with this, let's move onto the next section,
which is to create our ECS cluster. Inside of here,
it's really one pretty simple command, which is aws ecs create cluster.
Let me give it a cluster name and a region. Throughout this,
I'm using us‑east‑1.
Now,
make sure to copy the cluster ARN that comes out of this command, it should
appear towards the top of the results, and then put that in your output_values
too so we can reference the cluster later, and then we're ready to scooch onto
the next step too, which is to register a task. Now for this section, we're
going to need to make sure that we move into the folder that contains the
fargate‑task‑blue.json file, which is just p6‑register‑task.
Now we can double‑check that this is true if we list out the
contents and see fargate‑task‑blue.json in there,
and from here, we can run the commands that we need to work with this.
The first thing we'll need to do, though,
is go into the fargate‑task‑blue.json file and scroll down to the
bottom of the file where it says a ROLE_ARN. We'll need to replace
this value too by getting the ROLE_ARN we created at the very
beginning of the previous section.
Now we'll paste that into here and then save it, and this means
that we'll have an execution role configured for this fargate
task and that will just make sure that we have the permissions we
need to work with it. Now,
everything else in here should be set up as it is and
you don't need to change anything.
In fact, if you do,
it might break things later, so please don't. Let's go to
the commands.txt file and let's copy this ecs
register‑task‑definition command here.
So let's paste that in, and this will register this task with ECS.
Now we'll need to scroll up to the very top of this,
which can actually go a little bit up, and we'll get a task definition error
and that we'll need to paste into our output_values.txt file.
You can think of this as essentially the first version of the
container that we're planning on running in the ECS.
Later on,
we'll make different versions that will then change to and deploy
to those different versions using CodeDeploy.
So with this done,
let's close out of our fargate task and let's scroll to the
bottom and make sure we've finished the last step,
which is to grab that ARN for the task definition.
Now that we're done with that, we can move onto Step 7,
which is to create the service that we'll have inside of the ECS cluster.
Now for this section too,
we're going to need to clear the screen and then change directories
up a level and then change directories into p7‑create‑service.
Inside of here, you'll see that we have a service‑bluegreen.json
file and a commands.txt file.
We'll need to change the values in the service‑bluegreen.json file.
There are several different values we need to change,
including the TARGET_GROUP1_ARN, the SECURITY_GROUP_ID, and both of the
subnet IDs, so change all four of those values now.
Once you're done making these changes,
then save the service‑bluegreen.json file and go to the commands.txt
section. From here, we'll be using the aws ecs create‑service command
to create a service using that service‑bluegreen.json file. So we'll
paste this command in here.
Make sure you're inside of the P7 folder when you do this.
If you get an error, that's probably what it's related to,
or if you get another error that says you're missing some value,
make sure you pasted all the values into that file too. Let's scroll
up and let's grab the ARN for this service now that we've deployed
it. We'll need to scroll up towards the top and there is a lot of
information that comes out here, so make sure you grab the right value.
It should look like this right here.
So let's copy that value and take it to the output_value section here and
we'll paste it in right here under the service ARN.
Now that we've done this, we have that service value,
which means that our service has been created inside of the cluster and
we've created a task that's registered that we can use to deploy different
containers inside of that service in the cluster.
So now that we have all this configuration done with, we've finished setting
up everything we need to for ECS, and we're ready to start working with CodeDeploy and deploying things to ECS using it.