Now that our ECS service is created,
we'll move on to step eight where we create our CodeDeploy app.
We could do this in the AWS console, but for consistency,
I'm just going to do it through the AWS CLI.
We'll copy this command here that'll create an application
with the name of tutorial‑bluegreen‑app.
We'll paste this into our command line, and then we'll copy our applicationId,
as this is another one of those values that we'll be using later on.
Next, we'll skip on to step nine.
Inside of here,
we should be able to create a bucket that will host our appspec.yml file.
And this will point to the TASK_DEFINITION_ARN that we got from earlier,
as well as having a container name,
which we already included in that task definition and the container port,
which we also included there.
So we only need to update one thing inside of here,
which is the TASK_DEFINITION_ARN.
We'll replace that with the TASK_DEFINITION_ARN we got from earlier.
Now, this should be the first one,
but we'll be creating a second TASK_DEFINITION_ARN later
on and using that in a later section.
Right now,
this one should have a :1 at the end of it because it's the first
version of this task definition that we created.
Next, we'll go to the command section,
and we'll upload the appspec.yml file to our own S3 bucket.
We'll create a new one just for this purpose.
So I'm going to use the aws S3 mb, or make bucket,
command, and then I'll pass an s3:// for the S3 prefix here.
Then, for my case,
I'm going to call this bucket something like
fernando‑unicorn for my favorite animal,
and then I'll have some gibberish letters and numbers at the end of it.
You'll need to create a unique bucket name for you,
so it won't be able to be the same as this bucket name here.
Make sure that you use your name, your favorite animal,
and some of your own unique letters and numbers.
I'll hit Enter,
and then we should have this bucket created so we can copy it into our
output_values.txt file right underneath UNIQUE_BUCKET_NAME.
From there,
we should be able to upload the appspec.yml file from
the p9 folder here into our S3 bucket.
So let's replace this part of the command here with our
bucket name and copy the entire thing.
And then because I'm in the p8 folder now,
which is where we started in this section,
we'll need to change directories up,
and then we'll change directories into the p9 folder.
And as you can see, that has the commands.txt file and the appspec.yml file.
So let's clear this screen,
and let's copy this appspec.yml file into our S3 bucket.
With this done, we have our appspec.yml set up to use for our first deployment.
So we can go to p10 for using CodeDeploy.
Now these instructions will guide you through everything
I'm about to do in the AWS console.
You'll essentially be clicking a bunch of different sections of the
CodeDeploy console in order to integrate that appspec.yml file we just put
in S3 with everything in the CodeDeploy console.
So I'll go over to the AWS console now, go over to the Services section,
and let's look for CodeDeploy.
We'll go to that section of the console,
and we'll click on the Applications section.
Here, we should have the application we just created,
which we can click on there.
And now we need to create a deployment group, so let's click that button here.
Once we're in this section, we can give this deployment group a name.
Let's call this ecs‑demo‑dg for deployment group,
and then we need to give it a service role.
We should see our service role that we created in the very
first step of this demo appear here, so we can click that.
Go to the ECS cluster, and our cluster should appear.
Make sure you're using the one we created in this demo
just in case you have more than one,
and then we'll use the service inside of that cluster.
From here, we'll click on a load balancer.
I'll be using the bluegreen‑alb, which we created earlier,
and the Production listener port should be HTTP:80.
We'll skip the Test listener section,
and we'll go straight to the Target group 1 and Target group 2 configuration.
Both of these target groups we created earlier should appear,
and then we're onto the deployment settings.
For this deployment, we're going to use the Reroute traffic immediately option,
and we're going to leave the
CodeDeployDefault.ECSAllAtOnce deployment configuration selected.
We will need to definitely change the time it takes for this
deployment to finish from 1 hour to 5 minutes.
Basically,
we're reducing the time it takes to delete the original task set
when we're doing these deployments so we don't have to wait for an
hour before we can do a second deployment.
So now that we're done with this, let's click the Create deployment group,
and then let's create a deployment with this deployment group.
Now that we've done this,
we'll be able to select the S3 file location for the
appspec.yml file we just uploaded.
Now if we don't know what this is,
we can go back to where we just ran the command.
We'll need to copy everything from the beginning of the s3:// all the way to
the end of the appspec.yml, and we can paste it in here.
Really, it should just be the name of our bucket and then a / and
the appspec.yml all following the s3:// prefix.
The final step will be to select the .yml revision file type after
we've pasted in the URL for our revision location, and then we can
click Create deployment. From here, this should start our very first
CodeDeploy deployment, and we can see the status of this deployment
right now is in progress.
It will go through the process of creating all the containers inside of
our ECS cluster and then moving the application through the steps that it
needs to get everything deployed properly.
Now right now,
if we take a moment and go to the Services drop‑down and look
for EC2, we should be able to see some of the services that are
actually being worked with here. Specifically, if we go to the
Load balancers section,
I only have one load balancer right now, which is related
to the application we're deploying.
So if I copy this DNS name for the load balancer and
paste it into my browser here, you can see that we have
this ECS service up and running,
and it's been successfully deployed inside of ECS using CodeDeploy.
Now if we wanted to change this to a new version of the application,
we could do that, too.
So let's go back to the management console here and go back over to our
CodeDeploy section, as we'll be doing one more thing here. We can find
CodeDeploy in the drop‑down here and review the rest of the application
deployment that we just did.
It looks like it's still in progress,
so it's still shifting the traffic from the original
task set to the replacement task set.
It's a little bit weird for this first deployment because,
technically, we're deploying the initial deployment,
and then we're deploying the replacement deployment,
and it's the exact same thing.
But in subsequent deployments, we'll be able to tell
the difference between the two.
If you scroll a little bit further down in this deployment section,
you'll see we have this process taking place where we have all the traffic
on the original primary task set, and currently, the Desired count of ECS
instances there is 1, and the Running count is 1,
and we also have the replacement task set that is currently active.
Eventually, we'll switch some of that traffic over,
and this process will complete.
After waiting for a few minutes,
our traffic should've shifted to our replacement task set.
So we can see it moved over from the original environment to
the replacement environment.
Now when this happened, it moved over from 0 to 100 right away,
and then it immediately went into the next step in step three,
which is waiting for 5 minutes before it removes the original test set.
Once this process completes,
it will remove everything in the original task set so we don't have to
keep managing that infrastructure or paying for it.
But what if we wanted to take this same sort of deployment,
but only shift over a few pieces of the traffic as it goes through?
Well, we'll do that in the next section,
but make sure before going on to that that you wait for this
deployment to complete and wait for the original set of tasks
to be removed by CodeDeploy. Once CodeDeploy is finished, It should look something like this.