So what is AWS CodeBuild?
And how can it help people like DevOps engineers putting together applications?
Well, AWS CodeBuild will allow us to do a few different things.
If we're working with a programming language that requires us to compile
code before we deploy it out into our infrastructure,
CodeBuild can help us automate this step.
It can also help us to run tests against any changes we
make to our application code to make sure that we're not
going to run into regressions, or issues,
or add additional bugs to our code that we would otherwise
have been able to catch with some tests.
Additionally,
if we compile our code into artifacts or we create other
sorts of artifacts that we need to deploy,
CodeBuild can help us produce those deployment artifacts and do
things with them using other AWS services.
So what are some of the benefits of using CodeBuild?
Well, first, it's fully managed by AWS.
Rather than having to create our own build server and keep tabs on that,
as well as patch it and secure it,
we can outsource this all to AWS CodeBuild, and this will help us avoid the
overhead of patching or versioning our build software,
as well as keeping tabs on the server that's running all of it.
Additionally,
we can get access to a bunch of preconfigured environments using CodeBuild,
so we can get access to different operating systems or a variety of
different language runtimes to either build or test our code.
And this can be helpful because CodeBuild will manage all these for us
without us having to go and install the languages and the different
versions of languages and runtimes that we might need.
So let's look at some or concepts related to CodeBuild.
The first one we need to understand is the build project.
This essentially contains all the information that we need to
create an environment where we build our code,
and this, kind of expectedly, is something called a build environment.
This build environment can be things like the
operating system and the language runtime.
And we also have something called the buildspec.
This will help us determine what to do during the CodeBuild
process, when we run specific commands, when we install specific software,
and when we output particular artifacts,
all those sorts of things will be configured inside of our buildspec file.
So let's try and visualize these concepts.
First, we have our build projects, and these get turned into build environments,
both the operating system, such as a Linux operating system,
or a Windows operating system,
or one of the flavors of the Linux operating system,
to be more specific, and the runtime that we're working with.
In the case of some examples we'll be working with later,
we'll be using Python,
but you could choose a lot of other runtimes to build and work with your code.
And we'll also have our source code.
Our source code is going to include a buildspec file, but it's
not just going to be that buildspec file.
It'll also be all the code we're using to build our application.
In the case of later demos,
this might be our flask application and all the files that
go with it alongside the buildspec file.
The buildspec file will then go into the build environment along with our code,
and we'll be using that to help determine what happens
inside of this build environment.
From here,
the buildspec file might tell our application that it needs to do something
like install dependencies inside of the build environment, and this might mean
adding different libraries to our applications so that it can run correctly
with all the dependencies that it requires.
It also might mean running tests against the application
after everything has been installed.
And when those tests are run,
it might need to output test results to some location so that we can
see them and confirm that everything is going well.
Now, these test results might get output to something like an S3 bucket,
and we could store them there to be viewed later.
But if our tests run successfully, we might also configure it to
package everything up from our application and deploy this out
somewhere too, potentially to an S3 bucket to be picked up by our
deployment infrastructure.
In addition to this,
CodeBuild will also keep tabs on everything that's happening inside
of the build environment, and it'll send logs from the entire
process inside of the build environment to CloudWatch Logs so we can
know whether or not things happen correctly or incorrectly inside of
our different builds.
It'll also store a lot of this information inside of the AWS CodeBuild
console as well. So now that you have a better understanding of what
happens inside of CodeBuild, in the next section, we'll look closer at the buildspec and how we write buildspec files.