Congratulations.
You complete this course and you'll learn a lot about the marine stack.
You'll learned how to combine all these individual technologies and build a complete application with
debt including important features like file upload or a user authentication.
Now the obvious question is where should you go next.
What are the next steps that makes sense.
Well as always it's all about practicing.
You need to practice practice and practice build more dummy Learn apps.
You saw one example in this course and you learned how things generally work together how to implement
certain key features like upload and what to watch out for.
But of course there is an infinite amount of apps you could build.
There are so many features you could implement so build your own dummy apps build an online shop build
something that utilizes some other feature build a different front end user to knowledge you have about
react note and so on and build apps that come to your mind build simplified clones of popular Web applications.
That's a great idea as well.
So did you encounter many different scenarios and also challenges.
You will definitely face some problems whilst building those apps and overcoming those issues on your
own with help of Google and stack overflow and so on.
That is how you grow as a developer so it's really an important point but also of course explored the
individual topics covered in this course.
Now having some basic react knowledge was a course requirement but maybe you can still dive deeper deeper
and or you want to learn more about node express or about Mongo D.B..
These are the building blocks after all.
And in order to be able to build any kind of web application you need to know as much as possible about
these technologies.
So diving into dedicated courses or tutorials or official documentation of these resources is really
something I also recommend.
Now I got courses on all these topics in case you were interested but of course any resource will do.
It's just important that besides practicing you also expand your knowledge on these topics so that you
really are able to build anything you want in the end and also keep in mind that the way we set up this
Marine stack here is just one alternative.
Arguably the most popular and common one but you could for example also build a graph que el API instead
of a rest api or you have a back end where you render views on the service side based on some templating
engine and you only use react and parts of your pages.
So explorers such alternative combinations as well it could be interesting to build your own graph QoL
API and by the way attached you also find a link to a tutorial I created where we do build basically
a merged application with a graph que el API so that could be interesting as well.
And if you follow these steps if you dive into these areas you will grow a lot and you will be able
to build anything you want with does extremely useful tech stack of longer to be expressed react and
know J.S..