So now did we worked on the back end and we're able to send requests to our REST API there.
And with no express and Mongo it be we are able to store data and database as well.
It's now part to connect the front end.
We all worked on with the back end so to connect react with our back and API data for in this module
we will work on this connection.
You could say does stand for a kind of is the heart of this course at least if we have a look at the
title of the course because now we're going to bring Merlin together.
Now we are going to connect react to mongo TB Express and notorious therefore in this module we'll have
a look at how we send HP requests to the back end to the API from inside our ReACT app and how we use
to respond stay that we get back will have a look at how we can handle our raws if something goes wrong
if we're sending invalid data or something like that and also how we can handle a loading state and
show a loading spinner to our users whilst we are waiting for an action to complete or for data to load
and of course we'll all make sure that we appropriately update the user interface.
One state I was loaded or won some action completed so plenty of work to do.
Let's not waste any time and instead dive right in.