When we talk about the Mearns stack we of course have to understand the E and the N part expressed jazz.
And no jazz.
Of course we'll build the entire back and off this application with these two technologies working together.
And therefore there you will learn a lot about them but in case you're really new to know jazz and express
I a recommend that you check out dedicated resources like my note J asked to complete guide but be here
in this module you'll also get a brief refresher will quickly dive into know jazz and express understand
what it is all about how it basically works and therefore hopefully by the end of this module we're
all roughly on the same page.
Now again this module is not there to replace a complete node or express scores.
There is a reason why that course has more than 30 hours on its own but it's there to make sure that
if it's been some time since you worked with node or express or you haven't worked with it but you're
learning it simultaneously to this course we all can get started with it quickly and it's not all brand
new.
What you're going to learn in the next course modules thereafter.
So in this module specifically we'll have a look at what exactly node J.S. is again and how it roughly
works.
And of course we'll all explore the E express J.S. what is expressed about and how does it work and
why do we use it.
Why do we need it when we build a back and with node.
So let's dive in.