We connected our ReACT front and to the back and obviously connect really just meant sending H to the
p requests from inside.
Do you react up to the back end.
But this is what it's all about before when we worked just on the back end.
We only used postman there.
Now we're doing this from inside our reactor.
But one thing was missing.
Image upload thus far.
We worked with some dummy image you are ls for both the users as well as are places it would be much
nicer if the visitors off our page could instead bring their own images.
If we had file pictures in our forums where users could choose images to use well and that's exactly
what we'll do in this module in detail you will learn how to accept and handle files or specifically
images on the back end of our applications or on the service site on Node express side.
And of course we'll also cover the front end and see how we can add a file picture data in our form
and then get that file from the front end with an H to repeat request to the back end all these things
will be done in this module.