Now one thing you might have noticed before is that if we send the request to a root which doesn't exist
for example API slash nothing I get an error here right and I get this kind of error.
Now that's OK but we might want to handle this defiled route not found error for that back and app.
Yes we can register a new middleware not an error handling middleware like this but a normal middleware
handling all requests no matter which word we used.
That comes after our roots.
The idea is that this only runs does middleware which we register here only runs if we didn't send the
response into one of our routes before.
Because if we do this in the response we don't call next.
Right.
We just send the response and therefore no other middleware after this one will be reached.
So put in our words this Middleware is only reached if we have some request which didn't get a response
before and that can only be a request which we don't want to handle.
So here I can then add my middleware and in here I now want to return a 4 0 4 error and I want to utilize
my default error handler for that and I'll simply import the h the DP error CLOs we created earlier
from the model's folder HBP dash error and create such a new HDP error here by calling new HP error
the messages could not find it is root and decode is 404 of course and then we can throw it or call
next hero will throw it because it's synchronous so nothing speaks against throwing it and that will
then reach our default error handler to send us back a nice response so we now save that and try this
again we now get our own response with a 404 status code as you see here and also with our own body
and that's just a little improvement which I wanted to add here so did we have proper error handling
for unsupported routes as well.