You can also pass data back and you still do this with props.
The idea just is that instead of having props that pass in data like a string or an array or an object
to the lower level to the child component as it's also called you pass a callback function from the
parent component to the child component.
So no array or anything like that but a callback function.
So here in the app component we could define a new function add new goal handler to name is totally
up to you and I name it handler because it also will kind of be triggered upon an event and here I expect
to get the new goal and then here I can reach out to course goals.
And for example push the new goal into disarray and thereafter console log course goals.
Now we have this function and now we can pass it to new goal via props so there we could add a prop
on at goal.
This is now not an event listener react the fines for all the built in age two male elements we have
built in event listeners like for example in the New Gold component on the form we had on submit on
a button we have on click on input we also have on click for example because you can also handle click
events on inputs you can handle those on any HD him out element now in the end here I call this an event
handler but what it actually is is just a prop.
Technically there is no difference between class name where I pass in a string and on submit where I
pass in a pointer to a function.
So in the end this is just a prop of the form element which react offers to you.
So here in app yes we can all to pass a prop here on NEW goal which holds a pointer to a function I
just named as prop like this not because I have to.
I could name it at goal or this year but it's a convention to name props which the end pass functions
to lower level components like event handlers because the functions you pass down to components in the
end will be called by these components upon certain events.
That is how it typically works and you will see that the more react applications you build.
So therefore I followed this convention and named this on ad goal and passed my ad new goal handler
to the new goal component so I pass a pointer not the execution but just a pointer to its function to
a new goal on this on ad goal prop now that means that instead of new goal I can now accept props here
I can accept this props parameter I always get it even if I don't get any props but if I don't get any
props there isn't much sense in in explicitly riding it out here but now I need a prop which I'm getting
on new goal and that is that on ad gold prop I defined here I want to call that function I receive on
that prop here instead of my ad goal handler in new goal.
So instead of logging the new goal I can now call props on ad goal here on ad goal because that's the
name I chose here and on ad goal Pass is a pointer at a function to the component so inside of the new
goal component I know I can execute on ad goal because it holds a pointer to a function so I now execute
that function pointed to and it can pass my new goal as an argument to on that goal because indeed in
the function I passed 2 on ad goal I expect to get a new goal as an argument as a parameter.
So now if we save everything we should see the difficulty at goal where outputting something from app
trace lines 16 which is this log here and we're outputting our new course Cole's array which are our
old goals and a new goal.
So passing the goal from the lower level from the child component the new goal component to the parent
component the app component in this case works and it works with props we just use props to parse a
function that is then called by the child components instead of passing data directly from parent to
child.
This gives us a way to communicate back from the child to the parent with help of such a function.