To control the visibility let's go back to main navigation because ultimately that is where we have
to draw and where we also have that menu button that hamburger icon Indian here.
I want to manage some state I want to manage the state where to draw is opened or not.
So we have to import U.S. State from react.
And then here we can have our draw is open state and set draw is open as a function to update that state.
And initially let's say that is false with the US state and the initial state.
Now we can use draw is open to only sometimes rendered as straw and one way of doing that is to wrap
the draw here into curly braces and then check if draw is open is true.
And if it is the case with a ternary expression rendered a side draw otherwise rendered null which means
render nothing.
This is how we can conditionally render content and react if we do that.
You see it's not open now.
By the way we can also shorten this and take advantage of JavaScript and use ideological and operator
here which means if this is true this year will be rendered.
This is how jobs good works.
It's a vanilla javascript so it has the same effect.
Now we need to make sure that when we click our button we do open the drawer.
So on the button we can add on click prop and then add a function to our main navigation functional
component which will name open drawer and dare I want to well open my drawer.
So here I want to call set draw is open and set it to true change to stage to true here on click.
I will point at Open draw if you do that I can now click this button and the draw is there.
It's not animated but it's there.
Unfortunately now we can't close it anymore.
So that's something we should fix for that.
I'll also add a number of function closed drawer and here I want to set drawers open to falls of course
the question just is where do we trigger this.
For that we need a new component a component we can render as a background to the draw so that when
we then clicked this background we close to draw and you find such a component attached backdrops sip
holds a new component which you should add to your UI elements folder next to Avatar and cart you have
a backdrop see as as fall in a backdrop J as follow the backdrop component also utilizes the portal
concept and therefore you should add such a backdrop hook place in your inexact Cheval file above the
draw hook I'll add the backdrop hook and the backdrop is simply well a backdrop a background which is
rendered behind the draw.
For example now in May navigation I also day from one to render the backdrop conditionally.
So there we can check if draw is open is true and if it is render the backdrop not important you need
to import backdrop for in order to use it.
So import backdrop from
and now let's go to UI elements and then backdrop with that we rendered the backdrop and the backdrop
component listens to a click on the backdrop.
So on this background and then emits a function it expects to get on on click prop its own.
So on the backdrop we can add on click because we do handle such a prop there and bind that too close
draw and now if we safeties we can open it.
Now we have that background it's a bit darker than before.
If you click that it closes.
So that's great but a little animation would be nice right.
So let's add an animation in the next lecture.