This is 8 4 to file upload adding file upload has two sides.
For one we need to add it on the back end.
Here we used to Malta package and the middleware it offers to us configured for our needs.
So we're configuring the place where it's stored how to file name is named and which files we accept.
We do this with the help of the MIME type map.
Then in the controllers we simply extract the path which Malta gives us automatically and stored that
in the database.
So not the file is stored but just the path off the file just a string.
We don't want to store files in the database because Deadwood bloated slow it down and be a really bad
practice store files on the file system locally instead now in case something goes wrong.
We have app J.S. where we roll back our file upload.
If the request where something went wrong has a file attached to it.
So if some other request goes wrong we don't roll it back.
Of course and on the front that we built this new image upload component which allows us to pick an
image and all to show up preview and we easily integrated this into our existing form.
Look at the for management we have in place already and then the trick just was to use forum data to
submit the data to the back end so that we can have a mixture of text and binary data and that is it.
This is file upload added to emerge an app.