To use this newly created custom agent if you look in the off page component here I'll replace my existing
logic to send the request here with the logic in my custom hook.
So here first of all we can import does hook we import use age to be client from shared hooks age to
the peacock and then here we have to call use H2 to be client not when we want to send the request but
initially in this component because keep in mind this custom hook creates everything we need to send
the request and then returns us for example a pointer at this send request function.
And this is then the function we need to call to really send the request so we can get rid of is loading
and the error is state here because this is now managed instead of the hook and instead call use h to
be client like this and then this returns us some data so we can use object D structuring here to for
example get access to is loading to the error and all that to send request which is very important also
to clear error which we need to well clear an error now is that if we scroll down we got a couple of
errors set as loading does not exist anymore and we don't need it anymore it will be done all inside
of the send request function which is managed in our own hook and instead of using fetch here I will
now call send the request pass my you are El but then actually not such an object here but as a second
argument the HP method.
So just posed as a string as a second argument The third argument if we have a look at send request
should then actually be the body so back in the off component let's grab this piece of data here
and add this as a third argument argument here after post and forth argument then is our headers object.
This now sends a valid request hopefully and send request all the returns I promise this however that
already has our response data and we don't need to manually parse it or check forty four hundred ish
status code that is already done inside of our hook therefore we don't set is loading here we don't
set it here and in the catch block we also don't need to set an error India because we're doing try
catch already in our custom hook so we don't need to do any Try catching here at all we can get rid
of this because everything will be handled by the custom hook here we will just get back our response
data in the end or undefined if we do have an error.
Now I don't care about the response data in this specific component so I can actually just a wait and
then log in thereafter.
Now we have to be careful though with this logic in the HP hook I said we do have try catch and we do
but in the catch block here we're not returning any response.
Instead we're just doing nothing which means automatically undefined gets returned.
Hence at the moment if we do have an error in here we'll actually still make it to this line here which
I don't want of course.
So a little improvement here actually should be that if we do have an error yes we set our error but
we then also throw the error again so that the component that uses our hook has a chance of knowing
that something went wrong and they offer a set as loading should be set here and also here in the success
case before we return a response data so now I am again throwing a an error here in the custom hook
into function there.
And so in our component we want to re add try catch just to make sure that we don't always call off
log in so let's move that in here.
Catch any hour or here in the catch block and call off logging only in the try block.
So if we get no error in the catch block we do have an error.
And while here I don't need to do much with it though we can log it.
We can ignore it because in the end here in the catch block I don't need to the error.
We're doing all of that.
We're setting our error a state ends on all in our custom hook so this can be an empty catch block in
the end.
Alternatively you could not use tri catch here and use the good old Venn method on the promise instead
and just omit a catch method now.
Similar logic flawed our of a request here there.
I don't care about the response but I want to send a request here.
It is a post request and the data is this that I hear so I will pass this as a third argument and then
these headers as a fourth argument just like this that's now a send request.
There it is and try catch to handle any errors we're getting we don't need to do anything of that here
though we just need to continue if we have no error or do nothing.
If we do have an error and then the error handler we want to call clear error.
This function we get from our custom hook or we get rid of the error handler altogether and then on
clear we just point at clear error which is this function coming from our own hook and with Dad let's
give it a try.
Let's save that go to a syndicate and maybe try logging in here.
If I do that.
See the spinner and I get an error here.
I got an error to a board controller is not a function that makes sense because I do have this a board
controller set up in a custom hook but at the moment I never remove and a board controller from my array
of a board controllers ever request completes.
That's a little oversight from my and of course we should do that once we have a response.
We know that the request complete it so once we're here after we passed the response body so here I
then want to go to my active HP requests and set current equal to active HP requests stored current
and filter out this specific controller that was responsible for this specific request.
So here I want to filter all my requests controllers and remove the request controller which I used
for this request which had you with this logic.
This keeps every controller except for the controller which was used in this request with Dad we're
not having any old request controller which we then would try to use to cancel our request which is
not on its way anymore but in addition the error actually although of course occurred because here I
have a board controller not a board controller.
The function is just named a board though so we got an error because I was calling a function that doesn't
exist.
But this call shouldn't have happened in the first place which is why adding this logic here also is
important.
We want to clear the board controllers that belong to the request which just complete it but of course
we also want to fix this error down there and make sure I use a board and not a board controller as
a function name or as a method name.
So with this change now we make sure we don't try to cancel a request which already completed and therefore
if we test us again here.
This looks way better now.
Let's also try signing up here and let's first of all try this with credentials where we should get
an error.
This works if I use valid credentials.
This also works and if I try signing up with invalid data I mean logging in with invalid data.
I get an error and I only continue if I have valid inputs.
So this is looking good to me it looks like our custom hook is doing its job.
And with that we can continue and we can use this custom hook in our users component as well.
Definitely feel free to try to implement it there on your own first in the next lecture.
We'll do it together.