So we get authorization added We got authentication at it.
Our app is really working quite well.
If there wouldn't be one issue when ever I log in and I reload I'm locked out again.
And this is really not that great.
It would be nicer if we could stay authenticated.
So did we reload.
We already are in the authenticated state again at least if our token is still valid it expires after
one hour.
So we'll have to reload again thereafter anyways.
But for that hour if we reload the page we should keep our authentication status.
And that implies one important thing storing it on the front end just in context isn't enough because
where is data stored that you store in your react context.
Well in the end just in memory it's stored in a variable in JavaScript in the end it's stored in memory
and whenever you reload the page in the anti entire react app restarts you could say a page reload is
like your react app restarting or starting it for the first time.
And that in turn means that any memory allocated to your old react app is basically lost.
So the tokens stored in memory is lost when you reload the page.
So to have it survive.
Page reloads we have to store it somewhere else that in memory.
And that is what we'll do now to store the tokens somewhere else in memory in app.
J.S. when we do log in and we set the token day offer I want to store it in a more permanent storage
as well.
And the browser we've got a couple of storage mechanisms we can find them in a browser dev tools here
actually if we go to the application area there you find things like local storage session storage indexed
TB and cookies now indexed TB is a quite complex database which we don't want to use for such simple
data as a token session storage is a bad storage because it's cleared whenever you close the browser
local storage is great because dear you can easily add and remove and manage data from javascript and
it survives browser restarts and page reloads and cookies are also great but not as easy to use from
inside javascript.
So we will use local storage to store the token.
And now here is one important note.
Some people are concerned about the security of local storage because you can easily write to it and
read from it with JavaScript which actually is the advantage you want to use here.
It has easy to use API cookies could be locked down to be not accessible from inside javascript.
And instead we could set them with the help of some server side headers known as adds extra complexity
on the server side.
But the most important problem with that is you have some fake security the problem some people have
of local storage is that because it's easy to access with javascript if people get access to your page
through a cross site scripting attack they can also read and write to your storage and they can steal
the tokens.
Now here's the error.
Many people who have this thought process make it's true if your app if your react application here
is vulnerable to cross site scripting attacks.
People can steal the tokens off your users but here's my point.
If your app is Will honorable to cross site scripting attacks you have different problems anyways because
the attackers can send age to the requests to the back and on your behalf and they could attach any
cookies that the users of your app path any ways so they can still get fake access to your back and
even without stealing the token explicitly.
So in general.
Of course you have to build an app that does not expose cross site scripting attack vulnerabilities
and our app here for example should be pretty secure although because react by default sanitize is anything
you output and you render to the screen.
So all the user generated content we're storing in the database when we output it on the screen with
the help of react then it's sanitized by react.
So we have built a cross site scripting attack protection here.
And unless we do something non reactive we should be pretty safe.
Therefore.
So this shouldn't be a problem for us and therefore we will use local storage to store our token.
That means here when we log in and we get the token we can access local storage like this.
This is a globally available object in JavaScript.
It's a global javascript browser API and we can add a new entry we've set item and here the entry of
want to create is actually called user data.
So not just token but user data.
And in there I will store a string you fight adjacent string you fight object because to local storage
you can only write text or data that can be converted to text like numbers.
Objects cannot be stored but with Jason bring your file of course you can turn the object into text
because Jason in the end is just text which looks like object.
So that is a way of storing an object in local storage.
And here I want to include my user I.D. so that you idea I'm getting on a user I.D. key and that token
I will store both in local storage with this command if I now save this and I do log in here
this succeeds but if I now have a look at my application area you see that deer in local storage you
have that user data entry and that's the value for it and that is Jason data.
It looks like an object but it's really just text.
But with Jason stringy fly and also a number method on that Jason object we can convert it back and
forth to and from JavaScript objects.
So now we get our data stored here.
Now that alone of course thousand logs in automatically when you reload.
But now we can use stats towards data to log the user in when he reloads.
So let's do that as a next step.