So let's use our custom HDP hook into users component for that first of all we need to import and of
course import use age to be client from shared hooks age to the PUK then justice before we can get rid
of these estates not off load of users.
I do want to manage this here in this component so I will call use h to be client here and what we get
back.
Just as before is an object which we can do structure.
There will have to is loading stayed our potential error state will then also have our send request
function there and to clear error function.
Now here I already got send request as a name and to a wide duplication all named as here fetch users
and they offer recall fetch users here of course so a little adjustment in the use affect function.
Then in here we can get rid of set is loading and then here I want to have try catch of course but I
will await send requests.
So does function that comes from my custom hook.
This needs are you are L and actually nothing else because it is configured to as a default send a GET
request not add anybody and not add any special headers.
So this is just fine as it is.
We don't need to do that parsing as you learned.
However of course what I get back here is my response data now because we do that parsing in the send
request function in our custom hook and therefore here we can set our loaded users if we have an error
we don't need to do anything here.
And I will remove set as loading here.
Now you see it as a fact complains here about a missing dependency because now indeed send request is
a dependency off use effect.
I used to send request function in there and the send request function is coming from outside.
The effect that's why it is important to have send request be wrapped and use callback here indie custom
hook.
Because if this would not be wrapped in use callback it would be recreated whenever to hook reruns and
the hook reruns whenever the component that uses the hook reruns because they recall use HD to be client
and it is just a regular Java's could function after all.
So of course it executes again and if does reruns and gives us a new send Request object even with the
same logic in the function it's technically a new object you as a fact would fire again and then you
request and we would have an infinite loop so use callback around send request in our custom hook is
super important.
With that we can correctly specify it as a dependency here as we should and we are sending our request.
Now we can get rid of the error handler and just point at clear error here on the on Clear prop and
with that we should be good.
If I now reload you see this seems to work if I reload we're fetching the users.
Now let's also see if we correctly get an error here.
If a for example sent us to an invalid you are L where I removed the s at the end and I get an error
could not find this root.
So this works of course our application is broken now but this clearly also is an error we should catch
as a developer during development.
So with that it works again.
This is looking pretty decent to me.
We're using our custom hook here and with the custom hook added now and being used in all our user related
routes it's now finally time to make sure that if we are authenticated we actually also are able to
create a new place here and send the request to the appropriate back and route there as well.