State is a crucial concept in react and with our knowledge about state we can now also make sure that
we don't just create a dummy goal but we actually reflect the real user input.
So for that let's go back to new goal.
What do we want to do is we want to store the user input in some variable on every keystroke so that
we have the latest value entered by the user and then pass that entered value to props on ad goal or
to our new goal here instead of that hardcoded dummy text we have at the moment.
So here in your goal I want to capture the user input here and send this instead of my hard go to text
here as part of the new goal.
So we could create a variable here.
User input or entered text maybe which is an empty string initially and here on input there actually
is a en change event we can listen to which is fired and every keystroke.
So now we can add a function
text change handler there we will get an event object and that event object will hold user input on
event target which refers to the input element value and therefore we could set enter text equal to
that now enter text will change with every keystroke.
Once we bind on change to text change handler like this.
Now here in New goal we can use enter text.
So what the user entered here and thereafter lets all the console locked and you go here so that we
can see that this works if we now save this and I enter test here and I click Add goal we see this works
and this is output here this approach is generally fine but it can have one tiny flaw.
What if we want to reset this.
After adding a new goal of course we can go to our add goal handler and once we created the new goal
we can of course set enter text back to an empty string.
But of course this won't do anything.
If I entered as goal you see this is not reflected here.
Why is it not reflected.
Because the new gold component didn't re render.
This is not state where managing this is a regular variable.
So of course we can change it.
Of course we can use to change the value but if we then set a new value to it.
This is not reflected on our input because this input only has a connection to the text change handler.
It does not know that it should reflect the current values stored and entered text.
Now we could tell the input component that it should do so by binding its value prop we can bind this
to entered text and with Dad we tell the input component hate the value displayed in the input should
be devalued stored and entered.
Text if we do that will notice something new.
Now we can't type there anymore if I type here.
The input is not reflected.
Now if you think about it that makes sense.
What you're telling react is that input should be rendered such that the value is to enter to text with
every keystroke we change enter text but enter text is not state it's a regular variable.
So that means that we changed a variable with every keystroke but react doesn't re render the input
component it doesn't reflect the updated value to react devalue always is an empty string because that
was the last time it rendered this component and therefore this us x code and therefore offered input.
So we need to tell react that this is some state and that when it changes it should re render our J
as X code.
So again we can import you as state here and convert entered text use a restructuring here and you state
is an empty string initially or has an empty string initially here because I'm managing my entered text
and the second element is a function to update the state which will therefore call set entered text
and now here on every keystroke I set my entered text to the value and event target value.
And here we don't need that function form of updating the state because we have a brand new value that
doesn't depend on the previous state.
So we can just update to state like this and now this will re render this component whenever we type
whenever we call set enter text so on every keystroke which sounds horrible but which is great react
we'll do this in a very efficient way and they offered this latest value will be reflected on the input
element and here in ad code handler if we want to update enter text and reset it we can def recall set
entered text and set it back to an empty string.
And was that we now have the best of both worlds we can enter something year that all works but we also
can manipulate it and reset after adding a new goal like this.
So this is now and never use case for a state management.
And of course there are many use cases in our ReACT application.
And here we are using state management to create something which is also sometimes called two way binding
where binding the value of the input and on every keystroke we're updating to value which we then bind
back to the input so that we always reflect the latest value inside of the input but we also are able
to manage this in a state driven way.
So we all have a chance of manipulating the value from inside our code up here and reflect this back
into the input in this case with that we have another scenario of state management and we are now able
to add our own goals.