Now actually before we move onto these user rods there's one tiny bug I want to fix or little oversight
from my site in places controller I have get placed by user I.D..
Now obviously here we can only get one place because in dummy places I added only one place.
If we had more than one place and that place had a different creator I.D. or it had the same creator
I.D. It wouldn't matter.
I would always just get the first place where the creator I.D. matches.
Of course that's wrong.
This year should be called Get play says by user I.D. and instead of a single place we should be retrieving
multiple places here because every user can have multiple places.
There can be more places here that shared the same creator I.D. It's not a unique one to one mapping.
We can have multiple places with the same creator I.D..
So therefore here we want to have get places by user I.D. and here we don't want to find which gives
us the first place that matches the criteria we want to use filter instead because filter will return
a new array full of elements that fulfill this criteria.
So full of elements.
Where did creator I.D. equal to the extracted user I.D. therefore let's name this here places and check
if we don't have places or more realistic if places length is equal to zero maybe if that's the case
we didn't find places for that creator I.D. And then I want to return cannot find places for the provided
user I.D. and here of course I return places and not a single place.
Now we need to adjust it down there on the exports as well.
This should be get place sets by user I.D. in on both sides and in the in the places.
ROBERTS Of course here.
I also want to point at get placed says by user I.D. with Dad if we save that and we go back to postman
and send the request to local host 5000 slash API slash places slash user slash you 1 which is that
one dummy user I.D. I have here.
Right.
We should get back and erase if I sent this here it's an array of places.
Now of course with only one place because we have only one matching place but that's battered and nothing.
If I sent this for you two for example we get back could not find places for the provided user I.D.
because indeed we have no places 40 provide the user I.D. then.
So that is now better than before.
This is the actual functionality I want to have in get places by user I.D. So let's make sure to fix
that.