To create a new place and to add it to user room we have to go to our places controllers now right here.
First we have to import our user model here because as you want to interact with the user well we kind
of have to establish that connection.
So let's import the user here and this is located in dot dot slash models slash user.
So with that we can use our user schema.
Now we can go down to our create police content right here and this is where we have to change some
things.
One thing that will change is the data type of The Creator a field.
Previously it was a simple string.
Now since we will establish a relation between places and users it'll be a special type which Mongolia
uses to manage.
I.D. wise is the case because we now store a real Mongo DP I.D. in this field not any dummy string anymore
but generally our created place content is fine.
Things changed down here though because instead of immediately saving the place we have to check whether
the user I.D. be provided exists already because only we have a user created with the corresponding
I.D..
We should be allowed to create a new place for that.
I'll create a new variable and name it user and I like and wrap the following code in a try catch block.
It's again the same logic we had before.
So in case we have any general error we should catch this.
Therefore we can actually get started with the catch block here and storage and a constant again.
Which is a new HP error here stating that creating place failed.
Please try again with a 500 error code and I'll return next code here.
So that's what it did before.
So that's just some general error but now the question is what do we actually want to do with our user
here.
Well user should be equal to user dot find by idea creator because what we want to do right here is
we want to access degrade the property of our users and check whether the I.D. we have for our log in
user is already stored in here.
So we want to check if the idea of the user is existing.
That's the code we have right here.
And as we are in an asynchronous task we have to add a weight right here once again.
So we want to check whether the idea of the logged in user is existing already in case we have a general
problem.
We catch it right here but in case our check is successful.
So in case we can check the idea of the creators well then we just wanna make sure that if the user
is not existing so if the user is not in our database.
Well then again we have an error stating that we could not find user 4 provided ideas.
Aero coach would be four or four here.
Don't forget to return the arrow once again to stop our code execution.
We could also console lock the user here if we want to.
That's optional though.
But let's maybe add it here in our code.
But if this user is existing well then we can do two things now.
First we can store or create that new document with our new place.
And second we can add the place added to the corresponding user to do this.
We have to replace this code here or we factor this code here.
The catch lock is fine but here try this is what we have to work on to do that.
We need to be able to kind of execute different or multiple operations which are not directly related
to each other.
And if one of these operations fails.
So if either creating the place fails or if storing the idea of the place in our user documents.
So if one of these operations fails independently from each other then we want to make sure to undo
all operations.
So basically to throw this error without changing anything in the documents so that's important thing
we want to do two things.
And only if both things succeed we want to continue and we want to change our documents to do that.
We need to use transactions and sessions that transactions simply does what I just said the transaction
allows you to perform multiple operations in isolation of each other and to undo these and the transactions
are basically built on so-called sessions.
So to work with these transactions we first have to start a session.
Then we can initiate the transaction and once the transaction is successful the session is finished
and these transactions are committed.
So with that our place is created and De Place ready stored in our users document.
Sounds a bit complicated again.
Let's do it step by step now and you'll see it's actually quite straightforward process what we first
need is a new constant let's call it sash maybe this is basically our current session that starts when
we want to create this new place for that we have to add a weight again we are still in an asynchronous
task here and we have to refer to the start session method Mongoose provides as I said with the session
here we can now also start our transaction so in our current session we want to start the transaction
another method we can use here and with that we can now tell Mongoose what we want to do here what we
want to do here is we want to make sure that our created place should be saved right.
We want to save it in the database and as an argument we have to provide the session property and refer
to our current sessions or a session that is currently running with that we will create a new place
and automatically create the unique idea for our place here and saving.
We learn that already is of course an asynchronous task therefore make sure to add a weight here.
So this was part 1.
Now we store the place and now with the place being created we need to make sure that the place idea
is also added to our user.
For that we can refer to our user here and now say user dot places right.
We want to access our places property.
And here we want to push so to add basically the created place pusher is not the standard push but you
can use on any javascript array by the way instead this is a method used by Mongoose which kind of allows
Mongoose to behind the scene establish the connection between the two models we are referring to here
so to say very important here behind the scenes Mongo DP grabs the created place a d That's an integrated
Mongoose feature here and adds it to the place feed off the user so it only adds the places idea that's
important that the stage moves that we store the place we added the places idea to our user what's missing
now is of course another asynchronous task we have to save our newly updated user now and again this
updated user should again be part of our current session that we are referring to and only once all
these tasks are successful so we could create the place we could at the place D and we could save the
user well then we want to make sure that this session commits the trends action right here another asynchronous
task so don't forget to add a weight and just to make this clear here only at this point the changes
are really saved in the database if anything would have gone wrong in the tasks that are part of the
session and transaction all changes would have been rolled back automatically by Mongo TB and that's
it actually.
With that we use the session and the transaction for all these tasks and only if this is successful
then the place will be created and the user will be updated and just to give you some examples when
this error code could occur either our database server is down or something related to that or database
validation fails.
So these are two cases when things could go wrong here the response can stay the way it is.
There is one important thing we have to know Don because so far when we created a new user or a new
place and we didn't have a collection de collection was created automatically in Mongolia IBM for a
transaction is this different here.
If we don't have an existing collection.
So in our case you want to create a new place.
This means we have to create a police collection.
Remember here police chiefs we have placed this means police says without the capital P It would be
our collection name.
So we have to create this collection manually you know because if you go to our Mongol TB database you
see we have two places database that's a database name but this database only contains one collection.
Therefore we have to hit the plus right here and now add the collection name.
Places like this and press create this make sure our transaction is successful.
As I said this is only required if we don't have the collection created already.
With that let's go back to our code and make sure we save our places controllers our police chiefs and
our user j ust file and of course that our development server is running.
And if we now go to our database to users here we can all first delayed our two existing users
and write their to start this whole thing from scratch.
Now let's go to postman create a new post request here slash users slash sign up to create a new user
we need the body raw data and Jason.
And now we need to provide our name let's say menu here then we have to provide our email which could
be test at test dot com and we need to provide our user password for the newly generated user here let's
use testers again with that if I'll hit send we should see that the user he's created.
We see we have an empty array for the places as this new user doesn't have any places at the moment.
And we see the idea right here.
And if we now go back to our database and reload we can also see that the user was created right there.
Although if the object added here let's copy this I.D. because now we will create a new place and here
as I said before we have to copy and paste this user I.D. to allocate this to a specific user.
This will be changed in the authentication part.
I repeat that don't forget about that.
It's just a dummy solution at this stage of the project.
So back in postmen we have to create another request another post request to localize 5000.
But this time not users but simply places we need.
Again the body and raw and Jason format here and now which properties do we need.
We need the title again and let's stick to the Empire State Building here.
We need a description.
Again a very famous building.
We need to address I'll add it in a few seconds.
Let me first copy paste our Creator idea here.
This one's idea of the user we just created.
And now let me quickly grab the address of the Empire State Building and again using Google Maps for
that.
Here we go create tur by the way.
So missing the a.
Not a properties look fine with that if we had sent.
Now we get back an error and I think I know why to be honest because while we are using Mongoose here
right and up here We didn't import it to our file.
Well this can of course not work.
So let's quickly add Mongoose here save this.
And if you now go back to postmen and again hit send I think this should work.
Yeah.
This looks good.
Now we created this new place.
So this is de Place idea.
And on here we also get back our Creator ideas and if we have a look at Mongolia be once again in our
places collection.
We can also see that the place was created successfully also with the place I did and the creator idea.
And if I remember that a five at the end that's the idea of the place.
And if we check now our users will see we have the area right here.
And if we click onto this area you can see a five.
At the end this is the idea of our place.
So this seems to work fine.
Let's not see what happens if we enter a wrong user I.D. for that we can just change the seven here
to a six for example.
And if we had send we get back could not find user four provided ideas.
So this works fine.
This means we can only create a new place.
Now if the user I.D. is existing and this was exactly the goal of this operation here what is missing
now though is of course the option to also delete the place.
And if we delete the place we kind of have this similar logic.
So we want to delete the actual place and we want to delete the idea of this place in the document off
the corresponding user.
Let's implement this as a next step.