I want to set a timer which basically ensures that we lock the user out automatically if the token expired.
To do this I will add a new variable up there logout timer it's actually outside of my app because it's
just some behind the scenes data I need to manage not data which should re rendered as component or
anything like that.
So it's not a state of this component but just a general variable in this file.
And now I want to use or I want to set this timer here whenever our token changes so we'll add a new
use effect call here we can have more than one effect and the dependency here is my token if the token
changes then I want to work with my timer.
Now it either changed because we locked in no matter if we locked in through the form or through order
log in or it changed because we locked out.
So you don't want to check if token is valid which is the case after a log in.
And in this case I want to call set time out here like this.
And point at the log function if this timeout triggers.
So log out the log function also as a dependency here thanks to use callback it's never recreated and
we have no infinite loop now to duration here of course depends.
Sometimes it's an hour but after all to log in it all is very likely is less than an hour.
So we should make sure that we reflect this expiration time here as well.
Now the expiration time changes whenever we call log in India end then we got a new expiration date
hence we can store it is as a state here token expiration date and set token expiration date.
And here I call use state and setters to nothing at the beginning in log in.
Then create a constant named Token expiration date thanks to scoping.
This will be a different constant than up there but if this is confusing to you you can choose a different
name here and here then of course but this will not overwrite our state or anything like that.
It's just a shadowed variable in the end.
I do want to call set token expiration date here though to also set my state and set it to the derived
token expiration date.
We got here so I set this here and react will batch these state updates together so it will not update
the same component three times instead it will just batches all into one update and thereafter in the
next three render cycle of this component will have to correct token expiration date so this will then
be the token expiration date.
So here in use of fact down there we should also add this as a dependency now because I will use it
in this use affect function if I got a token and I got a token expiration date then I want to set my
timer.
Now of course the timeout here does not take token expiration date as a second argument though because
it is is a date year and not duration not a number which I need to enter here though.
So we need to calculate the remaining time so remaining time for the token to be valid is basically
the token expiration time which is a date object minus new dates so minus the current date.
Now like this this won't work but we can call get time here to again get this in milliseconds since
the beginning of time which is somewhere around 1970 in JavaScript.
And here we call get time.
So now we got the difference in milliseconds and that's exactly what we need here because set time out
wants a duration in milliseconds so I can parse remaining time as our argument here.
And with that we set the timer to take as long as it takes for this token to expire.
Now if we have no token or no token exploration time.
Then I want to clear my time out.
So I want to clear any ongoing timers because maybe we got no token anymore because we manually clicked
on logout.
In this case we set the token to no use effect with trigger and it would want to clear my timer because
there is no need to trigger logout again later if we locked out manually.
We just might end up with multiple timers or something like this.
If we then log in again which is definitely not what we want.
Thankfully set time out returns us an I.D. off the timer created and we can store it is in logout timer.
So in this variable I have up there.
It's just some behind the scenes data is stored so we don't need to manage this in state.
And then I can use the same logout timer here to clear this timer whenever the token changes again.
So when we log out we cleared a timer.
When we log in we set a new timer.
So with that we hopefully have a flow that now works.
Now let's see this.
If I authenticate and I log in I am locked in of course.
Now if I reload here I stay locked in.
Now if I go to the application area off my def tools here I can edit the state a bit and go to the end
and now change that time here to actually 1 hour early on and then let's say 50 here.
If I now hit enter and I reload I was still locked in but if I wait for a few seconds this time will
be reached and I should not be logged in automatically anymore because my time is no longer in the future
then so let's wait a couple of seconds here and indeed now over reload I'm on authenticated again.
So this work because I manually hacked is of course but just to prove that this auto log in logic works.
Now let's see if we are logged out of the timer expires and for Dad temporarily I will reduce his log
in period to not 1 hour but just 2 seconds.
So did we see if we are locked out after these two seconds so if I do log in here I am locked in of
course but after two seconds you see the switches.
However now if I try to log in again I immediately am unsophisticated.
So something is not working correctly here and that most likely has something to do with logout because
remember we're having token expiration date as a state now but in logging.
I'm not clearing this I'm clearing the token but not expiration date.
I should reset this to null here as well.
Otherwise we still have our old expiration date managed in state here which of course will lead to an
immediate log out which I don't want.
So when we log in I also want to clear my existing token expiration date with that if we tried as again
and I do log in here I am logged in and after 2 seconds I should be logged out.
But if I log in again this should be possible.
Yeah and if I reload real quick you see then I had my auto logging going on but of course a new timer
was set which is super short and I am logged out.
So this all seems to work.
And with Dad we can of course increase does again and not wait for 2 seconds but 1000 times 60 times
60 instead.
And we d forgot properly implemented authentication with the functionality to automatically log a user
in and the functionality to automatically log our user out both after our regular form based logging
or dis auto log in I just talked about.
So this is our finished authentication flow.
Now let's just do some refactoring to clean it up.