This is react in a nutshell.
No there is way way more to react and we'll see way way more.
Our course project where we will build an entire app with react where we will also add routing and do
more complex user input management and so on.
But for does refresher we learn everything we need.
Now as I mentioned multiple times really also take some dedicated react resources no matter if that's
my complete guide course or the official box or any other tutorial.
If you are serious about react this course has not the goal of teaching you react from the ground up.
I do explain a lot to ensure that we're all on the same page and I will explain every feature we add
for all this course.
But in dedicated resources you simply get a way deeper and better insight into react into all its features
including features which we don't need in this course and how it works under the hood.
So that's my strong recommendation from this refresher.
The most important takeaway is that you understand that React is all about components that components
are functions that return J as X or JavaScript classes with a render method which we don't use here
though that components can receive props to receive data from parent components that props can also
receive functions pointers at functions so that the child component the component used in a natural
component can communicate back to its parent component so to the component using it and that you have
this very important concept of state which allows you to manage data that when changed with one of the
state updating functions actually causes react re rendered a component and re rendered to J as X code
and re-evaluate what needs to be output on the screen.
This is what allows you to render dynamic content with the help of react.
These are all the important takeaways and again there is more we will learn and more you can learn about
react in general but these are the concepts which definitely should be clear by now.