So for all this module we learned how we can connect our backend our node Express back and in our case
to among would be database.
We learned what Hmong would be actual is we had to look at no secret about the simple databases and
build around how we can set up Hmong TB with Mullah TB Atlas.
We then use the default Mongol TB tribe of firsts.
You connect to the server and to create and get products.
This was the code we wrote here in our Mongo J S file.
We soon saw that using the Mogadishu driver is fine but a bit cumbersome.
Therefore we then added Mongoose to our project mongoose is the third party library which kind of manages
the interaction between our backend and Mongo would be in a very efficient way and allows us to focus
on real business logic.
Also because Mongoose comes with this concept of schemas and models which allows us to create blueprints
for documents stored in our database with Mongoose we can make interacting with the database a lot easier.
We saw it here in our Mongoose Che s file when we simply use the model in the end and we also saw that
besides managing the connection we saw it up here with the connect method or saving documents easily
or finding documents easily Mongoose also helps to convert the ideas so the object idea that gets created
automatically among would be to a string.
Again another nice little helper function.
And with that we hopefully refreshed our knowledge on one would b and mongoose in the next module.
We can now implement this knowledge into our course project.
Really looking forward to this.
So let's continue.