So the missing pieces that we can delete places and for that on user places on a single place.
So on such a place item actually in the place item component we get that delete button and there at
the moment or just console logging deleting here instead I want to send that age to the request now.
So to do that again we import our custom hook so to use HBP client hook from shared hooks age to be
hook of course that's the hook we need.
Now just as before we can initialize it here with object restructuring and get is loading our or a send
request and clear error all the functionality is we used multiple times by now and we want to send the
request and they confirmed delete handler now because dad Data's when we're sure that we want to delete
we can turn us into a sync function date for us so that we can use a single wait in there and call send
request and send us to a specific you are ell which has a dynamic segment which is why I'm adding back
ticks here why I'm using back ticks.
Because if we check the back and then our places routes we see that the place I.D. needs to be part
of the U.R.L..
So we need to send this to local host five thousand slash API slash places slash the idea of the place.
So here it is HDP local host five thousand slash API slash places slash the idea of the place and we
get that place idea here.
Fruit props in place list I forward the.
Prop here which points at the place I.D. So in place item J.S. I can just use prop stored ideas here
this sends a request but by default that gets request.
So we should change this to delete to make sure it's a delete request.
We don't need to add any body or extra headers though we can then await this and of course all the rapid
and try catch to ensure that we only continue if this really succeeded.
So here and catch I won't do anything.
If we succeed.
The question is What do I want to do.
Well in the end I want to reload the page we're on right because in the end we are on the page where
we display all places.
Well if we deleted a place I just want to make sure that we update the current page knowing the place
list component we need and map our list of places into place.
Items and we get our items here from user places in the end and then user places we have our loaded
places.
So in the end we need to tweak the loaded places once we delete a place.
So in the place item component.
Once we're done deleting I will call props on the lead and expect that on delete I get a function which
in the end therefore is executed through that prop.
So in the places component we have to make sure that we set the on the lead prop on a place item which
is where I call this to a function which I expect to get from outside.
So here in place list I will also call on delete place let's say.
So I will forward this to a number of function I expect to get on a on delete place prop directly on
this place list component.
So now we need to set on the left place as a prop on the place list here.
On the left place.
And now here in user places with just a component I'm working and now there I want to trigger a function
plays deleted.
Handler maybe.
And here I want to update my loaded places appropriately.
So let's put plays deleted handler into all delete place and Dale for in the end we forwarded to on
the lead in the place.
Item and then user replaces Indy's place to lead handler.
I don't want to call set loaded places and update my loaded places and then when I update them such
that they filter out the place which was just deleted for Dad we can use the function form of setting
a state here.
So we got our previous places and I want to return to new places and the new places are based on the
previous places but there.
This is an array I want to call the filter method to filter out a certain place so we'll go through
all my places here and only keep the places where the idea is not equal to let's say the deleted place
I.D. which I expect to get as an argument here so I expect to get this parameter here delete the place
idea and only if the place I'm looking at in my existing array of places is not equal.
I'll keep it because if it is equal it's the place I want to delete.
So in the new Array which I return here it should not be included so that I set my loaded place a state
to a new array where the deleted place is filtered out now we just have to make sure that we pass this
delete it place I.D. to this function and in the end we are calling this function place item J.S. here.
So here we should forward props I.D. because that's the idea of the place which was deleted.
This is the trick.
Hopefully this should do the trick.
Now let's still handle the loading and the error state here and therefore we import the arrow modal
from shared components UI elements error modal add of course import our loading spinner here from shared
components UI elements loading spinner.
And with that if we go down there and react fragment we can add our error modal here and there forward
our error we might be getting and point on clearer at clear error or side note also make sure that and
confirm delete handler.
You call set show confirm modal false first so that you close to confirm modal before you sent that
request and may be all to open up an error mode thereafter.
So we don't have multiple models open at the same time and to all the show loading state.
I'll scroll down and here inside of my card.
So on top of this place which I want to delete I will check for is loading and then send or render my
loading spinner in that overly mode.
If we are loading with that if we save this.
Here are the places.
Let's now log in like that and now a year if I click delete I can cancel Of course.
But if I click delete here you'll see the loading spinner.
And we're done now this year looks good to me.
It seems to work if I reload.
Let's see if it still is gone.
It is and if we check the database now.
And we refresh the places we should only see one place.
Yes we do.
And for a user as if we check that we should also see that the first user only has one connect the place
so that this connection to the place was all that clear there and the other users have no places.
And this is looking good to me it looks like our application is working and we successfully connect
that front end and back end.