So let's start by adding validation to our patch road in the places rules file they are all at the second
middleware which is actually an array of millionaires.
And again we can check the incoming data here.
Now when we update a place there are two pieces of information which are extracting title and description.
So I want to validate these two pieces.
I want to check the title with the title field here and check that it's not empty.
So the same criteria I had up there.
Well before the description I always want to have the same.
So I will check that we have a min length of five characters.
And now with that let's go to the places controller and actually we can now copy that logic which we
got and create place.
We can simply copy that over to update place so that we first check if we do have validation errors
and if we do I sent back my error response.
If we don't I continue with my normal updating logic here.
So with Dad let's give it a try.
Let's try it running this patch request with an empty string for a title and this fails.
Now let's enter something valid here but have a description which is too short and it fails.
And you also see that it does not just fail.
It really also doesn't apply any of the updates of course.
Now if I do enter a valid description however this succeeds and therefore if I get that single place
we see that updated data here as well.
Now that's the validation for the other places right now for the user routes.
I also want to validate.
So first of all let's import the check method here in the places where it's file and now the question
is Where do we need validation the obvious answer is these two routes.
Right.
These two post routes but actually I would argue that we only need to validate on the sign up road.
Why.
Because when the user logs in we're searching for a user with that email and thereafter we're comparing
passwords.
So if invalid data was entered there the log in will fail anyways.
So there isn't really a need to validated before we run our logic.
Hence I will only add validation here on the sign up around there.
I want to check the name of the user and make sure that it's not empty.
I'll not require a minimum length because well we have very short names in the world as well.
Right.
Just as we have very long ones.
So I certainly don't want to check for any minimum or maximum length just not being empty would be a
great thing.
I also want to check the email and there I will validate something else.
I don't care whether it's empty or not.
I want to make sure it's a valid e-mail address and for that we have the normalized email method which
for example makes sure that test at test dot com is converted to test at test dot com enter after after
normalize email.
I also want to call is email and this now validates that this really is a valid email address after
being normalized and last but not least the password the user chose also has to be checked.
Here I want to check that it has a min length of six characters for security reasons now justice before
this is one half of the validation logic we all need to copy this year where we check for validation
errors into our sign up middleware.
And that means we need to import devaluation result function.
So here I will use object D structuring to get validation result out of the object I import from Express
validator and then down there we sent back our error response.
If we couldn't validate the input data now with that back to postman and let's try to sign up with an
empty name invalid inputs past let's try to sign up with a valid name but an invalid email address.
I deleted the at symbol does not work.
Let's try to sign up with a password which is too short doesn't work and let's enter validator everywhere.
And this works now for a log in.
If I for example leave the email field empty we simply couldn't identify a user.
And that's totally fine.
We need no extra validation there.
So this all is looking good.
The added validation I noticed there is one place where we can add some extra logical step and that
is for a delete place.
I want to check if we have a place before we try to delete it.
So I'll check if dummy places find finds a place where the idea is equal to the place idea we're trying
to get rid of.
And if that is not the case if this is false see then I actually want to throw a new HP error where
I want to say could not find a place for that I.D..
And hence not returned is delete place message.
That's just a little bonus which I want to add to ensure that when we do delete a place it works.
If we do have the I.D. but we get back could not find a place if we don't have to I.D. or don't have
a place with that I.D. instead of always returning delete place with that validation was added and now
the only missing piece which I still want to implement here is that when we create a place I don't want
to assume that we get the coordinates from the client but instead my assumption here is that we get
the address and we then translate that to coordinates by actually working together with the never rest
api which we won't write on our own but which instead already exists a rest api created by Google which
helps us well convert addresses to coordinates.