To output Google maps with react or to render a Google Maps driven map and react.
You'll find plenty of packages if you search for a react Google Maps and you could absolutely use one
of these packages.
I will not do that though but instead build my own basic custom map to show you how that would work
behind the scenes because I think that's really interesting to see and to learn now for this in the
shared you ie elements folder here.
Let's add a new map J.S. file and a map C as as file next to it now in the map J as file we build a
regular react component of course by importing react from react.
And then here our map component which receives props.
And then by exporting that map component.
And then of course all the import dots slash map yes as you can probably soon do that asleep.
Now here let's return a death that div will be the the host so to save for our map and that Dave will
receive a class name which should be set dynamically.
So I will again assign a default clause of map but then also offered the possibility of customizing
this.
You don't have to then use this possibility but at least you could I will also set style to props styles
so that you could also directly manipulate the inline styles just adding some extra flexibility here.
No matter if we use it or not.
Now I want to render a map here with Google Maps and for Dad we need to Google Maps SDK so you can search
for Google Maps Javascript SDK and you'll find the official documentation.
Now first of all we need to setup a project here and get a API key we'll all later by the way in the
notorious module do the same because there will need some other service from Google and you can then
later reuse the project you're about to set up here to set up such a project.
You need a Google account and click on get started now.
Also one important word here for Google Maps and to use their tooling and their API eyes and their esta
case.
You need an account with a credit card.
It's generally free to use and you can search for Google Maps pricing to find their pricing information.
You get to 100 dollars of free usage every month which is a lot and which definitely suffices for what
we're doing here in this course.
But if you're using it in a real project of course you should definitely check which prices or which
amount which costs you can expect and you also now need a credit card to continue and render a map.
If you don't have one of course you could look into alternatives like map box or simply render some
dummy div with a background color here so that you can still continue with the course even if you're
not seeing the map.
Unfortunately you need a credit card not my rules but Google's now here in this overlay what you see
on Google's page check maps and also maybe places because we'll need that later when we in the notice
module also need a Google project and unlocked maps functionalities click continue their offer and now
you have to select or create a project there.
I will create a new project which I'll name Merlin but you can pick any name you want here and click
Next notice will take a while and you'll have to confirm that this is the account you want to use for
billing.
As I mentioned what we do in the course here will be possible for free but definitely check the pricing
if you're using it in a real project.
Confirm this year and after while the creation will be done and you should see an overlay with your
API key which you will also need.
If you're not seeing it go to API eyes and then click on maps.
Javascript API credentials and this is the API key here which you will soon need.
Now why do we need it for that search for Google Maps JSA SDK again and go to their docs again where
we've been before.
Here you'll learn how to render a map with Google Maps and here you learn way more than what we will
use in this course.
So if you want to become a Google Maps expert and you want to use it in a lot of different ways in your
next project these docs are the place to go.
Now one thing we need to do is we need to grab this script here and add this to our index H to Mal file
their let's say here at the bottom of body.
But since it has a single defer on it this doesn't do matter so maybe also here in the head.
We entered this script and now here we need to inject our API key.
So this API key I just mentioned copy it and then here replace your API key without the ampersand with
your API key but get rid of that callback in it math thing here so that you just have to script import
ending with your API keep this will import D javascript package that helps you render Google maps with
that let's go back to our map chars file because here we can now use this package which has added to
our application in there.
In this component we create a map with new window dot google dot maps dot map.
This is a constructor function which will now be available on the global Window object in the end.
Thanks to this input we just added here this SDK will be loaded and will add global variables on the
window object the Google variable to be precise which then gives us access to the maps feature and then
ultimately to the map constructor function.
This now needs a pointer at an element.
So in this case at this div where the map should be rendered.
Now to get this pointer in react world will not use.
Document get element by I.D. and assign an I.D. to the div even though did all the work but it will
do it in a more elegant way.
We can import use ref from react this is another hook which we haven't used before.
Use ref can be used to create so-called references which can be one of two things we often use them
to get a reference a pointer at a real Dom node that's one use case a very prominent one.
The average one is actually that with refs.
We could also create variables which survive re render cycles of our components and don't lose their
value.
But that's not what we need here.
So all we do here is we create a map or constant by calling use ref whips concert and then on the dev
here we add a special prop the ref prop which react understands where we point at the map ref and react
does the rest and sets up a a magic connection between this death and this constant so that in this
constant we in the end score a pointer to this death.
And now here to this map constructor we pass map ref though not like this.
In step there we have a current prop which holds this actual pointer which we need.
So now we tally Google maps where it should render the map.
Now the map constructor here takes a second argument which is an object where we can configure that
map specifically we can set a center and assume level.
Now I want to make sure that both can be set from outside.
So here I want to be able to use props center and props soon so that this is really controlled from
outside.
This component and now it would also be nice to render a marker at the center.
And by the way you can learn all that syntax here in the official Google Maps docs in case you're wondering
how I know all of that.
So here to render a marker I is simply call New when no dot google maps dot marker and 2 Marker you
pass an object which has a position key which should be prop start center and as a second argument you
pass on a map key which should point at your map object which you created before.
So here this map constant.
This will create a new marker in the center of our map.
Now with that we have everything in place which we need to render a map.
So let's now go back to the place item and import map from shared components UI elements.
Map like this and render it here instead of age to the map.
Instead we render our map here as a self closing component.
And now on this map we have to provide this center prop which should be props coordinates and assume
prop which I'll set to a level of 16 which should work quite well.
Not important this coordinates prop here right.
This has to have a specific format.
You'll find that in the official box of the Javascript SDK Of course it has to be an object with a let
at the LNG key where both values are numbers.
Now that's exactly what we have in our coordinates prop here because in place list where a set the coordinates
of a place item I refer to placed on location.
And if we have a look at a place there we do have a location property which is exactly an object off
that structure we need.
If you created this in a different way you definitely have to add some step to map it into the value.
Google Maps expects here so into an object with a let and the LNG key and with that let's save this
and let's have a look.
If I click on View and map this crashes.
Now why is that while this is something to do with some react internals.
Let's have a look at the map component again I've rendered a map by using map ref current here.
Right.
And that uses our reference which I said is magically set up with the help of react here to this diff.
Now what's the problem here when this component renders for the first time which will in the end happen
when we render our place item then does is executed from top to bottom.
We initialize our ref but the connection has not yet been established because this part hasn't executed
yet.
And this is where the connection is established.
So we just initialize the ref but there is no connection yet.
And then the very next step I tried to render a map in that place.
But the connection was not established yet so this can't work because Google Maps can't find out where
to render this.
Now thankfully react has got us covered.
We can import a number important took the U.S. a fact took.
I haven't covered it thus far but it's a super important hook and we'll see it a lot throughout this
course.
U.S. effect allows us to register logic a function that should be executed if in certain inputs change.
So for example here we set up use effect and we set up the function that should run and then as a second
argument to use effect an array of dependencies of that function.
And whenever one of the dependencies changes then the function here will be read execute it.
If we specify no dependencies this will only execute once when the component is initially mounted and
loaded and never thereafter.
So now we can move our map creation and market logic into this function we have in use of fact here
now whether it moved in there.
We should also be clear that center and assume in the end our dependencies here.
So we'll use object D structuring again to get these two proper properties out of props center and soon
I do this so that I can add them as dependencies independently here and I don't have to add the entire
props object as a dependency which could change more often than just center and some so here in there
we just refer to center and soon therefore in all these places and now we have a use affect function
which will rerun whenever the center or to assume value which is passed in from outside changes and
again that's just object D structuring a default javascript feature which pulls elements out of props
or which pulls keys and their values out of props.
So out of this props object and stores them in New constants.
Now how does this help us.
Well use effect will run Windows component first is rendered because then center in some changed today
had no value before.
Now they have a value but and that's the important thing about use effect and why it helps us here.
It will run after J as X has been processed and rendered so it will run in the first render cycle but
after the J is X code has been rendered.
And that means disconnection here will have been established by the time this code runs and we take
advantage of this.
If we now save this this reloads and if I now click on View and map this works I'm not seeing the map.
So something is still wrong but generally it works.
We get no error.
So let's now make sure we also see the map though because that of course should be the case.
And the reason why we don't see the map is simply missing Stiles in our map component.
I have that map class here right on the death well in maps.
Yes SB should add some styles here for this map class selector and we should set with to 100 percent
and high to 100 percent so that the map is rendered in the entire container we provide to it.
And if we now safety's here as always should work.
Otherwise reload.
And now you should see that and you get a Google map here which you can scroll and move around and sue
in and out and really use like your normal Google Maps functionality.
You can even switch to satellite mode if you wish to.
So now we're rendering this if you click on View and map in our standalone modal and was that we already
achieved a lot here and we're still far from done we're not able to at place says authenticate is not
working and so on.
So there is a lot of missing work or a lot of missing functionality but we will get there.
This is a great step forward.