Before we conclude this module though let's have another look at our code and see if we can clean up
some things if we have some redundant code and so on because we changed a lot for this module.
Therefore let's make sure to keep the code as lean as possible you appear.
The first thing I see is our dummy places part.
I don't think we need this anymore so let's delete these right here immediately.
I think this outcome and that code can also be removed here.
We also got some out commented code.
I think we can also get rid of this right here.
Also this part then let's see here.
Yeah we could actually leave the places here to be honest.
As this is just an alternative way.
So let me maybe add our previous syntax you to once again just to make sure you can refer to it.
So this was the previous logic we had before we changed our approach to populate method here in the
last lecture.
So I just keep this as a reference here.
So this should be helpful I hope this looks all good for me.
Maybe also formed our code a bit here.
This and the rest looks fine for me at this stage.
Here we again have some cold.
We don't need any more.
So let's delete this one yeah.
And I think the rest of this file looks all right so we can keep this code.
Let's also have a quick look at our users controller here.
Here we also have some dummy information so let's delete our dummy users as we don't need these anymore.
Could also get rid of you you idea actually we don't need that idea generator.
So this looks okay now.
And if I look for the code does generally looks quite fine.
I don't think we have any more dummy code in here.
Same thing for place J Yes I guess this looks also good.
And also I'll use the tree as file looks all right.
Let's also check the places roads quickly whether we have any kind of comments here.
Note This looks OK and in use those roads.
Yeah here we have test a test outcome.
I guess this code can also be removed.
This old commented code and in the aptly us file we can also get rid of this I'll come into your code
here.
I would say but the rest looks alright with that.
We really arrived at the end of this module now and now is finally the time to conclude what we learned.