Now to conclude this module there are some tweaks which we can apply on the back end in the places controller
for example when we create a new place here we're extracting the idea of the user to whom the place
belongs.
From the request body No actually keep in mind did we protect this create place route here in places
routes we can only get to this route if we are authenticated and indeed check off middleware.
I am extracting the user I.D. and I'm storing it on this user data object on the request.
So actually it's better to not get the I.D. from the front end user where invalid I.D. could be provided
but instead to rely on the I.D. we extract that from the token which has to be attached anyways and
which can't be faked.
So here when I create a new place creator will be a request user data dot user I.D. to use does automatically
extract that I.D. which we get here and check off middleware.
This is a better approach of getting the I.D. instead of getting it as part of the request body now
just to avoid confusion in the places roots here where we need a user I.D. to get all the places for
a user that I.D. should still be part of the you are L because you're able to get places of any user
to see places of any user not just your own places.
If we would get user I.D. from the attached token we would only see our own places because that then
is the only user I.D. we know so here.
This should be part of you or else still.
Now another week I want to make is that I want to ensure that when ever we return user related data
we actually omit the password.
But I think we already are doing that.
So here in the places controller we are returning a message here here.
I returned a place converted to an object but there I got no user data mixed in it's just a place data
in create place in the end I returned he created place but again there we got just a user I.D. as part
of the place not the full User object for find or get places by user I.D. we do populate places on the
user but what I return then is just my array of places which again just has a user item then and not
the user data.
Besides that and forget place by I.D. we all have just returned to place now in the user controller
when we sign up I return user I.D. email and token.
I mean when we log in.
Sorry.
When we sign up I return the same though and when we get all users I return all my user data.
But I already exclude the password here with projection so we're already doing the right thing here
and we're never sending any confidential data over the wire here.
And with that I am happy with the setup.
Now we just need to reflect this change we made in the places controller where we now get the user I.D.
differently in the front end because now in the front end we can adjust our code and make sure that
when we add a new place here in New Place J.S. we no longer add to create or field to the request because
we're not interested on it on the back end anyways.
And with that let's give it a try.
Marine plots to there only is one but still
let's use the right address in the good old image we used before.
For now click Add plays.
This fails.
So let's see why it failed.
If we go to the back end I print NOL here yeah.
Of course it fails because I'm still using creator here to find a user by I.D. here of course I now
all to have to use the idea which is part of the request creator is not received anymore.
So with that however we should be fine.
Let's quickly search for a creator here.
This is all in different contexts so this should be working now.
If we save this and we simply read centers on the front end now it works.
Now we get to places here on manual can also delete a place of course and we get a working application
with a little bit of a cleaner back and.