So back in our application again I got the front end open here in one window and the back and in no
visuals you code the no next to it.
Now it's all about accepting files both on the front and as well as the back end.
And it's up to you where you want to start.
I would say let's start at the front end so that we have a file right away which you then can send to
the back end.
So do we then as a next step can work on accepting that file on the back end.
Now on the front that I got to places where I want to accept files one is the off page where new users
can authenticate where they can sign up.
When you do is sign up I also want to offer a possibility for the user to provide an image or not just
a possibility.
You have to provide an image.
So that's one place you should provide an image here.
The other place where I also want to accept the file is in the places area in the new place component
when you add a new place besides adding title description address and so on.
I also want to ensure that you have to provide an image for that place because we are using images for
places and for users and I have these really nice dummy images here.
Well it would be nice to replace them.
So in order to do that I will build an image picker and I will build a brand new component for that
which we can reuse both on the new plays as well as the off page.
So in form elements and shared components of form elements.
I will add an image upload dot J as file and of course you can named as however you want attached you
all to find that image upload.
Don't see us as file which you can just copy into this shared components form elements folder so that
in the image upload js file or in the image upload component we're about to build you have the right
stylings later of course you can always tweak them to your personal preferences we'll built the image
upload component together from scratch no.
And in there of course I will import react from react.
What we always did all setup my image upload component like this whips like this.
Accepting props from outside and then in their will later returns I'm J X..
And of course we have to export the component here so that we can use it in our files as well.
Now also don't forget to import image upload dot c as as to ensure that the styling gets applied now
in the image upload component.
I want the returns I'm j as X code of course.
So let's write that markup for the image uploader together.
Now as mentioned of course there are different ways of building this.
Here's just my way I will add a wrapping device which has a class name of form dash control.
This class name form control is provided an input CSX and whilst you might think that we're only importing
this here in input J.S. don't forget that all these classes generally are available globally in the
application.
They're not scoped to a component.
We're not using C as some modules or anything like that here.
Hence we can use the form control class also in the image upload component.
Now in there I want to add a input and that input will be of type file which is a default input type
supported by the browser.
This input will also receive an I.D. of let's say props I.D. and also a little inline style here.
Just a quick and dirty solution where I said display two non.
This is how you set inline styles and react to set an object to that style prop and then you have your
CSX properties on the left as keys and then the values here on the right as values well and I use display
not here because I actually want to hide this input with this play not it's still part of the Dom but
it's not visible because I will expose a button to the user which the user can click to bring up that
file picker.
I don't want to show this file picture itself because it's relatively ugly.
So I will hide it here set the type to file and set except here to dot Jay Peck comma dot PNC comma
dot Che pack with an E..
So these are the file extensions which a user is able to select then later.
Now of course as I said this is hidden so to show it.
I also want to render a button and for that I will import the button component from dot slash button
like this below this input here but inside of that surrounding div all day for add a new nested div
this div receives a class name of image upload and actually I want to be a bit more flexible there so
I will wrap this and put this into a template literal with back takes because I also want to check if
we do have a center prop being set equal to true or being set at all.
And if it is I also want to add a center class here.
This allows us to later control how the image preview which will add anti picker button will be positioned
if they're centered or not.
So inside of this new div I'll add yet another div here and that div receives a class name off.
Image dash upload underscore underscore preview because I want to show a preview ofthe picked image
in there.
We need a image element therefore.
And here we'll need to set the source to something and do all to something.
I'll set the all to preview.
The source is something we will come back to now outside of that div here.
So off that preview div but inside of this div I'll then add my button and they're all just say pick
image.
Now of course we have to set a tie up here and I'll set this to type buttons so that it doesn't accidentally
submit any form which we might have around our image upload component later.
And I will of course add on click listener.
So does on click prop to point at a function that should execute when the button is clicked and for
it we can add a function here to pick image handler the pick image handlers should be triggered whenever
we click this button and in the pic image handler I in the end want to make sure that we opened this
built in file pictures so that we utilize this input component which is invisible but which if we could
click it would open up a file picture so therefore to simulate a click on this we have to get access
to this input element and then just call its click method and to get access we can use a reference so
we can import use ref from react and now not use it to store some value which survives re render cycles
but instead to store of value which well which actually does survive re render cycles but which most
importantly establishes a connection to a dom element.
So here I'll have my file pick a ref created with use ref and set us here on input by adding the ref
key and pointing at file pick the ref here and then Andy pick.
Image handler we can use file pick a ref dot current and then called a click method.
This method exists on this Dom note and it will open up that file picker so we utilize the input element
without seeing it.
That's my idea here now.
When this gets clicked you file picture opens and once the user chooses a file on change fires on this
input.
So here we have to provide a function that should be triggered once user picked a file.
So here I'll add my picked handler function where I get an event object and I will wire this up to on.
Change here.
Picked handler and now here in the picked handler the goal is to generate something that helps us preview
that file down there.
And of course to then also forward the file to the surrounding component where we use the image upload
component in so for the moment here I'll just cancel log event dot target which is the file input in
the end and see what's in there.
And now let's go to our off page here and import this component of course we're not done with it yet
but for the moment we can already use it.
So I'll import image upload from shared components form elements.
Image upload and use that here in the off page there.
My idea is that just as with the name the name and put here I only want to show this image upload button.
If we are in sign up mode so I'll have the same check here if we're not in logging mode then I want
to render image upload like this.
And for the moment it can be as simple as that.
I'll just forward an idea here and that's the image idea.
This idea will be picked up in the image upload component.
For example I bind it here to this input.
If we now save that and this reloads and we go to authenticate and switch to sign up mode we see our
file picture here.
Now it would be nice if dev would be centered so back in the off page.
I will add this center prop to image upload and now if I switch back to sign up we see does centered.
Now that's nice but of course this doesn't look that great seeing while no image at all.
But what we can already see is if I click pic image this file picture your opened up automatically and
I can select an image there and there after you see this log on the right which locks this while this
file picker element Q to develop a console.
So this is generally working.
Now we have to work on managing this file correctly true getting a preview and getting it into our form
here so that we can submit this in the end.