Now in this module I will switch between the backend code set up which you can recognize by the word
back and here in the top left corner and the front end the react project with well front end here so
that you can always quickly see where we're working on back end and front.
And now for the back end I will start with one tiny adjustment in app J.S. where we have our connection
string to the database there.
I will now connect to a new database so that we basically start from scratch and we kind of clear all
the data we created in the previous modules so that we don't have in the old data lying around in the
database.
So here I will connect let's say Merlin in my connection strings so that all data gets written to collections
in that database and other than that I'm fine with the current state though and we can dive right in
and get started.