Now earlier in the courts we of course already planned our ReACT front and our single page application
pages.
We want to have there and pages here really means different React Components which then will be loaded
with help of a third party library that reads the browser you are L and instructs react to render different
components.
And here is our plan.
Now we'll not implement everything we see here in this module.
We will add all these pages or components but the authentication part you see on the right Dad will
be added later in the course.
Once we also added authentication on the server side.
So it's something we we can't ignore for now we can't really implement right now but we can build the
general skeleton and idea of the entire application.
So let's do that now.
Let's start with that and to get started.
I have a brand new project.
You'll find that project setup attached to this lecture here you can simply extract it and then run
npm install in the extract that folder and thereafter you can run NPM start.
Here I am again using that built in terminal in my I.T. NPM start to bring up that development server
serving our ReACT single page application.
Here this.
Now don't be worried regarding the gray background that will make sense later once we start adding more
and more components and styles this will be the general background color of this application.
Here of course it looks a bit strange.
Later it won't.
And of course all is not a must do.
But I will use it is to the developer tools here.
I like to have them open so that I can quickly see any errors we're getting and so on.
Cause you don't have to do that but I will work on this project with the developer tools open and with
that let's go back and let's start working on this application and add components pages and more.
But of course the question is how does that all work well.
There are different ways of getting started but since we know that we will have different pages I like
to add these pages which are regular React Components just components which will control everything
on the page.
Step by step.
So for that I'll first of all add a new sub folder in source and use sub folder which in the end will
hold my pages.
Now there are two approaches you could follow.
You could for example work with a pages folder which will hold your components that are in the end rendered
as full screen pages and you can add a components folder to hold your components which are not used
as full screen components but instead which are only used on parts of every screen.
For example a button component could be in the components folder then you place page component could
be the pages folder.
You can't do that end for application of this size.
It would certainly work.
However it's not the approach I will use because for bigger applications it can be hard to then quickly
find your different components and pages if they're all managed in two main folders and then a couple
of sub folders.
Instead I will split my logic by feature which means I will create a new folder in the source folder
which will named places and in there I will have a page's folder and a components folder some ideas
that I will have my place related components in the places components folder and replace related pages
in the well Places Pages folder.
Now why do I do that.
Because I'll also add a user folder next to the places folder so directly to source folder where I effectively
will set up the same structure components and then user pages.
Now this allows me to organize my components in a bit better way because I have user related components
and pages in the user sub folders and places related components in these sub folders.
Side note if you took my complete guide pages was effectively named containers because in react you
also sometimes refer to components that have a lot of state management logic in them.
Ask containers and pages tend to be components with a lot of state management logic in there.
I will opt for pages instead here to make it really clear that these are the components loaded with
the help of this routing package which we still have to install.
Now I will also add a third folder in source and that is shared folder because we will have some general
purpose components and also some other features which don't really belong to either places or users.
So in shared I'll also add a components folder no pages folder because pages by default can't be shared.
They can't be shared amongst multiple pages because a page is a standalone thing and later will also
add other things here to the shared folder.
For now just a components folder.
So this is the general structure I like to work with.
It's one possible structure not the only correct one but it is one which I think is particularly helpful.
Would working on bigger projects.
So with that general structure setup we prepared to folder structure.
Now let's actually quit the development server with control C and install a new package and that new
package which I want to install.
Is that a routing package that routing packages a third party library we can integrate dead will help
us read to you are elder user entered for example local hosts slash nothing whereas this slash users
or something like that and we'll then load different React Components on the screen based on the you
or L entered.
Technically we still are on the same single H HTML page but that a routing package will tell react that
now everything on the page should be replaced with the content of component B or off component a and
so on.
The name of the package is react router dom.
So lets npm install with dash dash save react dash router Dash.
Don this is a third party library not managed by the REACT team but a very popular library that helps
us implement this routing logic so that we don't have to manually pass the U.R.L. and then do different
things based on it.
So this now installs this let's wait for this to finish so installation finished for me and now we can
use that package to load different components as full screen pages in the end.
Now if you want to learn all about routing and the react router of course the official box of the react
routed on package are a great starting place.
Or as all as I mentioned before in my complete guide you also learn more about routing.
Here we will only use the features of the package which we need for this specific application.
So how does routing work then.
It starts in the app J File because in the end this is our route component right.
It's the component we render into that place here in index chain.
So app component really is the starting point of our entire application it's the first thing which is
getting rendered so it's inside of this component here created with the function keyword which all those
fine could also changed is to use the arrow function syntax.
So here in this component it is where I want to set up a routing.
Now how do we set up routing.
Well we first of all import something from that react router Dom package and that something is the browser
router here.
I'm using this import syntax instead of that syntax because react rather dumb actually is a package
that has named exports which means it exports multiple things by their name.
And then here this is using this curly brace syntax to target specific export of things by their name.
And here I need the browser router which is export it and I will also renamed as with as to just a router.
This is a feature you can use with iOS 6 modules which does in the end is to assign an alias to something
you're importing.
And now we can use that Roger here in the app component as our route.
J.S. ex element if you wrap this around everything that is part of the app that should be able to use
the router.
So we wrap this around every route that should be able to use our router.
The question is what should be able to use our router.
Well our pages should be loaded with help of the router.
For example if we go to the user pages folder there we can't add a user's J.S. file and in there I want
to create a very basic react component where we react from react and then I'll named as users.
And this is our regular react component where I can export it as a default.
And in a year I return users works just some dummy text so did we see that this is rendered.
If this is our users component and we want to load dad with the help of routing whenever the user is
unjust our domain slash nothing.
Well then we can go to app Chase and there we now can use a number of feature from react road router
Dom the root component.
Here we can use root as a component.
So as J as X code the end we're importing goods from react ruder Dom.
And on that root component which is provided by that package which can only be used inside of our router
which has to be setup as a surrounding element there on the root component we can't add a path property
and defined the path in the you are L so to think often a domain that should be entered to reach this
specific root.
So here slash and what should be rendered when that root is reached.
Well the thing you pass between the opening and closing tax off route.
Alternatively you can also add component prop to root and then create root as a self closing component
that all the works but moving forward this package actually all supports and alternative syntax where
you only set up the path on the root component itself and then you wrap the component that should be
loaded for this path inside of the root component tax.
So in my case I'll import users from dot slash user slash pages slash users and then render this year.
Now the trick is that this will not always be rendered on the screen but thanks to this wrapper of thanks
to this package it will only be rendered if ah you are L path is slash so if I saved is now and I restart
my development server we should actually see our users content on the screen because I am on slash nothing
by default here and hence we should see that.
So let's wait for the development server to start up and indeed I now see users works.
Now if I enter something else by the way I also see that though not just for a slash nothing.
The reason for Dad is that by default this path is treated as a filter which means any path that starts
with this will render users.
No that's not what I want.
I want to only render users if the POV is exactly this.
So exactly slash nothing.
After the domain you can enforce this by adding another property to route and that's the exact prop
you can set this to true but you can also omit this if you just added like this.
The value that is passed in will be true automatically.
This means now this route is only rendered if the path is exactly Slash.
So for now safeties We see users works but if and after something else we see nothing because now we're
not on exactly slash nothing and therefore this does not work for that scenario to make sure dead we
are not able to end up on unsupported pages.
We could import never a component from react ruder Dom and that's the redirect component we can add
this here and a router as well and there on redirect.
We use this as a self closing component.
We can add a tube property and redirect to slash.
Now this code is parsed from top to bottom and what react router will do is when you are L changes it
will basically go for all the routes we have set up here and it will see OK if the path is nothing we
render dead.
If the path is anything else does will not trigger and instead redirect will kick in and will redirect
us back to slash nothing.
So if we save that and now enter anything else you see we are automatically redirected to slash nothing.
So this works exactly as it should and now we make sure we always end up here.
If we enter anything but this path so now we can see our users now our users are not everything of course.
We also want to be able to create a new place for example and we will fill these components with more
life later.
No worries.
So in our pages in the places folder we could add a new place J.S. file and in there also create a straightforward
component by importing react from react.
Then creating this function new plays where we return some J as X code.
In my case here are just some H to tag new plays works.
So did we see that this also is loaded successfully and then export does as a default.
New place.
Now we can register this as a route as well in app Jesus we can duplicate this here and for example
say if the path is places slash knew then I don't want to load users but I want to load new plays so
import new plays from slash places slash pages slash new place.
And then here we render new plays as a self closing component here.
If that is our path to be now safe dad and I enter anything I'm redirected to slash if I enter slash
places slash new though
I'm also redirected.
Why start.
Well that happens because of the way the router works.
I said that it would parse this from top to bottom and indeed when it encounters this route here and
this here is our path and a U.R.L. it will render a new place.
But that's really important to understand.
It doesn't stop there off grid still evaluates the lines there off dress well and that's good because
we could be rendering something totally different here.
Let's say on a of footer we definitely would want to render dad below our roots right.
So that on every page we have to add footer for example.
So it does still execute the next line and therefore it does still redirect to make sure that we don't
redirect but that instead we even render this route this route or we redirect we can import one object
component from react ruder Dom and that's the switch component the switch component can be wrapped around
your root definitions so before the starting road and off to redirect and this now instructs react router
that ends up off the switch block whenever it encounters a fitting route it will not evaluate the lines
thereafter.
So it will not redirect if it was able to identify this path here and hence rendered this new place
component.
So with this switch component wrapped around our routes if we now enter slash places slash new again
you'll see now we're not redirected.
Instead we rendered this we enter anything else which does not exist we are redirected and therefore
now it just works as it should.
And this is routing in a nutshell with the help of the react router ID on package.
This is how we can still stay and react world but make sure we render different main components.
So to say which still are regular react components in the end based on the path the user entered into
you are L and that's how a single page application in the end becomes a multi-page application.
It's still all on the same single H to male page with which we started.
You can always validate this if you view the page source that is the single HDMI code with that root
death but react re renders what we see on the screen without reloading the page it just read renders
it based on the U R L we enter thanks to the third party library here which simply instructs react which
component to render based on which path we entered.