And let's get started with well a very important question.
What is Mongolia to actually no longer.
B is a no secret database which stores documents in so-called collections.
Now if you're coming from a secret world and as a developer chances are that this is the case.
You might refer to documents as records and collections as tables.
Now with Mongolia being a database we use it to store application data in our course project as would
be users and places and storing this data doesn't enforce a specific data schema or any relations we
can define a data schema.
But it's not really strict and we can also have relations lots of tools throughout this module.
But in contrast to a secret database for relations player coral this is not the case for no secret databases
like Mongolia and Mongolia.
It can also be easily connected to node and express but very important we can connect Mongolia to our
back.
And therefore we do not connect it directly to our front end.
More about that in a few minutes.
So to summarize that Mongolia Bee is a powerful data base and it can be easily integrated into a node
express environment so the environment we're using in this course.
One important note though you can of course also use other databases secret databases for example.
And this brings us to the next question.
What is the difference between a no sequel and a sequel database.
And why are we using a no sequel database here.