So we have our basic input but right now it's just a presentational component in the end.
It just takes some configuration here and then renders a nice looking input field and a label.
Not too bad for sure but also not all that I want instead my ideas the following and I really want to
highlight that this is just one possible approach of doing this but my idea is that in the input component
here we manage some internal state we manage what the user entered and we also manage whether what the
user entered is valid or not.
The answer to that question whether it's valid or not is provided with some external configuration.
So when we use the input component here for example in new place I want to be able to pass in an array
of validators which of course has to be an array of some clearly defined values or objects or identifiers
which we pick up in input component through which we then go instead of input component to find out
whether the input is valid or not.
And then we basically pass the information whenever the input is valid and what the input actually was.
So the concrete value entered back to new place with that pattern we already know where we have something
like on change here or on input or whatever you want and then you simply pass in a function to the input
component which you call from inside there.
So how can we implement this.
Let's start simple.
And in the input component let's add a new function in a function D change handler which should trigger
whenever the user enters something we can simply bind this on our element and therefore I will actually
move it up here we can bind this to our element here on both the input and the text area so we can add
on change here and point at the change handler do that on the text area and do that on the input with
that this function will be called for every keystroke that is went on change triggers.
Now when that change handler is fired we want to do two things we want to store the value just like
that and we want to validate it.
As I mentioned now when you're managing more than one state and the two states are kind of connected
you could use use state and simply set up two states what you manage.
That is absolutely fine you're not limited to one.
So we could manage de let's say entered value and have set entered value here and then call use state
and start with an empty value and then replicate this and have these is valid and set is valid state
here maybe and start with false and then you update both.
You could do that and it wouldn't be a horrible but often when you have to kind of connected states
and these states clearly are connected the validity depends on the input value then using a different
hook is better use reducer you reduce your also allows you to manage state in a component and it also
gives you a function you can call which updates the state and re renders the component.
But the difference to use state is that with you as reducer you can manage more complex state with ease.
You can write some logic that basically runs whenever you want to change the state to do more complex
updates than just set a new value.
And if we use reducer is great.
Whenever you have more complex state or you have interconnected state so therefore here I will use use
reducer.
But how do we use it.
Well we call it like this and then we have to pass in at least one argument and that's a so-called reducer.
Hence the name a reducer is really just a function of function which receives an action which we can
dispatch and I'll show you how we dispatch an action in a second and that receives the current state
and then we updates to current state based on the action we received returned and you state and use
reducer will take that new state and give it back to us in the component and rearrange or everything
so we can run a more complex state updating logic I'll set up the reducer function outside of my component
because it does not depend on any component inputs and I'll name it input reducer.
Now it is just a function which gets to arguments the current state and does action.
I was talking about.
So we have this function here and we pass the input reducer here to use reducer in this function we
then always have to return a new state and we can use a switch statement here.
Vanilla javascript construct to find out what action we have.
Now it's up to you how we determine which action we have but often you will dispatch actions that have
a type property which have a unique identifier that describes the action.
And here we could wait for a change.
Action let's say and it's totally up to us which identify we use here you could use any identifier.
I'll wait for a change action and then it will return unused state here unused state object to state
here doesn't have to be an object.
It could be anything but in my case here it will be an object because it will merge multiple different
state pieces into one grouped state and it will return as if we have this change case.
I will also provide a default case here where I return the existing unchanged state in case we dispatch
some action which we don't handle explicitly here.
Well then we'll just make it in here.
So what's this new state which you want to return here.
First of all I will create a copy of the old state so that we don't lose any data off the old state
and we can do it with the spread of greater the free dots and then state.
This copy is the old state object and copies all key value pairs of that old object into this new object
and then we can overwrite selected keys select the properties for example value let's say we want to
have a value property in our state I will set it to action dot Val.
And again it's up to you how you pass that new value along with the action.
I will store it in a Val property on that action object which I will eventually dispatch.
There is one other state piece which we need to manage and that is the is valid state whenever that
input is valid or not.
And now here we will have to run some validation logic now for the moment.
I'll just set it to true but we'll replace this with the actual validation logic which we just don't
have yet.
And I don't want to introduce too many new things simultaneously.
So for the moment that's hard code this to true so we have our simple reducer we register as year with
use reducer user ID user also is able to take a second argument it's optional though and that can be
an initial state you want to set up so a state with which you want to initialize your component here
and there.
I want to have a object where value is set to an empty string.
Let's say and where is a valid is set to let's say false.
So that initially the input is treated as faults and now this is my use reducer initialization.
Now just like use state use reduce or return something.
And just like use state it returns an array with exactly two elements.
So just as with U.S. state we can use array D structuring year to get these two elements out of the
returned array and stored them in constants.
And the two elements we always get from use reducer no matter how we configured our reducer is the current
state.
I will name it input state here and a dispatch function which we can call this is then how we will be
able to dispatch actions to to reduce our function which will run through to function and return a new
estate which will then update input state and re render to component in the end.
So with that in change handler I of course want to call dispatch I want to dispatch to this reducer
and therefore Europe pass an object which is such a action object.
And here we in our code defined action to have a type end a Val property.
So we should make sure we provide these two pieces of information here.
So type should be set to change.
And here of course I want to use the exact same identifier I expect up there.
So if you chose a different identifier you have to use a different identifier down there as well.
And all said Val to event target value event is an object we get automatically on the change event and
event target is the input element on which this event was triggered and value then simply is the value
the user entered with this we are updating our estate now to kind of reflect it.
I will do two things.
I will bind the value of input back to input state DOT value so that we have as to where binding going
on again and I will do the same of course on text area value to input state DOT value by the way in
react if you want to set the value on a text area you don't set it here between the text area tags as
you might think instead you do reset that value prop here.
That is how you set the value of text area.
And last but not least to also have some extra feedback on whether this is valid or not.
Here below the element I will check if input state is valid is false.
Hence the exclamation mark at the beginning.
If that is the case I want to render some error text and that error text should be suitable from outside.
So I will render props air or text if that input is invalid.
Now I also want to render a conditional class name here.
So we'll check here in my class name template literal if input state is valid is false.
Hence the exclamation mark at the beginning again.
If that is the case I will add a form dash control dash dash invalid class so that we add this extra
class to in the entire div if our input state is invalid which it is.
Initially it only becomes valid after we type at least one character because that has been a hard coded
to true with Dad.
Let's go back to NEW PLACE AND USE THE INPUT appropriately validators is not something we use yet.
So passing in an empty array is OK on input.
We can't specify this yet because at the moment we don't really have a mechanism of feeding devalue
and d input validity back to the parent component.
But what we can and should provide here is an error.
Text which all here set to please enter a valid title and with that if we save this we have input which
initially is invalid and therefore looks like this.
But as soon as we type at least one character it becomes valid.
No this never becomes invalid again because we have no real validation set up at the moment but it generally
works.
We are able to type we're able to change the validity initially and that is not looking too bad.
Now of course it would be kind of nice to have some real validation built in and to be able to really
check for example if that's empty and so on.