So let's now have a look at the design sketching part.
And as I mentioned we'll not worry too much about the design when it comes to picking color lessons
on there.
I will just provide you with some colors.
I came up with an advance instead here.
I now want to focus on sketching out the front end of this application.
So how this app should roughly feel how the pages are connected what should be visible on the user interface.
For that you can now have a look at my amazing drawing skills not.
But I hope it will still be helpful.
So what do we have in the front end of this application.
Well it all starts with a page.
We're visiting.
And by the way I'm drawing the desktop view here.
We'll also build this application such that it looks and works great on mobile.
But here I'm just sketching out the desktop view.
So we'll start on that page where we probably want to have a header with some title of our applications
or the name of the app our brand.
Something like this.
And then also some menu items on the other end of our header here.
Now I'll come back to these menu items.
Let's think about what we see on the starting screen there.
I want to have a list of users.
So a couple of list items at the end which simply are rendered beneath each other where for every user
we have like an image of that user the name like Max or menu.
And then the number of places off that user.
So the number of places that user shared.
So maybe here I shared two places.
And man you shared one place let's say and of course we have more users here.
So that's the starting screen now.
When we tap a user something should happen before we think about that though.
Let's talk about the menu items I want to have in the header there it depends on whether we are authenticated
or not if we are not authenticated then here in the header I want to have an authenticate option here
I'll just name it off.
You could name it log in.
So basically option which we can tap to be taken to the off indication screen if we are authenticated
then here I want to have the option to create a new place.
So to be taken to a screen where we can simply well create a new place.
I also want to have option which should always be available.
And that's basically the the users list.
So this SQL starting screen here that should always be available no matter if we are logged in or not.
We could also say that this option when we tap this is basically all happening if we tap the title because
Stead is our starting screen of the app.
So these two options here are basically equivalent we could say I think that would be a setup which
should generally work.
But now let's see what happens when we tap a user here so when we click our user here like menu then
I want to be taken to a new page.
Now on that new page here which is loaded of course we have the same header as before with the title
and with our different menu options here not going to write them out again.
These are the same options as you see up there.
So instead let's focus on the main area off this page.
What do we see there.
Well man you has one place right.
And he has one place.
So here I expect to see that one place if he had more places than I would expect to see a list of these
places here.
Now that place should have an image and we'll see how exactly we create this.
We could have the image at the top here for example then the title and then also options that allow
us to interact with that place.
For example we can have a few on map button here.
The idea is that when we click this or when we tap on this option we open up this place or the location
of this place in a motel.
So in an overlay to the screen where we can see that place marked with the help of Google Maps.
In addition I want to have two other buttons on the right here and edit and delete button which we always
see if we are the creator of that place.
So that's only visible if creators.
So if the menu in this case.
So if they're locked in user who is viewing this screen is all to the creator of the place.
Otherwise only the view on map button is visible.
Now when we tap that view on map button as I said I want to open an overlay which has a map.
So which uses Google Maps to display the place on the map with a marker.
That's the idea.
What should happen when we tap this view on map button.
So this is roughly how that could look like we might all add a description so that we have the title
and description here.
But that's my general idea.
The idea is not that we can tap this place to be taken to a new screen where we then view all the details
but that we can see all details or reach them like in the case of the map from this screen.
But of course that is something you could build differently.
It's just the approach I want to go with here.
OK.
So that is our list of places where we can all of you Place details we get there from our list of users
because every place is mapped to a user.
So we have to tap a user first before we can see the places.
Now what about these other buttons we have there.
The off button and the new button up there.
Well let's start with the off button.
When we pressed is off button I of course again when I have my header up there with the same menu options
we saw before.
But then here I want to have a form where the user has to enter some data namely the e-mail the password
and also any other data we might need.
For example also button which allows us to pick and emissions on this all should be here and then we
need a button which allows us to log in or also switched a log in mode so that we can basically toggle
between log and mode and sign up mode.
And this will all affect what we see up there.
So when we're in logging mode we of course only have to enter email and password if we are in sign up
mode.
We will also need to provide the image and the name of the user and so on.
So let's see authentication for him which we only are able to reach if we are not authenticated yet.
Now what about the use case.
We are authenticated.
Well then we can of course press this new button here in the menu and go to a new page where we also
see the good old header but where we then can create a new place and that is very similar to the authentication
page with totally different fields.
But the idea is the same here.
We have input fields to create a new place.
Also our image picker for the place and so on and then of course a button to add that place.
That is the general idea here.
We simply have a page which allows us to create a new place.
Of course when we tap this Add button or when we tap the log in button down there we send the HBP request
to the back end where we will then basically send or attach all the data we picked here in the form
and then on the back and we can extract that data and create the user create the place and so on.
Now creating a new place is one thing.
We also have this edit button here right.
So when we tap this we all want to go to a new screen and that should be a screen with the good old
header we already know.
And on that screen I also want to see a form a shorter form though where we can edit some data specifically
the title and let's say the description of a place not image and address but these two fields should
be editable here.
So we basically have like a a shorter form off that create new place form here.
We have a will shorten form to update title and description.
This is what we could have here.
Now when we clicked the delete button I want to open up a modal where we have to confirm the choice
and basically have a chance to cancel the deletion process in case we click this button accidentally
well.
And that is my beautiful drawing which basically lays out the front and off this application.
Now I can guarantee you it will look pretty hard and what I drew here but this drawing here this skeleton
which I sketched out here basically gives us an idea of the flow of our app and how users can navigate
through it.
It gives us a rough first idea of the pages and components we will need there.
And it basically helps us build the right application to write react the application for the app we
want to build Indian.
So that's my sketch for the front end.
Now let's analyze which data we got in our application and which endpoints we need on the backend.