We made a lot of progress.
Now let's fine tune some smaller things or one smaller thing which I noticed or which we still have
outstanding and that is in the end when we load our list of places here.
So when the place list component gets rendered you might remember that dear we also have to share place
button which we show if we find no places we can simulate this.
If I temporarily comment out the two places we added here two dummy places if I saved at and I go to
my places here that button I want to fine tune this I want to use my own custom button here.
So let's import button from and then gets let's move to shared components form elements.
Button to use our custom button we used a lot for all it Apple ready whips that was the wrong component
though let's do that in place list component of course that is where we need the button and in there
let's replace this button here with our custom button.
Now dear I also want to add a to prop now because the button is configured to work with such a two prop
and then renders a link in the end.
And of course here I want to point at places slash new.
Do you have a proper button there.
This looks way better and we're taken to ad places when we click it.
Now with that I also want to test something else.
Let's go back to user places and comment these places back in and there let's make sure that when we
added a place right the U or L is place p 1 for example if I use P P2 we load at our place and to see
that we really loaded a different place here all named as EMP dot state building so that we have a tiny
difference.
And now when does reloads here.
Of course I need to rename it and update place as well because it just copied my array and did not exported.
So let's replace as an update place J us as well so we have different places in the end and indeed it
loads that different place.
Now if a load p 1 we should see Empire State Building and if we load P free we get an error so good
that we tested this.
We should fix this as well.
And the error we're getting is here in update plays that I call set for data and identified place title
is what I want to access.
The problem is if we find no identified place this is undefined and you can't access properties like
title and description on undefined.
So we should actually check here and use effect if we do have an identified place.
So if this is not on the find and only if we do have it I will call set form data.
I will always call set is loading their offer and set this back to false.
But I want to only set for data if I identified places not undefined so if dad now we see could not
find a place.
If we have a invalid place but we don't get an error and we can also make this could not find place
thing a little bit more more pretty by simply importing card from shared components.
UI elements card.
So the good old card we used before.
And then wrap this in a card.
So down there where a render could not find place.
How about wrapping this year into a card.
Let's see how that looks like if we do that.
Yeah.
I think that looks a bit nicer.
With that we made some changes which I found quite important to make.
Now we have a nice flow here where we can added a place where we can view it on a map of course where
we can also add a new place.
Of course all not really doing something because the back and dismissing but the general functionality
is there and once we do add a back end we can then connect react to it send requests had loading states
and of course then also send our data and get our data from the back end.
Not a one missing thing I want to add now is the delete button it still won't work because again we're
not talking to a back end yet but at least I want to make it do something and on authenticate I actually
want to go to a separate page where we can enter some credentials where we also have a forum they are
for.
So that this is also already prepared for later when we then will add real authentication.
Now let's start with deleting though.