Where do we delete the place.
Well that happens in place item in place item we get this delete button.
So here is where we have to to work on to make sure something happens when we press that button.
Now the question is what should happen when we press it.
And my idea is that we open a modal that asks the user whether he or she is sure if you want to proceed
so that you have a chance of canceling the deletion process.
And only if you then click yes in that modal we will later then once we have a back and send the request
to the back end to delete this.
So let's add such a mode.
We already do have one modal here.
That's the model for the map.
I will simply add a second modal because we will only render one of the two at a time.
I will add a second modal next to it where I want to render it is this question whoever you really want
to delete it or not.
So the content of this modal is a paragraph let's say where we say do you want to proceed and delete
this place please note that that it can't be undone there.
After so some warning like this now we need to configure that modal as well.
I will add a header here where I say Are you sure and footer clause of place stash item underscore underscore
modal dash actions to nicely position my buttons in the footer.
And speaking of that I will add footer and there I want to have some J as X which is rendered in the
footer off the modal and that should be two buttons one to proceed and one to cancel.
So therefore yea I will have Q Jay as X elements next to each other.
That is not possible you need one root element in any place where you basically create a brand new J
as X branch and therefore here I will use react fragment and in there then have my buttons.
So the first button gets this inverse style here and I will say cancel there the second button gets
the danger style and there I will say delete so desist and really when we will delete the item.
So now we need to wire things up.
We need a couple of functions to handle our different states and of course therefore we also need some
state itself.
So let's add new state here and that is basically D the state that manages Weber we show debt confirm
modal or not so we could named as show confirm modal and set show confirm modal is then our update function.
And here with use state we initialize this to false because initially of course we don't show this modal
and then we need some functions we need to show delete warning handler which has the single responsibility
of calling set show confirm model and setting this to true then I want to have my cancel delete handler.
This has the responsibility of setting show confirm modal to false and of course we'll have to confirm
the lead handler datas where we then really will go ahead and delete displays place and again that is
something we can't do right now.
But for now I'll just log deleting here so that we can still see that this was triggered.
Now we need to wire up these different functions and also use our state.
Let's start with the state on the model here I will set the show prop which controls whether the model
is shown or not to show confirm model.
That state we just added an on cancel will be set to to cancel the lead handler of course the same forward
as cancelled button on click here will simply trigger the cancel delete handler on the other hand on
click on this button here on the delete button in the model will trigger to confirm delete handler.
And now we need to wire up that delete button at the very bottom there of course upon a click.
I want to show my confirm modal node.
That's the wrong thing.
Show delete warning handler is the functioning that should be triggered here.
With that if we safeties if I click delete we see that modal figure cancel it gets closed if I click
here it gets closed if I click delete here.
Of course nothing happens but I see deleting.
I want to close my model in that case as well though.
So in here in the confirmed delete handler we should also set show stats show confirm modal to faults
too close to modal.
So with that if we now click delete and click delete here we would really send the request to delete
it and we will do so later.
And for the moment we just close the model and print this.
So that's all the working the real magic will happen later but it's a good start.
And with that let's work on authenticate and make sure that there we all also show a form we can even
switch between two modes.
Log in and sign up mode and we at least gather the user input for now.