Let's work on authentication and here's a little challenge for you.
Try starting this or working on this on your own for Dad.
Make sure that when we click authenticate here we're not taking to this page but to a brand new page
which you have to create in the user pages folder.
You could named as page of as or authenticate jazz or something like this on this new page add a form
you can use to use form hook for that and add a form that renders that email and the password field.
You also want to add some validation to these fields and then you tell for example you find this function
you can execute to setup email validation.
The password should be validated with validator min to check that it's at least let's say 5 6 7 whatever
you want.
Characters long so add such a form utilizing our form hook and this validation and T input component
and added on a brand new form.
Definitely try this out on your own as a next step.
After a short pause which I give you to pass this lecture and try it on your own we'll do it together
so where are you successful.
Let's try to gather and for that I will add a brand new page here.
The off J.S. page in the user pages folder.
I will also add off C as s to have some styling for it and attached you find that styling you can just
paste it in there and I'll leave it up to you whether you now use my styling and my markup or a stick
to yours.
The general logic of course should be the same so that we have no problems in the rest of the course.
So in the off J is file of course we import react from react.
We import that off CSX file we just added to get the styling and then here we have the off component
which will render some J as X later and we export this off component now instead of the off component
for the moment I'll just render off as a text here to see whether I can get there because an aptly as
I now want to registered as a root and there I simply want to add a brand new route maybe here at the
end where the path is slash off let's say and then we render our all page which we therefore need to
import.
So here we got off from slash user Seth slash pages slash off and off is getting rendered here like
this OK so now with that if I now click on authenticate I'm taken to the off page.
So that's working.
Of course make sure that the link here in the NAF links is the same link you're watching for in your
out config.
So now in the off page let's replace the H to tag with the actual content we want there and the actual
content we want there of course is totally up to you.
I of course want to have a form in there but a form which I will wrap into a card.
So import card from shared components UI elements card.
So I'll actually wrap everything here in such a card like that and splits across multiple lines to make
it easier to read.
And besides my card here or besides my form in the card I want I have some text subtitle where it's
a log and required and then maybe there's horizontal separator just to have some visual separation between
the title and the actual form on the card.
I'll also add a class name of authentication which is simply a class set up here in of CSX now inside
of the form we can now add our controls.
So let's import input from shared components form elements input and let's repeat that for the button.
So let's import button from shared components form elements button so that we have these two things
that way label these two components.
And now in the form we can add our button here our input here excuse me.
And that will be the input for the email so I'll set an I.D. of email here I will also set the element
here to input because it should be a regular input.
The type can be set to email here.
So if we take advantage of this native built in email type and the label can also be email to give the
user a clearer idea of what we want their validators of course is an array and they are a mentioned
that we can use some of the validators I created.
So I will import them from shared you tell validators there I want to have these validator email and
do validator Min length.
That is what I need so here then I will execute validators email as a function to add that email validation
here and also provide an error text which could be Please enter a valid email address like that now
on change all the needs to be connected to something and here I will use my custom hook again.
So import use form from shared hooks form OK so that we can call use form up there and initialize it
initially to form is invalid and 40 inputs.
We have a email input where the value is empty and which is also invalid initially and will also then
have a password input where where the value will also be empty initially and it's also invalid.
So that's my initial state and then just as before use for returns something it returns an array with
three elements.
I need two of them here for now and it's a form state and the input handler and now the input handler
here can be bound to on change on this input and then we can replicate duplicate this input here and
create a separate second input with an I.D. of password and a type of password and a label of password
and a validator of let's say Min length 5.
But it's up to you which Min length you want to require here and of course here it will say in the error
attacks Please enter a valid password at least five characters.
Now let's all at a button here of type submit and on the button I'll say log in for a moment later we'll
also add a sign up functionality but for now it's just about logging in now that button should be disabled
if the form is invalid.
So we'll set this April equal to not form state is valid if the form is not valid the buttons disabled
with that.
This should actually work.
Let's save this and I get an error or yes because it's not on change but on input on our own input components
so let's replace on change with on input there and that looks a lot better.
Now we will see if I enter the email here.
This is not valid.
If I tap out of there as soon as I make it a valid e-mail address it is except that though password
has to be at least five characters long and then it's accepted as well.
And yeah this all seems to work here.
Let's also submit it and of course that does not work yet because I haven't added a submit handler.
So let's add a new function here the off submit handler maybe where we get the event and then call event
prevent default to prevent this automatic submission of this request and the reloading of the page data
for and then in here I will cancel lock form state later as always we'll do more.
I'll actually console Lockport and state inputs later we'll do more because later we will also have
a back and for now let's just bind on submit here to the off submit handler where we log our input state
now is dead.
If we retry that enters some data here log in.
This looks good to me.
So this basic form is working and that's nice it also shows us how reusable our own hook and the input
component is.
But of course logging in alone is not enough.
Users have to sign up before they can log in and during sign up they should also provide a name.
And of course we want to able to switch between both modes so you can also try implementing this on
your own.
It will be a bit more tricky in the next lecture.
We'll do it together.