So let's implement this switch.
But now and for dead at the bottom of the form below to submit button and actually outside of the forum.
I'll add a new button with an inverse style which I find to look quite nice where I will say switch
to sign up and upon a click here.
I want to execute a switch mode handler function lets say the name is up to you.
We have to add that function to our functional component now.
So here I'll add this new switch mode handler function and the idea there is of course that we do just
what the name implies we switch our mode off that for him to switch a mode.
We need to manage a mode and that has to be a state because when we change it our component has to be
rendered or at least parts of it will need to be updated and react.
We'll figure out which parts that are.
So let's import used state from react to manage some state and then here I'll set it up.
Use state and I'll name this state is log in and set is log in because we even are in logging mode or
not in initially let's say we are in log in mode.
So initially this is true we can also name it is log in mode and set is logging mode to be even clearer
about what we're managing here.
So now in switch mode handler I want our well switched at mode so we'll set is log in mode to what it
was not.
So I will inverted for Dad I'll use the function form here and get my preferred mode and set a new mode
to not preferred mode.
This is this function form of updating the state which we should use if our new state update is based
on the previous state.
And it basically inverts it by adding this exclamation mark.
So if it was true it's now false and the other way around.
Now we can use this log in mode.
This is log in mode constant now which will change.
For example here on the button it shouldn't always say log in.
Instead I want to check if we are in log in mode in which case I say log in.
Otherwise I'd say sign up.
Also here I want to switch to.
Well that depends if I'm in log in mode I want to switch to sign up.
If I'm in sign up mode which is the opposite of logging mode I want to switch to log in.
So we want to output some text dynamically here.
In addition I also want to render a brand new input if we are in sign up mode because then I also need
to fetch the user name.
So here if we're not in logging mode which is to sign up mode therefore I will render a brand new input
here and displace the element is an input.
The I.D. is name the type is text and the label is name or your name whatever you prefer and validators
here.
Well here I will just required us so we'll actually import a new validator validator require and use
dat down there in my validators array 40 name.
So here I'll just execute validate or require the error text here can simply be Please enter a name
and on change of course points at my good old Input handler and every safeties we see this button.
And if I click it I get an error and we get an error because on input is not a function yeah because
it's on input here and not on change.
So now this works and we can switch between these two modes.
But what you'll notice is that our form will not work correctly if I enter email and a password it's
not valid here and also not in log in mode.
So basically my button never unlocks here and that makes sense because what we just did is we added
a new input which sometimes exists and sometimes this does not.
And when we switch to sign up mode in the end this becomes part of the forum.
So if I reload for example in log in mode I can enable the button but now it's all enabled if I switch
to sign up so basically were not correctly considering this new field here.
The validation inside the input works but the form validation is not wired up correctly when we switch
to mode.
So we have to make sure we do that to make sure we do that.
We have to go back to the switch mode handler and deer in the end we want to set our forum data now
not to reflect some initial state in our inputs down there.
Those will initially always be empty but to correctly update our behind the scenes form data when we
switched a mode.
And keep in mind that in our hook when set data is dispatched which happens when we call set form data
we do is at the input in the form validity data.
So we do update the form data whenever we call set form data which makes sense if you have a look at
the name of that function.
So we want to call that whenever we switch to mode to bring it up to date with the available inputs.
So here I'll check if we're not in is log in mode let's say so if we are signing up in which case I
want to call set for him data now set for data is not available right now we need to extracted from
use form as a third element here then we can call set form data here.
Now here in set form data I want to set my form data for the case that we're not in log in mode.
Now keep in mind this year runs before we switched a mode so if you're not in logging mode we are in
sign up mode but since switch mode handler executes and we're in that handler it means we're now switching
to log in mode so to update our formatted correctly we need to drop the name field because we're coming
from sign up mode and we're going back to logging mode.
So the form validity depends on the validity of the email and the password field.
So here I'll check form state inputs.
Email is valid and form state
inputs.
Password is valid if both are valid the future form will be valid because we're switching to logging
mode and there we only have these two fields now here for the inputs.
I simply want to retain the values I have for email and password and drop devalue.
That was stored for name so we can simply said Name two undefined here.
For example to drop it now else in the else branch where we are in log in mode but we are executing
switch mode handler so we are moving to sign up mode.
In this scenario here we want to call set form data and the form will definitely be false.
The validity of the form will definitely be false because we just edit the name and put field and effort
can't be valid.
Now I want to retain my current form state input state here so my current values for email and password
but I want to add a new name field now and forward a name field.
The value initially will be empty and is valid they offer will be false which is the reason why the
overall form validity will be false.
And with that recall set forum data and then all the set is log mode to switch to mode visually and
hence our UI and the behind the scenes form should be updated correctly.
Now one important note in the end of course we are performing multiple state changes here set for and
data will in the end change some state and re rendered a component and set is log and mode will do the
same react as smart.
If you have multiple state changes in the same synchronous code block so in the same function which
execute synchronicity so all the steps executed immediately after each other it will batch them to gather
and perform one single state update and one single rerun or cycle to a wide unnecessary render cycles
was that if we now safeties let's see this let's enter something here some valid e-mail address and
a valid password and switch to sign up you'll see now this button is disabled which makes sense because
we edit the name which is empty go back to log in it's enabled again unless I have something invalid
here which is when it crashes so dad is something we'll need to tweak let's see what's going wrong here.
Cannot read property is valid of undefined in our form hook and yet that makes sense because here when
we switched from sign up mode back to log in I said name to undefined to drop it.
Well that's nice but of course I always have to copy my existing fields otherwise I also lose them.
So we need to copy all the fields and then just overwrite name to be undefined.
Now even with that changed apply though.
If we go back and I switch to sign up enter nothing here and go back to log in you'll see this still
crashes with a similar error and the reason for that is related.
Now I do keep all my old inputs.
Now that's great.
But he's still set name to undefined so the property is technically still part of the form object.
The value of it Justice undefined but since it still is part in the form look in the input change case.
When I go through all my inputs I still of course find this name input as I input the value justice
undefined but the property is still there and therefore I still try to access is valid on the property.
There are various solutions for dead ones illusions that we add one extra if clause here in the for
loop and we check if state inputs 40 given input I.D. if data is true of the or to be precise by adding
exclamation mark here if it is false see which means is it undefined if it is undefined then I continue
here.
Now what does continue do continue basically tells javascript that we don't continue with this iteration
of the for loop and instead we go to the next iteration.
So do the next property in this case.
So we skipped this property if it is undefined because then I don't need to validated and I don't want
to adjust my form validity and if we now safe does and we go back I can switch to sign up and switch
back here and if I now enter something here you see this works just fine.
And if I now go here and her Max that's looking good.
Remove the password here it's invalid switch back enter it back.
So that is looking good.
This looks now like it works and that fixes the issue of us switching modes and changing the form therefore
never click submit.
Here we see email name and password being submitted with the data we entered for go back log in and
click log in.
We see name is undefined which is fine but email and password is there.
So this seems to work and this is how we could implement this with different modes between which we
switch and different form data which we manage for those modes.
Behind the scenes.