And that's it for this module.
We wrote a lot of code here.
We built an entire little react application made up of a bunch of components including Google Maps and
much much more.
There's tons of stuff we can do with this application.
And this really shows what you can build with react only.
Now of course we're not done though.
This is not a react only course.
This is a course about react and Node express Mongo D.B..
So in the next modules we'll dive into a well node Express and Mongo TB and we'll build a back and forth
his application as well so that all the cool features we implemented here with components with hooks
with context with our own form validation and our custom hook ends on.
So that all these cool features don't just work here and as standalone front end application but that
we actually have a real merged application a full stack application where we connect the front end to
the back end as well.
So it this something we'll do as a next step in this course.