On the front end we also can work with environment variables.
There of course we're not using Node 1 but you can simply add a new file thought EMV and this file will
automatically be used by the configured build and development process we're using here.
This is a create react app project in the end and the react scripts package which is used under the
hood picks up such a dot EMV file automatically and we can use the dot in we file to also store data
we need here on the front end so which environment variables could we use here on the front end.
We could use one environment variable for this Google API key we're using in the index HD email file
in the public folder and I think we got one ever environment variable that would make sense and that
is d u r l we're sending our back and requests to hear it's local host five thousand and not only are
we duplicating this code everywhere where we are sending a request this of course will not be the correct
you are L once our application is deployed because once the node application is on a real server it
will have a real IP or a real domain attached to it and therefore this will then simply no longer be
correct.
So there are two environment variables I want to add.
Now here's one important thing.
Your environment variables here have to start with react app all caps react app underscore actually
all caps for no chance for the back end this was not required.
You could use any names here for the front end.
This is required.
Also keep in mind that of course the front end code as you will see later in this module will be built
locally on our machine and then we just upload the built files.
So the prepared H team Al javascript and see us as files to a server.
This also means that you must not have any confidential data in your code.
So also here in your environment variables would ever use store here.
When you use it in your react code later everyone can read and see it in the deployed application because
it's not running on a server it's running in the user's browser so therefore never store any confidential
data in your react app no matter if you're using environment variables or not.
So with that however here we could store our ReACT app Google API key and that is simply set a value
here in this file by adding a equals sign and then right there after without any whitespace as the value
you want to store.
So it looks a bit different than in the note man Jason File.
Here we will had a Jason format here it's just a simple key value pair file and a new line.
I will add another environment variable and this will be my back end.
You are L and now here.
During development that will be locally hosted 5000 slash API.
Let's say later we can swap this for a different value in production so with this we prepared to 2 environment
variables.
How do we inject them.
We get two different sin taxes.
I want to inject my Google API key in the public index each html file.
There if you want to inject an environment variable like this key here you do so by adding percentage
signs at the beginning and end and in between you reference your environment verbal name so react app
Google API key.
In my case here or whatever value you defined here in this thought and file this should go in here and
it has to be between two percentage signs.
So that's how we add an environment variable in the index age to metal file in our javascript code.
We use them in a different way.
We use them just as we would use them in notorious for example in New Place J J.S. here.
I want to replace this part now with my environment variable with this react app back and you are L
environment variable and to do so we use process thought and again so the same syntax you know from
notorious.
And then simply.
Well at your part after you are L which is dynamic.
So this is how we can refer to the back and you are L here.
With that I will quickly search for local host five thousand in my project here to replace all occurrences
for example in place item here.
I will get rid of this part always although delete slash API.
Because in my case at least I included that in the environment variable.
So that's my correct you are L now here for the image it's the same.
They are however and that's a little mistake on my side.
I don't need slash API so I will add a new you are L here react app acid you are L because we could
theoretically also upload our images to a wholly different page so think it makes sense to store it
is in a new environment variable and now I will use reactive acids you are L here
so Paula assign react AB as if you are L and of course access does on processed ends and with that we
make sure that we are able to access d you are L where our images are stored removed trailing slash
here in the environment variable file though because I do have to slash here.
Now let's move on here and update place I do send a request so let's remove that part including API
and instead injected here says DOT and three act app back and you are.
L was the U R L I was using.
Same here let's replace this part here with dynamic where with the environment variable part to be precise
like this.
In user places it's the same.
Let's replace that here with our API for Avatar image.
It's again our back and asset you are L.
So yea I will use my upper environment variable process thought and react
and then the name was asset you are L so your asset you are l like this in off J as let's get rid of
this here and instead again use process dot and react back and you are L and combine this with the string
in of J is here it's the same get rid of this part combine it like that and end users J as the same
get rid of this combine it like that.
So with that I ensure that everywhere in this application we are able to conveniently control the back
and you are L fruity dot env file here and the Google API key as well.
Now of course we still have a couple of unanswered questions at this point how can we provide different
values for production here in reacts and notes case and what do we do with that Google API key.
Well let's start with the Google API key before I then come back to that whole production values thing.