What's causing this error here this error is a course error.
It is an error you might see sometimes when building something like this when communicating to an API
from inside your front and app course is a security concept it stands for cross origin resource sharing
and the general idea in courts or with this course concept is dead resources on a server can only be
requested by requests that are coming from the same server.
So for our back end which runs on local host five thousand.
The idea is that we can only request data from there from an app that also runs on local host five thousand
which our app of course thousand runs on local host three thousand and you might say it's both on local
host but actually these are two totally different domains.
It's like having a page on your page.
Dot com and the cool backend dot com.
So really two totally separate domains now course is a security concept and forced by the browser which
is why we had no problems with postmen but the browser and for systems and the browser sees that here
we're trying to send a request from local hosts thousand to local host five thousand and hence it does
not take the response by that server.
So it's not a service site error it's a front and error it's an error in our browser because course
is a browser security concept to work around that the server has to attach certain headers to the responses
it sends back to the client that basically allow the client to access the resources and then the browser
automatically detects these headers and sees OK.
It's fine you may access this and the browser will not throw this error here so we need to do some work
on the backend and we need to make sure we attach to right headers to our response and a great place
to do that is in the app J.S. file because we will attach these headers to every response we sent back
on the back end.
So it's not just on user routes it's really on every response.
Therefore a here let's add a middleware before we forward the request to our specific routes here and
we were just a middleware with app use as you learned.
And there I will have a regular middleware function with request response and next.
So basically what we already learned about in previous modules and the idea here is that we don't send
back a response but that we just add certain headers to the response so that when later a response is
sent back from our more specific routes it does have these headers attached.
So here in the end we will call next to let the request continue its journey to other middle wears.
But before we call that we want to add certain headers and we can do that with rest set header.
This sets a header on the response and there we will need to set free headers the first header is access
dash control dash allow dash origin so make sure you don't introduce a typo year it really has to be
named like this the value which is the second argument we passed to set header then can be start.
This basically allows us to control which domains should have access so where the browser should allow
this.
We could restrict us to local host three thousand but actually here on this API I'm fine with opening
this up to any domain.
Keep in mind that this is not a general security concept but that it's just enforced by browsers so
you can't lock down API access in general here for example postmen simply doesn't care about these headers
for the browser.
However this is a first step but not the only step.
It allows any domain to send requests but it's still not enough.
We also need to specify which headers these requests sent by the browser may have.
Therefore we send a new header to the responses the access dash controlled dash allow dash headers header.
This controls which headers incoming requests may have so that they are handled.
We can set this to star as well but here I want to be a bit more specific.
I want to allow the original header the ex requested dash with header the content type header the first
two are basically set automatically but the content type header is one we set explicitly on the front
end D except header which is also set automatically by the browser and also the authorization header
which is not set automatically by the browser but which we will set later in the course.
So we'll already configure it here as a next step here.
I will add a last header and that's the Axis dash control dash allowed dash methods header and this
basically controls which H P methods may be used on the front end or maybe attached to incoming requests
and they don't want to handle get post patch delete requests.
Because if we have a look at our routes these are the type of incoming words we handled there with that
if we saved it our back and restarts and now we should be able to test this again.
Let's go to authenticate again.
Switch to sign up enter our data here and click sign up.
And it now works.
Now you can see that here indeed we are allowing this access.
And here as a response we hence get back our user data with all that entered data.
Now we do still include the password here for example in plain text which we might not want to submit
like this.
It is something we can change later once we add authentication for the moment.
This is fine.
And therefore here we see that the general of flow works.
If we now check our collections on the back end and we go through that learn database here we see there
is a new user's collection in there.
Indeed the user I just created.
So that's not looking too bad.
We are able to send this request and we made a huge step forward deal for of course though that's not
all for example at the moment we're not giving the user of our application any indication that we're
waiting for a response.
And we're also not handling errors.
So we definitely want to do that as well.