We have this ugly looking application and now it's time to change that.
Attached you find to see us as follows.
Users lists CSA s and user items C as s and you can replace yours with those files or simply copy the
content you find in those files into your respective files.
That's what I'll do here.
Just paste it all in.
Now safeties it reloads and doesn't look that much better.
We still have this super huge image here and just our text is a little bit differently formatted now.
Now to change that I prepared a separate component which we will add two shared components and they
are all create new sub folder UI elements to have some core UI elements we need.
And there you can paste in a component you also find attached in the Avatar CIP file you find a Avatar
J.S. and Avatar as as file paste both into UI elements.
So did you have avatar.
J Is there an avatar of CSX.
We're not writing this from scratch because I don't want to bore you with writing more and more components.
This is a component which has a div which wraps the image and which has some styling to properly styled
at Image and we can use this avatar component in our user item component down.
So let's go back to user item and in their import Avatar from going up to levels shared components UI
elements.
Avatar.
And then here replaced his image tag not the surrounding div but the image tag with Avatar and to Avatar.
You need to pass a image prop because if you inspect that component I do expect the image and the old
prop also with Prop by the way so I do pass in an image here and set this to props image and the all
prop which has set to props name.
Now I'll not pass in a value for the width and Aldon or for a class I'm in style.
This component Justice build such that it supports these special props and later we might need that
but you don't have to use that.
There are some default stylings and if those are right for you there is no need to change this.
So we only pass the old and the image prop and if we now save this this definitely looks better now
it's still not perfect though we can still improve that it will look better once we wrap our user a
component also into a link because I have some styles set up for anchor tax and a one to have a link
because when we clicked the user it already has a hover state right when they clicked the user.
I want to be taken to all the places this user created.
Now we won't render a link with a regular boring anchor tag though because instead we again want to
leverage react router Dom and make sure that we don't have a real link which would try to load a brand
new page and therefore would reload our existing page but that instead do react routing package react
router Dom can step in before a navigation happens before a page reload happens and block that default
action from happening and instead have a look at our configured routes here and load the appropriate
react component we want to give react broader damage chance of doing that.
So here in user item I will import something from react router Dom and that something is the link component
under the hood.
This wraps and renders an anchor attack but it also adds this extra block the navigation logic we use
that instead of the list item inside of the div here but outside of that div which holds the image we
can add a link opening tag and then a closing tag after this inner death.
And now all the links you need to specify to prop which defines where to you want to go and there's
no actually will be a dynamic path.
It's not always the same you are because it is a you or L that should reflect the I.D. of the user because
we want to load all the places for a given user later.
So the idea is that later we have something like user I.D. places for example where user I.D. of course
is dynamic and not always the same because we will have multiple users.
So to here is built with help of a dynamic expression and hence we need curly braces.
And then here I will use back takes to create a template literal which means a string where we can easily
inject values and I want to go to slash and then inject a value and that value will be props ideas.
So it will be the user I.D. slash places so that we always have a different link for every user.
If we now say if this does looks way better and now we can hover over it is and click it and nothing
happens.
But if you watch the bottom of your browser you see that it will go to slash user I.D. slash places.
We just haven't added such a page yet.
Which is why at the moment nothing happens.
But generally this works and that is of course amazing.
Now I'm still not entirely happy with the way this looks.
I also want to add another utility component which you also find attached to this video to this lecture
and that's the card the card CIB file if you extracted holds a card J.S. and cards C Ss file copy both
into your shared components UI elements folder as well.
This renders a simple diff with some nice styling attached with a little drop shadow and so on it gives
us this card look.
You might know from our web pages and now we can use doesn't use our item as well there.
We can now also import the card import card from shared components UI elements card and wrap our link
with it.
So instead of that inner div but outside of the link add card and then close card after Dilly.
And with that it looks a bit worse actually because now is one thing we need to do.
We now need to get rid of this div here.
Copy the class name first don't get rid of the off the opening and closing tacked or after and add the
closet him to card because card is a component that is able to accept the class name prop and merged
with its own classes.
And with that if we safeties we now have a nice look rounded corners does nice Cardi look with a slight
drop shadow.
And I think this now looks really nice.
Now of course still it's a relatively empty page and we will add more but we are getting there and at
least now we have our list of users with only one user at the moment.
But we could render more and we can click that user.
So that is pretty nice.
That is a nice first step.
Now let's continue our work and let's add more and more components and then also at some point more
and more logic.