So how did it go.
Very successful.
Let me show you my approach now.
For that we have to go down to our get places by user I.D. constant again user I.D. is fine right here
but our dummy places.
This is what we have to work on and we'll always have a look at these if code.
Let's see if we change this too.
But this is actually what we should focus on now.
So therefore let's get rid of this code here and now we can again refer to our place model here.
And this time we will not use the find by a DMA offered up here as I said but they use a different method
to find method find generally works similar as fine by a D.
This means we again do not return a promise here but you can again use EXEC If you want to.
But again find still allows us to use async await here or then catch again.
This is a mongoose specific feature available right here.
It's not of a promise but you can use this asynchronous operations here find has some other important
things to keep in mind though generally using find like this would return all places.
This means if we want to have a specific place in our place a specific place by the user I.D. We have
to add the user idea here as an argument.
So in our case we can use to create their property and refer to user I.D. as we define it right here
in our constant.
And that's one thing you have to keep in mind.
Another thing is that find is available in both Mongo TB and Mongoose which we are using right here
in Mongolia.
B Find returns a so-called cursor a cursor are simply points towards the results of our final effort
here of the query with it.
And it then allows you to iterate through the different results you would have.
The reason for that is that if you would imagine you would have hundreds of place in years so hundreds
of documents.
It was a way to block your data immediately and to return big amounts of data.
So that's the way how monger TB approaches this.
So you get back a cursor and then can iterate through the different results in Mongoose find doesn't
provide a cursor but directly an area.
We could also get a cursor in Mongoose by the way to do so we could use decode as a property on our
find method instead of only using just find that's what you have to keep in mind here.
So using the Mongoose find method.
We are now adding to create the property and therefore we can filter for the specific document where
the creator has the user I.D..
We are looking for in our Get request.
This means we can again add our try catch cold block here put the content into it.
With that our content is not available anymore due to block scoping.
Therefore we can create let places outside of our tribe log and get rid of the constant and also make
sure that this again becomes an asynchronous task.
Again we have a fine operation therefore will add async appear and await
front of our place model.
And we also catch our error again with the same logic we had before.
Let's again use the constant which should be a new HDP error your and let's say that this should return
fetching places failed.
Please try again later.
And again that's the logic we have.
Indy 500 error case.
So in case anything goes wrong with the request in general and here we also have to add return next
again.
With that this should work fine down here.
This code could also be re factored.
So in this way that is stored in a constant.
But to show you both ways again let's this time keep it this way.
As I said you can adjust this to be in line with the rest of the code but just for demonstration purposes.
As part of this course I will just keep this the way it is.
But done here our response has to be adjusted once again.
There is a little thing that you have to keep in mind.
This was a bit more tricky.
I must say but maybe you did it in case your problems we'll solve it together now because again we have
to add a method to our places here.
But this time we cannot use our to object method appear because the problem is that as I said find returns
an error right here and we cannot use to object with an array.
Therefore we have to use map here a standard javascript method and with map now being in place we can
again use place to object right here and then apply our getters feature to make sure that the underscore
from our added property is removed so gathers is again set to true and with that if we now go back to
postmen and trade and you get requests here again to HDP local post five thousand but this time we have
to go to our users rights.
So we go to API slash places slash user slash and now YouTube.
So the idea of our user right here at this present.
Yeah.
This looks fine.
We get back our response.
We again get the idea without the underscore.
So getters also works fine.
And again if I would no use let's say you free ride here click send.
You see we couldn't find places for the provided user I.D..
So this is this arrow right here which is also working fine.
And with that we finished our so read in our crud feature chain right here.
Let's now continue with updating places.