You might notice that when we built our application we got four files here in my case and the biggest
file is in my case disk chunkier with 52 dodge to four kilobytes.
No that is not a problem.
This is not too large but in bigger applications of course this might be bigger.
And one problem if you want to call it like this which we have in does application and this react application
is that we're not splitting our code.
Now what does code splitting mean.
It means that not all code is required to right from the start.
If a user visits our page he or she might be logged in automatically or he or she might not be.
No matter if that's the case or not we might not yet have visited the places for one of our users we
might not yet have visited the off page.
So the code that is related to authentication and to user replaces or to code which is related to creating
a new place or for updating a place might not be needed yet it is needed once we visit that page once
we navigate to places new but not before we do so and therefore we could load these routes lazily which
means initially when our app starts we don't download the code for these routes but as soon as a user
goes there we download the code on the fly and then render these pages so that the initial page loading
time is reduced because we download less code initially and react thankfully has built in support for
code splitting.
So how do we set this up and react in the aptly as file I will create a new constant here one for each
route which I want to load lazily for example users and then we can comment out or remove this import
here and users can now be created with react dot lazy and react lazy takes a function and this is a
function which executes import as a function.
So import not as a statement like this but as a function instead.
This is also supported in modern javascript and also in this react build set up here and there we pass
a path to the file we want to import.
So that path here and yet now the difference is that now this is not imported immediately when app J.S.
runs and they offer in the bundle produced here by our built tool it's not included right from the start
but it will be loaded on demand once this user component is required does users component excuse me
and we still rendered this as a regular component react lazy does the rest.
So down there we don't need to change how we use that we just change how we import it.
And now of course we replicate this all for new place where I grab this path and use it here and let's
call it this out all also for user places where I grab this path here and use it there
and also for update plays Here
wrap this replace it there and then I want to do the very same with off like this now not all lazy loaded
routes I set up here makes sense for example users is the route we load by default at the beginning
so we don't actually need to lazy load that we can still do it though but other routes like new place
or update place make a lot of sense because we definitely don't load them initially when the app starts
up so there is no need in loading this in advance.
Now you don't need to use a similar syntax in the other react files because this really only works with
the routing here at the moment.
And in addition this is our biggest opportunity for splitting our code into meaningful chunks for the
different features of our application so we only need to do this here an app J.S. however like this
it wouldn't work.
We now have to do something else.
We have to wrap our routes which we render in the end with a Navarro component which we get from react.
We imported from react and that's the suspense component.
Suspense is required to make react lazy work so we wrap this year our roots with suspense so you're
a lazy loaded code is wrapped with suspense and on suspense you provide a fallback prop and this has
to point at some J OSX code which is rendered as a fallback if loading lazy loaded code takes longer.
So if downloading that code for dead new route the user wants to go to if that takes longer react show
us T.J. has X code you render here.
In between a we could render a div with a class name with a class name of center let's say and then
our loading spinner for Dad.
Just make sure that you of course also import the loading spinner here.
We need to import this from the shared components UI elements folder and then we can render IDs here
as a fallback if loading of our road should take longer.
With that let's test it locally so I will use NPM start again to build our app for development as so
that we can test it here on low closed and let's wait for this application to reload.
Now you see it starts up.
I'm locked in but now something interesting happens.
If I clear my network tab if I go to ad place you see there are new downloads of these chunks and that
in the end are the code chunks that are required for this page.
And if we go to authentication for example a new chunk was downloaded.
So this is the code splitting in action.
These are the different code chunks for the different feature areas we have and if we're now having
quit this and we run NPM run build again we will also see that for production different chunks are produced.
Now the entire of when to load what thing will be managed by react.
You don't have to worry about that.
Therefore you get a free win here.
You got more code files as you can see more chunks were created and therefore the initial chunk decreased
a bit.
Now it's still almost the same size as before because the majority of the size is actually taken up
by the react library itself and by AB of third party libraries we included.
But still we're able to get some improvements out of this here and on bigger apps of course the improvements
would be way bigger because you would be able to get way bigger chunks out of there in an app like this
where the third party libraries make up the majority of the code.
Of course you don't gain that much.
Still it is important to know this technique.
And with that I would say our ReACT app is looking quite decent.
We're ready to deploy it and 2 deployed.
We need to understand which two different options or which two different main options we have for deploying
it.