Let's work on the navigation links snow pretend.
Let's go to NAV links and import react from react.
Because here I want to have a list of navigation links of links in my main header or also in the sidebar
depending on where were you rendered at so there.
I'll have my nav links component which could receive some props.
We'll see if we need that and then export nav links as a default.
I also of course want to import dot slash nav links dot CSA as for some styling.
Now instead of NAV links I will definitely also return some J as X code that includes some links so
we'll import something from react ruder dom.
But that something is not link but its NAV link.
A special link in the end which also can analyze the RL and allows us to for example color the link
differently if we are on the page the link leads to to show the user dead.
This is the currently active link for example and then here I return to unordered list where I'll add
a class name of NAF dash links to it and you should do the same to make sure that the styling I will
provide to you.
Works and then we have a list item in there without a c as as class and they are a nav link which leads
to slash nothing and says all users.
For example and that will now copy that to provide another link here to lets say my places to later
view all the places we created.
So our places.
Let's add another link where we say new place so that we can also add a new place later or also add
place.
Therefore and another link
authenticate which will not be that important right now because we won't add full fledged authentication
at this point.
But it's still good to already have that link.
Now be aware that later not all links will be rendered all the time.
For example my places will only be rendered if we are locked in.
Otherwise there is no way we can view our own places at place will only be rendered if we are logged
in authenticate on the other hand will only be rendered if we are not locked in.
So at the moment they are all rendered.
This will not be the case later.
That's really important to understand.
Also one other thing too the first NAF link which leads to slash.
Nothing at exact as a prop.
This tells the NAF link that it should only mark does link as active and apply to styling.
I will give you in Napoli C as s later when we are exactly on slash nothing and not on any route that
starts with Slash.
Because that would be every route and then this would always be marked as D active link.
Also we need to adjust the other 2 props here of course.
For my places I want to go to slash you one slash places.
This is a dummy place holder.
Later we will populate that with the real user I.D. of the authenticated user but since we have no authenticated
users at the moment there's nothing we can do regarding that here on ad place.
I want to go to slash places slash new.
That's the link we were missing before which we had to manually enter and here let's say for authenticate.
I want to go to slash off.
No that's up to you we haven't added that around yet but we will add it later.
So now we have all these NAF links we can now use that in the main navigation component.
So in there we can simply import nav links from dot dot slash Nath links and then render this year instead
of the free dots nav links like this all the important attached to now find a nav links CSA as file
and you should replace yours or the continent side of it with my nav link see us as content if you do
that and you'll save all files you should see nav links here and you see the active page highlighted
like this.
Of course you can always by the way adjust styles indices as follows If you want to have a different
styling does it just a.
I will go with so all users is currently active if I click on Add place to see does this now active.
So this works we can switch here and of course some routes are not yet supported for example my places
and authenticate we always are redirected there because I haven't registered routes for them yet but
at place and all users were X and now we can switch with help of these buttons.
Now that's great if we highlight this in Mobile you here in the Chrome dev tools by clicking on this
icon though we have the hamburger icon but clicking on it doesn't really do much.
We open those sidebar.
Instead I have the NAV links all clammed in here which doesn't look super great so we should fix that
and we should make sure that on mobile view does.
Also looks good.