Before we work on more of these roots here let's actually restructure our roots file a little bit.
It's already getting a bit bigger still OK but getting bigger and the more roots we add and with all
the logic that needs to execute for every route the bigger it is file will get.
Therefore it's a good idea to follow this MVC structure which stands for a model view controller.
Now we want to have a view here that is what the user would see.
We're building a REST API so there is no page no H html file we would render on the server which we
show to the user but we have models like the arrow or blueprint here and we will have controllers.
Well we don't have time yet but controllers will be files that hold the actual logic that should execute
when a certain route is reached.
So day glued to gather the incoming request and then our models and the logic that should run for such
a incoming request.
Hence here I'll create a new folder controllers and in there I will add a place to stash controller
J.S. file.
Again you could just name it places because it already is a controllers folder.
But to make it really clear all day if I have to file open like this you can quickly see it here at
the top.
What's in the file.
I will name it like this so that this is always clearly visible what's in there.
So we'll have a place as controller and later also user's controller file.
So already create both.
And the idea is that in the places controller we have all the middleware functions which actually are
reached for certain routes.
So for example here Ford is first round here for a specific place idea.
I would cut this function from places routes and move it to the places controller there.
I will add it as a new function and it's up to you which kind of function you create if you use a function
declaration or a function expression here I'll go for a function expression with an arrow function and
it will name it get place by I.D. and paste in my function.
Now as I mentioned alternatives would be to create a function get lazy by IED and then have your logic
there or get place by I.D. and use the expression style but not use an arrow function but use the function
keyword.
These would be alternatives.
All you go for the Arrow function here.
So now we have get placed by idea.
I also have another function of course.
So I'll cut this as well from my roots file and added here in a controller and this file of course will
now get a bit bigger but it's clearly focused on only middleware functions.
And that's the whole idea we want to have focused files we want to have a file which is all about routing
and mapping paths and to HBP methods to controllers and then we want to have controllers which are all
about having these middleware functions.
And the logic.
So it's okay if that file gets a bit bigger we can always go into this file if we want to look for the
logic and go into this file if you want to look for the mapping and the paths we're using and we're
not mixing both in one super huge file.
That's the idea.
So in the places controller we can now add that our function get place by user I.D. paste in that function
here and now important also move the dummy places from the roots file to the places controller file
because that is where we interact with the dummy places.
That's of course therefore where we should have that array.
Now this is all nice.
We don't need to import express here by the way because I'm not using any feature from express here.
I'm just setting up some regular functions which receive everything they need as part parameters.
But we need to export our functions here so that we can link him to the routes which are registered
in a different file.
Side note we also need to import the HDP error model here in the places controller though because I'm
using it in there but now I want to export to get placed by I.D. and they get placed by user I.D. function.
Now we learned that we can export by using module dot exports.
This allows us to export a single thing.
But here I have multiple things for that node.
All the has an alternative export syntax instead of module exports.
You can use exports dot any name of your choice.
But here I like to repeat my function names.
So get a place by I.D. for example and set this equal to the thing you want to export under that name.
So in this case I'll point at get placed by D.
Important I don't execute it.
Express will execute it when that request is incoming.
I just want to export a pointer to that function.
So the Express is able to know what to execute for an incoming request and I'll therefore do the same.
Forget placed by user I.D. here now both will be bundled in one object which now has these properties
which hold the pointers to these functions as values.
So now in places routes we can import our controllers our places controllers can be found with require
by going out of the routes folder into the controllers folder into places controllers and then here
for a router get place I.D. I can point at places controllers get placed by Aidid.
Again I'll not execute it here.
I'll just point edit so Dad Express has a pointer at the function it should execute for us when a request
reaches this route and we can do the same thing here for this route.
And now we have a pointer at this function for this route and a pointer at this function for this route.
The result is that it should work ASP before let's try both the error and the success cases Yep that
is looking good but the difference is that now we now have a clean routes file where we can quickly
see our paths and methods and which controller function is responsible for it and then our controller
file which is a bit longer but which itself then is also clearly focused on just defining our middleware
functions.