This is basically it for this note express refresher.
Now obviously there is more to note and more to express.
We'll learn about a lot of our features throughout our course project.
I don't want to explain everything about note Express here in this refresher.
Instead of we'll all learn more things later.
But as I also already mentioned earlier this course doesn't replace a complete note.
EXPRESS course I do have a dedicated course for that.
So if you want to learn everything about note express then definitely have a look at that course as
well.
One final thing which I want to do here.
Is I really want to make sure that we all understand how this code executes and when what executes because
that can be confusing at times when we start Node 1 with NPM start or we run our file with node app
s which does the same.
If we ignore the life reloading functionality then what happens.
It's important to understand that when you execute this file with node the entire file is passed and
executed.
So this means these imports are passed and executed.
So no chess goes into these packages runs their code and gives us back whatever they export we'll see
these export syntax and how we can use it on our own later by the way they're after this concern is
created and then all these you is post and get methods are called as well as the list method.
What's not being executed immediately when we execute this file are these middleware functions here
not because node has a special exception for them but because of the way javascript works.
These functions here are callback functions provided as arguments to post use and get and therefore
javascript registers them.
Stores a reference a pointer to that function in memory but only executes them once there are getting
called and we are never calling these functions.
Instead with post you isn't get.
We basically let express J s set up some logic which will execute these functions for us when a request
is reaching our server and that request meets our criteria here.
So it's a post request with this path or a get request with this path or in case of does where any request.
Only then these functions get executed it can all be confusing that here.
It doesn't look like we're actually passing a function instead I am executing a method here.
Well this actually returns a function though so here does all the registers.
Such a to be executed function and these functions really only run for incoming requests not when we
start our server and execute app chars with node no D middleware functions are executed for incoming
requests on these requests and that's it with the refresher.
I hope the basics are clear again check out further resources like the course or the official docs of
note and express if you want to learn more.
With that we can move on to the node express app for our actual course project and start working on
that.