We're still not seeing the image here despite using a correct.
You are L because there is something important you have to understand about the back and coat or the
way node express here works in service and general work.
By default none of the files on the service side.
So in our note express app are accessible from outside the server and that's good because otherwise
we could just enter locally host five thousand slash app she asked and have a look at the source code
there.
But fortunately this does not work because every incoming request on the back end goes into our middleware
funnel here in the end and it goes through all the different middleware this year and only the logic
we have in an Middleware is executes so you can't request any file you can just go forward amend the
wares and you ever have a request that's handled by one of the main lawyers or you don't.
For example if we send a request to a U R L which ends with Slash API slash places we make it into our
places routes and that's how the logic there it kicks off.
But for some random image link we've got no middleware that would handle this.
Now of course however we want to grant access to images and to do so we can add a new middleware maybe
here after passing request bodies we can add a new general middleware and then filter for requests that
start with uploads images so requests which have logos 5000 slash uploads slash images at the beginning
of there you are L such requests will be handled by a special middleware which is actually built into
Express Express static you can execute static as a method and this will return a middleware actually
and this is a middleware which just returns you request that file static serving means Dad you just
return a file you don't execute it you just return it.
Now here we have to control which files in which folder we want to return express static.
Then once a path pointing at the folder from which you want to serve files without any extra check.
Now is such a path has to be an absolute path and we can build this with the path module which is built
into node chess.
So we imported with this syntax here and expose it on this path constant.
And then here to static we pass our built path where we join two segments uploads and images.
And this builds a new path pointing at the uploads images folder and any file in there.
If we request it will be returned.
Otherwise all files are locked down but files in this folder if requested are returned.
If we save this and now we go back and we reload our app here.
We see our image Dale for because now we're statically serving it.
And with this the upload works and serving it works.
Now of course we have no places for a user so let's make sure when we locked in that we can actually
also add a place here and that we have an image upload here as well.
Now this is a great practice for you because essentially the steps are the same for uploading an image
for a user.
So definitely try this on your own first in the next lectures we'll do it together.