Now I want to start with the back and forth that let's have a look at the server J.S. file.
This is India and our node express server.
And one important thing about node and express is that unlike with for example P HP when you're building
a node application you launched a server itself with node J.S. with P HP.
You need some extra software like Apache to launch a server which then runs and interprets your P2P
scripts with node you use node itself to launch that server.
So the server js file has all the logic it needs to run the server but also then to handle incoming
requests.
Now we'll dive a bit deeper into how node and express works in a standalone refresh or module.
So I don't want to lose too much time on that right now.
In the end what you'll just see at the end here is that we have some Ellison method which you call which
in the end will start your server and listen on port five thousand.
So this is also where you could change the port but not all ports will work.
Some are not allowed by your system.
And for example three thousand is not allowed because that's where our ReACT AB runs already.
So you should leave that at five thousand.
And in addition besides some obvious setup you will see an app get and app post method this registers
so-called middleware for certain parts.
So here you see that path thing for certain HDP efforts namely here a get method a post method.
So here you see that method path combination thing I was talking about and then some functions that
should be executed when their request reaches such a method path combination.
And then here in the end I sent back a response with some products here I create a new product I validate
the user input before we do anything else and then I create the product create a unique I.D. with some
third party library added here to this dummy products thing I will have a look at in a second and then
sent back a response upon successfully creating that product.
This is our core back and logic.
Now what we're not doing here is talk to a database because for Dad we need to set up a separate long
would he be server which is a bit more work not horrible but a bit more work and therefore we will do
that in a separate module.
But what we do have here with dummy products is a dummy javascript error rate.
This however is only stored in memory of this running node application which means whenever we restart
the server which we can do by quitting our notes server with control C and then rerunning NPM start
all that data will be lost.
So after restarting that server if we reload do react app you'll see it doesn't find any products anymore
because as I mentioned this is only stored in memory of the node app which of course is not a great
storage.
It's just a dummy storage here.
Later we'll of course store data in a database.
You will also see this strange thing.
I will come back to that later.
That is important to allow communication between our front end which runs on a different server than
our backend.
But again I will explain in detail why we need this and what this does later in the course will and
debts already at for our back at you might not understand everything here.
But again we'll have a refresher on Node express later but it should be relatively clear that these
are our endpoints and that this is where our main logic happens on the backend.
Now let's have a look at the front end there we have a react application and react applications are
all about components components can be functions or JavaScript classes.
And in this course I will use only functional components in my react to complete GUI course you'll learn
about both though.
So there you can learn more about real components and different ways of building them.
Now here in the front and folder you'll see that indexed J is fall.
This isn't the end.
The entry point for our front end application this is where we render our ReACT app which is imported
from the app J.S. file.
So let's maybe have a look at that here.
This is D.J. OS X code by the way if you've never seen this before.
This looks like H2 M. It's H HTML in JavaScript an invention by react in the end it's called J as X
and aid is trends to validate javascript bi to build setup which views behind the scenes here with our
NPM start process in the front end.
This is simply a special syntax which allows us to write code which is translated to instructions that
should insert or remove elements in the DOM in a highly readable way to us developers.
So here what I get is I'm rendering a couple of react components header or new product product list.
These are all react components and also some default H HTML elements like Main and paragraph based on
certain conditions for example if we're currently loading or not and I'm passing some data to my components.
Now these components are all imported here at the top and you can find him in their separate files.
For example a button component which wraps the native HDL button and add some extra styling the input
component which combines a label at input to element and adds extra styling and behaviour the header
component which looks like this and some product specific components.
For example our new product form here our product list and a single product item.
This to gather is responsible for getting onto the screen what you saw there and in case that's totally
new.
Besides that react the complete guide course I would recommend to you.
You will always get that brief refresher.
I also already mentioned multiple times now an app has always got more than just our components which
are rendered.
We also got some front end logic so logic that decides what should be shown on the screen and which
also is responsible for sending these background H TTP requests to our well back end which is our No.
Us express server.
Now you see that logic here in the app function in this app component and there.
I use a feature called react hooks.
These are special functions provided by the react library which help us with managing state which is
state dad when it changes leads to a rerun or cycle of the component so which basically tells react
to update the real Dom.
If the data changes and we also use to use a fact hook this is the end hook which allows to random code
when certain pieces of data change.
And here specifically I configured it to run when our application launches and only then.
Now here in this when the application launches code I in the end reach out to the back and the fetch
API is a native javascript API built into browsers.
I send the request to this back and you are L here it automatically is get request and this is a combination
which is supported there get to slash products as you can see in the back and code triggers this function
and then I expect to get back and optic which has a product array which I indeed do sent back here on
the back end and I extract that response.
Then access this product key and set my loaded products so those loaded products state data to the data
I got from the back end.
And as I mentioned this state data is special when it changes react will re render the UI which is the
reason why Windows loading finished it swaps is loading.
Keyword here for either our products or this fallback text.
I also got the ad product handler function of function in a function which is totally fine and JavaScript
it is supported in javascript with out any special tricks.
And in this ad product handler here I can build a product object and then also sent it to the back end.
But to a different you are L slash product and also with a different HBP method.
The default ones get but here I overwrite the default to set it to post and post to slash product that
is also supported on the back end and it triggers this function here now there.
I attach my data and send some extra headers to let the back and know that I'm sending Jason data.
This is a helper method available in javascript to create Jason data.
I'd check if the response is Ok otherwise in the end I will show an alert.
For example if invalid data was entered in the inputs and if everything is fine and we stored our data
in the back and I update the products I work with on the front end to re render the UI and reflect that
newly added product.
This is what happens here.
Now again more detailed refreshers on the ends will be provided later but I hope that with that this
big picture is clear in general.
Now as I mentioned multiple times will build a complete app for all this course from scratch.
You just get this finished app here.
Later we will build it from scratch.
No worries and therefore then you will learn how these pieces are built and how they work together.
But the general structure should already be clear right now with that big picture here.