So we need a list of users here on the users page instead of our dummy users.
So we'll actually get rid of the dummy users here and instead here I want to send a HDP request and
I want to send that request.
When ever this page loads.
That's a difference of course to the off page there we sent the request in a function.
When we click the button.
Now I want to do this when this page loads.
Hence we could of course send a fetch request here right instead of our component function.
And as soon as this component renders we sent the request right.
The problem is we would also always send this request whenever the component re renders which it most
likely does.
Once we got the response data and we change something on the page so we would actually create the infinite
loop to work around that we can use a react hook.
They use a fact hook here.
They use a fact hook allows us to run certain code only when certain dependencies change the code that
runs is defined in the function which is our first argument.
The second argument is an array of dependencies so off data that needs to change for this rerun.
And if this is empty it means it will never rerun.
It will only run once which is exactly what I want here.
So now instead of this only once running use affect function we can send our request to age should it
be local hosted 5000 slash API slash users.
And if we check our backend and we check the users roots there we see it's just slash users.
Keep in mind we only reached this file if we're on API slash users here.
So it's just slash users which triggers dysfunction which is that function I want to trigger and in
this function in the get user's function in the end we return a list of users so a 1 isn't a request
there it should be a GET request.
Hence we don't need to configure it is to send a post request or anything like that.
We also don't need to add a content type header because we're not attaching any data we're not attaching
any content to the outgoing request and we also therefore don't need to attach anybody.
So this request is good like this.
Now it does yield a promise so we can use then here or a single wait.
Now here's one important rule.
Don't turn this function here into a async function.
You could technically do that and it would work but it's not good code.
You as a fact doesn't want a function here which returns a promise and any async function so any function
where you add async will automatically and always return a promise.
So don't do that it's not good code.
It goes against what use effect expects here.
So instead you can create the if.
So an immediate the executing function.
I will name it send request here.
This is now a function which in the end has to is fetch command in it.
This now can use async and it will then execute this function right away here in the end.
So this is just a pattern which I would recommend if you want to use async await because using async
here is not recommended and not where you want it.
So now we can await whips await our response here and then of course we can get the response data by
a waiting response start.
Jason and now we want to use the response data and that's all the difference to before.
In the off component I didn't care about the response data in the success case.
I just called off log in.
Now here I do care about the response data so we actually still want to manage the loading and the error
state here.
But I also want to manage my response data so we can again use use state ok here and setup some states
in this component.
We got the is loading state which we set with set is loading which initially is false we got the error
state and set to air or of course initially undefined and we got the let's say data state or actually
loaded users maybe since we know that this is what we'll have here and set loaded users.
And this initially is also undefined let's say and now here we got the response data.
Once we get that I want to call set loaded users and set as equal to response data.
And now let's have a look at the back end and see what exactly we get back we get back and object which
has a user's key and that user's key will be an array of users.
So in our response we should have that user's key.
So here I want to set my loaded users which should be an array equal to response data dot users.
All the will set is loading to false here because I want to set it to true right before we sent the
request here set it to true
we also might have an error so we can use try catch again.
Move all of that into try and then catch errors here and then in here we can therefore also set is loading
to falls.
But I also want to set my error to error DOD message
and justice before we don't get an error by default if we have a 400 dish or 500 dish status code.
So I will check if the response is not OK so if we have such a code in which case I throw my own error
here response data dot message and then we'll still make it into this catch block we could now all move
set is loading often try catch so that this only runs no matter if we do have an error or not here in
the catch block we don't just update our state otherwise we update set loaded users now I will also
add a function our our handler justice before where I will call set error and reset this.
And now we can add the error modal and the loading state.
And of course all then make sure we use our loaded users.
So let's first of all import some extra component here.
Let's import the error modal from the shared folder and they from components UI elements error modal.
And let's repeat this for diesel loading spinner.
This average component we have in their with both imported.
Let's go down to our J as X code and here items which I pass in should be my loaded users now.
But besides that I will use react fragment because I want to have multiple top level JSA X elements
here which only works with react fragment around them because of course I also want my error modal here
and the error i pass is the errors stage we're managing on clear points at the error handler and besides
the error modal I also want to show a loading spinner so dynamically I'll check if is loading is true
and if it is I will actually add a death here with a class name of center.
That's a globally defined C as s rule and in there I want to output my loading spinner to have a full
screen loading spinner
with all of that.
Let's see where that works if we save that we get an error here.
Kennedy property length of undefined note this error makes sense for two reasons.
For one it makes sense because we render a users list all the time that includes the initial rendering
of this component.
So before this request was sent and before we got back a response loaded users initially is just undefined
and undefined doesn't have a place as property and therefore there is no way for us to render anything
so we should actually only render the users list here if we're not loading.
And if we got loaded users then I want to render this users list so that we don't rendered as a loaded
users is undefined with that.
This looks way better now.
We still don't output places correctly and you'll see I picked a really cool picture here for my avatar.
But besides that you see the number of places is incorrect.
There is no no showing at all.
The reason for data is that the places we get back now on our loaded users is actually an array of places
in the user's list component.
We expect places to actually be well the number of places itself.
So actually since places now is an array we just need to changed as in set place count equal to user
dot places dot length.
And with that if we saved that we see zero places.
So now we can click on a user and we're taken to that users page.
But of course we can't load any places because at the moment we have no places.
So we want to make sure that now when we are logged in we can also create new places.
However before we do that we might want to reorganize our HBP requests and encode a bit because as I
mentioned before we have a lot of duplication.
Managing all that loading in our state is basically always the same.
The same is true for extracting the data and checking the response status and I don't want to repeat
that in every component which needs to send a request.
This screams for a custom hook and hence we will create one a custom hook that sends requests and manages
all the related state.