So we finished the places for the moment.
That's a great first step but there is more to come because in addition to places we also want to add
users to our app users means that we want to be able to sign up so to create a new user account.
We also want to be able to log in so to log into this account and then we want to be able to create
a new place for this specific user.
And this actually shows the two things that are missing.
First thing is the implementation of this user sign up and log in logic.
And the second thing is the relation between the users and the places.
Because if you think about our application data then we have these users and these places and each user
has different properties for example the named email the password and the user image.
And we have the places with the title description the address location and the image.
This is what we build already.
Once we built the user standard which will be the next step then we also have to make sure to create
a relation between these two entities.
You could say because in the end we want to make sure that one user can create multiple places and that
one place can only belong to exactly one user.
So that's the second important step in the rest of this module to establish the connection between the
users and the places.
Therefore let us not continue with step 1 creating our users logic.