So let's make sure we all use our token on update and delete requests because these are the two remaining
routes which are protected so for dead.
Let's maybe start with update place.
There we have our age to DPD request here and there we already are attaching a header but of course
you can attach more than one header.
We can also add authorization here and now we need access to our off object our of context.
Conveniently we already got access here so we can just tap into this existing off object here and get
our token from there.
However remember what we added to authorization is not just a token but actually bearer plus token just
a convention we're following here.
With that we're adding a token here and this should be all for now.
Now let's all do this on place item J.S. where we have our delete functionality HERE WE SEND TO DELETE
request and at the moment all they do here is set up the U R L and then add my method here.
Now we certainly need no bodies that we can pass null here but we want to add our headers object and
there we want to set off for a station to bearer plus off token and we already got access to the off
context object already in this file here.
So with that token is added to all these requests and hence we can give that a try and quickly authenticate
here with the right user.
We will later of course also add a functionality to stay logged in.
And now if you click edit here and click Update this works and if I click delete does all the works.
So we are able to update and delete places we are adding the token there but we still got missing functionality
for example we still can delete and update places that don't belong to us.
We're having some security mechanisms here on the front end.
For example we only show the buttons if we're the right user but we could use postmen to delete places
which don't belong to us because we have no service protection against that.
And addition to that issue on the front that we have the problem that whenever we reload we are locked
out again which of course is all not great.
So there still is room for improvement.