GraphQL also has the ability to update the data stored
on the server by means of mutations.
Mutations such as creating, updating, or deleting will change the data,
unlike a query.
Mutations are defined in the Java code by defining a class
that implements GraphQLMutationResolver.
I've opened the project and navigated to Mutation.java.
Let's take a look at it.
Mutation implements GraphQLMutationResolver.
The mutation resolver allows Spring to automatically detect and
call the right method in response to one of the GraphQL
mutations declared inside of the schema.
So in the schema for Mutation, there are three, creating a new application,
deleting an application, and updating the application owner.
So there're three methods that map to those operations.
Here we have the newApplication.
It simply creates a new application with the values passed in,
and it calls the save method on the applicationRepository.
Next, we have the deleteApplication method,
and it calls the deleteById method on the applicationRepository and returns
true. And, lastly, on line 31, we have updateApplicationOwner. It takes in the
newOwner and the ID of the application to update,
and it uses the applicationRepository to first find the application,
and then it calls the save method here on line 38. So this is a look at the mutation resolver.