Adding error handling logic is straightforward.
For example,
what if a user queries for an application that doesn't exist?
Similar to how we handled the error in the RESTful API by
throwing an application not found exception,
we will follow the same model.
Let's look at exception handling. I've opened the project and I've
navigated to the ApplicationNotFoundException.java file.
Adding error handling logic is pretty straightforward. In this example
we are going to throw an ApplicationNotFoundException if the client
requests an application that doesn't exist.
So let's take a look at this.
The first step is to have the exception extend
RuntimeException and then implement GraphQLError.
GraphicQLError provides a field called extensions, right here on line 13.
And this is used to pass an additional data to the
error object sent to the client. In this case simply, we will pass in the invalidApplicationId.