Hi, this is Kesha Williams from Pluralsight.
Welcome to my course, Spring Boot Fundamentals.
Spring Boot is an extension of the Spring Framework that helps
developers build simple and web‑based applications quickly with
less code by removing much of the boilerplate code and
configuration that characterizes Spring.
This course explores major features of Spring Boot,
like the time‑saving Spring Boots starters to help jump‑start
your development and auto‑configuration,
bootstrapping a simple application using the Spring Initializr,
data access,
and we look at the ease of development when you
combine Spring Boot with Spring MVC, RESTful API development,
and GraphQL servers.
I will also show you how to make your applications
production ready using the Spring Boot Actuator,
and we wrap up with me teaching you about unit and
integration testing with Spring Boot.
When you're finished with this course,
you will have mastered Spring Boot to make
development faster and deployments easier.
You will learn all of this while using a fun case study called TrackZilla,
a bug tracking application that will help you to develop using Spring Boot.
The demonstration vehicle for this course will be
based on a use case from Keysoft,
a fictitious company that needs to quickly develop an application to help manage
bug fixes and enhancement requests for their applications.
Keysoft's engineering team has decided to utilize Spring Boot
to make development faster and deployment easier with minimal
boilerplate code and configuration.
During the course,
you walk through the use case of creating the bug tracking application TrackZilla using Spring Boot.