This course targets Java developers who want to increase their
understanding of Spring Boot and focus on fundamentals.
This course assumes viewers are proficient with the use of IntelliJ or
another Java IDE, Java 8 or above, Maven 3 or above, and have at least a
beginner‑level understanding of the Spring Framework.
This course is not the best starting point if you are just getting into Spring.
Fortunately,
the Pluralsight library has several of these courses. I would recommend
the courses shown for students to gain the beginner‑level understanding
required for this course. Along with the basic knowledge highlighted in
the learning path, they are prerequisite tools needed on your machine:
Java JDK 1.8 or later, a favorite text editor or IDE. For this course,
I will be using IntelliJ, but tools like Eclipse
will also work. Maven 3.0 or above.
This runs in the IDE, but you can also run it from the command line,
which requires you to install it. And Git. So let's get started with Spring Boot.