RESTful APIs are easier to create and easier for many clients to
consume when we compare them to something like SOAP.
They are used a lot for web integration and mobile device applications,
so let's look at how we build REST APIs using Spring Boot.
So this is the TrackZilla application.
The TrackZilla application is now updated to use RESTful APIs.
So let's look at the TzaController, and here on line 23 I'm using the
@RestController annotation. This simplifies creating RESTful web services. The
controller now simply returns object data that is written directly to the HTTP
response as JSON. Here on line 24, this @RequestMapping is an important
annotation because it maps HTTP requests to the correct handler methods in the
controller. Tza will be the root of all requests coming into this API. Now these
two, the @RestController and the @RequestMapping annotations, these are Spring
MVC annotations.
They are not specific to Spring Boot.
Spring also offer shortcut annotations where each method can be annotated.
So let's scroll down to getAllTickets on line 38 look at this @GetMapping.
So this @GetMapping annotation specifically handles get requests
and get requests coming into the tickets path.
So anytime there's a get request to tickets,
it will be mapped to this method getAllTickets.
Now let's scroll back up.
If you remember from the previous lesson,
we annotated our controller with the @Controller annotation.
But in this case,
I'm using @RestController. Now @RestController is really just a
convenience annotation that does nothing more than add the
@Controller and the @ResponseBody annotations.
I do want to note that @RestController doesn't work with our view
technology Thymeleaf, so methods cannot return models. Notice here
this method is returning a ResponseEntity.
Now it can't return models because of the inclusion of the
@ResponseBody annotation. @ResponseBody on a controller indicates
to Spring that the return value of the method is serialized
directly to the body of the HTTP request.
That's fine because what we are building is meant to be consumed as an API.
So here on line 44 let's talk more about ResponseEntity.
ResponseEntity represents the entire HTTP response. That
includes status code. Here on line 46 I'm passing a status code
of OK. So it includes the status code, headers, and the response body.
Now the HTTP response is fully configurable. All I need to do is return it from the endpoint, and Spring handles the rest.