The magic of Spring Boot. I briefly mentioned
auto‑configuration in the last module.
Auto‑configuration is a very useful and powerful feature of Spring Boot,
which takes a convention‑over‑configuration approach.
This is a huge time saver that helps boost productivity when you're building
Java applications. Auto‑configuration looks at the JARs on the class path and
auto‑configures beans automatically. For example,
it auto‑configures a data source if a Hibernate JAR is found on
the class path, or it auto‑configures a DispatcherServlet if a
Spring MVC JAR is found on the class path. Auto‑configuration is
designed to be non‑invasive.
For example,
if you add your beans, like a data source bean, the default embedded
database support backs away and uses what you've provided.
Auto‑configuration is always applied after
user‑defined beans have been registered.
If you need to find out what auto‑configuration is currently being
applied and why, start your application with a debug switch. Or
you can turn on debug logging by adding a simple property value to
application.properties, which I will demo for you in a moment.
Or you can use the Spring Boot Actuator, which we will cover in detail later.
Let's look at adding the property to the application.properties file.
In the demo, we're going to turn on debug level logging for all logging.
Doing so enables debug logs and reports to the console and
helps us better understand auto‑configuration.
Let's find out what auto‑configuration is currently being applied.
I've opened the fundamentals project in IntelliJ,
and I've navigated to the application.properties file.
In this example,
I'm turning on debug level for all logging by simply using DEBUG here.
This enables debug logs and reports it to the console.
So let's restart our application,
and we should eventually see an auto‑configuration report printed in the log.
So let's scroll back up because this is the entire report right here.
So it says CONDITIONS EVALUATION REPORT and Positive matches.
So it shows all of the auto‑configuration that it's doing.
Jackson, DispatcherServlet, all of that's common with Spring.
Now if you continue to scroll down,
you will also see what wasn't auto‑configured.
So there we go.
If you look for negative matches,
it shows what it did not auto‑configure for you, and
this could be helpful as well.
It also shows specifics about why a specific bean is auto‑configured and why it wasn't auto‑configured.