Integration testing allows for testing of the entire application and
all of its layers and not just individual units,
and it is useful to be able to do this without
requiring deployment of the application.
The @SpringBootTest annotation is useful for integration
testing and is chosen over @WebMVCTest because @SpringBootTest
starts the full application context, including the server,
and does not customize component scanning at all. @SpringBootTest
will look for the main configuration class,
annotated with the @SpringBootApplication annotation, and use that to start
a Spring ApplicationContext, simulating a client call.
Let's look at integration testing. I've opened the project and
navigated to the TzaControllerIntegrationTest.java file.
Let's take a look at it.
Let's go to the very top. Here on line 19 we've seen this @RunWith annotation
before. On line 20 there is the @SpringBootTest annotation.
Notice here we are passing in a RANDOM_PORT.
This is very helpful when you're working in a test
environment to avoid conflicts.
And here on line 21 I'm using the @AutoConfigureMockMvc annotation.
This annotation simulates calling the code from the client exactly the
same way as if we were processing a real HTTP request.
And let's scroll down to line 27.
Here we're using a TestRestTemplate.
This is perfect for integration testing,
and it allows us to consume a REST API from this test case.
The neat thing is Spring Boot provides this TestRestTemplate automatically,
and all I have to do is autowire it.
Let's scroll down to line 30.
Let's take a look at the getAllApplications test. Notice on line
32 I'm using the getForEntity of the REST template. The
getForEntity invokes a get request on an API,
and the response is converted and then stored in this
response object, which is of type ResponseEntity. Scroll
down. On line 34 there's an assertion.
I simply assert that the status returned is OK. So let's
execute this by clicking Run Test.
And let's expand this window so that we can see the output of the
integration test. In a moment we should see a green check mark saying
this test passed. And there we have it.
We have the green check mark, and this test was successful.
The next unit test that we have is called getAllTickets,
and it's simply testing that we receive tickets.
So let's execute this one.
And in a moment we should see that green check mark saying that our
integration test passed. And there you have it,
a green check mark for the test passing. And that was a look at integration testing with Spring Boot.