We've reached the end of the course.
Thanks for following along with me and being fully engaged.
You've mastered Spring Boot Fundamentals,
and you've learned how to make development faster and deployment easier.
Let's recap.
We started by talking about the benefits of Spring Boot,
which you've seen firsthand during this course,
things like the Spring Boots Starters and automatic configuration.
You've seen how easy it was to bootstrap a simple application using the Spring
Initializr. We then saw how easy it was to access data using the H2 database
and creating simple queries using repositories.
Next, we looked at configuring a Spring MVC application using Spring Boot.
Then, we looked at the REST architecture style while building a RESTful service.
Then, we explored GraphQL, which is a query language for APIs.
We saw this by creating a GraphQL server that exposed APIs to create,
read, update, and delete data.
We then learned how to make applications production ready by using
Spring Boot Actuator for monitoring and metrics.
We then wrapped up with testing.
I encourage you to take all that you've learned about Spring Boot and
put it to good use as you build your web applications. Good luck in your future endeavors!