Let's see this in action.
We'll look more closely at the application layers used to create this uber‑JAR.
When the TrackZilla application is deployed,
it's packaged in an uber‑JAR with an embedded Tomcat server.
Let's review an extract from the log files. So the first thing that I
want to point out here is that Tomcat started on Port 8080, so we're
using the embedded Tomcat web server.
It's a configuration that you can change in the application.properties file.
Spring Boot also provides a number of options to configure the
embedded server through application.properties as well.
Now there's one other thing in this log file that I want to show you.
So notice here, this is the JAR artifact name,
and this JAR can be used to run the application on any machine where Java 8 is installed.