Since this lesson is devoted to the H2 in‑memory database,
I did want to take the time to show you a quick demo
on how to access that database.
You would go to localhosts:8080/h2.
And on this screen, we have the JDBC URL, and this needs to match
exactly what's found in the application.properties file.
So let's navigate to IntelliJ and look at the
application.properties file, and this is the JDBC URL bug tracker.
So let's go back to the console.
The username is sa, and there is no password, click Connect.
And notice here on the left‑hand side, we see our entities, so APPLICATION,
RELEASE, and TICKET.
If you click this, notice it automatically populates this
command window with the SQL statement that you need in order to
select rows from the application table.
Select Run, and it shows a list of all of the applications in the system.
You can clear it. You can also type SQL here, so select * from
release, and click Run, and it shows all of the releases, and
you're able to see all of the tickets. So this is a quick look at the H2 console for the in‑memory database.