Today I showed you how to configure a Spring MVC application using Spring Boot
covering topics such as the needed POM file dependencies.
We then had an overview of the MVC design pattern,
including the Model, View, and Controller layers for TrackZilla.
Remember that the View layer of TrackZilla uses a
templating engine called Thymeleaf.
We also learned about useful annotations like
@Controller, @Repository, and @Service.
We saw how Spring Boot's automatic configuration assists
with setting up Spring MVC applications.
We wrapped up with me showing you how simple it was to deploy an
application using an embedded Tomcat server. Next, I will show you how to build a RESTful web application with Spring Boot.