Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
It was just my imagination running away with me while our minds are drawn to the unusual.
Even when we did the baseline test at the very beginning of the course,
I bet you got Clint Eastwood.
Why?
Because Clint was the odd man out.
Clinton's unusual in the context of the other items that I gave you more unique than the
other unique items.
If you know what I mean more memorable,
something stand out automatically on that makes them difficult to forget,
as was the case reclaimed eastward.
But cast your mind back to the science.
A lecture,
that part where I said that our minds capture multiple reference points as we learn
something well,
what we're going to do now is maximize that to our benefit.
Can you think of anything else that would make something memorable?
Well,
knowledge,
something that we are already familiar with novelty is another one uniqueness.
How unusual is it?
Emotion.
Does it stimulate your emotions?
Does it make you laugh?
Exaggeration makes something unusually big or small or any other exaggeration guaranteed to
make it memorable senses.
We use these automatically sight,
sound,
touch,
smell,
taste and if you can incorporate that when you're remembering something,
you'll have multiple trigger points.
And sex.
Sex is a great aid to memory.
Enough set.
You can even remember that using the pneumonic Mies with an extra S at the end.
Now the best thing about our imagination is that it's completely private.
We can apply any amount of imagination we like to what we want to remember.
We can link to something we already know,
making novel,
emotional,
exaggerated call in all our senses or make it sexy.
In fact,
the more of those things we can pour into it,
the more reference points or triggers will have and the more memorable it will be.
It's worth noting that your trigger doesn't need to be precise,
just as long as it gets you back to the thing you're trying to recall.
When I recall the Spanish word for waitress,
I immediately picture a waitress with a camera around the neck.
The actual word is camera,
but camera gets me most of the way,
and then it's just a short step to get to camera.
In the next lecture,
we're going to combine everything we've already learned,
and we will use that to memorize the 10 Commandments forwards backwards and in any order.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.