Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back in this exercise,
we're going to memorize the 10 Commandments,
and you're gonna need a route with 10 waypoints.
Given that we will be memorized in the 10 Commandments,
she may want to consider setting this scene at some suitable location,
maybe a church.
You can either have your individual locations inside or outside,
or moving from one to the other,
as long as you are familiar with the route.
Now,
be sure that each of the 10 points are distinct and separate from each other on.
Remember your knees.
Call in everything at your imaginative disposal to make each scene unforgettable.
Now,
remember,
you don't have to get it word for word.
Just something that you can latch onto to get back to what it is.
The rest we can fill in as we go.
Now,
if you need to pause the lecture now,
plan your route.
And when you're ready,
hit,
Play on.
Let's do this.
I'll give you about 10 seconds between each.
But if you need a little longer,
just hit.
Pause.
Ready?
Okay.
Number one,
though shalt have no other gods before me,
though.
Shalt not worship false idols,
though shall not take the name of the Lord in vain.
Remember the Sabbath?
Only your father and mother.
Those shall not kill,
though shall not commit.
Adultery,
though.
Shall not steal,
though shall not bear false witness against your neighbor.
Those shell nook of it.
Okay,
got them.
let's do a quick review.
What was the first,
though,
shall have no the gods before me.
I think of my first location is just having one person in it with a big red rope.
Power in entrance as no one else is allowed in.
Okay.
And number two,
though,
shall not worship false idols here.
I just think of Billy Idol.
Maybe you thought of someone you know who is idle,
which is phonetically the same thing.
Okay.
Said,
though shall not take the name of the Lord in vain.
I think of Carly Simon singing your so vain.
Perhaps you used a weathervane.
Whatever you did is perfectly fine.
Number four.
Remember the Sabbath here?
I think of Ozzy Osborne,
lead singer of Black Sabbath,
who was born just up the road from me in Birmingham.
Okay,
we're halfway point now.
Number five on your father and mother.
I just have my mom and dad here,
nice and simple.
Number six,
though,
shall not kill here.
I use Max from the eighties TV detective show heart to heart wherever there was a case to
be solved.
Maksoud against this being avoid up number seven,
though shall not commit adultery.
You don't need to know how I remember that one.
Number eight,
though,
shall not steal.
Here.
I have a cartoon thief complete with a striped jumper in a swank bank.
And we're almost there.
Number nine.
Now those shelnut bear false witness against your neighbor.
Or like in any other words for me.
I use the whole cast of the TV show Silent Witness which gets me back to the witness and
bearing false witness on the last one.
Those shelnut covet yearn to possess something belonging to another.
My buddy has a really nice motorbike,
which I like a lot,
but it spends more time in the carriage than on the road.
Okay,
so how did you do?
If there were any in there that you struggled with?
Go back and take a look at the association you formed.
Could you add anything to it using your wild imagination that would make it more memorable
.
Sometimes just coming back to it a little later can be enough to give you a new flash of
inspiration.
Okay,
time for another test,
and I'll see you after that.