Okay,
guys.
And welcome back the memory palace and collections I mentioned in the lecture on location
that locations a great for preserving the sequence of things as we just did with the 10
Commandments.
But I also said that location could be useful for grouping things together.
And that's what we're going to do now.
One of the first things I ever memorized just for fun with the American State capitals.
No,
I've never bean to America,
which would be the logical choice of store in this kind of information.
But what I do know really well is cheers.
I never missed an episode of that American sitcom that ran from the 19 eighties to the
nineties.
I know every detail of the bar where Norm sits,
where cliffs.
It's sums office,
the pool room.
When the Indian statue is.
I had no need to recall them in order,
but it seemed like a natural place to solve them,
as that was the most American thing I was familiar with at that time,
a good place for my collection.
When I started to memorize foreign vocabulary,
I store all of my French,
weighs in and around my school.
I hadn't been to France,
but I did learn French in school,
so that's where they live.
When I did Italian,
I stole them in and around Florence.
I visited there many times.
They have lots of places that I can hook things onto.
Spanish vocabulary is stored in and around Barcelona.
Another place I know really well.
To recall anything I've memorized,
I just close my eyes and instantly visit any of the places in my memory palace.
Now we've already started filling yours.
You've lent the planet's andan order,
I might add.
We've memorized the first time wedding anniversaries on.
We've even mastered the 10 Commandments.
Imagine if you entered a pope quiz and all the questions were on those subjects you would
win.
So let's add to your memory palace again Right now.
I mentioned collections at South of this lecture.
So let's memorize a bunch of collective now owns.
Choose a place that's right,
view where you can instantly go back to to retrieve them.
We're going to do 10 of my favorites here,
but there is a huge list is a damn illegible resource from this lecture.
If you really want to test yourself,
I'm gonna give you about five or six seconds between each one.
Ready?
Hagos Bears sleuth.
So a group of bass is called a sleuth of bands.
Buoys a blush of boys,
girls,
a giggle of girls,
head jogs and porcupines,
a critical lizards,
a lounge.
Owls,
a parliament of owls,
wizards.
An argument of Wizards.
Rhine Nursery,
a crash of rhinoceros skunks,
a stench of skunks,
tigers,
an ambush of tigers.
Okay,
did you get them all?
I'll just recap them now so that you can see how you did.
Okay,
so the 1st 1 was bass,
and it's a sleuth of bears.
Next we had boys,
and that was a blush of boys.
Next we had girls,
and it's a giggle of girls on next,
we had hedgehogs and porky pines.
Both had the same collective now,
and that is a prigel of hair junks or porcupines.
Next we have lizards,
and that was a lounge of lizards.
Next came owls,
and there was a parliament of owls.
After that,
we had wizards,
and it's an argument of wizards.
Then came rhinoceros or rhinos,
and that's a crash of rhinos.
Next came skunks,
and there are a stench of skunks and finally we did tigers on.
There is an ambush of tigers.
Okay,
just for completeness.
Here's my associations.
For those bears,
I imagine a bunch of grizzly bears with magnifying glasses,
just like the famous sleuth Sherlock Holmes.
And for Boys.
I imagine a group of boys all blushing as the girls walked by.
So we have a blush of boys girls.
I imagine the girls giggling at the boys as their blushing hedgehogs and porcupines.
I imagine a bunch of hedgehogs with little cocktail Indian skewered on their spiky spines.
This gives me pickle,
which rhymes with prickles,
which is a natural collective known for her jugs and bulky pines.
Okay,
lizards on this one won't apply to everyone,
but it's simple.
For May I just hear the crowded have sung weather with you on the lyrics?
Or do I lie like a lounge room lizard on?
Until I actually looked up?
What the collective name for listens Waas.
I didn't know that it wasa lounge,
so they go do I lie like a lounge room lizard.
Els.
I imagine a mini parliament,
and all the politicians are owls for wizards.
I have Harry Potter and Merlin in an argument casting spells to each other for rhinos.
I imagine a rhino crashing into the side of a car in a safari park,
which almost happened to me years ago.
At the skunks,
I imagine a fell smell coming from a line of skunks,
all sitting on a bench,
which rhymes with stench.
And we have a stench,
skunks and tigers here.
I imagine a group of tigers dressed as red Indian warriors waiting to ambush the Cowboys
coming through the past.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.