guys,
I'm welcome back.
The unusual is nothing to be afraid off phobias.
So we've seen that by forming an association in our minds,
Using our knees on storing that information in their memory palace is pretty damn powerful
right now.
I mentioned earlier about picturing a camera around the neck of a waitress to trigger the
Spanish word for rate waitress camera.
Now,
that's simply enough because the camera on a waitress are easy pictures for us to imagine.
But what if what you want to remember isn't something you can instantly visualize?
Well,
we just break it down until it is in this lecture,
we're gonna memorize a bunch of names of certain phobias which mostly have their roots in
Greek.
The easy part is the suffix.
All phobias end with well,
phobia.
We just need a way to convert those tricky first parts.
So if we took the word milana phobia,
which is the word for the fear of the color black,
Yes,
that's a real thing.
The phobia part is a given,
but what do we do about the melon?
Oh,
is there anything you can think of that could get you back to that?
Perhaps she would think of a melon.
But instead of being yellow,
it's black for the beautiful Italian city of Milan on all Italian cities,
Beautiful except everything is painted black there,
or Gillette a phobia,
the fear of being laughed at.
What does the stem gelato remind you of?
Perhaps gelato that lovely Italian ice cream?
This is how I remember this one.
Have a friend is a stand up comedian and he's rather portly and he does love gourmet ice
cream.
OK,
it's over to you again.
Pick a place in your memory palace to store 10 phobias.
Ready?
Okay,
let's do this.
A Mecca phobia,
A fear of being scratched.
Astra phobia A fear of thunder and lightning.
Claustrophobia enclosed spaces and the fear have having no escape.
Cool ra phobia affair of clowns Frida phobia A fear of becoming too cold.
Jill ETA phobia a fear of being laughed at glass.
A phobia,
a fear of public speaking millennia phobia,
fear of the color,
Black spectra phobia,
fair of mirrors,
xenophobia,
A fear of strangers,
foreigners or aliens.
Okay,
got them.
Let's have always through and see how you did again in no particular order.
So I'm going to give them to in the order that I just gave them to you.
Here are those 10.
Now I'm gonna mix it up a little bit,
Hex.
I'm going to give you the name of the phobia in some instances,
and in some instances I'll tell you the fear and you have to get back to the phobia.
So here we go.
A Mecca phobia.
That's the fear of being scratched and thunder and lightning.
What's the fear of thunder and lightning?
Astra phobia.
Claustrophobia is the fear off enclosed spaces with no escape.
Now,
what's the fear of clams called cool Ra phobia.
Okay,
Andi frig A phobia is the fear off becoming too cold on the fare of being laughed at J A
lot of phobia.
Okay,
Andi glass.
A phobia is the fear off speaking in public and fear of the color Black is milana phobia on
the fear of mirrors,
spectra phobia.
And finally,
xenophobia is the fear off strangers or foreigners or aliens.
Okay,
here's how I remember them.
A Mecca phobia for scratched.
I think of the scene towards the end of Enter the Dragon where Bruce Lee has those
scratches on his chest.
But instead of fighting hard his fighting my friend Amy and she's delivering the scratches
with kung fu chops.
So I get a me and chop,
which is how it's spelled a Mecca phobia.
Okay for Astra phobia here,
I imagine a terrible thunderstorm,
but instead of lightning,
Vox's All Astra's are raining from the sky cause in a thunderous noise and sparks when they
hit the ground for claustrophobia.
This one is quite well known,
but I imagine Santa Clause,
which gives me the clause trapped in a tiny covered claustrophobia on Kalra phobia.
I imagine a bunch of clowns,
all wearing sunglasses cool on rowing,
cool row phobia,
Kalra phobia,
fear of clowns,
freak A phobia.
Quite simple.
This one ages.
Have a refrigerator with the door open,
making everything cold.
Joetta phobia.
I already told you about this on this is my friend,
the gelato munching stand up comedian.
Glass.
A phobia is this fear of public speaking,
and this is a speaker at a podium.
But he can't read these cue cards as the whole room is polished to a high gloss,
blinding him so glass o phobia is a fear of public speaking maleta phobia again.
As I said before,
I just have huge black melons.
Spectra phobia,
I imagine.
Someone wherein spectacles.
But instead of glass,
they have mirrors for lenses.
Just like cool hand Luke on xenophobia.
I imagine an alien from the Ridley Scott movies sitting like Buddha.
Very Zen.
Okay,
so that's 10 phobias committed to memory.
But again,
you can find a huge list is a downloadable resource from this lecture.
If you fancy a challenge,
we'll do one more quiz,
and then I'll show you one of the biggest memory problems ever faces.
Okay,
I'll see you soon.