Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
I never forget a face,
but in your case,
I'll make an exception.
I'm just kidding.
Well,
we've all bean there.
You're out shopping or in a restaurant,
and all of a sudden someone walks up to you and say hi.
Fancy seeing you here.
You see the face.
You know that you've met before.
But for the life of you,
you can't recall where or when and their name.
Forget it.
So you respond in the way with socially conditioned to do.
I'm great.
How are you?
Unless the conversation continues,
you rack your brain.
When do I know this person from?
If you could just get to that,
you may be able to get to their name.
You hope that something they say in the conversation will trigger the memory.
And it will all come flooding back.
But no.
And now you're in a bind.
You're a few minutes into the conversation,
and now it's too late to say sorry.
I know we've met,
but who are you again?
If you would just come clean at the start and said remind me of your name.
Everything would have been so much easier.
But Wouldn't it be even better if you have a system for never forgetting a face?
Or,
more importantly,
a name again?
But if you think about it,
we actually have a pretty good natural ability to remember.
Faces were designed that way.
When most people struggle is putting a name to a face on People can be terribly offended if
you can't recall their name when you meet someone for the first time.
The general advice is to immediately use their name back to them in conversation,
in the hope that repetition will make it stick.
Now,
sometimes this is useful in the short term,
but next week or next month,
next year not so much.
I want set a meeting with the supplier on the guy.
I won't name him.
Actually suffix almost every sentence with my name.
Great to meet you,
Alan.
Yes,
I'd love a coffee.
Alan,
Thank you for seeing me,
Alan.
There is a point where it becomes weird on we just don't do that with people we generally
know do way.
So why do we do it with people we've just met?
It's unnatural.
So how do we do it?
Well,
looking for us we do have any NACE ability to recognize faces,
so we're already halfway there.
All we need to do now is apply a little association,
a location on a dose of imagination and permanently link the name to the face on while
we're at it.
For the ultimate flattery.
A few of the details about them,
too.
No names tend to come in pairs,
with the exception of people like Beyonce and Madonna,
Sting and Prince.
So we have two things to recall.
A thirst name on the last name,
so let's take them in order.
By far the simplest way to recall someone's name is to associate it with something We
already know the K off knees knowledge.
If I want to give you a bunch of names,
you may find that you already know someone with the same name.
Let's try it.
Emma David,
Sally Luca,
Tracy Joe.
Now,
obviously,
depending on where in the world you are,
you may personally know Farm or Lucas than you do Emma's.
You get the picture.
What about these names Elvis share Clint,
Alanis,
Keifer,
Charlie's all these and much more unusual,
but I would be willing to bet that you could probably picture someone with those names some
at least,
if not all.
Now.
I happened upon this method quite by accident when I was in my teens that then I had
trouble with Poles and Johns.
I don't know why,
but whenever I met someone named Paul or John,
it was 50 50 on whether I would call them by their right name,
even after I had known them for months.
The only exception was my cousin Paul.
So that's where I started.
Whenever I met someone named Paul,
I would instantly transport him in my mind to my cousin Paul's house and have him right
there in the room talking to him.
This works so well.
I embarked on a campaign of all the John's and Paul's I already knew and surreptitiously
solicited their names from other people.
If needs me and deposited all my polls at my cousins,
have I even dropped all my Paul is in there for good measure.
That's a pretty crowded place now,
now this off my Paul problem,
but not my jump problem.
I didn't know anyone named John well enough to be all the other Jong's Star Trek style to
be with them,
then he don't on me that the only John I was really quite familiar with was the American
term for toilet or bathroom for those in the US So all my johns were immediately and
irrevocably tele ported to the toilet.
Not terribly ceremonious,
but effective.
Now,
like most people,
I have quite a few people.
I know friends,
family work,
but is and this gave me a veritable treasure trove of hooks I could use whenever I met
someone new.
I just zoom them to the A place that I associate ID with my name alike.
But what if I didn't already personally know someone with that name?
Well,
I just go to the movies or the charts.
I looked for an immediate namesake in someone famous and tie them together that way.
Then we get to the more unusual derivative names.
Paulette,
for example,
also lives at my cousin's halves,
but instead of interactive with all my other polls and Paul Er's she's separate from them
loading a washing machine.
Now this reminds me of Lawn Direct,
and I can successfully reconstruct her name.
From there,
I get the stem Paul issues in my Paul Place but doing the washing gives me the at ending.
In fact,
all my ex do the washing wherever they happen to bay.
Similarly,
all my ekes drink champagne.
Dominique's Vera leaks Anja leaks all set the finest champagne very elegantly from
beautiful crystal flutes.
Ik just sounds posh to me.
All my l's are ringing bells and I bet you can guess why,
Isabel Mirror,
Bell Brielle.
All my Ellis have umbrellas.
Stella.
Gabriella!
Antonella.
If I come across the name I've never heard before I look for sound alikes or break it down
fanatically.
Brielle at,
for example,
gives me cheese.
Brie on umbrella.
Enzo makes me think of Ferrari.
Leif gets me to Leaf.
See one associations you can create out of the following names.
Ladies first.
Jessica,
Sarah,
Emily,
Rebecca,
Emma on the boys Joshua Daniel,
Matthew,
James Thomas Do you already know someone with any of those names or buy a plane?
Your imagination?
Could you make an association hook that could get you back to them in a little while?
I will share with you.
Some of the self is that my friends have sent me so that you can practice on them.
But next we're gonna have a look at surnames.
I'll see you in the next lecture.