Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Meet some of my friends or the rogue's gallery.
Now,
when you're Lincoln and name two face,
be sure to use something permanent about the person.
When I say permanence,
I mean their personal features.
Remember,
Close could change or frequently will ask her their style of dress.
Even something like hair color could change all.
Be less frequently whenever possible.
Go for the things that won't change.
If they happen to look like Tom Cruise,
use that.
Chances are that if they instantly remind you of Tom Cruise the first time you meet,
they probably will the next time,
too.
If they have extraordinarily large years used that.
Just remember to never tell them that that's the first thing you noticed about them.
Okay,
we're going to begin with the picture off this lovely lady.
Now,
remember,
concentrate on the permanent features this young's laid.
His name is Emma Scrivens,
and I'll give you a few seconds just to tie that name to the face.
Okay.
And next we have this gentleman,
my friend John Ropa.
Okay,
Governor.
And there we have the lovely Daniel Jones.
And there we have one of my best friends Jed I,
Joe Lung and now one of the coolest people I know.
This is my friend Roland Campbell.
And now another one of my good friends.
This is the lovely class Saleh win.
And now another cool dude,
Clint Washington.
And now a strikingly handsome fellow with the same haircut is me.
This is Richard Leggett on this lovely lady is my sister off sorts.
And she is Holly cart right on Another great friend of mine.
This is Ashley.
Stanford on this lovely lady here is another great friend of mine.
And this is Emma Thorpe's.
And finally,
this Dodger looking character is my great friend Johnny to phone.
Okay,
let's run through those again backwards.
I'll put the picture on the screen and you name the Perth's and boast their first and last
names.
So who's this guy?
This is Johnny to phone on.
This lovely lady is Emma phobes on this gentleman is Ashley Stanford on this lovely young
lady Holly card.
Right on the one with the same hair.
Critters me,
Richard Leggett's Mr Cool himself,
Clint Washington on this young lady class Selwyn on the King of cool Rolling Campbell Andi
,
this man is Jed.
I Joe Lung on this adorable young lady is my good friend Daniel Jones.
On this rather distinguished looking gentleman is my good friend John Robot.
And finally,
this lovely young lady,
the inimitable Emma Scrivens.
Okay,
how did you do?
If you got all of them?
That's amazing.
Well done.
If not,
don't worry.
There's plenty of opportunity to practice.
If there were any of those that you struggled with,
just go back over the lecture and think about the connections you made.
If they're not sticking,
you can apply your knees to make them more memorable.
As with all things,
practice makes perfect on.
The more you apply these techniques,
the faster and stronger your associations and your memory will be.
If your job brings you into contact with lots of new people,
that's a great chance to give your new skills a test run.
Maybe meet a lot of people socially.
If you don't,
maybe this is a chance for you to kill two birds with one stone.
Make new friends on develop your superpower memory.
Okay,
in the next lecture will take a look at how to tag on extra information about the people
that we've just met.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture