Okay,
guys.
And welcome back the number rime method.
Both of the single digits systems we will look at have been around for a long time,
and you probably may even remember that from childhood.
But just because some method works nicely for Children does not mean that it can't work
equally as well for adults.
In fact,
whenever I begin a study of a new subjects and I have started a lot of stuff my go to
places the Children sections in Waterstones,
which is kind of the UK equivalent of Barnes and Noble adults tend to complicate things
farm or than they should.
It's a curious thing.
I think the kids love land and they eat it up.
It's fun that is right up until the point where adults teach them just out.
Difficult learning is,
and then the joy goes out of it.
But I digress,
so the number rime system is very,
very simple.
You pick a word that rhymes with a number and substitute that simple.
It goes something like this.
Zero hero one bun to shoe three tree full Dole sighs.
Hive six sticks seven heaven eight gate Knowing wine 10 den So it's childish,
as I said,
but let's give it a try.
Picture each of these scenes for about 10 seconds.
How many under par is a birdie?
Engulf one?
Imagine playing golf,
but you use a bung for a ball and you hit a bird.
Just picture that for about 10 seconds.
Okay.
How many humans went into Noah's Ark?
Eight.
No.
Imagine there is a gate eight and everyone on the Ark has to pass through it.
Just picture that scene for a few seconds.
Okay?
Five is the atomic number of boron.
Now imagine a boring person sitting on a beehive.
Five.
In tennis,
how high is the net in feet three.
Imagine a tennis net tied between two trees.
Three on Finally,
the opposite sides of a die Always add up to seven.
Imagine rolling to die at the craps table and praying to heaven for a win.
Okay,
we'll do a quick test now and I'll see you after that.