Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
Let the Internet dual the hard work.
Okay,
now,
this is my preferred website,
which is perfect if you have a little time to come up with good images for your pneumonic
scenes.
It is a C t p colon slash last major die assist system dot info slash e and slash.
Now there's a link to this in the download,
so you don't need to struggle to write that down now.
So let's take a look at it now,
and I'll give you a quick risk through the basic things.
I'll show you something really useful.
So this is the website.
So in here we could we could have a number.
We can type in a number,
just say 25 hit show words and all the words that fit within the major system.
25 to bean N five bean L will be displayed along the top here.
So if you're struggling to instantly come up with the word for 25 using N on D l.
These are all the words that actually fit,
so that's fairly self explanatory.
So you could you could use that or let's certain let's Rodman sake say we we want to type a
word in.
If we talked Michael,
we could see that Michael translates to 365 so you can convert words two numbers so you can
do it the other way around.
So have a play around or that it's It's fairly intuitive,
but here's my favorite,
but this bit the numerical sequence toe words.
So let's think of a big historical thing.
Okay?
DNA mapping was was invented in 1984 by Alec Jeffries,
just up the road from me in the University of Leicester.
So if we said 1984 in here,
the numerical sequence toe wears it was said,
split length of 21 that's gonna do is give us all the words for 19 and all the words for 84
.
So they go.
We can split it any way we could split it.
111 Let's just show you that show words.
So then you could perhaps come up with sentence that would lead you back to the creation of
DNA mapping.
Let's go for two and see if we can find anything anything useful in there.
So let's have a look.
What have we got down here.
We've got dubbed We got tab.
We must have.
We must have done dab.
Must be any that then let's have a look dubbed the latest Dub Dub.
OK,
so dab they do a swab when you have when you have a DNA test,
so DAB is good.
Is rain filling 84?
That could be they go viewer Dub viewer.
That's a fairly good pneumonic to memorize that day and a map in was created in 1984.
They go dub viewer.
Let's think of another thing.
Titanic.
Titanic sank in 1912 didn't it?
If he said 1912 and hit show words,
what have we got?
We got deep on the Titanic sank so that might be a good word to have their someone else do
we have Down here we have deep onda We have deep down detect where we sit down deep down so
they go 1912 translates in the major system to deep down on I'm sure you can find a way to
memorize that that the Titanic sank in 1912 by using the words deep down.
Anyway,
this has another particularly useful purpose and we're gonna come to that in the next,
like jet.
OK,
I'll see you then.