Okay,
guys.
And welcome back.
The Dominic System and the Dominic system was developed by a fellow Brit,
Dominic O Brien,
on,
like,
the major system and also relies on converting numbers to something more memorable.
But this time,
ultimately,
people.
Now,
in my view,
this was a stroke of genius by Mr O Brien as people and much easier to remember,
we have no trouble at all making a picture of a person.
As with the major system,
each number is converted to a letter that the Dominic system has a much simpler logical
released,
I think so.
Those letters then become the initials of someone memorable.
And that's how you get to the person.
Dominic O Brien also went one step further.
Each person will have a unique action or prop associated with them,
making it easy to stack multiple pairs of numbers,
making memorize longer numbers much simpler.
So I'll show you what I mean in a second.
But first here is the number toe letter key.
And as you can see,
it's very simple.
A B C D e a numbers one through 56 is s because it's a strong s word.
Seven and eight G and H.
Just like in alphabet nine is a strong n word and zero is Oh,
so they go.
It's that simple to memorize a B C D e s g h n onda.
So if you know your alphabet,
then you're already 80% of the way there.
See,
I told you it was easy.
The one thing to nose here is that if you can make an instant association between a number
on a person,
go with that over the system.
So 07 may well mean you need to find someone with the initials O and G,
But you probably think of James Bond first.
So use that now.
Similarly,
people of a certain age will possibly remember the movie 10 with Dudley Moore and Bo Derek
.
So for 10 I would go with Dudley Moore Qusai instantly associating with the movie I still
keep Bo.
Derek is 24 though I have an entirely separate action for Bo Derek.
Now,
all of the numbers in the Dominic system are double digit numbers.
So 66 would give us S s on.
There are a few famous people with those initials with Sharon Stone,
Sylvester Stallone Steven Spielberg.
I'm gonna go with Sharon Stone.
So you may recall me saying that each person has a unique action or prop associated with
them.
Will My unique action for Sharon Stone is that famous crossing the legs,
Seen from Basic Instinct.
Stay with me here.
So the Battle of Hastings was in 10.
66 to remember that using the Dominic system,
I have an image that reminds me of the Battle of Hastings,
D.
C.
I,
Hastings from line of duty in battle.
And in that scene I have Dudley Mawr 10 crossing his legs provocatively.
The action for the lovely Sharon Stone.
So Dude,
crossing his legs is 10 and 66 therefore I can get back to 10 66 see how easy that is.
So if I need to remember 66 10 I would have Sharon Stone playing the piano as Dudley Moore
was a virtuoso pianist,
and that's the action I have for him.
I warn you that this system requires you to do the work up front.
You will need to map all 100 pairs of digits from 00 to 99 with corresponding unique action
or props now this could take a while to do,
but the investment is worth it.
As once it's done,
it's always with you.
As always,
there is a downloadable resource with suggestions for famous people you can use with this
course.
But as I mentioned earlier,
if you have an instant link between the number on a person,
use that first in the download.
That will also be a link to a website that will give you a bunch of other suggestions for
people.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.