Okay,
guys.
And welcome back talking telephone numbers.
Now we're going to expand on the Dominic system and I'll show you how can you can utilize
it to memorize even longer numbers by stacking.
We're going to take a phone number of a very well known organization on one.
I hope you never have occasion to call Interpol into pulse phone number.
ISS plus 33 47 24 47.
Double +00 Let's put that into a table civilly.
Looks like.
Okay,
this is what it is.
No,
the memorizing and 11 digit number may seem daunting at first blush,
by stacking that is,
combining one person's action with another persons person.
We actually only need three stages toe our journey.
33 equal Sisi,
who could be Charlie Chaplin,
Charlie's Action or Prop is swinging his walking cane,
but today he's not going to be doing that.
Otherwise,
we'd have 33 33.
47 equals DG equals Danny Glover on I Use that famous scene from Lethal Weapon two,
where he faces off with Joss.
Ackland just claims diplomatic immunity,
and Danny stretches his neck and say's has just been revoked.
So when Charlie Chaplin,
33 stretches his neck and say's It's just been revoked.
We have the person 33 on the action of 47 1 scene four digits.
Next,
we have 24 47 24 equals B D equals Bob Dylan,
and he's normally playing a harmonica on a brace.
But today,
his stretching his neck and saying,
You guessed it has just been revoked.
That scene to know we have eight digits in the bag.
Finally,
we have Ozzie Osborne with a football or a hero,
depending on where the use the number,
shape or number.
Rime system.
So that gives us seen one.
Charlie Chaplin,
Danny Glover's Action 47.
Seen to Bob Dylan,
Seen three.
Ozzie Osborne 00 playing with a football zero.
So 33 47 24 47 000 is into pulse phone number.
I'll see you in the next lecture