Okay,
guys.
And welcome back,
the titans.
Deepen your knowledge.
This is a really short section,
but it's designed to add an interest in fact,
toe what you just learned.
It's completely optional.
But if you find yourself craving even mawr,
you can find a bunch of interesting facts about these gods in the downloadable resource is
ready.
Hagos.
Cronus,
this is a long one.
But bear with me.
He overthrew his parents,
who warned him that his kids would do the same to him.
So he ate almost all of his Children as they were born.
There were more also there.
Okay.
So Zeus didn't get eaten.
Ria his wife swap Zeus out at birth with the rock wrapped in blankets.
And Kronos.
Eight that.
So just pick out a few images and make a picture of that.
Okay.
Really?
A moon of satin is named after her.
Hyperion had three Children who were the gods of the dawn.
The sun and the moon.
CIA.
Her name means Goddess kiis.
His name means questioning or queer e Phoebe.
A moon of Saturn is named after her.
Oh,
she honest had 3000 sons and 3000 daughters.
Busy man Texas.
A moon of satin is named after her creates his wife was hysteria the goddess of fall in
stars.
You'll remember.
He's the god of constellations.
I apparatus a moon of satin is also named after him.
Never signed.
She was the mother of the nine muses.
Zeus was the father.
Feminists,
she instructed mortals in the laws of justice and morality.
Okay,
then let's do a quick review.
Which God ate all of his Children except one Cronus.
What was the interest?
In fact,
about Rhea?
One of Saturn's moons is named after her on what was the interest in fact,
about a high period.
His three Children with the goddess of dawn,
the sun and the moon.
And what does Thea's name mean?
Her name is Goddess on what?
This key s his name mean questioning or queer?
E The interest,
in fact,
about Phoebe.
A moon of Saturn is named after her and who had 3000 suns on 3000 daughters?
Oh,
she on this and tetanus A moon of Saturn is named after her on whose wife was hysteria?
The goddess of falling stars creates God of constellations on the interesting fact about
Iapetus a moon of Saturn is named after him.
I'm almost there.
Who was the mother of the nine?
Muses Never sign on the last one who instructed mortals in the laws of justice and morality
.
Feminists on There you go.
OK,
guys,
Well done.
I'll see you in the next lecture.