Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back.
What you tell yourself is important,
and the chances are that you will have use this phrase before when you're trying to recall
something I can't remember.
But that's just not true.
If you google the phrase,
how much can we remember?
The number one hit is from the excellent team Scientific American Scientific american dot
com.
Check them out.
It say's.
You might only have a few gigabytes of storage space similar to the space in an iPod or a
USB flash drive.
Yet new wrongs combined,
so that each one helps with many memories at a time,
exponentially increasing the brain's memory storage capacity to something closer to around
2.5 petabytes or a 1,000,000 gigabytes.
That's quite a lot,
isn't it?
How many gigabytes do you think you would need to pass your next exam or recall your
mother's birthday or your pin number the American state capitals,
the capitals of every country in the world,
for that matter,
or a forum vocabulary?
Have you ever had this kind of thing happened to you?
You're out with your friends and you're talking about something.
Movies,
Let's say,
and someone say's who played the Liquid Metal Terminator in Terminator two.
You can immediately picture his face.
You may recall that he also replaced Fox Moulder in the last few seasons of The X Files,
and he was in that other show more recently,
Scorpion.
He has the gravelly voice,
the PS ing blue eyes.
Now you may have a dozen different reference points,
but what is his name now?
All of those thoughts conclusively demonstrate that you know who you're talking about.
It's in there somewhere.
If you could just get to his name.
So the night moves on and there was later you're lying in bed,
just about to drop off to sleep.
When you wake up with Start Eureka,
it's Robert Patrick now.
This is because once we set our minds to the task of retrieving a piece of information,
if it's not immediately available to us,
it does not stop looking.
Your mind naturally seeks resolution.
It wants to succeed instead of giving up our mind,
takes the process out of our active consciousness and continues working on the problem
unconsciously on when it is located.
That particular piece of information,
it gives our conscious mind prod and say Hey,
I found that thing You were looking for its Robert Patrick.
So the problem we face is not no capacity to store information.
That is,
for all intents and purposes,
almost limitless.
But in their ability to recall it when needed.
In this course,
I will teach you how to encode the things you want to remember,
so you can instantly recall them on demand.
So from this point forward,
I want you to change your language to something more accurate.
If you find yourself about to utter the words I can't remember,
swap it out immediately.
For at the moment,
I can't recall your memories.
Fine.
And together,
we're going to install a super learner recall mechanism on.
We're gonna have fun along the way.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.