Okay,
guys,
And welcome back the European capitals.
There's a whole wide world of countries and capitals you can practice on,
but for now we'll stick with Europe again.
There are quite a few,
so we'll just do 10.
But this time in reverse alphabetical order.
Now,
at the end of the lecture,
I'll tell you how to remember them.
But these are just pneumonic AIDS,
and no offense is meant to the citizens of those countries.
Okay,
it's just how I remember them.
As always,
you can find a complete list is a downloadable resource,
but let's get you started right away.
Vatican City Vatican City United Kingdom,
London Ukraine Kiev,
Turkey Ankara,
Switzerland Bern,
Sweden Stock home be at Spain.
Madrid,
Slovenia Lubljana,
Slovakia Bratislava and finally Serbia.
Belgrade.
Okay,
have you got them all?
If so,
feel free to move on to the quiz.
But if you struggled with any,
here's how I remember them.
Vatican CITY Vatican City I imagine entering the Vatican to find a slightly smaller Vatican
inside.
I entered that Vatican,
and there's an even smaller Vatican inside that one.
You get the picture now.
United Kingdom London.
Okay,
I'm British,
so I don't need a demonic for this.
Ukraine Kiev I have phrase a crane from the TV show Fraser Eating Chicken.
Kiev's turkey Ankara I have a Christmas turkey anchored to a table.
Switzerland!
Bern I have a very posh bank,
which I associate with Switzerland on fire,
and anyone who goes near it gets burned.
Sweden Stockholm Have Eureka Johnson from Sweden in the stocks home.
SPAIN Madrid I have Spanish Armada off the coast of France,
but Sir Francis straight gets mad when he sees them coming and rids them away.
Madrid,
Slovenia Lubljana.
I have a slow van Slovenia,
driven by my friend Anna.
It's a yellow three wheeler,
like the one in only fools and horses and Del Boy Trotter is saying,
That's lovely.
Anna Lubljana,
Slovakia Bratislava.
I have a slow vacuum being operated by one of the brats in a balaclava.
Okay,
and finally Serbia Belgrade.
I have a servant ringing a bell on being graded on.
Doing so right.
There's a fully sheikhoun download if you want to do all of them.
But until then,
I'll see you in the next lecture