Okay,
guys.
And welcome back introduction to the language section.
So learning a foreign language is tough,
right?
It can take a lifetime to master.
Now,
if we're talking about having complete command of all the intricacies and new insists of a
foreign tongue,
that may be true.
But by that school,
I can't even speak English yet.
But I seem to get by on that,
I think,
is one of the reasons that many adults have put off trying to learn a second language.
Now I say second deliberately because once you've got number two under your belt,
number three isn't so daunting.
A number four easiest still years ago had a debate with the lady had been study in Spanish
for five years.
She said that in order to be understood,
you must understand grammatical structure on be able to use it.
And she spent most of her time learning that before she began memorized in any words.
Now I agree the grammar is important to speak well,
but it kind of takes the fun out of it.
Who wants to study for a year before they actually learn to say anything?
They want to Well,
those with more patients than me.
That should probably be more patients than I.
Now I think you can get off to a flying start by acquiring a bunch of useful words off
front.
At least you will have the basics of communication.
It may not be pretty,
but you'll be understood now.
I live near Birmingham in the UK,
and a lot of tourists from all over the world visit to shop in the bullring.
Now,
if someone approach me said Toilet,
where I would understand and direct them,
I wouldn't say,
Hey,
buddy,
you know,
that was a poorly form sentence,
donu.
So in this section,
we're gonna learn about 10 words in multiple languages.
Now,
you may be thinking that that will get confused him,
but we will store them in completely different places.
So for each language picker place,
you associate with that language and store your pictures there.
Let's begin with French.
I'll see you in the next lecture