Okay,
guys.
And welcome back Spanish vocabulary.
Okay,
so you've got a few French words and Italian words.
Let's get straight into this with Spanish.
Remember,
Make sure you choose a location that will instantly remind you off Spain.
Okay.
Hey,
goes knife Curcio Folk telling door spoon.
Cruchaga plate,
Plateau bowl.
Quinn,
Go cook Tessa Glass Vassal Vogtle.
But tell yah Source.
Spin casserole.
Kettle.
Tell her.
Okay.
Did you manage to create some weird and wonderful scenes out Those as always,
If you struggled with any review your scene and see if there's anything you can make
stronger using your knees.
Here's how I remember them.
Knife.
Correggio.
A depressed,
low Anton culture.
I use Anton Kercher.
Quite a lot.
Fork 10 A door.
I have throwing fox at tempo notes.
Tenors on a door.
Adore spoon.
Cucchiara.
I have Anton Kercher again playing spoons in a rah rah skirt.
I have Roscoe.
It's quite a lot to plate.
Plateau.
I have a plat on a round plate which gives me plat platter Bowl Cuenca.
I have Koo Stark sitting in a bowl winking coup wink Kolinko cup Kasse.
I have a cup with tassels on the handle again.
Glass Vasa I have a glass filled with Vasso Lean Bottle Bhatia.
I have Ella Fitzgerald,
which is how it's spelled with a bottle.
But tell you source.
Been casserole a again.
Cooking casseroles in a pen.
I'm finally kettle tele,
a stuttering Terry Jones in a row.
Rask ERT boiling a kettle.
I told your are Raska is featured heavily.
Okay,
so that's three romance languages French,
Italian on Spanish.
Next will switch it up a gear and learn German.
Now again,
you're going to do exactly the same words.
But just be sure that you stole them in a completely different place.
Something Germany E Okay,
I'll see you in the next like champ.