Okay,
guys on Welcome back.
You'll see an awful lot of downloads from this this course,
but I wanted to give you this as well.
And this is what I used to build your downloads.
Now,
what we have here is a simple Excel spreadsheet template,
and this one's particularly geared,
or this one's set up to be 100 lines long.
So if you have something that you need to memorize,
you can put it into your study plan On the off screen I have all the capitals of the United
States was.
I'm just gonna copy.
I'm gonna click in here on the right,
click and juice pay special,
and they're all my American state capital.
So I'm just going to type up here state.
And I'm just going type over here can be towel.
No,
because I only need 50 lines.
I'm just going to delete everything else that's below it.
So I'm just going to drag down,
right?
Click and hit.
Delete.
This isn't a neck soul course,
though.
I do have some amazing excelled courses.
Do check them out.
And I'm just gonna put a thick border around that.
So they go.
That looks all pretty.
So you have you state your capital.
Let's just line those up on here.
You have your comments.
This is where you can write details about your No Monix.
Now,
if you need to,
you can change the template name here.
But if you put it up in here,
American State Cappie Towels.
When we flip over to the revision plan,
you'll notice that it has pulled the title over with it.
And it has also pulled all the values that we had in the first sheet,
so you don't need to type them out again.
Now again,
this is set up for 100 lines,
but I'm just going to delete everything.
Bill low there.
So it's going to right.
Click and delete from Andi for pretty in the sake on the part of thick box around that
again.
OK,
so here is your revision plan in the Yellow Cell,
insert today's date and sell seasick,
so today's 31st of the eighth and you can see that your optimum revision plan has already
been calculated for you.
So today immediate assumes you've learnt it.
Do your revision.
Take the test.
If you don't want to see the ounces here you can always right click on choose Hide.
So we have one day,
three days,
seven days after that.
14 days after that,
among three months.
Six months.
You will never forget anything if you follow this revision plan.
So just to show you how this works,
If we went Teoh to where we Alabama and put mult grant OPEC and spelled Montgomery and his
enter,
we get a green on 2% because we got one of our 50 answers.
Right?
But if we went to Alaska and typed Texas and hit enter,
you can see that that goes red.
Now,
obviously,
for the more that you get right,
you get more greens,
get them.
All right,
You get 100%.
I suggest that once you've done your first revision plan,
let me just delete those on unhygienic.
There we go.
Once you've done your immediate revision plan,
just hide that and hide that on.
Then carry on with this,
and if you need to print it out,
you can print it out easily.
On that is your revision template.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.