Okay,
guys.
And welcome back,
German.
Okay,
so you've made a start with three?
Yes.
Three foreign languages.
Did you notice how some of the words are?
Very similar Tasks seems to be common for cup.
We just slight differences in spelling and pronunciation.
So now we come to a Germanic language German.
Remember to stall these in a German themed place knife,
messa folk gobble,
spoon Look.
Fell plate teller.
Bold Schuessel Cup cuss glass Glass
bottle Flasher Source.
Spin cook tops Kettle Castle.
Okay,
So Germanic words send a little different from words in the romance languages,
but you can still turn them into pictures.
Here's how I remember them.
Knife Messa Making a mess with a knife Folk gobble Gobbling your food with a fork Spoon
Lawful,
loving Elvis So much you spoon with him.
Plate teller.
A bank teller Juggling plates Bowl Schuessel.
Excellent bowls.
Cheap price.
A short sell Schuessel Coop Tacit a cup with tassels on the handle that's comin through all
four of the languages we've looked at glass glass,
typically a German word that's also in English are used.
Boris Becker drinking from a glass bottle Flasher.
I have a Flasher with the bottle Injuries,
Mac.
Preserving his dignity.
Source Been cock top.
I have a cockerel on top off a source.
Been blocked off.
Kettle Castle.
A kettle whistling.
Okay,
that's the start of four foreign languages.
I bet you didn't think it have that India belt this time last week.
Of course,
you can enter this by getting a bilingual dictionary and creating even more crazy scenes.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.