Okay,
guys.
And welcome back the story method we learned in the last lecture held by forming a
connection.
An association between items we want to remember.
We have a really neat way of committing seemingly unconnected things together.
Not only did we go from Item 1 to 2,
Mercury to Venus,
but then 2 to 3.
Venus to Earth,
3 to 4,
earth to Mars.
And so one until we got an entire memorable scene that we can instantly play back in our
heads forwards backwards and in any order.
Cool,
Right.
Well,
this time it's your 10.
Now,
what I'd like it to do it's not compulsory is to post your story to the Q and a section of
the cause.
So we can all see how creative you bean Nothing rude or offensive.
Please.
As I say,
it's entirely optional.
Okay,
as start point,
I want you to imagine a wedding scene of some sort.
Maybe here Mendelssohn's wedding march playing in the background,
I'm going to give them to you want us?
It's home with five or six seconds in between each.
If you need a little longer,
just hit pause until you've made that connection and then come back.
Remember,
your first thought is often the best.
Ready.
Hagos paper.
Cotton,
Lead them limn.
Would I n wolf
Bruns.
Pottery Tin.
Okay,
let's see how you did.
Close your eyes.
Can you see that welling seen here?
The music.
Okay,
good.
Then what was the first item?
It was paper and then a second item.
Cotton.
I said leather number.
Full linen number five would sinks.
I n seven was wolf eight with bronze.
Nine pottery on 10 was 10.
Okay.
Did you get them all?
If you did well done.
That is amazing.
If not,
that's fine too.
As we still have more techniques to come,
they can you guess what?
That sequence Waas.
It's the 1st 10 wedding anniversaries.
Now I must point out that this is the US version.
The UK version is slightly different,
but both through available to download from this lecture along with all the subsequent
anniversaries if you fancy the challenge.
So here's my story for recall in them.
I imagine I am outside a church in the wedding march is being played and that sets the
scene for me And the entire church is made of papier mache A,
which is paper,
and that's unusual.
Now the bride and groom appear at the church door.
Notice the order,
their bride and groom.
The bride is duct cotton from EastEnders and that gives me cotton.
On her groom is a big cartoon cow,
which gives me leather.
They walked down the past to a pile of wedding presents,
which they then proceed to open,
and everyone is bought than the same thing.
Bed linen,
linen So everything doesn't make a mess.
A little help is dragging each one away as they open it.
That's Woody Woodpecker would.
But what's he doing with them?
Well,
because they're all creased from the pathogen is ironing them so that crisp and neat and
that gives me iron as he completes,
Each one is stacking them on the backs of sheep,
and that gives me wolf.
Eventually,
there's a herd of sheep balancing piles of betting on their backs,
and they all end off in the same direction.
But they keep bumping into things.
I looked to see why,
and I can see that sun is glinting off something in the distance,
and it's blinding them.
The poor things I get close to the object,
and I can see it's a huge bronze statue of Cupid Bruns.
Now they are so in love and Cuba.
This firing is Arrow Demi Moore and Patrick Swayze E.
Who were recreating that scene from Ghost,
the one where he sits behind her at the potter's wheel.
Pottery.
Now the trouble is,
the wheel is making such a squeaking noise is going to ruin the entire day.
Luckily,
help is on hand,
and the Tin Man from the Wizard of us 10 comes to the rescue and oils the wheel,
and everyone lived happily ever after.
And don't all the best stories having that way?
Okay,
Before we move on,
let's take another short test and I'll see you after that.