Welcome welcome welcome in this lecture.
We're going to get straight stuck in with actually figuring out how to jump in and have two players
in the game look at this.
I've got my first player which I'm going to be calling Harry running around in front of my other player
which I'm going to be calling Bob.
And you can see that on Bob's screen he can see me running back and forth and not only that I can swap
into Bob's screen and move him around and Harry can see me moving around.
And I just want to show you how easy it is with an Real's built in multiplayer support to achieve this.
In fact we're going to retrieving this in one lecture the first lecture.
So you are going to be having a whale of a time.
Let's dive right in.
Okay so we're diving right into Unreal.
Out at the outset.
So why want you to do right now is go and make sure you've got the latest version unreel and Visual
Studio or X code.
If you are on a Mac.
So here in these videos I'm going to be using four point seventeen.
But these instructions should work for other videos if they don't let me know and I will fix them.
So as I said four point seventeen Let's go ahead and launch.
This is the stage at which should go and pause video and get it running because for the rest of this
video we are going to be showing you you can have your hands on your lap and waiting for be unreal installed
to happen.
But I'm going to show you and then at the end of the video I'm going to challenge you to do the same
thing.
So it's important that you have a real ready by then.
So go ahead and pause if you haven't done so already.
So that was my quick note on unreel versions and as you can see here how have forgot to update the bar
at the bottom but generally what I'm going to be doing is updating that bar to show you where we are
in the video.
Okay so next up we I've got four point seventeen open.
What we're going to do.
Well we are going to be making a puzzle platform game third puzzle puzzle platform game.
So the logical place to start is with a third person lay out so let's just have a look at that.
I'm going to create the base project here.
So I'm going to go to the new project tab in the unreal project browser to the C++ tab and we're going
to be using that third person example which is probably quite familiar to you if you use a lot of unreel
before.
Now I'm going to exclude any starter content excluder have maximum quality do a desktop console set
up and what am I going to do.
Well I'm going to put it.
It's already selected the folder I want to put it in and I am going to just give it a name which is
going to be puzzle platforms.
That I'm using camel case and no spaces.
So I'm going to go ahead and create that project obviously.
You call it whatever you like put it wherever you like it.
The important thing is just that you know where it is and that you are consistent in naming and all
that source Good stuff which you should probably be familiar with at this point.
So we got to go ahead and just leave it to compile at this point and build the project and do all the
fiddly things that unreel likes to do.
Now the whole point of diving right into Unreal here before I even told you about our course is before
I have even told you about how to go and get support and anything else about this multiplayer journey
that we're taking is because it's just so easy to get started and get a quick win with multiplayer and
real and I want to show you just how easy that is and get you diving right into one real from the get
go.
So that's what we're going to be doing we're going to be learning how we can test with multiple players
in unreel just with a very simple base project.
Now as I said you can just be following along with your hands on your OF FUN real is updating where
you having to install Visual Studio vice or so on and so forth.
Well that is just fine or you can be following along as well.
It's not going to hurt if you are following along.
That's going to be the challenge later for those of you who are still downloading and stalling.
So here I've got visual studio has popped up.
We're also going to see that we have had our own real editor pop up here with a very common third person
example map.
Go ahead play they go.
Here's my third person he can run around.
He can jump around and it's all very fluid and lovely and good graphics as unreel is very noted for.
So how do we go ahead and do this thing which I am saying at the bottom test with multiple players.
Well we just go to the drop down menu next to play.
It's as simple as changing the number of players we can select to players.
And if we go ahead and hit play you will see that we've got one player.
There's a second player over there and where is he.
Well if I go and windows tab then I'm going to see that there's another window here which is my second
player and I can control that second player to.
Again I can jump around walk around and let me just prove it to you.
Here's my other player he can see.
But the other non-plan Number two is now standing in front of me let's call him Harry this player that's
running around now.
And Bob as the other player that is second place.
So Bob can run in front of Harry and Harry can see that Bob has run in front of him that's all hunky
dory fantastic.
And if you don't believe me that it's not happening at the same time I'm just going to stick these two
windows right next to each other like so.
And I'm going to repossess.
So I do possess there.
What's going on.
I've not got focus.
And if I go to my windows a bit small but in this extra expand toolbar menu I can go in and hopefully
possess or a ject player so that I'm possessing and you can see that's running around.
This is Harry I believe if I move Harry around then Bob's screen can see that very same movement.
Okay.
So that's quite cool.
A lot's going on there under the hood.
In order to achieve this so let's have a little chat about what is going on under the hood in unreel
when you change the number of players and hit play.
In fact what's going on when you hit play full stop you know why we got this little character here and
why are we able to control him and where.
Why is that other dude.
Bob we called him.
Why is he spawning over there.
Let's find out.
So what's going on under the hood is that unreal is loading a map.
That's kind of.
And Real's central concept is the map and you have a map loaded in the editor.
And so when you hit play that map is the one that you're playing.
So there's a map simple.
Okay now the map specifies game mode.
You've come across game modes before.
Just to remind you if you go into you I think it's the blueprints menu on the toolbar.
Then you can see that there's a project settings and there's a game mode but you can also override the
game mode for a world.
Now World and maps are more or less the same thing there's a little bit more information in a world.
But for our purposes world equals a map now.
Then we've got a play a controller who joins the map.
That's when we put two players vs. one player we create two player controllers and join them into the
map.
So that means that we've got two players essentially.
But we need a little character controls so this is where the player control and asks the game mode to
spawn a pawn for it.
Then that pawn is linked to the player controller and you can move around.
Now this link actually happens over the network when playing in a multiplayer game out or playing in
multiple screens.
But we will worry about the link over the network in greater detail later.
So no worries about that just yet so it is now time for you to do the same thing hopefully unreel has
finished downloading for you or setting up if not you may have to pause and wait around a little bit
but do don't go too far.
Don't get tempted away by things so this is a challenge slider he can tell by the pause symbol down
in the bottom right.
And in this challenge I'd like you to get set up so here is the definition of the challenge I'd like
you to make sure unreal as finished updating and it's all up to date installed.
I'd like you to create a third person project just like I did and test with multiple players again just
like I did try fiddle around try playing with three players see what happens and try using the different
types of play mode.
So for example I had just to hit play but there's other types of play mode such as a new editor window
standalone game simulate see what happens with those different types.
Game mode.
And then finally as a bonus for those of you who know what version control is make sure you have got
your version control all set up with a guess ignore and things like that.
If he's in gear it obviously has been or mercurial.
All have their own different ways of ignoring files that you don't want to be version controlling.
If you know about version control you already know about that.
I do recommend you read up on it.
If you've got the time and the interest case a pause video and have a go at the challenge.
Okay welcome back.
So the final part of this challenge that I haven't showed you is what happens if we do a play in editor
Ed a new edit window.
Very simply what we've got going on here is that we've now got two windows one for Harry and one for
Bob which can be quite handy especially if you've got multiple monitors to move them into two monitors
like I have.
And you can see them side by side now.
I'm not going to be using that feature because you guys won't be enough to see the other monitor so
let's just close.
So that's the most useful play mode.
The other ones will do other things such a standalone game will actually spawn it into a separate process
etc. etc..
It's not terribly important but the main one is there that you know about the new play an editor window
back.
Be quite helpful indeed.
Okay so with that there is just that final bonus part of the challenge which you can go ahead and skip.
If you're not using version control which is to set up a YOUR version control set up a kit ignore now.
I already have some version control running here I've got source tree in the background to those of
you familiar with Gimp.
Then this may be a tool that you're using you might be using the get command line.
Those are all sorts of ways.
If I go and have a look at my uncommitted changes we can see that I've got my puzzle platforms I made
it in the right directories where I already had get set up.
You can see that my puzzle platforms has got lots of uncommitted changes and some of which we don't
really want to be keeping such as these visual studio database files.
They are good as going to be a bit of a nuisance aren't they.
So let's not version control those.
Let's make sure we go and get a premade version control gitte Ignore.
And I'm going to go ahead.
Open up.
Chrome and I'm going to just search for unreel Gates.
Ignore because you're going to find it very very easily on the gitte hubs.
Here we go.
Here's the hubs and I am going to look at the raw version of the file because this version I can right
click save a has and I am going to right click save as in to my one puzzle platforms puzzle platforms
directory said this is important thing is the root of the unreel project that's where we want to save
it.
And as always we want it to be called Dot gate.
Eg.
Naw exactly like that.
No spaces no capitalization and a dot at the beginning.
We go ahead save that you see downloaded and we can hop on over into source tree.
Maybe with an EF 5 refresh or maybe not.
Here we go.
It's already done it and we've got rid of all those ugly files though didn't want.
We can stage we can commit this.
I'm going to commit this off-screen because that's what I usually do and we are good to go set up with
version control.
We are golden and I'll see you in the next lecture we were going to talk a little bit more about this
course and how to get the most out of it.
See you there.