Welcome in this lecture.
We aren't going to be looking at the essence of a client server model and why.
And real users in the first place then we are going to learn how we can launch a server in unreal and
connect to it as clients and we're going to be doing this using the command prompt over here.
As you can see I have launched up a bunch of things here.
You probably don't know what that means yet but don't worry you will do by the end of this lecture.
And you can see that I've got three other windows here too for the clients and one for the server.
And I've got two visual windows for the clients.
If that's all gobbledygook to you then you really need this lecture.
So dive right in.
And we'll find out what that all means.
So I want to tell you a little bit about something called the client server model and why we use this
in unreel to do that.
We're going to start off with a little bit of grounding in what being a multiplier and doing a multiplayer
is all about.
And the main two things that it's all about is input end state.
Now let me explain what I mean by that state is basically everything in your world and its positions
it's velocity's anything that can basically affect what you see the state as what gets rendered by the
engine into the image you see on the screen.
So it's all the transforms are the actors the various variables in the components the various variables
in the actors and so on and so forth.
So it's whether an explosion has just gone off it is where the actor is OK at certain position with
a certain velocity.
I'm repeating myself.
That's the idea of state and what happens with state.
Well we add to it some actions some inputs which are things like me pressing a button or holding down
a throttle or a joystick and all that sort of thing.
Now what happens in an engine is that during the tick particularly called the Tick.
And real you combine the current state with the current inputs or the current actions and result with
a second stage.
The next step.
And then this state is the thing that gets rendered and showed to the user.
And so on and so forth.
The cycle repeats and repeats.
Now clearly to have a good multiplayer game you've got to have the different players agree what the
State of the game is.
It's no use one player thinking oh I've won.
And the other play thinking oh no I won because that's obviously going to be a bit of a silly game.
It's really more of a single player game than a multiplayer game.
Someone's got to win.
You've got to be able to call up your friend and say I just did this amazing headshot on you deny and
that friends got to go oh yeah you did.
So that's the idea we want to be able to agree on the state and we need to be able to incorporate the
actions from both players.
To do that otherwise it would be very straightforward it would be like lives streaming a twitch castino
one person's doing the actions everyone else is just watching his state.
So we need crucially to have actions from both players and for both players to agree what the state
is now saying both players obviously here it can be way more than just two.
So let's talk a little bit about one of the simple and kind of naïve ways of implementing this kind
of thing.
It's called peer to peer because there is no server.
It's only about the players all communicating with each other.
So we've got four players here denoted by these four computer screens I don't really like people I like
computers so I'm only drawn the players as computers.
And what we're going to do is say that when I make a change to my inputs I'm going to broadcast it to
everybody as in I'm going to send a message to all the other players saying here's the input that I
have just made.
And what's going to happen is that all those players are going to update their state based on the inputs
they have received.
Now one crucial thing to note about this is that in order to correctly update my state I need to wait
to listen to everybody else's inputs before I update the state.
And before we can move on to the next frame before we can do the next tick and as the crucial problem
because it means we have to wait for the slowest person and I don't mean the slowest person in terms
of their trigger reactions.
I mean the slowest person in terms of their network connection the time it takes for their message to
reach my computer.
So we have to take that into account and we have to wait for that before we can do the next take and
unfortunately this can lead to an incredibly incredibly slow game.
So this is one of the crucial downsides of a peer to peer architecture like this.
Another big problem with this architecture is the security.
You could easily have one of these players just cheating and sending out inputs that it doesn't know
to be true.
So it's not actually doing the right thing at all or am i be saying that I'm going really fast and you've
got no way of making sure that the states are staying in sync.
You hope that with the same inputs things are gonna stay the same but often with things like the physics
engines these can slightly differ and these differences can compound and become really massive.
So you don't end up agreeing on state at all.
Now there are ways of fixing this but one of the very easy ways of fixing is one of the simplest and
most intuitive ways of fixing this is that you take the same four computers that you had before and
instead of connecting them to each other you connect them to a central server this ominous looking obsidian
box here.
Now what we do is when we have some input to talk about help we tell the server not all the other users.
Then that server will update its notion of the state.
Now its version of the state is authoritative.
That means that what the server says goes and then the server will say okay well I know what changed
in this state.
So I'm going tell everybody else what's changed so they can update their local versions their local
copies of the state and they can render that to their player.
So this is a very very simple model and this is one real uses which is why I am kind of finishing with
it because it's very useful for you to understand what's going on under the covers and we're going to
become Grebe covering the whole replication concept in much more detail later on.
But for now it's sufficient to understand that we need to connect to a server.
Everybody needs to connect to a server so that this kind of thing can go on so that we can send our
inputs and we can receive the changes to the state that we need to make in order to render.
Okay so let's have a look at how we can achieve this.
The first thing that we need to do is open up the command prompt or on Mac you're going to be opening
up the terminal because we want to do is be able to launch a game from the command line because it allows
us to launch it both as a game as a client or as a server or as a server turned client.
That's another thing that is not on this diagram but something to point out that the player can also
be the server they don't have to be two separate boxes.
They can be the same.
And I'm you probably familiar with this from playing online games itself.
So the first thing we need to do is find the unreal executable so Im going to go to my file browser
here.
And it has opened over on the other window.
But those of you on a Mac just bear with me for one minute while we do the windows instructions and
your instructions will be next.
Going to go to my program files so the seed cedar rectory.
I think its program files not the exe.
Eighty six and I'm looking for and real.
Four point seventeen which is down here.
And then we are going to go in to the engine folder.
And then two binaries.
Then in two wins 64.
And in here we should have an executable called you E4 Ed..
Here it is right here.
It's going to click on that and click copy path.
Now you can do that any way you like on Mac.
It's going to be slightly different.
I'm going to paste that into my command prompt.
Then the second thing I need is the project.
Where do I find the project.
Well you obviously know where your own project is and we're looking particularly for the EU project
file.
And I'm going to copy the path of the you project file.
And I'm going to stick that in to command prompt again at and pace that they go.
So for those of you on a Mac the process is going to look ever so slightly different.
So go to the root of your device.
In my case it's a MacBook Air yours might be different then go to your Macintosh HD or whatever your
main hard drive is now you might expect to find an application in applications but you'd be wrong.
It's slightly different with unreel you've got to go into users and shared and there will be a shared
user there and then you go to big games.
I believe yes there are big games then the unrule version this one's a bit older on my Mac.
And then we go over to the engine.
Binary is very much the same now.
Go to a Mac this time rather than Windows.
And you've got the UNIFOR editor now you might be tempted to just take that as your binary but it's
not actually a binary it's an app.
So we have to do is you have to right click it go to show package contents and this land you inside
the app and you go to content Mac OS and then down here somewhere we have the actual binary which has
no extension at all which is ewy for Ed. And you can command see this binary and go ahead and paste
it in that you already in waiting terminal and then I'm sure you can do the rest yourself.
Now notice a couple of things.
There is a space between these two.
And if you've done it via copying and pasting like I've done you'll see that there are also quotes around
the two patterns.
Okay so that's going to be helpful.
Now if you launch it just like this is going to launch up an editor window.
So what we need to do to make sure it launches again is put a dash and game on the end.
If I do that then what I'm going to see hopefully will go is the puzzle platforms a dialogue loading
up which is telling me it's late in the game and then hopefully that will pop up in to a full screen
game.
Here we go.
See this happily.
Here I am in my third person environment jumping around moving around so that is a standalone game.
Now this can be very useful.
For example if you've got a bug that's crashing the editor consistently and you want to figure out what
it is because if you launch a game up like this it won't crash the editor it will only crash.
This one particular game.
To quit all we need to do is alter for with the window highlighted and that's command.
Q On the Mac.
Very useful.
You can also get more information out of your game by putting the dash log.
At the end again space dash look like so and that will give you more information.
They go giving you the whole log of what you would expect from the log for bozoum Log warn that you
using inside C++ etc..
So I'm going to close this down because we don't need it.
They can see all of the verbose logging going on in the game.
One more thing to note is that you can see in a particular map if your project has multiple maps.
You can tell it which one you would like to load in the game.
Now the way you do this is using a particular type of you are real.
It always starts with Slash capital G game like so slash and then it is the path from your content directory
down.
So if I'm wanting to look at my third person map I know it's under Content.
Third Person C P P maps.
Third Person example map.
So how does that translate.
We've got game.
Now then it would be third.
Person.
C. P. P. Because that's what comes after content we don't include content.
And you got maps then you've got a third.
Person example map.
And you don't have to put the dot you map on the end.
It will automatically do that for you.
So it needs to be exactly like this.
You hit enter.
It's obviously going to do the same thing because it was also an example map but you've got the option
of putting in there an IP address instead of the map.
Can we close this down.
So you can put an IP address instead of the map and that's going to connect you to a server.
So I'm going to challenge you now to give something a go.
And that is to launch a dedicated server so to create your own mini network.
The first thing you need to do is find your IP address.
Now there's lots of instructions on the web for how you can find your local IP address.
I should stress if you're struggling with that at all then take a look at the resources for this lecture
where I have instructions for Windows and for Mac.
Then I would like you to launch a server you like hang on Sam I don't know how to launch a server.
Well let me give you a hint.
Try swapping out the dash game for instead dasch a server and see what pans.
Then I'd like you to launch some clients.
Now you say Sam I don't know how to launch some clients.
Well remember I just told you that you can put an IP address instead of a map and that will connect
you to the server running at that IP address.
Give that a shot.
And then I'd like you to ensure that they're all connected by making sure you can play together.
Let's give that a shot now.
Just as a hint for those of you on a Mac especially you may need to open up multiple terminal windows
in order to do this.
Okay welcome back.
So let's give it a go.
I'm going to launch up a server by replacing the dash game with the dash server.
Like so.
And what we should see is that something launches.
But there is no visual element to it.
That's the same as we had on our slides.
There's obsidian box with those screen.
Okay.
So that's the server launched and triggered.
Now I'm going to connect a client to do this.
I'm going to instead of my map I'm going to put in an IP address.
Now I know my IP address to be 1 9 2 1 6 8 dot one dot 90 this the local IP address they aren't going
to be able to hack me based on this.
And I need to replace server with Game.
Let's hit enter and see that connect up to the server in fact.
If you are very nerdy in what like reading through logs you can probably find a log in there somewhere
mentioning that it is connecting up to a server.
And.
Oh good joke.
They go.
We've got the server seems to have at the main player even though we don't have a way of controlling
that main player.
But that's okay.
We are running around.
And let me add in a second.
Clients just go over to my command prompt again and just launched that same command a second time.
Now when I get up a third instance of my puzzle platforms game and hopefully this will spawn into the
same world with the guy that we were just seeing.
Okay here I am.
And they go there are three people in this world and that one has moved.
So I'm assuming he's the dude and there we go we've got three people from our first players perspective
as well.
So fantastic apart from the fact that we've got this phantom server dude.
Everything else is hunky dory we've connected.
We've spawned a server.
We've connected clients to it.
Congratulations Pat yourselves on the back and let's dive onwards.
Now if you're having trouble connecting and getting black screens or just not ending up in the same
room as the other character then there is a couple of things you might want to try.
First of all if you're on a four point seventeen point two or greater.
Just try adding a question mark.
Listen to the end of the map on your server and that should help you out.
If you're still having problems then the issue might be that the server is listening on a different
port than the one that unreal defaults to.
So let's go ahead and start up a server and I'll show you how you can find out which port.
Unreal is starting on and how you can connect a client specifically to that port.
Now just quickly a port is a way of identifying where an application is it can choose to listen on a
specific port on one machine that means that you can have more than one application running on a machine
and accepting network traffic because the IP address only specifies the application only specifies the
computer and not the application.
So to find the IP address of your server you're going to do a control F or a command F and look for
listening.
And if I spell it correctly.
And listening will bring up a logline here which is saying log game.
NET driver I pinette Drive a blob a block.
The important bit it says listening on port 7 7 7 7.
Now that is the default.
So for me it would automatically connect to that but I want to show you that if you had a different
port number here how you could connect a client up to it.
Now one quick thing to say is that because I've just done a search in here is actually paused the server
to unblock the server.
On Windows at least you have to do a control.
See that one block the server on Mac.
You don't have that issue.
Now we can go ahead and attach a game and the way you attach a deck game is super easy is just the same
as before with the IP address and game but you add to the IP address a colon without a space and the
port number.
So in this case 7 7 7 7 and that will go ahead and make sure that the client is going to speak to the
server at the correct port.
So if you go ahead and launch up a game like that we should be fine and should be able to connect in
with the server.
Let's see if it will do that though go load loaded in.
And I have loaded in along with the server.
So that's a quick little fix.
If you're having issues connecting just make sure that you can find the IP address in the server.
Make sure you unblock the server and then just add the IP address to the.
Add the port to the IP address and I will see in the next lecture.