Welcome to another exciting lecture of one real multiplayer in this one.
I am going to show you how we can differentiate between server and client.
So here we've got a moving platform that we're going to code in this lecture and you can see that on
the left I have my server in on the server.
The platform is moving.
Whereas if I switch over to my client which is on the right and go and have a look at the same queue
you can see for a start it's not in the same position but it's also not moving.
And that's because we've written some conditional code that will only run on the server and doesn't
run on the client.
So in fact you get some weird glitching when you try and run through this queue because as far as the
server is concerned this dude can move freely through it but as far as the client is concerned you can't
move through it.
Got to be dealing with all those sorts of issues around replication in the next lecture.
But in this lecture we're going to be just looking at how we can make different behaviours on server
and client So let's dive right in and see how it's done.
So let's start adding the first real gameplay element the moving platform which is going to be the core
of our game.
I'm going to use a static mesh actor as the basis for this so that it can have some kind of position
some kind of thing in the world.
The static mesh.
So let's begin with that let's go and create a static mesh actor as the base class.
Now the idea of this platform by the way is it's going to be moving just between two points at a fixed
velocity.
So if it RIGHT starts a point A goes to point B it's going to then stop at point B and then go back
to Point A.
That's the kind of moving platform we've seen them in all sorts of games.
I don't have to explain it too much though.
Let's go to the content browser in your own real editor and new and then new seapass plus class at this
point you can be following along with me.
Now once you get that dialogue I would like to go to show all classes because the actors static mesh
is not a Under the normal classes shown without doing a show or classes.
So it's called static mash act.
So let the static mesh act then go to next.
I'm going to give it a name.
Mine's going to be called Burt.
No it's not it's going to be called moving platform.
A very obvious name.
And then we're going to go ahead and create the class and let it compile.
Now at this stage this should be the kind of stuff that you're familiar with and comfortable with.
So I'm going to give you a little mini challenge to go through and do this for yourself or you can follow
along with me if you're feeling pretty confident you can do it quickly because I'm going to zoom through.
So the thing that we're going to do is create a moving platform that just has basically a constant velocity
at the moment.
It's not going to go to Point A and B it's just going to go away from point A at constant velocity.
In for example the x direction.
So it's just going to move at five centimetres per second in the x direction just continuously going
to through walls it's going to not care about any kind of physics obstacles there's just going to move
super super simple.
Now I'd like you to remember just a couple of caveats here we've got the moving platform actor and I'd
like you to remember that moving objects need to have a mobile mobility that's one thing.
And also remember that by default not all actors tick.
So if you're having issues getting something going in the tick then that might be the reason for it.
Okay so you can play a video and have a go at it putting together your own static mesh actor.
Okay if you've done that or are just going through with me then let's go through.
So I am going to go over in two visual studio and advance the bar at the bottom because we're adding
mobility in C++.
So the first thing I want to do is enable ticking on this object so I'm going to use the public specifier.
For the constructor and in the construct we'll set up ticking.
So it's going to be a moving platform.
I like to copy and paste so copy and paste the moving platform definition and go into the C plus plus
file and would be a moving actor platform coelen code a moving actor platform no arguments to the constructor
and curly braces for the body.
Then we are going to set it to tick so that is primary actor tick dot B can ever tick equals true.
Basically yes we can tick.
Now if you don't remember that then you can look it up in the documentation.
It's a fairly standard thing to do with new actors.
Then we are going to create an override the ticking method.
In fact I think I'll leave that one as Verch as a public function.
Tell me about that tell me what your feelings are on whether tick should be virtual or public.
It's kind of an ambiguous one so it's going to be a virtual void of the return type of tick.
It's going to take a float which is a delta time.
And it is going to.
I'm just going to put override on the end as a kind of safety guard to make sure that indeed I'm overriding
and haven't missed belts and the tick and I'm not creating something new.
Now I'm actually copying this definition from off screen.
I don't expect you to remember it off by heart so do go and copy and paste it from unreel documentation
or from other engine code.
So take that Tich definition.
Everything after virtual before override paste it into the C++ file and then copy and paste the class
name just for name spacing Matt and remove the at sign that I accidentally typed there and then we're
going to implement the body with curly braces again.
Now I want to make sure now I know that in this case with a static mesh actor there is no supertech
but just for being in the habit I want to make sure I call the super method when overriding classes
and I'm going to pass it.
The argument that was passed to me which is the delta time and then we can actually getting to implementing
this thing.
So what we want to do is go ahead and get the actor locations sell-outs get actor location.
Which you can find in any good documentation for unreal like its own and that go ahead save that location
into a variable which is going to be of type f vector.
You can see that again in the documentation.
I'm not going to regurgitate all this stuff which is fairly basic knowledge then we're going to location
plus equals.
And it's I'm going to increment it by an F vector So I'm going to add an F vector to it which is only
in the x direction so let's have a look at the constructor is available here.
We've got three of them and I'm going to.
Got 11 of them actually.
I'm going for the one with three arguments which is the X Y Z floats and I'm going to pass in a distance
to move in X which is going to be my velocity of five centimetres per second centimetre remember.
Are the units in unreel at five cents per second multiplied by Delta.
Time will give me the distance to move because I've got a meters per second.
Multiplied by a unit which is in seconds which tells me how much to move in this frame and then I'm
going to put 0 for Y and Z.
So it's just moving in the x axis.
Now that I have taken a copy of location I have incremental that copy of location I want to set that
back to the actual location to update our location so that's going to be a set at a location.
Or I can type set at location location semco and that could be hit.
You might be tempted to think that's it but remember that this is not an immovable object.
It's by default all actors are going to be static objects.
So want to set them ability in the constructor.
Now if you not come across sensibility before don't worry it is basically if we take this moving platform
that I've got in I just created in my content browser and go to unreal content browser get a moon platform
drop it into the world and they go.
It's created a object in the world a moving platform and that moving platform hasn't got a static mesh.
So first of all let's go and add a cube as a static mesh so that we can see it better.
And there's my moving platform.
Fair enough.
And if you look at the details.
Pain.
You will notice that under the transform category we have a mobility property which is static.
Now if you try and you can try this now to move it without setting that mobility it's going to give
you an error in the output lock.
So let's go back in two moving platforms constructor and do a set mobility.
It can look in the documentation perhaps if you weren't sure what that method call was e component.
Mobility is the type.
It says it's taking it's a nun.
So Ian punnett mobility chalong Coleman moveable and then semco on to end that off.
So that's just going to make our component movable.
Let's go ahead and compile those changes.
Now if that was all moving a little bit faster for you you might want to go through and look at it again.
But definitely I recommend taking these challenges these many challenges when I suggest you take them
so that you can have had a look at the relevant documentation for things like settlor ability for set
actor location get out to location.
Before I go through it because this is slightly more advanced course we don't want to be getting stuck
in the details we want to be up at a higher level.
So says my campath has failed.
Let's go and have a look at what compile failure is I'm going to show the log because this is a little
bit easier to read.
Okay syntax errors I have mistyped clearly.
So let's go and see what that syntax error is.
Yes you probably saw it.
I did not see it while I was typing.
So it is just a square bracket.
For those of you just listening rather than watching my video ID my mistakes.
So you were probably screaming Sam it's not going to compile.
Well now it has indeed compiled.
So let's see if it actually works.
I'm going to go ahead and hit play and go up to my slow moving platform and see whether it is indeed
slow moving.
No it's not an escape.
And see what could the matter be now often what the matter can be is that the constructer doesn't get
called again when we just play quick edit.
It actually does get called again.
But the reason it's not getting updated is because changing the variable in the constructor won't change
the values that have already existed in the world and in the derived BPL these will stay there as you
will now get a little yellow arrow which you can check off which will allow you to go back the defaults
set in the constructor.
Thanks to Dan M for pointing that out.
So let's make sure that we can refresh this moving platform going to delete the moving platform.
Go back to the content browser and place it again.
Raise it a little bit off the ground and add in the static mesh and go ahead and hit play.
And now let's see whether that refresh has helped move.
Yes it has.
Look at it go.
It is rocketing away at 5 centimetres per second.
Mega slow So do tune your eye into it as you may not be able to see the cube moving at all on a first
pass.
But that is enough for us to test the next thing which is actually the purpose of this lecture which
is to understand where the code is running here in the client or whether it's running on the server
whether we are a server or a client.
So let's just back up there just a minute and change gears.
What I'm talking about is that when we have multiple players playing and we have these multiple windows
there is no dedicated server running one of the clients is the server for the other client.
And what I'm asking here is how can we tell whether we are the server client or just the client client
and what what should we do about that.
And in fact when we have a server whereas the code for that server and how is it different to the client
and when we write code is it on the server or is it on the client.
Well as the question I want to answer.
Basically the code that we write runs both on the server and the client in exactly the same way.
Exactly the same way.
The only difference being that there are some method calls that allow us to detect whether we are the
client or whether we are the server.
Namely that method call is has authority.
Let me just go over into visual studio and show you what I mean.
We've got a method called intech called has authority.
Has authority in fact not just intake it's anywhere on an actor and that has authority method.
As you can see is on a actor and returns boolean.
When it's the server remember that we said the server is authoritative It keeps is the one with the
true state that tells everybody else what the state should be.
So that's why it's called has authority.
Say you've got something to link it to and it returns it and so if it's true it's a server.
If it's false it's a client because you can either be assigned or you can be applied.
And that explains it okay.
Time for another small challenge this time.
To do with the actual meat of the lecture I'd like you to make it so that we are only moving on the
server and on the client that cube doesn't move at all so it should only be on the server.
That's the definition of the challenge.
Remember that you've got has authority that you can use to do that or any other method that you might
know of.
If you know a little bit about unreal multiplayer already then you can use any other method just to
achieve this.
And then I would like you to just abstract the speak because we've got hard coded five centimetres per
second.
What is that that's arbitrary.
Let's make that into a blueprint editable variable as well while we're at it.
So pause a video and have a go.
Okay welcome back.
Now if this isn't working for you do remember to first of all go and check with the code.
Check your code against the link attached to every lecture.
That's always very helpful if you have any issues with the coding challenges.
Now with a bit of testing you should be able to do this fairly easily.
So it has authority is obviously returning boolean.
So I'm going to just wrap our movement code inside and if statement so I'm going to say if it has authority.
And then.
Be curly brackets I'm going to put my curly brackets on a new line to be in line with an Real's coding
conventions.
And I'm going to nest my movement code under the has authority if statement and then remove lines 23
through 24 which was just for showing you.
Okay so this should now if we go ahead and build it.
Only run on the server.
Things crossed.
And while we're at this let's go ahead and abstract out this number five which I do not like one bit
of course for being a hard coded value so let's go ahead and do it you property.
That will give us the actual speed of the object.
And it's going to be an edit anywhere.
So that we can edit both in blue prints but also in the map.
And then I want to do a float speed equals five is a bit slow let's do 20.
That's correct.
The indentation that visual studio so incessantly wants to put into our header files and then I'm going
to replace the five with the speed that we just defined.
Let's go ahead and make sure that that's included in the compile as well.
Compellation complete.
Let's go ahead and hit play.
And I'm going to move up to this dude and see that he is moving so I reckon I am the server.
Let's go and have a look at the other dude which I reckon is the client and see whether he sees the
Q Moving or not.
No you see.
So this is the difference that we have going on here.
Now what's actually happening here is that the cube is not getting pushed from the server down to the
client because by default actually actors don't get updated.
Unreal.
Optimizers that way and you have to tell explicitly to do it so what's happening here is that cube is
saying well I'm on a server so I will move or I'm not on a server so I won't move and nothing else happens.
There are no kind of replication that state happens to the client.
So from the client's point of view that cube does not move because he doesn't get the code running that
says it should move.
Just get that into your head and if you really want to just cement a little bit more you can stick some
logging statements in there as well and you should be able to see what I'm talking about.
Or you can do some other things like getting it to move in the other direction.
If it's a client and that should help understand things but you can see that actors are indeed being
shown the same on both screens but that cube is not as he can see the cube totally disappeared from
ISO has probably gone through the wall at this point so that gives us some idea of whether code is running
on the server or not and in the next we can talk a little bit more about this tricky issue of why the
cube doesn't stay the same between the client and server whereas these two characters are in exactly
the same position.
We're going to deal with that in the next lecture.
So see you there.