Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be learning how to implement our own custom console commands so that when we open up
a console like this we can type in a command such as host and get a message back at the top.
We can even make it do stuff but we haven't made it do anything just yet.
And I can do console commands with arguments as well such as join and I can join for example that's
using while the previous commands that I've done I can join an IP address and it says that it's joining
that IP address.
Fantastic.
And also going to see how it can do other cool things.
As you will just see in a minute.
So let's dive in and see how these console commands work and how it can be implemented.
And you might even want to use them to implement cheats in your game.
Let's dive in.
So let's quickly overview once more what the console is so that we can understand how we are going to
be using it.
Go ahead and hit play in a stand alone in a new edita Window plane and then I am going to go and hit
the till the key or the one underneath the escape key in your different on different keyboards.
And here we've got at the bottom of our game the console show up before I hit Tilda twice.
Then it shows up with basically a few things like messages that can show up as well as previous command
history so I can use the if I had done some previous commands like these then you can see going with
the up and down arrow goes through the previous commands I've executed very much like any old terminal.
Okay so what we're going to do here is execute is create some of our own commands.
You can see that when we start typing as some auto complete commands some of them have got arguments
as well.
So we could do things they like change size and then and give it a float it seems so maybe twenty three.
What does that do that has done something really weird to my characters change the size of my character
by the looks of it.
I changed the size to one.
Let's see what's going to happen there.
He goes back to normal size.
I change the size to two.
He becomes double size.
So these are kind of the basis of being able to do cheat style commands.
This is very weird and his large and running around and generally that doesn't work very well but you
can see how you could use this to create cheats and it's going to be how without implementing user interface
we can actually have some interaction with a user interface type class.
So implementing these types of command is actually really easy.
All you got to do is go over in to your class and go.
I think we're going to do it in the try to do the game instance as a starting point.
You go to your head a file and all you have to do there is create a new function.
And what I'm going to use as an example is the you function for host.
Hosting a server.
And all you've got to do is put in the you function properties exec.
Like so we'll use it with a capital T although I don't think it matters.
And if you go ahead and create the implementation for host.
Go to your C++ file.
And do the relevant things.
Copy the class namespace and add curly braces instead of the semicolon as you are well aware of by now
then.
Well we can do that we can go ahead and build and we'll see how a console command appears called host
and will be able to auto complete that console command.
But this has worked because we've done it on the game in the science class.
What other classes are eligible for us to put X deck functions on.
So let's take a look at this list.
The first thing is player controllers.
So basically the idea is that these commands come in through a single player controller and it will
execute on the play a controller who is actually typing the command So that's one thing you want to
maybe change the size of a certain player.
Change the controls for one particular player and you can add a command on a player control and it'll
go straight to that relevant player controller and then obviously things are possessed by that player
controller.
It trickles down to them too so if you want to change the size of a pawn like we just did then when
you type that in it only affects the size of your own porn Hard's.
Again the ones attached to the relevant player controllers and then things like cheat managers.
So this is where we're starting to go into more global things where it trickles up into more global
stuff cheap managers if you know how to create them and what they are game modes game instances.
Again we're in the Global Domain now.
It's kind of trickled up from the play controller into more global stuff which is what we're going to
be using the hosting and for joining games.
We're going to be doing in the game instance as we've already seen.
Now we've created our own host.
And what I want to do is go ahead and log this out to the screen rather than to the console.
Previously we've been doing things for the console but that's not going to work.
If you're giving this to your friend and they want to see some feedback you're going to want to actually
log out onto the games screen itself.
Now to do this let's go and have a look for some possibilities which is go and google for search terms
like logging to the screen in unreel.
Then one of the results here is from the unreal Wicky and it's got lots of examples of how you can use
a Yule log.
But what I'm interested is towards the bottom.
Something called ADD ON SCREEN debug message and it's got some examples here of how you can use these
debug messages.
Now it's using something called the G engine.
Now this is a pointer to an engine object.
Let's go ahead and have a go.
If we see if we can get a hold of this ourselves so we're in the host method of our game instance and
I want to get hold of the G instance object.
But one thing about this if we go and have a look at its documentation or its.
Just yeah just go and look at its documentation was auto complete settings.
You will find that it says the G engine.
At the moment say muchy engine is UN identified.
That's a bit strange isn't it.
Okay.
Well one other way that we can do it is by doing a get engine instead.
Engine is a method on the game instance so it doesn't exist everywhere but it does exist on this game
instance and that gave us an engine object a new engine I believe.
So a new engine pointer and I'll store this in a.
Variable called engine well enough.
Now one thing about this is the engine can be null at times and we don't want to cause a crash when
that happens.
So I'm going to put my no return expansion for engine here to make sure that we've not got a null engine
and then we can use the arrow operator on said engine to see what is available.
You'll notice there's nothing available at the minute.
And that's because we need the relevant had a file so let's go ahead and look at the new engine documentation.
I've already got it in my history and we can go to the bottom of this file of this page and see that
the head of we need is engine for search engine dot H.
So let's go ahead and include that at the top of the file again leaving a bit of a space between our
includes and the includes from the engine.
Okay.
Now arrow should work.
Once auto complete has caught up but you can also go and look at the documentation which I just shared
with you and is in the results.
And here in engine what we can do is we should be able to find a add on screen debug message or can
just look for message or at on-screen debug message and then we can have a look at what is this built
up of what are the arguments to it.
Well for that I'm also going to look at the documentation for ad on-screen debug message which can be
found from the you engine docs page.
Let's go and search for add on screen debug message and was going to include this as a separate link
for you folks.
And you can see it's got some quite in-depth documentation here.
Basically what we're saying is that the first argument there if it's a minus one or a zero tells us
whether we want to overwrite the existing message or always add a new one.
The second argument gives us the amount of time the message as Dana screen third argument the colour
of said message.
And the fourth argument finally the text of said message.
So let's go ahead and give this a little shot who got an on screen message.
I'm going to make it replace the last message so it's going to be zero.
I'm going to keep it on screen for two seconds.
I'm going to give it a display colour of f colour.
Long calon.
And it's going to be colour green.
Because I want to say access we've hosted and then it takes an edge string which we can make with the
text macro like so and I can then call it just hosting like that and put semicolon at the end.
This time it's important they have SEMICON go ahead build and see if that has worked out whether we
can actually call the host command and whether we can indeed see the result of this on screen debug
message.
So build succeeded Let's go and see this in action.
I'm going to go ahead play.
I open up the console start typing host as you can see is auto completing to host there by just hit
tab to finish the all to completion.
Hit enter and you can see our log message comes up on screen in Green saying house doing fantastic.
It's worked out exactly according to my plan.
Now let's escape out of that game.
And next up we want to deal with arguments and we want to deal with joining in particular so we've got
a message for hosting.
Now we want a console message for joining as well.
Well that is going to be a your challenge to make a join the command.
Repeat the steps for host.
Needless to say it's going to be very similar and a dress argument and see how does this show on the
console.
How is that impacting on the command that you have to type into the console.
Then I would like you to print said address to the screen.
And as a hint to print to the screen you may want to make use of the F string code on code on print
F function.
Have a look at the documentation for that function.
Pause video and have a go.
Okay welcome back.
Let's dive in to creating this.
Join the command so over into my game instance dot H I am going to create a new function.
With exec behaviour.
So we called by the console and it is going to be a void return type no point returning anything when
it's a console.
And it's going to take an F string.
So it's going to be a concert f string reference just so we can avoid copying the string around when
it's unnecessary.
And this is going to be the address.
Put a semicolon after it and remove that horrible indentation that visual studio so insists on having.
And then let's go over to the C plus part to implement paste namespace it and replace it semicolon with
braces.
We've got cells a join come out now.
What's going to happen is we're going to try and print out this log message so I'm going to copy and
paste most of the code.
But the code for checking the engine and then doing the log message.
So this time I'm going to say joining.
And I want to be able to do is format in the address which is an F string so it would be percent.
As for formatting in an address whether you can't just do this in a text macro and you can't just do
this in the add on screen debug message because it wants an F string it doesn't it hasn't got any funny
macros to do anything in particular particularly clever.
So what you can do is as I hinted you can use f string colon colon print F and that allows you to do
the same string formatting that we would usually be doing in a U.S. log messages.
So it allows us to put some arguments after our text and format it so I can put in my address which
again has to be star addressed to get hold of the inner representation of the F string.
And then we can close off and make sure our lab brackets are matched up.
And that seems to be not giving me any red squiggly so I can go ahead and build and hopefully well that's
going to do is give us a joint command with some way to give the address we're gong to have to look
and see what that looks like and then it should print back joining with the address that we typed in.
Let's see if that is indeed going to work out.
Build as complete.
Let's go back on over into one real hit play.
Open up our console.
And then we're going to join and as you can see what it's giving us here is that we need to hit space
and it's telling us that we need to put in a dress and then it's going to be of type String.
This is perfect.
This is exactly what I wanted so I could put in something like 1 2 1 6 8 1..
70 or something like 79.
It turns out I go ahead and join and they go is printing back exactly what I want to join.
That was a little bit short in my opinion.
I think I could do with having that on the screen for 5 seconds but I'm not going to bother recompiling
because I'm sure you can imagine what adding 5 seconds to that add on screen debug message is going
to do perfect.
We've shown how to use exect phone functions and as a bonus we found out how to print things to the
screen from C++ pixels on the back and I'll see in the next lecture.
Oh you're going to make these functions do something more meaningful starting with our join.