So I'm pretty excited about this upcoming lecture because what we're going to do is we've already got
hosting implemented and you've had that in the last lecture.
So let me go ahead and host and get this get a guy standing over here on the cube.
And what are we going to implement in this letter as you might well guess is the ability to join So
this dude is standing around the lobby and he's been told by his friend that he's got a server.
So what he's going to do is he's going to go into the console and type and join and then the address
on the server.
Which is this address the usual one for me and he's going to go ahead and join and boom he is in the
same room and playing with his friend without having to ever have touched the command line or the terminal
or command prompt or power shell.
He's just download the binaries.
So this is one step closer to being able to share this with your friends.
I'm really excited about it and gets us involved in the whole circle of joining and hosting.
So let's dive in and see how it's done.
So now that we've got server hosting built right into our game we want to build in also the server joining.
Now one thing before we do that is that you'll notice when launching the game by default at the moment
it opens up into the third person level.
We would rather that it opened up into the lobby.
So that's something we didn't quite get round to doing.
Let's go to settings project settings and then within project settings we can search for the default
map.
We search for default map then you will find the there are two options the editor start up and the game
default.
Now I just want to change the game default because I like it booting up the editor into the third person
example map that's where we're doing most of the work but it's good to be in the lobby for the game
default because then be in the lobby which is the right place to be as why we set it up right.
So let's close down that project settings and move on with the first item too.
Understand the difference between client travel and server travel now when it was called so a trial
we may have guessed that there was maybe a client travel as well.
Well you weren't wrong.
Let's go and have a look at this so server travel as we've seen works at the world level you call it
on the world or you call it on the engine and it moves everybody with it.
It moves all the player controls over to the new world which are telling it about.
So what about client travel that operates on a player controller level.
And it tells the individual player controller that it should move.
So it does only one at a time like so.
And this can be used for connecting when you're currently connected as a player controls your own lobby
on your own machine.
You can use it to client travel from that lobby to a server to an actual IP address and it will connect
to the Internet connection.
Load up the map and place your player in the world does all that magic.
So let's go ahead and have a little look at the documentation for the client travel.
I have handily got a tab in the background here with the player controller client travel and as you
can see it's got just a handful of arguments.
It's got the u r l and it's got a travel type and then it's got a few other optional arguments like
seamless and match package good and things like that.
We don't need to bother with those two.
Those are optional but we do need to provide a trowel type in R U R L So the U R L is very simply just
going to be the IP address that we want to go to.
Very very simple.
And the travel type.
You'll notice an in and there's a couple of different options with this in some absolute partial relative.
We're going to want absolute because we want to specify the server.
We don't want to just move the map on the same server we want to actually change the server so absolutes
the best way to go there.
Okay so the reason I'm not telling you are not implementing all of this is because that's going to be
part of your challenge now as you can see it's a play control method so we're going to get hold of the
player controller in the game instance let me show you how it's go over into visual studio and go to
the game instance C++ file and the join method in there or function whichever you prefer as terminology.
And we're going to how to get hold of a player control in fact it's a play a controller indeed as the
name of the class is.
So play a controller.
Star is going to be a variable called Plek controller funnily enough.
And how are we going to get hold of it.
Well fortunately the game instance has a handy method called Get first.
Local.
Play a controller.
You can find that in the documentation for game instance so you can copy and paste it.
If you're on a Mac for example get first player controller okay.
That works okay.
And we need to check that now as always because there might not be a first player controller at some
point in the game.
Very rare but we'd like to know about that rather than having the editor crash so I'm just going to
put in a little bit of protection with my macro.
Is Gary Player controller.
So we ensure the player control is not null and if it is we return say that we're safe to continue in
this method.
Doing stuff with play controller.
Okay so with that said let's go ahead and use the play controller.
Well that is going to be your job to find how to use client travel there.
And that is indeed the next step to implement client track.
So as a whole you are going to be implementing join in this challenge you're going to be implementing
travelling client travelling specifically using that player controller we've got hold of a test hosting
with joining.
So are you going to be joining and hosting at the same time.
So are you going to be able to use the command line for both hosting and joining now.
That's the idea.
That's what you're implementing after all.
Going to have to do this in a standalone game because obviously won't be able to get two instances of
the editor running well you can do.
But no need really.
And when you got it done I wanted to celebrate get out your chair jump around again.
Yes.
And Pat yourselves on the back.
Okay that's an optional step if you're really introvert and I wanna do that.
But I do recommend stretching your legs and celebrating a little bit that we've got to.
Awesome milestone of being able to host and join a server in the game was video and have a go at this
challenge.
Okay hopefully you're all full of energy from having celebrated this challenge.
Let's go ahead and give it a shot.
So play a controller.
We're going to open up with an arrow to do a client travel.
And then what we're going to pass in more address is it gonna be why it's going to be the attract Funnily
enough that came in there's an argument and string here just perfect.
Let's go ahead and pass that in and then we can use the E travel type enaam.
Coal on coal on.
And it's going to be travel absolute.
I said would be the best option.
And that's the end of the method so let's go ahead and build and give this a shot.
I'm going to go and open up how a shell so I can use the commands that were used previously.
As I said you can use command prompt or terminal on the Mac.
So having waited for the builder to complete which he just has I can go ahead and launch the game.
Now I notice I'm not passing in a map now because the default map will be the lobby just using the game
argument so it doesn't launch the editor and I'm adding a log in case anything goes wrong and I'm going
to spawn up two of these one of them is going to be for hosting on and the other one is going to be
for joining with my games are launching up.
Now I'm getting one black screen and hopefully there'll be another one in the background.
So let's have a look.
Yes we've got two and then I'm going to open up the console on this first one and I'm going to host
from here.
Okey dokey.
So it seems to have worked all right.
I seem to be the host.
I'm going to stand on this cube.
And if we see a character standing on his cue then we know we have Joe and joined into the correct world.
So go over to my other puzzle platforms game.
I'm in my lobby at the moment I go and open up the console and I'm going to join.
The IP address.
That's just.
Then scroll back.
But I don't think I can scroll back because I haven't joined yet 1 9 2 1 6 8 1.
Ninety one I go join and boom.
We are in the correct place because that dude is standing on the cube the whole server host is there
standing on the cube.
Fantastic.
Big time to celebrate.
Stand up.
Celebrate because we are joining and hosting from all within the game.
This means that you're one step closer to being able to give this to maybe slightly more technical laymen
who don't mind typing and commands.
But still they don't have to open up a command prompt or terminal they can just use your game and your
binary So we're going to find out in the next lecture how we can create that binary and distribute it
over services like HBO to play with your friends.
Fun stuff.
See you in that lecture.