Welcome in this lecture.
We are going to make our menus clickable doesn't seem like a big job but trust me when we're doing it
in C++ it's not always straightforward.
The documentation is a little bit tricky to navigate.
So I'm going to be showing you mainly in this lecture how to navigate the documentation to achieve the
goal of being able to click on things and also to be able to see the cursor.
Let's dive in and see how that's done.
Okay so we've reached the stage of adding it to the viewport.
But currently our main menu is unusable.
The reason for this is twofold.
One we can't see our cursor.
And second we can't click on anything so the input is going into the game behind our menu or the level
behind our menu rather than the actual main menu that hasn't been focussed it hasn't been given what
we what it needs and to do that we are going to have to change something about the play a controller
because the control of the play controller is currently going in to the game and we want it to go into
the menu instead.
Now the way you do this is using a.
Method called Set input mode.
Now for this bit of video I would like you to put your hands on your laps and just watch what Im doing
rather than doing anything for yourself.
Because the challenge is going to be to recreate this without looking at what Im doing because I want
to see how well you can do these things for yourself.
Just using the documentation and just discovering.
So this is the entry point you can use the resources that I've included they are going to be helpful.
But Id like you to try and do the challenge that comes later on without looking at my code at least
at first and then see where you get to.
Okay.
So with your hands on your lapps Lets get stuck in.
So the first thing is we want to set input mode on a player controller.
Okay.
So the question here is going to be how do I get hold of a player controller to set its input mode in
the first place.
We go over to Visual Studio then we should see that weve got hold of a player controller before when
we were trying to do client travel so this should be fairly straightforward.
Just going to get the first play control like we did down here.
We're also going to do the same nul return check thing you Bob.
So then we're going to load after we've loaded the menu at the viewport.
We're going to get hold of a play a controller.
Okay that's all straightforward.
Now we want to go ahead and do the next step which is to set the input mode so we need to think about
what the arguments to set input mode are.
Okay we've got an F input mode data base that's a bit weird it's not a database it's a data base because
it's the base class that's what it's saying here not a database or anything like that.
So if we click on that it's going to give us the documentation for this f input mode data base and you
can see that by itself it's not particularly useful but it's subclasses.
Ah that's why it's a base because it has some subclasses and their names kind of suggest what they do
want input mode game and why.
Game in F input mode game only and F input mode UI only.
Okay so clearly what we want to be doing is having the input mode for you why only so that we don't
have part of the input going to the going on par going to the UI we want it all focussed entirely on
to the you guys.
So we've got to go ahead and create one of these struts.
We know that creating structures is pretty much as simple as just creating one and then setting its
variables.
So let's go in to C++ that might be a reminder for some you if you didn't know that.
Don't worry I just told you so we can copy the f input mode.
You my only head on over to the C++ and paste that in and I'm going to call this the input mode data
semicolon so that's created it already.
That's called the struct constructor and we've initialized some input mode data.
Here locally it's not a pointer so it's here on the stack.
If you know what that means we're going to do input mode data.
DOT.
Because not a pointer.
And then we want to set those properties that are there in the variable.
We want to look at those variables and see are any of these useful Do we want to stick with the default
behaviour.
Or do we want to go with something else.
So we've got widget to focus.
That's an interesting one to start off with a widget to focus.
We know which widget we'd like to focus now it's not auto completing.
And if I hover over it it's going to tell me that the identifier is not defined.
That's because I've called it data not data.
So were going to do a dot widget set widget to focus.
And then we need to pass in an s widget.
Now that's a bit problematic because what we've got is you use a widget.
So hopefully the next thing you'll be thinking about is looking in the user widget manual and seeing
whether there is anything that can help you convert or return an S widget.
So let's just have a look through here for s widget.
We've got a get widget handle that's not quite what we want on the widget rebuild.
We don't want that e there so one thing to remember here is that it's only showing the functions that
were declared in this class not necessarily the ones in the super class.
So let's go one level up to a new widget because that might have something relevant as well.
Let's go and search again for the s widget.
K.
Got a few more things here.
And if you go looking through them we've got my widget.
The underlying s widget that might well be the thing that we're looking for.
It's a variable.
Let's see if there's any functions in stead that might return the same thing.
Okay granted this one's a little bit tricky to find so I'm going to include the link in the lecture
resources for you to use during the challenge.
The thing that you want is a take widget because it as the documentation says gets the underlying slate
widget or constructs it.
If it doesn't exist.
So let's go back over to Visual Studio.
That one was a little bit of a tricky one to find.
So we'll do menu arrow take widget.
And that's a function.
So that's going to set its widget.
Anything else that we want to set on the input data let's go and have another little look at the input
mode data.
At this point we are configuring the input mode as we have already seen so the other thing here is the
mounce lock mode.
So let's see if we can set the mouse lock mode down here so input mode.
Data dot.
And here we've got a set mouse to viewport behaviour set lock mouse to viewport behaviour.
Got a couple of options here.
Let's take a look at the docs to see which one we would prefer to use two functions here.
Set mouse to viewport and set mouse to viewport behaviour so the mouse to view poor behaviour takes
in a lock mode in.
Let's take a little look at what that E name does.
Do not lock a lock on capture and lock always.
I think we're going to do a do not lock when we're in the menu we can move our mouse outside of the
menu.
So I'm going to use that version who are going to set mouse to view poor behaviour.
It's going to be the e mouse lock mode colon colon do not lock.
So we can't finish that off.
So now that we've constructed an input mode data we can indeed call our set implode so it's going to
be player controller.
Arrow.
Set.
Now I wonder why it's complaining here.
Because I've misspelt player control a set input mode.
Isn't working out.
Why is it not auto completing for me.
I can go and copy set input mode from the documentation so if that helps.
So input mode and then we can give it the input mode data which we have been constructing.
MIKE So semicolon to finish that off.
And one more thing that we're going to need to do is make the cursor visible.
This is a very straightforward one indeed.
If you go and have a look at the play a controller documentation we can search for curser in here and
you'll see that we've got a property called B show curse.
Show mouse cursor.
We obviously want to set that one to true.
So it's going to be player controller.
Arrow B.
Show mouse cursor equals true.
Okay.
So that is the things that you need to remember and don't worry.
The challenge is going to prompt you.
Obviously you can use all of the resources to help you out in the challenge.
Well done for keeping your hands on your lap if you managed to resist the temptation to follow along.
Let's build and see that in action.
So that build is completed Let's go and try playing from our main menu level I'm opening up the main
menu level which is under content.
Many system I'm going to hit play.
And now you can see I've got my cursor it's not locked in to the screen I can move it out but I can
click on buttons and I can hover over them and I can see my cursor.
So that's fantastic that's done an input mode allowing us to click on things and it's also done our
cursor because we can see it and it's not locked in to the window.
Fantastics.
Now it's time for you to have a go.
To repeat these steps for yourself.
Now that might sound like a daunting task.
But let me just prompt you with that or make it a lot easier.
You're going to be rediscovering the API.
I think this is going to make it really settle in your minds much better than if you just copied me.
And it's quite a complicated API but also very useful.
So you were going to be setting the input mode.
That's number one thing that you are going to be doing and you're going to be using obviously all the
resources I've given you to help you do that.
You got to make the mouse cursor visible.
That one's fairly straightforward but you've got the resources there as well to help you remember what
the calls are user documentation to help you.
Again all the links against this lecture that can help you out and try not to peek at my code.
Try and do it entirely from the documentation and the fact that you are trying to set the input mode
and move it make the mouse cursor visible.
So it's directed towards those goals.
Use the documentation to aid.
Okay.
Pause a video and have a go.
Welcome back.
So hopefully you got on all right without Let me know in the Q and A how you found that challenge I'd
be really interested to know whether you got through the documentation without peeking or whether you
did have to peak in the end.
Obviously I'm not going to go through it again.
You've already seen how to do this.
And if you need to you can re watch the video.
Remember that you can always look at the code on gitte Hub now after having attempted the challenge
and see whether there was anything that I did differently.
Maybe you did it better.
Dont necessarily throw away your solution because it wasnt the same as mine.
If it works if it achieves the same thing then just evaluate the pros and cons and maybe yours is better
and if its better.
Share it with us on the community website and I will see you in the next video.