Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be making this awesome looking menu by customizing fonts by customizing the buttons
as you can see down here and adding in a background and making sure that while we do all of this it's
carries on scaling nicely as you can see here.
Great stuff.
Let's dive in and see how we can achieve this.
So at the moment we've got a menu and it's nicely laid out but a bit boring at the moment.
So what kind of things can we do to make this look less generic and more interesting.
Three things I can think of.
The first one is giving it a nice background.
Second one is changing out these buttons for something a little less generic.
And the third one is to change the font and the font can make a very big difference as well.
So let's start off with Point number one.
Set a background to this whole thing so that we can get a theme rolling.
Well the first thing I would suggest you go and do is head on over to Google and go to it an image search.
And search for the theme that you're looking for.
So for me I'm looking for a sci fi wallpaper often wallpaper is a good kind of thing that we're looking
for are some really nice ones here but they're not all free they're all and some of them are copyrighted
so I'm not going to go looking for the copyrighted ones.
Let's go to Tools just underneath the Google search and go to the usage rights and look for labelled
for reuse how nogami modifying it so let's just look for labelled for reuse and have a little scan through
here for some.
Good photos that we could use as a background.
Like look at this one here with the meta yours things hitting the Earth.
So it looks quite cataclysmic.
It's got a signature down the bottom.
Let's see if that matters too much.
Probably best not go with one that has got a signature on the bottom.
Let's have another look at maybe this one at the top with flicker one.
Let's go ahead and visit the page and see if we can download an original quality.
We've got a download button on Flicker and I'm going to go download the original Now you obviously find
the image that you like the look of maybe you're not going to go for a sci fi the IM at all.
That's just the theme that I'm deciding to go with.
You can choose whatever you like.
Okay so here we go.
We've got Jay Pegg ongoing import into unreel and the boss.
Let's go to our content browser and create a new folder for images.
I'm going to have a few images in a UI so let's include them at least in one place and I'm going to
drag from flicker to that image folder.
It's going to import the image for me.
Okay so I've got my image now imported.
I want to set it as a background to this whole box thing.
So to create a background for this I think what I'm going to do is wrap that whole vertical box with
a.
Overlay.
So if we go over and over wrap it all with an overlay right click on the buckle box and wrap with an
overlay.
Then what we're going to get is the following the vertical box is too small.
So let's click the vertical box and set it horizontal and vertical alignments to be the full width of
the page.
Get an image and put that as a sibling of the vertical box and just above the vertical box so that it
goes behind it in terms of the z order.
And similarly with the image selected let's do the horizontal and vertical fill.
Obviously white is not what we're going for.
So let's go to appearance and brush image and change that out for the texture that we wanted.
Okay.
So we've got at texture it's maybe a little bit bright so if we want to dull it down a bit then selecting
the image we can go to the tint and change the tint slightly to be just a little bit darker.
So we got a darker background.
Great start there.
So that has been scaling the box for backgrounds.
Let's have a look at how we can do more interesting buttons.
Let's click on our buttons and see what properties they have in the first place.
If we go to appearance that we've got the colour in a pastie in background colour and things like that.
But another thing is the style.
Now if you really want it changed how the button looks You gonna need to change the style because we've
got the style for the normal hovered and pressed buttons.
You click on the normal.
Then it gives you an option to include an image.
Let's see how this image works if we have a look at the documentation which is linked in your lecture
on styling.
You'll see that there is a section here called setting image States and there is a complicated graphic
here that for me was a little bit hard to follow.
So let's do the following.
I'm going to right click the box and save that image.
So this first image on the left say that into my downloads and I'm going to import that image in two
on.
So let's go to the content browser to the images folder and drag over to there.
Actually import and let's replace the image of the button.
With that box.
Example.
So little bit confusing at the moment.
Let's rescale it by selecting the text in our button right clicking wrap with and wrap with a size box
so that we can control the size that I'm going to select the size box go to the details pane and check
next to width and height.
And so I can set a width and height for this box like so I can drag it out to create a different width
and height.
Now what's going on here with this image.
Well what you'll notice is that as I'm scaling less the corners of the image are not being scaled.
So these bits with the Green Cross are not being scaled.
However if I change the height then the two sides on the left and right are being scaled just in the
height.
But the side on the top and bottom is not being scaled.
With the width it's the other way round.
So the top and bottom has been scaled But the Left and Right are not.
And whenever I'm scaling any of these.
The centre section is always being scaled so this is what's known as a nine slice image named after
the fact that it is an image sliced up into nine pieces and it's very common for creating things where
you want to have border detail such as a button.
This is because it keeps the scaling around the edges constant and you don't end up with weirdly scaled
things.
So it's great for doing borders of boxes and so on like that.
And so if we have a look at the documentation again then you'll see near the bottom there is an example
of these kinds of buttons you can see that they have borders round the edges which are a bit complicated
and you wouldn't want to scale the whole thing up without doing this kind of nine slice.
But then there's a way of naturally scaling but it's okay.
So another thing that we can have a look at is with buttons.
They have different types of display mode.
Let's select the button again and go and have a look at the style normal and draw as properties as time.
You can see that currently it's draw a box that's doing this nine slice behaviour.
If we saw a border it's going to cut out the middle of our box and instead just show those edges.
Now it's not quite working just right because our margins aren't set up exactly right just underneath
doran's there's a margin property and you can go and fiddle with those margins to make sure that it's
cutting out the right bit of the image.
Mike so.
And then what you've got is essentially just the border done via Well essentially what's now an 8 slice
image rather than a 9 slice image.
And you can also choose the draw as option of image.
Now what this does is very very simple.
It just scales everything so you can see all those bits in the nine slice image all getting scaled equally.
So that is how we can do three different ways of doing buttons or customizing buttons within an unreal
button.
How about fonts.
Where would you go to go and get some fonts.
Well I'm recommending Google fonts which is phuntsok google dot com and here they have got a great comprehensive
list of all sorts of different fonts which you can use completely for free.
They're designed to be used on websites so it's free to download free to distribute to other people.
If you go and hit the little surge icon in the top right there are some filters for these fonts because
there are a lot of fonts it's hard to find the ones that you're looking for.
And the font the filters work as following.
Let's have a look at mostly at the category that's the most important thing for me.
Serif means that it has these little spiky bits on the end of the letters and that's as if it had been
carved out of rock Times New Roman is the classic example of a serif font.
The Sans serif font is the one without the spiky bits and sans being French for without.
We've then got handwriting fonts handwriting fonts are as they say on the tin.
Meant to look like handwriting.
Monospaced fonts are fixed width fonts also known as fixed width.
It's typically used in terminals and programming editors because it makes it really easy to see the
formatting and because of that constant width and some of them are really pretty cool.
And then finally we've got our display category which is the kind of font that you might use for headings
on a website.
Just the interesting looking fonts that you wouldn't want to be reading a huge long paragraph because
they're quite hard to read but they are very cool looking and can lead to a very interesting effect.
Now what you can do is select the fonts that you like the look of white as you scrolling through I like
the look of this audio wide ones I can click it and it has this font family selected.
I've gone.
I recently changed page didn't mean to.
I can just click on the font family selected and there is a download.
This selection here which allows you to download a zip with the font in it that will be able to import
very easily into unreel So it's time to challenge you to make your menu look pretty.
How are you going to do that.
Well that depends on you entirely.
Add a background just like I did and one thing that we might want to have a look at.
Actually with that background I dont think its fully complete yet because if I go ahead and hit play
with my background as it currently stands and try and scale it.
Then you will notice that it is being stretched in a bizarre way which is not very nice.
So let's complete that background just a second.
Now the way that we can prevent it from scaling in such a fashion is to use a container called a scale
box.
So if I right click on my image and go to wrap with and select scale box then you'll notice it has done
something clever already.
Select the image and make sure that it's at the correct image size.
It does look like it as go to the scale box and have a look at its properties.
It has a stretching property here and there's a couple of options for the stretching property.
You can scale to fit x you can scale to fit Y or you can scale to fill.
So scaling to fail is probably what I want to be doing.
And if you go ahead and scale it what you'll notice is that it automatically scaling in both x and y
to keep the aspect ratio but without.
Without letting anything creep in from the edges so always make sure there's plenty to see on the screen
but it will cut off bits of the crop off bits of the image just to make sure that the scaling and the
aspect ratio is all the same and that the image is centred in that.
In fact you can probably change that whether the image is Senator or not.
By clicking on the image and changing its alignment within this slot I think that does work indeed it
seems to go ahead and align it to the left.
Then when I scale it does indeed.
Just a line to the left.
I liked it scaling with the centre so I'm going to keep it that way.
Like so now you understand how to use scale boxes to make sure that backgrounds work better like that.
We can go on and continue with the challenge definition.
So add a background of your choice.
Do whatever you like and make those scaling work however you like it.
Customize the buttons and choose a custom font.
Now with the custom buttons I have included a pack.
If you can't find anything yourself it's attached to the lecture.
So because the challenge is actually quite long we're going to be completing it in the next lecture.
Now don't worry it's just long because there's lots of pointing and clicking.
Not because it's very complicated.
So I'll see you in the next lecture when you've attempted the challenge.