Welcome.
In this video we're going to be polishing off the last bit of you.
That doesn't work which is our join button on the second joins green.
So now that we've got our join game submenu pop up.
And we want to be able to type in an IP address and we want to then hit the join button and be able
to go to that IP address.
And sure enough as I have just done I have gone and joined in a game that was hosting on my own machine
and I'm able to play with the dude over here.
Fantastic.
So that's pretty much the I entirely sorted at the end of this lecture.
So let's dive in and see how it's achieved.
So our menu is starting to take shape.
We are able to host we're able to join and go to a different menu go back from that menu type in our
IP address hit the Joined by and but nothing happens.
So we're going to have to fix that join button pretty damn soon.
But before we do that I just want to fix one annoyance one pet peeve that I have which is that if I
play the game from the filesystems if I go to my you project right click on my you project and then
go to launch game and then we'll see that the game actually ends up launching doesn't start off with
the main menu which is kind of silly really because that's the whole point.
That's the whole reason that we've been having our our game set up this way.
And at the moment it's still showing up in the lobby which is not ideal although it does still have
the old functionality so it does still work.
So now that we have pretty much surpassed that with the functionality of our menu or we will have done
by the end of this lecture I would just might go ahead and set up the correct.
Start up level as a starting point so let's go ahead and do that.
We remember how to do it in the settings and it's in project settings.
And then we go and look for the start up.
Map and so on eds start-up map let's have a look instead for default.
Default mode then we got default maps.
And sure enough under here we've got a game default map which I'm going to go ahead and swap over to
our main menu and while we're at it.
I'm going to change the the edita default start-up map to Main Menu as well because in this particular
project we're all about that main menu and that's what we really want to be seeing and testing out.
So up next we want to make that join submenu actually do something to make that happen.
We need to get the IP address from the text field when we hit the join button how we're going to do
that.
I hear you ask.
Well it's very much the same as we've been doing everything else.
We are going to bind the text field into our C++.
So let's go and have a look first in our widget blueprint and take a look at the text editable text
box that we've got here.
Sure enough there we go.
We've got an editor will text box somewhere and I want to hover over this to see what the class is for
our edits look editable box.
So I will hover over this.
It's not telling me anything so I'm assuming that it's an edible text box is actually the name of the
component so we can go and check this out in our C++.
Let's hop head on over into visual studio.
And go to our menu and Dot H.
And she know we're going to be doing this in the C++ at the top of the C++ like we did last time with
our widgets which we want to include the editable text box.
So let's try them out.
Hash include quote components.
And then editable text box sure enough editable text box is right there.
Fantastic.
That's exactly what we're looking for.
That means that you a text box is going to be the component type so we can go into our head a file and
you could be following along very quickly with this at this point because we've done this many times
before.
So I am going to call this the IP address.
It's going to be a new property.
It's just copy and paste this.
I'm not copying and pasting because I've got something in the clipboard.
I'm going to paste that there so I'm going to copy the any bind with it really anything will do.
It's got all the same structure to it.
So we take our editorial text box that I copied and try not to scroll in and out too much.
Let's go back to a normal level and let's paste in.
And the type that the editable text box is going to be you editable text box and the name of the property
isn't.
We join menu but rather the IP address.
Address field.
We can take this IP address field name and go over into our editor.
And rename that editable text box component to whole widget to the IP address field so we'd then have
a way of it being found by the C++.
Let's make sure all of that works.
Let's go ahead and build that compile is successful.
So something has certainly been done correctly.
Let's go ahead and have a look at what we're going to do with this editable text box field that we just
created.
If we go to initialise then at least here we can use it to have a look at our auto complete.
In fact I shouldn't do the auto complete trick because that's not fair on the people on Mac.
Who for whom auto complete isn't necessarily as straightforward So let's have a look at the documentation
which is just as good.
Here are the edible text box documentation's which are in again the links of your lecture.
Let's have a look at what could be going on here let's just do a little scan of the variables.
Do a little scan of the functions and see what we get.
So we've got a set text that might be handy.
Got set.
Hint text.
We have got set text and we've got get text as well as having some properties along here.
Some variables that is one called text one called text.
DELEGATE.
Not entirely sure what the text delegate would do but we could always find out if we wanted to.
A set where there is a password or is read only and other such cool niceties.
So that's going to be quite useful for.
So it's your challenge time to call the join function we are going to be making that join dialogue functional
the way we're going to do this is to hook up that join button to actually do something.
Going to tweak the interface as appropriate and call the join function and test it thoroughly so pause
the video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
Let's dive right into this.
So first things first I am going to go over to visual studio.
And.
I am going to bind that second join button the join button that is on the join screen itself.
So you see we've got a joint but we've got a cancelled join menu button.
And I am going to do a join join menu button so let's try that one out.
It's going to be a little bit of a weird name so let's actually think of maybe a better name.
Maybe something like that confirmed join menu button something like that.
I think cancelling confirm makes more sense than join join menus.
They might just think I made a typo.
And that would just be silly wouldn't they.
So Will do and confirmed join many button.
I'm going to take that and copy it in to the editor.
And I am going to go to the actually find the join button itself which is currently called button underscored
to helpfully named after and I'll change that to the Confirm join menu button.
We can go ahead and hit build on our visual studio project file.
Like so.
And in the meantime let's think about what we're going to do with our confirm.
Join menu button Well for starters we're going to want to call a function.
And I think I'm going to create a function next to the host server called join server and I can just
go ahead and copy this as a starting point and we'll call it join server and join server is what we're
going to connect our confirm and join menu button up too.
So I'm going to do that over in the C++ and copy basically cancel cancel join many button.
And use that as the starting point.
Also going to copy be confirmed join menu button name identifier and replace it in that copied code
that has been fed a quick set up.
Next up I'm going to copy the join server declaration into C++ just after our host server deck definition
in the C++ is where I'm going to implement it.
Implement the body remove semicolon.
Do the namespace.
Okay so that's the join server done.
We just now need to hook it up in the binding and dynamic.
So I will copy the name in fact the whole namespace name or copy that.
Including all the semicolons.
And I will paste that in to add dynamic.
Basically I always copy and paste things I don't use very much memory.
Maybe that's because my memory's not particularly good.
I just learn to copy and paste things really quickly and I find that really helpful.
So the next thing to do is we've got join server and we want to call our menu interface with a join
call but we don't have a join call yet.
So let's go ahead and open up our menu interface.
Dot H.
Remember this the only the DOS H that we actually care about.
That's where we want to implement our join.
But what's the signatories going to be.
Well to find that out we can go to our game instance and see what the signature of join currently is.
Go to our puzzle platform game instance dot H and find the join function which is on line 30 for me
and it takes an F string konst reference.
So I'm going to take that over to my menu and face.
And I am going to paste it in them.
It's going to be virtual because like host we want it to be implemented by subclasses in this case the
game instance and we want it to be a pure virtual which means we need to put an equal zero at the end.
To make sure that it has no implementation and the compiler will be fine with the fact that it has no
implementation now because we've chosen exactly the same signature I don't have to worry about implementing
it in the game instance.
We know that it's already implemented there.
So I'm going to go over into my menu not see P P and do a null check for the menu interface so it's
going to be an if menu interface.
Not equal now.
No pointer.
And then we can do the body of our IF which is going to be menu interface.
Arrow and then we are going to call and join.
Except we need to pasek in F string so how are we going to get hold of that f string.
Let's create a string variable here.
Which is going to be the address.
And what are we going to.
Well and let's pass that into it.
Join as well.
So what are we going to set that address from.
Well you may have guessed it is coming from the field.
So let's figure out how we get hold of that let's go and have a look at our documentation again.
There is a function that I thought was pretty promising when I looked through it the first time which
was get text which returns an F text object.
Let's have a look at the F text documentation as well.
And sure enough.
There's somewhere in here let's have a look for just search for f string.
Somewhere I think there will be a conversion to an F string.
Build source string.
Doesn't sound like it.
From string there's a from string I think there'll be a two string somewhere.
There may just be a two string so let's have a look for that.
Yep sure enough there is a two string.
It just wasn't showing up in the search because there's these ellipses or dot dot dot after an F string.
So that is all okay so we can do a two string on the straight.
The text we get back.
So it's going to be what's the name of our property.
Again I'll go to the main many dates to refresh my poor memory and it is called IP address field.
Go back into the C++ IP address field.
It's going to be an arrow.
Then it is going to be get text.
And then we are going to do on the text.
I believe it's an F text so it will just be a dot.
And then it be.
Let's see we said it was a two string.
Sure enough it is.
And that's a return a string for us to put into the string.
Now if we want to be careful about memory usage then we can make this a contest f string reference and
if you're not comfortable with why that is you don't have to use it like that either.
Okay so we've just returned.
A constant string reference from our IP address.
Get a text field and we're passing it in to join.
Fantastic.
So this is all great.
I'm just a little bit paranoid about our IP address field being null So I'm just going to do a little
check.
For the IP address field.
There we go.
So now it will return if our IP address field is not good.
So let's go ahead and build that and see whether Now when we hit a join button we're calling the right
thing.
I'm also going to check against the challenge definition that I've done everything that I said I would
do.
Hook up the join button tweak the interface.
Yeah we've tweaked the interface we call the join function and we then have our testing it.
That's the last step on the process.
Okay.
Successful build.
So that's step one done at least we've got a successful build.
Hardest part sometimes is to get the bill to succeed.
And I'm being lucky in these videos because I'm not showing you too many of the build failures so that
must be either me improving or just preparing well.
So let's go ahead and try and join when you go to and type in an IP address.
And join.
And you can see is definitely calling the write function.
Because we've got our little green join now there isn't a server running.
So this is actually going to do anything.
So let's close this down and go ahead and launch a server from our puzzle platforms folder and right
click on the project.
Launch game.
And I'm going to do that twice so that we have two games.
Here I am in game number one in this game.
I'm going to host.
And then I'm going to go over into my game number two.
And I'm going to join from there.
And my IP address is 1 9 2 1 6 8 dot 1 ninety I believe.
Let's go and join.
There I am I am ingame.
It's not quite working.
I've got.
But shot at the moment.
But if I go in to the host game that does have control.
Then we definitely can see that there is another player there.
This is a good start.
So let's go ahead and go to our menu and figure out what's going on.
Okay so you may guess it.
You may think that okay we've gone and joined and we got exactly the same problem as host.
So hopefully you have drawn your conclusions and you have pointed the finger of blame at the game in
since.
Which is not removing the menu when it is moving onto a new level.
So to do that we will go to our game instance dot s.p..
We will find that culprit to join function.
Another beginning of it.
If we have a menu we are going to tear down said menu.
So just the same as we do in our host We're going to do in our join.
Go ahead and build that and see if we can test it.
Okay.
The build has succeeded at least so let's go over to the puzzle platform folder and in there we're going
to launch up a couple more games again to try this a second time launch game right click the launch
game and then we will be able to host a game and hopefully join the game this time.
So Game 1 and 2 have loaded I'm going to host from this particular game and I'm going to go and stand
on the cube just to say hi to the user that's going to be joining in very soon.
And let's go over in to our other instance of the game.
Hit the join button.
Take us to another menu we go to one line to add up 1 6 8 again.
1.
90.
And we hit join hasar.
We are in the right level we have control.
We can jump around on the same block as our other dude.
And the other dude is now here and he can control as well.
And we're all happy.
Everything is working fantastically all from the menu.
So a few more polishing tweaks to be done but mostly that's it that's mostly the menu completely polished
off.
So Pat yourselves on the back and I'll see you for the next couple of videos.
Well just be rounding this whole thing off.