Welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be creating an in game menu in fact you're going to be creating an engagement.
Let's see what it looks like.
That's what it looks like.
And you are going to be responsible entirely for creating this because you have all the tools you need
already in your noggin.
So I'm going to be challenging you to do this.
So the whole purpose of this lecture isn't going to focus around our main menu but rather our game and
we're going to be looking at how we can create a menu in the game itself.
Perhaps when we hit the escape key that rather than taking us just out of the game entirely will allow
us to go back to the main menu for example of running in a standalone game and allow us to quit the
game rather than having to hit alter for which not one might know about.
So how we're going to do that.
Well actually in this lecture it's going to be all in the form of one massive challenge.
You're actually entirely capable of achieving this for yourself with all the knowledge from the previous.
17 odd lectures.
So I would like you to go ahead and apply that knowledge and actually see if you can do it.
So let's see.
We are going to create an in game menu.
The components of this to create a separate widget.
So like many widget unthinking create a lay overlay widget that we will be able to put in our world
and then a C++ parent class because were going to want that we should be doing some actual stuff so
will want to do that in C++ and add some cancell and Main Menu button so cancel to make them and you
go away again.
Main Menu to take you back to the main menu level and leave the current game.
And then I'd like you to load the menu on scaped he pressed in the level not obviously over the top
of the main menu because that would make absolutely no sense.
Only in the level itself.
Okay so that's a fairly vague challenge I don't want you to do anything with the cancel the main menu
buttons just yet.
I would like you just to make them so.
Pause a video and have a go at putting this menu together from scratch for yourself.
Okay welcome back.
Now it is my turn to have a go at the big challenge.
So let's start off by creating a new widget.
So I am going to create a let's see ad new then we're going to look for user interface widget blueprint
and I'm going to quote WB P underscore and then we're going to call it in the game menu.
Like so.
And then I can create out straight away a C++ based class.
But that's I'm going to add new new C++ class and I am not going to find it in here.
So I'm going to go to show all classes.
Look for the user widget.
Which is he'll go to next.
And then choosing a folder wisely in a you II menu system folder.
We are going to go ahead and create a main menu not a main menu an in-game menu class.
So.
Go ahead and create that.
Okay with that finished compiling we can go ahead and use that as a base class for our widget blueprint.
So let's go back up to the top level and go down into our menu system open up our widget blueprint in
game menu then.
From there we're going to go to the graph remember to go to find our class settings and in our class
settings that we are going to go to the parent class and change that out for the in game menu as the
parent class.
Okay.
So we can save compile and close that widget back down and had it in need to close it down because the
next step is to create the layout.
Now I don't want to be creating that whole lay out from scratch again so I'm going to open up my main
menu widget and hope that we can copy some of it across.
So what I'm hoping to copy across is this whole main menu chunk because I think that our in-game menus
going to look very very similar.
So I'm going to select all that hit copy go into my in-game menu and hit paste in here.
Sure enough we've got a menu of sorts in here something isn't quite right with it entirely.
I'm sure we'll find out in a second but what I want to do is I notice I've got a Cambers panel in here
so I'm going to right click my Cambers panel and go to replace with and replace with the child so that
we don't have that Cambers panel there any more.
Excellent that's a great start.
Now our main menu is the right size again so it must be something to do with the canvas.
But it is floating up in the top left.
Ah we can fix that quite easily we know how to do this by now.
So we go to our size box.
Now is this store actually in anything so we need to wrap it with something.
I'm going to right click and go and wrap it with a let's see a vertical box perhaps vertical box will
do.
And this vertical box we are then going to go onto the main menu and we can.
Horizontally align it to the centre in both dimensions and let's see.
I want to go to my vertical box and check that its full size which it is.
So how do we make sure that it is in the middle.
Yes we need to hit fill.
So now that is floating smack bang in the middle and the only thing is want to change its name from
Main Menu to something a bit more meaningful like in-game menu.
Mike so we can change the text.
To.
Pause menu or something like that.
Or no we're not actually pausing the game when we do this so let's call this something more meaningful
maybe just menu at this stage.
And we want to give the button some good names so House is going to be cancel.
And join is going to be main menu.
Like so now and counting issue with our button.
So let's just call this quit instead.
That makes more sense.
It fits on a button.
Sometimes you have to do that just adapt the text to your images rather than the other way round.
And I'm going to rename our buttons just for clarity to cancel button and quit button on the actual
buttons themselves because we're going to want to hook them up to stuff in a subsequent lecture.
So there we go.
We've got quick but uncancel button.
It's starting to all take shape.
I'm happy with this.
Okay.
So next up we want to actually be able to launch this on the escape key.
Now the way that I want to do this is from launch in the game instance but call the game instance from
the level blueprint so we're doing as little blueprint work as possible how that is possible to call
it from C++.
But I think in this case it's just going to be easier to cheat a little bit in inverted commas and use
and blueprints.
I'm going to go to the game insistency plus plus and we are going to first of all need to get hold of
our menu class.
So let's go to the game instance.
Dot H.
And with the game instance dot H I am going to create a T subclass of.
That's going to be a t suit subclass of use a widget called in-game menu class.
I'm going to call it.
So and then we are going to see.
Go into the constructor for our game instance using our class finder a racer get a copy and paste all
this code.
And use it to help us find the in-game.
Menu BP.
I can just basically copy that in-game portion because that's what we're going to put in front everything
else.
Which I just done.
And we can change also the WP in game menu.
So we've got that should all hook up.
I'll start the compellation process and then what we were going to want to do is we're going to want
to provide a blueprint callable function that can be called from our level.
So let's do that.
Go to the game instance got some blueprint callable load menu in here.
Actually that might be useful.
We could have already got a load menu we're using it in the other blueprints so we can just do something
very similar.
Were going to do just copy and paste that load menu function that's blueprint callable and we're going
to make it in-game.
Load menu.
And it's how this all gets easier as you got more and more code you can basically start to plagiarize
from yourself and start to see patterns and repeat those patterns.
Very very easy.
OK so we've got a load menu.
And under the load menu we are going to implement our in-game load menu.
And we're going to add the name space.
And we're basically going to be doing very much the same thing as our load menu.
Except this time the menu is going to be different.
We aren't going to store it in the private variable but rather just in a local variable here called
A You use a widget.
It's going to be of type you use a widget as is the create widget.
It's going to be a type you use a widget.
Like so.
And it's going to be storing into to you.
You use a widget star and the class is going to be an in-game menu class not just the menu class.
And so let's copy and paste that.
Okay.
So just a few things to point out we haven't got a set up here and we don't have a set menu interface
here because the menu that we are using is of type.
You use a widget.
Now I'm beginning to see a bit of a repetitive pattern here.
This set up is needed both for our.
Main Menu and for our you use a widget which is actually a in-game menu.
So the set up is actually going to be identical as it is at the menu interface so maybe we want to be
abstracting this out into a base class and that's what we're going to do next.
We are going to go ahead and create a new menu widget.
Okay so let's go ahead in to the engine.
First of all and create this C++ file that we need.
So add new.
New C plus plus class showreel classes and search for user widget.
Go to next.
Select the correct folder.
Which will be the menu system and call our menu widget.
Create that class and wait for the compilation to take place.
So I've got a compilation error here.
I'm not too worried about it because I think that it's probably related to some of the in progress stuff
we've got going in Visual Studio.
So what I can do now is instead of including.
Our main menu.
H or as well as including main menu.
H I think we should go ahead and include our menu widget.
H.
Which should allow us to use a new menu widget.
Instead in our in-game menu I'm going to go ahead and do that.
And I want to take those functions that were the set up and set menu interface and bring them up to
that new level that we've created.
So let's open up our menu which it does H and also open up our main menu.
H.
Let's see if we can get these side by side Super got enough room for that.
Drag the tab out and try and put it on the right hand side.
See if that's going to work.
Yes I think that I'll just about work just got about enough space.
So what do we want to bring up there I want to set up and tear down.
So that's going to go up to the menu widget.
We also want the set menu interface to go up so basically all of that public interface is going up to
the menu widget.
So we can remove the public section entirely from the main menu.
Next up let's scroll down to perhaps have a look.
Yes we need to have that private variable the menu interface because that implementation of set menu
interface relies on that.
So put that in a private section of the menu widget.
Okay now we've got that interface the interface.
I'm going to actually include.
I need to include the menu interface in my header.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Above the generated dot H remember.
And as I'm doing this remember I am cutting and pasting all of these because I don't want them in my
main menu as well because my main menu is now going to in let's make sure this happens.
It's going to inherit not from you use a widget but instead from the menu widget.
So let's go ahead and include that.
So instead of including use a widget I'm going to include a menu widget or h.
And I'm going to inherit from it you menu widget.
And now we can go to the C++ for my main menu.
I open that up and put it in the other side of the split as well as the C++ for the.
Menu widget menu widgets dotsie P P I put that on the left hand side of the split.
So obviously looking very empty.
But let's go ahead and take our set up and tear down first of all.
That's what we did.
That's the order we did them in.
Not the order matters particularly.
It's not wanting to scroll.
So I am going to do them one at a time.
Set up first.
Tear Down second.
Then the set menu interface.
And that should be about it because that was everything in our public.
Declaration.
And hopefully that should do the trick.
Let's go ahead and build it and see whether we've got any errors.
Okay so I do have an error.
And the first error I'm noticing is that it's saying you may menu is not a class or namespace in the
menu widget DCP.
Sure enough I haven't updated it to use the you menu widget namespace instead of for the new class.
So let's make sure we do that and copy it into set up tear down and set menu interface.
Now let's try building again and see whether it's STILL doesn't work.
Okay we got a little bit further this time but now is saying that we cannot access the private member
of menu interface from our main menu.
That's true because it is private.
If we make it protected however go over to Main Menu and change private protected and then that means
that everything that inherits from the new menu widget has access to it.
So that would be fine.
We don't mind that at inheriting classes have access.
Okay finally build succeeded.
Now a few more tweaks that I want to put in place such as the fact that we know our you main menu widget
and menu widget is not the parent of our in-game menus.
So in our ingame many do h we want to make sure that we change that over to be the new menu widget and
that we include the menu widget dot age as well.
So that should help immensely with making sure that we are getting the right thing.
It's a damn included menu menu rather than menu widget.
That would help if I included the right thing wouldn't it.
So now our in-game menu inherits from the menu widget as well which means that it has a set up and tear
down function which means that in our puzzle platform game instance dot c p p We are now able to with
a clear conscience call set up and tear down on this create widget of type you menu widget and we know
that it is indeed of that type because that in-game menu class points to the end game menu which inherits
from our in-game menu.
Are you in game menu which in turn inherits from our you menu which is so so a few steps to get there
but we've removed a little bit of duplication and made things I think a little bit clearer.
Maybe not on first pass but on second path I think it's a bit clearer.
So let's head back into unreel with our build succeeded and see if we can now launch our game as we
wanted it to in the first place.
So let's go ahead and open up our level which is under I think still the third person cbp Maps and the
third person example map.
And I'm going to go to my blueprints.
And I'm going to go to open level blueprint.
I'm going to right click in here and we're going to try and create an event around the escape key.
Sure enough there is a keyboard event called Escape this is very easy from this node we can drag the
pressed key and we're going to look for the game instance.
We can cast to game instance a puzzle platform go instance and casting from the puzzle platform game
instance we can use that game instance object that was cast to call.
What do I call we want to call load.
In Game load menu.
Okay.
That's what we do.
And I forgot that we need to pass an object into this cast obviously which is just going to be the game
instance.
Get game instance very simple Kate so that's fairly straightforward thing to be doing there in the level
blueprint.
Let's go ahead and play that and see if a scape now does what we intend.
No.
Now the reason for that is probably because the escape has a double meaning when you do escape inside
the editor it quits your game.
So let's just go ahead and add another key there as well.
And I want to go for the keyboard M for menu just say it's got a mnemonic that I can easily remember
to skip through a few things that get keyboard.
Em searching for that will also if I bring this Prest key to also go in to cast then what we've got
is that either escape or M will trigger an in game menu to load.
So let's go ahead and hit play.
And see whether we can use the key to load a menu.
Yes we can has it doesn't do anything but we successfully loaded it.
So we're going to figure out how to cancel it and quit it in the next lecture.
Congratulations if you manage to get all the way through that challenge on your own.
Now obviously I wasn't expecting you to do the last bit that little refractor into the menu widget but
hopefully even if you had to duplicate code you managed to get to the end of the challenge so pat yourself
on the back for having gone through such a big challenge even if you didn't get to the end of it for
having attempted it.
And if you didn't attempt it then shame on you you should be attempting more challenges.
It's the only way to learn.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.