Congratulations on getting to the end of the U.
S. and other section down.
Now I know this wasn't a very multi player resection but it is going to be incredibly useful for us
going forward to be able to build UI that allows us to do more complicated things in the network and
allows more complicated connection procedures.
And that's what we're going to be using in the upcoming sections.
So if you want to spruce up you die a little bit more and a bit more polish and go and share it in the
discussions.
Now the discussions link is again as usual in the sidebar but I've also included a link to the student
showcase where you can go and see what other students have put together for this section.
What are the kind of extensions they've done and hopefully take a bit of inspiration from that to add
some polish to your own UI before moving on and to make sure you share your final product before you
take the next section.
I look forward to seeing what you come up with.