Hello and welcome this lecture.
We are going to be producing a very exciting output again.
I'm afraid it's going to be just some couple of luck messages but it's going to tell us that we are
starting to find sessions and finishing finding sessions at different times.
And it's going to be a delay between the two.
Let me show you in fact if I go ahead and play then it's starting to find sessions.
We're waiting for it.
Find sessions waiting for it to find sessions and it has finished finding sessions so we are going to
be doing this a synchronized operation of finding sessions and that is going to be the first step in
the process or actually being able to list out the session that we have created perhaps on another game
and perhaps across the land.
So let's dive in and see how it's done.
So now that we are able to create our sessions the next logical thing to do is to be able to find said
SESSIONS So let's figure out how to do that with the help of our documents.
You can find the link in there your resources and we're going to be using FIND sessions online session
now to use this.
We need to understand a little bit about 80 shared Reff we've seen T shed winter shared Reff is very
similar to tea shared pointer except that it cannot be NULL unlike a pointer very much like the distinction
between a standard pointer in C++ and a reference a shared reference is exactly the same it cannot be
NULL it has to have it has to be pointing to something on the heap.
Okay so that is what we're going to need to know about.
The reason is because Find Sessions is going to take the searching play number which again we're going
to be just using the player zero for that.
But it also takes the search settings and the search settings.
Basically you need to live longer than just the find more basic for the duration of find sessions so
it needs to be there on the heap because that's where the results are of the session search are going
to be put.
And then we need to basically manage that somehow so we're going to manage it using a reference counting
because we don't want all the bulk of having to put it in a big you object and having to deal with that
on with garbage collection basically.
So we're doing it with reference counting instead.
So without further ado let's dive into the code and see if we can actually implement this so Im going
to be doing this on it because at the moment we dont have a better place for it.
Were going to work on having a better place for it but for now let's stick with it.
I'm going to just put it here after we've checked that assertion interfaces valid we've been putting
our call-backs.
I'm also going to do the find session so session interface find session auge Swan and emphasized were
just doing it here for testing purposes for being able to get it to the stage where we've got something
useful and then we can wrap this all up in a nice interface which actually shows the servers available
and gives us the opportunity to join them doesn't it.
OK so we've got fine sessions Zerah with search and play at zero and then we are going to create a t
shared a ref.
Okay so how are we going to create this Tiche ref.
Well for that I have two documentation pages for you the shared reference page which tells you basically
a lot about the shared reference and tells you how you had to construct it with something it can't be
now fairly straightforward.
But it also at the bottom tells you about the two shared ref.
So that's basically saying that if you have a pointer then you can convert it into a reference as long
as you're sure that it isn't NULL.
So that's what we are going to be using.
We're going to be creating first.
A shared pointer and I want to show you another aspect of shared pointers that we can use.
And I'll do that after I've created the pain after we've seen what the issue is.
Well the issue is that I want to create this session and I'm in to live longer needs to live until a
delegate is called so is going to need to be created at the class level.
So I'm going to create it in as a private thing and what's the time.
Well let's go and have a look at the F online session it's going to be a shared pointer to an F online
session search.
So going to get that online search session search it's going to be a tea shared pointer.
Then we are going to have a template argument which is going to be the f online session search and it's
not too short pointer but teacher P are revision for pointer and we're going to call this the sessions
each.
So that's a session cert by default.
It's going to be null.
Kurtz We haven't signed anything to it.
And then what are we going to do.
Well we are going to assign to it so sessions search.
Is going to be equal to.
And this is the interesting point because I can't just set it equal to a new.
What was that type again.
I can to have it in my paste buffer.
Yep f online session search.
I cant just do that by the way the new key word create something on the heap if you haven't seen that
before.
It's just saying don't make this f online session search here on the stack but make it on the heap and
is actually giving us an error about that because we can't just assign that to a shared pointer.
We need to wrap it and how do we wrap it.
Well that's also in the documentation for the shared pointer.
You just need to wrap it in a make shareable method which will take any standard C++ pointer and convert
it in to a reference counted pointer for real.
So we're going to use that make sharable wrapper to achieve that and then we're going to pass the session
search object in to the session interface and let's see if that works and just hitting the build button
and see if it succeeds.
Okay no we've got some errors so let's have a look at the output log the output log.
He is telling us.
I think that's not the beginning of the output log.
Go quite wait.
Okay the output log is telling us the f online session search is under a cloud identifier.
Go to the line it's complaining about.
It's actually in the head a file that it's saying the F online session search is not there.
So what we need to do is means do a forward declaration and hope that in the C++ file everything is
going to be hunky dory.
Okay yet more errors Let's have a look at the output log and see what these are about.
So the first line of error which I think is relevant here.
Is saying.
Cannot convert argument to from t shared pointer to t shared Reff.
That is because I have tried to pass a shared pointer in instead of a shared ref.
So what we need to do is first check whether it is valid and then we can convert it to it.
Right so we're going to do an if session.
And spelled properly search is valid.
Then we will be able to convert it to a reference and subsequently find the session.
So it's going to be sessions search dot to shared Reff which is in that documentation that I linked
you to.
And if we go and build that we should be able to.
Should be building just fine and we should be trying to create a session.
Okay the builder succeeded but obviously we're not going to see anything at this point so it's going
to be your challenge to handle on file in session complete delegates and a going to do that.
Are you going to print on find complete So when the find session has completed you are going to need
to find the type of the delegates you're going to need to register for call-backs and you're going to
need to print out from that call back to test that find was indeed called correctly and that the result
coming it came out.
You can even print when you start finding and when you stop finding so you can see how long it takes.
It's kind of interesting.
Pause the video.
Okay welcome back I hope you post pulls a video and it stopped.
I told you rather suddenly didn't I rather strict.
Didn't mean to.
Okay so let's start off by printing.
When we start the final session.
So let's take a log message any log message and paste it in here so I'm going to do a log temp warning.
Starting to find session starting.
I call it starting.
Find session.
And I will go ahead and remove everything after that.
So now we know when the session is starting.
We know that our session search is valid.
Next up we are going to get that call back.
So what is the call-back called.
Well you can find it in I online session.
I'm not going to teach you to suck grapes or eggs or whatever the saying is and we're going to do a
session interface arrow on find.
Sessions are complete delegates.
Then we're going to add the you object or add this and we need to create ourselves a function.
So let's go over to the head of far and create something new and going to copy basically a delegate.
The on destroy session complete.
I'm going to change it to on find a sessions.
There we go on fine sessions complete and then it's going to take.
What's it going to take.
Well if you look in the documentation you'll find that it only takes these success because the list
of found Sessions is actually in that session search t shared point.
So it doesn't need to send that with it as well.
So I'm going to copy this take it over to the C plus plus file where we're going to implement it.
I'm going to implement it.
Let's see just after our on creates session complete.
Maybe well do it and I will implement the body and I'll remove the semicolon and I will add the name
space.
Okay.
And then we are going to copy our log message for brevity and change it from starting to finishing.
I can find a thing I just wrote back then it's going to be finished.
Find session.
Okay so that is great.
We've got on find session complete finished fine session and hopefully that's all gonna work out.
Let's go ahead and at no we don't want to build just yet because we want to have the address of that
function.
So let's get the fully names based on find session complete and do the address of operator on that fully
names based function and pass that in to add you object.
Okay so let's go ahead and build now.
Okay the build has successfully completed Let's go over into one real and see whether we were successful
in achieving what we wanted to starting find Sessions has been logged out here.
And that's see and finished fine session so you can see that there is a bit of a delay between the two
in fact a few logged messages are coming in between the two.
So there's starting find session.
And then finished final etc. So it does actually take a little bit of time because it is waiting for
a while to see whether it's got all the sessions until it is returning.
So that is showing us that we are calling find sessions correctly in the next lecture.
We are going to go in to actually reading the results of find session and printing them out and making
sure that we are able to find the game.
The session we have created using FIND session I will see you there.