Welcome to another lovely video of a real multiplayer and this lecture going to be looking at debugging
engine code because what I want us to be able to do is look at a session here in our find session dialogue
and be able to see that there are indeed one of two players and this is not using seen.
This is using the null subsystem.
So what we've done here is we've been able to find the bug in the subsystem by using the techniques
I'm going to show you in this video and we have been able to find a workaround.
And we have been able to then go to the cervalis and see that there is one player currently playing
and if I go and join that we'll see that there will be two players currently playing so this is great
stuff.
Let's dive in and see how it is done.
Now before we dive in I'd like to point out that the way we are doing this in this lecture the way we're
getting hold of the game session name by debugging the engine is valid but will break between engine
versions as zeo eury seventy eight has pointed out in the Q and A.
There is a better way of doing this by including the unreal names header and finding this the name underscore
game session.
As this will not change between engine versions which is very very helpful so do go ahead watch this
video to see how the debug bugging works.
But please use this if you are unsure.
Well basically use this.
It's not going to change between engine versions it'll be less fragile it's better.
Thank you for coming up with that.
So something is really irritating me with our game at the moment and that is that the number of open
connections being advertised on ad join screen is not getting updated so it always looks like we have
no players on the game even when it's almost about to start.
We want to be able to fix this even in the null subsystem I know it does work with steam but we want
to figure out and get to the bottom of why this is not working with the null subsystem and to do that
I'm going to take you through the process of debugging bugs in the editor to see why.
Whether you understand the API whether it's the way you're calling the API or whether it is the API
itself that has problems whether it's the editor itself that has problems.
So the first step of this process we're going to need to get hold of something called Ed symbols and
as a debug symbols these symbols basically allow us to attach a debugger to a processor processor game
using the unreel editor and it will allow us to jump into the Ed code and jump around the editor code
so that we can see what it's calling what the code is running a warit we are in the call stack and what
variables they are so we can really see the inner workings of the code in action not just statically
by trying to read the code that may often helps massively when trying to debug these issues.
So to get hold of those ed symbols is really easy just fire up your epic games launcher and go over
to your unreel tab to the library tab and then for your for your version of unreal.
Mine is four point seventeen point two.
You can go to the drop down menu go to options and in options you've got the various components of the
engine which can optionally be installed or not installed.
You're looking for the ED symbols for debugging option.
Go ahead make sure that's checked and go and hit apply for me nothing should have changed though.
That should be fine but for you if you need to get those ed symbols then it will go ahead and download
it fairly large download so if you need them go ahead and pause the video now to start the process while
I show you what we're going to be doing with the debugging.
Okay so hopefully you've gone ahead and done that.
Now we're going to go and have a look at how we can figure out or start looking at this bug.
The first step is going to be finding the null subsystem code we know this is going on somewhere in
the null subsystem and we know it has something to do with this variable of num public connections.
Those are the two pieces of information that we're going to use as our leads.
To start off with and we're going to go and find the implementation in the null subsystem where this
number should be altered.
So let's go and find that null subsystem.
The best way to do that is on both x code and Visual Studio will be just to do a project wide search
for something that should be defined in the null subsystem such as create session for example.
So copy the text create session go and do a project wide search though for visual view that's control
shift F and search for create session in the entire solution.
Go ahead and find all of those symbols there'll be a few of them but we're going to be looking for the
one in a file that clearly means that it's part of the noell subsystem.
So here already in the search results we are seeing things like online session interface online session
interface.
I o s and here there is an online session interface null dot copy.
So that seems like the implementation for an LOL subsystem.
Let's click it and open up our online session interface null dotsie Key.
Now this file is obviously rather large if I scroll on to the bottom we can see that there are about
twelve hundred lines of code in here and that's a lot of code going on in just this null subsystem and
the null subsystem as we know doesn't actually do very much.
It doesn't even do internet connection like unlike the steam subsystem so well where is the code that
is updating that variable we were talking about.
We go to the C++ Mort was a variable called it was called num public connections.
Let's copy that and go over to C++ and let's see if we can find some occurrences of this and see how
it should be used and then we can verify that with some debugging in just a minute.
So if I go searching through then we've got one instance of it being called here it's being used to
set a session that says number of open public connections.
So actually that's the variable we're looking for.
That's the one that we're reading off so none public collections is what we're setting in create session.
But when we are getting our find.
Where is it.
Somewhere down the bottom here.
No.
I'll do a search for find in our game instance or see BP find session complete.
In here we are getting our search result back and we're looking for the number of num open public connections.
So then copy that and actually look for that in the nul session interface because that's what we want
to see so we can see that.
First off when you do call create session.
So we got a call to create session here on line 180 and it is being the number of open public connections
is being set to the number of public connections so it starts off as the maximum that makes sense.
Lets go and look for the next occurrence.
This is somewhere in.
Needs to advertise and its being used as part of a boolean expression so its unlikely to be that.
Where else do we have it.
Is that session joinable again here it's saying that we need to have more than zero open public connections
for it to be joinable.
OK.
That's probably not it either.
Okay this looks interesting in register players.
We have got a check first that it's greater than zero but then subsequently we are subtracting from
that number of open public connections.
So that seems like the problem we probably aren't subtracting from that variable.
So the question is does register players ever get called at all.
And if so what are the arguments it gets called with.
And do we ever get to this line of code that subtracts from number of public connections.
Well we can try and find this out using the debugger.
What we're going to be doing with the debugger is attaching to the editor that means we are getting
the editor to run its code and we are listening to basically what code is being run with the debugger
and then we can reproduce the issue and we can see we can set breakpoints in our code a breakpoint is
very easy to set both in Visual Studio and ex code where you basically just click next to the line number
and you see this little red dot that shows up.
And that is a break point and this means that when execution in the thing that you are attached to reaches
this line its going to pause and throw you into visual studio and you will be able to have a look at
what the variables currently are.
It will be able to have a look at the call stack and all sorts of things like that.
So I would like to you to jump in and actually have a go with this yourself.
So I'm going to set a couple of break points and you can do the same going to set one on Lown 885 where
we call we decrement num open public connections.
I'm also going to set one on register players right near the top just to see whether we're even calling
register players.
So that's going to be online 866 for me just after Reg's the players has begun.
There's been no ifs.
So if it had called this method at all we would have got to this line.
And then we can go ahead and attach very simply and just a quick refresher if you've not done any attaching
in a while then the way you do this is you go to the debug menu attached to process and then you can
search for either the basic just look for unreel and you'll see there is a ewy for Ed but if you have
some games open then you will have some unreel games here to attach to as well.
And you can do this and you can see whether you can basically try attaching to the host attaching to
the clients and see what happens in all of these situations.
So let me structure this as a challenge for you.
You're going to be debugging the noell subsystem and these are the sorts of questions you are going
to be asking yourself now and throwing you in the deep end a little bit here just see how far we can
get with these questions.
Don't worry if you can't answer the more we'll go through in the change solution.
So the first question to answer is does the host or client call register player and do that doesn't
get called at all.
As it should be called.
Does the open no open public.
Connections decrements do we reach the line where the decremented happens.
And if so why is it then not showing up for us.
And if not why not.
Why are we not reaching that line.
What goes wrong in the IF statements.
Do we even get to register a player and have these questions and then come back and watch the video.
Okay welcome back.
Hopefully you've had a stab at doing this for yourself.
Now I'm going to go ahead and create the situation in which this problem will occur.
You're going to shut down the unreal editor just for simplicity and to save on a few resources.
And I'm going to launch up power shell and I am going to launch up two instances of the game one to
be the host and one to be the client.
I'll do that and I'm going to skip the step of attaching to the client because I happen to know that
Reg's the players only get called on the host.
I've done this by experimentation obviously.
You go ahead and experiment for yourselves and see that if you're attached to the client you won't get
registe the players called.
So I'm going to go ahead and attach it to the host.
First of all so actually I'm going to close down one of the instances to make sure that when I'm attaching
to the game in since there's only one around so that only I'm definitely attaching to the right one
which is going to be housed.
So I'm going to go ahead and go to let's have a look.
Project.
No debug.
That was the one attached to process and I'm going to look for unreel and sure enough I've got just
one process as I'm expecting.
I can go ahead and attached to that because I've got the debug symbols this is going to work out okay.
I've got my breakpoints in place that I put in place before the challenge and it has gone ahead and
attach the process and we can see that it's now running by looking at the diagnostic tools we can see
as a bar moving along there which is just tracking time basically.
And it's not stopped at any of the breakpoints so wrenched the players hasn't been called yet nor has
this line with decremented a number of public open connections.
So let's go back into the game and actually host a game or go ahead and create a game with our favourite
hostname.
Let's go ahead and host it and see if anything it's called.
Okay.
So I've got a breakpoint here which I must have said before I'm going to unset it by clicking on it
again and we can continue by going to the top bar where there is a green arrow that says continue and
continue through.
And I've got a few of these breakpoints that apparently have been remained set from previous debugging
sessions.
So I'm going to just play through them and eventually we reach the break point of Register players.
So Register players is getting called game called when we host our own game and it's getting called
on the host.
So that answers the first question for sure.
Now does number of open public connections get called let's go ahead and see if it does.
I'm going to continue playing and we should hit the next break point if we actually reach that line
of code that's hit continue.
Nope it does not reach that line of code it's stopped somewhere else and then continue playing.
So we've never got to actually decremental saying that that variable now.
Third question why.
Let's go ahead and launch up a new game so you can see the debug session has just finished and Visual
Studio has gone back to looking normal.
I'm going to launch up the power shell again and I'm going to go ahead and attach to it.
So I'll go to my debug attached to process.
I may have to wait for the game to launch first being a bit impatient.
So now it's up and running we can go into visual studio and debug go tos attach to process.
And we can search real again select the unreal editor with title puzzle platforms attach.
Wait for it to it's attaching we've got the bar moving along in the diagnostic tools and we can go ahead
and host a game and get the behaviour that we want to observe.
And here we are in Reg's the players.
Now let's have a look at our IF statements.
Where could we be going wrong in these if statements.
We can go actually and step through this one.
One line of code at a time.
So in the top bar we had continue there are also some other buttons one of which if you hover over it
will say step over and you'll have very similar controls on X code.
We can step over line by line and see whether we're going into all these if statements do we go into
the first IF statement.
No we don't.
We actually skip over that first statement that set tries to get hold of a session because the session
is not.
So this pointer to f named session is null and we can hover over it and we can see that the value is
now another place that we can see this is in the panes labelled locals.
Where you can see that Sessions it's sessions bearable which is a local variable is not.
So why is it now because it is set by get named sessions and of the session name coming in.
Is game.
That's interesting.
Why is the session name that comes into Reg's the player's game.
It's clearly not the session that name that we've given it.
If we go to our game instance or s.p. Scroll to the top of the file you can see that the session name
we are using as a session name constant is my session game.
So what is going on.
Why is it giving us this variable name coming in.
Well this is where we can have a look at the call stack remember the call stack is one function calling
another calling another queally another.
And they're actually written out kind of backwards here on the call stack.
The top item is the one the deepest most function.
The one that we're currently in and then the one above that E is basically the function that's calling
that and so on and so on so we can double click on these to navigate up to where they're being called.
And we can try and trace back to where this session name is actually coming from.
So here if I go up to levels we're in a file called Online engine interface import implementation shortfall.
And that itself has a Reg's to play a method but that Reg's the play method is taking session name in
and as we can see by hover over hovering over it you can see the session name is game in quotes.
So we've already got a problem here we've got to go up a little bit further.
We go up to a class called Play a state DOT cbp and here you can see that the session name is coming
from the player state itself and the play state if we look at that variable in this function you can
see that the player state is being created as a get default call.
We don't quite know what a default call is but I can pretty much assume that get default is getting
as a default instance of the class a player state.
So this seems to mean to me that player state is basically has got a default session name and that default
session name is game.
So there is a bug here whether it's at this level or down in the null subsystem.
But for some reason it is assuming that the session name will be game.
So that's a bit of a problem.
But seeing as we're just using a session name constant anyway we can go ahead and change our session
name constant to match game which should fix the problem.
So let's go ahead and give that a shot.
I'm going to stop debugging here by hitting the stop button.
Go into my game instance dot s.p..
And we can change this session name variable from my session game just to game with a capital G.
So I'm going to go ahead save that rebuild and then we can test this out in an instance of our game.
So I got a couple of weird compile errors here and they seem to be talking about the key word here to
look for is that it says access denied somewhere access to path.
Blah blah blah is denied.
That typically happens I think when a game is open and you try to compile because it doesn't do the
usual hot reload thing that the editor does.
So just close down the game and try to recompile if you ever get those sorts of errors.
And sure enough this time we had a successful build so lets go and launch up to instances of the game
and in one of them we will be the host and then the other one we will just go and observe the host list
and hopefully this time we will see that there is one player instead of zero players currently in the
game.
So the game is firing up.
And here it is so in the first one I am going to go ahead and host.
Give it any old name and there we are.
Im in the lobby as the host and in the second instance I'm going to go ahead and join wait for the menu
to populate from the north subsystem and when it has we can let out an exclamation of joy because our
player number is indeed 2 1 out of 2 which means that in all that debugging which was quite complicated
and difficult but well done for sticking through it.
We have been able to identify the by and find a workaround to it so hopefully you're feeling really
energized now and then the next video we are going to be looking at non bug related stuff how we can
actually shut down a session once the players have gone off from the lobby and make sure that it doesn't
show up in the server list anymore.