Hello and welcome in this lecture we are going to be making a start on our new game a card based game
which is going to allow us to understand everything that we need to know about the control and physics
in something like a movement component.
And this is going to form the basis of being able to understand how to synchronize this movement across
a network without it feeling laggy without with you keeping control and with keeping the fairness all
all of those things we're going to be learning.
But first of all we have to actually create a car that can move around the world as you are currently
seeing.
So let's dive in and see how we can do that.
This section is all about being able to synchronize the most complex of things which is player movement.
Very hard to do in a convincing way so that both the player feels responsive and everybody else can
agree on what the player is doing without giving that player an advantage can be very very tricky to
understand it properly we're gonna actually have to build up our own player movement object component
our own play movement code and rather than just replicating a character move.
We're going to do something a little bit more interesting and a slightly more simple which is to create
a movement set up for a car instead.
So we're going to be doing a racing type project.
It's going to be very very basic.
We're not going to be using physics we're going to be creating our own very rudimentary physics in order
to do this.
So the first thing to do is go ahead and create a project based on a vehicle project in on real So I'm
going to go ahead and launch up the four point seventeen Ed where we can go ahead and create ourselves
a starter project.
So the first few lectures in this section on actually going to be about multiplayer at all.
They're going to be laying the foundations of how we can create a movement component so you fully understand
what's going on in movement in the first place absolutely vital to being able to replicate it over a
network.
And then we cannot go in to that replication step and make sure that it replicates.
So the first things first we are going to be going to new project tab go into the C++ tab and we want
to look for the vehicle start a project not the vehicle advanced because that has way more physics stuff
in it than we want.
So were going to get a vehicle which gives us this nice sedan model and a nice obstacle course and then
we are going to select the desktop console option maximum quality and I'm going to select no starter
content and I'm going to stick this in side with the project that I've already created my great project
and I'm going to call it crazy carts which is the name of that section.
So they would go crazy carts and I am going to create that project and it's going to it can populate
all of that.
But while it's can populating I'm just going to make sure that my guitar ignore which I had get automatically
create for me and you can do that too when you create me in new projects then I'm going to take that
and I'm going to copy it in to the root of the unreel project so that it applies at the right level.
Because if you open up the guitar ignore for those of you understand the get ignored syntax and I'll
just tell you very briefly it's very straightforward in this case then this is telling us that anything
that begin that ends with SLN in this directory so it has to be in the right direction he is going to
be ignored if we put it directly above then it wouldn't have picked up on the SLN it wouldn't pick up
on the binaries folder and those would all get including get.
Which of course I don't want.
Okay so my project has finished modulating and has now got visual studio here for crazy carts and I've
also got the crazy carts ed.
Now what's fun to do is go ahead and play this game and you're actually going to see how nice and physically
accurate this whole sedan model is and you can go over the torain you can accelerate.
You can get up the touraine like so and want to conceal the suspension and action and it's it's quite
fine and you can knock over these cones.
Unfortunately we're going to be reducing the functionality of this game to make it really straightforward
so that we actually understand of what is going on in the whole physical simulation because it's vitally
important that we are in control of every step.
Not just.
No not not just being able to control a physics engine we need to be able to literally control it down
to being able to move the car.
So what we're going to do unfortunately is we are going to dispense with this car and we are going to
replace it with our own siding and to remove this porn from our scene.
And we are going to create our very own car porn instead.
We're going to go to the add new menu.
We're going to create a new C++ class because we aren't going to be doing this.
We are going to be doing in C plus then select the pawn go to next and I'm going to call this go cart
because it's going to be the basis of a go cart.
Go ahead and create that class.
Wait for the C plus plus to compile and then what we're going to need to do is we're going to need to
create a blueprint based off of this which will have the mesh and the camera and we all need to create
a blueprint based off the game mode so that we can edit it and make sure that the correct pawn is being
loaded when we hit play which is at slightly more boring at this point because we haven't added any
functionality into that porn but will soon be rectifying that situation.
Okay so it has gone ahead and created the C++ porn.
We can go ahead and quick on that go cart porn.
Create a blue print class based on go cart porn and I'm going to actually create a new folder to put
that in first.
So let's go up to the top level and I'm going to create a folder for all of our assets new folder called
crazy carts.
Mike so.
OK so we've got crazy carts and then we're going to go to the ad new and air.
Go create a new blueprint class and it's going to be based off one of our classes so all classes go
kart is what were going to base it off I'll select that go ahead select and then I'm going to prefix
this with BP under score and then go kart.
So same name but it's that BP some platt's.
Okay good.
Now let's open up that blue print subclass and we can create the go cart.
So here is the go cart blueprint editor and instead of the default scene route we're going to want to
add a skeletal mesh.
Because the skeletal mesh because the car that we saw previously is actually a skeletal mesh rather
than a static mesh.
So then when we've got skeletal mesh we can go over into the details and selectively mesh for the sedan
skeletal mesh.
So if we zoom out they go you have got yourself the sedan that we were seeing previously as the object
of our.
Of our.
Basically.
And if we go ahead and we can go ahead and save this and go over into our vehicle example map and set
this up.
You need to set up the game moden to spawn correctly so to do that I'm actually going to go and add
a new blueprint class and I'm going to search in here for a game mode.
And we've got a few game modes including the crazy cartes game mode.
So let's override the crazy card game mode and I'm going to prefix this BP game mode and we can take
this BP game mode and actually go to our blueprint menu on our vehicle example map select under the
world override.
And fact over the project settings.
We're going to go and select a default game mode so select game mode based class and then we select
B game mode.
That should change our game mode over to this blueprint game mode.
And what it all crucially allows us to do is if we open up our BP game mode then we can look in the
details pane and find our default porn class.
And I can change it from the crazy cart porn over to ad BP go carts.
Now when we go and play we should spawn with no still spawning with the wrong thing.
So let's check that out.
If I go in to the world and I select the world settings and expand out at the world override game mode
is actually still crazy card game mode.
So if I go to my blueprint menu again and I go to the world override then I should be able to just go
and select the.
No none override.
So this world should not override the game mode which now means that if we go ahead and hit play.
We've got another problem which is that we appear inside our go kart.
The reason for that is that there's no camera so we can go ahead and set up a camera.
In fact let's make that part of your challenge so the challenge is going to be to actually get the thing
moving.
Now the first part is going to be adding an appropriate camera of your own so that you're not just pointing
inside the mesh body.
Then I'd like you to look hook up the forward axis so you can see how that's done on the current pawn.
That was the default in here you can see how to bind the axis in case you've forgotten you can you then
use a set velocity member variable to set a velocity that will later use in tick.
So if it's going forward you set a forward appropriate velocity.
If the axis is backwards any set a backwards appropriate velocity and so on and so forth and then I'd
like you to update the position in tick.
So those actually got the porn moving backwards and forwards and you can see it so pause a video and
have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
So first things first let's get that camera working.
So it's actually pretty easy to see out the camera what we're going to do is we are going to add a spring
on first of all.
So I'm out in the spring arm which is based around the centre here I actually want to move it up a little
bit and towards the back of the car and then I want to change its rotation angle somewhat.
So I'm going to do that by indeed changing the rotation and then at the end of the spring arm we can
go and add another camera component which is going to go on the end of the spring or looking at the
car.
So let's go ahead and play and see if that works.
There we go.
We're now looking at the car where it's a bit close up.
So I'm either going to adjust the angle of the spring arms slightly.
I think that's what I'm going to ahead play.
And now you can see we're looking out in front of the car still not quite right in my opinion.
I think we might need to move that spring on just a bit further up.
So play.
Okay.
So now we're getting there.
Just a couple more tweaks.
I like my two weeks ago.
Okay.
So now we are have got a spring arm and it is going to roll.
You can see as it's pointing at our car we can't currently move it.
We can't use the wsb a car keys like we were able to with the previous car so that's the key.
The throttle set up that we're going to be doing okay.
So first things first I said to them the go can't do it.
We're going to have to have a velocity member variable.
So I'm going to create a private section for that.
And I'm going to create a f vector.
Called Velocity.
Like so.
And then what are we going to do.
We are going to go over to the C++.
We wanted to bind some input which we know happens in set play a input component.
But if you forgot how to bind.
Exactly we can go into our sources and we can go to crazy cards and find the crazy cart porn copy and
look in there set up component set up input component and you can see they've got a bind axis move forward
so I'm going to go ahead.
Copy that go over to my C++ and stick that in there so that we are binding the axis to move forward.
The player input component is not happy with for some reason.
Because it's got some incomplete classily must have been a header that we were using in the other crazy
carts porn.
So let's go and have a look at that.
And sure enough there's a component input components I'm going to go over to my head a file actually
my C++ file and pop it at top.
And we are going to hopefully have that error go away.
Now it's obviously complaining about move forward nonexisting on this class.
Well I got change first of all the class best fire.
Then I've got to actually implement and move forward so it's going to return void.
It's going to take the axis which is gonna be a float.
Or just call it value.
And then got a body.
And then I can take this and make a signature out of it in the head a file so go over to the pedophile.
It's going to be private because we don't need that calling from the outside.
Thank you very much.
And we are going to just remove the name space and add a semicolon which allow us to build this file
now.
And we should be able to use it to set a velocity.
So that's what I'm going to use it to do.
I am going at two in here just do velocity.
Equals.
And then it's going to be equal to pretty much.
I'm just going to say let's see it moves in centimetres per second.
But I'm going to leave my velocity as meters per second for simplicity and will convert it in tic at
the last moment.
So I am going to go with 10 meters per second is going to be the velocity of my car in fact that's pretty
slow lets go forward 20 meters per second and I'm going to multiply this by the value of the throttle
that we've got in here because that means that this value will be negative and we're heading backwards
and positive woman going forwards.
So multiplying it by 20 will help there and we actually.
Velocity here as a vector.
So we need a direction to this quantity and I think the direction should be the forward direction of
the car.
So that's pretty easy we can do a get asked forward vector let me just do that without messing up the
rest of the line get actor.
I think forward vector you can easily find this in the documentation.
Here we go to save you the hassle of looking for it.
This is the documentation page which I will include and I'm going to copy and paste it over here.
It wasn't quite able to auto complete in visual studio.
Okay so we've got an active forward vector with multiplying it by 20 meters per second and then we're
multiplying it by the value so that all making either positive.
So in the forward direction or negative in the backwards direction.
And that should do the trick for setting up a lost time.
Now over in tick what we want to do is actually update the location of our porn.
Based on this so I'm going to create an F vector Delta.
Which basically.
I mean delta in the sense of the Greek letter which is typically meant to mean difference so difference
in space is what we're going for here.
It's the difference in space and in fact let's go ahead and call it something more meaningful like that.
Let's call it the translation.
That's the translation in space.
And then what we're going to do is we are going to create that from the velocity.
So we've got a velocity which is a vector and it's in meters per second so it's how many meters were
moving in a given second the translation on the other hand is just in meters.
In fact it's in centimetres.
So we need to do two things to convert it.
First of all we need to multiply by Delta time so the time elapsed in this when the last frame.
So that's how far we have to move it because that's how much time has elapsed.
So that is the meters per second multiplied by seconds just makes it into meters now and then the other
thing we have to multiply by is 100 to get from meters in two centimetres.
So we're going to multiply by 100 as well so its velocity multiply by 100 multiplied by Delta time gives
us the translation and then what we can do is call another function on actor which allows us to translate.
So the way we do this is with actor and actor world offset.
So you can see it takes two arguments.
One argument arguments actually necessary which is the Delta location which is also what we're calling
the translation.
So add actor offset translation and that should have us pretty much done for updating and moving a pawn.
Let's go ahead and build and try it out.
Build works that's fantastic.
Let's go over and actually test it in the motion.
That's my maps not saved for some reason so I'm going to save current and I'm going go ahead and play.
And there you go.
I can hit my forwards and backwards buttons and sure enough it moves forward at 20 mins per second it
moves backwards at 20 meters per second and we can't turn at the moment but a it's also got no acceleration.
So all those things we are going to be fixing in subsequent lectures.
But for now it is a start.
You've put together the basics basic of basics of a rudimentary physics system which is a velocity and
some control.
I'll see you in the next lecture where will be adding more to it.