Welcome to another exciting episode of crazy cartes.
Here we're going to be looking at rotation so you can see we've got this funky kind of non-physical
rotation where I can just rotate here on the spot without moving my car.
Obviously not very realistic but it's going to be fun enough for us for now.
So we're going to be using this so that we can accelerate our car and we can rotate and move around
our obstacles very much like a real car would.
So let's go ahead and dive in and see how we're going to create these rotations so the car rotates as
well as the velocity that we are using here.
Okay.
Let's dive in and see it.
So as have been already mentioned in this video we want to get our car rotating.
Let's talk about how are going to do that going and drop in a car into our scene.
Here it is.
And let's talk about how we want this to rotate.
Basically we want to just rotate it about the pivot the simplest kind of rotation you can possibly do.
If we go to the right rotate tool.
I just want to rotate it like this.
When I hit the A and the D keys and I want to do that at a constant rate per second so say 90 degrees
per second is how quickly it should be rotating in this direction if I hold down a.
And if I hold down the it should be rotating at 90 degrees per second.
In the other direction.
Okay.
So that's what we want to do.
How do we achieve this with rotation how do we define a rotation in a way that is sensible and intelligible
and not at all ambiguous.
But this there is a concept called an angle axis rotation and we can represent this using the f quat
used in unreel which is a slightly more complicated than f rotator and we'll talk about that.
So how do we do this.
Well the angle axis rotation is a very straightforward way of defining a rotation.
Now imagine you had an orange in front of you.
Or maybe go and grab an orange angle axis rotation is where you say I'm going to stick a pen through
this orange that's the axis as you can see here denoted by the vector E and that's the pen.
That's the direction the pen goes through the orange and then the angle is going to be the number of
degrees that you rate.
Rotate it around this pen so imagine you're holding onto the pen on the top and the bottom on your orange
and you are rotating it by a number of degrees around that pen.
This is actually a way of defining any rotation imaginable just by the angle and the angle and the Axis
that's enough.
And you can see here we end up with a if we started off with a unit vector So a vector of lect at length
one then you could multiply it by the angle and that would give you a vector which fully defined the
rotation.
Now we're not going to be using it quite like that but that's the basic idea that you got one vector
which is the pen that you stamp the orange with and then a number which is the angle that you want to
rotate around.
For us it's fairly straightforward the pen that we're stabbing through this car is the up vector the
vector that goes straight up or straight down and then we are rotating by a number of angles around
that pen.
That's what we're trying to achieve.
So let's go over into our code and see if we can code it up.
We'll go into the go kart C++ and I'm going to do this in that tick then we can abstract it out and
make it a bit more pretty.
In just a second but I want to build my rotation first of all so for that we're going to use the type
as I've already mentioned called F quat which stands for f core tourney on so akwa turning on is a rather
complicated algebraic construction which allows you to define rotations and apply them to each other
and it's what unreal uses under the hood to do its rotations in.
It is very very expressive and for many many reasons.
We can do more things with F quat But one of the reasons is that we can do angle axis rotation with
quads and we can't really do that with rotators so easily because they are just basically three numbers
just X Y and Z rotation.
So we'll start with an F quat we're going to create an F quote and we're going to call this the rotation
Delta.
Because we're going to be using it to rotate some.
A certain number of degrees depending on the delta time and then what are we going to do.
We are going to have a look at what its various constructs are.
So you can find the documentation accompanying the lecture.
Let's go and see what it's constructor's are down in the constructor section so we could give it an
F quat we could give it a matrix we could even construct it from an F..
Rotate out but the one I'm interested in is the one that takes an axis and an angle in radians notice.
Now you may know about the difference between degrees and radians but will just cover that in a second.
So we're going to take in an axis which as we've already mentioned is the upper vector.
So go and do get actor up.
Vector is going to be the pen through which we're going to stab our car and then we are going to rotate
by a number of degrees.
Now this degrees is going to depend on our throttle so our Or rather our steering angle so that's going
to be the a different axis isn't it.
So we'll go over to our car crazy can't pawn C++ and have a look at what they are using for their steering.
They've got their move right axis so I'm going to go ahead and bind that in my plus as well so I need
to create a move right function so I'm going to update the namespace that it's referring to in this
bind axis.
I'm going to go ahead and create that function underneath my move forwards of going to return FOID.
It's going to take a float value.
You can follow along with me.
You guys know how to do this and we're gonna call this the steering throw.
And we're going to use that to set.
We're gonna use the value to set the steering throw.
I'm going to have to define both the steering flow and the move.
Right so let's go over into the header.
Having copied move right I'm going to put it in my just underneath.
Move forward and I'm going to put a semicolon.
The end and remove the namespace so that it is header compatible then we are going to go and find our
steering throw.
And were going to go up to the head of file again and I'm going to put that underneath the throttle
so it's gonna be float staring throw good.
So were going to be updating that from our move right.
We're going have a steering throw and we're going to want to have.
We've currently got a max driving force we want to have some other eligible property here.
It's going to be a new property anywhere.
It's going to be float as well.
But what we want it to be for is the maximum number of degrees that can be rotated per second so we'll
call it Max.
Degree.
What degrees.
Per second.
Like so.
And I think the max degrees per second at a good starting point will be around the 90 mark.
So we'll start off with 90 and let's give it a good comment.
So the number of degrees rotated per second at full control fros going to be my comment in brackets
I've put degrees per second as the units for this Max degrees per second.
Okay let's go over into the C++ with this because that is what we're going to be putting into our rotation
Delta.
The angle that we're going to rotate so that actually creates a float rotation.
Angle.
Is going to be equal to the max degrees per second multiplied by the delta time.
So remember that Delta times units are seconds.
So when we've got degrees per second multiply by seconds it's going to give us the number of degrees
to rotate in this frame.
And then were going to multiply that by itself by the steering throw which is that control throw.
And then we can use our rotation angle in our rotation Delta to construct that rotation Delta.
So ended up this quat rotation Delta.
And finally we need to apply this rotation to the actor.
How do we do that.
I hear you ask.
So let's take a look at the documentation for a actor for looking at how we can add a rotation to our
actor.
So let's have a look at ad rotation LOL Just look for rotation and see if we can find something useful.
K we've got asked a local rotation and we have an outer world rotation so what's the difference.
Well if we had some hierarchy of transforms this would make a bit of a difference.
But in this case.
Doesn't really matter too much but we're going to go with world because we know that the UPA vector
that we're using is in world coordinates space so it should be fine to go ahead and use a world level
rotation so I'm to use the an outer world rotation and we can do that right after our go kart.
We've created a rotation Delta so add actor world rotation and then we add in the rotation delta that
we have just created and that should pretty much do the trick.
Let's go ahead and build that make sure there's no build errors and test it out.
Okay so the build was successful Let's go over into unreel delete the actor I was playing around with
to show you how rotations work.
Let's go ahead and hit play.
And oh that's looking rather weird.
When I hit rotation we seem to be rotating far too quickly.
So whats going on there then.
Well remember that I said the number of the degrees.
Basically the rotation angle that we take in here is in radians.
And what weve given is the max degrees per second so we actually had to convert that into radians.
Don't worry.
It's very easy.
There is an F maths function just for doing that called F maths and then is going to be.
Degrees to radians and that will allow us to convert between the two formats essentially of an angle.
The difference is that radians are what one couple of raly and basically has a whole circle of rotation
where as the degrees are as we know 360.
So it was rotating incredibly quickly.
Let's go and update that code and see it work with radians rather than degrees.
By the way a full rotation in a circle is to pi radians.
Okay so no problem with that bill.
Let's go ahead and stop the game and hit play again.
Now when I rotate you can see we're getting a much more sensible one to a 90 degree every second of
rotation which is a pretty decent staring rate.
Obviously it would dry steering in a very bizarre way here without applying any acceleration.
So if I accelerate myself forward you'll notice that as I turn I keep going in the direction I was going
which kind of leads to a very strange way of driving.
So what we actually need to have here is basically complete slippage is what's going on here.
But what we need to do as a basic approximation which feels about right is we are going to have to rotate
our velocity vector with the nose of our vehicle so as we rotate our vehicle we need to also rotate
the velocity vector.
So that's going to be your challenge actually is pretty straightforward so you're rotating the velocity
vector reads the quat documentation to see what functions you need to help you help update the velocity
as we want and test it and see whether it feels right based on updating it and then refactor.
So pause video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
So if we go into the documentation for what.
What is it that we are looking for.
I'm going to go to the ATF quat documentation then the function that we're looking for is actually called
very helpfully rotate a vector I believe or let's see vector.
I say just search of extern somewhere in here.
I will have.
Yeah.
Rotate vector.
That's the one we're looking for.
So very simply what we need to do is get an F quality is our rotation Delta.
And do a rotate vector taking in our velocity.
And the outputs of that is going to be an F vector which we can set at velocity 2.
So based on that rotation we have just rotated our vector by exactly the same amount as we have rotated
our our car which should give us a good effect.
Now what I'm going to go ahead and do now is refactored some of this.
So all this section which is talking about rotation.
I'm going to refactor right into its own method using Visual Studio refactored function so extract function.
I'm just going to call it apply a rotation that's go ahead and refactor that out below this function.
Okay.
Looking good.
So let's go into the head of file make sure that it's in the right place because it obviously isn't.
It's gone and put itself in the public section which we don't want.
I'm going to put it right above our update location from velocity in the head a file and I can go ahead
and save the C++.
Now ATIC is looking fairly clean.
We've got an apply rotation function going to go ahead and build and test it out.
Okay well the build at least the successful.
Let's go and test it in the editor.
Let me go ahead and play.
If we are rotating You can see that as we rotate the velocity is rotating with us which means that we're
able to do what we usually would do in a car which is use the steering to rotate around the obstacles
so it's starting to feel like a good sensible car now.
The only problem is that once we've accelerated We never decelerate because there's no sort of resistance
no rolling resistance no no air resistance.
Both of which basically mean well no air resistance means that we'd have no top speed.
We just keep accelerating until we hit something and no rolling resistance means that we don't just
start rolling to a stop which doesn't feel right either.
We're going to be looking at those two types of resistance as resistance.
In the next few video so I will see you in.