Welcome in this lecture we are going to be making our autonomous proxy smooth again.
So here you can see that I'm driving around very smoothly.
But no matter what I do with all this slaloming and I've already been playing for a little while the
location here that I'm seeing is the same location that we're seeing over on the server.
But without having a horrible liking say a little bit of glitching and that's we're going to talk about
why that's the case but we're going to figure out how we can make sure that we are simulating between
getting our server updates So let's dive in and see how it works.
So we can see that the issue right now is that our Thomas proxy is coming across a little bit jittery
basically and we want to find out why and we want to find out how to fix it so let's take a little bit
of a deep dive on to property replication.
So here are two timelines for the server and the client.
Now what happens with property replication is that we regularly check on the server whether a particular
property has changed.
So we do a check if nothing has changed we do nothing to another check.
Nothing's changed nothing happens.
But if we have a change something denoted by this orange arrow then we get a different kind of check
that check says hey something has changed and we need to do something about it.
What we do about it is that we send an update to all the clients to for them to update their replicated
property and they will set it to whatever the server just saw the update.
Now this does happen on a kind of fixed or update interval.
So he you can see we kind of had a regular interval here and thats what carries on you keep getting
these regular intervals and if you update comes somewhere between the interval.
Well it has to wait until the next check and if the next check come through then thats when it gets
updated on the client.
So it would be useful for us is to actually know when that update has come through rather than just
reading the property every tick actually knowing when it has changed and getting some events from that
change.
Now that is possible in unreel and this does mean that between these events which could be fairly infrequent
depending on the network update time then you should be simulating to give a smooth experience to the
user.
So the first thing is that network update time we actually set it can we stress test that network update
time and make it really bad so that we have to do a good job.
Well yes we can.
And if you go to the documentation which you should be able to find its also linked in the resources
you can go and look for the next update frequency as it's called.
It's this float here that you can set on the actor.
And as it says in the documentation it's how often per second this actor will be considered for replication.
So that's what we want to do.
We want a set and Net update frequency to make it really bad let's go in to the go kart.
So unusual to be trying to make our game worse but it's the stress test it and make it better.
So were going to go into begin play go and do an IF has authority.
And if we have authority then we're going to go ahead and set this Net update frequency.
Now remember it's for frequency not a time that's not the time of the interval but how many times per
second we want to update.
I'm just going to for one which is going to be basically small I can make it I'm going to go ahead and.
Build.
So we'll try to make it as small as possible because then the time between will be as large as possible
we're going to have 1 second between each update and that's going to make it look really horrible and
we're going to do the best we can to ensure we're simulating in the gaps between the updates from the.
So that has succeeded to build Let's go over to and real and hit play and see it in action.
Except we haven't spawned Probably so Let's escape go and play again.
So the spawning issue does still crop up we'll look up into it a bit more hopefully.
But if you go and drive your car now with that now update you can see that it's working fine on the
server.
In fact from the server I can drive it fairly effectively but from the client my word the update once
a second is clearly not enough for a driving game.
So we're going to need to be able to simulate much much better locally.
So to do that we need to know how we can get those notifications and we get the notifications.
Well there is a.
Parameter for our you property and it is called replicated use.
But as you can see the documentation here is rather rather scarse.
So I'm going to take you through very simply what it is you need to do with that.
Leaving that page hopefully.
So let's go over in to Visual Studio.
We're going to go to our head of file and hear here we've got our replicated location.
We are going to switch out replicated for.
Replicate using which is what it's called.
In fact replicated using make sure that's correct.
And then we need to have a function to give it own going to declare a function that's going to be void
and it's going to be on rep as the prefix to it unwrap underscore and then I'm just going to use the
name of the property that is triggering for which is replicated location.
OK.
So not taking any arguments is not returning anything because all it is it's a trigger saying yet that
property has been updated and that's what we're going to pass in to you property.
Now if you build it now you'll see that there is an issue and that is that this function needs to be
a new function for it to be called as an event for our note basically being a replication notification.
So getting ahead and build that and going to actually go ahead and implement it is going to give us
a warning at the moment that it's not influenza's So I'm going to go over in to the C plus plus now
it's going to be used for overriding what's happening ticks I'm going to put it near.
Just to show that they are related and I'm going to use it to log out so we don't have any log function
here that I can copy for for speed for brevity.
So what I'm going to actually have to do is write a long list from scratch you e log.
I understand then it's going to be log temp warning.
Not waning.
And it's going to be text and it's going to say replicated location so we to see what that actually
goes ahead and does going go ahead build it and see.
Got one error at the moment let's go to an output log and see what that is it's saying unresolved externals.
That'll be because in my C++ I've forgotten to name space.
Oh dear.
So we're doing a cart kilgallen should do the trick.
Sure enough that builds So let's go over into the I was.
And I hit play and all I can see is that in the log at the bottom Currently there is only two replicated
locations coming through is probably the initial ones.
But if I give some input then you can see that roughly once a second we are getting some replicated
locations coming through and to our car will come to a stop at which point there will be no update to
the location so it will stop replicating the location.
Okay.
So that's how we replicate location.
What about the next bit how do we actually go ahead and do the simulation between the old days.
Well actually you're going to figure that out.
You're going to simulate between updates.
So first thing is I personally think that we need to replicate the transform for simplicity.
So rather than doing this separate location and rotation I'm going to refactor towards just using the
transform.
You can choose to do that or not to then I'd like you to ensure that you're simulating locally and in
order to do that you going to need to make sure that you only overwrite when there is an update rather
than every tick.
So pause a video and see if you can figure this out.
Okay welcome back.
So let's dive in and give it our best shot.
So what we're trying to do is simulate between updates.
I'm going to do.
First of all this refactor towards the transform.
So everywhere where we currently have a replicated location I'm going to refactor towards replicated
transform instead.
So of got replicated location going for replicated transform where the Find Replace in file.
Let's go ahead and replace all those.
Done all that in the head a file that's go ahead and do the same thing in the C++ file.
Replace all of them.
And that should pretty much do the trick.
Except now we want to get rid of our replicated rotation.
Don't need that anymore.
And replace the F vector for everybody kids transform with obviously an F transform instead.
Okay.
So we're going to have to go in and change where we are doing over writing because we're currently getting
the actor location which he wants to get.
Actor transform instead an semicolon.
And we're going to do a set.
Actor Transformers set a location.
And we were need to do anything with the rotation now.
So that's really simplifying things down a little bit.
And we're going to have to remove our replicator rotation from the end get lifetime replicated props.
So let's build that and see if it's still working as it was before.
So just a couple of errors here due to my spelling mistakes it seems that talking about get out transform
is undefined.
And I think that's just because I've misspelt transform so I can go ahead and build it again.
So it looks like there's just one more misspelling of transform in here.
Sorry about that.
Look go ahead and build it one more time.
I guess that's an advantage of a blueprint isn't it.
Fewer misspellings So let's go ahead and play.
See it's still working with the update on the transform.
So I'll go in to my all my autonomous proxy window client one and move around.
Yes I still get the rotation yes.
The position start dates.
So that is working just fine.
So we want to make sure that we are only updating or only overwriting when we are getting this rep replication
notification.
Now this replication notification will only come through on the client so we dont have to check that
we are the client or we got to do is over write the transform.
Whenever we get this on rep.
So thats what I'm going to do set the actor transform so we can get rid of this ELT's but we do still
need to set the replicator transform every frame when we are the server.
So that is pretty much it.
Because now you can see that if were not the server we are going to go ahead and update our location
and velocity from our own knowledge of it and only when we get data from the server we're going to overwrite
that asset actor transform.
So that builds succeeded.
Let's actually see whether it's going to work.
I'm going to go ahead and play and I'm going to be the autonomous client and you can see I'm definitely
getting smooth movement here.
And if I am moving around the updates don't seem to be affecting me that very much.
I'm pretty much guessing exactly the right thing you can occasionally see it glitch just a tiny little
bit just a tiny bit of glitching but for the most part it is very very smooth.
And the simulation on the client isn't diverging enough from the server in that one second gap for us
to see a significant jump from service client.
So this is seems to be working absolutely fantastically really really good.
But there is a problem and the problem is going to be a concept called lag or latency and that is going
to be the subject of the next lecture we're going to see how we can simulate some lag in our game.
And we're going to see well initially what we can do to try and improve on that.