Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are one step closer in refactoring towards the goal of being able to replay and moves locally so
that we aren't skipping backwards in a laggy scenario.
And in this letter it's all about this method here that I got highlighted the simulate move method and
figure out how we can simulate a moon so that it's consistent both on the server and on the client.
Let's dive in and see how it's done.
So in the last letter we left a handful of tattoos in the C plus pass code.
So let's have a look and see if any of these jump out of it at us as the first thing that we could tackle.
So I've got the update.
The last move that's definitely something we're going to need to do make a better validation mode that
can wait that's just about cheating and you know in testing and making sure it works we don't need to
get quite there yet and we've got the set the time on the move again something that may be useful maybe
not yet.
What we're going to be doing now is the following We're going to be looking at the bit highlighted in
green on this slide of the pseudo code which is the simulate move.
Now you might be saying but Sam we're already simulating the move.
Yes we are but not quite.
We're simulating something with the same inputs as the move but it might end up being different because
the timestep is using the tick from that of the server.
So what we're going to want to do is pull out a new method which we are going to call simulate move
give it a signature implement it and call it from the server.
When we receive a move and call it on the client when we are first creating that move to simulate it
locally and later Ron will be using it.
Also when we are replaying the unacknowledged moves so this is going to be a very useful method indeed.
That's what the going to be laying the groundwork.
So let's go into the head file have a little think what should simulate move do simulate move on going
to put right the top of the privat functions.
And it's not going to return anything because it's simulating it on this actor going to be called simulate
move as already indicated.
And we are going to have to give it something.
What are we going to give it.
Well kind of seems obvious from the name doesn't it.
It should be a f go cart move.
Let me just copy that name from the struct And that's what we're going to pass to simulate mover the
go cart move called move and a semicolon.
So that is going to be.
The method that we want and I am going to go and stick it just let's see above the get air resistance.
After all the replication stuff and a tick.
And I'm going to implement.
Or give it at least the namespace of our go kart.
Now I'm not going to go ahead and implement it just yet.
But instead what I'm going to show you is how we are going to use it and you're going to be implementing
it a challenge.
So we're going to be using it to update the canonical States we're going to simulate the move and then
we're going to send the canonical state to the clients.
We know that this happens where on received move or in actual fact it's now called the server centre
move implementation.
And you can see that at the moment the way we are doing simulation is simply to set the throttles set
the steering for it which is not really what we want is it what we want to be doing instead is calling
assimulate move with the move that we just received.
Mike so and then after we have simulated the move we can update the canonical state so we can say that
our service state.
Like so dot last move is equal to the move that we just simulated because that's the last move that
was simulated and then is the service state DOT transform is just going to be equal to well actually
all this stuff that we currently got tick this stuff including the update last move so we can go ahead
and pull all of that out.
In fact it means we don't need this if statement with has authority any more simplifying a tick down
which is nice and we can stick that in to our implementation we're going to move to do we've got want
to do less now because we've set and move and that makes sense doesn't it.
We've got basically what it's saying here check that move is an idiot.
We're skipping that for now simulating the move using a function that youre going to have to implement
and sending the canonical States for clients including the transform the velocity and the last move
crucially that we had thats great because now that we have removed the necessity for having the throttle
and steering throw We dont need those to be replicated anymore so let's go to Don H and remove the replication
for that they're now being replicated entirely using the state the server state.
We do still need them there because they are a way of getting our input from where it's being used as
input to where it is being used in the tech.
So where it's being set to where it's being used in the tech.
Okay.
And we do want to go ahead and remove the replication on that throttle and steering throw we can go
ahead and build that.
Just to make sure it runs okay.
So builds which leads me to think that all the reds quigley's that were there are just there because
the built system and quite caught up.
So obviously this isn't going to work yet because we need to implement the simulate move.
And that's going to be your challenge to implement simulate and move.
So you're going to put out a tick basically you can pull most of the code that's already existing in
tick because we're not doing anything new here.
We know how to simulate moots but were going to have to change a few things like where will you get
the input data and where will you get the data.
Time to have a think about these things and go ahead and implement simulate move both video and have
a go.
Okay welcome back.
Let's dive into doing this simulation.
So as I said Tich is going to be our source of inspiration.
We've got a move here from is locally controlled and we've got all this stuff that we are currently
doing there including drawing a debug string which I think we can get rid of at this stage.
We don't need the authority in knowing whether it's authority or not.
Actually we can just leave it.
We can just leave it in tic.
Certainly not to do with simulating a movie so we can leave that.
How about dating a location for a lost.
Yes.
Apply rotation.
Also to do with a move velocity updating the velocity.
Yes.
Also to do with updating the state due to a move.
Acceleration yes force yes yes yes.
All these lines from the line 70 down to 81 on my screen are the simulation of a move.
So I'm going to go and cut these out and stick them in my simulate move function.
Now you'll notice we will get some reds quigley's in here because of Delta time.
But that's not the first thing I'm going to tackle.
Why I'm first going to tackle is where do I get the input data.
Because I don't want to just get the input data from the actor.
That's maybe not correct especially if we're not being locally controlled.
No what we want to get it from is the move that's been passed in.
We want to know exactly the throttle data of this move at this time start with its delta time.
So were going to replace throttle with Move throttle.
What about the moved or steering throw.
Well that's actually buried unfortunately somewhere inside apply rotation so if we go to apply rotations
implementation you can see that it has a steering throw in here and it's just reaching up to the actor
to get that.
Well what we can do is we can expose that in as a parameter in Apply rotation so let's go up to the
definition of apply rotation where it has it takes a flow time it's going to take a float steering throw.
And if I copy that in to the signature in the implementation as well then everything will be hunky dory
and that steering throw is going to change colour hopefully to be grey on your studio which indicates
that it's a local variable rather than a variable up at the level of this act.
Okay so that's all good.
We've got a ply rotation should now be pretty pretty good.
We need to pass in to apply rotation obviously the throat.
So we're going to do a move dot steering throw to pass it the correct steering throw in into apply rotation.
So now all that data about input is coming in through the move and not directly from the act.
Very useful if we're not actually locally controlled.
Then where will we get the delta time that's the red squiggly.
I was telling you about well we're also going to get that from the move because remember we want it
to be simulated in exactly the same way.
And that requires that the errors are going to have to be the same the errors of integration.
We know that's what we're doing here is a new map of integration we're not worried too much about having
some small errors as long as they're not too visually visible.
But we are worried about having different results on client server so we're sending the time step for
this move.
And we must make sure that we use the time step when Reece simulating it so that we get exactly the
same result.
So that's what I've done.
I've gone and put moved the time in front of all the references to Delta time in assimulate move in
knacker's check that we don't have time anywhere else.
I don't think so because they're all being passed in this argument anyway which was a clever move for
us.
Okay.
So simulate move is now pretty much implemented so let's go ahead and build make sure that we haven't
got any build errors and test it out.
Okay so the build was successful Let's hop on over into visual studio sorry into one real and hit play
and go and control our autonomous proxy that's driving around.
Now you'll notice that he is driving pretty smoothly on the server but the updates we're getting from
on the or Thomas proxy side are very laggy indeed.
The reason that they're laggy is because I've forgotten to call simulate when we are the controlling
autonomous proxy.
So here we've got in tic is locally controlled have gone ahead and created a move and we sent the move
to the server but we've forgotten to call simulate ourselves.
So we have to go simulate move with that particular move for the very astute among you you may have
noticed that I've just introduced a bug there because the server is locally controlled and so we are
calling simulate move multiple times on the server.
Not a great thing.
So this is going to be fixed in a later lecture.
The exact letter name is on the screen now fixed fixing a simulated proxy is where it's going to be
called.
So don't worry about the bug.
You can try and fix it yourself or you can wait till that lecture.
That should do the trick.
Just checking that it's also been called in send move.
Implementation of course that is that's why we are getting to see anything at all.
And if we go ahead and build that hopefully it will be running a lot smoother.
Build successful that's tried out hit play with the autonomous proxy side drive around.
Yes he's looking smooth now.
We're also able to see him moving on the server which is Happy Days.
Just check that we aren't losing our position.
No we seem to be in exactly the same position.
The only problem now is obviously a lag if we set our lag to very large then we're getting our usual
kind of resetting because we still haven't implemented our resetting queue and that's going to be the
work of next lecture.
So I will see you in that lecture.