Hello and welcome in this lecture.
Yet some more invisible changes I'm afraid still haven't been able to get rid of this lag.
But we're going to be doing it in the next lecture hopefully.
But we've got the say stage completely set at this point as you can see in the logs.
We've got this queue length that's being printed out and it's doing some interesting things.
We're going to be seeing what it's actually doing because it's going up it's going up and up from up
to about 100 and then suddenly resetting down to 15 not down to zero.
And it's going up again.
And this queue is basically the thing that is going to be making sure we're always as a client able
to stay ahead of the server even though it's sending us out of date updates with the lag situation.
And we're going to be figuring out basically how we can implement such a queue using a T array and how
we are going to make sure that queue doesn't grow unboundedly.
So let's dive in and have a look.
Okay so in last lecture we saw that we still have a problem with our lag by set my lag to one second
then go and accelerate away.
I'm getting lots of those resets which makes it incredibly frustrating and hard to control my car even
though I'm sending moves up to the server.
That's because the servers delay is meaning that I get reset to a move somewhere in the past.
No good.
We're going to have to implement this.
Now finally this means that we are getting on to the interesting bit of our pseudo code.
We're going to be looking at saving list of unacknowledged moves and removing all moves that are already
included in the state or tiding up that list of unacknowledged moves not only looking at replay just
yet that's going be the subject of the next lecture.
But we're going to be looking at making sure this queue of moves is in place.
So the first thing we'll do is ask ourselves what is this queue going to be made out.
What is it going to be.
Well the obvious answer for this is that we know that collections have objects in unreal typically are
best served with a T array.
Now there are other data structures available such as t.
Q You can try and use a T Q But you'll find that it's rather impoverished in terms of the methods available
to it.
Array is by far the most complete data structure and real supports for collections of objects so that's
what we're going to go for.
It's going to be the easiest one to use.
So let's go in to the header of our go cart and we're going to add in some data about this.
Now I'm going to add it right to the bottom because it is closer to being about the throttle and steering
throw than anything else.
Is data that is only being stored after all.
On the client.
So I am going to go ahead and create a T array with angle brackets of f.
Go cart move close angle brackets and then we are going to call this on a knowledged move like so and
end it with a semicolon.
Okay so unacknowledged moves is a T array of f a go cart move type So it's a list essentially if you
like or whatever.
So what is it.
We need to do with this data.
Well we're going to have to save to a list of unacknowledged moves.
So as we know we can use the t array.
And to do that if you don't know then do go and refresh your knowledge with this documentation page
all about teh arrays.
It's available in the links from this lecture but if you do know about it then you can follow along
with me.
So the array of ADD is what we're going to be looking for as go into AC plus plus and find where this
is happening.
In fact this forecast pseudocode says on tick.
Create a new move and then save a list save to the list.
Well that knowledge moves.
So if we follow that then we can see that in Tich we've got this is locally controlled and a half.
This is where it's getting a little bit complicated here.
The creation of the move is a multi line process.
So what I actually want to do is go ahead and extract this out.
I'm going to go right click quick actions you can do this manually of course and extract a function
and it won't let me extract function so I'm going to create it myself.
And I am going to create it.
Let's see just below simulate.
Move.
That's kind of the order it's happening in.
It's going to return f.
Go cart move.
I'm going to create call it create move like so and I'm going to go ahead and implement it in the C++
file.
Do right above right below simulate move.
So.
And then I am going to implement its body and give it a namespace to the class.
And what are we going to do in that belt we're going to just do this bit of code.
Basically I'm going to cut that and instantly write its replacement which is going to be an F go cart
move.
Move is equal to create move.
Like so cake and then create move.
It's going to do that and at the end of it return the move.
By that I mean the thing that I just copied paste it now.
You'll notice that it doesn't have a delta time so we're going to have to pass that in as an argument.
So let's go up to the head of file and do float.
Delta type and copy that over in to the C++.
I've got a create move.
They go delf times out there and we can pass delta time in that tick.
And that's all hunky dory.
Okay so now is just a little bit of tidying that we were doing to be able to add what they see then
have our code look exactly like the footsteps of our pseudo code.
So let's go ahead and add to the unacknowledged moves.
So going to have an acknowledged moves dot add.
Move out with adaran move into the list of on acknowledge moves later to be tidied up.
But why do we need to tidy it up at all.
Well that is what we're going to be finding out.
Let's print the Q length just as a debug thing so Im going to do a eui underscore log log temp warning.
And its going to have the text queue length and it is going to take an argument to that which is going
to be a decimal so percent.
And were going to get the length of the acknowledged.
Do you remember how to do this.
You can have a look in the documentation if you dont acknowledged moves Dot and I believe its going
to be numb which is a method.
So were going to call it with the brackets.
Then semicha on the end of the line go ahead and build it.
And lets see when we play whats going to happen this queue length is are going to keep growing and growing
and growing.
And if so what can we do about it.
Well the good sign is that the build has succeeded Let's go over into one real hit play and go over
to our autonomous proxy in fact we don't even have to do anything.
We can already see that in the logs AQ length is just growing and growing with every sextus subsequent
tick which is no good.
Eventually we will run out of memory so we need to make sure that that Q is going to be properly pruned
down to just the difference between what the server has seen and what we have created locally.
Thats the whole point of this kit.
So its going to be your challenge to prune the queue.
So right they clear acknowledged moves methot that's going to be basically the main work.
This challenge is going to be called from on rep server States and forget to do that and use the trv
documentation to help you in terms of what levers you have to pull around a teaser rate and think about
this question thats kind of a central question and what makes a move stale.
And see how you can update the T array to remove the things that are stale and keep the things that
are not stale because of Theyll have a go.
Okay.
Welcome back.
So the approach Im going to take.
Well actually first of all let's just go ahead and create the signature for clearing the moves.
I'm going to do it right after create move so we keep things more licence in place.
It's going to be void and it's going to be clear acknowledged moves clear.
Knowledged.
What's it going to take.
That's a very good question.
Well think about that in just a second.
So I won't put it in there just yet.
But actually I will.
I think what we need to have is it takes the last move.
So that's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to do an F. go cart move.
Last move and that's going to tell us whether moves older than this move or including this move or actually
stale.
So I'm going to go ahead and implement this now going over into the C++.
Let's go and find a good place to do this and do it right after create move.
I'm going to have a clear acknowledge moves give it body give it a class name space.
And then we've got this last move.
Okay.
So what we going to do in here.
Well my basic premise is going to be that we're going to build a new t array.
I think there's going to be just the easiest way it may not be the most efficient way although I think
it might also be the most efficient way.
But the thing is it's quite simple.
So what we can do is we can iterate through the current array we can check which ones are stale and
which ones are current and we can populate the new T race so it's going to be fairly straightforward
so we're going to do a TI array of F go cart moves new Let's see new moves is what I'm going to call
it.
And then we can do a simple for loop.
So I'm going to do a full loop over the unacknowledged moves and it's going to be a bunch of constant
moves.
Let's see if go cart moves the type.
They're going to be references so I don't have to copy them around all the time and I'm putting cots
in front because I don't want to edit them.
I don't want to be able to edit them and I'm going to be taking iterating.
The UN acknowledged moves array which we can just do like this handly with the T arrays.
Great.
So we've got four loop we've got a full body we've got the move the last move.
Got a new moves array we're iterating at for it.
Fantastic.
So we've got these moves how are we going to check if they are valid.
Well you've guessed it.
It is about that time that we haven't yet set.
So what we want to do is be able to differentiate between these things based on the time at which they
were created.
Well actually this is going to be fairly easy to replace this to do in create move.
Now we're just going to move dot.
Time is equal to and remember that time is available on the Get world.
So on the world it's got time.
So we're going to just search for what things are available for time and there's time.
Seconds is the one we want.
There are a few different types of time but time seconds is one we want because that's pause and the
game is paused it's dilatant clamped and so on and so forth.
It's basically the game simulation time.
So we are going to go ahead and set the time stamp from the head.
So we've got a time in our move and it is constantly incremental.
So if it's constantly incrementing that means anything that is less than or equal to the time of the
last move is now stale so we only want to put new moves in new moves the ones that are greater than
the last moves time.
That's very straightforward.
Do an if statement that says that the move dot time is greater than the last move time.
Then we can take a copy of this move and we can add it in two new moves.
So there are new moves to add and we're going add that move.
So and then at the end of this method we need to not forget who we want to replace our t array with
this new moves hit rate.
So what we're going to do we're going to say that the unacknowledged moves on now the new moves like
so that should pretty much do the trick.
So all we have to do now is make sure we clear acknowledged moves.
Where do we say we're going to do it from Let's Go and have a look it says on reps for state which is
basically when we receive the new state from the server so it will find our on rep wears out on rep
hears on reps of state.
We are overwriting our service state as it is.
And then what we want to do is after we've over in that state we want to clear the acknowledged moves
with the server.
State.
Dot last move as the argument so that it knows which was the last move applied and we can clear all
the unacknowledged move.
Let's go ahead and build this play it see if the queue length is now going to be keeping to a manageable
amount.
Okay.
So build succeeded.
Let's give it a play.
Go and play and if we go and have a look at our log.
It does seem to be growing constantly.
But this actually might be because we have had the authority only and it looks like the client hasn't
spawned.
But that still seems to be a problem.
Maybe there is a problem there let's go ahead hit play again.
Now what we're seeing here is something like differently in the logs we go and quit and have a look
at what happened in the logs.
We've got two sets of queue length.
One is happening on the server.
One is happening on the client.
Okay so that has revealed a little bug what we have got.
Here's the we're adding move to the queue even if we are the server obviously with the server.
We don't need to be adding things to the queue.
So let's just make sure that we do it.
And we want to basically say we don't have authority.
So if not has authority then we're going to be adding to the queue.
Otherwise don't bother adding to the queue and don't bother printing out the queue either because we
don't need to go ahead and build.
Okay then give it another shot.
Hit Play.
Have a look at the law.
Let's go over to the ultimate proxy a little drive around we seem to be driving around Okay let's go
to the logs.
And sure enough here you can see that we are going from one up to about forty six and then resetting.
That is probably because we're getting an update once a second.
What happens if we had some land let's go and try to emulate some lag.
Go to our autonomous proxy and open up the console and do a packet lag of 1000 and quits after a little
bit of waiting and go and have a look at the queue lengths.
Okay so what's happening in these queue lengths.
You can see we are going all the way up to 100 and then we're resetting.
We're not resetting down to one you'll notice were resetting down to 50 which means that there have
been 50 moves since the servers update that came back to us.
So we're keeping this queue length ahead of the server which is exactly what we wanted.
If you go all the way back and have a look at your slides you remember that is there bitly dot com.
Let's have a look at your else.
Bitly because l y forwards slash multiplayer slide you can go and have a look at the old slides and
see make sure you understand why this queue length is being reset in this way from 100 down to 50 when
we have about a second of lag pause a video well then pause video actually that's the end of the video.
Our see you in the next lecture where we'll actually be restimulating these moves to make sure that
we aren't getting the resetting.
That is still present and I'll see you there.