Hello and welcome in this lecture.
I am going to be reviewing why we do refactoring and something called the red green refactored loop
and I'm going introduced to this website called refracting look through an excellent resource for knowing
what kind of refactored to do what kind of codes smells to recognize even a section on design patterns
to be going into that in this lecture.
So let's dive in and just recap how we do refactoring.
So as I mentioned in the last lecture this class is getting a bit too big and it's getting really hard
to figure out what we want to do now.
How do we get into this state.
You know we had some nice clean code when we started off clean code by the way is code that's easy to
read in easy to maintain and doesn't easily hide many bugs.
That's what we mean by clean code.
And it started off fairly simple.
You know we didn't have very much going on with justice and physics emulation it was all hunky dory.
Now why has it got a little bit out of control.
Well let me explain something to you called the refat the red green refactored process.
So typically the red greenery factor loop is referred to in that test driven development but it does
apply outside of test driven development as well.
It does apply to any situation where we have a list of requirements that we want to implement and a
process of verifying whether requirements exist.
In our case it's just manual testing.
We just come up with a new idea that we wanted to do something and then we implement it and we check
whether it works.
That's a sort of test drone development although it doesn't actually have any automatic tests which
means that unless you are very good and keep a list of requirements written down somewhere and every
time you make a change you run through to check those requirements all still work.
Then you may end up with something called a regression which is where you had something working and
then it stopped working.
But anyway that's a little bit on a side note.
So we start off having written some code and it's fairly clean it's fairly easy to understand.
Then what happens to it.
How do we end up with messy code.
Well we introduce a new requirement for a start so we might say okay we want our autonomous proxy to
move around without having to jump back.
In the case of lag so suddenly our nice clean and working code is no longer working it's red it is incorrect
it is failing a test which is that new requirement that it doesn't jump back because it does jump back.
So what do we do.
Well we try and think up a solution and we play around and we implement that solution we coded up hackitt
up and we implement it quick and dirty so we don't worry too much about how we're implanting it we don't
try to slow down because our solution might not even be right.
It might not even fix the bug.
They might not even fix the new requirement.
So we do have to do it fairly quick.
And so we end up with something that passes the test but it's messy and messy means it's going to be
hard to maintain.
Hard to add new features.
We've got something called technical debt which is basically the fact that we managed to do it quick
and dirty because it was clean.
But in the future we aren't going to be able to do it so quickly because it's not clean anymore.
So what happens after we've made it a bit messy.
Well hopefully we go ahead and refactor.
Now the more you miss this step out the more you don't reflect that after having implemented something
quick and dirty the more messy and messy your code gets and the harder it becomes to implement a fix
to things.
So that's why eventually and people end up having a really big refactored or just grinding to a halt
on projects because they don't know how they can proceed because their code is so hard they spend most
of the time reading and trying to understand Rick does and can't implement anything.
And if they try and implement anything it behaves in weird and wonderful ways.
So how do we know when it's time to refactor Well if we're struggling to write code or we're finding
that we're creating bugs when we do write code that's often a good sign that there's something wrong
and this something wrong is typically referred to in programming as a code smell.
So how do we spot these so-called code smells.
Well if you are very experienced then you will probably just have an intuition for them.
But if you're not as experienced then you might want to go and have a look at a reference of kind of
known codes smell's if you like.
And I really recommend this one is called refactoring dog guru and it's a very well put together website
and great for beginners.
If you are finding yourself stuck grinding to a halt and not being able to progress with your projects
then it might be your good deeds as a good idea to see if you've got any of these codes metals now.
The place I recommend you go is to the left pane to the section a site called refactoring sets.
Refactoring doggery affords laterally factoring and particularly we want to look at the section called
Code smells.
And here you have a whole long list of code smells.
Lots of them and they're grouped together depending on what they are like.
And you can go ahead and click on one of them and here it has a nice description of why they come into
being how you should treat them.
And.
Why.
You know they might not need anything doing to them do make sure you read all of that.
And then once you have read all of that you can have a look at what the treatments are and try and choose
the best treatment and these treatments are called Re factors in the terminology of refactored or Kuru
refactoring logorrhea.
And here it kind of in the refactor shows you again a summary of what the problem is.
But in more detail how you might solve it.
So for every code smell there's a couple of ways that you might need to solve it depending on your specific
case.
Now you'll notice this website also has a design pattern site and I know a lot of people get really
hooked up on design patterns and want to learn all the design patterns It's like Pokemon you got to
catch em all you got to know them all.
And it is very tempting.
I recommend if you are very tempted by design patterns go and read the.
What is the pattern section.
And under what is a pack pattern section.
There is a criticism section and this talks about reasons why design patterns are always a fantastic
idea why you shouldn't necessarily always use them.
Particularly I'm interested in that if you have a hammer in your hand things start to look like a nail
because if you appear especially as a beginner start to learn design patterns and you start to want
to apply them everywhere even when they're not applicable and they just make things more complicated
rather than what they're intended to do which is make them more simple.
But by all means you can read that section of the site as well.
That's just a word of caution.
So I'd like you to use this website to identify a suitable refactor for our specific code smell.
So if we go ahead and look at the challenge definition your challenge is going to be to plan the refactored
So first of all identify the codes as well.
Secondly choose a refactor And thirdly plan that refactored so by Identify the kossmann I mean go on
the website go and have a look through the refactoring codes Mel's section here.
And see which one you think most applies.
Maybe make a list of them if there's more than one and then choose a refactor from any one of those
small pages and have a look at which one of those three factors is probably best.
In our case and then go ahead and see what you can do about designing planning on paper at first.
What we're going to do in that refactored so pause the video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
So let's go ahead and identify what we think he is a suitable codes.
All the codes melet most matches in our case what I'm feeling like is that class is getting too big.
So there is a code smell here if you've had a little look through called large class that's what I'm
thinking here.
Get the large class and signs and symptoms.
A class containing many fields methods and lines of code.
So we've definitely got all three of those.
We've got 200 lines of code which isn't too bad but if you go and look at the header file and you can
see that we've got about 100 lines of head of file which means that we've got loads and loads of fields.
We've got loads of methods most of them private in fact not even public methods.
So this class is probably doing more than one thing as shown in this lovely illustration of it trying
to work out and do the hoovering and cook and phone and everything.
So reasons for the problem.
So usually we start off with a small class Yes we did we started off with an actor that was all we had
and it didn't do very much and we started to and slowly the physics simulation then we added also the
replication cone.
It was just easier to put it there because it had everything that we needed we have access to all the
methods that we needed.
It was just simpler very much in the same case as if you have a really long method that typically is
because it's just easier to add lines of code to an existing method than create a new one.
So how are we going to deal with it.
Well there's a few different ways you could pull out part of the behaviour as a smaller separate class
or is even calling a component here.
We could extract it in to a subclass so we could create a class that derives data from this and specializes
it.
We can extract an interface so that the list of if we had lots of public operations that serve for different
purposes like we did with our game instance then different interfaces might be able to access in different
ways.
That just simplifies the public interface.
If we've got too many public classes and then there is a special case for UI so that's not particularly
interesting to us.
And it says the pay off for refactoring these large classes spares the developers from needing to remember
a large number of attributes for a class.
And in many cases putting a lot of assets into parts avoids duplication of code and functionality.
Case I've just read it to you.
But basically the refactor the treatment that we want is the extract class we want to take a big class
and split it off in to a smaller class and in real the typical way of doing this at least from an actor
into smaller bits is to use components so let's go ahead and plan our refactor for extracting out classes
from big act class.
So typically the principle that applies here in Sutter engineering is called the single responsibility
principle that a class should be responsible for.
Just one thing and not more than that.
So what we're going to do is we are going to have a go cart actor and what is our go cart actor going
to be responsible for.
Well basically what it's.
What it needs to be responsible for which is binding input binding We can't do input binding anywhere
else so maybe we could do it on the player controller.
But here in the go cart actor is a good enough place so we're going to leave input binding there.
But it is going to need to have a new component a component a movement component very much like we've
seen with characters and porns and the responsibility for the movement campaign is going to be simulating
physics in fact simulating movement.
We're going to be able to give it things like throttle's and so on and it is going to have to be able
to move the actor around in the world according to the movement rules of our game.
Now obviously that's not enough because we've got a network element to our game so it's this go kart
component is going to need gokul actor rather is going to need another component for replication so
a replication component we'll call it and its responsibility is going to be replicating movement exclusively
only movement and it is going to need to have direct access to the Movent component so that it can get
properties of it.
Mike what was the last move you did.
Go ahead and simulate this thing for me.
Because I'm a simulated proxy for example.
So it's going to need to have access to reading from and also driving the movement component.
But the moving component should work in single player as well so you want to make sure that if we didn't
add a replication component on to the actor the movement component is going to work just fine you'll
be able to drive around and so on.
Okay so this is the plan.
This is what can be achieving in the next couple of lectures and hopefully we'll end up with a product
that is going to be much much easier to understand and will be able to implement interpellation on top
of it.
Okay.
Let's dive in in the next couple lectures.