Hello and welcome in the show.
We are going to make it possible to disable the movement replicator component completely comment it
out as if we were if it never existed if we commented out that movement replicator then make it possible
that our go kart is still able to move even though that movement replicator is commented out and remove
that comment because I don't have it uncommented at the beginning of video and neither will you.
So let's dive in and see how we can make it so.
The movement still happens even without a replicator at least in single player.
So this is the set up we have at the moment.
Right.
Well if this were the case what happens if we disable the replicator.
Well everything should work just fine because we've got a movement component we should still be able
to move around.
It just won't replicate in multiplayer.
So let's go ahead and give that a shot if we go to the unreal editor and we are going to as you just
do this in blue prints going against the Graser can't folden the blueprint go opened the BP go cart.
And with this BP go cart going to move into the main editor and I'm going to go to the movement replicator
an ongoing to try and deactivate this or even remove it if I can can I remove it.
Do I am might not be able to remove it.
So what we can do instead is that we can just not create it in the first place so we won't have a movement
replicator.
And I believe that I'll be okay I don't think we actually refer to the movement replicator anywhere
and we should check it for now any.
No we don't refer to the moving replicator anyway so we're going to go ahead and build that without
a movement replicator and man should work just fine right according to our dependency.
Because the loop Remicade depends on the movement component.
So if we remove the movement component and had a replicator obviously nothing's gonna work because what
is it going to replicate.
But if we do it this other way round everything should work it just will disable the replication feature
at least that's what my architectural diagram is telling me.
OK so let's give it a go.
Head over in to the map.
An obscure sport.
One player in the Selecta viewport and have a guy driving around.
So nothing works so clearly there is some hidden dependency going from the movement component replication
component and that hidden dependency is if we go and look at our code that in the movement replicator
we rely on.
So as a sort of dependency we rely on our create move and simulate move being called from the movement
replicator that's not any sort of dependency other than a kind of runtime dependency depending on being
called.
And we'd rather not have to depend on that.
We'd rather do that stuff in our own tick component.
So why aren't we doing that.
Well let's have a look.
Seems to be because we need to use the move to add it to an unacknowledged move.
Q We also need to use the move to.
Well that's pretty much it to send up to the server that's the other thing we need to do.
So we're going to need to basically strip some of that back and allow our Movent component to work by
itself essentially removing this dependency here.
So let's go ahead and try that out by allowing the movement component to tick or at least tick properly.
Already ticks we've got a moving component cbp which has got in it a tick component which we did not
remove explicitly because I knew we were going to have to do this and if we wanted this to move then
it very simply.
All we've got to do is take these two lines of code the create move and assimilate move and move those
in2 or copy them into our tic function.
That should be sufficient to get as moving now because we're in the mood component we don't actually
have to use a pointer.
That's even easier can just use create move and simulate move which are local functions to this object.
And we'll have to think about how we're going to make the movement replicate a work again.
But first let's take that as a first step.
I'm going to build it and see if we can move our couch around.
Now just using that Moven component that builds succeeded.
Let's have a go at driving around or restart game play.
And yes sure enough I can move my authority around just fine but we've got no replication.
So if I go and increase the number of players and hit play.
And then I will move round as the authority.
But as the character and the autonomous proxy I'm going to see it jumping around if I move randers the
autonomous proxy it's even worse because I will go and see it from the authorities point of view that
that car has been moved because there's no replication up to the server in the first place.
So I'm going to actually challenge you to make replication work again and get all the information you
need to replicate.
In this challenge so we're going to make the replication work.
So you can expose the last move that was made from the movement component using a geter replace the
simulating code in replicator to use that last move and not do the simulating itself.
You're going to change server send move.
Because that does some simulating for us and we need to change that when we're simulating on the server.
You all need to.
Will you be able to make some new methods private here then maybe now some methods that you don't need
to access.
And finally when Shouldn't the Movent component simulate.
There are some instances some places some machines on which it shouldn't be simulating and we should
rely on the replicator to be doing the movement.
So pause a video and have a go at making this replication work again.
Okay welcome back.
I'm going to start with the last question when Shouldn't the M.C. simulate.
Well basically if we have a look at attic in the replicators that go to represent C++ in are already
there and have a look at where we're currently simulating we are simulating at least we are creating
and simulating a move where we are doing it when we are in control of the porn.
In which case and we are the authority we are doing it here we're getting creating the move and sending
the move to the server.
And we are also doing it when we are the autonomous proxy.
Well here's the thing to note that we've got a bit of redundancy in an IF statement here this get on
a roll.
Equals authority and get remote role equals simulated proxy.
Well actually if I get rolls is remote roll is a simulated proxy.
Then we know already that the role will be authority so we can actually go ahead and remove the first
part of this statement but only to say Authority and remote role simulator proxy we can just say that
the remote role is the simulated proxy which means that in our movement component we can do our Get
on a roll.
Autonomous proxy.
So let's go over to the moon component and wrap the simulation in if statements it's going to.
If.
We are an autonomous proxy or in this case.
We are.
We have a remote role of simulated proxy.
Then we can go ahead and execute the simulation code.
Here on this machine Otherwise we are just not going to execute.
Which would be the case if we are the simulated proxy or if we are the server and there is an autonomous
proxy on the other side.
So that seems fairly straightforward.
Let's go back over to the C++ and I have actually cut out that statement.
I don't think I intended to cut out the statement.
So let's pull it back.
So we got the autonomous proxy you've got the simulated proxy.
That's all good.
Now what we need to do next according to the challenge is we need to replace the simulating code in
the replicator and we need to explode it explode.
Expose the last move.
So we've got this move here which is just a local move to the tick.
We need to make that into a last move.
And that's going to be a property at the moon component level.
So the cut to the Movent component and create our selves and F go cart move field which is going to
be called last move and we're going create an excess for that.
It's just going to be for reading.
You're not going to be able to set the last move so it's going to be a read only property essentially.
So we're going to do it returning echo can't move and it's going to be a get last move.
No arguments and all it has to do is return the last move.
See I'm just define this in line like we've done with all our other getters because it actually makes
them easier to read in some senses until they get to be doing more stuff than just this.
So we're going do a Get last move then were going to go into the replicator C++ and instead of simulating
the move as we're doing for the autonomous proxy creating the moving simulating the move what we're
going to do instead is we are just going to add the get last move from the movement components we do
move in component arrow get last move it's pacing in the wrong place get that move brackets and that
will basically do what we need to get the last move send it up to the server and add it to the unacknowledged
move.
Q Okay so that's working just fine or looks like it will work just fine.
However in the role remote role simulated proxy we have a slightly different issue here.
The problem is that we are using server send move to simulate.
But also if we go for go to it go find it.
No we have got to go into C++ and find it in the implementation service and move implementation.
You can see that we are using it because it is able to simulate the move and then update the state.
These are actually two separate things.
So what we could do instead of calling server send move is we could remove that altogether let it do
the simulation essentially and just update the slate.
So update server status which we don't have a function for yet but I'm going to create to go over to
the replicator dot H and we will create a private function for this.
I'll put it just at a clear acknowledged moves going to be void update server state.
Not take any arguments because it just has side effects and this updates overstate.
What are we going to do with it.
We are going to create a function for our day so state and going to stick it actually.
Where am I going to put it.
Maybe I'll just stick it after take.
And it's going to return void which we already know it's going to have the name space.
You go cart movement replicator.
And it is going to be called data a state with no arguments and a body and the body is going to do exactly
what happens at the end of send move implementation then cut that out.
Everything that updates the service state and replace it with a call to update server state instead.
So we've removed the code duplication but we have.
Allowed us to.
Call it.
In tick and you'll see we don't even take the move.
The update service state as you'll see here.
In fact that is a bit of a problem.
It does need to take the move.
Move is an argument that gets passed in here.
So let's go up to the movement replicator dot H.
And we're going to take a move.
A data service state with.
But this move can actually be a constant reference because we do not need to be editing it.
And we do not need to be copying it around because we're not really taking a copy sivers can't date
that so that we have the right move in place and that means that we need to get hold of the last move.
And now you can see we're doing this the referencing of get last move a few too many times in my opinion.
So let's go ahead and do a f and go cart move.
And call it the last move.
Going to just do this outside the IF statements so that we have access to inside all of our statements
and going to replace that with all the blast moves around the place.
So that do the trick now are doing update state with the last move in our Send Moven implementation
we need to pass in the move that was received for updating the service state.
Okay hunky dory.
That seems like it's going to hopefully at this point compile and hopefully even more.
Hopefully it's going to actually work.
K so we've got a little bit of a build area let's have a look at what that's saying.
So it's an error to do with assimulate move cannot convert argument one.
Ah I see the problem here is that we haven't renamed.
Simulate glacier move.
So last move simulate move should simulate the last move and we didn't do that.
So let's build that again.
Okay.
So this time it built successfully.
Let's just check that it's still working.
I'm going to play in the new editor window and I'm going to put it on as proxy on the right and the
authority hopefully on the left.
Let's move the authority around Kate.
That seems to be replicating successfully.
How about I'm sorry I haven't actually read enabled the replication components.
That was just replicating by the slow method and by the fact that the movement not the movement but
the position was being replicated by the actor.
So if we go into the C++ go cart see passed bosson re-enable and movement replicator that would give
us a better indication.
Kate let's try that one more time.
Hit Play.
Put the authority on the left.
The autonomous proxy on the right.
And let's actually drive the autonomous proxy because that's going to be the hard thing to get.
Right.
Okay.
So the autonomous proxy isn't driving which is telling us something might be wrong.
On the whole.
So the reason for that was actually because my go cart needed my blueprint go cart blueprint needed
compiling and saving and if you did that funnily enough and go and play again then we've got control
of the authority and if it drives in front of the autonomous proxy Let's go and do that we can see it
and we can see the replication stuff happening.
What if the autonomous proxy drives in front of the authority.
Well so far it's driving okay yeah it drives nice and smoothly in front of the authority so the code
was correct just we needed to recompile the blueprint of how close that blueprint cause it was being
a little bit having it open sometimes creates problems as we just saw in refresh in the code.
So the final question from the challenge was can we make some methods private Now let's have a look
if we go over to visual studio.
Have we removed any calls that we previously had.
I believe we have removed the call to create move.
So if I go and take and create a signature which was previously public I think I can now move this into
the private section of go kart movement component and hit build and that shouldn't change anything now.
We aren't able to create moves from the outside but instead we're able just to observe the moves that
have happened on the go cart movement component.
Isn't that neat and excellent.
Sure enough that has worked.
So congratulations.
We've now got to thoroughly decoupled Movent component and Movent replicator and a very lightweight
actor.
And I'll see you in the next lecture where we're now free to go ahead and implement that client interpellation.
I was talking about some three lectures ago.