Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be looking at more linear interpolation this time we're going to be doing linear interpolation
for rotation also known as slurping.
So it's rude to slurp but not when you're doing it for interpellation.
And here is the results.
You can see it's not perfect but it's certainly looking a lot better than it was before and looks worse
when we're moving faster but when we are moving slowly it looks quite good.
So we're going to be investigating what when this is appropriate to do it in this situation and what
alternatives there might be.
But we're going to figure out how we can do this.
Interpolating over rotation in this lecture.
So let's dive in and find out.
It's all in the last lecture.
How rotation is a missing piece in this linear interpolation puzzle.
That's what we're going to try in fix.
So the first thing we need to understand here is the difference between slurping and learning one sounds
like you've got a limp.
And the other one sounds like you're eating your spaghetti rather noisily.
So the idea of the spaghetti slurping or is that what we are doing a linear interpolation but it's a
spherical linear interpolation and why do you need that.
I he ask let's.
So he on this slide we have got ourselves a pawn or something which is orientated along this arrow.
So the Green Arrow is kind of the forward arrow of the pawn.
And we can say that its initial rotation is this rotation a minus 100 degrees for example I don't know
where this exactly minus 100 degrees but it's good enough.
So basically what we're saying is that the arrow is pointing at this point over here rotated away from
the forward direction and the rotation that we want is positive 90 degrees.
So very much like our Lerp we have an A in A B that we want to interpolate between.
So why can't we just use a slurp on this.
Well part of the reason there is more to it is that if we want to do this Lerp between these two rotations
the logical way that you and I would try and draw an interpolation is like this.
Going from in this case from point B to point A.
But it could be the other way round just as well.
And that thought was going to happen with a loop.
This is what's going to happen with a lap.
It's going to want to go round the other way.
Now can you think of why that might be.
Just have a little thing for yourself.
The reason for this is that nothing about a linear interpolation tells it that a circle wraps around
at 180 degrees.
That is something completely away from those numbers.
So as far as the Lerp is concerned the shortest route from A to B has got to be through zero right.
It's not through 180 and then minus 1 80.
That doesn't make any sense but it does if we use a spherical linear interpolation or a spherical linear
interpolation using something called Quick turning ons kid turning ons are a complicated mathematical
structure which we aren't going to go into any detail with.
I'm sorry if you really were interested in that but you can obviously read up on them for yourself and
quit turning on is very clever and it understands things like 180 degrees like wrapping round itself
and it understands.
All of this in three dimensions.
And it avoids things like gimbel.
It's very very clever.
So anyway the way we do it is using a similar thing to the Lerp but with Queta anybody.
And the point is you aren't going to use your Lerp function.
You're going to use the slope function of attorney ons and how does it look where you can obviously
look up the documentation.
But I'm going to go to a client tic and just show you instead of using F maths we're going to use f
quat colon cancer.
This is a static member of this class and it's f k dot dot chemical and slurp.
And that takes to quit turning ons which are one of the rotation representations in a real which you
probably already know of and a float which they've called slurp it's the same as an owl for it's the
same as our Lerp ratio.
So very easily it should be possible to go ahead and do something like this.
So the thing that I notice however is that now we are storing or going to want to store both location
and rotation you can see here we've got our start location is the clients start location we're going
to need to do something very similar with the rotation as well.
So now you've got location and rotation.
This is starting to look like a not a client start location but clients start transform instead so that's
what we're going to go with.
Let's go up to a go cart movement replicator dot H and change the client location to a client transform.
Or at least change the name to that and change from F vector to f transform as well.
Like so and we can go ahead and copy this variable cause we're going to use in a couple places.
First place to use it is here the clients start location clients stock location dot and get location
will do exactly the trick that we want.
You can see exactly like we've done it for at Target location.
So there we got the transform on the client on the service date.
Here we're doing it saving it the client start transform.
Okay.
So that's all good.
Now where else do we currently use that let's remove slurp for now you've seen what that looks like
and you can find the documentation for yourselves.
Now let's go down to our simulated proxy on rep service state.
There it is.
And in here instead of setting the client start location we're going to get owner and set the transform
and we instead of getting the act a location we can just get the actor transform like.
So in that should do the trick it should get both the rotation and the location for us to use later
on and get to build it just to make sure.
But I'm fairly sure that is going to compile.
So on to implementing the slurps location but Opus One second we do have a build area let's figure out
where that is the first build error is here with the client transform equal.
I seem to have somehow managed to delete a bracket.
Oh and also called it at a location transform has changed both of those and build again.
Okay so let's take a look at your challenge definition.
You're going to slurp the rotation so you're going to do this all by yourself is very similar to learning
the location.
And so what we're going do is repeat the pattern that you have already seen.
We're going to use f quat slurp instead of the F maths Lerp or Lerp stable here there is no slurps label.
You don't need to do that.
Then you don't do anything differently and test it.
Basically not a whole heck of a lot to do that.
Okay so let's dive in and see the solution to this challenge.
So it's going to be fairly straightforward.
In fact I'm going to be mostly copying and pasting code and the way I'm going to do this is I'm going
to basically copy all of this target location from Target location to get owner.
I am going to copy it and we're going to make a duplicate copy loops.
Over selected it seems so.
Let's try again.
And instead of target location we're going to go with a target a rotation instead.
And we're gonna do that same thing for both our start location as well.
And our new location are both we come rotations.
Also at transformed or gets location will become transformed or get rotation.
Same thing goes for clients start to transform or get rotation and then what we've got an Lerp ratio
we don't want to redefine that.
We've already got one ratio that's good enough and we can set acthar location to act a rotation from
our New rotation as well.
Now ain't going to be happy about this.
If we hover over it we can see that it's saying that we can't convert between f quat an F vector which
is understandable because they are two completely different things.
So we're going to swap out the types for Target rotations start rotation in New rotation with F quiet.
And now we're going to get the complaint that Lerp stable isn't happy trying to do things over our f
quotes.
So instead what we're going to do is what we've already shown you which is the f quote colon colon slurp
instead of the Lerp.
I love these functions they have such funny and almost memorable names not completely memorable sort
of memorable.
There's lots of other funny ones as well as another type of rotation with Eternium that you can do called
squad.
And I just love that.
And that you've got squads slurp and Lerp anyway funny's zoo of different types of interpellation.
So let's go ahead and build that.
I believe that is all we need to do in this challenge.
Fairly easy compared with the last couple of challenges.
So you probably had a little bit of risk spiked with this one.
Now let's go ahead and see when it's finished building whether this has had a good impact on our rotations.
Well so built at least let's go into the edit hit play get our authority and our client side by side
excuse the mess of my windows and I am going to move my authority around and you can see the rotation
is definitely updating.
It looks a bit funky.
And if you aren't able to pinpoint why it looks funky it's because the car occasionally moves sideways
across its rotation there's nothing that pins its rotation to its velocity.
So sometimes it kind of seems to float across the ground.
Now this is a problem in a car based game but it may not be a problem for other types of movement component
do remember that this is all dependent on the type of movement that you want to achieve for cars.
We're thinking about one consideration.
But if you have a character the fact that it moves sideways and Straight's is not at all a problem your
animation can deal with the fact that it's moving sideways and make it look natural even if that wasn't
what the play was actually doing on the server.
If it looks natural everything is fine.
So that's one thing to consider this might be good enough for you.
Also we have very few updates.
So the fact that it looks like it's suddenly changing direction would be much less.
And by having more updates in general so think about that as well as not necessarily bad to be doing
linear interpolation but we can do better.
We can do better than these sudden changes of direction by using non-linear interpellation things like
kubik interpolation for example and that's going to be the subject of future lectures.
So I'll leave it there and I will see you in the next lectures.