Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be applying her mite's blinds into one real seeing what functions we can use in the
f maths library to actually do that and figure out how we can also calculate the velocity interpolate
the velocity as well as the position from that cubic spline.
So lots of stuff to learn lots of stuff to implement in this lecture.
It's going to be exciting and the result is going to be even more exciting.
We've got this really nice smooth movement on the simulated proxy as you're seeing here over on the
right.
And this is just sending updates once every second.
Can you imagine that and it looks so smooth.
That's fantastic.
Let's dive in and see how we achieve that.
So we want to start off by getting an understanding of how we can use cubic interpellation instead of
the regular old linear interpolation and to do that we need to understand at least three terms Slope's
derivatives and velocity.
Now you may have heard of them you may even understand them.
We're going to see how they all relate to each other.
In our particular context.
So to begin with understanding this topic let's have a look at our cover.
So we've got these two points we saw in the last lecture and we've got them velocity's as vectors and
this is the curve that goes through them now as before our interpolation is done using an outer parameter.
And when we put in an alpha parameter into the curve that we have specified.
We get a point come out and that's what we wanted so far.
Except this time our interpolation doesn't just require two points.
It requires a velocity as well.
So what we want to get out of this process is a velocity as well as a point because remember we have
a look at our code and I'm going to just dive in to your visual studio right away here.
I'll go to the replicator dot cbp and you can see that as we when we get our on rep server state in
our simulated proxy you can see we're taking this snapshot taking the clients start transform as a snapshot
in from the current location basically and this snapshot is what gets used in take when we are doing
our Lerp stable because the start location is actually that client transform location.
So if we're going to be including the client transform location start location and we're going to be
including the start velocity.
Were going to need to be able to snapshot the current velocity.
So that's a long way of saying that as well as getting the point out of our interpellation we need to
be able to get the velocity out every interpellation as well so it's not only worrying about interpolating
the point through this curve but also interpolate and velocity and that's fairly easy because actually
this velocity is just the slope of this line or related to the slope of this line.
I should say because that's the next slide.
How do these slopes derivatives and velocities relate to each other well slope and derivative are really
just two words for the same thing.
And if we had a look at this this is our curve and the slope is the vector that points along the curve
and its size is how quickly our we're moving over Alpher during that part of the curve.
So put more rigidly what we actually mean is it's the Delta location divided by the Delta alpha.
So the change in Alpha the delta and change in location divided by the change in our Earth.
And we could have done this over a linear interpolation as well it wouldn't have been very interesting
because it would have just been constant and pointing in the direction of the line.
Now this is somewhat similar isn't it to our definition of velocity.
Have a lost t is equal to if you remember Delta location divided by Delta time.
So these two things kind of seem to relate to each other except this delta Alpha and Delta times slightly
different.
And I've actually colour coded things depending on whether they are location velocity or whether they
are alpha.
We had our author turn and time.
Okay.
So Delta Alpha is related to health time in this way Delta Alpha is equal actually to the delta time
divided between the time between the last updates because remember it takes that amount of time to move
through from 0 to 1 in the althorpe range.
So if you're delta time were the whole time between last updates then they are the same thing.
So how can we use this knowledge to relate velocity and slope or derivative.
We're going to be using the term derivative and stick with that.
So how we relate derivative to velocity.
Well we've got this equation for derivative being a Delta location times Delta Alpha.
Got this equation for Delta Alpha equals Delta time.
So if I substitute this equation in to this equation what I'm going to get after a bit of manipulation
is that the derivative is actually equal to the velocity multiplied by the time between the last update.
So that's a fairly straightforward equation that we can actually work with.
And that's what we're going to do.
So I'm going to show you.
Up next how we can actually use the her might's blinds that we've seen in the previous lecture and in
unreal.
It's really quite easy because we've actually got a function in F maths to do this and the function.
It's called F maths colon colon kubik interp.
And what's it take.
Well it takes a few more arguments than we used to.
It has this piece 0 ampie 1 arguments which are essentially an A and B from the interpolation it's the
point the starting point and the ending point and T which is the tangent.
Another word for slope or derivative at that point.
So we've got the derivative at zero the derivative at one which remember is the rate of change for the
vector Alpha not with respect to time.
So is the over Delta Alpha not the over Delta time.
So and we've still got a which is at Alpha.
So we can use this very much as we were using at linear interpolation Except we need to add a couple
more things we don't need an F vector to be our start velocity.
In fact no astarte derivative because we know that those are different things that start velocity and
were going to an F vector for the target derivative as well.
Like so.
And then we're going to do in maths kubik interp.
And start location is going to be AP 0 then start derivative.
I don't find it is going to be our team zero.
Like so.
And then our team one is going to be a target derivative like so and we keep the Lerp ratio as we had
it before.
So this seems to make sense.
I'm fairly happy with this but what is our start derivative and target derivative going to be.
Well the start derivative.
We don't know yet.
So let's keep that one for later.
But let's have a look at the target derivative the targets are to is going to be equal to.
We said that derivatives are equal to the velocity multiplied by time between last update.
So let's have a little look at this.
We have got the edge Drew.
We have got our server state and in the server state we send back the velocity.
So that's the velocity you're going to be using as the target for this interpellation.
We're going to multiply it by the client time between last updates fact I'll just copy that.
And there's one more thing we have to do and this is because of the strange quirks of one real Remember
that AV a lost he is in meters per second.
But our location is in centimetres.
So we just need to remember that this needs to be all multiplied by 100 to convert between meters and
centimetres.
OK.
So that's that.
Next thing we need to do is have a look at astarte derivative what's astarte derivative going to be.
Well that is going to have to be something new because we haven't stored it in our client start transform.
We're going to have to create a new variable to store that so let's go up to our replicator H and we're
going to create an F vector to store our client start velocity.
Like so we're going to do the same conversion process for the start velocity where we multiplied by
this client time between our dates and 100.
In fact just to make it clear what this is.
Let's cut this out and make it into a floating point variable that floatpoint variable.
I'm going to call velocity.
Two derivative.
Like so.
And I'm going to declare just above these derivatives free float velocity two derivative equals the
this quite time between last dates multiplied by 100 and then I can reuse that variable which is quite
self descript for our client.
Velocity converted to a start derivative court.
So this has done kubik interpolation for us.
Now there's one piece of the puzzle that we're missing and that is as snapshotting on rep which I mentioned
earlier in the lecture.
So if we go and find our simulated proxy on reps over state you can see that we're snapshotting the
start transform.
We also need to snapshot this start velocity and start velocity is actually going to be from the movement
components we're going to grab the velocity of movement component I think you're wondering at the moment
whereas that the loss the actually coming from because we haven't set this out well that's going to
be your challenge.
But for now let's just go ahead and get the velocity.
That's going to be how we're snapshotting and let's make sure that our move component is not noll's.
I'm going to copy the nulled check from the autonomous proxy on reps of state and put it at the beginning
of our simulated proxy on rep server state.
So this is almost working now but we do need to be able to set the velocity.
As I said with our curve we need to be able to interpret both the location and the new velocity.
So let's have a look at your challenge to interpolate the velocity what you can do is you going to research
the function called Evan ascalon code on kubic interp derivative.
Now the name of that function should kind of give you a hint to what it's doing.
And that is basically providing you the slope of that kubic which is what we want.
And with that directive using the equations from last night you should be able to convert this in to
a velocity and interpolated velocity and from there be able to set the velocity on the movement component.
So that's my challenge to you to have a go at that and finally test it once it's done.
Pause a video and have a go.
Okay welcome back.
So this is where we actually get to see where that you understood that stuff I was wittering on about
the derivative.
So we've calculated and new velocity.
The next challenge is to calculate the f vector new velocity like so and how are we going to do that.
Well first of all we kind of need to know what the new derivative is.
So let's start off with that.
The new derivative is going to be the f maths cubic interp.
And let's have a look at how it functions laid out actually has exactly the same arguments as the QB
interp.
So that is what we're going to use.
We're going to use exactly the same arguments.
Now I'm just going to copy the name of the function to avoid me misspelling derivative like I probably
done about million times.
And we are going to copy all the arguments from the start location start derivative start target location
targets rivet.
And the Lerp ratio.
So this is going to give us we would have given us exactly the same point if we had put it in to the
cubitt interp function.
But instead what it does is it gives us the slope or the derivative at that point on that kubek.
So with that information in hand this interpolated derivative we can calculate the interpolated velocity.
So we've got this f vector new velocity has what we're looking for and how do we calculate it.
Well it's just the inverse of calculating the derivative from the velocity.
And we've already got a constant for doing a velocity to derivative.
So it should be fairly easy we just do new derivatives divided by instead of multiplied by the velocity
to derivative which is fairly straightforward.
Now we can be fairly sure that this is okay.
Usually it's a problem if we're driving by 0 or by very small numbers.
But at the beginning of our function we have already checked that the client time between last update
is not a very small number.
It's a normal sized number which means that when we multiply by 100 it's definitely not going to be
a very small number.
So Avelox t to derivative has got to be a large enough number to not be getting errors when we divide
by it.
So we've got this new velocity and with this new velocity as I've already said what we want to do is
go to and move components.
Arrow set.
For losty.
And we're going to be setting the new velocity right there.
And for your studio corrects my spelling mistakes which is very nice of it.
And what we're going to do if we don't have a move component we've got to make sure we've got at nulled
check if we weren't able to find a move component.
And so what I'm going to do is I'm going to basically abort the function just after it's updated the
delta time because that's safe.
So and just after it's done the clients time between last dates check.
I'm just going to check the Moven component return if we don't have one so that we aren't doing any
extra work that won't be useful if we don't have anywhere to set that velocity.
Okay.
So we're going to go ahead and build that and see what the results are because we are now snapshotting
that velocity we're updating that velocity from the derivative of that cubitt Curve which we now know
everything about and we are converting quite fluidly between derivatives and velocity's.
So let's dive in to the one real Ed and hit play.
And I won't put my authority on the right for a change.
And the autonomous proxy on the left and arm go drive around in front of it and sure enough we're getting
a much smoother movement you can see here where I'm changing directions.
It's not suddenly just jolting in a different direction it's smoothly going through a sort of curve
through sort of meander.
Now you will notice that the movement is slightly different because occasionally the rotation goes a
little bit sideways.
So we're going slightly sideways to the direction of motion.
That's because the motion of rotation rather isn't linked to the velocity and we're actually calculating
the velocity in a slightly different way to the way it's being calculate on the server.
It's just an interpolation of it's not the actual thing which means that when we are doing this interpolation
of rotation it doesn't always match up.
Now what we could do is we could point our rotation in the direction of the velocity and that is a legitimate
way to do it.
The only problem there is that when you reverse you are going to flip your car around 180 degrees and
that would look very weird.
And as far as I've been able to tell in my prototyping there's no easy way to solve that problem.
So for us it looks good enough.
The slurping rotation is doing a fairly good job and the Cubic interpolation is doing a phenomenal job
at being able to give us a smooth movement through the world.
I'm very happy with that.
And in the next video we'll be looking at a little problem around our colliders will see that actually
the collider is being moved on assimilated proxy and that can lead to collisions and interactions in
the world that shouldn't happen because they didn't happen on the server.
Were going to figure out what we can do about that problem.