Hello and welcome in this lecture.
We are going to be learning about a technique called meche offsetting At least that's what I call it.
And it's for client appellation to make sure that the position of our Collider doesn't go through different
routes because we're using this approximation of clear interpellation for the smoothness.
So what you're going to see here as I move my authority around you can see that the collider is moving
ahead of the simulated proxy so the collider is actually moving through the route advertise to us from
the server.
So it's never in an incorrect position.
However the mesh is being offset against that Collider location so the Calli location is at the root
is the active location.
But the mesh is having a different offset so that it gives the illusion of the actor moving smoothly.
So we're going to figure out how we can achieve this.
Let's dive in and see how.
So let's highlight the issue that we're trying to fix in this lecture.
If we go ahead and play and I if I just open it up again this time hopefully we'll on positive will
show up.
But the authority on the rights or Torse proxy on the left and I'm going to drive the authority around
so here goes my authority I'm going to do the pins are going to go between the pins and you can see
that authority or the simulated proxy rather is knocking over pins left right and centre even though
on the server I've dodged them all.
Now why is that.
That's because the kubik interpolation is going through a different path than what's on the server it's
still smooth.
It looks good but it's not the same path.
And we don't want to fix that issue but we do want to fix the issue where the collider of the simulated
proxy goes through that path.
That's different to that on the server.
And the problem that that creates obviously is that sometimes it can knock over things.
It's not meant to.
Sometimes it can cause false collisions etc..
So what we want to do and if we go ahead to our See our credit card folder and open the BP Go Card is
we want to make sure that we only ever change the location of the actor and therefore the box Collider
off the actor when there is a server updates so we know that that is a legitimate position that the
server has been in.
However we want our skeletal mesh to move smoothly through our client interpellation.
So how can we do that.
Well quite simply we can position that skeletal mesh in a different place to the box Collider and that's
what we're going to attempt to achieve.
Now there is a slight catch here is that this skeletal mesh is offset against our box.
So what we really want to do is not move the skeletal mesh itself but rather something else that is
at zero so I'm going to select the box I'm going to go to add component and create a new scene component
here and is seen component.
I am going to call the name of this technique which is meche offsetting.
So I'm going to call this the mesh offset route.
Do that.
Okay.
Like so and then I want to child discuss full mesh to that mesh offset route.
And as you can see the mesh of that route is now at 0 0 0 and the scuttleful mesh has got its offset
which is fine and that means that if I move the mesh offset route to any location.
It is going to keep that relative offset of the skeletal mesh so that it's about the right height off
the ground which is what we want.
So what we're going to be doing essentially is ENaC interpellation code we're going to be setting the
offset of this mesh offset route in global space coordinates.
And when we get an update from the server We will update the location of an actor and therefore our
box.
This means that our box will not be moving the same route as the mesh which is okay and casing the mesh
may pass through things.
That's fine.
It'll look more or less okay.
So again this is just an approximation technique we are really only sending an update once every second
and it's impossible to get things perfect.
It's all about trade-offs and just making it look right.
So I'm going to go ahead and save this and compile it because what we want to do next is set up the
mesh offset route component and connect it up to app movement replicator.
So let's go to Visual Studio and open up movement replicated that s.p. and go to the head of file down
at the bottom of the head of file and going to create a new you prompt and it is going to point to a
you seen component.
Asterisk.
And then we are going to call this obviously the same as we've called it in.
BP go kart which is going to be the mesh offset route.
So mesh offset route.
Mike so.
Okay.
Now this measure offset route.
We haven't got it set here how we're going to go ahead and set it well actually because we've created
it in the blueprint we haven't created it in C++ and because the box Collider is also created in blueprint
so it's going to be complicated.
Basically if I try and create the scene root anywhere.
But blueprint I'm going to create a setter in blueprint as well so it's going to be a u function so
we can call it from blueprint.
I'm going to make it blueprint callable.
And the signature is going to be void and just going to be basically a setter for this mesh offset route
so he's going to copy mesh offset route set and I am going to take a you seen component star.
And I'm not going to call it meche offset route but rather just route.
And then I can implement it here in line some going to get the mesh offset route is equal to that route
semicolon and that should be good enough.
I'm going to go ahead and build here and see if we've got this you function to call from our blueprint
was built successfully.
Let's go over to the BP go cart and go to the event graph and begin play which is where we are going
to try to call this set mesh offset route.
So drag off the pin from begin play selected the mesh the movement replicator component and we're going
to call set mesh offset route to go that seems to have worked and we're going to drag in a mesh offset
rate component to activate this setup song and go ahead save compile that.
This is just the easy way out.
We've got little warning here.
It's saying that it isn't the mesh replicator is not blueprint visible.
So we do want it to be blueprint visible and to do that we have to go in to our go cart or H and find
out.
Two components which are visible anywhere.
We also want them to be blue print visible.
We can do that for both the components while we're at it no point them not being visible in blue print
Let's go ahead and build it again and see.
So it looks like blue print visible is not the term it's actually read only I believe so going to have
a blueprint read only for both of these.
Let's go and build that.
Okay and finally saying the blueprint read only cannot be used on private members so let's move that
in to the public section.
Although it pains me slightly then do tell me if you can think of a better way than moving it into the
public section let's go ahead build and see if that works.
Okay great.
That did actually finally compile and go over to our go car.
And sure enough we compile it.
The error has gone away so I'm happy with that.
So one more thing that I want to do is make a box Collider visible so I'm going to go and select the
box Collider in the BP go cart and I'm going to go down to a rendering where you can see it is visible
but it's hidden in game.
So let's compile and save that blueprint and move it into the main window.
And then I'm going to go ahead and play with our colliders posable and you can see that if I move the
authority in front of the autonomous proxy his Collider is moving along with him what we want to happen
is for that Collider to be moving in jumps as the server updates come through and the car to still be
moving smoothly.
So I'm actually going to leave this up to you in a fairly open ended challenge to manipulate the offset.
So what you're going to do you're going to reset the actor location on rep.
So that's the only time we're going to change the location I want.
Everywhere else you need to strip out the use of the at location instead use the component location
both getting the component location and setting the location.
Beware that you'll need to make sure it's the global location and not the local location and you need
to do obviously rotation as well.
So pause the video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
Hopefully you managed okay with that challenge it's a little bit tricky but I'm sure you got at least
some headway which is the most important thing.
Let's go to the replicator s.p..
I've got to open some reason but this year seems to be liking giving me two files at the moment.
Probably something to do with checking in and checking out and stashing and so on and so forth.
So first of all I said on rep server state is where we are going to be setting our actors transform
and that is what were going to do.
So I'm going to say the get owner just at the end of this function and do get own a set actor transform
Now I don't like that we've got these reds quigley's and I can't auto complete so I'm going to actually
go ahead and include the head of file for the acto shouldn't be strictly necessary because we compile
but it is in the game framework folder and it is game framework.
Actor Don H.
Like so and that should hopefully they go remove the Reds greeley's from all those get owner calls and
it's just to help out with autocomplete really.
So then where was I.
I was in the on rep for the simulated proxy.
Were going to then do a set actor transforms somewhere.
Let's find out where that is.
I guess I asked a transform and what are we setting it from.
We're selling it from the server state DOT transform.
So we're going to be jolting this actor with every successive update like we had been doing previously.
But the difference is that we're going to be changing a mesh offset in between these updates.
This is actually what happens in the character component with the interpolation if you care to go and
read back that countermovement opponent is a very long file so I warn you that it might not be the lightest
reading that there is now.
The next thing I said is we want to change the references to act a transformer location elsewhere.
So one of the first places where this occurs is with our simulated proxy on rep service state.
We've got the client transform being set here from the actor current actor transform.
We don't want to be doing it from a current act transform Well we actually want to do is do it from
the location of our mesh offset.
So I'm going to do an if mesh offset route Wint be careful of null pointers so and say is not equal
to no pointer.
They see things on going to work very well.
If you don't have a mesh root offset and we want to then set our transform.
But the way I'm going to do it here is I to do it as the location and the rotation so it's going to
be the transform dot set location and the location is going to be a mesh route offset arrow.
And then we can get components.
Location and that if you hover over it or look in the documentation for the you seen component is in
worldspace.
So that is what we are looking for.
That's all I see.
So we've got worldspace there and I'm going to do the same thing for set rotation.
MIKE So that rotation and set component.
Rotation as well.
Well get component rotation from our offset route notice is actually saying it can't convert from F
rotators to f quat That's because get compan rotation returns an F rotate so if you actually do get
component I believe it's called the get component what it'll return you the global space rotation instead.
So that has replaced the use of the transform in a simulated proxy on reps state.
Next up we need to do the same thing for our clients.
Tic so inclined tick now we spread out into different functions so looking down where have we got instances
of our location where we using the client start transform location.
That's okay because we've just set that from the correct thing.
The velocity we're not interested in the interpolate location.
Yes this might be interesting let's have a look.
Yes we're setting the actor location here.
That's not what we want to be doing what we want to do instead is we want to check again to this nold
check let me copy the nold check for our meche route offset or meche offset route and place it in here
and then we want to do.
Within that if statement we're going to have a block and in that block we are going to say mesh offset
route arrow and then the mesh offset route arrow we're going to set I think world locations so this
is a bit of a strange one.
There's not a set component location but rather a set world location.
So they are getting and setting has a different name.
That's fine.
You can we can deal with that.
But it is a little bit.
It probably could have found this all in the documentation which is why I didn't tell you about it.
Okay.
So this is the mesh of set setting the location I'm going to copy this code because we need a very similar
one for these setting the active rotation here instead of doing the set world location we can set the
world rotation and I'm going to give it the new rotation could turning on and you'll see that the cell
world rotation with aquitania on worked just fine.
So we're going to leave it at that.
Is there anywhere else we need to change out our location.
I think not.
Let's go ahead and build see if it builds as a starting point and then see if it works nicely.
Well it did build so that is a good side point.
Let's head on over into the vehicle example map.
I'm going to go and hit play and put my authority on the right and my Thomas proxy on the left.
Now let's drive our authority around and all this is looking promising.
You can see that the box is leading the movements of the simulated proxy mesh which is exactly what
we want we can tell that the rotation is working because the box is coming out with different rotations
to the mesh but the mesh is moving smoothly behind it and moving very well.
I would say which does mean that let's do a little test of the slalom that if we try and go through
our slalom Okay that was interesting you see when I came at it with some force it kind of extrapolated
past the end of our pillar and the mesh moved through it.
I'm trying to replicate that.
I think I need to be going a little bit faster.
So the mesh tried to move through it but it didn't knock it over because our Collider didn't move.
So that's a good sign.
So I'm kind of going through the slalom here and so far I'm not hitting any of the pins which makes
sense because on the collider on the server we're not hitting the pins so that's not getting replicated
down to these simulated proxy.
And so we're never actually hitting it with a collider we're only of hitting it with a mesh and we know
this mesh won't cause any collisions.
So that's all fantastic.
We've now corrected for that problem where our mesh was knocking things over because of the different
route taken by the client interpellation pats on the back in the next lecture we're going to fix up
that little bit of anti cheat code that we've left as a to do.
So I'll see you there.