Hello and welcome in this lecture were going to be looking at how we can protect our games from more
advanced cheating.
So for example if I go to my movement component and when I create this move I actually say haha sneakily
I'm going to multiply my Delta time by Delta time by times 10.
So it's time is going to be running extra fast for me which means I'll be able to fly around the course
much faster than everybody else.
This is me pulling my sneaky hat on and trying to be malicious.
But if we go over into one real and hit play and try to drive around as the authority has NOT spawned
up the authority properly Here we go.
Here's you we've got the.
Sorry not the authority with the autonomous proxy.
Well you can see that he's actually labelled as authority so that tells us something has gone wrong
already.
If we go and have a look at the logs you'll see there's an error message here saying the client is running
too fast at cheap protection has caught my sneaky behaviour.
So let's dive in and see how we can implement some advanced tree protection to stop such behaviour as
this.
So there's a little to do here that we haven't yet got round to fixing which is this validation for
our move.
And there are currently lots of ways that our user could actually cheat if they wanted to.
Now the first and most obvious way is using different inputs.
So let me actually implement a cheat.
First of all and then we're going to implement cheap protection to make sure we can catch that cheat.
So the first kind of cheat that we might end up having.
If I go ahead and going to close down these windows because I've got a few too many open and it's a
little bit confusing.
So the first thing is going to the Movent component or C P P and where we go ahead and create and move
right here.
You can see that we are setting the throttle to the throttle value.
Well what if I wanted to go twice as fast or accelerate twice as fast.
Well then I might just be able to multiply that by 2 or even by 10 so I'm going to go ahead.
Multiply my throttle by 10 which should mean that I'm able to cheat as a player I'm basically able to
go 10 times as fast as the other players.
Let's see how that works.
It's obviously not going to catch because we haven't written a cheap protection code but we want to
see the effect and then we're going to write the cheat protection code that should kick me out because
I'm doing this case so it compiled successfully.
Let's go over into one real and hit play and let's try driving around.
Okay so let me put the authority over here on the right.
The autonomous proxy on the left and I'm going to be driving the autonomous proxy's So I drive the tomás
Proxy.
Yes indeed it is moving around like a crazy person and is doing the same on the server so we definitely
haven't stopped it from being able to accelerate to silly speeds.
It's actually quite hard to drive.
So it's a bit of a rubbish cheat but it certainly is quite effective at getting me from A to B much
faster than the simulated proxy or the authority would be able to do so.
What we do want to do is payable to prevent this sort of silly behaviour.
And well that's quite easy if we go into our replicator.
Dot h r c p p rather what we want to be able to do in this validate is check that the move has got valid
bounds on its throttle its Ballo bounds on its steering throw as well so we can do this quite easily
actually by I'm going to implement or help a function on the F go cart state struct And is that the
one I want no the F go can't move struct as what I want which is in the go cart movement component.
And I'm just going to call it is valid.
So Gary Ball.
Is valid.
And it's not going to take any arguments and it's going to be a concert function because we don't have
to do anything in there.
And then it is going to very simply I'm going to just define it in line because it's going to be so
simple going to very simply check that the absolute value of the throttle the absolute value of the
steering throw is less than or equal to 1 so that's going to be fairly straightforward.
We can do an F maths code on code on abs throttle.
I'm not just talking about having great abs we're talking about absolute Manly's equals
less than or equal to one and then we're going to do one and to do the same thing not just with the
throttle.
But to do it with the steering throw as well because I could apply that sheet to the steering flow as
well now you might be asking Sam how can they apply this treat seeing as they don't have access to my
source code.
Well you can do clever things by compiling the source code and it's very very easy to find the place
where you're steering throw is getting into some variables and then just apply a simple multiplication.
It's not a hard cheat to be able to implement even if all you've got is the machine code to deal with
a case that's built.
Let's go ahead and see whether that's going to be an effective cheap protection.
Go ahead hit play.
And here is my autonomous proxy.
If I drive the let's try and drive the autonomous proxy.
Okay that hasn't worked.
I wonder why.
I know why because we've only implemented the helper method.
We need to go into the replicator c p p and instead of returning true we need to do return move.
Dot is valid.
So basically validating the move can move this to do because we're doing it.
Let's go ahead and build.
Okay so that has built.
Let's see if it works.
I have launched up miles on a proxy.
I try and move.
Boom I'm kicked out of the game because I'm a cheater and cheaters are not allowed to play.
So that is a fairly simple thing to do.
But what about if I go for a more complicated cheat what I'm going to do is I'm going to be stressing
delta time this time so we'll go into the moving component c p p and here's my Delta time and one thing
that I know I could do is just make time run faster for me.
So every time I create a move and send it up to the server I can either say that the delta time is larger
than it was or I could send more moves up to the server.
Now I am going to go with just one of these options.
But we should be able to protect against both of them.
So I'm just going to multiply my Delta time by 10 and I'm going to remove that from the throttle so
we know that's not the reason it's failing.
Go ahead and build and see what the effects are.
OK.
So the build succeeded.
Let's go ahead and play it.
And dive into my or tolley's Proxy.
Please try to.
And if I drive around were I still going.
Credibly face in fact and go much faster by multiplying by 10.
My delta time in fact so fast I really can't control.
You can see how this would obviously be a problem that the physics simulation has been completely perverted
by me multiplying that delta time.
I just want to show you that there is another way of achieving essentially the same type of effect which
is if we go into the replicated NCP s.p. and where we've got this send server send move the last move
which has Antec component.
If I go ahead and copy that a couple of times so that we basically don't duplicate these moves then
we've also got problems so if I comment out for now this multiplied by 10.
Like so and build with this particular treat.
We should see a very similar thing in place.
Let's dive back into one real quick.
The game is currently running and hit play again.
I'm going to go over into the autonomous proxy and move them around and you can see that he's certainly
moving faster than even we're expecting.
Obviously we could update our position better but you can see that we're moving very very quickly indeed
across the authorities screen he maybe didn't see it too well but take my word for it.
If you didn't so that's what were going to want you to try and fix.
See if you can get that delta time for both of those cases both by multiply that time and by sending
multiple simulated moves.
Whether we can make that look like a cheat in the validation function.
So I'd like you to prevent a delta time cheat.
Now the way that you're going to do this is by tracking the time that has been simulated so far from
the client so every time it gives you a move you've got Delta time that gives you an amount of time
that you're going to simulate.
Like you to keep track of how much of that time you've already simulated and ensure that it's is less
than the server time it should always be less because there's a delay from the client to the server
so the server should always have its time running ahead of what the client asked to simulate.
If it gets a head then it means that the client is trying to cheat it's trying to run ahead of the service
trying to move time move time faster than it actually moves.
Obviously that's not allowed.
And then I'd like you to check that it's preventing multiplying moves and it's preventing long delta
time so pause a video and have a go at this challenge.
Okay welcome back.
So we're going to implement this tracking of simulation time.
It's actually fairly straightforward.
Hopefully you've had a go at it yourself.
If you're a little bit stuck Don't worry.
The important thing is that you have a go even if you do get stuck because you learn from even not managing
to complete.
A challenge is still learning.
That's the important thing.
So what are we going to do in a replicator.
H.
I am going to add a new variable and I'm going to add it.
Let's see where I'm going to put it.
After our client chunk of variables so it's going to go after a client start velocity and I'm going
to call it client's simulated time like so and it is going to be a float.
As time tends to be a float.
So what client simulated time.
That's what I'm going to go with.
And then in our replicators c p p every time we receive our simulated move I am going to increment that
time so it's going to be the simulator time plus equalled the move Delta times that every time we've
simulated a move that simulates time has moved forward.
So now another way of saying that there is a problem is going to be that the simulated the client simulator
time.
Plus the move delta time.
So the simulator is what the simulator time would be.
In fact let's say that in a variable set free float proposed time.
So and we want to check that the proposed time.
Is going to be less than the Worlds time.
So we're going to do a GET world.
And then we're going to do an arrow.
And it's going to be I think time what we have before.
Somewhere in here already.
Time.
Seconds.
It's probably in the component c p p.
Yes time second so I can just copy that from the copy over from the components you pee into the replicator
cbp.
And where is it.
Down here in the validate go time seconds.
So what's this property.
This is a boolean and it's basically telling us.
Client not running ahead something like that.
And basically I'm going to say.
If.
Not.
Client not running ahead.
Bit convoluted but I think it's easier to read because then were going to do an a quick return false.
And we're going to put a little log message so that we can see that this is the thing that went wrong.
It's going to be a log temp and I'm actually gonna make it an error instead of a warning.
And the text is just going to say that the client is running too fast.
And then we're going to obviously have kicked it so we can check that.
We can also put an if not move dot is valid and we can put a log message for that case too.
So there's just a bit more useful logging information here.
We're going to a return early return false.
And we're going to put a eui Log.
Very much the same as our client is running too fast instead is going to say.
Received invalid move.
And then at the end if none of these two early returns have been hit we can just return true.
So the way this now reads is that we're getting a proposed time we're checking that client's not running
ahead.
If he is running ahead then the clients running who fast is logged out.
And we return false.
And if we've received an invalid move then we log that out instead.
So I'm going to go ahead and build this and see if we're catching the client is running too fast error.
Okay.
Let's dive into one real See if that does get caught.
There we go.
We have actually already been kicked.
You can see that because both our cars and labelled authority go to our output log we can confirm that
go and find the red error.
So the connection has been lost.
And if we scroll up a bit further we can see that the client is running too fast is the error message.
And what I want to do next is go ahead and check that it still works in the actual running case.
Let's go and find a tic function and remove the multiple send moves.
And build that.
So check that it still works in the normal case.
So let's dive back in to the unreal.
Ed hit play and his apple top his proxy hasn't kicked yet and we can seemingly move around as normal
so that seems to be working for our working cases not throwing up false positives about cheating which
is also something we don't want.
What if we were to multiply at Delta time by 10.
Hopefully this should also mean that our simulation is running ahead of the service simulation and should
be thrown up as that sort of cheating.
So that succeeded to build play.
And sure enough we've been kicked out already.
We're saying authority if we look at the logs it says somewhere down here.
Scroll to the new message it says that their client is running too fast which is correct.
So we can undo that and build it back to a working state.
But now we are fairly sure that our replicator has got some good anti cheap protection.
You can't make the client run too fast.
It has to stay within the time bounds.
So that's going to prevent a lot of terrible cheating.
We also can't give invalid throttle values and there's basically no other way of cheating if we go and
have a look at a component c p p or at least no other way of treating that I can think of.
I might be wrong.
You might find some other ways and if you do please give it a test see if you can create some cheating
behaviour and pace that you just mentioned that in the community site where it would be really interesting
to see what extra cheats you could find and what other cheap protections you can find.
Because this is really a game of security and with security you've never finished the battle you're
always trying to put more protections in place.
But there's always some ways that cheaters can come through that people can hack your system.
We're just trying to catch as many of those as possible and make it as hard as possible for people to
actually try and treat so the throttle value we've bounded that they can't cheat through the throttle
value of the Go can't move their steering throw.
We've bounded that well Delta time has been bounded over time by that some that we're keeping and the
time property is actually not used on the server at all it's only used on the client so we can't use
that to cheat.
So that's the interface between the client and server also how often you're sending these moves as the
interface between the client server and it seems that we've mostly locked that down.
I'm fairly happy with that.
As a second pass at our cheat protection and hopefully you are too but do bashin around see he you can
think of any other ways that you might be able to cheat and do share them in the community.