We are going to create an async servlet.
The first thing we'll do is to create a servlet that will log
out information about the request it receives.
In particular,
you want to log out thread IDs so we understand the threads that
are used for various parts of the request.
To do this, we'll start an async call, get async context,
and add async listener.
That listener can log the various events that are fired.
So it's giving us information about async calls.
As part of this logging, we log out the thread in which the calls are being made,
we get the thread at these to give us more information.
So the first thing we'll do is mark the servlet as async.
In the servlet we say asyncSupported = true.
Then in the doGet method, we add a call to print out the current thread ID.
We can then grab the async context by calling startAsync.
This tells the container, we are going to work asynchronously.
Now we can add a listener to the context to log out the
events that get fired within the container.
This listener takes the AsyncListener instance that is four methods,
one per event.
Each method is passed an AsyncEvent object.
There is an onStart,
onComplete that are called when the async call is started and completed,
an onError that is called when there are any errors in the async call,
and onTimeout if a call of the context times out.
In each of these methods,
we'll log that the event has being called along with the thread
ID of the thread on which the event is called.
After that, we'll start the async work.
We do that by calling start on the context and
passing the start method a lambda.
Inside the lambda we'll do a couple of things.
Firstly, we'll add a try catch block to handle any errors.
Inside the try,
we add a log method to show the thread that is calling this lambda,
and also write that ID back to the caller.
To write to the browser, we use the context to get the response object,
then on that response object we call getWriter and write
a text message back to the browser.
Then inside the catch, we simply log out any errors.
After the try catch, we call context.complete.
This tells the async context that we are done and allows
the container to free up any resources.
Now we can deploy the application.
In the browser, browse to async/simple,
and that executes the asynchronous servlet.
And in the output here we can see the thread ID.
And if we now look in the log file, we see the messages.
We'll see the call to doGet is the first log message we had,
and the call to start, which is in the start body.
We also see a call to onComplete.
However, notice that we don't see a call to onStart.
We don't see the onStart event fired inside this listener.
That's because we start the async context before we wire up
the listener so that the event is fired before we've wired
up the listener to the context.
Also notice the thread ID of the calls.
These calls all happen on different threads.
DoGet happens on the initial thread,
start happens on the thread created from the lambda, and onComplete happens on a thread created by the container for these events.