So the first thing we want to do is to create a tag inside a tag file.
And these tag files live inside the webapp,
WEB-INF directory, and inside here need to create a tags folder.
So we can do that inside IntelliJ, so we just do New,
Directory, and we call this thing tags.
To create our first tag, we simply create a tag file with a tag extension.
So I can right-click and do New and just create a new file,
and we'll call this helloworld.tag.
So I've said that tags are just JavaServer Page fragments,
but to be a tag, we have to add the appropriate directives.
In this case, we have to add the tag directive.
So the tag directive is simply less than percent at tag.
And tags themselves can have many attributes.
For example, we can give the tag a description,
we can specify things about the language of tag users.
We can also specify whether the tags should or should not have a body.
So we can say body-content=empty,
and that says that this particular tag can only exist on a single line,
i.e.
it has no body inside opening and closing elements.
Once we have that in place, we can close off the tag.
And then the simplest tag we can create would simply
output some text onto the page.
To make it slightly more exciting, we can wrap this in a header tag.
So we can say h3, then inside here we'll just say Hello World.
Now that we've written the tag, we need to use the tag on the page,
so to do that we need to find the page,
which in this case is going to be inside main,
webapp, inside WEB-INF, and it's going to be index.jsp.
On here, we already have one taglib imported,
that's for the core tag libraries,
and we simply need to import this new time library.
So to do that, we use a taglib directive.
So again it's less than percent at taglib.
We need to get this in the prefix.
So these are simple tags, so let's say st for these tags.
But then we also need to specify where these tags come from.
Now for the core tag library, we use the uri prefix,
and that tells the compiler to find a taglib.jar file
that is referenced via that url.
In this case, we're using a tag file,
and we'll use a tag file and we'll use the tagdir attribute on the directive,
and the tagdir attribute tells the page which directory to find the tags in.
In this case that's going to be WEB-INF/tags.
Once we have that in place, you can then use the tag on the page itself.
In this case, we're going to add the tag into the Profile tab on the page.
So that's at this point here where it just currently says Profile.
So in here we can say st:,
and notice that IntelliJ is smart enough to find the Hello World tag.
We can then just place that inside there.
Now if we deploy the application and browse to the page,
we'll see helloworld on that, inside that tab,
so let's do that.
So if I look in the browser and go to the Profile tab,
sure enough, it now says Hello World.
So that's about the simplest tag that we can write for JavaServer Pages.
So at the moment, this tag is particularly an interesting,
and it simply outputs some text onto the page.
What we'd like to do is to pass some data into tag
and have the tag use that data.
And the simplest way to do that is to use attributes.
So inside this tag, we can add an attribute directive,
and that directive will specify the name of the attribute and
maybe some other information about the attribute,
such as whether this is required or not.
That looks something like this.
So here we create an attribute with the name of name,
we also specify that this attribute is required.
Inside the tag itself, rather than saying Hello World,
we can use the name of attribute and grab the value from that,
and I'll put that value into the tag.
And we do that using an expression.
So we'd say dollar brace, then inside here we'd say name.
Once we have that in place, if I go to the index page,
IntelliJ now tells us that there's something missing from the tag.
In this case that's the name attribute, and this is required.
So if I say name=Alice let's say, just to prove that this works.
Notice I've also made the profile pane active here,
so each time we browse to the page,
we get the profile pane so we can see this output.
Notice here, I don't need to really plug the application,
these are JavaServer Page changes,
and they are picked up automatically by Tomcat.
So if I go to the browser, you can see that it currently says Hello World.
If I refresh the page, that will change to Hello Alice.
Again, not particularly exciting, we're simply passing in hard coded text.
But to these tags, I can also pass expressions.
So if you remember we have this user object,
and the user object has a name value.
So I can take that and I can pass that property
inside the attributes to this tag.
So we pass in dollar brace user.name, again no need to save.
If I go back to the page now and refresh,
then we see Hello Kevin, where Kevin is the name passed through that user object.
So the tag we've just created is relatively simple.
We can create more complex tags.
So for example, in the Profile tab here,
we might want to show some information about the user.
And we could do that by, for example,
creating a tag called profile and then including that tag on the page.
So we will do that the same ways we created the previous tag.
So back in the tags directory, we can do New, File, we'll call this profile.tag.
Again, to mark this as a tag, we need to give it a tag directive,
so we say less than percent at tag.
And again we set body-content to be empty for this tag.
To our profile tag we'll pass a user, so we'll add another attribute in here,
less than percent at attribute.
The name of the attribute will be user.
Again, this will be required, so we say required is true.
Now by default, attributes that are passed into a tag are strings.
In this case, we're actually going to pass a user object.
To do that, we need to tell the runtime the type of this attribute.
So we can say type=, and the type of ours is going to be com.mantiso .User.
So now when we create the tag and use it,
we specify the user attribute, with also name of type User.
The body of the tag will just be a table,
and each row in the table will display some part of the user,
so something like this.
We should have a table entry here with a Name row and EMail row,
and maybe an image that displays a photograph of the user.
So we can save this.
We can then go back to our index.jsp page,
and underneath the helloworld tag, we can say less than st,
we've got a reference to our profile tag,
and then give this thing to user.
So to pass the user object into here, we use an expression.
So we say dollar brace user.
And then we can close off the tag itself.
Now we'd like this information shown only if there is a user.
So like before where we've put an if entry in here,
we can do the same thing just to make sure that there's no
user and the profile tag isn't executed.
So we end up with a test, something like this.
Again, there's no need to deploy the application.
If we go back to the browser, and refresh the page,
then we see on the page now the Hello message,
and then the information about this user,
so name, email, and an image.
So we can see here we can actually pass around attributes other than strings,
in this case we're actually passing in a user object and using that within the tag.