The primary way of passing data to a JavaServer Page and having
that data visible on the page is to use JavaBeans.
The expression language has quite a rich syntax for accessing these beans.
So using the expression language, we can also get to the bean properties,
and we can use either a dot syntax, or a square bracket syntax.
So it's very similar to the way that JavaScript works.
So if we have a user bean with a name property,
we can say user.name, or user, square brackets,
and then place the name property in quotes.
We can also use the square bracket syntax to access
things like lists or arrays or maps.
We can also use the square bracket syntax to access nested beans.
So for example, if we have a name bean that has a first property,
or a name bean that has a second property,
for example, we can say a, brackets, name.first,
or a, brackets, name, brackets, first, and we can nest this arbitrarily.
So we can go down as many levels of beans as we need to.
The expression language also gives us access to a set of built-in objects,
also known as implicit objects.
So for example,
if we need to reach in and get values from the
header as a header values property,
there's also a header property that we can get out,
so we can say header.host to get out the host header,
or header, square bracket, host to also get at the host header.
Things like pageContext or the session,
so all of these things are available within the expression language itself.
So in this code, we've introduced a new bean.
So if we look at the ApplicationSettings bean,
rather than just getting the name from here,
we've introduced another class called CssClass,
and the idea behind CssClass is that we can store CSS information
that we need to use for a particular thing.
So in this case, we're just using the name,
similar to what we were using previously.
To use this in the servlet, we now create a CssClass,
we set the name within our class to be, in this case,
blueUser again, and then add that CssClass onto the applicationSettings,
and then store the applicationSettings object within the ServletContext.
So we now have a nested bean.
So to get at the name,
we need to go through the applicationSettings object called app,
from there to the CssClass, then from there to the actual name itself.
So now to use the name,
we have to go through the formCssClass and get the name property.
So we treat this as a nested bean.
So we say app.formCssClass .name.
Then if we go to the browser and refresh,
then everything works, and just to prove that it is still working,
if we go back to the ApplicationSettings to where we set the
applicationSettings inside the servlet,
and change the name from blueUser to redUser,
and redeploy the application, and then go to the browser and refresh,
and we should get red, and sure enough, we do.
We can also access the nested properties of the bean
through the square bracket syntax.
So rather than just saying app.formCssClass .name,
we could say app,
and then use square brackets and quotes to get the name that way,
and then say .name in the same way, and again if we go back into the browser,
nothing should have changed.
If I refresh, sure enough, the page still works,
and we can also go one step further and put square
brackets around the name property, and again save and go back to the browser,
and sure enough, things are the same.
So we also saw that we can use the built-in intrinsics to
get the data within the application.
An example would be the init parameters.
So here we have an expression to get the init parameter,
ProductName, that we can use as the title of this application,
and we can change that to use an expression.
So here we can say, dollar, brace, and inside here say initParam.ProductName,
and if we go into the web.xml file and change the product name from
My Application to using the expression language,
redeploy the application, and if we go the browser,
we can see currently it says My Application,
if I refresh the page, now it says Using The Expression Language.
So within the page itself,
we can access these intrinsics within expressions using the expression language.
So we've added some tabs to the user interface,
as we can see if we go to the browser.
So here we can see Home, Profile, Messages,
and Settings as the names of those tabs.
The way this is set up is by adding an unordered list to the page,
and within that list,
each list item defines a tab; the text here is the name of the tab.
Now it may be that we want to set those names dynamically
depending on possibly the user's preferred language.
So rather than English in this case, you might want French or Spanish.
In that case, we'd like to get these strings from some value passed to us,
maybe from the servlet where we can configure these values.
To do that within this application, we've changed our ApplicationSettings class,
and the ApplicationSettings class, we now have another property called tabNames,
and tabNames returns to us an array of names.
So we return the string array.
We can set the values of the tab names inside ControllerServlet.
So here we set the tab names, we set maybe SignIn and Home,
Profile, and Settings.
TabNames is then set inside the ApplicationSettings class and passed
into the JavaServer Page though the ServletContext,
which is the same as we had previously when we were just
using this for the CSS class name.
What that means is that inside index.jsp,
rather than just using home here,
we can use an expression to get a value from the string.
So here we can have an expression, let's say dollar brace.
Inside here we can say, app.tabNames 0,
and then after we deploy we can go back to the browser and refresh and run,
we see in Home here, we should see Sign in.
We can then replace the rest of the tab names with the value from
the bean passed in through the ServletContext.
So after updating the JavaServer Page, we can go in back to the browser,
and we see now we have Signin, Home, Profile, and Settings.