So the first thing we're going to do is to add a filter,
and this filter is going to log events, and for that we're going to use Log4j.
First we need to set up the filter.
So we add a new package for the filters and add a class that implements filter.
We implement the methods for the filter,
and there are three methods we need to implement,
init, doFilter, and destroy.
Init is called when the filter is first initialized,
doFilter each time the filter is used,
and destroy when the filter is disposed of.
In the init method, we'll capture the filterConfig so that we can use it later.
As we're going to use Log4j version 2, we need to add two entries to the POM,
so these references are available to our application.
In the filter,
we add references to Log4j and then we get a reference to the logger.
And then we can then use that logger to log request information,
and then we simply chain the request to the next entry in the filter chain.
In this demo, we're not going to show using this through web.xml,
we've done that for events, instead we're going to use annotations.
So we add the WebFilter annotation and we use star to
specify that this filter is for all URLs.
To use Log4j, we need to create a configuration file,
and this configuration file has to be on the class path,
so we add it to the resources section.
That means it gets included in the WAR file in the classes folder,
and so will be on the class path.
Notice this configuration file uses a system property to tell
Log4j to log to the Tomcat logs directory.
And this is the same place that Tomcat itself logs to.
Once we have that in place,
we can deploy the application and refresh the browser.
And if we now open the log file,
we can see the entries with the request made to the
servlet * .do and the various support files,
the CSS files and the JS files.
With that simple filter in place, we can now add a wrapper.
In this case, we'll add a request wrapper to capture the requests,
and log information about those requests.
And here we'll log HTTP headers that are sent as part of the request.
So to do this,
we add a LogRequestWrapper class and extend HttpRequest servlet wrapper.
In its constructor,
we take a reference to the logger and store that for later use.
We override the getHeader method, call the superclass method,
so that getHeader is passed up the call and the header's returned,
and then just log out the header information.
In the filter, we create an instance of the wrapper,
passing the original request object and the logger,
and we pass the wrapper down the filter chain.
And again, we can deploy the project and refresh the page.
And now when we look,
as well as seeing the logging information about the request coming in, we can also see the logging information about these headers as well.