So now that we have multiple tags, we need to think about packaging.
Tag files, and indeed other tags, are packaged into things called tag libraries,
and tag libraries are JAR files, hence the need for a separate project.
So here, we have a taglib project, and that taglib project is set up in a Maven,
and indeed in IntelliJ, to build into a JAR file,
and that JAR file will then be included along with the web app itself.
This project is set up to have a source directory with a main and
inside here resources with a META-INF folder.
And we are doing that because if we want to include tag files
inside a JAR inside the library itself, inside tag library,
we need to put those type files into the META-INF folder.
So to do that, inside the META-INF folder,
we create a new directory and call this tags.
And into there, we can simply place one of our tags.
So we'll take the helloworld.tag that we created here,
so that was down inside main, webapp, WEB-INF tags,
so I can take my helloworld.tag, cut that out of there,
and place it into here.
And that tag is now part of this library.
Unfortunately, creating a tag library is not quite as simple as that.
We also need something called a tag library descriptor file.
And the tag library descriptor file tells the user of the tag
library how to use the tag library itself and what tags are
available within that tag library.
So the tag library descriptor file, or the TLD,
is an XML file that also lives in that META-INF folder.
So in here, we can do New, File, and we call this thing taglib.tld.
So the tld file has a taglib root element.
And then this contains some subelements to describe the tag file.
So these elements are the version of this library
the short name for the library, the URI,
and this is how the library is uniquely identified,
and then the JSP version of this library is 4.
And we can start that at 2.2, that's the latest version.
Within the tld, within the taglib element, we can describe two sorts of tags.
We can describe tag files, which we looked at already,
and we'll have one of those in a moment,
and we can describe tags that are written in Java,
which we'll do in a little while.
To describe a tag file as part of this library,
we use the tag-file element, which unfortunately shows up in red inside IntelliJ,
but it is a valid element.
Tag-file has a name, so we can say name, which can be helloworld for our tag.
And then the tag-file has a path,
and that's the path within this JAR where this tag file lives.
So that's going to be /META-INF/tags/ helloworld.tag.
So we use this tag library in the same way we use the core tag library.
So back in the JSP page where currently we have a reference to the core library,
I can copy and paste that, maybe change the prefix from c to let's say m,
and then in here we can say http:// mantiso.com /simple.
So that'll give us access to the library.
This is showing red, so down here we can see where the helloworld tag is.
This is still referenced using the st prefix.
So if we change that to say m and change this here
to say m on the closing element, and then change the username to say Alice,
just to prove that we are now using a slightly different tag.
Now I do need to redeploy this as we've actually built the JAR file.
So, I need to redeploy and then we can go to the browser.
So let's redeploy first.
So I go to the browser and go to the Profile page.
And here it says hello Alice.
So, to prove that we are using this tag library,
if we go back to the application and go to the helloworld tag
and change this so it says Hello name..., say,
and then back on the JSP page, and then here say name=$ user.name,
redeploy, and then go back to the browser,
refresh, go to the Profile tab.
And sure enough, it says hello Kevin with dot dot dot,
so that dot dot dot is coming from the tag library itself. So we can clear the tag file actually inside our tag library.