So now that we've seen the logging filter and taken a
look at how we wrap up requests,
we'll now take a look at how we wrap up responses.
And we do this because we might want to change the response.
So for example,
imagine we have a website where the response data is coming back as XML and we
need to run an XSLT transform on that to turn it into HTML,
and we can do that with a response wrapper.
So to do this, we create an HttpServletResponseWrapper derived object,
and as we'll see, response wrappers are more interesting than request wrappers.
There's more work to do inside the response wrapper.
We have to cope with at least content length,
content type, the container might call getWriter to write the data,
or it might call getOutputStream to write the data,
and we have to deal with all of these things.
So to show an example of this, we'll write a compression filter.
So what this filter will do is any response that comes back to it will use
the Java GZipOutputStream class to compress the content.
Once the content's compressed,
we have to change the headers going back out of the servlet
container to say this data's now compressed data,
and we have to make sure we set the right content length and
content type headers on the response as well.
And we do that by overriding a response wrapper. So let's see how we do that now.