The next two tags we're going to take a look at are
the import tag and the URL tag.
The import tag is like an include tag,
and it lets us bring other data into the page.
So we can include for example other HTML files,
we could bring that data maybe from another server,
we could bring that data from another what's called a context on this server,
i.e.
another application running on the same server.
When we import the data, we can also store the data inside a variable.
That lets us reuse the input on the page.
So rather than running multiple import tags,
which may be costly, we can run the tag once,
store the data, and then display that data multiple times.
So within the page currently,
we include the header.jsp file that's included here,
and if we look at the page inside the browser,
so that gives us this section here within the page.
That's the navigation section.
And if we take that page, include out, and refresh the browser,
we see the header's disappeared.
So in the page what we could do is to use the import tag, so that's c:import.
We specify a URL, which is header.jsp, and we can just close that off.
And if we go back to the browser, and we should get the header back.
And sure enough, the header's there.
Now in this case, the input tag is perhaps not appropriate,
as the include tag does the job perfectly well; however,
there may be occasions where we want to reuse the data we import.
So to do that we can say var=, and give this variable a name,
and in this case maybe _header.
If we rerun the page now, we'll see the header disappears.
That's because now it's reading in the data, but storing it inside the variable.
And to display that header now, you need to use an expression,
so we'd say dollar brace, and inside here we'll just put the variable name,
and the expression will just render the variable.
If we go back to the page and refresh, we get the header,
and indeed we could use this in multiple places,
and we see the header appearing each time we use the expression.
Not a good idea in this case obviously,
but it's something you can do with the tag and something that might be useful.
So we use URLs inside a web application in many,
many places, but they aren't issued when we create URLs inside a web application.
That's primarily because the browser has no concept of
what a web application actually is.
Remember that when we deploy the application,
we deploy it to a server, and then to an application in that server,
and often when we create URLs,
we'd like to create the URL relative to the application itself.
However, depending on how we generate the URL inside the server,
if we use something like / somepage.jsp,
that forward slash says to the browser that this URL is
relative to the root of the server,
so we'd end up with a URL that looks like http:// myserver.com / sompage.jsp.
If we leave the slash out,
then we end up with a URL that's relative to the current page,
so that will give us myserver.com /application name/ where
this page is in the application/page name.
So if we need just to create a URL that was relative to the application,
that's impossible to do just using a standard anchor tag with an href.
So to fix that, we can use the url tag.
The url tag allows us to create application-relative URLs.
And we can do that by simply using c:url as the name of the tag,
and then specifying the value, which is the value of the URL we want to create.
Just like the import tag,
we can store the value of this URL inside a variable name,
and again use that within many places within the page.
To illustrate how this works, I've set up a very simple JavaServer Page here.
This JavaServer Page is called home.jsp,
and it's in the app directory of the application itself.
So the URL of this page is hostname/app/app/ home.jsp.
Then within here I've added three anchor tags.
So the first one has an href of / signin.jsp,
the second one has no forward slash, and the third one uses the core url tag,
and inside here that would give it a value of,
again, / signin.jsp.
So based on what we know,
the first URL we see here should be relative to the root of the server.
The second URL should be relative to the root of this particular page,
so that should be /app/app/ signin.jsp.
And the third URL should be relative to the root of this application,
so it should just be /app/ signin.jsp.
So if I run this page in the browser, we can see the three URLs here,
and if I click on each one in turn, we can see that the address bar will change,
and the address bar will change to the URL defined by the href here,
and with the first one, which was a root-relative URL,
if I click on that, the address changes to localhost of / signin.jsp,
so we get the fully server root-relative URL.
The second one we created with a standard href,
but with no forward slash, so that should be the application relative,
so that should go to /app/app and then the signin.jsp,
and if we click on that, sure enough, we get a 404 because the page isn't there,
and it's at /app/app/ signin.jsp.
And the third one was the application relative sign-in page,
so that should go to /app/ signin.jsp, and sure enough we get some input.
We get some display here, and the URL changes to /app/ signin.jsp.
Frequently in a Java web application,
you'll need to create application-relative URLs,
and c:url is your friend. It's the way that you do that.