So while the expression language is not a full-blown language,
it does define a set of operators that you can use within the language.
So for example it has mathematical operators,
plus, minus, div, mod, etc., it has logical operators,
so and, not, or, and it has this thing called the empty operator,
and the empty operator can be used to check if the value of something is empty.
So an empty string, a null value, 0 maybe.
These are typically used in conjunction with tags.
When we talk about writing tags a little later, we'll see more examples of this.
We can see some simple examples now.
So the expression language operators are typically used with tag libraries.
When we talk about the standard tag library in the next module,
we'll see the use of operators there.
However, just to show how these things work,
within the page here, if we add an h2 element,
and then in here add an expression,
and say something like user.name is equal to Kevin.
So user.name comes in here, that has the value Kevin,
so this should print out the value true.
So if we go to the browser, sure enough, the value true appears.
We can do the same thing with some other expressions.
So we could print out for example, the value of 3+2, comes out to be 5.
We could compare 3 and 2, and that will come out as false,
and as we saw, there are other operators that we can use within the page.
Again, just to emphasize, these are simple operators,
doesn't make this a full-blown language, but it does make certain things easier within the page.