For the IDEs for this class, I'll be using IntelliJ IDEA and also Eclipse.
To download these, you can get IntelliJ IDEA from jetbrains.com,
again simply follow the links there to the Download tab.
From here you can download one of two editions,
the Ultimate Edition, which is a paid-for,
and the Community Edition, which is free,
although the Ultimate Edition does give you a free 30-day trial,
so well worth trying that.
For Eclipse,
simply go to eclipse.org /downloads and you'll want to grab the EE Edition.
Again, make sure you grab the right one for your platform.
In this class you're running on Windows,
but there's Eclipse versions for Mac and for Linux.
As we are building Java web applications,
we'll need to run the applications on a web server.
The web server we'll be using for this class is Tomcat.
Tomcat used to be the reference implementation for the
Servlet and JavaServer Pages APIs.
It's no longer that.
It has been kicking around for a number of years and it's now at version 8.
For this class we'll be using version 7.
And again, you can grab that from tomcat.apache .org.
Go to the Download section for Tomcat 7 and just grab the zip file for this.
Unzip the zip file into the appropriate location.
Once you've done that, you again have to set a couple of environment variables.
Set CATALINA_HOME and point that at the location you've installed Tomcat,
and add CATALINA_HOME\bin to your path to make sure you
can run Tomcat from the command line.
Once you've done that, you can go to a command prompt and run catalina,
and it should just show that Tomcat is installed and able to run.
And to start Tomcat, you'll do catalina start.
And this will kick off an instance of Tomcat.
At this point, Tomcat should be running on port 8080,
so we can go to a browser and open an address on localhost:8080. And we should see the Tomcat home page.