So we are going to make use of this MVC pattern.
To do that, I'm going to introduce another servlet.
We'll call this one ControllerServlet,
and this will respond to the startup.do mapping.
I've removed that startup.do mapping from the SimpleServlet
so the application doesn't get confused.
So the first thing we do is to add the servlet class.
So we do that by right-clicking and doing New, Servlet.
We'll give this the name ControllerServlet.
That will add the servlet for me.
And here's the code.
It has a doPost and a doGet method.
And it also adds an entry into the web.xml file, which is here.
So it adds a servlet entry, but no servlet-mapping.
So the first thing to do is to add a servlet-mapping for this.
I'm going to say * .do.
Then back in the servlet, we've got to change the doGet method.
So what we'd like to do here is to create a user,
we'll treat this as maybe a login servlet,
so we'll create the user and then pass that user
data off to the JavaServer Page.
To do that, we have a User class here.
So it's just a standard JavaBean.
It has a couple of properties, a name and an email,
a getName, a setName, getEmail, and setEmail.
And we can use that within the controller.
So inside the controller, we'll create an instance of the bean.
So the ControllerServlet is acting as a controller,
and what it's now done is it's created an instance of the
bean and executed some business logic, i.e., it's given the user a name,
it's given the user an email.
We now need to pass this request onto the JavaServer Page,
and then use the JavaServer Page to display this data.
To do that, we use something called a RequestDispatcher,
and request dispatchers are available through the ServletContext.
So to get the RequestDispatcher, we first get the ServletContext,
then get the RequestDispatcher, and then forward the request onto the page.
When we get the RequestDispatcher,
we give it the name of the thing that we are dispatching to,
which in this case is the index.jsp, and we can save this in a variable.
Once we have the dispatcher,
we can now move this request onto the JavaServer Page,
and we do that by calling dispatcher., and we can
either call forward or include.
If we call include here, we send the request off to the JavaServer Page,
once that JavaServer Page is finished processing,
then the request comes back to here and we carry on processing this servlet.
If we say forward,
we send the request off to the JavaServer Page and
the code does not return here.
So we do no further processing inside the servlet.
So as this is the ControllerServlet, we've done all we need to do here,
we're going to use forward and we pass this the
request object and the response object.
So we'll now forward to the page; however,
we haven't passed on this bean to the page.
We have this user bean that we've created,
but we haven't told the page how to get that bean.
There are several ways of passing the bean to the page.
We could pass the bean through what's called global scope.
So we could call getServletContext,
and then on the ServletContext do setAttribute.
Notice that attributes have names and they're given a value,
which is the object we're passing here.
When we call setAttribute on ServletContext,
we're placing this object into global scope,
so anything that is within this web application has access to this bean.
So anything that can get at this context,
so any servlet, any JavaServer Page, can see this bean.
When we pass the bean through the ServletContext,
we make the bean available globally,
and it might be that we want to limit the scope of the bean.
So the next scope down is the session scope.
So we can't pass the bean using the session object.
This session is this user session,
so all requests sent by this user from this browser constitute the session.
Beans that go in a session scope could well be a user bean,
it could also be things like shopping carts maybe,
so any information that we need to share across all requests within the session.
The session is available through the request object.
So we say request.getSession.
And once we've done that, again we can say setAttribute,
and again the attribute is a name value pair.
The final scope we might want to use here is actually the request scope.
So the request itself has a setAttribute method.
So we're going to say setAttribute on the request,
and we give this thing a name and a value.
So here we'll give it a name of user and the value of user,
and that's just the user bean.
In this case, the request will be forwarded to the JavaServer Page.
The page could also make use of the attributes inside the request.
Once that's done,
the request is finished with and anything inside the
request such as this bean is then destroyed.
So now that we've placed the bean inside the request and
we've forwarded the request off to the page,
we can go to the page and then access the bean from the page.
So within the page we can add some code, so we can do that anywhere.
So let's here add in the code to access the bean.
So we'll get the bean from the attribute,
giving it the same name that we used within the servlet.
It has to be the appropriate type.
And we are checking here to make sure that the value isn't null.
And if it is null, it is creating an empty bean.
We can then make use of that bean within the page.
So for example here inside the div, we can say something like h2,
and then within here maybe Welcome, then a user directive,
so less than percent equals, and we have the user object,
and we'll say user.getName.
So once we have all that in place, if we go back to the browser,
and rather than browsing to index.jsp inside the app,
we could browse to work.do, and inside here we hit the servlet,
the servlet creates the bean, it gives the bean the name of Kevin,
it forwards off to the JavaServer Page,
and the JavaServer Page displays the name here, so Welcome Kevin.