So for the session listener, again there are two events.
One is fired after the session starts,
and then another event used to be fired before the session ended,
however, the Servlet 2.3 specification changed this.
So if you're running your code in a 2.3 container or later,
this event fires after the session has ended.
There's no session data available now at this point.
Again, this is passed an object, and this time it's passed an HttpSessionEvent,
and this gives us access to the HttpSession.
Let me give you an example.
So here we have a WhitePagesSessionListener,
and we can see that this has a sessionCreated and a
sessionDestroyed method that correspond to a sessionCreated
event and a sessionDestroyed event,
and they both passed the HttpSessionEvent object.
Then there's also a request listener.
So this is fired before the request comes into scope.
So it's fired before the request enters the filter chain.
We haven't talked about filter chains yet, we'll see those in the next chapter.
Then the sessionDestroyed event is fired after the
request leaves the filter chain.
So the behavior, we create a request object,
call the requestInitialized event, send the request through the chain,
which means it's being handled by everything in the chain,
including our servlet.
When the request leaves the chain, we then call the requestDestroyed event.
Both methods, again, are given access to an event object,
in this case it's the ServletRequestEvent object,
and through here, we get access to the ServletContext and the ServletRequest.
And again, an example.
So requestInitialized, requestDestroyed method, they're both passed the ServletRequestEvent object.