So we've seen how to write tags in tag files.
Those are written using fragments of JavaServer Pages.
We've seen how to gather those tag files together into a tag library.
We can now take a look at how we write tags actually in Java itself,
and this gives us more flexibility because,
well,
this is Java and Java obviously is more powerful
language than just using JSP on its own.
Tags written in Java must be part of the tag library,
which is why we introduced tag libraries first.
So we create our first Java tag, we go into our taglib project,
we go to the main folder, and we can add a subfolder called java.
Then inside this,
we can add a new package and create a package called com.mantiso.
And then inside this package we can create our first tag.
And again, just to do what we did with the tag files,
we'll create a Java class, and we'll call this thing Simple.
So there are various ways of implementing tags in Java.
But by far,
the most straightforward way is to extend a base class called SimpleTagSupport.
So here we just say extends SimpleTagSupport,
and that will bring in the import for us,
and then inside here we simply add a method,
override a method called doTag,
and it's inside this method that we add the work of the tag.
If we look at the SimpleTagSupport class,
we can see that this class has various properties that we have access to.
We have something called a JspContext.
The JspContext is similar to things like the ServletContext.
So this gives us access to the outside world.
And we can use this JspContext to write out into the output stream
that the JSP is currently being rendered to.
So inside the tag, we can call getJspContext.
What this will return us is something of type JspContext
that is in fact actually a PageContext.
If you remember back to the JSP chapters,
the PageContext is the thing that a JavaServer Page creates to,
again, let us have access to things outside the page,
so things like an output stream for example.
So here I can say PageContext ctx = getJspContext.
And we can either cast, we can cast this the appropriate thing.
Once I have the PageContext, this gives me access to the output stream,
so I can called getOut.
And then to this thing, I can write, and I can write a message into the page.
So let's say Hello from this tag.
Now that we've written the tag, we have to add this tag to the tag library,
and we do that by editing the TLD file.
So in the TLD file, we add a tag attribute,
and this tag attribute have various sub-attributes,
so we need to give this thing a name.
So we can call it Simple.
We specify the tag-class, which is going to be com.mantiso .simple.
And we tell the library, the body-content of the tag.
So just like we do for tag-files, we say body-content,
in this case we'll have body-content of empty.
Once we have that, we can then use the tag in the page.
So I go to the JSP page and go to the active pane,
which is just the home pane, then inside here above the priority tag,
you can say m:, and Simple shows up there,
so I can say n:simple.
So we're using the same tag library prefix and the same tag
library URI as we used for the tag files.
We can mix tag files and tags within the same tag library.
So again, if I deploy the application and go to the browser and refresh,
then we see Hello from this tag on the page,
so the tag is working.
So that was indeed a simple tag.
We can also write something slightly more complex.
So how about having a tag that maybe repeats data?
So we go back to our tag library and add a new Java class,
let's call this Repeat.
And again, this will extend SimpleTagSupport.
And again, we want to override doTag.
So for this tag, we want to specify how many times to repeat the body of the tag.
So to do that, we can add a public setter method, so public void setRepeat.
The setRepeat will take an int, it should be the repeat.
And we can assign this value to a variable within the class.
Then within the tag body, we can say for int i = 0, i is less than repeat, i++.
Then inside the loop, we can execute the body of the tag.
So the way we do that is by calling another helper called getJspBody,
and getJspBody returns back to us the actual body data
that's encapsulated by this tag.
Once we have that, we can then call invoke,
and if we call invoke null,
this will just write out that data into the current output stream,
so the current place the page is being rendered to.
So this is similar to executing a fragment inside a tag file.
So once we have this tag in place,
we need to add information about this tag to the TLD file.
So we need to add another tag element in here,
this thing will have a name, and we can call this thing repeat.
It's going to have a tag class,
and the tag class is going to be com.mantiso .repeat.
Then we'll have body-content.
But now the body-content won't be empty just like our tag file,
the body-content will be scriptless.
This tag also has an attribute, the name of the attribute will be repeat.
And again, just like a tag file, we can specify that this attribute is required.
So we can say required is true.
Once we have this in place, we can go back to the JavaServer Page,
so index.jsp, and here where we have our simple tag,
we could wrap that in the repeat.
We can say m:repeat, repeat equals, let's say, 5 times here.
And if we grab the closing tag and wrap that around our embedded tag,
again we need to deploy the application.
And if we go back to the browser and we refresh,
which we should see Hello from this tag repeated five times.
And there we are, no extra data in here, but we could mix in some HTML as well.
So we can say simple and then maybe put a break here.
No need to deploy this time, it's just an HTML change,
go back to the browser and refresh, and sure enough, we get Hello from this tag with HTML embedded inside it.