So there's one last thing to do.
At the moment, the files we're using such as header.jsp,
errorpage.jsp, and index.jsp are publicly available.
This means that somebody within the browser could send
a request directly to those pages.
So they could do something like this,
and that doesn't work because we haven't set the name.
And to the set the name we have to go through the controller.
The same applies to errorpage.jsp.
And again, we end up with some,
we get output here because the exception object hasn't been set
and we're not using this as an error page.
The way we hide the pages is by moving them into the WEB-INF directory.
Anything in the WEB-INF directory is not publicly available.
So back in the app, if we take these three pages,
we pick them, we just move them into WEB-INF.
We need to check that in web.xml the error-page is
set to be at WEB- INF.errorpage, which it is.
We also need to make sure that in ControllerServlet,
we are now getting a RequestDispatcher for /WEB-INF/ index.jsp.
And then we can redeploy the application.
Once the app has been redeployed,
within the browser if I try and access errorpage.jsp,
it's no longer available and I can't get to WEB-INF/ errorpage.jsp.
If I go back to the servlet, the page is still available,
so we're still hitting index.jsp, but it's now in the WEB-INF directory.
And if I try and send a request to home,
and this was the request we used previously to fire off the error handler,
we again hit the error page, and the error message is displayed correctly.
And this is typically how you build an MVC application using the
foundations of servlets and JavaServer Pages,
by making sure the JavaServer Pages are only used as part of the view and only available indirectly through a servlet.