So, we've seen filters in the previous chapter.
Filters can also be asynchronous, but the mechanism is very similar to servlets.
So again, we mark the filters being asynchronous,
we grab the context from the request object,
and we do any work we need to asynchronously inside the servlet
before chaining the request further down the call.
So in summary, the Servlet 3 specification introduced asynchronous behavior.
We can write asynchronous servlets, we can write asynchronous filters.
However, be careful when you're using asynchronous calls inside of a container.
You may simply end up offloading the call from one
thread to another with no real benefit.
The servlet container may end up using another thread that
could simply be used for other requests.
You may be better creating a thread pool yourself and
handling the request off that thread pool.
That's the end of the class. Thank you for joining me, and I hope you've enjoyed it.