So, certain things to be aware of with listeners.
If inside our listener code we throw an exception,
then the exception gets passed to the application to
handle and no more listeners get fired.
If the exception is initialized by the container,
for example the application startup that's an exception that gets thrown,
these exceptions aren't handled by the application,
but they may cause the container to make the application unavailable,
and in this case the container will return a 500 status code,
so the client knows that it can no longer use the application.
So in summary, web applications fire events that we may be interested in,
and an event listener can respond to these events.
There are application, session, request,
start and end events, as well as various attribute events,
and we've seen we can configure these event handlers either in web.xml or using annotations.