[Autogenerated] Hi, This is Craig Golightly and welcome to using I am users,
groups, policies and rolls.
We're going to start out talking about I am identities.
Specifically,
I am users and how to create and manage those users with I am groups will also
cover the different types and use cases for I am policies.
And I am Rolls.
I am is a big topic, so you'll definitely be seeing more of it.
This module will give you a solid understanding of these core pieces
of I am that you can build on in future modules.
You have a couple of different options for identities.
In a WS you can define an I am username code,
be tied to a person or application with access to
certain resource is in an AWS account.
You can also leverage existing users Federated from a company
directory or other identity providers like Amazon,
Facebook and Google.
We'll cover federation more when we talk about the
Amazon Cognito service later on.
In this course, when you create an I am username,
decide what credentials you want to allow for that user.
You can allow a username and password for console access as well
as A W s access keys for programmatic calls.
You can also configure an M F A device for the user or
require them to set one up when they log in.
As an I am user administrator,
you can disable or reset passwords as well as generate,
deactivate or delete A W S access keys.
These tools can help you manage user access as your organization changes.
Or if a user account is compromised in AWS,
you'll define permissions using policies.
Each policy has four components principle,
which is the entity that is allowed or denied access.
Usually and I am username.
I am roll action, which is the type of access that is allowed or denied resource,
which is the Amazon resource.
The action will act on and condition,
which defines the conditions under which the access to find is valid.
When you first create an AWS account, you have one user.
The root user who is allowed to do all actions on all
resource is under any condition.
This is why you do not want to use the root user for anything
more than the initial set up of the account,
or the few tasks that can only be done by the root user.
Policies are easy to create and use,
and they provide a very granular way to define user access in your
AWS account with over 175 services and growing.
Giving every user full access to all services is rarely necessary
and is not a recommended way to manage your users.
At the very least, you should determine which services a user actually needs,
then create a policy to only grant them access to those services.
You can take it a step further and grant only the
operations they need to do their job.
In that service, for example, a users may need read only access to an S3 bucket.
Or you may only want to allow certain users to delete E.
C.
Two instances.
We'll cover more detailed policy configurations in the designing
for advanced security within a W S course.
But policies don't have to be complicated,
and we're going to use them from the beginning so you can avoid the
pitfalls of making every user and administrator.
AWS starts with deny for all actions.
By default,
there must be an allow present and no specific deny when it evaluates a request.
Everything in a request must match up with a policy
in order for it to be allowed.
If something isn't working like you expect it to,
then one of the conditions is not matching.
Between the request and the defined policies.
Look at the principal making the request,
the action being requested,
the resource the request wants to act on and all of the
conditions which can include things like I,
P address, time of day and many other items.
We'll get into all of the different policy types and how
they interact with each other later on.
But these basic policy mechanics can help you evaluate
scenarios that involve I am permissions in a W.
S.
You can have resource based policies and identity based policies.
Let's first look at identity based policies.
AWS has several managed policies that cover the most
common use cases for your account.
These error automatically updated and maintained by AWS
without you having to make changes.
You can also create a customer managed policy.
If you need some specific customize ations that you
can't find in an AWS managed policy,
you can use a similar AWS managed policy as a starting point,
then edit it for your specific needs.
Using managed policies makes maintenance easier,
since the policies could be attached to multiple principal entities
and they centralize your I am policy management.
I am also stores up to five versions of your customer managed
policies to help you manage policy changes in the event you
need to roll back a policy change.
A W S recommends that you use managed policies for most scenarios.
The other type of identity based policy is an in line policy.
These error embedded directly in an entity and have a 1 to 1 relationship.
The policy only exists within the entity,
so when you delete the entity, any in line policies are also deleted.
In line.
Policies could be used to ensure that the policy defined is assigned
only to the specific user where you define the policy.
But for most cases,
you should be using managed policies while you can
attach policies directly to users.
An easier way to manage user access is to attach policies to I am groups,
then add users to those groups.
The group policy will automatically be applied to any users in the group.
This allows easier movement of users from group to group.
As the rules change, and as you expand your use of AWS,
for example,
you could have an administrator's group that have full access to the account,
then the developers group with a different set of permissions.
Many organizations also have a billing group to limit
access to account and payment information.
You can set up whatever groups you need based on your organization and rolls.
Just keep in mind that you can only ad and I am username a maximum of 10 groups. That's an AWS limit and cannot be increased.