[Autogenerated] Hi.
This is Craig Golightly and welcome to reserved instances and spots reserved.
Easy to instances can help you in two main ways.
First, price reserved instances.
Can do have a significant cost savings over on demand instances.
Second capacity reserved instances guarantee you capacity for a certain
instantiate type in the availability zone you have reserved.
You may have received the insufficient instance capacity
message when launching an instance,
meaning that AWS doesn't have enough on demand capacity
in that particular availability zone.
To service the request with reserved instances,
you're guaranteed to have instances available for the term of the
agreement When you specify and availability zone.
A reserved instance isn't actually an instance, but it's an agreement with AWS.
The first part of the agreement has to do with the instance itself,
specifically instantiate type.
For example, M five large the region where the instance will run,
for example, US East one.
The tendency of the instantiate er shared or dedicated,
and the operating system, for example, Linux or windows.
The second part of the agreement is a term commitment.
How long are you going to commit to use these instantiate You're reserving?
You can specify.
One year or three years with a three year commitment getting a larger discount.
The third part of the agreement is the payment option.
You can pay for everything up front and not be billed for
the rest of the term for that instance, partial up front,
where you pay some upfront cost than the rest at an hourly
rate throughout the term or no upfront,
where you're just build an hourly rate throughout the term.
Once you have a reserved instance agreement in place,
then the reserved instance rate will apply to instances that match the
criteria of the reserved instances you have purchased.
For example,
suppose you have four M five large Linux instances running on
shared hardware in the US East one region.
Suppose that the on demand price for these instances is 10 cents an hour.
This configuration would cost you 40 cents an hour.
Let's say you purchased two reserved instance contracts that
apply to M five large Linux instances running on shared
hardware in the US East one region.
Suppose the hourly rate for those works out to be five cents an hour.
In this case,
your bill for an hour would show two instances at the
reserved rate of five cents an hour and two instances at the
on demand rate of 10 cents an hour, for a total of 30 cents an hour.
If you terminated two of those instances,
then you would just be charged for two instances at the
reserve rate of five cents an hour, for a total of 10 cents an hour.
Note that the reserved instance rate isn't tied to a specific.
Easy.
To instance, when we terminated two of the four instances,
then the reserved instance rate was simply applied to the next
running instantiate that matches the contract.
The other thing to be aware of is that you are being charged what amounts
to a reduced hourly rate for your reserved instances,
whether or not you are using any instances.
So if you had to reserved instance contracts that
were not running any instances,
you would still be charged for the two reserved instance contracts,
or 10 cents an hour.
Traditional reserved instances are designed to offset the cost of workloads
that you know are going to be running all of the time.
There are some additional options you can apply to reserved
instances to give you more flexibility.
Scheduled reserved instances allow you to choose a
reservation that Rikers on a daily,
weekly or monthly basis with a start time and duration.
You are then charged a discounted rate for instances during that window.
This could be a good option for reports or batch processing that happens on a
regular interval but does not need to run all of the time.
Scheduled reserved instances are only available for certain instance types,
so you want to check out the AWS documentation for the
latest details before setting that up.
Standard reserved instances allow you to modify instant size during the term.
For example, from M five large to M five extra large convertible.
Reserved instances allow you to exchange for another
convertible reserved instance,
and change things like instantiate yam lee type platform scope or tendency.
If you think you want to get into convertible reserved instances,
be sure to read the AWS documentation for important details.
When using this option,
a regional reserved instance will apply the discount for the
instance in any availability zone of a region where,
as a zonal reserved instance,
will only apply to instances running in a specific availability zone.
Note.
that regional reserved instances do not guarantee a capacity reservation.
So if your main use case is to ensure capacity, then be sure you are setting up zonal, reserved instances.