[Autogenerated] Hi, This is Craig Golightly,
and welcome to maintaining compliance.
We're going to cover the shared responsibility model to understand what AWS is
responsible for when it comes to cloud security and compliance and what items
are your responsibility As a customer using AWS,
we'll cover AWS artifact, which is a great source.
AWS provides free of charge to give you the information you
need to meet your compliance guidelines.
Finally, we'll cover some tools you can use to limit and control access,
like password settings and service control policies or s.
C.
P s.
When we talk about shared responsibility, you can think of it like buying a car.
When you buy a car, you expect that certain things will work in a certain way.
For example, when you push on the gas pedal,
it'll go faster, and when you push on the brake,
it's going to slow down.
The car manufacturer guarantees that those things are going to
work according to a standard expectation.
However,
they have no control over how you're going to drive the
car once you get behind the wheel.
If you break the speed limit because you chose to go too fast,
you will be issued a ticket, not the manufacturer with a W s.
You can think of it as security of the cloud versus security.
In the cloud security of the cloud are those things that AWS is responsible for,
such as the Physical Data center, including physical security,
redundant power cooling and restricting access to authorized personnel.
Only the hardware.
Redundant physical systems to run the infrastructure.
Backup disks.
Proper disposal for out of service hard drives and regular
updates and maintenance for the equipment.
The software.
The underlying host operating systems that run virtual services.
Keeping them patched and up to date software systems used
by customers to interact with the cloud.
And networking sufficient redundant internet
connections to handle the traffic switches,
firewalls, routers,
cable and everything else necessary to move data into out of and
within data centers and customer networks,
as well as preventing attacks on that network infrastructure.
As an AWS customer,
you are responsible for proper configuration of the provided resource is,
for example, if you leave several ports wide open,
then your services could be compromised because of your configuration settings.
You must enforce strong credentials, especially on your route accounts,
utilizing things like multi factor authentication and password
policies to prevent compromise through weak credentials.
You also need to keep track of any access keys you issue and
monitor the use and rotation of such keys.
Your application must be secure.
Weakness in your application could expose.
Underlying resource is in your account,
avoiding things like embedding long term credentials in your
account and instead utilizing temporary credentials with STS can
help mitigate risks due to your application.
Finally,
what you do with customer data to ensure proper handling is your responsibility.
For example,
ensuring encryption both in transit and at rest is
something you have to choose to do.
AWS services offer many options for encrypting data,
but you have to use them in your handling of
customer data for them to be effective.
Here's a graphic that AWS has put together to detail
the shared responsibility model.
You can find it at AWS .NET amazon dot com slash compliance
slash shared dash responsibility Dash model.
You confined many different compliance related resource is
under the compliance pages of the AWS website.
Ultimately,
it is your compliance requirements that will determine how much or how little of
the AWS infrastructure and its various features you will utilize in your
application architecture er to meet those requirements.
Another great tool for compliance is A.
W s artifact.
This is a central resource to find compliance related information on demand.
You can Elektronik lee sign agreements you may need for
regulations like HIPPA or download audit reports for
various regulations like PC I and S O.
C.
Users will need certain I am permissions to accept agreements.
So be sure to work with representatives from your legal
department to understand what you need to demonstrate compliance for your organization.