[Autogenerated] Let's go to the AWS console and create an I am
group in an I am user will attach an AWS managed policy to a
group and assign a user to that group.
Let's create a couple of I am users.
Go to I am.
Then select users will add a user.
Let's call this admin one and we can.
Go ahead and add another user in the same console.
We'll call it Dev one.
Notice how we can select the access type for these users.
We can enable programmatic and or console access.
All just enable console access.
For now,
you can decide what type of password and whether they need to reset
it when they log in will go to the next screen.
Notice the message about groups.
It's much easier to manage users by creating groups
than adding the users to those groups.
So we'll go ahead and create a couple of groups for these users.
I'll call the first one administrators and I'll create
another group called developers.
These to users will automatically be added to these two groups.
We'll go ahead and shuffle the users to the correct
groups after we're done creating them.
I'm not going to add any tags at this point.
At this point,
we can see to users Admin one and Dev one that have
AWS console access with a password,
and they'll be a member of the administrators and developers group
with the ability to change their own password.
At this point, the users are created as the administrator.
You could send them email with logging instructions or
download a CSV with their passwords.
I'll go ahead and download the CSV so that we can use that later on in.
The demo also noticed the management console sign in.
This has the account number embedded so that they
can sign into the correct account.
These users only exist in this AWS account,
so they need to know that information, in order to log into the console,
will exit the wizard and go back to the AM page to manage which
groups a user belongs to select the username.
Then, under groups,
you can remove any groups that they're currently
assigned to or add them to a new group.
I'll remove the admin one user from the developers group,
then go back and remove the Dev one user from the administrators
group now that the users are in the correct group.
Let's take a look at some additional options to
manage each user under permissions.
We can.
See which policies are attached to this user.
This user only has permission to change their password.
Let's take a look at security credentials.
This is where you can see their activity,
whether or not they've logged into the password.
You can manage the console password, require them to use an M F A device,
and you can also manage access keys and SSH keys.
Let's go ahead and create an access key for the Dev user to see how that works.
We'll download the CSV so that we can configure that later on.
Keep in mind that you cannot retrieve a secret key from the AWS console.
If the user somehow loses their key, you can simply create another one.
Then deactivate or delete the lost key to manage groups.
Select groups, then the group name you want to manage.
We need to add some permissions to this group so that the
administrators can actually do something.
We'll go ahead and attach an AWS managed policy.
We'll use administrator access.
You can take a look at the policy details under show policy,
and we can see that this allows all actions on all.
Resource is this is fine for the administrators group,
but suppose our developers only need access to S3.
Let's go to the developers group and attach a policy
that only allows access to S3.
We'll select Amazon S3 full access and attached the policy.
Let's log in using the Dev one user.
I'll go to the console,
sign in link in a different browser and enter the username
and the password that was generated.
Recall that we required a password change on the first log in,
so I'll take care of that.
This user only has access to S3.
Let's go ahead and go to S3 and create a bucket.
We successfully created the bucket and we can access at
list and do everything that we need to do.
If this user tries to go to easy to and see any running instances,
notice how they get an error.
They're not authorized to perform this operation.
If we go back to the administrator's account and refresh,
we'll see under console password that it's enabled
and it was last signed in today.
You could go ahead and disable the password or set a new password or
require the user to reset it the next time they sign in.
Let's try using the access keys for the Dev one user to use the AWS CLI.
I've gone ahead and configured this AWS CLI with the
secret and access key for the Dev one user.
Let's try listing the S3 buckets.
They're we can See the bucket that was created by this user.
If we go back to the admin console we can, see when the key was last used.
If we make the key inactive and the user tries to run the command again,
notice how they get an invalid access key message.
Creating separate I am users than issuing them.
Keys is imperative to account safety.
It's very easy to activate or inactivate keys or delete
and create new ones if you need to. We'll go ahead and make the key active again, and now we can see that it works