[Autogenerated] Now that you've enabled organizations,
you can start adding other AWS accounts as member accounts in your organization,
you can add an existing account or create a new account.
When you add an existing account,
it will send an invitation to the root user of that account who will need to
accept the invitation in order to join the organization.
When you create a new account,
it is automatically added to your organization by default.
Your organization has a root and all accounts start out assigned to the route.
You can use organizational units to structure and group
accounts within your AWS organization.
Organizational units can also contain other organizational units.
Let's go add a couple of member accounts to our AWS organization,
will create a new account and also invite an existing
account to join the organization.
Then we'll create some organizational units to see that process and
add a member account to an organizational unit.
Let's add a new member account to the organization,
select add account and will first create an AWS account in this organization.
Enter a name for this AWS account, an email that is globally unique.
In other words,
it can't already be associate ID with another AWS
account and for the I am role name.
When you create a new member account in your organization,
these organization account access role is automatically added by a W S.
This allows you full control of the member account from the master account.
Once that's all filled in, go ahead and click create.
Then after a minute you'll see the new account that was created.
You might be asking.
So how in the world do I log into that account?
We never set a password.
In order to access the account that you just created,
you need to log out,
then log in using the root user email of the account you created
in this case test plus one at sea that go com.
I'll go ahead and log out of my master account,
then log in using the member account.
At this point, we never set a password,
so go ahead and use the forgot password link.
Solve the puzzle, then check your email for the password.
Reset instructions.
You should also see a welcome email for that account that you created.
We'll click the password reset link,
then set a password for the root user of this new
member account in our AWS organization.
Remember,
you should be using a secrets manager with a randomly
generated password at least 20 characters long.
Now you can sign in to your account here,
we can see our newly created member account.
That's part of our AWS organization.
We won't do anything else in this account for now,
as this demo was mainly just to see how to create a new
account inside of your organization.
Let's go back to our master account and invite an
existing account to join our organization.
Well,
log out of the member account and log back into the master account
will go to AWS organizations we can CR two accounts.
Let's add another one.
This time we'll select invite account.
I've opened a different AWS account already with a different route user,
so we'll invite that one to join our organization.
If you have a new AWS account,
you'll need to verify your email address before you're able to
invite other accounts to join your organization.
Once you verified the email address of the master account,
you can try again with the invitation.
I'll enter the email of the root user for the account that
I want to invite to the organization.
You can add some notes, then click invite.
The invitation will show up under the invitations tab.
If you're managing multiple invitations,
this helps you see the status of those invitations.
And when they're going to expire,
the root user of the account that you're inviting will get an email like this
explaining that they've been invited to join the organization.
They can then log in to their AWS console to view the invitation.
Here is the invitation in the account that you would
like to join your organization.
Notice how it lists the master account name and email and the requested
controls that the master account will have over this account.
If you join, I'll go ahead and click.
Accept confirmed the action and receive the confirmation
notice that the member account can choose to leave the
organization back in the master account.
If we refreshed the invitations, we can see,
the account has accepted the invitation.
Now,
when we go to accounts we can see the account that was
created and the account that joined.
Let's create some organizational units and place these
accounts in those organizational units.
Go to organize accounts.
Then select new organizational unit.
Let's make a sales global app one then inside of the sales organizational unit.
Let's create a customer One organizational unit to do that,
select the sails unit,
then select new organizational unit Notice This will nest the customer One
organizational unit under the sales organizational unit.
If we go back to route we can, see the three accounts Member one,
which is one of our member accounts test to which is the other member account.
Then demo, which is the master account denoted by the star.
If I select member one than organizational units we can,
see that it is not currently assigned.
Select move and I'll go ahead and put this one in global app one.
Let's also move test to into the customer One organizational unit.
Now, when we select those organizational units we can see the account listed,
we select global app one we see the other member account.
A.
W s organizations are a great feature to help you avoid the problems
Globomantics experienced when they started using AWS.
They're easy to create and free to use.
You now know how to add accounts to an organization both new and
existing and you've seen how organizational units can help you
structure the member accounts within your organization,
join me in the next module to learn about using I am users,
groups,
policies and roles and see how you can manage user access and permissions in your member accounts.