[Autogenerated] the cost optimization pillar of the AWS.
Well architected framework identifies five design principles.
First, adopt a consumption model.
Pay only for what you consume when you need it.
Second measure overall efficiency.
Measure the business output of your system and the
costs associated with delivering it.
Third, stop spending money on data center operations.
Let A W S do the heavy lifting of racking,
stacking and powering IT infrastructure so you can focus on
your customers and value added projects.
Fourth, analyze an attribute expenditure.
Identify the usage and cost of systems and what I T costs
are tied to different revenue streams.
Fifth, Use managed services to reduce cost of ownership.
There's several services that you need to just work in
order to get your actual work done.
These services usually involve a lot of undifferentiated heavy lifting.
By utilizing managed services that operate at cloud scale,
you lower your operational burden and get services at a
lower cost per unit than doing it yourself.
This can especially be true for things like redundant storage,
long term archival and email services.
The well architected framework also identifies four best practice areas for
cost optimization in the cloud expenditure awareness.
Cost effective resource is matching supply and demand and optimizing over time.
We've already covered several items from these four areas,
so we'll just highlights um, key actions you can take in each area.
Setting up your account with AWS organizations and utilizing tagging to
overlay business and organizational information onto billing and usage
data is extremely helpful to maintain cost awareness and properly
attribute costs for your operations.
Utilizing reports can do give proper visibility to
stakeholders and help them understand the differences
between cloud and on premises operations.
Actively defining the lifecycle for resource is and regular
cleanup ensures you don't have services.
Adding to your bill that you're not aware of several of the common
mistakes we discussed dealt with cost effective use of resource is
remember right size your resource is and understand the different
purchasing options for the services you're using.
Always explore managed services before doing it yourself to avoid
the undifferentiated heavy lifting that takes resource is away from
your core business value proposition.
Look for ways to optimize your data transfer through proper geographic selection
and utilizing services like cloudfront and direct Connect.
This could help ease some of the load on your compute resource is and
provide your customers with a better experience.
There are three main strategies you could take when it comes to
matching supply and demand first demand based.
This leverages that elasticity of clouds Resource is
where you can programmatically vary.
The amount of resource is dynamically based on demand.
Second, buffer based.
This leverages things like queues or streams to smooth out the demand on
consumers and handle less time sensitive loads with fewer.
Resource is third time based.
When you have a predictable, well defined demand,
you can scale resource is up and down based on time of day,
day of week and other time based parameters.
Cost optimization is an ongoing effort to measure, monitor and improve.
You're going to continually established goals and metrics.
Gather insight from available tools,
analyze the data and report and validate according
to your cost optimization goals.
Be sure to keep up on new features that affect your
services and how you purchase those services.
For example, new instance types are regularly added to easy to,
and savings plans were introduced several years after reserved instances.
Some of these new features can significantly affect
cost optimization for your AWS usage.
You've seen some common cost mistakes people make in their AWS accounts.
So you know what to avoid.
And you've learned about the tools AWS provides to
make cost optimization easier.
You know some additional cost benefits you can gain
from utilizing A W S organizations, and we've covered some key principles.
You can apply as you continually look for ways to optimize costs.
If you're using easy to instances,
it is essential that you understand how reserved and spot instances work.
We'll take an in depth look at those in the next module, as well as other AWS services that offer a reserved pricing model.