[Autogenerated] a resource based policy is attached to
a resource instead of an identity,
as three buckets are a common use case for resource based policies and a role.
Trust policy is also a resource based policy for a complete list of
AWS services that support resource based policies.
See the AWS documentation just because a resource based
policy grants permission a username us to also be given
permission from their account to act on.
The resource like we saw in the previous demo and AWS account
was an authorized principle for a role.
However,
policies for individual users in the account could allow or
prevent users from assuming that role,
even though the resource based policy on the role allowed it
recall that a user will have a certain set of permissions when
they operate in their account.
When they assume a role,
they leave those permissions behind and take on only
the permissions granted to the role.
For example, if a trusting account used a role to allow cross account access,
user's in the trusted account would only have the permissions
defined by the role when they assumed that role to access the
resource with resource based policies,
the policy is attached directly to the resource you want to share and
specifies which principles can access that resource.
When a principal accesses the resource,
they retain all of their normal account permissions.
Here is a resource based policy that allows all members of this AWS
account to perform the list bucket action on the Docks bucket and the
GETT Object Action on Objects in the Docks bucket.
This policy defines the maximum allowed access from the trusted account,
specified as a principal in the trusted account that has been granted
access users will need to be given permission to perform actions on the
resource is this policy could be added to a group.
Then users who belong to the group could perform both actions that error
allowed by the resource based policy attached to the bucket.
However, if the policy only specified the list bucket operation on the bucket,
then users in this account would not be able to perform the gett object action even though the resource based policy allows it