[Autogenerated] AWS Security Token Service,
or STS,
allows you to request temporary credentials for limited access to
your resource is without creating an I am user.
STS Credentials are generated on demand,
so you don't have to embed any long term access keys in your application.
Since they are temporary credentials,
you don't have to rotate them or remember to remove
them when they're no longer need it.
There's an STS endpoint you can interact with directly,
and the AWS SdK s have libraries and functions to
create programmatic access to STS.
STS also supports AWS CloudTrail so you can log requests
and information about the request,
such as who made the request and when it was made.
And those logs will be placed in an S3 bucket.
STS is what enables the Samel 2D a to federation
we've been discussing in this module.
Let's take a closer look at the conceptual flow a client authenticates with an
identity provider and the identity provider returns a sample token that token
can do then be used to call assume role with XAML.
The role must be defined in the account that has the resource is the
client wants access to and will determine what permissions the client has
to access resource is when it resumes the role.
STS returns a temporary security credential that can be
used to assume the requested roll.
The client uses the STS credential to assume a role
to access the desired service, in this case,
S3.
To retrieve an object from a bucket,
you can also use federation to allow external users
access to services in your AWS account.
Using Amazon Cognito Cognito allows users to authenticate with
third-party identity providers like Amazon,
Facebook and Google then exchange the token from the
identity provider for a cognito token.
The cognito token can then be used to get temporary
credentials from STS to access.
Resource is in your AWS account.
Cognito also allows you to create an unauthenticated profile to
still allow some access to unauthenticated users of your application
without making your resource is public.
Cognito is a great solution to offload common user
management tasks like user creation, verification,
authentication and password reset.
This can save you a lot of time and maintenance,
not to mention that cognito is very secure and can scale to millions of users.
With these, you've got some additional options now for user management.
You've seen how to use a W s s S O to create Federated
users and how to manage what access.
Those users have two different AWS accounts in your A W s organization.
You can also integrate with other third-party services
with your single sign on experience.
You've seen how STS enables federation and some of the
advantages of using temporary credentials from STS.
Finally, if you have external users to manage,
you can leverage cognito to offload those tasks from your applications and
grant secure temporary access to your AWS resource is join me in the next
module to learn about how you can maintain compliance and some of the tools AWS provides to make that easier.