Getting information about your Kubernetes deployments and objects can help you
to see if they're in their expected states and give you the information you
need to fix them if they're not. Kubectl offers a number of commands that can
help you see what's going on in your Kubernetes clusters. We've covered a few
of the most common kubectl commands in previous modules. However, as you're
working with Kubernetes,
you might want to get information about a number of different components.
One of the most essential commands for quickly getting information about
the current deployment is the kubectl get all command that you see at
the top here. Kubectl get all is a quick way to see the status of all
the important Kubernetes objects, including deployments,
ReplicaSets, nodes, pods, and services.
You can use this command to quickly see if the objects running are in
their expected states, as well as their current status.
Next, if you have performance issues,
you might want to look into using the kubectl top commands that you
see here underneath that. A kubectl top allows you to see your
current CPU, memory, and storage utilization.
If you're having trouble connecting to your pods,
knowing their IP addresses can be very important.
We've seen this in the previous modules,
but Kubernetes services provides the network connectivity for your pods.
Running the kubectl get services command shows the status of your services,
as well as the external IP addresses that you're using. Next, a best practice
in managing Kubernetes is to make sure that all your yaml declarations are
part of a source control system.
However,
not everybody does that, and if you haven't done that and you have
any doubts about how a given object was created,
you can essentially reverse engineer your Kubernetes components and
retrieve the yaml that was used for them by using the ‑o yaml
parameter as part of your kubectl get commands.
For example, to get the yaml for a pod,
you could use kubectl get pod, supply the pod name,
and then the ‑o yaml parameters,
as you can see at the bottom of this screen. Next,
kubectl describe commands, they can be an essential tool about getting
information about almost all Kubernetes deployments.
We've seen a few examples of using kubectl described in the previous modules,
so I won't spend a lot of time on it here,
but it can be an essential troubleshooting tool. Kubectl
describe can be used with deployments, pods, and storage.
Filtering with the label parameter like you see here,
can help you find and focus on the apps that you're interested in.
Next, examining Kubernetes logs is one of the most important
troubleshooting tools that you're going to have. Kubernetes logs for SQL
Server pods are generated directly by the SQL Server application, and if
SQL Server is having some type of problem,
these logs can be one of the best places to get information.
Kubectl logs displays the logs for a pod. Like the kubectl describe
command, using labels can be a convenient way to quickly get
information about the apps that you're interested in without having
to retrieve the actual pod name, which can be somewhat lengthy.
Kubectl logs shows you the logs for a pod that's currently running,
but what about a pod that's crashed and it's not
running? Is there a way to see that too?
Well, fortunately,
there is. By adding the ‑p for ‑‑previous, the ‑p parameter means previous pod
to your kubectl logs command like you see here in the middle,
you can retrieve the logs for the previous instance of a pod.
Kubernetes also keeps track of something that it calls events.
Events are different from logs.
Logs are generated by the application.
Kubernetes events essentially track changes in
state to the objects in a cluster.
Events show you things like when a container is being created
or when it starts or when it terminates.
Events provide only limited information,
though. They'll tell you what happened, but not much about why it happened.
Events are pretty easy to see when you're trying to debug different issues.
For example, when you use the kubectl describe pod commands,
these will show the events at the end of the output display.
And, like you would expect,
running kubectl get events will retrieve the events for the cluster.
By default, they're sorted by resource, so if you
want to see them ordered by time,
you can add the ‑‑sort‑by parameter like you can see in this example.
Likewise, if you want to restrict the events to a certain resource type,
you can use the ‑‑field‑selector parameter like you
can see here at the bottom to, say,
restrict the display or filter the display for just pods. Next, what if
you've made a mistake in your deployments or services?
How do you deal with that?
Well,
there's a couple ways. Kubernetes allows you to edit
and update your objects, however, since Kubernetes is declarative,
sometimes it's easier just to delete the objects and recreate them after you
edit your yaml. The kubectl delete command enables you to roll back or undo the
results of previous kubectl apply or create commands.
To use kubectl delete, simply supply the ‑f parameter pointed to the yaml
file that you used to originally create your objects, and execute that,
and the objects you want will be rolled back.
Another problem that you may run into is when you try to
use the wrong password when you attempt to start or
connect to your SQL Server pods.
If you attempt to use the wrong password,
you're not going to be able to connect to those SQL Server instances.
Kubernetes secrets can help you obfuscate sensitive data like passwords,
but they can also be retrieved if you think there might be a problem using the
correct password. The kubectl get secret command can retrieve, and optionally
decode passwords and other data stored in Kubernetes secrets, like you see
here on this slide. Here you can see how you can get the value of the
Kubernetes secrets named mssql‑secret.
And by the way, as with most kubectl commands,
if you're using namespaces, you can essentially add the ‑‑namespaces
parameter to filter on the desired namespaces.
I didn't show any namespace examples here because I didn't need
them, but in production you often use them. Okay, we've covered the basics, so let's move on to a demo.