A couple of other tools that can provide some useful information are
the Kubernetes dashboard and then kubectl exec.
The Kubernetes dashboard is a web‑based portal that provides
information about your Kubernetes deployment.
To run this on AKS, you need to grant some AKS cluster binding permissions.
Otherwise,
you can basically run this portal by opening a connection using kubectl proxy
and then opening your web browser to the following URL This is going to
launch the dashboard that you can see to the right,
and you'll see this in action in just a second.
Next, you can use kubectl exec to execute commands in the pod's container.
You can use these commands to view the status of the
container or to make changes to it.
With kubectl exec, you pass in the it parameter,
which indicates that you're running this command interactively.
And then you pass in the pod name followed by two dashes.
After the dashes, then you pass in the actual command you want to run.
Here you can see this example would run the top command in our container.
Even more useful from a troubleshooting point of view is
the ability to open an interactive shell on the containers
that are running in your pods.
To open an interactive shell, you can use the kubectl exec command,
like you see here.
Again, you pass it that it flag, indicating that this is going to be interactive,
then the pod name, followed by two dashes,
then the command.
Only in this case, the command will be a /bin/bash,
which is going to run the bash shell on the container.
Then, you can go ahead and run your standard bash commands in
that container to explore the container, navigate through it, or to make changes to it.