Okay, let's wrap up with a few tips.
First of all, you know when you're using your containers,
avoid using the latest tag when you're deploying your
containers with your Kubernetes deployments.
The latest tag doesn't allow you to very easily specify
which container version you're using.
This can make it harder to roll back, harder to track what you're doing.
Next, in your YAML files, don't use tabs and be aware of indentation.
YAML is very sensitive to indentation,
and simple mistakes that are virtually invisible can cause you headaches,
so be aware of indentations, and tabs are not going to be your friend there.
Next, when you're using SQL Server in a Kubernetes pod,
be sure to set a memory limit for those SQL Server containers.
By default,
SQL Server will use about 80% of the memory that's available in the base OS.
In many situations, this can cause SQL Server to use too much memory,
and Kubernetes will evict the pod for going over its resource constraints.
So be sure to set memory limits for your SQL Server containers.
Next,
using a Kubernetes‑aware editor like Visual Studio Code can save you some time.
It can help you with IntelliSense‑types of things while you're creating
the code and also help you track that indentation issue.
And then, if you're looking for some more additional information,
Pluralsight offers a number of courses out here
that you might want to look into.
If you're not familiar with Kubernetes, the Getting Started with
Kubernetes course by Nigel Poulton is a good place to start.
If you want more in depth information about Kubernetes,
the Managing Kubernetes API Server and Pods and Managing
Kubernetes Controllers and Deployments by Anthony Nocentino is
a great place to get more information.
If you want more information about SQL Server availability groups,
you might want to look into the course Administering Microsoft SQL Server
Availability Groups by Russ Thomas. Plus, along with that,
this course will contain some additional resources that you can look into
to find more information about running SQL Server on Kubernetes, as well as
SQL Server availability groups on Kubernetes.
In addition,
the resources for this course include all the scripts
that we've run in the different modules.
Altogether, there's 40+ scripts.
They've all been tested, and they work with Azure Kubernetes Services.
If you use a different Kubernetes provider, the only things that
need to be changed are the scripts that create the clusters and the
YAML that specifies the storage classes.
These need to match the requirements of the provider you're using.
The rest of the scripts will run as is.
This kind of cross‑platform support is one of the big
advantages that Kubernetes offers.
And remember, as you run these on your own,
you can also use your own customized SQL Server images, which can be pre‑configured, and they can have your own data as well.