So in this module, we looked at the importance of updating your
tools and saw some of the advantages that Visual Studio Code with
its Kubernetes extension provides.
We looked at getting some important Kubernetes information using kubectl.
We also looked at troubleshooting Kubernetes deployments using the
interactive tools, like the dashboard or using kubectl exec.
Then, we dug into some of the techniques for troubleshooting SQL Server,
along with SQL Server availability groups.
Finally,
we looked at some tips and some additional places for
information that you can go to to learn more about Kubernetes
and SQL Server availability groups.
And that's it for this module. Thanks for watching.