So why containers for SQL Server?
Well, first,
it's great for development because you can deploy a new SQL
Server instance in just a few seconds.
If you're attempting to install a new SQL Server
instance on a physical system or a VM,
then restore a bunch of databases, that is a lengthy
process that could potentially take hours.
With a container,
you can spin up a new SQL Server instance along with some
ready‑to‑go databases in just a few seconds, so there's no need
for lengthy SQL Server installations.
This is great for dev and test kind of environments.
Containers also allow a good deal of portability, because
containers run on both Linux and Windows systems, so you can
deploy containers to different operating systems.
Also, today many businesses are looking to move towards
DevOps in a continuous integration,
continuous delivery kind of development model.
And with that,
you get a new microservice style of applications. Running SQL
Server in containers can be a better way to integrate your
databases into those CI/CD development models.
When you look at the architecture that's used by containers at the bottom level,
you have your host server hardware.
This could be a physical machine or it could be a virtual machine.
Containers can run on both.
Then you have your host operating system.
This could be Windows, it could be Linux, it could
even be the macOS. Then above that, you have your container support.
This is where the Docker Engine runs,
and then each container runs on that Docker Engine.
Each container will typically run an app,
and it will share a set of binaries, and those binaries will all share
the same host operating system kernel, so the same host kernel serves all
the different containers that are running.
This makes containers much more lightweight than virtual machines,
which have to virtualize the entire stack,
including the system hardware.
Then on top of those binaries in each container,
that's where your applications run.
Each of these containers is basically a sandbox,
and they do not actually interact with one another,
they all run independently. However,
you can set up shared storage for the different containers,
and I'll talk about that in a little bit.
As you get ready to run Docker, there are a few
prerequisites that you have to do.
Essentially,
you need to install Docker container support on the platform
where you intend to run the containers.
While the specific steps vary depending on the Linux distribution that you
will use, if you're running Ubuntu 18.04 and higher,
you basically need to run the commands that you see here listed on the right
side of the panel to download and install Docker support.
First,
you use the sudo or a SuperUser DO command, and use that with apt‑get
install and the curl command to download the Docker support.
Then you can run the sudo apt‑add‑repository command to
update the Linux application repositories.
Then you can run the sudo apt update command, and finally,
the sudo apt install docker‑ce command,
which will install the Docker Community Edition.
And, by the way, the Docker Community Edition is completely free.
You can see the Windows install on the right‑hand side of the screen.
For Windows, you can install Docker using either the Server Manager for
Windows Server or through PowerShell. With PowerShell, you first run the
Install‑Module command using the name of DockerMsftProvider or
DockerMsftProvider, then specify the PowerShell repository, then run the
Install‑Package command, and then finally, restart the computer and Docker will be installed on your Windows system.