First, some quick background on Kubernetes.
It was initially developed by a team at Google,
and there was a definite Star Trek influence as its
original code was named Borg.
It was turned over as an open source project in 2014.
And if you're wondering about the name Kubernetes,
Kubernetes is Greek for helmsman. Now,
Kubernetes is maintained by the Cloud Computing Foundation.
Kubernetes is really all about managing containers.
It was designed to facilitate container orchestration,
application development, scalability, and management.
You know, managing a few containers with Docker is pretty easy,
but when you need to manage complex applications with hundreds of containers,
then it gets really hard, and that's why Google developed Kubernetes.
It's all about deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications.
Kubernetes works with a wide range of container platforms.
While it's mainly used with Docker,
it's not limited to Docker so you can use it with other container platforms.
The examples in this course all use Kubernetes to
manage SQL Server on Docker containers.
Kubernetes is also deployed on multiple platforms.
You can deploy Kubernetes on‑premise using managed
providers or by using cloud providers.
That said, it's primarily designed to manage cloud‑based applications.
So let's take a quick look at some of the different
platforms that Kubernetes can be deployed on.
First, Kubernetes can be deployed on‑premise running on your
own hardware using kubeadmin or minikube.
These are both relatively easy to set up and they're
great for testing and development,
but they lack the scalability that you get from cloud providers.
There are also a number of managed providers that can
span both on‑premise and the cloud.
A couple of the most popular managed providers are Red Hat
OpenShift and Pivotal Container Services.
These types of services and managed providers are often used by
larger corporations and they manage a number of different
enterprise services beyond Kubernetes, however,
they could be quite complex and they can have a pretty steep
learning curve to get started with them.
Kubernetes support is also provided by all the Tier one Cloud Providers.
Microsoft provides their Azure Kubernetes Service, Amazon
provides their Elastic Kubernetes Service,
and of course, Google provides their Kubernetes engine.
Now let's take a closer look at the basic Kubernetes
architecture as it relates to SQL Server.
When you deploy Kubernetes, you get a cluster.
A Kubernetes cluster consists of a set of worker machines called
nodes that run containerized applications.
Every cluster has at least one node. Nodes can be bare metal servers,
but they are more commonly virtual machines.
Nodes host the pods that are the main component of the application workload.
Each node contains the necessary services required to run pods.
Pods contain one or more containers,
along with the specifications of how to run the containers.
Each pod in Kubernetes is assigned a unique pod IP address within the cluster.
Each pod is meant to run a single instance of a given application.
Regarding SQL Server,
there are a couple important aspects of the Kubernetes cluster.
First, SQL Server needs to connect to the outside world,
and that's where the Kubernetes load balancing service comes in.
The load balancing services spans the Kubernetes cluster,
and it connects the cluster and the containers in
that cluster to an external network.
Next,
SQL Server needs to be able to access external
storage for its database operations.
Containers are stateless, and that's great for applications,
but not so great for stateful applications like SQL
Server that need persistent data.
The data always needs to be available if a container goes down so it
needs to be stored external to the Kubernetes cluster.
A Kubernetes persistent volume connects the cluster to external storage.
A storage claim describes the storage and a persistent volume claim
tells the cluster how to access that storage.
There is a lot more to Kubernetes architecture,
but these are some of the most important concepts to know for understanding SQL
Server availability with Kubernetes. We'll cover more details about the Kubernetes architecture and components in the next module.