Now let's talk about some of the background that can help you
understand what's going on in this module.
If you have a basic understanding of Docker and Kubernetes, that's great.
You're good to go.
However, if you're not all that familiar with Kubernetes,
there are a few resources that could help you get up to speed.
First,
Pluralsight offers a number of courses that can provide the Kubernetes
background that you need to understand some of the basic tools and
technologies that are used in this course.
If you have a basic knowledge of Docker and containers,
the best place to start is Getting Started with Kubernetes.
This course is 2 hours and 53 minutes long, it covers all the
Kubernetes basics that you need to know,
including information about Kubernetes architecture, masters,
nodes, pods, services, deployments, YAML, and kubectl.
If you're not that familiar with Docker and containers,
you may want to take a step back and watch Docker
and Kubernetes: The Big Picture.
This 1 hour and 47‑minute course starts back a bit farther
and it's designed to give a first start into the world of
containers, it introduces Docker,
and it also provides a high‑level overview of Kubernetes and
tells you about the roles Docker and Kubernetes play in a
container and microservices world.
Next, Pluralsight provides a couple more advanced courses on Kubernetes.
These courses pick up where the basics leave off and they
provide much more in‑depth information about the different
details of running Kubernetes.
First,
you can dive into managing the Kubernetes API server and pods. This in‑depth
course last 3 hours and 9 minutes, it's designed for administrators and
developers who need to deploy Kubernetes clusters.
It explains how the Kubernetes API server works,
and then it shows you how to use labels,
annotations, and namespaces to to better manage your deployments, and finally,
it digs into the details of how pods work.
Next, Managing Kubernetes Controllers and Deployments provides a deep
dive into Kubernetes controllers and deployments.
This 2 hour and 40‑minute course digs into the details of deploying Kubernetes.
This course will teach you about the different types of controllers and
the types of scenarios that you would use them in.
You'll also learn how to roll out,
maintain, and scale production workloads in Kubernetes,
And of course,
there is the core Kubernetes documentation that you can
check out. This material is kind of dry,
but this is the source of the information for Kubernetes, it's the
official documentation so you can find it at this URL.
Now let's talk a little bit about the deployment
platform that I've used in this example.
Kubernetes is pretty much platform agnostic. For the examples in
this module, I used Azure Kubernetes services.
I should mention that you don't have to use Azure Kubernetes
services to build Kubernetes deployments.
In fact, as I pointed out in the previous module,
you don't need to use the cloud at all.
You can deploy Kubernetes on‑premise using minikube or one of the
managed providers. I used Azure Kubernetes services, or AKS, because
Kubernetes is primarily built for running cloud apps. I was familiar
with Azure and found it to be a cost effective way to get experience
with Kubernetes.
There is no upfront hardware costs. There is a free Azure trial with
a limited usage credit, and AKS is a free service, you just pay for
the resulting VM and networking costs.
Of course,
you can use a different cloud provider if you want to, like Google or AWS.
The difference is in the specifics of the creation of the
Kubernetes cluster that you'll see in a little bit. The Kubernetes
configuration itself is pretty much the same.
So the demo scripts that accompany this module can be used
step‑by‑step verbatim with Azure Kubernetes Services.
However, if you use a different Kubernetes platform,
the portion where you create and connect to the cluster will
have to be changed to meet the requirements of whatever
Kubernetes provider you're using.
In addition, there are a few other minor dependencies on AKS,
like if you get into the storage class definitions
that specify Azure storage types, those would also need to be changed.
Next,
let's discuss some additional Kubernetes components that are
used in this SQL Server Kubernetes example.
First,
a deployment tells Kubernetes how to create or modify instances of
the pods that hold a containerized application.
Deployments automate the launching of pod instances and they ensure they're
running as defined across all the nodes in a cluster.
A ReplicaSet is very important in a highly available environment like the one
we're creating. A ReplicaSet, it maintains a stable set of replica pods that
are running at any given time, it's used to guarantee the availability of a
specified number of identical pods, it creates and deletes pods as required to
reach that desired number.
In this example,
the ReplicaSet ensures that there will be one
instance of a SQL Server pod running.
While I don't use one in this example,
you'll undoubtedly run across the concept of namespaces. A Kubernetes
namespace provides a way of scoping Kubernetes objects.
Namespaces are intended to help multiple users share a Kubernetes cluster.
Labels are used to identify the resources within a project.
They're created using key value pairs and are often
assigned to Kubernetes objects like pods.
In this example,
we'll be using the label of MS SQL to identify our SQL Server pod and
Kubernetes secrets let you store and manage sensitive information like
passwords. Again, in the example you're about to see, a Kubernetes environment variable is used to store the SQL Server SA password.