So let's start off with a little background about SQL
Server AlwaysOn Availability Groups.
Originally,
SQL Server AlwaysOn Availability Groups were designed to provide
database high availability and disaster recovery.
They are a replacement for the older and more
limited database mirroring technology.
And, like you might expect, they originated on Windows,
and Microsoft later brought them over to the Linux version of SQL Server.
AlwaysOn Availability Groups are designed to provide database‑level
protection and availability by replicating the changes from a primary
availability group replica to one or more secondaries.
They can protect multiple databases,
and there can be multiple secondary replicas.
In a typical availability scenario,
each availability group supports one primary replica
and up to eight secondary replicas.
There can be up to three synchronous replicas, and the rest can be asynchronous.
A single distributed clusterless availability group can
have up to 17 readable secondary replicas.
The replicas can use a mixture of both synchronous and asynchronous connections.
Synchronous replicas are often used for high availability
as they provide near zero data loss,
while asynchronous replicas are often used for disaster recovery,
and they can be implemented across geographic boundaries where
there can be significant latency between the nodes.
Connections between the primary and secondaries can be highly secure.
Availability Groups support both encrypted data streams for security and
compressed data streams for improved network utilization.
In a high availability scenario,
availability groups support both automatic and manual failover.
Availability groups were initially designed to be run and
to provide high availability for SQL Server instances in
Windows Failover Clusters.
Then, as Microsoft ported SQL Server to Linux,
they extended the cluster support to Linux Pacemaker.
However, with SQL Server 2017,
Microsoft added the addition of a clusterless availability group
that provided read scale for multiple SQL Server instances
without requiring any type of cluster.
This is the type of availability group implementation that
we're going to be covering in this module.
So this slide gives us an overview of SQL Server
Availability Groups and their capabilities.
There is one primary replica, and there can be multiple secondary replicas.
You can have up to eight secondary replicas.
Three of those replicas can be synchronous, and the rest can be a synchronous.
So you can mix and match synchronous replicas in an availability group.
In the past, this was done for high availability and disaster recovery.
So synchronous was used for high availability,
and asynchronous was used for disaster recovery.
There are differences for availability group capabilities
depending on which edition of SQL Server you're using.
The full‑featured availability group is available in the enterprise edition,
while the standard edition provides a two‑node availability group,
which can provide protection for one database.
However,
you can have multiple availability groups defined in your standard
edition, multiple two‑node availability groups. And with availability
groups, you can have readable secondaries,
and that means you can offload or scale out processing to these
secondaries for things like reporting, ETL, or backups. Now let's have
a quick look at how availability groups work.
The databases that are going to be part of an availability
group are defined on the primary replica.
Next, secondary replicas are added to the availability group.
As users work with their database applications,
they create transactions that add, update, and delete data in the
databases that are part of the availability group.
These transactions are then captured by the primary replica
and forwarded to the secondary replicas.
The connections between these primary and secondary replicas can
be either synchronous or asynchronous or both.
If a given secondary replica is configured for asynchronous replication.
The primary replica does not wait for the secondary replica to harden its log.
This provides faster performance, but can result in some data
loss. For synchronous commit mode, the primary replica waits for
the secondary replica to confirm that it has received the
transaction before it hardens its log.
The primary replica will then write the transaction
to its disk or hardens its log. This is slower, but there is no data loss for synchronous replicas.