So we talked about some of the basic Kubernetes
architecture, so what are some of the benefits that you get
for running SQL Server on Kubernetes?
Well,
first, Kubernetes, since it is all about running containerized applications,
you get all of the advantages of running SQL Server in a container. That is,
you can get fast, standardized deployments.
It's also great for dev, test, and Q&A.
You can spin up test versions of SQL Server in just a few seconds
using standardized methods with Kubernetes packages and deployments
opposed to the hours it might take otherwise if you were building a
new VM and installing SQL Server on it. And these kind of deployment
benefits are great for testing in Q&A too. It's also great for
allowing SQL Server,
which is a stateful application, to fit in with the new DevOps and
CI/CD types of deployments for applications these days. It helps the
database to be a part of your CI/CD pipeline.
It also is great for projects where you have quick,
repeatable components. Say you have a project that
needs to possibly perform an EL task,
or maybe you need to train a machine learning database, or you need to
have a reporting server come up and generates some quick reports for
you, so it's great for these kind of quick,
repeatable tasks.
And, of course,
and what we're talking about, Kubernetes can also provide high
availability for SQL Server implementations,
and it can be an alternative to Windows failover clusters.
So what are some of the requirements for running SQL Server on Kubernetes?
Well, you're going to have to select a Kubernetes platform.
We saw it runs on‑premises with managed providers or in the cloud.
In this course,
I'll be mainly using Microsoft's Azure's Azure Kubernetes
Services as the platform for running Kubernetes on.
You also need a SQL Server 2017 on Linux or SQL
Server 2019 on Linux container image.
These are the only versions of Microsoft SQL Server that
Microsoft supports within a container.
So if you want a supported production environment,
you need to use one of these SQL Server on Linux images.
You can get Ubuntu images off of the Docker Hub,
and you can get images for Red Hat from Red Hat's catalog. And, in addition,
you also need to access Kubernetes persistent storage where
there's some form of external storage where your database is
going to be located so that you can get access to the database from the different Kubernetes Pods.