After Docker Support has been installed, you're ready to run Docker containers.
To run a Docker container, you can pull a Docker image from the Docker Hub.
Docker images are templates for containers,
and they contain the software that makes up the container.
That software can include OS binaries, as well as the application software,
applications like SQL Server.
The docker pull command will retrieve the image from the Docker
Hub and execute that image on the local system,
instantiating a Docker container.
In this slide, you can see the Docker Hub,
and you can see that a microsoft/mssql‑server‑linux
container is listed at the top,
along with a microsoft/mssql‑server‑windows‑express container and a
microsoft/mssql‑server‑windows‑developer edition container.
By selecting one of those images and using the docker pull command,
you can run that image.
And when you do that,
the container that has SQL Server preinstalled on it is ready to run.
And then SQL Server will essentially be running on that
container that you've downloaded to your system,
with no need to install anything.
So to actually run a container, you use the docker run command.
The docker run command has a few important parameters for SQL Server.
It's actually a pretty simple command to run.
Here, the ‑d switch means the container will run detached,
which means it will run in the background rather than on the host desktop.
The ‑p parameter specifies which ports to map from
the host system to the container.
In this case, it's mapping port 1433 on the host to the same port,
1433, in the container.
That is the default port for SQL Server.
While the values match in this case, they don't have to match.
And then, the ‑e parameter allows you to specify environment variables.
These can change depending on what containers you're running.
In this case, two environment variables are used.
The ACCEPT_EULA=Y key pair tells SQL Server that you
will accept the licensing agreement.
The SA_PASSWORD variable sets the SQL Server system administrator,
or SA password.
And finally,
the docker run command passes the name of the
container image that you're going to run.
And this would map to one of the container images that you
saw listed earlier on the Docker Hub.
In this case,
the command will run a microsoft/mssql‑server‑windows‑express image.
So, let's go ahead and see a quick demo of this in action.
First,
we're going to go ahead and list the various Docker images that are out
there on the Docker Hub so you can see where they're at.
Next, we're going to use that pull command,
and we're going to pull down a SQL Server image,
and then we're going to run it.
Then we're going to go ahead and connect to that SQL
Server instance running in the container,
where you'll see that running a containerized version of
SQL Server is almost exactly like running a standard SQL
Server standalone instance. So, let's go ahead and jump into it.