Okay, now let's go ahead and actually put these tools to work.
First, we're going to go ahead and create a two‑node Kubernetes cluster.
Next, we're going to connect kubectl to that cluster.
Then, we're going to go ahead and list the cluster nodes with kubectl.
Okay, let's see it.
Here's the Ubuntu system that has previously installed the Azure CLI,
as well as kubectl.
The window you see here is Visual Studio Code,
which is a free cross‑platform editing tool from Microsoft.
I should point out you certainly don't need to use Microsoft code
in order to follow the examples in this module.
I used it because it's an effective presentation tool that can
show you both the code that's going to be run,
as well as the results all in the same window.
On the left‑hand side of this window,
you can see a number of shell scripts that I created to make
the demos in this module easier to follow,
as well as easier to replicate.
Of course,
the demo scripts are all part of the resources that accompany this course.
So first, let's open the first script that creates the Kubernetes cluster.
You can see the Azure CLI commands at the top to first log
into the cluster using the az login command.
Next,
the az group command creates a resource group that will
contain all our Kubernetes objects.
Then the az aks create command is used to actually create the cluster on AKS.
The command specifies the resource group name that we just created,
the name of the Kubernetes cluster where you can see here it's SQLCL.
The cluster will consist of two nodes,
and we're going to be using the smaller nodes size of Standard_B2s.
Let's go ahead and execute it. First,
as the az login command runs, we're going to sign in to Azure.
At this point,
it's going ahead and creating the resource group and then creating our cluster.
It takes it just a few minutes to do this.
Okay, that took it about 3 to 4 minutes to create that.
Now let's go ahead and we're going to get the credentials for this cluster.
And here's the code that does that.
You can see we're going to be running the az aks get‑credentials command,
supplying it our resource group name and our cluster name.
It has prompted us that we've already done this before, and it finds
some of the preconfigurations in our kubectl file.
We're going to go ahead and overwrite them. And now it
has done that, and we've gone ahead,
and we've got the credentials for our cluster.
Next,
let's go ahead and we're going to take a look at the code
to go ahead and retrieve the nodes for the cluster, and
that is in this script file.
You can see it will be running the kubectl get nodes command.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And at this point,
you can see we now have two different nodes running out there, and these
things are both ready to have a pod deployed to them.
You might note at this point there are no pods deployed
because we haven't created a pod yet. But we're going to do that in just a few minutes.