Now, let's take a look at SQL Server failover on a Kubernetes cluster.
SQL Server failover with Kubernetes is similar to Windows failover clustering,
but there are differences.
Without a doubt, the biggest difference is that Kubernetes
manages containers while Windows failover clustering protects
either VMs or physical systems.
Containers are much lighter weight than VMs. And when Kubernetes
determines that a pod or container has failed,
it can rapidly spin up a new one.
In this slide,
you can see an overview of the basic Kubernetes cluster with multiple nodes
running a SQL Server container. If you recall from our earlier discussion of
the basic Kubernetes architecture, Kubernetes clusters consists of nodes,
which are typically VMs, and then pods,
which are used to run containers. Here, a new concept,
a replica set,
is something that ensures that the pod is
automatically recovered after a node failure.
At the bottom, you can see persistent volumes in a persistent volume claim.
Persistent volumes in a persistent volume claim connect
pods to external storage. And again,
the load balancing service enables external network clients to connect
to the SQL Server instance running in the container.
Kubernetes ReplicaSets guarantee the correct count of
healthy instances in the cluster.
If there's a failure in the SQL Server container,
Kubernetes will start a new container according to its deployment rules.
The new container will reconnect to the same persistent storage,
and the load balancing service connects to the recreated SQL Server container.
This failover process only takes a few seconds as it takes
Kubernetes to spin up a new container.
Likewise, if there's a node failure,
Kubernetes will start a new pod on a different node. The SQL Server
container reconnects to the same persistent storage,
and the load balancing service connects to the recreated SQL Server container.
So, in summary, you know,
with SQL Server and Windows failover clustering, that works at the server level.
It uses clustered SQL Server instances,
which are special install options for SQL Server.
It can range from two node clusters for the Standard edition
up to 64 nodes for the Enterprise edition.
It's more complex to set up than a Kubernetes cluster,
and failover time depends upon the activity level that's going on.
Kubernetes and SQL Server, here, it works at the container level.
It uses standalone SQL Server instances, which are easier to set up.
The number of nodes that you're using are not limited by the
edition of SQL Server that you're using.
This is simpler to set up, and failover tends to be much faster within seconds,
just the time to spin up a new container.
So, in summary, in this module, you got an overview
of Kubernetes with SQL Server.
You learned about running SQL Server on a Kubernetes
cluster and how it affects availability.
You learned about some of the basics of running SQL
Server with a Windows failover cluster.
We learned about SQL Server high availability with Kubernetes,
and we saw a comparison of SQL Server availability between Windows failover clusters and Kubernetes clusters.