Okay, I know that was a lot of code to cover.
Now let's get to the fun stuff, and we'll see this in action.
First, we're going to look at creating and connecting to our Kubernetes cluster.
Then we're going to look at creating the external storage for
the three pods that we're going to be using.
And then we're going to create three SQL Server deployments,
one for the availability replica primary and two others for the secondaries.
Okay, so now to run all this stuff, we've switched over to our Ubuntu system,
and this is Visual Studio Code again that you see here that we're
going to use to display and run the code with.
And here is the first set of code that we're going to run
to go ahead and create our cluster.
You can see in it, az group create, create ‑‑resource‑group,
and after that,
creating our cluster with a node count of 3 and using the
‑‑node‑vm‑size of Standard_B2ms. So, let's go ahead and run this.
And, we are executing the create cluster code.
It takes it just a couple minutes to do this.
So, I'm going to go ahead and let this run,
then I'm going to come back to it when we've got it finished.
Okay, that took it about 3 minutes.
And now we have a 3‑node cluster running up in Azure.
Now let's go ahead and get the credentials for that
cluster, so we can manage it with kubectl.
So here's the code that does that,
and we'll execute step2 to get our credentials.
So it's going ahead and connecting and overriding our local config.
And at this point, we've got the credentials back.
Now let's go ahead and list the nodes in our cluster.
And there you can see our three nodes are out there running.
They haven't been running long, and they're fresh out of the box.
So now that we've done that,
let's go ahead and create the storage that we're going to use here.
And you can see here our kubectl apply command. And now let's
have a quick look at that storage command again.
We have looked at this in some detail just a minute ago,
but you can see our StorageClass.
You can see the type of storage we're using.
There's our first PersistentVolumeClaim.
If we can scroll down, there's our second PersistentVolumeClaim,
and there is our third PersistentVolumeClaim.
Each one is going to be used by a different SQL
replica in our availability group.
So, let's go ahead and execute this.
All our persistent volume claims have been created.
Now, let's go ahead and display the storage like we did before.
And we're going to be executing these two kubectl commands to do that.
And you can see our StorageClass, you can see our access
mode, and then at the bottom, you can see our persistent
volume claims and their capacities.
Let's go ahead and bring that back.
Now,
let's go ahead and create the secret for our cluster, which is
going to hold our SQL Server SA password.
And we've gone ahead and done that.
Now, we're ready to go ahead and create our deployments.
So if we look at this, you can see we're going to be running kubectl apply.
We're going to be running it three times, once for the
sqlAGPdeployment.yaml, and a second time for the sqlAGS1deployment.yaml,
and the third time for the sqlAGS2deployment.yaml. The first one creates
the primary, the next two create the two secondaries.
Let's take a quick look at those .yaml files.
We won't spend a lot of time here because we did explain
them previously, but this is the primary.
You can check out the name that we're using, the number of replicas. And there
is our app identifier. If we scroll down a little bit more,
we can see our hostname, and we can see the image we're
using, the environment variables, the SA_PASSWORD, our memory limitation.
And, of course,
then the persistentVolumeClaim that we're going to use. And
finally, the load balancing service to use with it,
which is opening up the two ports, 1433 and 5022.
If we have a quick look at the other two .yaml files,
you can see they are all very similar.
They follow the same pattern.
Each has a different name, and this one is mssql‑secondary1‑deployment.
The replicas are the same.
Our app label, again, is different.
If we scroll down, our hostname will be mssql‑secondary1.
Our image name will be mssql‑secondary1. All the
environment variables are the same.
If we come down, you can see we're using a different persistentVolumeClaim here.
And our app selector is different, and our ports are the same, 1433 and 5022.
Same is true with this file.
If we go and look at sqlAGS2deployment, and we can scroll
through this file and start at the top again.
We've got a different name. Our app name is different,
mssql‑secondary2. And our hostname, mssql‑secondary2. Environment
variables are all the same. Our mountPath, again, is different using
that third volume claim that we created, mssql ‑ s2db. And our
service is matching our app name of mssql‑secondary2. And then, we
have our two ports that are open.
So, let's go ahead and create our deployment. And, at this point,
our deployment is created.
So now, we have nodes,
we have pods, and a load balancing service, and persistent volume claims.
So now, let's go ahead and have a look at our deployment
status, and we can do that by running this code. And we are
going to run kubectl get all to do that.
And, if we open this up again,
let's go make it a little bigger so we can see it,
there's our get status command.
There are three pods that are running right now since they've just
been created there in the STATUS of ContainerCreating. It is in the
process also of assigning external IP addresses for the services
that are running out there.
And at the bottom, you can see our replica sets.
Okay, let's check it one more time.
And now, we can see our pods are all running.
We have external IP addresses,
and our replica sets are ready to go in their desired states.
So let's bring this back.
And, in fact,
let's go ahead and flip over really quickly, and we'll run Azure
Data Studio, and we're going to go ahead and connect into it. So
we'll paste in our server address,
our sa login, and then we'll connect, and there we're connected.
Now remember, at this point, we have our databases ready to go.
It only has the system databases on it.
It's basically a plain vanilla SQL Server system.
But remember,
there are also two other systems running out here at the same time, too.
And if you pay attention,
take a look at our computer name, it's the name of the host that we just recently assigned to it.