Okay.
Now let's get ready to jump into the SQL Server portion of this code.
First,
we're going to go ahead and look at creating the
primary availability group replica.
Then we're going to take the master key we create there and copy that
master key to the two different secondary replicas.
Next, we're going to go ahead and create the first secondary replica.
Then we're going to create the second secondary replica.
Then we're going to test the availability group,
and we're going to watch it replicate some transactions
between the primary node and the secondaries.
And then we're going to test a failover to see how Kubernetes
is providing availability for this cluster.
Okay, at this point, we have our three‑node Kubernetes cluster up and running,
but we don't have an availability group onto it.
So let's go ahead and connect into it,
and we're going to go ahead and create our availability group.
So first,
let's go ahead and fire up Azure Data Studio, and here, we're going to
go ahead and you can see we're going to collect the IP addresses for
each of the different nodes, then we're going to go ahead and start
Azure Data Studio, so it's waiting for us to hit Enter, and now here
comes Azure Data Studio.
Next, let's go ahead and connect into our primary node.
Okay,
so here it is in our list of servers, remember, we connected to it just a
little while ago, so let's go ahead and give it the password.
And now that we have our connection into the primary or
what's going to be the primary server,
let's go ahead and open up our script that's going to
go ahead and create the primary, and that's what we can see here.
Let's scroll to the top. At the top, you can see where we're creating that
master database and inserting a few rows into it, setting our database
recovery to full and backing up the database,
creating a login, and then below that, our master key and certificate.
And then we're backing up that certificate to a file that we're
going to later share with the secondaries.
If we scroll down a little bit,
you can see where we're going to go ahead and create our endpoint on Port 5022,
and after that, we're going to go ahead and create our availability
group called K8S, or Kubernetes S availability group.
Then we're going to add our different replicas, our primary replica,
and we're going to set it up as a synchronous, our
seeding is going to be automatic,
which means it's going to copy the database that we add to it automatically to
the secondaries, and our failover mode is going to be manual because this is a
cluster list availability group. Beneath that,
you can see where we create the two secondary replicas,
mssql‑secondary1, mssql‑secondary2. Secondary1 is a
synchronous availability replica,
while secondary2 is using asynchronous commit mode. And then at the bottom,
you can see where we're going to go ahead and add a database to
our availability group and this is our sample database that we
loaded a few rows into earlier.
Alright, let's go ahead and run it. So at this point,
it's going to go ahead and go through our script lines, it is going to add the
rows to the database, it's going to back up the database,
and then it's going to go ahead and create our
endpoint and our availability group.
If we go over and look at our server objects, now you'll
be able to see our endpoint out there,
and there is our AG_endpoint that we created.
Now, the next thing is to copy that certificate over to the secondary replicas.
To do that, we're going to go back to Visual Studio Code,
and we're going to open up step11_copy_certificate, and you can
see if we look at this, we are getting the different pod names
for our primary and two secondaries.
We're going to copy the certificate first to our local system,
and then we're going to turn around and copy it to each of the secondaries.
And again, we have to do that because, unfortunately,
I was not able to copy from pod to pod, so that's a workaround for that.
And here you can see it's going ahead and copying the
certificates. And at that point,
the certificate is on each of those secondary nodes. And next,
we're going to open up a connection to our secondary servers.
So there that should be our first secondary. We're going to
log in to it as SA, give it our password.
Okay,
and there is our first secondary replica that is now up and you can
check out our computer name mssql‑secondary1.
Now we're going to run a query on this system, our script that's
going to create it out of S1 and here we go,
create_secondaryAG. And you can see, again here, it's going
to use the master database, it's going to create a login,
it's going to create a certificate.
In this case,
it's creating the certificate based upon our
certificate that has been backed up,
and it's going out to the file system to find that certificate,
and we copied it in here just a little bit ago.
Then it's going to go ahead and create the endpoint,
and at that point, it's going to go ahead and add this replica.
So let's go ahead and run this.
Now it's going to go ahead and it's working at creating our secondary replica,
and it has gone ahead and finished it.
Now we're going to do the same thing on secondary replica 2. So first,
let's open a connection to our other server,
and this is our secondary replica, so we'll put in its IP address.
We'll give it on its sign on.
And now we're connected to secondary Replica 2. Now,
let's go ahead and open the script to add it up to our availability group,
and here, you can see this is very much like the one we ran on secondary
replica 1. Again, we're going to create the log in, we're going to create
the master key, we're going to use a certificate from the file, and then
we're going to create our endpoint.
So let's go ahead and run it.
At this point, it has gone ahead and completed,
and now our availability group is completed.
So if we now go ahead and look at databases,
let's see our sample database should definitely exist on the
primary, so we're opening up our primary databases,
and there it is.
Remember, we used automatic seeding,
so it should take it just a second before that database and
makes it out to both of the secondaries,
and you can see that it is definitely there.
Now let's go back to the primary,
and we're going to insert some additional data into this database.
So let's take a sample insert statement and let's go ahead and run it.
And now we've gone ahead and we've inserted 49 rows into our database.
Now let's go ahead and take a quick look over at let's say
the one in secondary replica number two.
So let's go ahead and open up our table and let's
select the top 1,000 rows here.
And at this point, there is all our data.
You can see it duplicated over very quickly.
Now, at this point, we're ready to go ahead and test a failover.
So I flipped back to Azure Data Studio.
So here is our code that's going to go ahead and demo a failover.
We're going to retrieve the pod name.
We're going to go ahead and kill a pod.
We're going to wait a couple of seconds and then
we're going to see the running pods.
So let's go ahead and execute this, step14.
So now it's going to go ahead and delete the pod, this takes it just a second.
Now it's going to wait a couple seconds,
and at this point, it has gone ahead and retrieve the pod.
Now our pod is in container creating, that won't take it long to
do. So let's go back over now, and in Azure Data Studio, we'll go
back to our primary, we'll bring up our database, and we'll
retrieve the rows from here.
We'll open up our database and you can see it's responding just like
it normally would so the container is already created, and we'll
select the top 1,000 rows from the container,
and there they are.
Now Azure Data Studio is not capable of managing availability groups, it's
really more of a development tool, but SQL Server does have another
management tool called SQL Server Management Studio,
and that's what you see here. And now, we're going to
take SQL Server Management Studio,
and we're going to connect in to our availability group,
and we are going to see how you can manage it from SQL Server Management Studio,
just like any other availability group.
And it's connecting.
And if we go down and we expand always on availability,
you can see our availability groups.
There is the one we just created K8sAG. We can go down and expand our replicas.
You can see there is our primary replica, our secondary replica
1, and secondary replica 2. And if we look at our availability
databases, there is our test database.
We have the ability to manage it from here. We can also show the dashboard,
which basically shows the health of our availability group.
And again,
this is our availability group that is spanning our Kubernetes cluster, and
you can see that at this point, all the nodes are basically healthy and you
can see our primary and our two secondaries, and at this point, you can see that they're both synchronized.