Hello everyone,
welcome to your first assessment test.
You've actually had a lot of challenges along the way
so this isn't gonna be a very long assessment test.
It's actually just gonna be three quick questions
and it's also gonna be in article lecture format,
so you won't see any videos,
you'll just get the actual text of the question.
You're gonna be provided with the answers to test against.
So for instance, if the question is something like,
tell me how many customers do X, Y, and Z,
you'll also be provided with the answer,
and it'll say something like, the answer should be 20.
You won't actually be provided with the full SQL solution
until the lecture after the test lecture.
Again, so the next lecture you're gonna have questions,
and then some answers to check your work against,
and then once you've actually matched up
or you still haven't been able to match up
to the exact answer,
you can go to the lecture after that
to get the full SQL query solution.
Keep in mind you may have done SQL queries
that are slightly different,
there's a couple different ways
to solve each of the questions,
so as long as you actually get the right answer,
you should be good to go.
Okay, thanks everyone,
and best of luck on the assessment test.