Welcome back everyone to the Select where Part 2 lecture where we're going to head straight to P.G.
Adelman and coat along with a couple of examples just to give you an idea of the different use cases
for select where as well as comparison operators and logical operators.
All right let's begin by exploring the customer table.
I'm going to just select everything from the customer table so we can explore it quickly we'll say select
and then Asterix from customer semicolon.
Go ahead and run this and I can see there is a customer I.D. column a store I.D. first name last name
email and address I.D. some active bullying whether or not that customer is active or not so true or
false the date they were created.
Last update and then also an integer corresponding to the active boolean so ones and zeros for the Choose
and false is here.
Okay.
So what can we do here to start filtering out customer information.
Well maybe something I want to know is who has the first name Jared.
Maybe someone comes to the store and asks me.
I'm looking for some customer named Jared so I can say select all the columns from customer we'll go
ahead and delete that semicolon and then we'll say where and this is where we have a condition.
So we have to say the column name in our case its first name so we'll scroll over here you can see we
have first underscore a name.
So we'll say where.
First underscore name is equal to and then single quote capital J.
And then Jared note how the single quotes are essentially automatically ended for you in post Chris
Eagle and P.J. Hedman semicolon optional if you want to end this or not.
We'll go ahead and run this and I can see I have that information for Jared.
Now let's go ahead and explore the film table to see how we can combine conditions with logical operators
we'll say select everything from film run that and it looks like I have different film ideas that are
unique to each film title for each film a description a release here a language I.D. rental duration
rental rate length etc..
So let's start playing around this.
Let's go ahead and find maybe all the rental rates that are higher than four dollars.
Recall that when we use distinct there's usually only three rental rates ninety nine cents to ninety
nine and four ninety nine.
So I can say select everything from film where the rental rates is greater than let's just say for some
I call and go ahead and run that and I can see all the results that are back here are now for ninety
nine forty nine et cetera.
So they're all greater than four dollars and let's go ahead and add a another condition on this so we
can do this for logical operator.
Let's go ahead and choose ones that are expensive to replace those we also have a replacement cost.
Let's go ahead and choose the ones that have a replacement costs greater than or equal to nineteen ninety
nine.
So say and and notice I don't need to rewrite where again.
So the where just applies to all these conditions that I can keep linking together with logical operators
so will rental rate is greater than 4 and let's say replacement cost is greater than or equal to nineteen
ninety nine and because these are numeric types I can directly compare them to these numbers know how
Postgres sequel it's you know what data type it is.
So there's different colors depending if I'm working the strings whether these are keywords in post
sequel or whether they're new metrics we'll go ahead and run this.
And now I can see here that we have 499 and then the more expensive moves to replace 1989 when 8 9 9
et cetera and I can keep tacking on more and more so maybe I want only certain readings maybe I only
want the r movies so you can always move that semicolon and continue on another line where we say and
and then maybe rating is equal to and in single quotes are go ahead and run that.
And now we keep filtering more and more on this etc..
And recall that here we're just asking for all the columns but can always just ask for only certain
columns so I can say select the title from film and then we run this and essentially I get a list of
all the titles where these three conditions happen to be true where the rental rates more than for the
replacement cost is greater than equal to 1989 and the rating is equal to R.
Let's imagine want to answer the question of how many titles there are where these conditions all happen
to be true.
Well what I can do is simply add in a count so I can either count title which is essentially counting
how many rows are returned here.
So if I run this it gives me back that there's thirty four movies where all these conditions happen
to be true.
But if you remember from the Count's lecture I can really pass in any column to this or in fact I can
just write an asterix here which since we just count the number of rows that are returned from the film
table that satisfy these conditions.
And if I run this always get back the same number.
So recall from that count lecture.
It doesn't really matter what actual column I apply here because I'm really just asking the question
here.
How many arrows are return that satisfy these particular conditions.
Let's go ahead and explore a quick example of the or logical operator.
Maybe I only want movies that have an R rating or a P.G. 13 rating.
Well what I can do for that is I can say where rating is equal to R or make sure we spelled this right.
Rating is equal to P.G. 13.
Notice here I'm still counting the number of movies returned here.
I run this and there's four hundred and eighteen movies that satisfy either the R condition or P.G.
13.
Now remember we also have the not equal to operator in case I want everything that is in our movie.
For example I could say something like the following I could say where the rating is not equal to R.
Let's just go ahead and grab all the columns here so we can see the results.
We'll go ahead and run this and if I scroll over to the right you'll notice on the rating that everything
here is everything that's not ours that's G P G P G thirteen NC 17 etc..
So we have all the ratings here but none of these are actually going to then be r All right.
So that's it for this code along examples.
Coming up next we're going to check your understanding by giving you a couple of challenges with these
select where statements hopefully can already tell.
This is a very powerful tool and something you'll be using quite often when it comes to your sequel
queries.
I'll see you in the next lecture.