Welcome back everyone to this lecture on the cheque constraint the check constraint allows us to create
more customized constraints that adhere to a certain condition such as making sure all inserted integer
values fall below a certain threshold.
So for example let's imagine we're creating a table called example and it's going to just have an example
I.D. column which is serial PRIMARY KEY AND THEN WE HAVE AN H column and let's say for this particular
example we have to make sure that the people are over 21 so we'll say age small integer for the data
type and then we add in this check constraint and after the check constraint we just have some condition
such as the H column must be greater than twenty one and we can also set conditions based off other
columns.
So let's add in a new column called The Parent H and then again small integer as the data type and for
its check constraint it's going to say that the parents age column must be greater than the age column.
And so if you try to insert a person at this table who has an age that's less than twenty one or if
you try to insert a person here that has a parent age that is less than their own age and that doesn't
really make sense.
We'll go ahead and produce an error let's explore this concept a little further in P.G. admin to show
you what we can do with the check constraint.
I'm going to create a new table and we're going to create a table of employees let's say employees have
an I.D. and we'll say employee I.D. that's going to be serial and it's going to be a primary key.
Then they have a first name which we'll say is a variable character.
Let's give them up to 50 characters for their first name and no constraints here or we can add something
like let's say not no.
They need to have a first name and then something else we can do is give them a last name variable character.
Let's say 50 let's say they also need a last name and let's start adding things maybe like a birthday.
So if we say birthday column this should be a date and let's make sure that the birthday happens to
be greater than or past nineteen hundred.
So we'll say check that the birthday is greater then and we'll say nineteen hundred and January 1st.
Basically we won't allow anyone to say their birthday is before the year nineteen hundred and let's
add in Alaska maybe last two columns one column to say the date they join.
So we'll say higher date.
This is a date and we want to make sure to check that there join date or higher date happens to be greater
than their actual birth date and list changes to birth date.
Just so it's clear that we're not referring to just the day of their birth but the actual dates of their
birth.
OK so we have this birth date and their birth date has to be greater than January 1st nineteen hundred
and then we have their higher dates and their higher date has to come after the day they were born which
makes sense.
And then finally let's go ahead and give them a salary.
This will be let's say a numeric data type.
Just go ahead to have it be integer or numeric so it's say data type is integer.
And then finally let's go ahead and make sure that the salary has to be greater than zero.
So we can't actually input a negative salary there.
So we have these various columns along with these check constraints.
You have a check constraint against a date a check constraint against another column and a check constraint
against some salary or integer.
We run this.
We've created that table looks good.
Let's go ahead and now attempt to insert someone into this table so say insert into the employees table
and then we're going to go ahead and grab those columns so those columns you only worry about the employee
I.D..
That was a cereal column.
We'll say we're going to insert a first name a last name their birth date their higher date and then
their salary.
So those are the columns we're going to be inserting into analysis.
Choose some values basically just made it values.
We'll go ahead and I'll show you some of my values here.
We'll see who's a tortilla and then what I'm going to do is let's go ahead and add in some birthdate
I'm actually going to insert some wrong values so we can see the check constraints at work.
So let's say I was born eighteen ninety nine let's say 11 0 3 and let's say I was hired in 2010 0 1
0 1 and let's give me a salary of one hundred dollars.
So if I try to run this I'm going to zoom out just a little bit so we can see kind of everything at
once.
We'll go ahead and run this.
I get back error neuro for relation employee violates a check constraint on the employee's birthdate
check.
OK cool.
So it looks like it.
That worked.
It's going to change this.
I'll make this nineteen ninety will run this and now I was able to successfully insert that.
Let's go ahead and add in a new employee let's call them Sammy let's call this Sammy Smith.
We'll go ahead have him be the same birth date.
But now let's actually say we put a negative 100 as our salary will run this.
It looks like that fails constraint for employee salary check.
So remove that negative.
Run it again.
It looks like everything's working.
So if we select all from employees run that I have of Jose and Sammy same birthday and same salary.
OK something that's really cool to notice here is that the cereal actually kept the count of those failed
attempts to insert so I failed on my first attempt to insert which means it started the primary key
at 2 then I failed another attempt.
And then when I got Sammy right on the fourth time it gave it a primary key A4.
So this actually lets you know that rows were either removed or insert commands failed before hos ay
and after Hosie so kind of interesting aspect of the serial data type there.
OK thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.