Welcome back everyone to this lecture discussion on the limit.
Keyword the limit command allows us to limit the number of rows returned for a query.
It's useful for not wanting to return every single row in a table but only view maybe the top few rows
to get an idea of the table layout limit also becomes extremely useful in combination of the ordered
by statement that we just learned about limit goes at the very bottom end of a query request and is
the last command to be executed because essentially what the limit does is after you're done filtering
with the where statement ordering with order by and sorting and any other sort of conditions or any
filters you want to do in your query.
The limit is just going to say All right how many rows do you want at the end of the day.
So let's learn the basic syntax limit through some examples.
This should be pretty straightforward and you should really be thinking about this in conjunction with
order by.
In order to answer certain business questions let's jump over to P.G. admin okay.
Here we are in P.G. admin.
Let's go ahead and explore this payment table again.
First what we could do is just select everything from the payment table so I can say select everything
from payment and I get this variety of payment I.D. customer I.D. stuff i.e. the rental I.D. etc. and
then I also get a payment date which has a timestamp without a time zone.
Essentially just a day and then the hour minute and then second and milliseconds where this payment
actually occurred what we could do is order by this payment date in order to see either the oldest payments
or the most recent payments.
So what I can do is say select everything from payment and then say order by payment date.
And if we run this on a timestamp what's going to happen if we refresh this notice we get two thousand
seven zero to 14.
So this is in American formatting meaning it's year month and then day.
And if I want I can either order this by default ascending to get two thousand seven two and then 14
or I could say descending.
Run this and I see two thousand seven 514 essentially 14th of May instead of 14th of February.
So what this actually means is I can use order by in conjunction with limit to get the top end rows
of something.
So for example I can answer the business question what were the 10 most recent purchases in the payment
table.
So after I conduct my order buy I call in the limit keyword and then provide how many rows do you actually
want.
So if I just say five you'll notice here that right now it's returning everything if I scroll down here
if I say five run this I keep scrolling down but I only get five rows.
So essentially what this answers is.
What were the five most recent rows or payments based off the payment date.
So we can see the payment date here.
And right now we're returning the five most recent payments.
So this will allow you to get the top end of anything based off some column.
So what we do here is just order by some column and then limit it to the top end results that we want.
And it's up to you whether you want to do ascending or descending depending on the actual data type
that we're looking at.
So we can see here in fact some of these payment amounts or zeros.
So what I could end up doing is also filtering it where the amount isn't zero.
So we can start to get really nice complex queries here so I can say select everything from the payment
table saying select all the calls from this payment table and then right here we're limiting it to the
top five most recent ones based off payment day in descending order.
So starting from most recent descending to the historical data and it could also then say where amount
is not equal to zero.
So we run this and now I can see the five most recent payments where there was actually a monetary transaction
and it wasn't just a zero dollar amount.
So this is where we start to see much more realistic sequel queries given just the few commands we know
we can already answer lots of business questions we can in this case select everything from the most
five recent payments where the amount wasn't zero.
All right.
So hopefully that gives you an idea of the power of limit and sometimes if you want you can simply do
something like SELECT everything from payment limit one to just quickly get an idea of what this table
actually looks like.
This would show you what data types there are such as integer small integers timestamps etc. in an example
of what these actually look like.
So some people like to quickly run this sort of command in order to just see the general layout of a
table.
OK.
So that's it for this lecture on limit.
It's a pretty straightforward thing.
Let me just comes at the end and you can limit the number of rows return.
Very useful in conjunction of order by.
So let's test your skills in the next lecture where we talk about some order by challenges.
I'll see you there.