Welcome back everyone to your set of challenge tasks regarding order by as well as the limit statement
so I'll start off by Give me the challenge task or business situation.
Then we'll go on to the expected result.
The hints and then a solution so your first challenge task.
We want to reward our first ten paying customers.
So the question is what are the customer I.D. of the first 10 customers who ever created a payment.
Up next is the expected result so they expect the result.
Are these 10 customer I.D..
Here come some hints.
So the hints is to use the payment table and you will need to use both order by and limit.
And remember you may need to specify ascending or descending on the actual payment dates column.
Here comes a solution.
So the solution is to select the customer I.D. column from the payment table and then you're gonna order
by payment date in ascending order.
And if you want you can just leave the ascending out of it because that is by default and then the limit
is 10.
All right let's move on to your second challenge so the next challenge task is a customer wants to quickly
rent a video to watch over their short lunch break.
What are the titles of the five shortest that is in length of runtime.
Movies OK.
Here comes the expected result so they expect the result.
Are these five movies and if you want you can see the actual length of those movies is 46 minutes each.
So you should get these five titles.
Here come some hints so the hint is to use the film table and then take a look at the length column
and you can use order by and limit.
And then remember you can use ascending or descending to get desired results.
Here comes the solution.
The solution is to select title and length or just the title since the question can really ask for the
length of the films from film and then order by length ascending.
Limit 5.
Now I want to quickly jump the PGA admin to show you something regarding this query so something I want
to point out here is if we actually run this query of selecting title length from film order by length
ascending limit 5 there's two things to notice here.
One is that length is also highlighted basically telling you later on we're going to discover that length
itself is actually a sequel keyword.
So you want to be careful on the way we use it.
In this case it'll work fine if we run this because it is a column name inside of this table but something
to keep in mind is you should try your best to avoid column names that match up with sequel keywords
and PJM and alert you to this with this highlighting.
Now one way to just make it clear whether or not you're using a column name or a keyword is the capitalization.
So from the capitalization it's quite clear that length here is a column name and not a sequel come
in.
The other thing to note here is I actually don't know for sure if there's more movies that have a longer
or the same runtime.
So notice here are the five movies that postcard sequel Return that are ordered by length in ascending
order.
So here are the five shortest movies Forty six minutes each.
But there actually could be a six seven eight nine et cetera.
More movies that also have 46 minutes in length.
So we don't actually know for sure if these are just the five shortest movies we could have more and
what we could do is keep expanding on this limit and then eventually we would see that the next limit
in length has been reached forty seven minutes.
So it's by coincidence that there's only five movies with the shortest runtime of 46 minutes.
But just saying limit by five doesn't actually guarantee you that there's only five movies here if the
shortest run time.
So keep in mind of that sort of issue that may arise when you're trying to solve a question like this.
OK.
And finally let's give you a quick Bonus Question So here's a quick bonus question no hints or anything
for this one.
Just quickly if that previous customer can watch any movie that is 50 minutes or less in runtime how
many options does she or he have.
Keep in mind you may actually not even need order by for this.
So again we're just asking how many movies can that customer watch that are 50 minutes or less in runtime
the expected result is thirty seven movies and hopefully you can recall back to your select and worse
statement.
So here's the solution so all we need to do is select and then we can count the title from film where
length is less than or equal to 50.
And keep in mind I don't necessarily need to count the title column.
I could be counting anything there.
So that could have an asterisk as well.
All right.
So coming up next we're going to keep talking about different sequel comments starting with the between
command.
I'll see you there.