Welcome everyone to this quick lecture on restoring the exercises database.
This database is slightly different than what we've encountered before with the DVD rental database
so we'll quickly guide you through it.
And we're gonna be using this database for a series of exercise questions so we're gonna use this new
database for a set of exercise questions.
We've pretty much exhausted all the questions we can think of that are relevant to you in that DVD rental
database.
So we're going to do is restore a brand new database.
And the important thing to know that we haven't encountered before is this database actually has two
schemas a public schema and then something called a C D schema which is the name of the schema.
And because our tables exist within the C D schema instead of the public one we just have to specify
in our queries.
So this means the queries for the from table's part will have a C D in front of them.
So there's two tables that you're gonna be using.
So one is bookings and the other one is facilities.
And so you'll be doing things like select everything from C D that bookings or select everything from
C D that facilities instead of just writing from bookings or from facilities and we'll give you a quick
little tour of the actual schema and tables after we're done restoring.
So let's go ahead and restore that database.
We have two options for downloading the actual dot tar file.
One is the exercise that tower file directly uploaded to You to me in case you have any issues with
that.
I've also provided a permanent Google Drive link you can download from.
So go ahead and in the resources you should see two links one for the direct thought tar file and another
one for the Google Drive that you can use either one I'm going to click on that Google Drive link to
show you what it looks like.
So if you click on that Google Drive link it looks something like this.
It'll say something like woops there was a problem with the preview.
That's totally ok.
You can't really preview a dot tar file within Google Drive.
So just click the download button here and it'll eventually download.
Notice I've already downloaded it underneath exercises dot tar.
The only thing we have to remember is where exactly this dot tar file is.
And you can just show in folder and eventually you'll find it if you explore it's most likely underneath
your Downloads folder actually have it here myself so I can see I have exercised that tar and I can
see the full file path to it.
OK so let's go ahead and restore that.
Now hop over to PGE admin.
OK here I am in PGA admin.
Very zoomed in right now just to show you I'm going to right click on databases.
After I've already connected to a Postgres SQL Server if you're starting P.G. admin you'll just have
to click on servers click on post graphs reconnect and then we'll go ahead and just like we did last
time right click on databases hit create and then select database.
Go ahead and name this database.
Technically whatever you want I'll just name exercises.
Same as the top tier file and then let me zoom out a little bit so I can select that save button.
So I'm pretty zoomed in for filming purposes that we go so I'll save this.
There we go.
Let's go ahead and click on exercises so we can connect to it and then we're going to do is right click
on exercises and then we will select restore and then restore.
We have this custom or tar format and then you have two options.
As always you can either manually type in the file name which we discussed before in the DVD rental
install lecture.
So if you have any issues finding these three dots just manually type out the full file path but you
can also hit the three dots and go to wherever you happen to save it.
So I have downloads here I need to change my format to show all files and then you can also show hidden
files and folders.
Let's go ahead and select this based off when I downloaded it.
Here it is exercised not tar.
Go ahead and select if you have any issues especially if you're on Mac OS or Linux with these three
buttons just manually type out the full file path.
You can easily google search to find the full file path for any file on your computer.
So if I couldn't find it through the three dots I just simply pass on the full file path.
OK.
Just like last time I'm going to restore with pre data and post data that's all we need to do there.
And let's go ahead and restore USA restore a job created successfully complete in some older versions
of postcard sequel.
You may find a failed exit code one that's totally ok.
You can go ahead and ignore that failed executed.
It just means that it accidentally tried to restore it twice.
This only happens on some versions of Postgres sequel combined with a certain version of sometimes Mac
OS or even Windows older operating systems.
However it looks like successfully completed.
So I had no issues there.
If you get failed exit code one you can ignore it safely for now.
Go ahead and exit that then.
Important step here.
We want to refresh to actually apply those changes now if we go get down here to schemas.
You'll literally have to schemas a public schema and a C.D. schema the C.D. schema is actually the one
we're using.
Where if we expand on this we have actually three tables bookings facilities and members.
So show you what these actually look like.
I'm going to right click and let's open up a query tool on exercises.
So be careful to make sure you actually right click on exercise is not the old DVD rental one.
So I see here exercises.
I'm ready to run my query Ed. And as I mentioned in order to actually grab stuff from the table you'll
say select from and then don't just type in bookings otherwise you'll get an error you'll say hey bookings
doesn't exist you need a type C dot bookings because it's under the C these schema you run that.
And here we have the bookings.
So essentially the way this works is to give you a quick tour of this database.
We have facilities in this and we have a facility I.D. the name of that facility you can think of.
This is kind of like a resort or a gym and we have tennis courts massage rooms squash courts snooker
table pool table.
We have the member cost so how much it costs.
If you remember we have a guest costs.
If you're not a member of our particular gym or facility they'll cost you extra.
Some initial outlay parameter and then the monthly maintenance costs.
How much does it cost us as the owners of these facilities to actually run the tennis court every month.
So cost us 200 bucks a month.
The guests cost is twenty five dollars.
Member cost is five dollars.
OK.
Less facilities.
Let's go ahead and take a look at bookings so bookings is essentially someone or like a member booking
a facility.
So we have the booking I.D. the facility I.D. the member I.D. the start time and then how many slots
were necessary.
So if they're doing something like tennis maybe they book two slots or maybe they're just there to practice
so they book one slot et cetera and then finally we have members see these members go ahead and run
that we can see we have the member I.D. the surname first name.
Notice that if they're a guest we'll just say guest guest as well as their address a zip code telephone.
Note some of these telephones are fake.
Well technically all known these people are real recommended by could be null.
So we have some possibility for empty values.
And then the date they joined.
OK.
So we do have some things that are a little bit tricky here we have some null values depending on whether
a guest maybe we have a membership but we have some null values for other information et cetera.
But that's it the three relationships between the tables are actual facilities booking those facilities
and then members who actually book those facilities.
OK.
That's all you should need to know.
And coming up next it's gonna be a bunch of questions for you to answer on this database.
Best of luck.