Welcome back everyone to this lecture on the as Claus before we learn about joints.
Let's quickly cover this as clause or as a statement which allows us to create an alias for a column
or result.
And what we mean by alias is just an alternative name.
Let's say the example syntax for this is actually quite simple.
Instead of just selecting a column from a table we say select column as and then we decide on a new
name to display in the data output we can also use this on functions on a column.
So we can say something like SELECT column and then have that instead of displaying as some of that
column in the data output instead have it display as new name.
Let's see some examples.
So this is the way it classically works where we say select customer I.D. from payment and notice that
the column name is the same in the data output below.
We see customer underscore I.D..
Now let's see what happens if we were to use the as statement so here we're saying select amount as
rental price from payment.
So notice here instead of having the output reported as the amount column instead we decided to give
it an alias or rename it as rental underscore price.
And maybe this will be easier for some other analysts to read when we actually show them our SQL query
results.
So really here it's just for readability on the data output.
And this starts to make sense especially when we perform functions on a column for example select some
amount as net revenue from payments and instead of having the output just say some of the amount here
we can clarify it with an alias as the total net revenue from the payment table.
So essentially in net revenue we've made around sixty one thousand three hundred twelve dollars.
Now keep in mind the as operator gets executed at the very end of a query and this is where a lot of
students especially beginners get confused.
That means that we cannot use the alias inside of something like a where operator or a group by call.
And I'm going to walk through an example of trying to do that and having it show an error because a
lot of students get confused on that particular notion.
You essentially only get to use that alias in the SELECT statement anywhere else.
It's not actually going to be valid.
So let's head over to P.G. admin and walk through an example of that.
OK here I am at my query editor.
What I'm going to do is say select and we're actually going to say count the amount from the payment
column.
So if I run this notice I get back just count as my output.
And if I just see this data output without any regards to the query it's pretty unclear what this is
actually counting.
So maybe I want to clarify this using an alias so I can say as and counting the amount from the payment
column is the same as asking how many transactions have occurred.
So I can say a number of transactions run this and now I see that the data output has been running yet
renamed to be num underscore transactions and recall with count.
You can always just passin anything here to check such as an asterisk and that will be the exact same
thing.
So here saying count Asterix as Num transactions from payment using this alias it makes it quite clear
what the data output is actually showing us.
OK.
Now let's imagine we were going to do a group by statement so let's through the following.
Let's say select the customer I.D. and then some amount from payments.
And then I'm going to group by customer I.D. essentially showing how much each customer actually has
spent.
So I run this and I get back the customer I.D. as well as some sum.
However if I'm looking at the data output maybe it's not super clear that this sum happens to be their
actual expenditure because I don't see a dollar sign here anywhere and unless I actually get to read
this query and understand the thought process behind it the data output results don't specifically tell
me that the sum happens to be their total spent so I can simply say as total spent and then as I do
this directly after whatever column or function result I want to rename and then I run this and I get
back here and the data output total spent.
Now here is where I really want you to focus because this is where beginners often make a mistake.
Let's imagine that I wanted to clarify on the sum amount we already know I can do something like this
having some amount and let's have it be greater than 100 and we actually did pretty much this exact
same query and I'm going to remove as total spent.
So what am I doing here.
I'm doing the exact same thing as before except after I've done the group by and calculated the sum
amount I'm going to do an additional filtering using having or some amount is greater than one hundred.
So I run this and notice now my sums are all greater than one hundred and I'm going to use again my
alias.
So just clarify that as total spent so I run this and now I get to see total spent here.
Unfortunately this alias gets assigned at the very end which means I cannot do this and this is where
beginners try to do this a lot.
They'll say having total spent greater than one hundred and if they run this you get back an error they'll
say column total spent does not exist which at this stage is true.
Total Spent is only going to exist at the very end at the data output.
So because an alias gets assigned at the very end you cannot use it in something like a where statement
or a having clause.
Unfortunately you have to go back and choose the original either column name or the original function.
So we'll have to say having some amounts greater than one hundred and we see back these results.
So keep that in mind these aliases get assigned at the very end.
So you can't use them to filter by.
So I'm going to show you another example of this.
Let's just go ahead and remove group by and having some and we'll just say amount
we'd run this.
So here all the customer I.D. notices repeats as well as the amounts.
Now let's imagine I wanted to qualify this for amounts greater than two dollars.
Well I could say from payment then where amount is greater than two.
So I run this.
And now notice I got rid of all those one ninety nine transactions.
Now if I happen to use an alias on amounts so we'll say as new name I run this notice new name is down
the data output.
Unfortunately I cannot do this.
I cannot say where new name is greater than 2.
If I run this I get the same error as before.
That new name does not exist.
So again just to clarify these aliases get a sign that the end and unfortunately you can't use them
in the WHERE clause or the having clause to filter by instead just think of them as being used in the
data output and you'll have to use the original column name if you plan to do any filtering or comparison
operations on it.
All right.
That's it for the as statement as you can imagine as you begin to join tables using joint statements
we'll become quite useful to be able to assign aliases for clarification.
OK.
Coming up next we'll begin discussing joins.
I'll see you there.