Hello everyone and welcome
to the course curriculum lecture
for the complete SQL bootcamp.
In this lecture, we're gonna go over
the entire course's curriculum and understand
the building blocks that make up this course.
To begin, you'll start off by installing
PostgreSQL and PG Admin.
We have full installation walkthroughs
for both Windows and Mac computer systems.
Once we've done that, we'll start off
with some basic sections.
The first section will cover databases and table basics.
Then, we'll learn about SQL statement fundamentals.
In that section of the course,
you'll finally begin to use SQL syntax
to query the database and the tables
you created in the previous section.
Then, we'll step it up a notch
by learning about the GROUP BY clause
and once we've finished that,
you'll have your first assessment test
during the course.
Once you've completed that first assessment test,
you'll learn about JOINS, some
more advanced SQL commands, and then
you'll have a second assessment test
to test your understanding of everything you've learned
up to this point in the course.
After that, you'll have your final sections.
You'll learn how to create databases
and tables directly through a SQL syntax.
Then you'll have your third assessment test
that will test your knowledge
on creating databases and tables directly through SQL.
Then we also have some extra bonus lectures.
The lectures and these topics include views,
using PostgreSQL with the Python programming language
as well as some special discount offers
for my other courses.
With that all being said, let's go ahead
and get started with the entire course
so we can build up our knowledge.
Thanks everyone, and I'll see you
at the next lecture.