Welcome back everyone to this lecture on the coalesce function the coalesced function accepts an unlimited
number of arguments.
It returns the first argument that is not null if all arguments are no.
Then they coalesce function or return.
No.
So in practice you simply have the coalesce function.
And then you provide in any number of arguments in order that you want them to be evaluated in and typically
they are going to be column names.
And so to show you very simple examples.
If you say select coalesce one two it's going to go along and order until it finds the first nominal
value.
In this case it's simply one.
So it returns one.
However if one of the values ends up being null first such as select coalesce no comma to come a three
then the first value is no.
So continuous along.
Finally it finds a nominal value which is to put returns back to now of course I'm sure by now you're
wondering when is this actually going to become useful.
Well the coalesce function becomes useful when you're querying a table that contains no value and perhaps
you try and perform some sort of operation on it which you can't actually perform a final value.
So in case it's not you want to substitute it with another value.
I want to show you a really common example so here we have a table of products.
We have the item name ABC the original price one hundred dollars 300 dollars 200 dollars and then a
discount in dollars.
So if the price or excuse me if the item has a discount off the price it's listed in the discount column.
So item a currently has a discount of 20 dollars.
Item B does not have a discovery now.
So it's no.
And then item C has a discount of 10 dollars.
So here we have a really common issue where we have a null value because something doesn't exist.
So technically Item B does not have a discount.
So it's a null value there.
But if we're trying to perform mathematical operations that is technically a discount of zero.
So it's really common to use coalesce to actually replace no values with a 0 for calculation without
having to effect or alter your original table so let's imagine we're trying to answer the question What
is the final price which is going to be the price column minus the discount column.
Well we could try the following We could say select the item column comma and then calculate here parentheses
price column minus discount column as final let's say as the final price from table.
Now unfortunately that gets us this result so we're able to correctly calculate the final price for
items A and C but since the discount was no for Item B sequel can't actually subtract no from an integer.
So those are kind of incompatible data types.
So instead it relays back the information to you essentially alerting you to the fact that one of the
items was null by telling you that item B for final price is null.
Now in this particular situation we actually do not want the null value there.
Instead we want to know the correct discount.
So this is where coalesce comes into play so since this doesn't work for Item B we want it to be three
hundred essentially three hundred minus zero.
We're going to use coalesce.
And so this is where we can use coalesce in a clever fashion in order to fill in values for a null in
case they pop up without having to effect the original table.
So here we're going to say select item comma price minus and instead of just subtracting the discount
column or we're going to do is say coalesce this cow comma zero.
So think about what's happening here logically sequel his first going to check this count and check
if it's a nominal value.
So if it's not null meaning there's actually a number there.
It's simply going to return back that number.
So if there's a number for the discount such as 10 or 20 returns back that particular number.
However if this count is null then it continues on to the next value which in our case is zero.
So super common just to how these two values in a coalesce function to basically say hey if this particular
column happens to be no go ahead and substitute in this next value which in our case is zero.
So now we no longer get a no value for Item B.
Instead we get price minus zero which is three hundred for that particular row.
Okay.
So that's really where you're going to be be seeing coalesce used a lot in the real world.
So I want you to keep the COLAs function in mind in case you ever encounter a table of null values that
you want to perform operations on.
However you don't want to actually go in and do any changes to the table itself because it's often nice
to understand that there's a null value there essentially indicating that there currently is no discount
on that product for example and not that in this particular case there's a zero discount because those
can mean different things depending on the situation.
So again we have that useful function coalesce which will come in handy if you ever want to do substitutions
like that in the future.
I'll see you at the next lecture.