Welcome everyone to this lecture on the create keyword Let's not learn the syntax to create a table
and sequel.
Using this create keyword in the generalized column syntax so when you're creating a table.
This is the full General syntax layout and we're going to focus on just a couple of things here and
then we'll walk through some examples in P.G. admin.
But let's go over the general syntax components.
First there is the CREATE TABLE AND THEN YOU choose whatever table name you want.
So you would say something like CREATE TABLE payments or CREATE TABLE CUSTOMERS next are the columns
that are within that table and you'll choose the column name.
Then the data type for the particular column and then you'll add in any column constraints and you just
have this almost as a list of different columns something to pay attention to are the fact that use
commas to separate out these columns.
A really common mistake for beginners is they forget this comma at the end and then you'll get some
sort of weird error that's hard to actually diagnose.
So again remember there's a comma there when we're dealing with the actual columns Next you add in any
table level constraints that you want so you can list off different table constraints.
And we talked about those options in the constraints lecture and then in case you have some sort of
relationship to another table and you can inherit from an existing table.
Now we'll talk about things like table constraints and the inherits command later on for now I really
just want to focus on creating the table and setting up your columns.
So we're gonna fall along right now for this lecture with what I'm going to call common simple syntax
which is just creating the table and then adding in your columns.
Let's work through a very quick example and then we'll go over to PGI admin and actually code it out
so for example syntax you would keep CREATE TABLE those keywords don't change and then you decide on
a table name.
So let's go ahead and make up a player's table then we have to decide what columns are going to be in
our players table.
Typically what you're going to do first is you're going to choose a column to be a primary key.
Typically each table should have a primary key.
Obviously this may change depending on your circumstances.
But let's go ahead and go with that.
So we're gonna have a player I.D. as the column name.
We have to choose a type and almost always especially a postcard sequel when you're trying to think
of a primary key the type should be serial.
So I actually want to focus in on this serial data type because it has some special properties so in
postcard sequel a sequence is a special kind of database object that generates a sequence of integers
and a sequence is often used as a primary key column in a table.
So what Serial is going to do it's going to create a sequence object and set the next value generated
by the sequence as the default value for the column.
And this is perfect for a primary key because it logs unique integer entries for you automatically upon
insertion.
So that means as you're inserting more data into this table you will actually need to worry about providing
a unique player idea yourself.
Instead a serial is going to do this for you which makes sense because as you insert data you're probably
not going to know what actual player I.D. you're on as far as the integer count goes.
So serial takes care of this so what's also nice about cereal is that if a row is later removed the
column with the cereal data type will not adjust.
It's not going to reformat everything in the cereal instead since it's not going to adjust it that's
actually going to mark the fact that a row was moved from the sequence for example in this primary key
column as you're inserting players you may see something like 1 2 3 and let's imagine we inserted 4
5 6 7 and then later on you decide to delete row number four because that player maybe left your team.
What's nice about this is cereal is actually going to show that gap as the primary key.
I'll show one two three five six seven which means as you as a user go back to that table and see that
you're missing number four from the primary I.D. column or primary key column you know now historically
that row four was removed at some point.
So cereal takes care of a lot of problems for us automatically it makes sure that each of these is unique
because it's a sequence that keeps adding one based off the previous value.
And then we ourselves as we insert data into this table don't need to even worry about providing a value
for the primary key column OK so you may already be familiar with this table.
We mentioned that in the data types and you'll notice that there's actually options for different types
of cereal.
There's small cereal which is just two bytes and it goes from one to about thirty three thousand so
three thousand two seven six seven and then we have cereal which is four bytes.
It goes to a larger value and then big cereal goes to a extremely large value.
So you can choose which one of these is appropriate for you depending on how large your table is going
to be so we'll just go ahead and choose cereal again.
You could chose small cereal or big cereal but we'll just choose cereal as our data type because it's
going to be our primary key because as is our primary key we actually type that in as a column constraint.
So we set the table to verify it.
This is a primary key.
And then finally let's go ahead and add in one last column.
So let's go ahead and put the age of the player.
So we have to choose a type for this.
Again you can go back to that table in the documentation decide what types are appropriate.
So if we take a look at this maybe we decide that a small integer is appropriate.
We don't need such a huge integer value arrange for ages especially for people because people can only
go from zero to a little above 100.
We don't need the integer to go to some huge large number.
So we'll go ahead and say that the data type is a small integer and then the column constraint can really
be whatever you want.
But let's imagine that for some reason our league that these players are playing in is constrained by
the age let's say players that are over 18 can no longer play in this league.
So because of this requirement we actually need to make sure that we know the age of the player in which
case we'll want to make sure that a column constraint could be something like not null meaning that
if you're inserting a player into this table you cannot leave the age blank otherwise the table will
reject the new entry.
OK.
So this is an example syntax of creating just a very very simple table so let's go ahead and actually
explore some examples in PGA admin and typing this out.
All right.
Here I am inside of P.G. Ataman to begin I want to make sure we create these tables in a brand new database.
That way we don't excellent contaminate our DVD rental database.
So what I want to do is if you already have a query Ed open which you may have as you're following on
this course you'll notice that it's open as a tab here.
No it says DVD rental post grass et cetera.
Go ahead and right click on this and just click remove panel and it's going to ask you if you want to
save any changes we don't need to worry about that so don't save.
And that way we make sure that we don't actually run this query Ed in DVD rental.
The next thing we're going to do is we're actually going to create a new database.
So underneath Postgres sequel underneath databases right click go to create database and then we're
gonna go ahead and you can really call this database whatever you want I'll call it learning.
And again it's really up to you.
But just for learning how to create databases and tables kind of make sense.
So don't you worry about changing anything else.
Go ahead and click save.
You should see learning appear here.
Go ahead and click on it and then just to make sure everything's working after you click on it and you've
made a connection.
Just hit refresh and then we should be good to go.
So after this I'm going to right click on learning and then I'm going to open up my query tool and the
query tool can not only be used for getting information from a database but we can also run secret commands
to create tables from here.
So that's what I'm going to do.
And just to confirm that we're on learning with this query Ed. Go ahead and take a look at your tab
here and you should see learning here underneath the tab.
OK so now that that's done let's go ahead and create our table.
So the first table we're going to create is just an example account table.
So we have our first keywords.
Create table and let's just say the table name is account and then we have open and close parentheses.
And here over multiple lines is where we can add in the actual column names.
So I'm going to have a user I.D. column and I'm going to set this as serial.
And because it's going to be serial the constraint I'm going to set on it is primary key.
So this is going to be a primary key identifier that is automatically set up for us so that as we learn
how to insert tape insert information into this table we don't actually need to worry about inserting
a user I.D. serial will take care of it for us and that'll make more sense when we talk about the insert
command.
So that's one column.
Don't forget to put in your comma and then we'll have a user name and technically I don't really need
to worry about indentation or spacing but just to make these lineup so it looks a little nicer.
We'll go ahead and do that and then we're gonna have just this be a variable character and we are using
variable character.
You have the pass and the limits of how long you allow this to be.
So this could be a limit of for instance no more than 50 characters inside of the user name string.
And we want to make sure that each user name that is set up here is actually unique.
That way we don't accidentally have people with the same user name so we can set it up to be unique.
The other thing we should probably set up here is that if you're setting up an account with us we can't
just have your user name be blank.
So we also want to make sure that it's a not null constraint here.
So we have that the next thing I want to set up here is a password column so we can store their password.
We'll have this be variable character 50 as well and passwords.
Let's say we don't need to worry about them being unique.
People can maybe have the same password.
Especially if this is not really a security threat.
But we should make sure that they actually have a password.
So we'll again say it cannot be null and obviously there are things like security concerns that we're
not really taking into account here when it comes to password.
So very very simple database really just learning the syntax here.
Let's go ahead and provide an e-mail column.
We'll have this b variable character as well.
Let's say e-mails are typically longer than let's say a 50 character limit.
Some people can have really long emails.
So go ahead and choose something like two hundred and fifty characters available.
And again we want to make sure that there aren't shared e-mails.
So the e-mails just like a user name should be unique and it should also be not in all the constraints
is really going to depend on your specific situation.
So keep that in mind.
Every single table and database has its own unique situation.
So I can't give you some general rules for what constraints you should provide on your own columns because
that really depends on your business situation.
And finally let's go ahead and create some timestamp columns.
We want to keep track of when an actual table is or a row is created like an account is created.
So we'll say created on and we'll have this be a timestamp.
We'll have that be not no.
And let's go ahead and keep track of when the person last logged in so say last log in and also have
that be a timestamp.
So if we scroll down a little bit here just to see the princes that closes this all off.
Notice my very last column didn't actually need to princes cause I'm not adding anything after that.
And also notice that I'm not going to go ahead and say any constraints on last log in because what I
want to make sure that is even if you have just created your account you won't really have a last log
in which means if I said not null here that may have created some sort of error.
So created on.
Should definitely be not no but last log in.
I don't want some sort of error occurring if the person created their account but doesn't have a last
log in because they just created their account.
So that's why there's no constraint here on last log in beyond just the data type having to be a timestamp.
OK so here's our CREATE TABLE account let's go ahead and run this so when you run this it'll say something
like create table query return successfully the data output shouldn't show anything because we're actually
not asking for anything here.
And if you see explain pretty much all this should be blank.
Keep in mind though you can only run this one time.
So take a look here underneath.
Learning schemas.
We have the public schema and then we have now tables expand on that and you can see this new account
table.
So this account if we expand on columns I can see the columns I created and I can actually also see
some of the constraints I created.
So notice here now we have a little primary key constraint.
And on the account email Key has one here basically indicating that there was a specific constraint
there.
OK so we have that all set up ready to go.
Something I want to know which is a really common error is I'm going to induce an error by clicking
execute.
Again if you click execute again the error is actually relatively straightforward it says relation account
already exists which makes a lot of sense.
You don't want to accidentally create the table account again and then overwrite an entire table.
So instead Postgres sequel is going to just tell you hey you can't create that table that already exists.
Later on when we learn about things like the alter command we will be able to alter and edit existing
tables.
So we have this account table.
Now what I want to show you is the ability to create another table and then link them through a foreign
key to show you this.
We're going to start by creating two more tables.
So we have this person with the account.
Let's go ahead and create a job table.
So let's say certain people can be assigned jobs later on.
So we're going to say create table job.
And this job table will have a job I.D. column.
And this is going to be a serial column primary key because it's a unique identifier for the job.
And then the job will have some sort of job name or job description.
So we'll say job name is the other column.
We'll make this variable character.
Let's give it a limit of two hundred and then they should be unique.
That way we don't accidentally have two jobs of the same name and we can't have an empty job so we can't
just have a job idea you have no job.
So here's our create table very simple for the jobs.
Go ahead and run this.
We should get back.
Create table career return successfully.
Remember you can only run this one time.
And I want I want to do is I want to create a table that references both the account and the job.
Basically it's going to be an intermediary table that connects someone's account to their specific job.
And when they were hired for that job.
So this is gonna be the table that shows us how to actually reference a foreign key.
We're going to say create table.
This is going to be the account job.
Table and it's going to have a user I.D. column and this user I.D. column should be the same as the
user I.D. in the account.
Which means it's going to be an integer type.
Notice that I'm not saying serial serial should only be used as a primary key for the table that it's
in when you're using it to reference in another table.
It's just going to show up as a normal integer because serial is really just a sequence of integers.
So because this is going to be a foreign key reference I'm just going to say that my user I.D. is an
integer.
And then here comes the keyword that references
and I need to tell it what column and what table to reference.
So I pass in the table name and then in parentheses I pass in the column name.
Inside that table.
So recall inside of this account I have a user I.D. column.
So the user I.D. column inside the account table will be the reference or foreign key reference for
the user i.e. the integer inside of the account job table.
Now we're going to say comma and let's do the same thing for job I.D..
So we will say job I.D. is also going to be an integer that references from the job table.
The job I.D. column.
And then finally let's go ahead and add in some column that basically tells the person when they were
hired for this job.
So let's say there was a hired date and I'm just going to have that be a timestamp if you want.
You can optionally add in things like it has to be not no but just keep things simple.
I have this hire date.
Let's go ahead and run this so I'm going to expand this a little bit run this and we should see query
or return successfully.
So now I have three tables I have we come back here.
Notice that right now it says tables 1 that's because I need to refresh this.
So typically you're going to need to refresh every time you create a new table.
Go ahead and refresh that lets the database essentially no.
OK here and now the information on the three tables I have job account job and account account was that
first table we created.
And if I take a look at account job taking a look at the columns I have user I.D. job I'm the hired
date then we have these constraints.
I notice now we see essentially information that we have these foreign keys.
You can check out our lectures on primary keys and foreign keys to refer to how you can confirm those
sort of connections.
OK so that's the very basics of creating a table with columns that have both primary key and foreign
key references.
Coming up next we're gonna learn how to insert information into the table.
I'll see you there.