Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to discuss the HAVING clause the HAVING clause allows us to filter after
an aggregation has already taken place.
So it comes after a group by call.
Let's take a look back at one of our previous examples let's imagine this very simple query where we're
selecting some sort of company column and then taking the sum of the sales column from some financial
table.
Regroup by company so we're aggregating sales per company.
Now we've already seen we can filter before executing the group by FOR WHERE statement.
For example here I could put aware right before my group buy and say we're company not equal to Google
because maybe I don't want to include Google in my final results.
So that's OK because the company isn't being aggregated in any sort of way.
It is in the group by statement however it's not having an aggregate function being called on it.
So it can use where but what if we actually wanted to filter based off the some sales so keep in mind
that since we're calling some on sales that's not going to happen until after that group by statements
executed all the way at the bottom which means we cannot use where to filter based off aggregate results
because those happen after the actual where statement is executed.
So if after performing the group by and calculating the sum of sales per company I wanted to then perform
an additional filter on that result based off the sum of sales I could add the having clause.
So having allows us to use the aggregate result as a filter along with a group buy so you can essentially
think of this as a where statement but only for something that is being aggregated through the group
by and hopefully can see that connection quite clearly here.
So again here I'm able to now filter based off the aggregate result of some of sales in my having clause.
So here I'm saying do the filter of the where.
And then after you group buy go ahead and do another filtering where we're having the sum of sales greater
than some number like a thousand dollars so you would end up of a query that looks something like this.
All right let's explore some examples of having in our own database and then jumped the PGA admin now
all right here in the PGA admin I'm going to work through a very similar example that we just made up.
Let's first check out our payment table so select select everything from payment.
Go ahead and run this.
And we're already familiar this we have the customer I.D. staff I.D. et cetera.
Let's go ahead and take the total sum amounts for a customer.
So we'll say select the customer I.D. and then take the sum amount from payment and we will group this
by customer I.D. so we can run this and this all works out fine.
I already know that if I for some reason wanted to filter out certain customers I could say something
like this where customer I.D. maybe I wanted to say not equal to or I could say something like not in
some list of I.D. like let's go ahead and remove one eighty four eighty seven and four seventy seven
we run this again and no problem we saw that.
Now those no longer exist here in the results.
Now what I cannot do is filter with a where statement on some amount because the sum of the amount is
not going to happen until after I called the group by.
So what I'm going to do then it's go to remove this where example to simplify things.
I can say after the group by having some amount and let's just say greater than 100.
So we go ahead and run this and we can check out the results here and now you'll notice everything's
been filtered so all the sums are now greater than 100.
You should also notice just like when we were using order by with an aggregate function on a column
we have to actually specify some amount.
We don't just take amount let's explore using having with a count call instead of just as some call.
We can do this by maybe exploring the customer table just to remind you will select everything from
customer table.
So this is the customer I.D. a store I.D. first name last name their email address I.D. et cetera.
So what we can do here is let's imagine we wanted to know the number of customers per store.
What I could do is if we scroll over here grab the store I.D. and the account number of customer I.D.
associate if them after a group by store right.
So we're going to say store I.D. and then count customer I.D. from customer after a group by store I.D.
we run this and I can see the total count of customers per store.
Keep in mind I don't have to actually pass on customer I.D. because this is just saying how many rows
are there per store I.D. so I could put an asterix here run this again and you'll notice I get back
the exact same results.
Now let's imagine I wanted to select only stores that had more than 300 customers.
Well in this case I'd have to filter based off something it's already been aggregated so I can't do
that where I can't do it with having so I can say having a count Asterix greater than let's say 300.
And that's essentially performing the filter after the group by.
And keep in mind depending on how you want to think about this.
You can switch out an asterisk there for customer I.D. and it will perform the exact same.
So customer and the customer I.T. run this.
We get back the exact same results.
It's up to you which one's easier to read here.
If you come back to this this quite clearly reads as number of customers group by store where the number
of customers is more than 300.
If we just left an asterisk there then we'd have to remember that the customer table represents all
the customers per store there.
OK so let's go ahead and test your skills in the next lecture we'll give you some challenges with the
having class.
I'll see you there.