Welcome back everyone to this lecture on the No.
If function the No.
If function takes in just two inputs and returns no.
If both are equal otherwise it returns the first argument passed.
So the syntax we're going to be using is you say no.
If and then pass in the two arguments.
So for example if you pass in ten and ten into the null if function since 10 is equal to 10 it's going
to return.
No.
However if you were to pass in ten and twelve since those are not equal to each other it's going to
return 10 this becomes very useful in cases where he null value would cause an error or an unwanted
result.
Let's go ahead and show an example of this so let's imagine we have this particular very simple table
and we want to calculate the ratio of people in Department A to Department B.
So for example we have the three entries so Lauren events and and Claire and their department.
So A and B and we can easily see here that the ratio of A to B is two to one or two hundred percent.
So we can actually use sequel to solve this with a case statement.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna jump to P.G. Ataman quickly create this table and then walk through
solving that ratio and then I'm going to edit this table slightly to show you why you may need a no
if statement.
OK let's jump the PGA admin and quickly create this table.
All right.
Here I am in P.G. admin.
The first thing I want to do is I want to make sure that I'm not editing an existing database like the
DVD rental database.
Instead go ahead and create a database specifically for testing purposes.
If you haven't done so already from previous lectures go ahead and right click on post sequel and create
a new database you can call it whatever you want and then just hit save.
So I've called my test me and it's for testing purposes.
So here I have under Test Me I'm going to right click and then set up my query tool.
So confirm that your query tool is connected to this test database by reading the tab here and notice
now right here it says test me Postgres sequel.
OK so now that I'm in this test database let's create this simple table we'll say create table and let's
call this table just DP T.S. for departments and it's very simple just has two columns which is the
first name column.
So let's say first name and the first name just make it a variable character up to 50.
No constraints and then the second one is going to be the actual department therein.
So that will also be variable character.
Let's go ahead and say 50 and make sure we put a comma here so we don't get an error.
So again very simple table just holds departments.
Same one we saw on the slides a first name and a Department letter.
So we'll go ahead and run this and the table has been created successfully.
Now let's go ahead and insert into this table so I can do that.
Delete this.
Create table will say insert into departments and I'm going to be inserting first name.
No longer need that variable character and I'm also going to be inserting department and then after
this insert command recall that we have values and then we say what values we're actually going to insert.
So I want to insert the same ones or roughly the same ones that I had in the slides.
So let's go ahead and say lips single quote here Vinton we'll have this person be in the apartment a
comma another entry here we're gonna have Lauren.
This person is also in the apartment a.
And then finally we'll have Claire and this person is in Department B.
So pretty simple here and then we're gonna end it with semicolon just to clarify that's the end of our
statement.
So we're inserting into the department's stable first name in the apartment.
Vincent Lauren and Claire go ahead and run that the insert should a return successfully if not make
sure you're checking for typos such as missing comments and then what I wanna do is confirm all this
by selecting everything from this new department table run that and I can see here the results I have
Vinson Lauren and Claire.
OK so as I mentioned let's imagine that I wanted to calculate the ratio between male and female members.
So the way I can do that is actually using a case statement.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to select and this is we're going to be doing a some call so I'm
going to sum up the case when departments
is equal to a then one else zero and then it just right is kind of as a one liner.
So what is that doing.
It's just going to essentially count up how many people are in the apartment.
So that should just create an extra column with ones for the A's and then zeros for the B's and then
what I want to do is sum that up.
So essentially this is going to be equal to two since there's two A's and then I'm going to take this.
Let's go ahead and then make sure our parentheses are OK.
So going to take that results and I'm going to divide it by the sum of the case when the apartment is
equal to B then 1 else 0 end.
So what does this actually doing.
This is basically again adding up all the A's so there's gonna be equal to 2 and then this is adding
up all the B's equal to 1 and then we're gonna take those two sums and then divide this sum using this
division operator with this sum OK.
So that should get me a two to one ratio right.
So then two divided by one should be equal to two.
And then what I'm going to do here is after this what I'm gonna say is as an analyst call this the Department
ratio so say the apartments underscore ratio and I'm doing this all from this department table OK so
again doing those sums dividing it to get the ratio as the partner ratio from apartments.
Go ahead and run this and you should get back to since there was two A's to want to be so far nothing
too crazy and we haven't actually used the null if function yet.
So what I'm going to do is now show you what happens if there actually are no more people in Department
B let's go ahead and say that person department B left.
So that means currently having a person department B to do this I'm going to delete this code and don't
worry still available to us in our query history as long as we ran it.
And then I'm going to type out delete from the apartments and I'm going to delete where the apartment
is equal to be so run that and that.
Notice that deleted one row.
So let's go ahead and say select from the apartments run this and I only have people from the apartment
a.
So let's go ahead and see what happens if I try running that same ratio.
So I'm going to go to my query history and note here I have the select command of the league command
and I have this select some.
So go ahead and copy this your query editor or you can retype it again if you wanted to but I just copied
from query history to create editor run that same code again and you'll notice that you get an error
this error makes sense because we are currently dividing by zero which you cannot do.
So how can we use the know if functionality in order to make sure that instead of getting an error we
just get back a null a null is a good indication that there essentially is no one in one of these departments
instead of having a full error in which case it's not really clear what's happening.
So we're gonna do is use the null if around this second one right here in order to say return a null
if there happens to be a zero there.
So the way I do that is recall that no if is going to return a null if they both match.
So that means if both arguments match the both arguments I pass to know if then it returns a null.
And right now I want to return a no.
If this entire sum happens to be zero.
So what I'm going to do is pass in this entire sum call go ahead and cut that and paste that into no
if and then the second parameter I'm passing into the No.
If and be careful of your parentheses here is going to be zero.
So what this is saying is if both of these happen to be equal to each other.
Meaning if the result of this sum is equal to zero return a null.
Otherwise if these don't happen to be equal to each other.
So the sum is actually returning something then just return.
The first argument.
So keep in mind order does matter within this.
No if function because it's going to return the first one.
If they don't happen to be equal to each other.
So now when I run this instead of getting an error it's going to return back a null because if you try
to divide something by null then that simply returns a null instead of a division by zero error.
So you really common use case for a null.
If it's just to check against something and specifically with the way databases are often designed to
check against something being equal to zero and then it happens to be equal to that go ahead and return
a null instead.
Okay.
So definitely take your time with this one.
I know the codes a little bit complex here because we're using this case statement but if you just take
your time and read through the logic of what's happening here it's pretty understandable that we're
essentially using null if as a check against returning a zero.
Okay thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.