Java web applications are typically built out of servlets and JavaServer Pages.
If you're using a framework,
that framework will also certainly build on top of these specifications.
For example, Struts.
Struts is a server and JavaServer Page framework.
If something goes wrong inside your application,
and your application is using a framework such as Struts,
it's important to understand the underlying APIs.
It's important to understand how a servlet works.
It's important to understand that a JavaServer Page is itself a servlet.
This will aid debugging,
it will aid in many other aspects of the application development.
The servlet specification also defines a couple of other large components,
filters and listeners.
In this class, we'll take a look at what a filter is,
we'll take a look at the lifecycle of a filter,
we'll also take a look at what a listener is and the lifecycle of a listener,
and how these two components can be used inside the applications.
Filters in particular are very important as many frameworks today use filters as controllers as part of their MVC model.