To write filters,
we implement javax.servlet .Filter and we implement the doFilter method.
And the doFilter method is passed the request object,
the response object, and a filter chain.
To pass the request down the chain, we call chain.doFilter.
Filters in many ways act like servlets,
so from within the filter we could dispatch the request with different resource,
we could call a different servlet,
or within the filter we may return immediately
without calling doFilter on the chain,
and so not forwarding the request further down the chain.
We configure filters in a web.xml file.
So there's a filter entry, we give the filter a name,
we specify the class of the filter, and filters have initialization parameters,
and we specify those with the init-param element inside
the filter element in the web.xml file.
Filters, like servlets, also have mappings associated with them.
So I can associate a filter with a given resource,
such as * .jpg say, or I can associate a filter with any resource,
which we do here with /*.
So this filter here, when it was registered, will be called for any request.
Notice we can also associate a filter with a specific servlet if we need to
by using the servlet-name entry inside the filter mapping.
So filters have an initialization method,
and this is called once when the filter is first loaded.
In this case it passed a reference to a FilterConfig,
and from here we can get the ServletContext.
So if we need to, for example, we can get context parameters,
and notice here we can call getInitParameter,
and this gives us access to the filter's initialization parameters.
Inside the filter itself,
the doFilter method is called for every request that
this filter is set up to handle.
Now as we saw, the filter is passed the request object,
the response object, and the chain object.
The request and the response object are of type
ServletRequest and ServletResponse,
but typically we can cast those to be an
HttpServletRequest and an HttpServletResponse.
Within the filter, we can preprocess the request,
we can do some work on the request before we pass it on.
We could also wrap up the request and/or wrap up the response,
and we'll see how we do that a little later.
Once we've processed the request ourselves,
we can call chain.doFilter, then if we need to when the call comes back to us,
we could post process the response.
So we can wrap up the request,
and you might want to wrap up the request so that you can
monitor calls on the request object.
So to do that, we extend a class called HttpServletRequestWrapper.
Then when we chain the filter call,
rather than passing on the original request object,
we pass on the wrapper, and again we'll see some examples of this in a moment.
So let's take a look at how we write a simple filter. We'll take a look at a logging filter in the code.