So what we have at the moment is essentially nothing
more than a glorified HTML page.
We can change that by taking advantage of some of
the features of JavaServer Pages.
So for example we might want to break the page down into its
constituent parts to be able to reuse those parts.
So here for example we have a header section.
It might be nice to have that section in a separate fragment that
we can include into the page as and when needed.
So we could do that.
So if I go to my project structure and add a new page here,
so new JSP, call this something like _header.jsp,
select this and paste it in the header.
If I go back into the index page and then delete the header,
just to prove that this is working, if we go to the browser and refresh the page,
and we see the header information has disappeared,
then if I go back into here, and now I need to include that header fragment.
And to do that we can use what's called a directive.
JSP has many directives.
In this case we're going to use the include directive.
And directives are introduced by using less than percent at.
And we can see here it says include, so I can use the include directive,
and it'll reference the page for me, so _header.jsp.
Let me close off the directive by using percent greater than.
Saving the page, going back to the browser,
and refreshing, and we now include the header.
When we use the include directive in this way,
the page that we reference inside the directive,
in this case _header.jsp, is included into the page at page translation time.
Page translation time is when this JavaServer Page is translated into Java,
and that Java is then compiled into the .class file.
So this happens during the compilation of the page.
We can also include resources dynamically in the page,
and we'll see how we do that a little later.
And those dynamically included resources are essentially executed as
part of the lifetime of the servlet rather than being compiled into
the page when the page itself is compiled.
So as well as the include directive,
another directive you'll use quite frequently is the page directive.
The page directive has many attributes to it that we can use.
So as we saw, the JSP page is in fact a servlet,
and the servlet when it's created derives from a base
class that's defined by the container.
We can use the page directive to change our base class.
So we could, for example, say less than percent at page.
And then here we could say extends,
and give it a name of a class that we want this page to
derive from or extend in Java terms.
And we can do that for example if we need common functionality in a
base class that all our pages are going to use.
Using the page directive,
we can also modify the behavior of the servlet container such as Tomcat.
So for example the JSP page will generate text output,
typically HTML, maybe XML.
That output may be buffered, and we can specify the size of the buffer.
So we can say page buffer =, and this defaults to 8k.
We can turn that off, we can set that buffer size to 0 for example.
We can also, along with the buffering, specify an option called autoFlush.
AutoFlush defaults to true.
We can set autoFlush to false,
and what that means is that as we generate the page output,
if the buffer is full,
then the runtime will throw an exception while it is
flushing the page down to the browser.
We can also use the page directive to, for example, set the contentType.
So by default the contentType is text/html,
we could change that to text/xml, we could change that to just plain text,
or maybe set it to JSON for example.
Another common use of the page directive is to specify an errorPage.
The errorPage is the page that's displayed.
If this particular JavaServer Page throws an exception,
we can set the errorPage in web.xml,
we can override that here by specifying a specific page here.
Typically though, the reverse is done,
in that a JavaServer Page is used as the errorPage.
So for example in that case here we'd say isErrorPage would be true,
by default that value is false.
And that means that this errorPage has access to some other intrinsic information that we can use to display errors.