So in this chapter, we'll take a look at event listeners.
So events are essentially method calls,
and they're method calls made by the servlet container at
appropriate times during the lifecycle of that container.
So for an example,
an application event can fire when the application
starts up or when the application ends.
So if we need to do any per-application initialization,
we can do it in response to this event.
Session events start when a session starts or a session ends,
and again we can use this to initialize a session for a user and
then tidy up when that session's finished.
Request events happen on every request start and request end,
so these are the more frequent events that fire.
There are also events fired when attributes are added to certain things,
such as a session or a request.
Listeners are classes and code that listen for these events and do
specific processing when one of these events files.
So to create a listener, we have to implement the appropriate interface.
So for an application event, we'd implement ServletContextListener,
for session events, there's an HttpSessionActivationListener,
and for request events, there's the ServletRequestListener.
There are also corresponding interfaces for the
various attribute events as well, such as ServletContextAttributeListener.
Each of these interfaces defines methods,
and those methods will pass the appropriate event object when an event is fired,
and we can use this event object to discover information about the events.
We can register these listeners in a web.xml file.
So here for example,
we've registered a class called com.mantiso .WhitePagesListener.
Notice here we don't specify the type of listener,
so this could be an application listener,
a session listener, or a request listener.
The type of listener this class represents is figured out by the
container depending on the interface this class implements.
There can be many entries inside listener,
and these listeners are executed in the order they
are listed inside the web.xml file,
and then called again in reverse order for the deactivation events.
We can also use annotations to register events,
as we mentioned in the introduction,
and to do that we use the WebListener annotation,
and we'll see examples of that as we build our event handlers.
So as a first example, let's take a look at an application listener.
So to be an application listener, you implement ServletContextListener.
Events on this listener are fired up at application
start and an application end, and they are passed a ServletContextEvent object.
This object, amongst other things, gives us access to the ServletContext.
And here's an example.
Here we have a WhitePagesServletListener,
it implements javax.servlet .ServletContextListener,
and notice there are two methods on here,
contextInitialized and contextDestroyed.
Both methods are passed a ServletContextEvent,
and these methods represent the event.
So the contextInitialized method is called when the application is loaded,
and that's the applicationInitialized event,
and contextDestroyed is called just before the application is unloaded, and that's the contextDestroyed event.