As a Java programmer, you're probably aware that there are many,
many IDEs that we could use to build applications.
There are also toolkits available to allow us to build
applications and to allow us to deploy applications,
such as Ant and Maven.
For consistency's sake, as part of this project we're going to be using Maven.
Maven is more than a build tool.
In fact,
people primarily use Maven to manage dependencies within the application.
In this project,
we'll use Maven as a standard tool to both build and deploy the application.
Our Maven usage will be fairly simple.
We define a project, the project has a standard groupId,
artifactId, and version, we define some packaging.
As we'll see later, we'll be using the Tomcat web server to run the application.
And in our Maven POM,
I'll define a Tomcat plugin that you can use to
deploy the application to Tomcat.
Apart from that, the Maven POM we use will be very, very straightforward.
If you've never used Maven before and you're interested in
understanding exactly how Maven works,
then Pluralsight offers a class that is an introduction to Maven.
You can download Maven from maven.apache .org.
Simply click on the Download link and grab the latest zip.
Once you have it, unzip it, and you need to set a couple of other options.
In particular,
you need to set MAVEN_HOME so it points at the
location you've unzipped the files to,
and you'll also need to add MAVEN_HOME\bin to your path.
Once you've done that, you'll be able to run Maven from the command line,
typing mvn, and you should just see the fact that it runs and so it's available, it knows where home is, and everything should be good to go.