The next set of tags to look at in the core library are the iteration tags,
and there are primarily two of these.
There's a for-each tag and a for-tokens tag.
So on our page, we have a set of tabs, and these tabs are rendered here.
They're in a list.
Whenever you see code like this,
this is a prime candidate for replacement with some form of iteration.
So here for example we're outputting the name of the tab,
the app.tabNames, and also an href for the tab.
You may remember that the way this is set up currently is that in
the ControllerServlet inside the init method,
we create the tab names, so we just create an array of strings,
and we call this application.setTabNames,
and application.setTabNames stores these tab names inside an array.
We can then set the applicationSettings into the ServletContext,
so these names are then available within the page,
and we use the names here.
What we'd like to do is to have a structure that
will associate the name of the tab, home,
with the href, and to do that we've created a new class called Tab,
and Tab has a name and a URL.
So we'll use the for-each tag to replace this hard-coded
set of list items in the tab list.
So to do that we need to add c:forEach here,
and that has an items attribute,
and the items attribute specifies the item that we want to iterate over.
You can iterate over any collection, so an array, a list, maybe a hash map.
In this case we're going to iterate over a list,
and the list is called tabs,
and tabs is stored in the ApplicationSettings object,
and that's part of the request scope.
So in here you can say $ app.tabs.
Each time the for-each tag iterates,
it stores the reference to the current item in a variable.
We give that variable a name.
So we can save var=,
in this case we'll just say var=tab Each tab in here is of type tab,
and that's defined here.
Each of these has a name and a URL,
and these are set up in the same way that list was
previously set up inside the ControllerServlet,
so inside here we create an ArrayList of tab objects,
and each of these has text that will appear on the page,
and the URL that we will go to when we click on that tab.
Just to make things slightly different here, we've added five tabs.
There's SignIn, Home, Profile, Messages, and Settings.
We've done that just so that when we refresh the
page we can see these differences.
So we create the tabs list,
and we set that inside the ApplicationSettings object,
and that is then stored inside the ServletContext.
So the ApplicationSettings object has a list of tabs that
we can access from inside the page.
So back in the page, we now need to output a list item for each of these tabs,
so just grabbing one of these, and we can now edit this.
So rather than hard coding these values on the page,
we can use an expression, we can say $tab,
which is the variable name defined here,
and then for this thing, say .url, and over here say $ tab.name.
And we'll get rid of this list.
So if I redeployed the code, back in the browser if I refresh,
I should see five tabs, and sure enough we now have the Messages tab.
So the iteration code has greatly simplified the UI
and it's made the page more dynamic.
We could certainly read this list of tabs now from a database.
That means that as an admin user, we could go in,
add new tabs when we need to, and we wouldn't need to go back in and edit the JavaServer Pages to do that.