As we've seen, doGet, doPost,
etc., get past an HttpServletRequest and an HttpServletResponse object.
These give us access to the incoming request and the
outgoing response respectively.
We can use the incoming request object to get at the data in the request.
For example, we can get at any headers sent as part of the request,
using the request.getHeader method.
We just specify the name of the HTTP header here.
We can get at specific things in the request,
so there's a request.getContentType if we need to know the
content type of the incoming request.
For example, whether we're sending up maybe JSON data,
if we're sending up image data, if we're sending up data from a form.
Perhaps the most important one is the getParameter call.
So this gives us access to any of the incoming HTTP parameters.
The parameters are those specified with a question mark on the URL,
or also as part of the incoming body,
so if we're sending up an HTTP form for example,
and that form contains data, those parameters will be the data from the form.
And we can also get at the actual data itself.
So again, for example, if we're uploading an image file,
then getReader gives us access to a stream reader,
and using that reader we can read in the data that
comes up as part of the HTTP request.
We can use HttpServletResponse to send data back to the browser.
Like the request,
the response object gives us access to various parts of the response.
So for example, we could do things like redirect the browser.
This will send back a 303 HTTP code,
and that will cause the browser to send another request to
the particular page that we specify here.
This is used for in a couple of circumstances.
So here, for example, we're looking at the logged-on status of the user.
So if the user's not logged on,
we can redirect the log on page and this lets us do authentication.
But this is also useful when we do the standard POST, GET processing for a form.
So when the user posts data from a form,
if that processing succeeds,
we want to redirect the user to the success page to
show the data that's just been posted.
We can then change the response in various ways.
So we can set the content type on the response,
we can set any headers on the response that we need to,
and again, very importantly, we can output data as part of the response.
So here for example, we grab the Writer object that we can send data down,
we call out.write,
and to this we can write out any HTML or in this case XML that we need to,
and that data will get written back to the browser.
We can also if we need to send back any error information to the browser.
So response.sendError sets a 500 error code that the browser
will see and display hopefully the appropriate error message
when that response gets sent back.
This is the server as we left it earlier,
and we can see that we're using response.getwriter to write
some information back to the browser.
What we're now going to do is to use the request and response
object to change the behavior of the servlet.
The first thing we'll do is take the request object and use it to call
GetParameter to get the value of a parameter coming into the servlet and
then send that value back to the browser.
To do this, we can say String name =, request.getParameter name.
Be careful here as the parameter names are case sensitive.
And then rather than using request.getWriter .write,
we can use request.getWriter .printf Hello,
and we'll say %s, name, to send back to the name.
We should also check if the name is valid.
So we will say if name is not equal to null, then send back the name.
Otherwise, we'll just send back a message saying please enter a name value.
We can now deploy this.
If we go to the browser, we can enter localhost simple/home,
and we get the text saying please enter a name,
and then from here we can use?
name=Kevin, and we should see Hello Kevin.
So request.getParameter takes parameters off the query string
and will also take parameters from a form.
So here we have a simple page, it's a JSP page,
that just has a form, which is action home,
method is post, and that's going to post requests into our servlet.
For this to work, we need to add a doPost method to the servlet.
In this case I'll simply copy the doGet method.
We will make some changes to this in a moment,
so rather than simply calling doGet.
So at the moment, this method is exactly the same as the GET method.
So out of the doPost method, we need to redeploy the application.
Then if we go back to the browser, and then to simple/ index.jsp,
we see the form.
If we click on Enter Name, we'll see a message saying Hello, blank.
That's because the name parameter does exist,
but the value passed back into the servlet in this case is just an empty string.
Like from the query string,
when didn't enter the name value that came up as a blank string.
So back in the code, I guess we should say if name is not null.
So back in the servlet, we should say if name is not null,
and name is not equal to the empty string,
then display the name, otherwise display the message.
Again, we can redeploy, go back to the browser.
If we go back to the form page and click on Enter name, we now get the message.
If we go back to the form page, enter the name of Kevin,
then we see Hello Kevin.
So one of the other things we can use the response
object to do is to send a redirect.
So for example in this case, inside doPost,
rather than displaying a message saying Please enter a name,
we should perhaps redirect back to the form page to allow
the user to re-enter the form again.
To do that, we can say response.sendRedirect,
and we give it the string to redirect to,
which is going to be index.jsp.
Again, if we redeploy the application and then go to the browser,
go back to the form, if we leave the name blank and click on Enter name,
we now come back to the same page.
If I bring up the Chrome tools and click on Enter name,
we can see here that we've sent the POST,
and the POST has returned a 302 code, and the 302 code means redirect.
The browser simply redirects and reclaims the page again.
So one other thing we might like to do is to change
the content type of the response.
So for example, inside the doGet here,
we can set the content type to something other than HTML,
which is the default.
We do this by saying resp.setContentType.
In this case, we can set it to text/xml.
And then we can perhaps surround the output in XML tags, maybe add a name tag.
Again, if you redeploy this and then go back to the browser,
if we say simple/home? name=Kevin again, now we'll get back the XML rather than the HTML.