Now finally let's see what happens when an async request times out.
Time outs are used to ensure that our threads are giving up if the
work is not complete inside a reasonable time,
whatever that means for the application.
So back in the FirstAsyncServlet, set a time out of 3 seconds on the context.
Then in the start method, let's put the threads to sleep for 5 seconds.
We can redeploy, refresh the browser, and look in the log file.
Now we can see the onTimeout message logged.
This means that we get told when a request has exceeded its time limit,
and inside this handler we can do some processing,
in this case logging a message,
but we can also do some other error handling here that means something in this particular context.