So here we're going to create another demo,
but now we're going to add an example of a real-world filter,
one that does compression.
If you're running your app on Tomcat and a reverse
proxy such as Apache or NGINX, then you may not need this,
but in other circumstances you might.
This example has a number of moving parts.
The first is the filter.
There's a class called CompressionFilter,
and this has a WebFilter annotation that it only runs against * .do endpoints.
There's no real reason for this other than it shows
you can apply filters selectively.
This filter checks to see if the browser accepts gzip responses,
and if it does, it creates a wrapper, gzip response wrapper.
And it passes that wrapper down the chain.
When the chain is finished, we call finishResponse on the wrapper.
This does tidy up as we'll see in a moment.
This wrapper is a response wrapper,
and it is more complex than a request wrapper.
This response wrapper extends
HttpServletResponseWrapper and overrides three methods,
getOutputStream, getWriter, and flushBuffer.
GetWriter and getOutputStream do essentially the same thing.
They create a gzip response stream that will actually compress the content.
The flushBuffer method flushes the stream when asked and finishResponse closes
either the writer or the output stream when it is called.
It's the GZIPResponseStream that does the work.
It creates a GZIPOutputStream around the stream that's in the current response.
It overrides the write methods to write data to this stream,
sets the headers when the stream is closed,
making sure the correct content length is set,
and flushes the output to the client.
So first, we'll turn off the filter by commenting out the WebFilter attribute.
If we now deploy this code, when we look at this in the browser,
we can use the browser tools to look at the network trace.
And if we look at the request * .do, we see that it has no compression.
And the size is about 5K.
If we go back to the code and turn on the filter and redeploy,
if we refresh the browser, you'll now see the compression is on and the size of the download is about 1K.