Here are some ideas on how to personalize a speech.
And I'm going to include these and more
in your success journal as part of an exercise
in the next lecture,
in case you ever need to access these personal touches,
or even a simple exercise or example in your speech.
Try to involve your parents or
something personal that others can relate to.
And I'm gonna give you five personal examples, okay?
And when you do this, you have to ...
You have to tie it into your speech,
remember the so what test,
(music)
in order to make it relevant, okay?
And we're gonna discuss many ways to craft the
beautiful content of your speech in Act Three.
Okay. Here's the first example
of personalizing content in order to appeal to emotions.
My first memory was in 1977.
Okay, these are all real stories.
My mom, in 1977, took me to the first movie ever,
that I ever went to, which was Star Wars.
And I couldn't read so my mom read the scrolling,
yellow words to me.
I didn't understand any of it.
But I knew at that point in my life
that I wanted to be a film maker
or do something with filming, right?
Second example, okay?
My father grew up in Egypt.
And actually, no joke,
today, which is March 25, 2017
is the 50th anniversary that my dad came from ...
Moved from Egypt to Canada.
Right, 1967.
It's a pretty amazing story, pretty amazing story.
Actually, the story is that he,
totally went off script here but whatever.
They wanted to put him into this stupid war
in the middle ... you probably know what war it was.
And he thought it was ridiculous.
So he bribed an army official so he could fail his eye exam.
And then he left the country, thank God.
Anyway, whatever.
Okay, so my dad he talks about Egypt,
and I've never gone to Egypt, right?
But I actually,
I asked him, "What was it like growing up there?"
He said, "Chris, on every Saturday my fondest memories was
going on long walks with my father in the marketplace
where I lived in a town called Zayed,
which is south of Cairo, right?
My dad showed me on Google Earth,
recently the path that they took.
Which you can see here.
My dad and his dad would always stop right here
for a loaf of (Egyptian accent) fresh bread,
that's how my dad says it.
It's better when he says it than me.
I say fresh bread he goes, (Egyptian accent) fresh bread.
My dad taught me about how they would
put sliced olives into the bread
and the combination of olives and bread was prophetic
and had different meanings for me to interpret
as he would discuss the bread of life
and the essence of the olive branch.
This led me to believe that we can achieve
peace and harmony through ...
You get the idea.
But I'm just trying to make it relevant.
Remember the "so what test", right.
You can tie it in beautifully to a speech.
Just separately, off script again,
this is just me being me,
if you get a chance, if you've never been to
where your mom or dad grew up,
Sit down with them through Google Earth
and ask them to show you where they grew up and record it.
It's really nice.
The third example of a personal example
is that Warren Buffett once guest lectured
in one of classes at MBA school.
He said something that really
changed my perception on investing.
He said that the New York Stock Exchange
is the only store in the world
where consumers sell stuff and it goes on sale, right?
That's, let's think about that.
It's a nice little anecdote or way to talk about investing,
if you're presenting about investing, right?
My fourth personal example is:
my father told me once never to take a short cut
I've never taken before when I'm in a hurry.
So I apologize for showing up two minutes late today.
You could do something self-depricating like that
at a conference if you're late.
And you're not going to be late.
Okay, my fifth personal example is
I thought my life was over.
It was 1991, I was at McGill University in Montreal.
I took accounting for the first time
and I got a D.
I tell this story as well in my ...
I teach a course on you and me called
The entire MBA in one course.
Before I talk about the finance and accounting section,
I talk about this.
I got a D in accounting.
I got a D in accounting because I memorized accounting
instead of understanding it.
You see, if you understand something,
then you remember it.
If you memorize it, it doesn't sink in longer term.
I took the course again and I did better later, of course.
So, I've already mentioned
how you've got to be yourself at all times.
Senior people really don't like it when you're
nervous around them or treat them differently.
I don't know why we do this when
people that are more senior to us
in our organization walk by.
They don't like it.
They feel uncomfortable, actually.
They feel just as uncomfortable as you sometimes.
And our peers certainly don't like it.
And our subordinates hate it as well.
People actually lose respect for us
and I lose respect for myself when I used to do that.
It's kind of like this,
I'm just telling you be yourself.
It's like when you, I don't know if this happened to you
but it happened to me a couple times.
Where you interview for a job or you go on a date.
And you're just yourself.
You almost don't care anymore, right?
And things work.
You get the job or the date went really well.
I've been so fed up in my life when I've interviewed.
I remember getting rejected a lot and I prepared a lot
and I remember going into one interview and I said,
"I just don't care anymore," I said it to myself.
I was just myself.
I got the job.
Anyways, the point is be real.
Be yourself when you present.
And your ability to communicate with your audience
will go through the roof, okay?
So here's some other examples of what you can use
in a presentation to tap into emotions
and give personal examples so you can
identify with your audience.
And make sure to ask yourself the "so what" test so
it can be relevant and then tie it into your presentation.
Okay, so being personal is why people love watching
wedding speeches more than corporate speeches, right?
Okay, so here's some more examples for you
that you can use.
I'm just gonna give you the first sentences.
When I was younger growing up in ...
Another one is this: one of my heroes is "x"
and they said once that ...
One of my favorite movies that I've ever seen is
yada yada yada.
Right? Or I once went to U2 concert.
And the lead singer named Bono
he got up halfway through the concert,
it was very loud I remember
and he said,(British accent) "I'd like you all
to please not make any noise as I sing this next song
and give you this introductory speech here."
My accent's awful. I'm trying. Okay? I'm trying.
He said this (hands clap) "Every time I clap,
somebody dies in the world of a rare disease."
And he kept clapping.
And then somebody in the audience, it was really quiet,
"Then stop freaking clapping you hands then."
(laughing)
It was pretty funny, right?
It's actually a true story.
It didn't happen to me but I read about it online.
It's online so it has to be real, right?
Pretty funny.
And apparently Bono, he actually ended up laughing as well.
Pretty funny. Okay.
Wait. Ummm, okay.
And so another example is this.
I'll make this one up, right?
I don't want to be too Toronto or Canada-centric.
My father used to take me to Ebbet's field
to see the Brooklyn Dodgers play.
I brought a ticket stub with me. Right?
Again, this one is not real.
My dad took me for my birthday.
The ticket was six bucks then
which was a lot of money back then.
And I'll never forget,
as we were playing the New York Yankees
and Jackie Robinson was playing that day.
And I got to sit by my number one role model
and my best friend ever while watching my second role model
who positively impacted the game forever.
That day we listened to Vin Scully on the radio
giving the play by play.
(Vin Scully radio announcement)
And I'll never forget while sitting in the stands
my dad told me that...
You get it, it's just an example.
But really personalize it, right?
Just make it real, make it about you.
And you know what, dude?
Sorry, I say dude sometimes to my friend.
You don't have to practice it
if you just kind of tell a story about yourself.
You can't screw that up, right?
Okay.
And so this one's true actually,
this story I'm gonna tell ya.
Before I tell this one to you, I gotta go down my elevator.
(elevator dings)
(elevator beeps moving floor to floor)
Okay. I found it.
This one's true, okay.
This is personal.
I've shown this to you before, okay.
This is one of the first Macintosh's.
When I was younger, in the sixth grade, and the eighth grade
they thought I had a learning disability,
the teachers or whatever. Right.
My parents were so awesome
in trying to boost my confidence and everything.
And so what happened was my
I had to go to these special places
and they tested my knowledge of stuff whatever.
I got the worst grades.
I was the worst student when I was younger.
And the reason was that I wasn't passionate
about what I was doing. Right?
And then one day, I was so awful in school,
my dad bought this.
This changed my life. I keep it with me everywhere.
See I have the Bluejays here. Right?
Pretty neat. My favorite number is number four.
All that stuff.
Anyway, my dad bought this thing and it changed my life
because I was incredibly passionate about using this thing
to create presentations and stuff.
It was just fun. Right? It was my passion.
And without it, I probably wouldn't have been happy.
Anyway, that's just me.
Now the point is that we gotta be passionate
as a team here, you and I. Okay?
We gotta be passionate about what we're doing
as we go through this. Okay?
Whenever you give that personal story,
of course you gotta keep it relevant,
(trumpets sounding)
Tie it in. Okay?
People will remember it because of that.
And there's so many other ways to personalize
and bring real life stories
and relevant emotions into a speech.
(trumpets sounding)
The point is that we must be passionate as a team here.
In our company, right?
If were gonna go from number two
in market shares to number one.
See I just kinda tied in the whole McIntosh,
computer thing, into a corporate speech.
You get the idea.
And there's so many other awesome ways to personalize
and bring real life stories
and relevant emotions into a speech.
And here's some more examples. Right?
You won't feel true happiness in life until
you hold your child for the first time.
Okay, that's true actually.
It happened to me when Andrew was born
and I was like I didn't realize I had this type
of happy emotions like this.
You'll see. It's exuberant.
Or another example is, and you can personalize your own way.
I'm not gonna go off-script.
But my near death experience was or this.
One day that changed my life forever was...
Yada yada yada.
See you're interested when you start a sentence like that.
One day that changed my...
Everyone kinda stops.
If in the audience you have lot of people
using these things, which are awful.
When they hear something like that, you know,
one day that changed my life was...
They'll kinda put this down and listen up.
And I kinda like you to do it
at the beginning of your presentation.
Cause that way, once you get them
(fingers snapped)
they're hooked. Okay. In a good way.
Or you could say I overcame my fear of public speaking
with, whatever it might be.
But I really want you to open up.
Because humility and or transparency builds trust
and helps you bond with your audience
because they share the same emotions that you have.
And the more human that you come across as,
the more your audience will be able to identify with you.
And the more affective your presentation will be.
I think you get the idea.
Just make sure you audience feels emotions
when they watch or listen to your presentation.
Just like how great movies or music or your heroes
or speakers that you admire make you feel emotions.
Like hearing a great song makes ya kinda shiver.
Okay so make sure of course that if you are pressed for time
these personal stories have to be very very short.
Now we're done with this lecture
but please watch this incredibly emotional
and yes, a bit extreme reaction from an amazingly,
passionate person who won an academy award.
I don't remember exactly what he said
but I remember how he made me feel.
It was in 1999. I was in New York City,
on the upper west side, in a bar on 73rd street,
around that area.
So anyway, this is a guy that won best actor award
for "Life is Beautiful".
I want you yo watch it.
Please watch it and then come back to me.
Now I'm not saying that you should act exactly like this.
But I want you to feel what the audience felt that day.
Like what Sophia Loren on the stage felt.
And what everybody in the audience felt that day.
And the billion people or so
that were watching that live around the world.
And that guy, Roberto, he didn't care what people thought.
He was being himself.
And God bless him.
What a great speech.
Notice in that video he talks about people that he loves
and his parents.
You don't get more joy and more emotion
than you can get it this speech.
Because it is right from the heart.
It is so real.
It's a masterpiece of emotions and the audience loves it.
And the audience will love you.
So please watch it again if you want to.
And just bookmark it.
Watch the video over again
if you're ever unhappy at any point in your life.