"The two most important days in a person's life
are the day you're born
and the day you find out why."
Mark Twain.
Please find attached to this lecture a 20 page document
of many of my favorite quotes.
Now you can pick one or more quotes
from the attached document and include them
in your presentation.
Now I did this because I want to help ya work smarter
and not harder when you're creating your speeches.
Okay, and so in this 20 page document
you'll notice that I created
26 different categories of speeches.
Everything from quotes about goals
or quotes about worrying,
or quotes about love or confidence or dreams,
distractions, gratitude.
Avoiding conflict.
Relaxation.
Energy.
Quotes about teaching, mentoring.
The power of why.
Believing in yourself,
vision,
and seeing the good in everything, et cetera.
For example,
if you're presenting to a sales team,
you can consider starting your speech
with one of these quotes.
"Nothing is impossible.
The word itself says I'm possible."
Clever.
That was from Audrey Hepburn.
Or here's another one:
"The successful warrior is the average person
with laser-like focus."
Bruce Lee said that.
Okay, and actually, I think it was Bill Gates
and Warren Buffet said that
the most successful people have one major thing in common,
which is the ability to focus, okay?
Here's another one:
"You miss 100% of the shots you don't take."
Okay, that's Wayne Gretsky, fellow Canadian.
Represent.
Okay, other quotes you can start your speech with
include the following:
"I've had a lot of worries in my life,
most of which never happened."
Mark Twain.
Okay.
Or "change before you have to."
Jack Welch.
Okay, another one is this:
"A goal is a dream with a deadline."
Napoleon Hill.
Or "If you're offered a seat on a rocket ship,
don't ask what seat. Just get on."
Sheryl Sandberg.
Okay, she's great.
Another one here is,
"you just can't beat the person who never gives up."
Babe Ruth.
"No one can make you feel inferior without your consent."
Right?
That's Eleanor Roosevelt.
I love that.
And I love the notion of
unjustified criticism is
nothing more than a disguised compliment.
So bring it on, doubters.
Okay, here's another one:
"What we dwell on, we become."
Oprah Winfrey.
Okay?
So you can even start wedding speeches
or personal speeches
or toasts if you're asked to make one
on the spot without any preparation
with some of these
and the 150 quotes included in the attachments.
"Whatever our souls are made of,
hers and mine are the same."
Emily Bronte, okay?
"There is only one happiness in life:
to love and be loved."
George Sand.
Or another one's this:
"When love reigns,
the impossible may be attained."
Indian proverb.
"Love is a moment that lasts forever."
Anonymous.
Okay, and I used a quote to start and end my TEDx talk.
I also used many quotes in between.
And you can check out my TEDx talk
later on during the course.
We're gonna critique it, okay?
And let's talk about some other quotes.
I've actually opened a couple of my speeches
by quoting the Dali Lama by saying this:
"What surprises me most about Western society is
people sacrifice their health,
their entire lives, in order to make money.
And at the end of their careers,
they sacrifice all their money in order to
maintain their health.
And then they look back upon their life
and they realized they never really lived to begin with.
Okay, now notice how I didn't quote that perfectly.
It was a little bit off.
But as long as people get the gist of the idea,
that's good enough, okay?
Now if you're giving a business speech,
you can't go wrong by quoting someone like Warren Buffett
who once said that the New York Stock Exchange
is the only store in the world
where consumers sell stuff when it goes on sale.
I already said that before,
but it's important to reinforce, okay?
I think you get the idea.
Again, check out the 150 or so quotes
in the attached quote resource.
Thanks.