I was the commencement speaker at a University recently.
And I took this cool picture from a
different perspective that says so much
and can be interpreted in so many different ways.
I really think that images are so
underused in presentations.
I wanna share with you 30 images
that you can use and show
when starting a presentation.
I'm also going to provide the internet links for
all of the images that I'm gonna show you.
I'll include all of them.
And then, in Act 4, Scene 2,
I'm gonna show you how to manipulate images the easy way.
Even if you have no experience with software
for manipulating images.
So, please choose to use any of these images
for your presentations,
or maybe they will provide inspiration for you
for other image ideas that you might have
to start your presentation with.
As many people believe that a picture is worth a 1000 words.
And this will help you stand out as well.
Now, I'm one of those guys that thinks that photoshop,
or any Adobe product, is just too hard to use,
for me personally.
Okay, just for me.
I'm gonna show you much easier and cheaper ways
to manipulate images in Act 4, Scene 2.
I'm also gonna you later how to morph images,
using only PowerPoints,
and Keynote as well.
Okay, and the goal here is to
just help you work smarter and not harder
when you're making your presentations.
Of course, I'm also gonna show you how to use
Google Slides and many other programs as well.
Again, that's in Scene number 4,
which is a lot of fun.
I digress.
Here are some images to consider using
for your presentations.
And you can just show them with a quote on top of them,
if you want and if it's relevant.
Remember this will sub well with text.
This is a gorgeous and inspiring picture.
It's from the Benagil Sea Cave in Portugal.
And beside these images, or better yet, on them,
you can insert one or a few words.
For example, in this image you can place
passion and preparation.
On this one you can write discovery and perception.
Here, you can insert forward thinking,
or a different perspective.
On this one you can also use a different perspective.
This one is for preparation.
What do you see here?
Waste, opportunity, wasted opportunity, or a dragon?
Real or not real?
Avatar, from the movie?
Or real?
It's actually real, it's in China.
I think it's called the Tianzi Mountains.
Why?
Or why not?
Unexpected!
Accident, karma, or chamelion?
If you have an audience from the 80s.
The macro is the same as the micro.
Or, is perception a reality?
Location, location, location and
a tale of 2 cities.
Breaking barriers.
Lost and found.
Fearless.
Here's another one, fearless.
I love Muhammad Ali, that guy was awesome.
If you have a chance, watch some of his speeches
or when he was being interviewed on television
back in the 60s and 70s.
He was...
There was no filter, he said what was on his mind
and he was so confident and
just everybody loved him for being him,
for being unique and not caring what people thought.
He was a real icon, he was amazing.
Here's another one.
Wrong conclusions.
Victory.
Hustle.
That's Pete Rose.
People called him Charlie hustle.
Time to move on.
The sky is not the limit.
New way to win.
Note the contrast here,
as we say new way but the picture is in black and white.
In this one we start by asking a question.
Does anybody recognize this photo?
And, this photo has been seen by more than 1 billion
people since 2001.
Anybody know what it is?
That's right,
this is a famous Microsoft Windows desktop image.
And it was actually taken here in Napa Valley.
And remember to make it somewhat relevant.
This one here is,
anything is possible.
Another one for,
Dream.
Gosh, driving to work today was a nightmare.
You can use humor as well if you want.
So, it's fun creating a presentation
pretending it's like a work of art.
Just take your time finding the perfect image to start
or end your presentations with.
This image here is so beautiful I had to include it twice.
And one day in my life I will go there.
Now, here's a really easy way for you to get images
and add text.
This website is called imagechef.com.
And here's a bunch of images I made using imagechef.com.
Pretty cool, huh?
It's free to use,
unless you want ridiculously high resolution images.
Then there's actually a fee for it.
And, if you want to make what are called, "memes,"
here's a great resource for you.
The website is called, imgflip.com,
it's written right here.
And here's an example of a meme for a presentation.
Here I'm making a meme for my current presentation,
okay, okay, done, alright,
fine.
First impression images are crucial.
And they have a really big impact on your audience's
ability to pay attention and feel inspired.
Images are...
Are more important than putting words up on the screen,
because we tend to judge books by their covers, right?
And it's so much fun creating a presentation
if it's creative and artistic.
It's like a work of art, right?
And I take a lot of time to find images to
include in my presentations that I give
in front of groups of people.
And you should do this too,
and just have a good time doing it.