(calming music)
I like to start a lot of the seminars that I teach and
the classes that I teach, and general keynote speeches with
very short motivational videos.
From movies or business events.
Right.
I even put on little funny clips every now and then as well.
It's a lot of fun that way.
Okay.
I kinda wanna give an experience, right.
Something that will be remembered.
It's fun for me to do it that way as well.
If it's not fun,
what's the point?
Okay.
I also show videos and images at least
every 10 to 15 minutes.
You know, nobody can pay attention for that long anymore.
Right.
That's why tedextalks are not much longer than 15 minutes.
So, on January 1, I sent this video to all of my
Udemy students saying how they really inspire me.
This video is actually created by one of my Udemy students
named Randy Tovar.
Right.
This video is so powerful.
Please check it out.
Showing a video can be incredible unique and fun as well.
Bill Gate's brilliance wasn't just, you know,
product execution or good market strategy.
It was actually marketing and presentation genius.
Right.
Which his head of sales and marketing, at the time,
Steve Balmer, helped out a lot with.
Bill Gates used to give keynotes at massive annual
Comdex Tech conventions in Las Vegas.
I went to bunch of them.
I loved his presentations, right.
He always showed these really cool videos.
Right.
Bill Gates was to Steve Balmer when
Steve Wasneck was to Steve Jobs.
The result is an entertaining presentation with
superb introduction.
Here's and example from Bill Gates very last keynote at
Microsoft.
We're going to go into a lot more detail on this in
the wedding speeches examples in Act 11.
I started my wedding speech in 2000
when Christine and I got married,
by showing a cheap video that I made.
It was actually a lot of fun.
Right.
I just try and be very different as always when I present.
I have to be honest with you.
You know, things really didn't work out this morning for
the groomsmen and I.
In fact, things were pretty chaotic.
Things got so crazy that I decided to video tape
the entire event.
I kinda want to share it with you today.
So without further a do I present the video.
How did you guys sleep last night?
I couldn't get to sleep for awhile.
How about you?
I slept very well.
Really?
Yeah.
I went to bed around 9:30 - 10.
Oh my God.
How do you think the guys are doing?
Oh I'm sure they're doing okay.
Chris is pretty much.
He is pretty well organized and
probably waiting at the church as we speak right now.
Really?
Yeah.
(calming music)
Ah!
I'm late.
(upbeat music)
Chris, I want to have a word with you.
Dad, I'm running late for the wedding.
Come in.
I hear that you getting married today.
Yeah, to Christine.
She's fantastic.
Christine is a lovely girl.
We all met her and we all love her.
Sit down son.
(coughing)
I have a word of advice for you.
Keep your friends close but keep your wife closer.
(upbeat music)
Breakfast of champions.
Oh my God.
I am running late.
Oh, the ring.
Ring.
Ah, she's gonna love this.
Oh!
Fluffy!
Noooooooooo!
Jimmy.
Chris, come on.
Lets go.
We're late.
You don't understand.
The cat ate the ring.
What?
What do I do?
The cat ate the ring.
What are you talking about?
No, no, no, no.
It can't be.
Chris you come here.
You drive.
I got it.
Okay, you get to the wedding.
Alright.
I'll get the ring and the cat.
Come on, lets go!
(upbeat music)
Actually, I've been having some abdominal pain.
It's that the physicians have actually requested
radio graphing you abdomen.
Have any emotional problems?
Problems at home?
Depressions?
Symptoms of like poor eating?
Something wrong?
The radio graph is actually demonstrate.
Buttons.
Odd coins.
Other consumed items like jewelry.
We need to discuss this.
Talk to me.
Talk to me!
I mean, we clearly have issues to discuss.
I'm late!
Come here.
Cough it up!
Fluffy, cough it up.
Fluffy, come one
Cough it up.
(upbeat music)
Fluffy, please try some pepto-bismol.
Please.
I have to be on time.
Please, Fluffy.
Please.
(upbeat music)
The ring.
Oh my God.
I've got to get to the wedding.
♫ Going to the chapel and we're gonna get married
♫ Going to the Chapel and we're gonna get married
Hey Soal.
How's it going buddy?
Listen, I'm coming to pick you up.
Are you ready?
Yeah in 10 minutes but come right now.
Aright, well I will be right over.
Hey buddy let's go.
We've gotta pick up the other groomsmen.
They've got all the alcohol for the reception.
How are ya?
I'm alright.
I hate my job.
Oh, really?
Don't worry about it man.
Let's go.
Yeah, let's go to the wedding.
(honking)
Guys come on we gotta go.
(upbeat music)
Guys, wait up.
I'll be right there.
Guys.
No!
(upbeat music)
Gonna get married.
Going to the chapel.
(upbeat music)
Feel something?
Yeah I did.
Guys, come on move the car.
(upbeat music)
Whoa.
(honking)
You're going off the road.
(screaming)
(water splash)
Guys, I'll come after you.
(inspirational music)
(wedding music)
(cat meow)