If you're starting a presentation by introducing a speaker
then ask the speaker or their assistant,
well in advance, to send you their bio.
If it's available, 'k?
And if it's relevant for the introduction.
Okay, then if you can add something
personal to the introduction.
You know, it could be the first time that you met
this person or a personal and flattering
story about this person you're going to introduce.
And so, here's the example of an introduction
that I did as a Venture Capitalist
at a Venture Capital conference that I organized
and I introduced all of the speakers, right.
And I'm gonna give you plenty more examples on
how to introduce speakers
in act 11, scene four and scene 11,
okay?
So just go to act 11 you'll see, okay?
But I wanna discuss just
one of the introductions that I did for a speaker
that I think is the smartest and most successful
person here in Silicon Valley history.
And I probably spent an entire day
just preparing this intro.
And I memorized it, too.
Before I give this example though
there's a five step outline that I created for you.
To make it easier to start a speech
when you're introducing somebody.
Step one, say who the speaker is.
Step two, say at least one complimentary thing
about the speaker from their bio
or from the summary section from the top
of their Linkedin profile if available.
Step three, list in chronological order
their background and accomplishments.
And sometimes it can go on forever because these people
you introduce are just so ridiculously successful.
Step four, say what the speaker is currently doing.
And then step five, end with how grateful you are
that they are speaking.
So, here's the script I used
at a Venture Capital conference
a while back when I was MC.
I was actually kind of nervous but I completely
over prepared and it worked out okay.
Here's actually how it went.
Our keynote speaker is Andy Bechtolsheim.
Andy was the very first investor in Google.
Legend has it he wrote a check to Google Inc.
before Google's co-founders had
legally registered the company name.
He had to actually explain to Larry and Sergey
how to cash that check.
True story.
Not only is Andy Bechtolsheim one of the best
Angel investors in the history of Venture Capital
but he was a full bright scholar.
He was also the very first employee at Sun Microsystems
and in 1995 he left Sun to start Granite Systems
which he sold to Cisco in 1996.
Andy held a senior position at Cisco until 2003
when he left to start a company that he sold to Sun.
He is currently involved in several incredibly
forward-thinking and disruptive companies
for which he is the chairman and founder.
One of which is Arista Networks and the other one is DSSD.
It is my pleasure, my honor and my privilege
to introduce our keynote speaker,
Doctor Andy Bechtolsheim.
Okay, I made a mistake there though when I gave it.
I said Doctor and he's not.
And he's so humble, he got up and he said
he said, "Chris, I actually never finished my PhD's
"so thank you, but I'm not a Doctor."
And PHD I think stands for pluming, heating and dishwashing.
I don't know.
So again I'm gonna you plenty of examples
and templates
in act 11 when we discuss 25 different
presentation and speech examples.
Thank you.