Please open your success journal
and turn to exercise number four called
starting your presentation.
We discussed in a lot of detail many different ways
to start your presentation.
This exercise here is going to help you create
an impactful and perfect start to your presentation.
So please choose one or more ways to start
your presentation based on the questions
you can answer in this exercise, exercise number four.
For example, you might decide to start by thanking
the audience and telling a personal story.
You know, another example is you might start
by saying a quote and showing a picture.
It's so incredibly important to please start
your speech the right way.
That's why I spent so much time on this.
In this exercise I included more than 40 pages
of different ways that I have researched
that you can start your speech with.
Please take your time with this exercise.
Lastly, whenever see a yellow shaded box like this one
at the end of any of our journal exercises
please complete the yellow box
as we're going to copy and paste
from these yellow boxes later in the course
when we create our final presentation, thank you.