When you give your presentation, you need to prove
that your bottom line message is convincing.
You might want to consider ways of being
qualitatively as well as quantitatively convincing
as there might well be data-focused people in the audience.
I was recently on a panel,
and a guy that was on that panel with me
was named Carl Page.
He's actually the older brother
of Google Co-Founder Larry Page.
In fact, Carl mentored Larry Page
when Larry first started Google.
So what, Chris? Why do you mention this?
Well, this was an opportunity for me to ask
Carl for advice on why he and his brother are so successful.
He actually told me that his dad,
who was a great professor in Michigan,
told them that without data to back up a thesis
then it's just an opinion and nothing more.
If you don't have data to back up a thesis,
it's an opinion and nothing more.
I thought that was interesting.
So, please consider finding data to back up your speech
if it's a corporate speech.
I've been trying to be a guest columnist or guest writer
in The New York Times for years.
I keep submitting my articles to The New York Times
but they won't publish it.
A friend of mine told me,
"Chris, it's because you need to have more data"
or proof of my arguments or statements.
I guess this is why I haven't really
been in The New York Times yet.
You gotta have a lot more footnotes
kinda like you do when you write papers.
On a personal level,
my dad reads The New York Times every single day
and my dream is for him to open up
The New York Times one day and say,
"Jackie, look here, Chris wrote an article
"in The New York Times (speaks in foreign language)!"
I guess we never stop looking for approval.
So, data is important.
Any time you can insert a picture instead of boring words
then your audience will be more engaged.
It's like if you're on an airplane
and in the seat pocket in front of you
there's People Magazine or The Economist.
What would you read?
Most people would start off with People Magazine
because it's light, it's more entertaining,
it takes less amount of time to digest.
It's just images and it's fun to look at.
What's really popular today
is something called infographics
which is a visual way to look at data or trends.
Here's a few very simple examples
from the cover of USA Today.
Here's some other examples here of infographics.
News websites are really on a downfall
unless they become much more Pinterest-like.
Visual-based websites are on the upswing
and infographics seem to be replacing traditional
news stories because they're just more fun to read.
Pictures work best, or else we would
take notes on what our kids would say
instead of taking pictures of them.
Do both if you can.
There's a reason why Instagram and Snapchat are successful.
So, we need to adapt our presentation styles too
in order to be more visual
and appeal to all demographics in the long run.
To learn how to create an infographic yourself,
please see the lecture in this course called
Act 4, Slides Scene 3:
Creating Animations to Explain Complex Topics.
We'll get there soon.
Now let's talk about how to get data
or informational sources for our speeches.
If you want to be really, really convincing
then mine your own data through online surveys
that you can create using Surveymonkey.com.
I actually paid for this sample survey.
Here are the results.
Your company can pay for this market research as well
if you're giving a corporate presentation.
My wife Christina is going to kill me
when she sees the MasterCard bill.
Just kidding.
I wanna help you.
I wanna be resourceful.
So here's the infographic results
of that Surveymonkey report.
Here's a cheaper way to do it.
You can go to Fiverr.com
Five with two Rs
F-I-V-E-R-R .com
You can also get a poll there as well.
(gentle guitar music)
Let's say you're doing a presentation
on a certain topic and you want data
but you have no idea what kind of data and where to start.
Well here's another cool product for you.
It's this really neat website called Wolfram.
(uptempo jazz music)
Now if your company has a very, very big budget
you can use this product
that McKinsey, Boston Consulting Group,
and other top consulting firms use.
Consultants are paid to analyze data and help companies.
Quite often, they use data
as their main source of ways to prove to their clients
that they have to change their business model.
You might be able to get a free demo of this product.
It's a company called Quid.
It's Q-U-I-D .com
Coincidentally, their office is one floor below
Udemy's office in San Francisco.
(uptempo jazz music)
Alternatively, if you are giving a presentation
on a company that is publicly traded
you can go to whatever government website
these companies have to list financial data at by law.
For example, let's say you're giving a presentation
on the future of the auto market and which companies
might be influential in this market one day.
Well what we could do is we could go to Sec.gov
that's the Securities and Exchange Commission.gov
that's a government website of course
and find the annual reports for companies like Google
and then we can quote these annual reports just like this.
Now let's say you're giving a presentation
and you want to put data in your presentation
on the topic of Human Resources.
You have no idea what to present and you just need ideas.
Go to Google and see what the auto response is
for "what is human resources"
"why does human resources etc."
Just check this out.
When you start typing something, a drop box appears
and you can kind of find out
what the most popular searches are
and it might spark an idea for you.
Here's another one for you.
Go to Quora.com, that's Q-U-O-R-A.com
and search on your presentation topic
for data or reference ideas.
(upbeat space rock music)
For example, if we're presenting on Nintendo.
You get the idea.
There are many ways to get data
or facts for your presentation.
The examples we just went through
can really help you come up with cool ideas
for your presentation as well.
The best way to make it engaging data
is by using interesting charts that are convincing.
Okay, this one's really not that convincing (chuckles).
Citing facts from reputable sources makes sense as well.
"According to the Ministry of Transportation,
"blah blah blah."
This works better than a generic comment like this,
"According to people familiar with the matter,
four out of five Canadians comprises 80%
of the population in Canada."
So just try to have reputable sources like big publications.
Also, try to use at least one
staggering statistic in your presentation.
Steve Jobs actually did this a lot
and of course it worked out incredibly well
for him when he presented.
Use facts to convince people and build up your argument
if it seems far-fetched.
For example, during my TEDx Talk,
which we'll analyze in more detail later,
I tried to convince people that everyone in the world
has as much access, or should have as much access,
to unfiltered internet data sources as food and water.
That, I said, is a basic fundamental human right
we should all have.
I know it sounds really far-fetched.
But I approached it this way
so people didn't just throw it aside as being ridiculous.
Maybe they did, who knows.
But I started like this:
I started by discussing the Berlin Air Lift in 1948
and how the Allied Nations flew literally 200,000 flights
over Berlin in that year, 1948
to drop off basic necessities like food and water
to those that were imprisoned behind this Berlin Wall.
Then later, I spoke about offering
unfiltered access to the internet
as being a fundamental human right, a basic necessity.
Similarly, lawyers use the same convincing tactic.
If you watch TV shows about law or movies about law,
watch how lawyers use qualitative logic to be convincing.
In fact, please check out this epic courtroom scene
of Tom Cruise and Jack Nicholson in A Few Good Men.
It's not too realistic, but you get the idea.
It's entertaining and the content and delivery is superb.
Check it out!
It can't be convincing if nobody understands it.
There's a brilliant man named Rubin Gruber.
He and I were on the Board up at McGill University
for a special startup group called The Dobson Cup.
We would analyze business models from students
and then vote who wins best business model of the year,
that sort of thing.
But I only mention this because
I had dinner with Rubin when I was up there.
He started Sonus and a bunch of other great companies.
He rarely fails; he's so incredibly successful.
So I actually asked him,
"Rubin, why are you so successful? What do you do?
"What's your secret?"
And he mentioned the usual stuff, like,
"I've always done what I've been incredibly
passionate about, I love what I'm doing..."
I drilled down, as I always do, and he said
that before he starts a tech company...
He lives in Boston.
Before he starts a tech company, he flies up to Montreal
and has dinner with his 90-year old mother,
who is not a techie at all.
He says that if she doesn't understand
the business model during dinner,
then he does not invest in the company or start the company.
I thought that was quite brilliant.
It's genius because if not every one understands
your product, you're not going to have many people
want to buy it.
If not many people understand your business model,
you're not going to get many investors.
Actually, when I worked at a large hedge fund
called Citadel, Management would always critique by saying,
"If you can't explain it, then you don't understand it."
You don't have to include all of this when you present.
I just want to save you some time.
So you know where to go if you need access
to stuff online to beef up the arguments
or data within your presentation.
During the presentation, you can right-click
during the Q&A Session and show additional slides
or data-oriented slides that you didn't include
or you have as extra resources.
Here's an example here.
You can right-click on, for example, PowerPoint,
and go to a bunch of slides later on
and it will make you look like a million bucks.
Don't worry if that sounds a little bit confusing right now
because I'm going to cover exactly how to do this,
exactly how to answer questions in the Q&A Section
in Act 7 of this course, called,
"Q&A and Reading the Audience"
Alright, we are done with "The C in CIDER, C-I-D-E-R"
which again stands for Convincing.
In the next lecture, we're going to talk about
the "I" in CIDER, which stands for Interesting.
Thank you.