Please make your speech interesting and entertaining.
If you're gonna do this, then please make sure
to make the content somewhat relevant.
Here's there ways to make
your presentation a bit more interesting.
#1, mention an interesting fact
by showing the cover of a newspaper
on a date that is important for your audience.
How?
Well, the first way to make your presentation
more interesting is go online
and you buy or you access a newspaper
from a certain date so it's important to your audience.
Remember, remember the so what test, okay,
meaning why is this relevant.
Here's a great idea.
If you're presenting to a company or an organization,
you can talk about the day the organization was founded,
that company was founded, okay?
And then buy or get the newspaper from that day
and show some cool items from that day in the newspaper.
Here's an example and here's the website you can go to,
and there's many others as well,
and of course, make it somewhat relevant as well.
If you're presenting at a wedding,
show the newspaper the day the person
that you are talking about was born,
or if it's a speech that, your parents wedding anniversary,
show the newspaper from that day.
For my Dad, on March 25th of 2017,
they marked the 50th anniversary that he immigrated
from Egypt to Canada, and we're thinking
of doing a special 50th anniversary thing for my Dad,
and so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna get
the newspaper from that day and kinda walk through that.
It's kind of a nice, cool touch.
And then you can say something interesting like
nothing has changed, or we have come a long way,
or if it's an international crowd, say something in
a foreign language in order to be inclusive of them.
(speaking in a foreign language)
The more things change, the more they stay the same.
You can also go to this website and enter the date
and you will find out exactly what happened
on this day in history.
If you're having issues coming up with an interesting way
to start your speech, then just spend an hour or two
going through that day in history
and I promise you you'll come up with something.
Again, make sure it's somewhat relevant to the topic
and we covered this topic already.
For more information, please go to Act Three, Scene One
in the lecture called Starting
by Mentioning an Interesting Historical Event.
Unfortunately, your audience cannot pay attention
for more than 15 minutes or so
and this is why TEDx talks are interesting
as most of them are are 15 minutes or less.
We talked about the first way.
Let's talk about the 2nd way now.
The 2nd way to make your presentation more interesting
is to personalize the content of your presentation.
Reality TV or watching YouTube stars is interesting
because it's so real and it doesn't feel scripted.
People might forget what you say in your speech,
but they'll never forget how you made them feel.
My kids actually, they don't want TV that much.
It's a different generational thing.
They watch these YouTube stars.
It's really interesting
and they follow the lives of these YouTube stars
like this guy named Rowan Atkins.
He's got way more than 10 million followers
and people love it because he's real
and he's documenting his life.
So what's not to love about you being you?
We've covered how to be personal
in a bunch of lectures already.
More information on being personal
can be accessed in Act Three, Scene One
in the lecture called Starting by Introducing Yourself.
The 3rd way to make your presentation more interesting
is through storytelling and being incredibly inspirational,
which we've covered in Act Three, Scene One in a lecture
called Starting with Inspiration and Motivation.
You can tie in these examples into your presentation
in so many different ways.
One way is to show an image or a video and then explain
how it's interesting to what you're presenting.
It has to tie in remember.
We know that stories work exceptionally well.
Here's some examples that you can use
to make your presentation more interesting
by using images, video, or stories.
The first example is when the odds are against a group
of people and they overcome a challenge
as David beats Goliath.
It's so interesting here in Silicon Valley
because when I invest in companies,
I'm not worried about competition from big companies
like Microsoft, Cisco, or Oracle.
I'm worried about a couple girls or guys in a garage
that are gonna disrupt an industry
'cause innovation comes from small groups of people.
David always beats Goliath.
Here's another example if you want to make your speech
more powerful and interesting,
you can talk about these stories.
If you have a formidable competitor,
you could say something like this is your time.
Their time is done.
It's over for them because our new strategy is,
you get the idea.
And just remember since the beginning of time,
people love stories since ancient times.
When I was a kid, I remember at camp with my parents
we'd just kinda sit around a fire
and my Dad would tell cool stories and my Mom, too.
I loved asking them what it was like growing up,
that sort of thing.
Stories are interesting and entertaining, too,
and if we don't entertain, then we know the Smartphones
will win, and it's so hard to get your audience back
once you've lost them.
So show a video or an image or tell
an interesting story every now and then.
It's so incredibly hard again,
to regain an audience once you've lost them.
That's probably why on Udemy,
lessons are usually well-under 20 minutes each.
Udemy kinda know that people might not be able to
pay attention for that long.
At least that's the way I am, personally.
And just remember, when you went a movie one day,
remember this, that was so good and so interesting
that you didn't look at your watch even once
during the movie, and that's what we're aiming for here
when we talk about the eye insider
making things more interesting.
We want to give an unforgettable performance and
an unforgettable experience, and not just a presentation.
Steve Jobs was so successful at this,
not only because his content was awesome,
but because his delivery and the whole experience
of his presentation was very interesting.
Whenever he released a new product,
it was free PR, all over the world, every media avenue
covered it because it was interesting
the way that he presented it.
We're gonna talk a lot about delivery
in Act Six of this course.
Here's another example of keeping it interesting.
Talk about dreams.
Everybody loves to dream and your audience
will pay more attention and think that the presentation
is more interesting because it's inspiring
and the one thing that all people have in common
is they want to feel inspired.
We all love how David can beat Goliath, et cetera
and if David can beet Goliath, we can crush our competition.
On January 1st, I sent this video I'm about to show you
to all my Udemy students thanking them
for inspiring me, and this video was actually from
one of my Udemy students named Randy.
He did a great job putting this together
and not just the video, but also the dialogue
right from the speaker as well as the music,
right from this movie, I think it was called Inception.
It is groundbreaking, and this video blew me away.
Please check it out and then come back to me.
Okay, welcome back.
I'm now gonna change the subjects.
You see how I moved a bit here?
In Act Six, we're gonna talk about body language
and why moving to a new position helps
when you talk about a new subject.
Let's discuss dealing with a crisis.
How do you motivate an audience to deal with a crisis?
One way is by showing an interesting speech
and nobody gives a better speech than Al Pacino.
He is inspiring.
He is personal.
In this video clip, Pacino is transparent
and most importantly, he is real.
And of course, this speech is a bit extreme,
but the reason I want you to watch these clips
is to give you ideas,
even if it's just a few words or a sentence
to include in your masterpiece of a speech.
Remember, a light bulb comes down in a few short moments
and when you talk in public, that is one of them.
Okay, let's revisit quotes.
Remember we're talking about the eye insider,
how to keep your speech interesting.
I love quotes, but mainly short quotes.
If you show them, make sure that you and the audience
like the person who said it, obviously
and again, keep them short because less is more,
just like a tweet.
In fact, in every word of a quote that you're gonna read,
or memorize or whatever, pretend that it costs you $100
and that will make sure that you have fewer words.
Less is more.
And for 150 awesome quotes to use,
I attached in this exercise a PDF of these quotes.
Quotes keep your presentation interesting.
Just for more details, I don't want to be redundant,
please see Act Three, Scene One in the lecture called
Starting with a Quote, 150 Examples Attached.
That's the name of that lecture.