Please try to make the content of your speech different.
Make the experience you're going to give your audience
incredibly unique and creative, okay?
Make your presentation new, fresh, exciting, and different,
because, you know, you're different from everybody else,
because you're you and everybody loves you,
because you act like you.
So, just be different, which means, be you.
Now, I came up with the idea of CIDER,
that's C.I.D.E.R., for content,
by using this website here.
Okay, so, check it out and you can come up with your own
types of ideas for creating a somewhat unique experience,
like I did with CIDER.
So, please try using this concept in your presentation,
if you want.
You know, create a number of topics,
and then, take the first letter of each of those topics
and use this website to make the content
of your presentation more fun to create and present, okay?
And we'll talk about slide structure
and creating slides in Act Four of this course, okay?
Now, you want to create content
that is groundbreaking, right?
And, thought provoking as well.
So, take your time with this.
You know, it took me close to a year
to write my TEDx talk,
and several months to make my wedding speech.
Alright, it took a long time.
And, we'll cover both of these topics in much more detail
in Act 11 of this course when we talk about
25 different types of presentations.
Okay.
Think of yourself
like you are an artist, right?
Remember, these artists don't feel like
they have a job, okay?
They have a passion, and a passion to create.
If you want to do the same thing
when you're writing your content,
then just kind of think like an artist
and be creative, okay?
Now, think of yourself like an artist.
Now, just remember, these artists don't feel like they're
working again, they have a passion, and a passion to create,
and I want you to do the exact same thing
when writing your content, okay?
And, if you want, again, please revisit our Journal Exercise
number two, which is called Emotions and Experiences to
Include in your Speech.
And,
you're being creative, so be like these artists,
as this is not work,
it's authentic creation of a masterpiece.
So, enjoy it,
and this goes for everything you create in business
and in life.
Be yourself, no matter what they say.
People feel uncomfortable when you're not you.
People feel more comfortable when you are you, right?
It's a win-win as you get to be yourself
and other people appreciate when you're just,
when you're you and you present,
and it's less work, right?
Otherwise, if you aren't you, if you're not you,
then it's a lose-lose situation
as you and the audience doesn't feel comfortable.
And, again, senior executives actually feel uncomfortable
and they like us less when we are not ourselves.
So, just be different, be you, it's easier.
Okay, and again, your peers and your subordinates,
people who work for you,
will appreciate it too.
Okay, so let's stop repressing,
you know, who you are
and now, have the freedom to express yourself with
passion when you present.
You be you, as it's easier,
and it has a much better result, okay?
People will remember you for being different.
And,
as a Canadian, I have to mention the late, great
Prime Minister, Pierre Trudeau, right?
He was authentic.
If you are like everyone else,
you won't stand out when you present,
and one presentation perfectly executed
can change your life.
And, Pierre Trudeau was our Prime Minister
for 15 years, right?
Most people don't know that.
He was our Prime Minister for 15 years,
which is almost twice as long as
Reagan was President at the same time.
And, Pierre Trudeau was himself,
and he even gave the media the finger one day, apparently.
I don't think you should do that, but he didn't care.
He was just him.
And, the last thing, (laughs)
the last thing I'll say is that Batman would never
give the finger.
(clears throat) Yeah, okay.
(chuckles) Be different and real.
Kind of like,
kind of like Han Solo, and not C-3PO, right?
I mean, this guy's name was a number, 3PO, for a reason.
The same with Data from Star Trek versus Kirk.
His name is synonymous with unemotion, Data.
You know, Han Solo is emotional
and the audience likes that more.
Be you.