Sometimes the best speeches you watch are the ones
where you are getting educated on a topic,
but it doesn't feel like it because the experience
and the content is entertaining.
And we call this edutainment.
It's actually learning by accident.
If it's a personal speech educating the audience
on the background of the people you are speaking about
is often used with humor.
For example, a wedding speech, which we'll cover
in a lot of detail in Act 11 of this course.
We're also going to cover edutainment concepts
in more detail when we talk about the delivery portion
of your speech in Act #6.
Using short animations in your presentation is a great way
to edutain the audience.
For example, using a program called PowToons,
Which I'll explain how to use in Act 4,
when we cover different software applications
to make your speeches,
you can make a really complex topic entertaining
and educational at the same time.
Super Bowl commercials are so successful
because we don't realize that we're being educated
about a product by watching these commercials.
This is the experience I really want you to provide
when we are presenting, okay?
And if you aren't sure what to include that is educational,
then please revisit journal exercise number three
which covers the purpose of your presentation.
Deliver that purpose and make it entertaining
and educational at the same time.
Lastly, here's the example of a time when I used PowToons
to create an education, or I should say edutaining excerpt
in one of my courses.
There are many different financial analyst roles,
from investment banking, to hedge funds,
to venture capital, to private equity,
to trading, to sales, etc.
There's many of them, and in this course,
per the images below, I'm going to go through
14 different financial analyst roles.
What we're going to do in this portion is,
I'm actually going to go over just the top seven of the 14.
We'll build on this logic very slowly, so you understand
what some of the basic daily tasks are
for these seven analysts you see in front of you.
And, I think you'll enjoy this session.
Again, we're going to build on this slowly.
So let me just kick it off with a quick animation
on what these roles are.
(upbeat music)