Please don't forget the So What Test
when you're presenting.
Is this slide or this topic relevant or not?
Is the music in this slide,
if you're gonna use it, right, relevant?
Is the quote relevant?
Is the image relevant?
So it's crucial that you please remember
the characteristics and background of your audience
in order to make sure that your speech
is relevant to them.
And if you aren't sure if it is,
then please review Journal Exercise Number One
called Who is the Audience
or Customers Plus Their Characteristics.
Also, please review Journal Exercise Number Three
on What is the Number One Goal or Purpose
of Your Presentation?
We do that just to make sure
that what we are saying is relevant,
and always thinking of the So What question.
So What?