Please open up your Success Journal and turn to exercise
number eight, which is called, Beating Writer's Block.
In order to beat writer's block and to get
into that ideal state of mind.
Please think of a moment in your life, when you were
incredibly creative, when you wrote an essay,
or a speech, or a piece of music.
And please answer the following questions for me.
Number one, I was in an ideal state of mind when
I created or wrote this.
K, and just write that.
The approximate date when that occurred was,
write down the date.
The exact location was, write it down.
Was there any background noise or music?
If, so what was it?
Write it down.
If you can remember, write down how you felt then.
And if you can remember, what were some additional
reasons that you were creative then.
K.
Another question is, what limiting beliefs do you have
right now that might hurt your ability
to be creative right now?
K, these might be new beliefs that you developed as you've
gotten a bit older, that you gotta ditch.
K.
Okay.
Also, what can you do right now
to obliterate these limiting beliefs?
K, and just...
I want you to take that walk to eliminate
writer's block as well.
That's part of this exercise, if you need to.
Okay, also, what are five additional things that you can do
right now, in order to get back into
that ideal creative state of mind?
For example, I can get rid of distractions, like turning
off my cell phone right now.
Right, and then I want you to list four more things.
Okay, and just please take your time with this.
As...
Your content creation is a product also of your current
ideal environment and state of mind.
Right and lastly for me, sometimes when I'm not feeling that
great, I'll snap out of it by meditating, or close my eyes
and just thinking about a moment when I was incredibly
exuberant and happy in my life.
Right.
And for me, my wife Christine, and my three boys are
the most important thing obviously in my life,
but one moment that I'll never forget was in, October
or September 2015, when my sons and I were watching
a Blue Jay's game, a baseball game on TV.
And one of our players hit this, incredible home run.
He flipped his bat, whatever.
And we were so excited, we were jumping up and down.
Yelling, "Woohoo", whatever.
And I lost my voice, right, because I was so happy, right.
I don't know think about a time in your life
when you lost your voice.
Maybe it was a sporting event,
and just how exuberant you felt, right.
Just to get yourself into that peak state of mind, right.
Just kinda think back and reflect, to get yourself into
your genius zone creative state of mind.