Please open your success journal
and turn to exercise number nine,
which is called, "Ending Your Presentation".
In journal exercise number four, we discuss
in a lot of detail many, many, many different ways
to start your presentation.
This current exercise, meaning exercise number nine
will help you to create an impactful and perfect way
to end your presentation
and you can end your presentations by answering one
or more answers in this exercise
and this will make a lot of sense to you
once you've completed the exercise.
Please just skip questions that are not applicable
to this speech that you are giving.
Thank you.
You can end your presentation with one of the options
that we cover in this exercise or a bunch of them, okay?
Please again skip all questions that are not applicable
to this speech that you're giving, okay?
And as you can see, in the question list for exercise
number nine, we're getting to do four simple things, okay?
Number one: Write down one sentence on who your audience is.
Just please see your answer from journal exercise number one
and copy and paste the answer here if you want.
Number two and this one's optional:
Write down a few emotions that you want your audience
to feel
and please see your answers to journal exercise
number two and write down a few emotions
that you used or that you covered in that exercise.
Whatever you want your audience to feel
just jot it down here, okay?
Number three: Write down one sentence on the purpose
of your speech.
And again please see the answer to your journal exercise
number three and copy and paste them here if you want to.
Number four: Per the exercise, write down people
or organizations you might want to consider thanking
at the end of your speech.
Business presentations often end with a call to action.
If you're selling a product or a service, which
most business people are, then ask for the sale
at the end of your presentation or tell the audience
to please come and see me now or contact me
at this address if you have questions
and if potential customers approach you
and they sound interested in the product,
don't oversell, please, okay?
Always stop selling once you get the sense
that they are interested in buying the product.
If you keep seeling past the close,
you might lose the sale as this potential customer
might be thinking, "Gosh, I was really interested
"in buying that product, but why does he keep saying
"great things about the product?
"I mean, he seems desperate for the sale.
"Am I missing something, right?
"Why am I so lucky to be given this opportunity?
"Something seems off here."
You get the idea.
It's kind of like (laughs) when you're leaning about
asking people out on a date and you overdo it
and you come across desperate...
I'm not gonna go there, okay?
I suck at dating advice.
Talk to Jimmy Nerang, right?
Go see his courses here in (mumbles) on that.
He's Mr. Confidence, actually a good guy.
I've met him, right?
Take his courses on that stuff.
Okay, sorry.
So what, Chris?
Moving on.
If applicable, write down your closing,
ask for the sale comment, right?
For example, if you're interested in purchasing
this product, please see me now.
That sort of thing and I cringe when I say that, you know,
but...
'cause I hate asking for...
I kind of hate asking for business I kind of want
to offer a great service or a great product
and then people just kind of buy it yourself, but...
Sometimes there's gotta be a sense of urgency.
Like we have a special price or a sale that's valid
for anyone at the conference today.
That sort of thing, right?
There sometimes has to be a sense of urgency.
That's why retailers have sales.
If they were always discounted, the products...
They wouldn't sell as well.
Anyway, there has to be a sense of urgency
if you're gonna ask for the business, right?
Okay.
The sense of urgency or call to action is pretty helpful.
Your call if you want to use this methodology
in the ending portion of your speech, okay?
It just, per the instructions in exercise number nine
and if applicable, just please write down
your closing ask for the sale script here.
Please keep in mind also, that all great entrepreneurs
and CEOs are sales people.
Okay, if they're not selling a product or a service,
they're selling themselves.
Kind of like at a job interview, okay?
And if you're not taking orders for a product or service
then just be sure to have business cards ready
or pamphlets or better yet, USB tokens,
right in your pocket in case an enormous potential
customer approaches you after the presentation, okay?
And here's a link actually where to buy these USB drives.
Buy the cheapest ones that will fit the size of your
presentation materials.
Your presentation materials won't really take up too
much space anyway, right?
And if you want to be really creative and different
and unique and stand out,
this is yet a bit expensive, but it's really worth it
then create your own business on a flash USB drive
that's the size of a thick business card
and there's so many fun examples
you can get online.
I think it's called customusb.com that'll kind of
help you get noticed.
You want to be different, you want to stand out.
And just give these things to massive potential customers
as they...
These things can be a bit pricey, right?
But definitely worth it, right?
Definitely worth it.
Remember, CIDER.
C-I-D-E-R.
As this is convincing, interesting, different,
educational, and relevant.
That little thing is, okay?
It's pretty fun too.
Heck, bring these to a job interview
if you want to take a calculated risk and really stand
out from the others.
You can make a one page resume and then have a USB card
in the corner like this that has exhibits on...
I don't know, stuff you've done or a video resume too.
It's kind of fun, but off topic, but I want to go here.
Hear me out please.
Here's some other examples of business cards and flyers
to give massive potential customers at the end
of your presentation or during an interview.
I had a lot of fun making this lecture here
there's tons of examples right?
You can even email your PDFs if they are small enough
and here's the amazing, free way to make your
huge PDF's small if they're too big.
The PDF version of the success journal that you can
download for this course was enormous, right?
So, I compressed it with this amazing, free PDF compressor.
I think it's a pdfcompress.com, okay?
Also, please write down in this exercise if applicable,
did you mention your contact details
when you ended your presentation.
Please don't forget to immediately connect using Linked In
with all contacts that you meet
the day of your presentation that you do this.
So write yes or no and put comments down if you want to.
I want you to memorize the first few words of the
ending portion of your speech, okay?
Why?
Because sometimes you have to end your speech early
for whatever reason that is completely out of your control.
Like someone tells you during your speech that we're
running out of time here, right?
In this case, just say your closing line
and if it's a business speech and with a call to action.
Meaning, asking for the sale or
listing your contact details or asking potential customers
to approach you right now.
You want to strike while the iron's hot
and while you have their attention, okay?
Here are a few words to use to start the ending
of your speech.
And you can always use these as a crutch
go to and for some reason must end right now, okay?
Again, it's out of your control sometimes, okay?
Here are five examples.
Number one: The bottom line is...
Second example is: In conclusion...
The third is: And so, the best solution to or
recommendation is...
Number four: Our next steps are...
Number five: We talked about topic one, two, three,
or whatever structure you use and the best approach
to take is this...
Before we complete exercise number nine for how
to end your speech, please review journal exercise
number four if you want to end your speech with
one of the following:
a quote,
and I include a 150 quote examples in exercise four.
Actually, I'll attach that same PDF with the 150 quotes
to this exercise as well, okay?
You'll see in the resources section, right?
And also if you want to end with a video,
a relevant or personal story, a historical event
that's relevant of course, so what?
An outline of your speech, for example,
we talked about X, Y, and Z and the bottom line is this.
In an image, I included 30 examples next to exercise
number four, you can see it there, including this one
on how to make memes, right?
And then lastly,
please write your
concluding sentence here as well, okay?
And you can combine several different ways to end
your speech as mentioned over the last couple of pages.
So, for example, per this image, the bottom line is...
Please let me know if you have any questions
or if you're interested in learning more about the product,
yada, yada, okay?
Anyway, you can see the examples here
and just write down my concluding sentence is or are, okay?
In that spot there.
And again, the reason why I do this is...
Again, it's gonna be out of your control sometimes.
Like say, say the speaker before you, if it's a conference,
spoke for way too long, right?
Or if you see people starting to get up and leave
for whatever reason.
You don't want to lose their mind share, right?
And so, you can basically have that crutch, right,
immediately to say...
That's why I want you to write down your concluding
sentence and just remember it.