In this lecture
I'll discuss what software products to use,
meaning PowerPoint or something else
and please note that I created this lecture
using Keynote software,
which is only available on Apple products.
In the next optional lecture I'll discuss
how I made this lecture but regardless
of what software you want to use
or what platform you're using,
meaning Apple or other platforms,
please watch this lecture as I want to expose you
to every type of major presentation software package
I think makes sense to take a look at.
Okay, so I'm gonna cover every single platform.
The first one is PowerPoint
and PowerPoint is available on all these platforms.
PowerPoint is free if you use it on mobile or tablet devices
but you have to pay for it if you use it on a desktop,
meaning Apple computers or Windows computers.
Okay, next up, I want to tell you
this is my number one pick, PowerPoint,
and I know that's controversial
but the reason I say it is there's so many
advanced features that you can use,
and more importantly for me, personally,
I kind of grew up in a Windows environment
and I'm used to using all of these applications
you see right there, so I love it, but I also love Keynote.
Next up, we have my second favorite pick,
which is Keynote and I love it,
I almost love it more than PowerPoint now
and Keynote is not available on all platforms,
it's available on iOS as well as
Apple desktop or laptop products
and it's free, sort of, I mean, you have to buy
all the Apple products first and then it's free.
Okay, so it's my second favorite pick,
again, almost my favorite,
it's really easy to use,
there's not as many advanced features
as with PowerPoint but that's debatable.
Let's talk about some of the more advanced features
within Keynote, okay, and I'll just give you
a quick little demo here of what Keynote can do,
some of the advanced features, okay?
So if you wanted to insert a chart,
it's got really cool dynamic charts,
I don't think you can do this
to the same extent with PowerPoint,
look at that, how beautiful is that, right?
Typical Apple product.
Alright, there's also interactive charts here,
where you can show data trends over time,
it's pretty cool, pretty cool,
but with Microsoft it ties into Excel
a little bit more with PowerPoint, okay?
So there's benefits to being in different ecosystems.
Let's move on now to Google Slides,
which is free on all platforms, which is awesome
and if it wasn't free on all platforms
then I'm sure we would pay for Microsoft products
on all platforms, thank you Google.
It's my number three pick,
it's really, really simple to use
and there's tons of templates available online.
Okay, next up let's talk about Haiku Deck,
this one's not as popular, but it's pretty cool
and it works on all platforms because it's internet based
meaning you use a browser with it
and it's really nice if you want
to throw in beautiful pictures
and I believe that you should have more images
than you think you need in all of your presentations,
a picture is worth a thousand words.
So I'll give you a couple of examples here,
look how beautiful that is, isn't that gorgeous?
Stunning, and you can download a lot of these as well,
isn't that nice there?
Love it, love it.
Okay, happy love teaching week, how awesome is that?
Alright, next up we've got PowToon,
and this one is off the charts, I absolutely love it
and it's browser based as well,
which means you can use it on any platform you want
and if you're a student or a teacher,
you can use it for a much lower pricing point
and it's free, except if you want to get rid of the logo
when you publish the animations,
so let me just kinda show you examples
of how I've used this software in the past.
So I've used this to create animations
to explain complex stuff within some of my courses,
so in this case I was kinda talking about
what are the different financial analyst roles
and how do they all work together
and with those purple circle locks, if you pay
for the product, you can get more advanced features.
Separately, you can move your characters around,
you can replace them, swap them with different types
and you can also insert your own images,
objects here, music, et cetera, and it's a lot of fun to use
and my kids use it in school actually,
it's probably the best animation tool I know out there
for simplistic presentations, okay?
And then there's Prezi, and Prezi is free
but you have to pay for it if you want to get support
and more storage in the cloud
and because it's web based, this one is also available
on all major platforms, okay?
And I've used this one a lot within my courses,
and I'm gonna give you a couple of examples.
So the first example is here,
when I wanted to discuss what is the research process
for analyzing a stock in one of my courses
and basically the cool thing about Prezi,
is you can zoom in and zoom out, it's really, really neat,
it kind of reminds me of Google Earth,
where you can zoom into different parts of the world.
So there's an eight step process
to investing in companies that I put together, whatever,
so here are the eight steps, I'm not gonna run through it
cos this is not a finance course
but I run through all eight steps here,
of course I would go much slower in my courses
and then you can see that I've got that character there
from my PowToons presentation that we just looked at,
and so I love to use multiple presentation applications
when I make my courses, right?
And you can do that as well
when you make your presentations.
Okay, so let's look at another example here,
so in this case I'm explaining how a mutual fund works,
so in this case you've got a mutual fund or a hedge fund
that's located in New York and it shows you the hierarchy,
who does what, again, this is not a finance course
but I'll go through it quickly.
So the portfolio manager works on the West Coast
and she has a number of analysts reporting to her
and you can drill down to see what these analysts cover,
those stocks, okay? It's kinda neat.
Next up, I had a course where I want to talk
about investment banking and I try and make it fun,
what is an IPO, or initial public offering, right?
I love to dream big or I don't like to dream at all.
And then you can zoom out as well,
in this case we're talking about the New York Stock Exchange
and you don't just have the world in your hand,
you have the whole galaxy.
And then we talk about a mutual fund here
if you're working for a company
that analyzes Japanese stocks,
in this case, in this example,
the headquarters are in London
and let's say that you are the Japanese portfolio manager,
and you can see who reports to you,
in this case let's talk about the technology analyst
that covers Japanese technology stocks
and those are the stocks, okay, let's move on.
Another example I had was a day
in the life of a hedge fund analyst,
and I used to work in the hedge fund industry
so I kinda zoom in and tell you,
okay, we work in New York here,
I try to make it as authentic as possible,
you can zoom in, let me just skip a bunch of these here,
and then I like to actually tie it back into PowToons,
so we'll go back to PowToons for a second here,
and so here you have me, or an analyst, whatever,
that works for a hedge fund,
and this analyst is at his or her house in the morning
watching CNBC or whatever
and they notice that one of their stocks
went up a lot before the market opens,
then they travel to work,
and then they get into work and this is the morning meeting,
and this simulates how a morning meeting is conducted,
for example, in the hedge fund space
and that woman on the left is the portfolio manager,
and that person on the right
is the analyst that works for her
and he talks about his stocks during the morning meeting,
in this case he lost money with a GoPro stock position,
again, I'm not gonna go into too much detail on this
because this is not a finance course
and so what happens is, you can see
that he's got a great idea,
and I threw a light bulb there just to visualize it,
and we talk about how that analyst goes through an idea,
he's interested in stock called LinkedIn,
which is no longer public, and here's why he likes it,
yadda, yadda, yadda, you get it,
and then later on he is at an investor conference,
and this simulates him using his iPhone
to tell his boss to buy a certain stock
because the CEO of that company said something cool
about that stock, I'll skip through this pretty quickly
if I can, so he's sending the trade over to the trader
and then at the end of the day, he's the king of the world
in true Titanic format, hi, I'm seven. (laughs)
So that's that, it's pretty cool, it's a lot of fun to use.
Now, let's say you use a couple applications,
different presentation documents in one presentation,
how can you throw it together?
I personally use QuickTime to record the screen
and then I throw it in and I'll show you
how I do that in a second.
Before we get there though,
I love to look at new products
and there's one here that lets you
kinda use different applications
or different presentation applications together,
it is called SlideDog, I haven't used it that much
but you can basically throw in
different types of products together
and it will run them concurrently, that sort of thing.
Next up, there is another free program here
called LibreOffice, that's free in French
and many languages, it's pretty cool,
it kinda looks like an older version of PowerPoint,
I don't think they've updated this product
as much over the past couple of years
but it is free, and it's quite intuitive as well,
I'm not gonna show you how to use it
because it's very similar to a lot of the products
that we already use in this course,
meaning PowerPoint as well as Keynote.
So, in the next lecture I'm gonna show you
how I created this lecture here
but before I get there I just want to mention
that we covered basically 98%
or almost all the presentation software market
and there's issues using other products,
and those issues are as follows.
Number one, they don't have as many features,
number two, there's not great support
or upgrades to the product
and number three, there's a survivorship bias,
will this company be a going concern,
will it still be in business years from now,
so I'm trying to cover the bigger ones for now.
And that's it, but before we move on to the next lecture,
I want to show you just really quickly
how I inserted some of those videos on the screens
and again, in the next lecture
we'll talk about how I made this lecture in more detail
but I used QuickTime, you go to File,
New Screen Recording, but because I'm recording already,
it shows here as recording, and I want to mention
that QuickTime is also available not just on Mac platforms,
but it's available on Windows if you want to download it.