Let's talk about Piktochart,
which is amazing for putting in infographics
and other images.
Okay, and what I'll do is I'll create
an infographic from scratch,
and I'll explain what that means,
and I'll show you some other really, really cool features.
Okay.
So let's create an infographic first, okay.
And infographics are great, to not only show
in a presentation, but also to email
to your customers, your associates, etc.
Okay, so let's do this one here.
Let's use this template,
and we always work smarter not harder.
We use what they have there, 'kay.
So let's just call this one, I don't know,
You 2.0.
Okay?
Alright.
Get rid of that.
Let's say we want to change the background image there.
We can go here to photos.
They've got like a million photos you can use for free.
It's pretty incredible, pretty incredible.
Right, so we drag that over there.
Okay, and actually let me try something cool here.
I'm going to throw in,
you can throw in icons of anything you want.
Throw that there.
I'm doing this very fast, on the fly.
You can throw in tons of different types of fonts,
or text styles.
It's pretty cool, pretty cool.
So I'm going to do a search one.
Here we go, it's what I was looking for.
Okay.
So we're going to search, I don't know,
search for you.
And I'm creating this on the fly, very quickly.
So there's tons of different types of graphics
you can insert, and photos, and photo frames
to go around stuff.
It's really, really intuitive,
and a lot of fun to use as well.
You can really get lost in this, right?
And so, let's put in a chart, okay.
You can really customize any type of chart you want
right here.
It's like you got your mini little Excel embedded here.
Right?
And it's free to use this,
but again they try to upsell you a lot of stuff,
which is always to be expected.
Okay.
So, say we threw in that one.
You can import your own data.
You insert it here.
Obviously I'd clean it up a little bit more
on a new slide.
Let me delete that.
This is neat here too.
You can go to maps.
Say we wanted to put in a map of Albania,
and just a certain area, right?
You can actually to this portion of Albania for example.
And you can add data visualization as well.
It's really, really cool.
It's amazing, it's amazing, right?
So when you mouse-over it can change colors as well,
if you wanted to, right?
And what you could do is you could even take
a screen print of this,
again on a Mac that's Command + Shift + 4,
or on a Windows desktop that would be,
you would just use the Snip Tool or Print Screen.
Take a picture and you can just put it
directly in your Powerpoint presentation,
or Keynote, or Google Slides
or whatever it is you use.
You can even do a video capture of this,
if you wanted to show a video of this in your slides.
And to do that, you would go here to QuickTime.
And QuickTime is available on Windows as well as Mac.
And you do a new screen recording.
It's not going to work because
I'm recording the screen right now.
And then you just crop and save whatever it is you record,
and put it into your presentation.
Okay, let's go back here.
What else can I show you here?
You can put in YouTube videos here
if you wanted to as well.
And that is an infographic.
Let me go back now and let's create something different.
Let's create a presentation, okay.
And you can use many different types of templates.
If you sign up for it and you pay for it,
they let you upload more stuff,
and get access to more presentation templates.
Right and you can use a lot of these things
and customize it yourself to throw into
any type of presentation you have,
or just browse through this to get ideas.
And then what you can do is if you pay for it,
which I don't, but if you do.
If you level up, it's kind of a cool upsell,
concept level up.
You pay 15 bucks a month or whatever it is,
and then go back and what you can do is
you can actually download those slides
in PDF format or whatever it is, right.
They try to get rid of the watermark
kind of like PowerTunes does as well if you pay for it.
Right.
So that's Piktochart.
Very, very quick overview.
Try it out, it's pretty cool.
And even if you don't use it,
just kind of browse through it
to come up with ideas for your presentation.
Thanks.