Let's talk about Pixelmator, it's this cool app
you can get from the App Store here on Macs.
You can also get it on your iPad, and I'll show you the
iPad demo in a second, okay you can download it here.
It's as complicated as it's gonna get for me personally
when it comes to images, but I wanna show you a couple
of cool things you can do.
Little bit complicated, little bit overwhelming for
me personally, but let's go to my favorite image website
and get, I don't know, let's download an image to play
around with.
Search for the word people, scroll down,
ah here we go, that looks fun, painted smiley.
Okay, here's what we'll do, then we'll go to file
open, we'll open that smiley face, 'kay here,
so the first thing I'll show you is,
if you want to change an image a little bit,
I'm not gonna do all this layer crazy stuff,
'cause I'm not smart enough for that, but watch this.
Say we wanted to get rid of, I don't know, say these
glasses, click on here like that, and you're like,
you know what dude, this guy's not supposed to have
glasses at all, right?
So what we do, is we draw around here, and I'm gonna
fast forward this on high speed mode.
And then, see what happens, there you go!
Got rid of the glasses, I told you he shouldn't have
had glasses, I'll clean it up a little bit more.
Little bit more, isn't that neat?
It's really, really cool, right?
And then you're like, hey wait a second, this guy here
shouldn't have all these little dimples, that's not fair.
(Laughing)
So it's not perfect, whatever, you can see it kinda
work, isn't that cool?
It's really neat, really neat.
Now, I want to show you Pixelmator here on the iPad, 'kay.
It's a lot easier to use than the Mac version.
Alright, see here.
And by the way you can use QuickTime to record your
iPhone if you want, or your iPad, just plug it in and
go to QuickTime, per that image, the bottom left hand
corner there, which I just threw on.
Okay, so I actually made my course image using
Pixelmator on the iPad, right it's pretty cool.
So, let' say I wanted to get rid of the Oscar image
there, okay, so I click here, and you go retouch,
and if you can, use Pixelmator only on the iPad,
it's way easier than a desktop.
Let's say I want to get rid of the Oscar dude,
you zoom in here, you go here, right, you go retouch,
and it's gonna say whoa, what do you want to do?
I'm like, okay, I'll repair, I'll remove it,
and I'll paint over top of it and I get a bigger brush
if I want, makes it way easier.
And it's gone, let's say I want to get rid of that
clicker in my hand.
Alright, now let's say I want to get rid of
my laptop, it shouldn't be there on the stage, right.
So I go here, and I'll go retouch, repair, and actually
I'm gonna make the brush a bit bigger this time.
Pretty cool.
Wow, my laptop's gone, how awesome is that?
Let's get rid of some of the people in the front there.
Not perfect but, it's kinda fun.
Now, let's say I want to get rid of that white stripe
on my shoe, because I'm very insecure about that white
stripe, on just my right shoe, not the left one.
So I'll go here, I'll go retouch, repair.
Ah, it's okay, not perfect.
Alright, now let's do something a little bit out there.
Let's say I want to, oh wow that hand looks awful
that close, let's say I want to get rid of the microphone
there okay, so let's go here, repair, retouch.
Get rid of that guy, goodbye microphone forever.
Not bad huh?
Now watch this, gone.
Not perfect, but you can play around with it a little bit.
Alright let's go back and let's say, actually in this
picture here, it was crazy, there was like a cup right by
his book, and a bunch of other stuff, say I want to get
rid of a couple of those wires in the background.
You go retouch, repair, let me zoom in a bit here,
you see that wire there?
Let me get rid of it.
Gone, almost.
It's good enough, and what happens if
we get rid of the Echo?
That's not bad actually, 'cause if you zoom out,
wow, I just torched that Amazon Echo.
And let's say, oops, let's say I want to get rid of
I don't know, the doorknob.
It's pretty cool.
And then you zoom out and it looks better.
Isn't that wild?
It's amazing.
Say I want to get rid of the plug, alright last one
I promise, okay so I go repair, here,
and I get rid of the plug, I don't like that plug on
the wall, and Mr. Cord you gotta go as well.
And you, get off my crown molding, or floorboard
whatever you call it.
Ah, works okay.
Let's see, zoom out, not bad.
Alright white speaker there, you're ruining my picture.
Repair, repair, white speaker you gotta go.
It's just one of those things.
Gone.
Wow, the shadow's still there though.
And let's see, that cable looks ugly.
It's good enough.
And that entire cable, you gotta go sir.
That is so awesome, ah man you gotta download this,
this is the coolest thing.
Wow, look at that, it's gone.
Incredible, incredible.
Okay, that's it you can get lost in this one for
hours, but you can retouch old pictures,
if you break up with somebody you can take 'em out
of pictures easily too.
Wow, the future is now, amazing, amazing.
Alright let me know if you have any questions, thanks.