All right, I want to show you Procreate.
See that little app there on my iPad.
In the bottom left-hand corner before I get started
you'll see the little image I just threw on top there,
which tells you how you can record
your iPhone or your iPad.
It's easy, you plug in the lightning cable
that came with the iPad or the iPod or iPhone or whatever,
you plug it into your USB port on your Mac,
and then you go to New Movie
within Quicktime, which is right here.
Let me see, yeah, New Movie Recording.
And then you'll see in the bottom left-hand corner there
I selected to use my blue Yeti microphone, which rocks,
and then Screen from the iPad.
Okay, let me just show you here Procreate.
This one's a bit more advanced,
I know I said before that I don't like using Photoshop yet.
This one you have to actually put in Layers, which I hate.
But let's do a Layer, okay.
So, see that Layer there?
I kind of, look closely here, let me zoom in.
Okay, you see the globe here?
I want to make it look a little bit better, so watch this.
I don't know, I want a little bit more white there.
So you actually create a Layer, right?
And you add it on entirely.
So, let's try one.
So let's create a new Layer, okay?
And now we're actually painting,
we're gonna manipulate this Layer here
and we can turn it off, okay?
So let's say that we want to paint something over top.
Let's make our brush big.
You can paint here, right?
And say you wanted to keep that,
or say you wanted to get rid of just that,
so watch this, I deselect the Layer,
boom, the Layer's gone, okay?
Okay, let's say I wanted to add
kind of a cooler, texturized background there on the board,
what I can do is I can click here,
I can, say, let's put a grid,
let's paint a grid, see what that looks like.
You see that grid there, in the background?
It's kind of a neat little touch, like that, right?
And then, I can export this,
and I can turn that Layer off too if I want to, see?
Okay, so what you do is then,
you can go and you can export this image
and then import it into PowerPoint
or Keynote or Google Slides or whatever it is you use.