Let's talk about adding music
to your presentations.
If you have a video,
you might wanna throw some music in the background.
There's a couple websites I use.
The first one here is called PremiumBeats
and I buy a couple of tracks from here
for my promos usually.
It's really really high-quality stuff.
It's a bit pricey though.
Next up, we've got this great website here
called AudioBlocks.
It's about 99 bucks a year.
It's what I do, so it's totally worth it.
And in this course that you're watching right now,
I actually put in a couple of hundred
of little audio clips from here
and you can search for anything
that really sets a great mood.
You can type in inspire.
Right?
As I mentioned before, whenever it's really high,
there's a lot more stuff going on
and whenever there's just fewer items,
really thin line,
there's not as much going on.
Hear that?
This is busy though.
Over here it's busy.
Busier here, hear?
Okay.
And I don't know how they name these things.
This is called Conspiring Cowards.
I guess that sounds like conspiring at the beginning. Okay.
But there's so much fun stuff you can throw in as well.
It gets quieter here.
And you could select the type of instruments you want.
Do you want sound effects or not.
Like laugh tracks or crickets, whatever.
And let's see what else I can search for.
Let's search for orchestra.
Okay.
And you can have short pieces, long pieces.
So this is just a little orchestra one.
Hear cymbals?
And this is an entire guitar piece orchestra.
Synthesizer I guess.
First snow orchestra.
(synthesized orchestra music)
Anyway it's a lot of fun.
I absolutely love it and you can select ambiance
or the type of background music you wanna have as well.
Right here. See? Dramatic or whatever it is.
Okay.
You can choose the mood.
Let's say we want something epic and inspiring,
which I love.
And then let's say the instruments,
we only want to have piano, which I love.
Like the movie, Up. Great piece.
Let's see what it is.
That sounds more than piano to me.
Maybe it doesn't have piano.
Really relaxing, eh?
Anyway, just play around with it if you want.
And then you can download it into MP3 format
and then what you do is you import directly into PowerPoint
or whatever program it is you're using. Right?
So let me just import here into PowerPoint quickly.
So you go to insert
and then it's audio
and you can record if you want,
but I get it from file and it goes
right to my download folder usually. Right?
So we go downloads. That's the one we just downloaded there.
Here it is here. Check it out.
You can make it lower volume, Right?
Isn't that nice? Really really cool.
Right? And you can format when it starts playing.
You could say play automatically or when clicked.
And it doesn't have to be in your slides.
You put it over here.
It doesn't even show up usually anyway,
but put it here just in case. Okay?
And then, let's see what else I got here for ya.
So I wanna show you GarageBand as well.
Sorry I've got a million apps open.
So this ships free with a lot of Macs. Right?
And people don't really use it that much,
but it's really fun to use to make scores. Right?
And you can even learn how to play instruments.
And you can download how to learn
or how to play instruments.
There are people like Sting will
teach you how to play guitar.
It's really cool. Check this out, man.
Sorry, a little off topic, but it's fine.
He teaches you how to play the song, Roxanne.
♫ Roxanne put on the red light
And within iMovie you can also put in your own audio.
Isn't that nice?
Beautiful.
Love it.
This, promos I've used in the past.
I bought this one from PremiumBeat.
I love this piece. Right?
But my favorite source is definitely AudioBlocks.
Please let me know if you have any questions. Thanks.