Please engage your audience.
Involve them.
Ask them questions.
They're gonna pay a lot more attention this way,
and they're gonna feel like they're actually a part
of the whole presentation experience
that you're giving them,
and they're gonna retain a lot more this way as well
if they're engaged.
And I personally love to go off script a lot
when I'm presenting, and I engage the audience.
How you doing?
We're good, yeah?
Excellent, excellent.
Well, I just want to thank you for the opportunity
to let me speak here.
I'm very humbled to be a part of this, right?
I've never been happier, never been happier,
and for the first time in my life
I feel like I don't have a job.
I love it, it's fun, it's fun.
So, Mark Twain had this great saying,
he said that the two most important days
in a person's life are number one,
the day they're born,
and number two, the day they find out why.
Pretty cool, huh?
And so I humbly believe
that if you get up in the morning
and you tell yourself you're going to work
then, with all due respect,
you're doing it wrong.
You need to find your passion.
You need to find your raison d'être.
Gregory, was that right?
Did I pronounce that right?
So that was good, right?
You need to find your purpose.
You know, what was the reason you were put on this earth.
And so, for me it's teaching.
I love it.
I wish I'd discovered it much earlier in my life.
I wish I did, and Udemy has certainly changed my life,
and I'm very grateful, very grateful.
So, in terms of my background, I'm from Canada.
Every now and then you'll hear me say out and about, right?
Any Canadians here?
Right there.
One, two.
That's what I'm talking about right there.
Excellent, excellent, so yeah.
I'm from Canada originally.
I started a couple of tech companies,
worked in consulting, came down to the States
to work on Wall Street, did the whole business school thing,
worked for a hedge fund,
came out to the west coast,
and worked for a venture capital firm.
And I keep saying the word work, right?
Those were jobs, those were jobs.
And then I started teaching at nights,
and I absolutely love it.
And teaching is very similar actually
to working in venture capital where I used to work,
and the reason I say that
is when you work in venture capital you sit on boards,
and your mission is to help your companies grow.
And as a teacher your mission is to help
your students grow career wise,
and help them find their passion, and their purpose as well.
It's a great gig.
It really is.
And the wonderful thing about what all of us do
is our passions are to help others be more successful.
And there's not many professions like that in the world.
You just be yourself.
That's all I'm saying, okay?
I even have fun games when I present,
and I have half the room
competing against the other half of the room.
And I make the courses more interesting
by creating these really fun games, right?
So, try and be creative, right?
And I'll show you an example here of a video right here.
Here's an example
from slides I use in my class
for university business students, right.
I have one side is the blue side,
the other side is the red side, or the red team, right?
And then what I do is I have them compete with each other
in boxing matches, right, or boxing rounds.
And I call it accounting boxing,
or legal boxing, or business boxing, whatever it is, right?
And then I show them funny video clips here and there
to let them know which team is winning, red or blue.
That sort of thing, okay?
I just try to be different and have fun with it,
otherwise, you know what?
It gets boring for me too, right?
I wanna mix it up,
I wanna mix it up and have fun with it, right?
Otherwise what's the point?
And you want to be creative like this
to not only engage the audience
but so your presentation can be memorable, right?
Because it's so original which is a concept
we have covered a lot in this course, okay?
And most importantly, if you have a blast
making the content for which you're about to deliver
to the audience and engage them with it,
they'll love it because you're gonna be
so much more passionate delivering something
that you really had a lot of fun making,
kind of like an album, right?
These incredible musicians, they love writing music,
and they love delivering the music too
in concert or whatever it is, okay?
So just enjoy making and delivering these presentations
like a musician enjoys writing music
and delivering it as well.
And I want you to give an experience
and not a boring presentation.
And a great way to do this
is to get the audience involved
like they have at concerts, right?
So, at the end of a two-hour concert, you know,
everyone is still so engaged
that they put up their lighters in the air.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm dating myself.
We used to do that.
I think maybe people, I don't know, maybe people,
what do they do now?
They don't put lighters up, right?
I think they put up their iPhones or whatever
and make it look like a lighter.
Anyway, I digress, I'm rambling.
And in summary try to engage your audience.