Keep your delivery simple
and try not to use words
that you wouldn't normally use in a conversation.
Keep it really simple.
And I worked at a hedge fund called Citadel,
and I remember my boss telling me,
"Chris, if you can't explain it
"in easy understandable terms,
"then you don't understand it."
And he was right.
It's true.
And Steve Jobs was great at this,
as he said that the iPod Shuffle
was as small as a pack of gum,
or that the iPod was the size of a deck of cards,
something we can all identify with.
So, simple works well,
just like how images work well
and much better than too many words.
And there's a reason why People Magazine
is always one of the top selling magazines in the world.
And the same thing can be said for National Geographic,
just given the incredible image focus
within National Geographic.
And so, the bottom line is
delivery should be as simplistic as possible
in a way that addresses as many people
in your particular audience as possible,
which is what we covered in act one.