Oh, you're back.
Sorry, hi.
Joking, obviously.
(chuckling)
Try to make eye contact with everybody
if you can, at least one time.
If it's a massive crowd, obviously you can't do it,
but divide your eye contact equally amongst
the entire audience, if you can
and try not to look at one particular person too much,
if it's a large audience.
I read this great book by Larry King on speaking
more than 20 years ago.
I think it was back in 1994 or something,
maybe it was a little earlier than that, right?
And Larry King said that if you make eye contact
with somebody and if it's a one on one meeting,
look away every now and then,
just to be polite and now intimidating at all.
And it's kind of like,
this is out there, but I'm going there,
if you walk by a dog,
you never stare the dog in the eye because
you're challenging the dog, right it's like.
♫ Who let the dogs out
It's a no no, okay.
I'm a little bit too animated in this session,
I know, sorry.
Anyway, so in general,
when you make eye contact with your audience,
they feel more engaged, right?
And part of the whole presentation experience
gets improved, and your presentation
kind of goes from 2-D to 3-D.
It's more animated and it's just whatever.
When you look around, you can tell if
the smartphones are winning or not,
and when you make a lot of eye contact, I find
people don't,
they don't use their iPhones as much,
maybe they're trying to be polite,
or maybe they're more engaged, I don't know,
it is what it is, right?
Anyway, don't look above the audience either,
as it shows superiority, which is
not what you want to convey.
I'm just kidding, okay.
Anyway, that's it.