As I mentioned earlier, please don't have too much coffee
when you present, it can make you a bit figdety or jittery.
Let me put that down there.
I know I talked about drinking too much coffee before
but I wanna show you a failure of mine
during the Q and A session after one of my speeches.
So check this out.
This was bad.
So here's an example of me in the Q and A session of one
of my presentations, watch how my foot is shaking so much
that you probably aren't focusing on what I'm saying.
Okay, okay, let's move on now to head movements.
Nodding for yes and vice versa adds effect.
Especially when somebody is asking you a question
and they have an issue finishing the question,
maybe because they're nervous, which has happened to me.
And you kinda nod and help them through it.
And we're gonna discuss the Q and A session in Act Seven
which is in the next act.
Lastly, don't cover your mouth ever.
I try not to, although I probably do it sometimes
subconsciously, but when you do it,
it actually might show that you're hiding something
and I know that sounds a little bit out there
but I worked at a hedge fund called Citadel years ago
and they hired 25 FBI and CIA veterans to train us
on how to tell if an executive is lying.
And apparently covering your mouth indicates
that you might be lying, so even if you cover your mouth
out of habit, example, if you have a goatee,
just please try not to, just for your presentation.