Let's talk about the Q&A crutch concept introduction.
It's helpful to have frameworks prepared
when you're answering questions
and you don't need to have the perfect answer,
you just have to have a logical framework
when you're answering questions.
I call this methodology a crutch.
I'm gonna give you a couple of crutches.
And again, crutches mean stuff you can fall back on,
if you need to.
The answers that I'm gonna provide
are generic enough to include in many types of answers,
if needed and I'm gonna give you a lot of stuff here.
For example, when I was in school
and during an exam, when I had to write an essay,
I would structure the answer like this.
Let's assume the topic is to write about X.
So here's the structure for the introduction
or the first paragraph.
The topic of X is controversial
as there's many reasons to be in favor or X,
including example number one, example number two,
example number 3 and example number 4,
but there are many risks to consider,
including risk one and risk two.
The next paragraph is this.
In terms of example one, bla bla bla.
Next paragraph after this is this one.
Moving on to, good transition words,
moving on to example number two, bla bla bla.
And the next paragraph after that is this.
We also must consider example number three, bla bla bla.
And the next paragraph after that one is this one here.
Lastly, let's discuss example number 4 bla bla bla.
The next paragraph after that one is.
Moving on to risk number one bla bla bla.
This is kind of a straw dummy of a risk.
You want to give a risk that doesn't obfuscate
or confuse your audience or your reader of this essay
to the extent that they won't want to purchase the product
or believe your logic.
You want to make it kind of like,
I don't know if you've ever seen in the corn fields,
here in American, they have a lot of scarecrows
or fake people.
They're fake and so you want to create
kind of a straw dummy of a risk
that you can list and then beat up,
but it has to be credible as well,
it has to be sincere.
The next paragraph is this.
To be objective, we need to also discus risk number two,
which is this.
And then here's the concluding paragraph.
In conclusion, X is a logical solution
because of example one, two, three and four
as risk one and risk two are easy to overcome.
As such, X is appropriate.
We're not writing an essay, I get it.
I just want to give you structures to think about using.
By the way, for those of you that are interested
in writing the GMAT, this is the exact methodology
I use when writing the essay portion of the GMAT
and I'm sure that it's applicable
to other standardized tests as well.
Okay, we're done with that.
I kind of wanted to mention that,
because if you're stuck during a question,
during a presentation, it's framework
you can kind of fall back on.
There's a bunch of other frameworks
I'll talk about too.
And again, these frameworks buy you time to think
as it takes a few seconds to repeat the framework
to the audience.
Most importantly though, using that framework
shows that you think and you communicate logically
in a well structured manner.
When it comes to frameworks to use
when giving a speech to answering questions,
we're gonna discuss three things.
One, qualitative frameworks or crutches to fall back on.
Two, quantitative frameworks or crutches to fall back on.
And three, help I have no idea how to answer this,
so please give me a framework that I can use
to answer any question.
That's what I call that one.