Let's discuss answering qualitative
general business questions using frameworks.
Now, if you're asked about a business topic
or an issue or most business questions
not involving quantitative concepts,
you can use several different qualitative frameworks,
right, and tell your audience
that you're using these frameworks, too,
okay, if you want.
And I'll give you plenty of examples.
For example, okay, so this is the first one.
If you want, and again I'm just giving you
a menu of ways to answer questions,
if you want, you can answer qualitative questions
using what is called the S.W.O.T. Analysis.
Right?
And the S.W.O.T. Analysis stands for
strengths, weaknesses, opportunities,
and threats.
Okay, and you can use that framework
when answering questions,
and it buys you time, right?
So say somebody asked you about a general
business problem or issue or question,
and it's not quantitative in nature,
you can use S.W.O.T.
You can say, well, in terms of the strengths,
I think that the most important thing
to consider is this.
Moving on to the weaknesses,
we have to also consider the risks,
which are blah blah blah.
Then in terms of the opportunities,
if we act now, I think our company
can gain market share because of.
And then, lastly, on threats.
The biggest threat, though,
is most likely blah blah blah.
But you see how I kind of
gave myself a lot of time to think of answers.
Right?
And it shows that you're,
I don't know, you structure your answers
and crystallize your thoughts much better this way.
Anyway, okay.
So that's S.W.O.T.
S-W-O-T, okay?
Now, let's talk about answering questions
using what's called the Porter 5 Forces
Analysis Framework, right?
And I'm not gonna go into too much detail
on this, because you can go to Wikipedia
to research this.
This is not a business course.
But the five forces that impact a lot of companies
are competition, supplier power, right,
threat of entrance, and then the power of
the buyer or suppliers to source products.
Right, et cetera.
And there's one other one you can see
right here as well, okay, so you can
go through that if you want
in a lot more detail by going to wikipedia.com
and just searching for Porter 5 Forces.
Again, this is not a business course.
Okay.
Let's move on.
So if you have a marketing-related question,
you can answer it using what's called the BCG framework.
Okay, BCG stands for Boston Consulting Group,
which is one of the great consulting firms
that rejected me.
And I interviewed there, too.
Broke my heart, but that's okay.
So the Boston Consulting Group matrix
will basically categorize products
into four different quadrants
based on growth and all that stuff per this graphic here.
Again, I'm not gonna go into too much detail
on this, right?
But you can categorize products as
question marks
or stars, right, or cows,
I guess cash cows, or adorable dogs,
like that one there.
And my son, Matthew, when he saw the star there,
he said, "Dad, that's from Super Mario Galaxy."
And I was like, "Yeah, it is."
Pretty cool, eh?
Anyway, so that's a framework you can use
for marketing-related questions.
If you wanna do more research on that,
you can do so online.
But it's a very simplistic framework
that you can use if you have questions.
Let me know!
Let's now talk about answering questions.
Qualitative questions, using P.L.C.'s framework.
That's Product Life Cycle Framework.
Okay.
And so on the y-axis here,
you've got revenue, right,
and then on the x-axis here, you've got time, right?
And there's different phases
for a product.
There's introduction, growth, maturity, and decline.
Okay, so you can use that framework
if you wanted to, as well.