Moving on to,
words or things never to say when answering questions.
Okay. So I don't want you to use the words honestly.
We're gonna tell you the truth. Okay?
Ever when you're answering questions.
And the reason is I worked at a big hedge fund years ago.
And they brought in 25 year CIA and FBI veterans
to tell us how to tell if somebody's lying.
And it's really interesting
because there's certain things people say
which could indicate they're not telling the truth.
And you know some of those words
are honestly, or to tell you the truth,
that sort of thing.
So it's, I know it might seem a little bit of stretch
and in different cultures
there's different ways to interpret it,
but anyway I just thought I'd throw that out there for you.
Because honestly I love teaching this course.
And to tell you the truth I'm really enjoying teaching you.
Just kidding of course I am.
Okay.
Don't do what I do, do what I say.
I'm just kidding.
Okay and next up,
never bad mouth a competition or anybody,
or a culture of any other firm.
Okay. Don't ever say anything negative right?
Otherwise people might not trust you, right?
It just, it is what it is.
And never ramble,
keep your answers short, okay?
And if you find yourself rambling
then immediately finish the sentence by saying,
and so the bottom line is,
and you put your final thought in there, okay?