How can we get the audience
to write down what we are saying?
Okay, so, here's a trick for ya.
If you want the audience
to write something down
or students write something down,
and I do this all the time.
All you have to do is say this:
"Here's a list of three"
"blah blah blah blah blah," right?
So you can say,
"Here's a list of three crucial things we need to remember."
Right, and so, whenever I say that
in my university class settings,
everybody writes it down.
And it's fascinating because
that's always been the case.
But one thing I've noticed
with media publications
is that the best articles,
or the most read ones,
are the ones that have numbers in the titles.
"Five reasons why you should get a new job."
Or, "Seven reasons why you need to get a raise."
Or, "Seven ways to get a raise."
That sort of thing.
Right, so, it works really well
when you use numbers because
what happens is people hear this in the audience
and they think,
"Oh, this is gonna be easy to understand."
"It's just a list of numbers."
"Okay, I'll write it down."
Right, and I use the word crucial as well.
Kinda like,
I wrote a certain book a while ago
and the word crucial is in the title.
Right, so it's action oriented.
Right, okay, anyway, no self promotion.
Okay, separately, never say
the following is not important
or won't be on the exam,
because what happens is
all students stop paying attention
for the following item you're about to discuss.
Right, and I know you did that in school too.
(laughs) We all stop listening when
the teacher said, "the following is not on the exam."
"Blah blah blah," that sort of thing.