Let's talk about more than 30 crucial things
you might need to bring or pack
or do before your speech, okay?
And I've been working on this list over 20+ years
based on my failures, right?
And I want you to work smarter and not harder
and learn from my mistakes, okay?
And I want you to look over this list a couple of times
before your speech, okay?
And prepare these days or weeks in advance of your speech.
Okay.
Number one, okay, please pack or bring an extra shirt,
pants, jacket, et cetera.
And don't forget to get your clothes dry cleaned, you know,
a week or so before at least, okay?
And don't forget to wear clean shoes because that's what
people see when you're up on the stage, right?
And make sure that your shoes are soft bottomed, okay,
so you don't make noise when you're walking on the stage.
Otherwise, all people will focus on
is that distraction, okay?
Number two.
I want you to pack or bring a steamer, okay?
I like it better than an iron, right,
because it's just easier to use and it doesn't
hurt your clothes as much, right?
And so that's how I did this backdrop here and this shirt,
you steam it, right?
It's really easy to use.
You can get them for really cheap on Amazon.
And separately, let me know, answer this in the Comments
section if you know what movie this is from,
I recall Central Park in fall.
Alright, anyway.
I'm dating myself, okay?
Hint, it's from the '80s.
Okay, moving on.
Oh, and steam and iron your stuff the night before,
never the day of, okay?
Because what happens is if you put on a wrinkled shirt
it irons to your body, you sit down, it's looks really bad.
Anyway, just don't do it.
Okay.
Number three.
Pack or bring mints in case you speak with anyone
after the presentation, okay?
Number four.
Pack or bring a Nutra-Bar, right?
And put them in your jacket pocket, alright,
or laptop bag and eat an energy bar, these Nutra-Bars,
right before you go on.
I love these things called Quest bars, right,
because they have low carbs, whatever,
or net carbs, I should say.
Anyway, the best one is the Oreo cookie one.
Okay, number five.
Pack or bring a bottle of water as they sometimes forget
to give it to you when you present.
Okay.
Next up.
Pack or bring business cards and product details
and brochures, if applicable, okay, on your product.
Okay, I want you to also bring a few cheap USB drives,
right, that have details of your product.
And have them ready in your pocket and give them to massive
potential customers, right, or sales prospects, whatever.
Okay.
Number seven.
If your speech is early in the morning and you
usually get up later, or if you're in a different time zone,
I want you to get up earlier for at least a few days
before your speech.
And if your speech is later in the day,
if you have the luxury, I want you to get up later
in the day as well so you're more fresh, okay?
Number eight.
Pack or bring your identification, okay?
As you might need it to get into the building, right,
or the room, okay?
Number nine.
Pack or bring a USB drive back-up with your speech on it,
okay, just in case, just in case, okay?
You want to be ready.
Number 10.
Pack or bring your clicker and back-up batteries
for your clicker.
I actually have a back-up of this one even,
which saved my ass one time, okay?
Number 11.
Please pack and bring your laptop and make sure
your laptop is charged in case you cannot plug it in
on the stage, okay?
And the audio-visual person should help you with this,
right, but actually, this is kind of controversial.
If the audio-visual person tells you to use their laptop
I want you to be very stubborn and politely say no.
Okay?
Just trust me on this one, okay?
Number 12.
If you can, borrow or bring a back-up laptop
from a friend, right?
And always bring your laptop with you on a flight
and carry it with you and not in your checked luggage
in case it gets lost.
Twelve.
I want you to bring in all types of cables to attach
your laptop to a monitor, just in case they don't
have the right cables at the events, right?
They forget a lot, okay?
And please don't be cheap, right?
I want you to buy the best brand, if you can,
and test it out before, right?
And if you can, buy the brand made by the company
that made your laptop.
And I think we all know that buying cheaper iPhone
or Android chargers doesn't work because they stop
working after a while because, you know,
you always get what you pay for, right?
Alright, number 14.
If there is sound in your presentation,
I want you to bring or borrow or buy small,
powerful speakers, right, as a back-up if you want.
You can keep the receipt, too.
(throat clearing)
Number 15.
Pack or bring a charged iPhone, Android, or tablet
for a timer, right?
Timers ships with these things, too, right?
It's part of the operating system now.
And what I do is I put the timer right beside
my laptop screen if there is a podium
and I have the timer there so I can keep track.
So I don't have to pay attention to somebody
in the back of the room holding up a sign that says
five minutes left, right, that sort of thing, okay?
Sixteen.
Bring the phone number, obviously, of your contact
for the event and keep your phone on only before the speech
and then please turn it off before you go live, okay?
Seventeen.
Wear or bring layers of clothes in case the temperature's
too hot or too cold,
kind of like when you used to write exams, okay?
Number 18.
I want you to buy earplugs, if you want to,
so you can sleep well the night before, if applicable.
And consider even renting a hotel room, if you can,
closer to the event if travel is gonna be a nightmare, okay?
Number 19.
Email your contact for the speech the day before to confirm.
Number 20.
If you're speaking out of country,
make sure you bring the appropriate
electrical plug adapters.
Twenty-one.
Bring markers for a white board or bring a portable
white board, et cetera, if you need to,
in case you need to use it in the Q & A session, okay?
Twenty-two.
Travel to the event the day before
so you're familiar with the setting, if applicable, right?
Do you know where to park, right?
And bring cash as well because some places where you park
don't accept credit cards, okay?
Twenty-three.
Turn off all those annoying warnings on your laptop
like security notifications from Symantec or McAfee
or Windows update or Apple update notifications
and all that other nonsense.
You know what, just turn off Wi-Fi, right,
if you can, right?
And that might stop stupid notifications, right?
Number 24.
Please restart your laptop that morning
and make sure you have plenty of space on your laptop
so it can run a lot faster, right?
And only have your presentation software program open
after restarting, okay?
Twenty-five.
If you use a browser during the Q & A session,
make sure you have Wi-Fi access, of course,
and open your browser in private mode if you want to, right?
And the Wi-Fi code is quite often written at conferences
on the back of your name tag, if applicable, of course.
Twenty-six.
Run a security software scan on your laptop the day before.
It'll get rid of pop-ups and all that crap.
Twenty-seven.
Bring earphones and listen to whatever music gets you
in a relaxed and peak state before you present.
And, by the way, the second lecture of Act Nine
explains how to get into a peak relaxed and confident
state of mind, okay?
Twenty-eight.
If you're flying to present, obviously,
arrive way before, like the day before at least.
Okay, at least.
Twenty-nine.
Bring a notebook and a nice pen as well as you might need
to write down a question that you just can't answer.
So you could research the answer later that day
and email people directly the answers or say you will
put the answers that evening on your website
to the audience, okay?
And, of course, provide your web address as well, okay?
Okay, 30.
Bring a classy and a conservative bag to carry
your presentation items in.
And the same thing with your suitcase, right, if possible,
whatever, you know, if you're gonna bring it to the events.
I bought this really nice murse recently,
it's a purse for men, anyway, it's a bag for my laptop,
whatever, sorry.
Okay.
Oh, bring, Number 31, pack aspirin or throat lozenges
as well, if needed, okay?
And one thing I want to stress is that perception
really becomes reality in the mind of the audience
when it comes to every single thing about your appearance.
Bottom line, why are we bothering to pack
or bring all this stuff?
Because your competition won't
and one speech can change your life.
Thanks.