On the morning of your speech please review
the items in Journal Exercise Number 21 in case you need
to bring those items with you to the speech, right?
And I don't want you to practice your speech
the morning of it all.
I want you to focus just on relaxing, okay?
If you want watch the second video of Act Number Nine
the morning of your presentation,
which is called "Getting in an ideal,
confident, relaxed, peak mental state,"
which is "the zone," okay, remember the zone.
I want you to show up obviously at least an hour early,
right, and make sure you get at least seven
to eight hours of sleep, okay?
And, make sure you had a meal before the presentation
that doesn't make you tired, obviously.
Don't drink too much coffee or you might be shaking.
Do what I say, don't do what I do, okay?
Just kidding (laughing).
Okay, and for a lot of us though
you can't quit coffee otherwise you get a headache,
right, so, anyway, smile the morning of your presentation,
as it puts you in that great state, right.
Just be happy, shoulders back.
And I want you to read the newspaper
or watch the news that morning, okay?
I also want you to do a Google search on the company
you're presenting to, and or the topic
you're gonna present about just in case important
news event was released that you might have
to answer in the Q & A session,
or somebody asks you about it,
or if you wanna kinda tie in something,
I don't know, local and cool into your presentation, right?
And if applicable, check the Twitter feed
or any other social media web sites on the topic
or company you're gonna present on.
And you know what, if Facebook or any other
social media stuff pisses you off or puts you
in a bad mood then don't check it that day.
Happy stuff only.