In the first and second intermissions,
you record yourself.
At that point in the course,
we'd only discussed act one, which is the audience,
act two, which is the purpose of your speech,
and act three, which is creating the content.
And since our second intermission,
you might have looked at some of the optional templates
to using act number 11.
So I want you to please record yourself
with your smartphone or your tablet
or your laptop or your desktop
or a video camera, whatever.
And make sure that your slides are even better
than they were in your second intermission
presentation, right?
And the same thing goes with your delivery
and your content, etc.
I want you to do this
and to please be serious about it.
And this time, I want you to have a dress rehearsal.
So please wear exactly what you're going to wear
right when you present, exactly, okay?
And for this exercise,
please present based on the content
that you've created in your success journal
and review every single success journal exercise
that you've completed, please.
And if you need help with any of the topics
then please go back and review the lectures
associated with that particular topic.
And after you've finished recording this video
and making the slides to the best of your abilities,
then save it and put it aside,
as we will analyze your slides and your speech
in the next lecture.
Thank you,
and have a lot of fun with this.
And after you record your presentation
and perfect your slides,
please come back to me in the next lecture.
Thanks, again.