If you're watching this,
I want you to take a few days, please,
and think about you winning a Nobel Prize,
or a Pulitzer Prize, or an Academy Award,
later in your life, okay?
Then I want you to prepare
a thank you speech for two reasons.
Number one, so you can think about
a gap analysis, meaning where you are
in your life right now,
and where you want to be later in life
when you accept and receive this award.
Right, and you're gonna have to give
a speech for it too, okay?
The second reason, is so you can practice
what you've learned in this course
by giving this speech now, okay?
And if you wanna be really ambitious,
record it now and show it to the media
the day after you win the award in the future.
I'm not joking.
Jim Carrey did this, right, sort of,
with a check that he wrote to himself
for 10 million dollars, right?
When he was dirt poor and cleaning urinals
at a high school while living in a trailer park
when he was a kid in Canada.
I mean this is a great motivational story,
so please check it out.