First, let's have a look at metadata properties of a PDF document.
What is metadata? Metadata is data that describes other
data. In document management, maintaining metadata on
documents is an important thing.
Metadata describes certain facts about a document. For a PDF document,
metadata like title, author, created date, modified date, producer,
subject, and a set of keywords can be maintained, and those are
contained in the document as properties. To handle metadata of a PDF
document in PDFBox, there are a few mechanisms like using the
XMPMetadata class, using an XML file to store the XMP metadata. It
should be stated that XMP, which stands for Extensible Metadata Platform,
is an ISO standard for creating,
processing, and interchanging of metadata for digital documents.
PDF files used this standard for storing metadata.
Then, using the PDDocumentInformation class is another convenient
way to work with metadata in PDF documents.
Talking about using these API features in an application, to use the
XMPMetadata class, the xmpbox dependency is required,
meaning you should include the XmpBox JAR file in your project.
However,
to use the PDDocumentInformation class, you do not need any additional
dependency, and it is available with the pdfbox dependency itself.
PDDocumentInformation class makes things simple by providing property
getters and setters to work with the metadata properties.
When setting metadata properties using the XMPMetadata class,
they have to be set to different schemas, because these
properties are available in different schemas.
For example,
you can set properties like Create date and Modify date to the
XMPBasicSchema, but the property keywords isn't available in the
BasicSchema, but is available in the AdobePDFSchema.
Similarly,
the properties Title and Creator, or in other words Producer, and
Description are available in a schema named DublinCoreSchema, and not in
other schemas like the BasicSchema or the AdobePDFSchema.
Therefore, you will need to set these different properties using those different schemas.