Now let's see how to get started, first,
by creating the quotation Excel document.
You will see how to create a blank workbook,
add a sheet to it, and start adding content,
like the title, company name, and contact details.
But first,
let's have a look at the API packages that you will
be making use of in this process.
The org.apache.poi.common package,
which holds the common functionality for all POI document classes.
The org.apache.poi.ss package consists of all classes that implement
common spreadsheet formatting‑related features.
Then,
the org.apache.poi.hssf package has all the facilities required
for reading from and writing to Excel files.
And also,
the org.apache.poi.xssf is the package that consists of features
required for reading from and writing to Excel files,
compliant with the OOXML file format.
Let's say you want to create an Excel document
In other words, a .xlsx file.
These are the basic steps you will need to follow.
First, create an empty workbook by instantiating the XSSFWorkbook class.
Open a file output stream to write the content of
the workbook to the file system.
Create a new blank sheet on the workbook,
then create a row on the sheet, followed by a cell on the row,
and set a value to the cell.
You'll keep adding rows and cells as required.
And finally, write the workbook that you created to the output stream.
I've opened up the Maven Java project that we've been working on.
You can find it in the exercise files of this module.
Here, I have already added a new Java class quotation,
and in it, there are few blank methods already added.
I will explain them as we proceed through the demos.
Inside this generateQuotation method,
the first thing to do is to instantiate the XSSFWorkbook class like this,
and then, create a file output stream to write the Excel file into,
surrounded with try with resources, and handle the exceptions.
Next, create a new sheet on the workbook.
Assign it to an XSSFSheet type reference variable,
as we are going to have to use it in the subsequent
code that we will be writing.
Now in this addCompanyDetails method,
you will be writing the code to fill the top section of
the quotation document that you saw.
In here, add this code to create a new XSSFRow on the sheet.
As you can see,
the sheet that you created back there is being passed into this method.
Notice that we pass 0 as the row number,
as we are creating the top‑most row of the worksheet.
Note that the row and column numbers in an Excel sheet start from 0.
Now, to this title row, let's add a cell.
We need to display the title product quotation in the fifth column from left.
So you'll need to pass in 4 as the column index.
Now you can set the value to this cell by calling the setCellValue method,
passing in the string value Product quotation,
which will be the title of the quotation.
In the subsequent rows, you'll need to add the company details.
So create another row.
This time, the row number would be 1, and to that row,
add the contact number cell in column 3,
which means the column index 2.
And to display the company name in the 11th column,
on the same row, specify the column index as 10.
Then set the value like this.
Add one more row.
Create a cell in it, to add the email address,
and set its value, and then, in the next row,
to set the web address.
Now, don't forget to call this method inside the generateQuotation method above.
Also, write the workbook to the file output stream.
If you'd like to see what the output looks like,
simply call the method from the main class by adding these three lines of code.
Don't worry about the values passed in as arguments to this method, for now.
We'll be talking about them in the upcoming clips.
Now, if you run it,
you can see the Excel file quotation.xlsx created inside the resources folder.
That's where we wanted it to create the Excel file.
So there you go.
You now created a Microsoft Excel file, and added content to it.
In the upcoming clips, we'll see how to add some more content to it, and do a bit of formatting and styling.