We are going to see how to add formatting and styling
to cells in the quotation document,
using the XSSFCellStyle class. We will format the date
cell, number cells, align cell content,
color cells, and draw borders around cells.
But before jumping into the demo,
let's have a look at the XSSFCellStyle class and its methods.
This class resides in the org.apache.poi.xssf.usermodel package.
There are a bunch of methods in this class,
but you'll find yourself using these methods most of the time.
The setDataFormat method will set the different cell formats like
date, number, and etc., the setAlignment method to set the horizontal
alignment, and the setVerticalAlignment method, of course, to set the
vertical alignment, and also, the setFillBackgroundColor and
setFillForegroundColor methods.
It should be noted that both these methods are used to set the field or,
in other words, the background color,
even though the latter is named as foreground color.
When using both these methods,
the setFillPattern method should also be added,
passing in the fill pattern type.
You will see more about them in the demo.
You can also find a bunch of setter methods to set different border
types and colors as well in the XSSFCellStyle class.
So, for specifying the cell format, you'll be using the setDataFormat method.
You will need to pass in the format as an int or a short value.
You can find the built‑in formats inside the BuiltinFormats class that
reside inside org.apache.poi.ss.usermodel package.
It defines formats as strings with their corresponding numeric values.
More about it in the demo.
Alternatively,
you can use the XSSFDataFormat class to specify the formats
as strings or as numeric values as well.
Go back to the addQuoteDetails method in the Quotation class.
Let's format the cell that has the quotation date as a date cell.
For that, first, you'll need to create a CellStyle object on the workbook.
Let's call it dateCellStyle.
Next, call the setDataFormat method on it.
So what value are we supposed to pass to this? As I said before,
you can refer to the BuiltinFormats class to find out the available formats.
Let's say we want to use this date format. So you can call the static
method, passing in the string representation of the format.
So back in the code, let's call that method and pass in the format string.
Now you need to set the style that you created to the date cell by
calling setCellStyle method on it, passing in the style.
Now run the application. And you can see that the date
cell value is now formatted as a date,
according to the format that we specified. You can also use another
mechanism to set the data format, that is by creating a XSSFDataFormat
object and calling its getFormat method for obtaining a format as a
short value to be passed to the method.
To do that, first,
you need to create a XSSFCreationHelper object like this on the
workbook. Then, call the createDataFormat method on it, and you'll get a
XSSFDataFormat object on which you can call the getFormat method,
passing in the string format that you want. Here, you can even pass in
your own custom format like this.
Let's see the outcome of this by running.
As you can see, the date is formatted in the format specified.
We can also format the price cell and quota cells with a
number format by following the same procedure.
So, here we can create a new XSSFCellStyle named
priceCellStyle. Set the data format,
once again, referring to the BuiltinFormats class to look
for a format. Let's use this format.
So pass it like this into the setDataFormat method.
Apply the style to the required cells, product price, total, and subTotal.
Run it, and you can see that the set cell values are formatted in the specified number format.