Now let's go ahead and add more content.
In the addCompanyDetails method here,
create another paragraph followed by your Run point.
Now we need to display the company name at this location in the paragraph.
For that, we need to add tab spaces.
Let's call the addTab method on this run 10 times,
for example, and then set the text, The Furniture Store,
to the Run.
We also should display the logo image at this location,
so, once again, add some tab spaces.
Then, as usual, create an InputStream to the logo image file,
and you can call the addPicture method on the Run object,
passing in the InputStream, the PICTURE_TYPE as JPEG,
the filename as a string, then the image with an image height.
Now, talking about width and height, 140 and 64 are in pixels,
the measurement unit used to specify sizes in Open XML is EMU,
which stands for English Metric Units.
In the org.apache.poi.util package, there is a utility class Units,
and by calling its pixelToEMU method, you can convert the pixel amounts to EMU,
so that's what we are doing here to specify the width and height.
You can give them in other units as well,
as long as they are passed in as int values to the method.
Next, in this demo, we add some more details to the Quotation.
You will basically be following the same process that
you saw before to add those details.
First, the Contact No.
Leave some tab spaces to display the date on the
right‑hand side corner of the same paragraph.
Then display the Date.
You'll need to format the Date.
You can simply use the SimpleDateFormat to do that,
and apply it to the Date value.
Then break the line at that point.
In the next line of the same paragraph, display the email address.
For that, you can create a HyperLinkRun on the paragraph.
To that, you can pass in the uri like this.
Then, set the text to be displayed.
Add another break,
and follow the same steps to add web address in the same paragraph.
And finally, add another line break.
Then to add customer details to the Quotation document,
you can simply add this code.
There's nothing new here, just the same steps to be followed.
This code can be found in the exercise files.
Remember to call the addCompanyDetails and addCustomerDetails methods
inside generateQuotation method before you run.
Then when you run the application, you should see the content that we added.
But the content isn't formatted as yet. Let's add some formatting in the next clip.