Now using the API classes and methods that you just saw, let's set the
layout of the title slide of the product presentation.
You'll use the SlideLayout.TITLE enum constant to retrieve the layout
that we want. And then set the title and subtitle text to the slide.
Back in the code, in the generateProductPresentation method, call the
getSlideMasters method on the PowerPoint presentation and retrieve the
first element of the list,
which is the default slide master. It will return a XSLFSlideMaster object
like this. Now for the default slide master, call the getLayout method,
passing in the enum constant, $lideLayout.TITLE.
This is going to return the title layout for you. In the
SlideLayout enum, you can find a number of different slide layouts
that can be used when creating your slides as required. But here,
we are using the title $lideLayout.
The next step is to create the slide, passing in that layout.
It creates a slide that has a titleLayout.
Now this slide will have a title and a subtitle in it.
So to access the title, call the getPlaceholder method on the
slide object, firstSlide, passing in idx: 0.
This returns a XSLFTextShape object, which represents the title.
Then you can call it setText method like this and set the title text.
Similarly, you can call the getPlaceholder method once again on this slide,
passing in idx: 1 to retrieve the subtitle. And then set
the subtitle text to be displayed on it.
Now save and run the application once again. You can see
that the first slide now has the title layout with the title and a subtitle set to it.