Next up is aligning cell content.
Talking about aligning cell content, you can align content in two directions,
that is, horizontally and vertically.
To align cell content horizontally,
you can use the setAlignment method in the XSSF cell style class, passing
in a constant value of the HorizontalAlignment enum.
To set the vertical alignment,
you can call the setVerticalAlignment method of the same class,
passing in the constant from VerticalAlignment enum. Back in
the code, let's left‑align the dateCell value. To do that, to
the style object, dateCellStyle,
set the horizontal alignment by calling the setAlignment
method, passing in the constant value, like this.
Also, align the cell values,
quantity and description, in the product details section to be center
aligned. For that, create a new XSSFCellStyle lineRowCellStyle. Set the
alignment as center, and apply the style to the required cells, quantity
and description. Now run to see the result.
You can see that the date is now left aligned in the cell,
and the quantity and description are center aligned in the cell.
Apart from aligning the cells,
it is required to increase the width of some of the columns.
Let's increase the width of columns 3, 5, and 11.
It can be done by calling the setColumnWidth method of the sheet.
So let's do that inside the generate quotation method, right here at
the top, sheet.setColumnWidth. Now, to this method,
you should pass in the columnIndex and the required
width as 1/256th of a character width.
What it means is if you want the column to be eight characters wide,
you should specify the width as 8*2 56.
So for the third column, that is columnIndex 2, let's say we
wanted to have a width of 30 characters,
you will need to give 30 into 256.
The fifth column, that is index 4, to also have a width of 30 characters,
and the 11th column to have a width of 20 characters.
Now, when you run it,
you can see that the width has been increased in those columns.
It should be noted that the number of characters that can be
displayed can vary depending on the font.
The default font in XSSF is Calibri,
and you will need to give it some thought in case you are using any special points in your workbook.