Next, we are going to look at how to work with different fonts in PDFBox.
Let's use different fonts in the Product Catalog PDF.
You will want the page heading to stand out,
so let's change its font by making it bold. Then the product name,
let's make it bold and italic and use a different font type for the
product price. As you saw in the module Creating a New PDF Document
and Adding Content to It, in PDFBox, there are 14 standard fonts that
you can use like Times, Helvetica, and Courier,
along with their bold and italic forms.
Let's go back to the method, generateCatalog, that you've already
written, and right here, where you are setting the heading font, let's
change the font to HELVETICA_BOLD. Next, in this line of code where
you set the font for product name,
set the font to be HELVETICA_BOLD_OBLIQUE to make it
bold and italic at the same time.
Finally, change the font of the price to COURIER.
Now, when you save and run, you can see the fonts changed, like this. That looks pretty simple, right?