Now it's time to see how to color the cells.
Talking about coloring the cell background,
there are two methods: setFillForegroundColor,
and setFillBackgroundColor.
It should be noted that both these methods are used to
fill the cell background with a color, despite their names.
To these methods,
you need to pass in the XSSFColor object or an indexed color value,
as short.
Remember that you also need to call the setFillPattern method,
passing in the FillPatternType to it in order for this to work.
Let's color the tax cell in the quotation.
You can fill the cell with a pattern, or do a solid fill.
However, it is important to note that if you need to do a solid fill,
you must call the setFiillForegroundColor method, and set
the fill pattern as solid foreground.
Go ahead and create a new style object, and call the
setFillForegroundColor method on it.
Let's pass in the IndexedColors. So for that, you should use the
IndexedColors enum. In it, you can see the available color
constants. So you can see IndexedColors, and select the color
you want, and get its index.
After that,
you will need to specify the fill pattern, so call the
setFillPattern method, and this method accepts a
FillPatternType, which once again, is an enum.
We need to pass in the constant, SOLID_FOREGROUND,
since we want a solid fill here,
and that's all it takes to color a cell using a different color.
You can pass in different pattern types as required. That can be found in the
FillPatternType enum, and also, you can use the setFillBackgroundColor method
instead of the setFillForegroundColor method as well.
But if you want a solid fill, be sure to call the setFillForegroundColor method.
Now you might find this a bit awkward,
but that's how the API works at the time of recording the course.
Things could, however, change with future releases of the API.
You can play around with other patterns and colors as you wish.
Oh, and before you run it,
set the data format of this cell also to the same numeric
format that we used before. Now run it, and you can see that the tax cell is now colored in aqua.