Next up is splitting and merging PDF documents.
Suppose you want to split the product catalog PDF into separate documents,
for example,
as furniture and appliances. It can be done simply by using the Splitter
class available in org.apache.pdfbox.multipdf package.
Then,
in case you get a requirement to merge multiple product
catalog files into one single PDF document,
how can we do that?
Well, it can be achieved using the PDFMergerUtility class.
Let's see how to do that.
But before jumping into code, splitting means breaking down a single PDF
document into multiple PDF files, and on the other hand,
merging means combining separate PDF files into one single PDF document.
Now, let's jump in and code. To get you quickly started,
I've added some code here to add some more product pages
to the product_catalog.pdf.
You can simply copy this addPage method from the exercise file and add it
to your ProductCatalog class. And to the main class, copy this method,
loadMoreProducts, and inside the main method,
remember to add these three lines of code right after the last
line of code here, just like this. Then back in the
ProductCatalog class, here's the method splitPDF, where you're
going to add the splitting logic.
The document is already loaded. By now, you already know how to write that code.
Provided that you added the code that I mentioned just now,
you should end up with a product catalog that looks like this.
It has the Furniture page, a blank page, and two Appliance pages.
Now, suppose you want to split this so that you have one PDF file
for furniture and another PDF file for appliances.
To do that, you will need to split at page number 2. So back in the code,
create a Splitter object, and then on it call the
setSplitAtPage method and pass in the value 2.
This will split the catalog PDF at page 2. Now call
splitter.split method, passing in the document catalog.
This is going to return a list of PDDocuments.
If you just print the size of this list,
you will see that it is 2. You can now iterate through this list and
do whatever you want with the Splitter documents.
Let's just save them as separate PDF files, furniture.pdf and appliances.pdf.
For that, simply write this code. This code iterates through the list.
Get each PDDocument and save the first document as
furniture and the second one as appliances.
That's it. And now, call the splitPDF method in the main class.
Save and Run. You can see two separate PDF documents
created under the resources folder.
If you open furniture.pdf, you can see the Furniture page is in it.
And if you open the appliances.pdf, you can see the Appliances pages. So that's how you can split a single PDF into multiple PDF files.