Now let's see how to draw borders around some cells.
When setting cell borders,
you can use the setter methods for setting different border
types and colors in the XSSFCellStyle class,
which is one mechanism.
You can also use the PropertyTemplate class in the
org.apache.poi.ss.util package and call its drawBorders
method to set border styles more conveniently.
So let's use the PropertyTemplate class in this case. Let's say you
want to draw borders around the Sub Total cell and the Total cell.
So how can we do that using the PropertyTemplate class? Back in the
generateQuotation method,
create a PropertyTemplate object. Then call the drawBorders method on it.
Now you need to pass in the cell range as the first parameter to this method.
So, create a new CellRangeAddress object, passing in the starting row,
the ending row, the starting column, and the ending column of the range.
Let's check what this means in the Excel sheet.
The Sub Total cell has a starting row index value of 12,
where the row index starts with 0, and a starting column index
7, counting from the left. And, of course,
the ending row index would be the same, which is 12,
since we are drawing the border around a single row, but ending
column index would be 10, because we want to draw the border
surrounding multiple cells. Then for the rest of the parameters
you need to pass the border style, the color index, and the border extent.
So let's pass BorderStyle.MEDIUM, IndexedColors.GREEN and its
index, and BorderExtent.OUTSIDE, which means we want to draw
the outside border of the cell.
You can check the other available values in BorderStyle and
BorderExtent enums. Then to draw a border around the Total cells, call
the drawBorder method once again, passing in the correct cell range
values and the rest of the values. Finally, apply the borders to the
sheet by calling pt.applyBorders, passing in the sheet. Now Save and
Run. And you can see the borders drawn around the Sub Total and Total
cells like this.
If you want,
you can also use the setter methods available in the
XSSFCellStyle class as well to set borders.
In that case, you will need to call set Top, Left,
Right, and Bottom border methods and their color method separately.
This will end up you having to write more lines of code.
It could be a bit tedious,
depending on the amount of formatting that you will need to do. As a final
note before we conclude the discussion on cell styling,
consider using cell properties when you want to work
with styles in a more versatile manner.
This is available in org.apache.poi.ss.util.CellUtil class.
You can call the setCellStyleProperties method of this class,
passing in the cell object and a HashMap of properties.
The HashMap has a key of String and a value of Object.
Here is an example of how you can use it.
You can specify a HashMap with a String key and Object value.
Then put all the required styles that you would want to
apply to multiple cells into the map.
Then call the setCellStyleProperties method, passing in the required
cell to be styled and the properties map that consists of the styles
that need to be added to the cell. This can help you to better manage your cell styles.