Now let's format the table and its content.
First, let's center align the table on the document.
For that, here, call the setAlignment method on the table,
passing in a constant value, CENTER, from the TableRowAlignment enum.
Then to set the width of the table, call the setWidth method.
This method accepts an int value.
It should be noted that it accepts values as 20ths of a point,
or twips. Twips is a measurement defined as 1/20th of a
typographical point. One twips is 1/1440 inches, where one
typographical point is 1440 inches.
So if you want the table to be 6 inches wide,
you should pass in 1440 into 6 to this method.
Now to align cell content and apply some formatting to text,
you need to place cell content inside paragraphs.
There is a paragraph added by default in an XWPFTable cell at the time of
creation. You can access that paragraph by simply calling the getParagraph
array method, passing in 0 to access the one and only element of that
paragraph array. Then you can set alignment of it.
Let's center align the quantity. Now create a run on the paragraph, and now,
instead of setting cell text directly to the cell,
set the text to the run,
and you can call the formatting methods as usual on
the run, like setBold, setColor.
Let's make it bold and blue.
Do the same for the description, unit price and LineTotalCells.
In addition to making the text bold and blue,
let's set the width of the unit price and lineTotalCells to exactly 1 inch. So
how can you do that? For that, call the setWidthType method of the XWPFTable
cell class to set the type of width. To this method,
you shall pass in a constant in TableWidthType enum. It has these values. AUTO
is the default value, if you do not specify anything. DXA is to specify it as
an absolute value, once again in 20th of a point or twips, and PCT is to
specify the width as a percentage value. Let's give it as an absolute value.
So, TableWidthType.DXA. Next,
call the setWidth method on the cell, and let's say you
want to set the column to be 1 inch wide.
So as a string value, pass in 1440, which is 1 inch in 20ths of a point.
Do the same for the line total as well. Then to format the rest
of the cell values, inside the for loop, that is the product
detail values, follow the same process.
Get the default paragraph of each table cell, et alignment, and into the run,
add the cell text instead of adding it directly to the cell.
Do the same for all the columns, and also to the
subTotal, tax, and total cell values.
Notice that the subTotal, tax, and total labor cells are set to bold and
italic, and cell values are aligned to the right of the cell.
Finally, add this code inside the addInfo method to add
the deliveryInfo and the generalInfo lines to the
quotation. There's nothing new here.
It's just adding more paragraphs and content to them. Before you run the
application, call addInfo method in the generate quotation method.
Now save and run the application.
You should see a document that looks like this. So you have now successfully created the quotation as a word document.