In the final demo of this module,
you are going to see how to extract content from the quotation
Word document by extracting text content,
table data, and the image. The main API class used here is the
XWPFWordExtractor. That is specifically to extract text content using its
getText method. Back in the code inside the extractText method here,
the first step is to create a FileInputStream,
specifying the path to the document. Then create a new
XWPFDocument instance, passing in the InputStream.
Next,
create an instance of the XWPFWordExtractor class,
passing in the document object.
Now you can call its getText method to retrieve the
entire document text content as a string.
If you call this method in the main class, and run the application,
you should see the text content of the document
printed in the console like this.
Now if you want to extract data from the table in the
document, inside the extractTable method here,
simply follow the same initial steps as before.
Then, on the document, call the getTables method to retrieve all the tables
in the document. It will return at list of XWPFTables.
Since we just have one table in our document, you can simply get it like this.
Now, you can loop through the rows in the table like this, and the
cells in a row like this, and get cell text.
And if required,
display like this. If you call this method in the main class, and run,
you can see just the table data extracted like this.
Finally, if you want to extract an image from the Word document,
go to the extractImage method in our class.
Follow the two initial steps. Then from the document, getAllPictures.
It will retrieve a list of XWPFPictureData objects.
Since we have just a lower image our case, you can get it like this.
Now get the picture data into a byte array,
then open a FileOutputStream, specifying the path for the image
file to be created, along with a name for it. And simply write
the byte data to the OutputStream.
That's it.
And now, when you call this method in the main class, and run,
you can see an image file created by the name that was
given under resources, images like this. This is the extracted image from the quotation Word document.