In this demo,
let's add text content to the product slides by displaying the product name,
its features, and the price.
Go to the addProductSlide method once again.
Below this code, create a TextBox on the slide.
To place text in it, first,
add a new paragraph line calling the method addNewTextParagraph.
Let's call it namePara.
Then to it add a NewTextRun.
Then on the run call setText method to set the product name.
Next, add a line break on the paragraph by calling the addLineBreak method.
This is to create a gap between the name and the feature
list that's going to be displayed below it.
The feature list should be displayed as a bulleted list.
So how can you do that?
Let's look through the feature list like this.
Then inside the for loop add a new text paragraph like this.
To display it as a bulleted list, you should set indentation on the paragraph.
Indentation can be set to different levels starting from 0.
Let's call the setIndentLevel method passing in 1.
If you want to create sub‑bullets under this,
you can set further indentation levels up to a maximum of 4.
Zero is the default, which means not indented.
Then you can call the setBullet method passing in true to indicate
that we want them to be displayed as bullet points.
Create a NewTextRun on the paragraph and set the text to be displayed,
followed by a LineBreak.
Next, you should position the text box on the right‑hand side of the image.
To do that, call the setAnchor method passing in 350 for x,
100 for y, then 400 as the text box width,
and 400 as the text box height.
Now Save and Run.
You can see that the product name and the list of its
features displayed as a bulleted list like this.
Now go back to the same method.
Create another text box on the slide.
In the same way, add a new text paragraph followed by a text run on this.
Display the product price.
The price should be formatted using a number format.
For that, simply create this format and apply it to the price when displayed.
Now to position it at the bottom left of the image,
call the setAnchor method,
now passing in the coordinates like this, and the
text box width and height as 200.
Now, if you save this and run,
you can see the price displaying like this below the image on the left‑hand side.