Finally, you are going to see how to protect a PDF documents.
What does it mean to protect a PDF document?
PDF documents are digital replacements of paper‑based documents.
You know that the paper‑based documents can be confidential sometimes.
Similarly, it could be required to make digital documents confidential as well.
PDF documents can be secured using passwords.
It is possible to specify the permissions as to who
can do what with a PDF document.
According to the PDF specification, access permissions for a PDF document are
print the document, modify the content of the document,
copy or extract content of the document, add or modify annotations,
fill in interactive form fields, extract text and graphics for
accessibility to visually impaired people, assemble the
document, print in degraded quality.
There are two types of passwords that can be attached to a PDF document.
They are the owner password,
which enables to access a PDF with all eight permissions that you saw earlier,
and they user password which enables to access with restricted permissions where you can specify what permissions you wish to give the user.