In this first demo,
you are going to load up the product catalog PDF that you created earlier.
To do this, you'll use the static load method of the PDDocument class.
After loading it,
we'll add a new page to it and then extract text content from the PDF
using the getText method of the PDFTextStripper class.
You'll also extract images from the PDF.
Since we've got multiple images in the product catalog PDF,
we'll look at how to extract them and also see a slightly different way of
extracting an image in case if the image is a full page image.
In the ProductCatalog class, let's add a new method,
load, and modify a product catalog.
First, we need to create a file to represent the catalog PDF document.
So create a file object, file.
You will need to specify the path to the file,
and for that let's define a string variable named path and initialize
it with the path to the product_catalog document.
Now the next step is to load the PDF document.
The way to do this is to call the static load method of the PDDocument class,
passing in the file that you created.
Now, remember you need to ensure that the document is closed after using it.
So surround it with try with resources, and handle the IOException as well.
Now that the PDF document is loaded from the file system,
we can do modifications to it like adding content,
removing content, and etc.
Let's just add another page to it.
So call the addPage method on the catalog document.
Remember to pass in the page size.
We want it to be an A4‑sized page.
Great.
You've now added another page to the PDF document.
But wait, you need to save it.
If not, the changes you made to the document will not be there.
So, call the save method on the catalog document, passing in the path.
Now let's test it to see if the new page got added.
Back in the main class, call the method.
Run the application, and you should see now that the PDF has two pages in it.
Now let's extract content from the PDF document, product_catalog.
I've added this extractContent method and have already written the
code to load the document which you've seen already.
The PDFTextStripper class has the methods that can be used to strip
out all the text content from a PDF document.
It should be noted that all formatting will be ignored
when stripping out the text from the PDF.
Once the text content of the document is stripped out,
you can work with that content the way you want.
As you can see,
this class has a bunch of methods that can be used to
handle the text content of a PDF document.
For example,
if you want to limit the text that is extracted you can specify the range
of pages using setStartPage and setEndPage methods.
However, let's use the getText method in this case.
So, to call the getText method for the PDF document,
let's first create an object of the PDFTextStripper class.
And then, using it, call getText, passing in the PDF document, catalog.
This method call is going to return the entire text
content of the PDF document as a string.
So, store the string in a variable textContent.
Let's see what we've got in textContent, so print it out.
Now, if you call this method in the main class and save and run the application,
you should see an output that looks like this.
You can see all the text content in the document from the
heading to the rest of the details, like product names,
their features, and the product prices.
You can simply use the getText method or use any other
method in the PDFTextStripper class to deal with the text content in your PDF document.