First, looking at the dependencies of the Apache POI API.
As you saw in the module outlining the essentials of Apache POI library,
it is made up of many components.
So what are the components?
POIFS is the fundamental component, and there are a set of components like HSSF,
HWPF, and HSLF used for working with OLE file format‑compliant Excel,
Word, and PowerPoint documents, and components like XSSF,
XWPF, and XSLF used for working with OOXML file format‑compliant Excel,
Word, and PowerPoint documents.
Talking about the dependency JARs pertaining to these components,
POIFS and HSSF components come with the POI JAR.
You will need to get the latest version of it available to your project.
Having these two components will enable you to work with Microsoft
Excel documents compliant with the OLE file format,
in other words, files with the extension XLS.
If you want to work with Word and PowerPoint,
you need the HWPF and HSLF components, respectively,
and they come with the poi‑scratchpad.jar file.
To work with OOXML file format‑compliant Office documents,
you need the XSSF, XWPF,
and XSLF components that come along with the POI OOXML dependency JAR file.
On an additional note, along with the POI OOXML JAR file,
there will be the poi‑ooxml‑schemas JAR and the XMLBeans JAR available.
They are required when working with OOXML‑based
Office documents with extensions XLSX, DOCX,
and PPTX.
As additional JARs that come along with the POI JAR and poi‑ooxml JAR,
you will get the commons‑loggins, commons‑codec,
commons‑collections, commons‑math, and the SparseBitSet.jar.
If you download Apache POI, you will get them along with the package.
And if you use Maven, you'll get them as transitive dependencies.
There are two ways in which you can set up Apache
POI with your Java application.
One way is to set up the JARs manually by downloading and setting
them up as external libraries to your Java project.
The other way is to use the pom.xml.
If you are using Maven,
you can specify Maven dependencies in the pom.xml of your Maven Java project.
So if you are manually setting up your JARs by downloading them,
you will need to include these JARs, POI JAR,
poi‑ooxml JAR, poi‑ooxml‑schemas JAR, and the XMLBeans JAR.
This will enable you to work with both OLE and OOXML‑compliant MS Office files.
If you are using Maven and if you want to work with older
file formats of Microsoft Office like XLS,
DOC, and PPT, you can simply include the POI dependency in the pom.xml,
like this, and it will provide the components POIFS and HSSF,
along with the other basic components required.
If you want to work with Word and PowerPoint,
you'll also need to include the poi‑scratchpad dependency,
along with this dependency.
If you include the poi‑ooxml dependency,
it will provide all the XML‑compliant components like XSSF,
XWPF, and XSLF, and all the other basic components that come with the POI JAR.
So simply, if you include this dependency in your pom.xml, you will be able to work with any file format.