Now, we do have non‑text content in our Product Catalog document.
There are product images.
So how can we extract them?
This could be a bit tricky though, meaning it is not so straightforward.
If you can remember, there are three product images in the first page.
So let's say we want to extract all the images in the first
page of the Product Catalog document.
The first step would be to get the first page by calling the getPage method,
passing in the pageIndex.
Note that the page indexes start from 0,
just like how array indexes start from 0.
This means that if you want to get the first page,
you will need to pass 0 to getPage method.
The getPage method call is going to return the first
page in the Product Catalog document,
and then we can access the resources in this page by
calling the getResources method on the page.
A small note here,
resources are the different types of content that can be present in the PDF,
like images and other types of content.
Among these resources, there can be external objects, like images.
In the PDF file structure, these are known as XObjects.
XObjext, or in other words, external object,
is a way of _____ _____ elements in a PDF.
In PDFBox, these XObjects are represented by the PDXObject class.
PDXObjects come in different forms, for example,
as PDFormXObjects and PDImageXObjects.
PDFormXObject can be thought of as a top level XObject representation,
whereas PDXImageXObject is a more specific representation for image objects.
So in this case,
it is possible to find out the ImageXObjects in the resource stream and access
the images in the PDF page we are looking at through them.
You will need to write a couple of lines of code to achieve this.
Now, we have obtained the PDResources from the first page,
so let's iterate through the XObject names of the resources by
calling resources.getXObjectNames within a for loop.
According to the PDF specification,
everything in a PDF document has a COSName, so the
XObjectNames are also in the form of a COSName.
So we get the COSName of the XObject, and then by the name,
we can retrieve each PDXObject from the page resources by calling getXObject,
passing in the COSName.
Let's assign it to a variable of type PDXObject named xObject.
Now, we are in the process of extracting the images,
so we need to find out if this particular xObject is an ImageXObject.
So, using an if condition,
we check if the XObject that we have is an instanceof PDImageXObject.
And if so, we can cast the XObject in to a PDImageXObject,
and then we have any ImageXObject.
As you already know, in PDFBox, images are represented using PDImageXObjects.
So now, you can access the image using this ImageXObject.
So let's save the extracted image on the file system.
For this, call the Image I/O's write method.
We need to pass in the file path to it in the form of a file object.
So first, specify the file path, like this, simply save the extracted
images inside the images folder under resources.
Let's give the image file a dynamic name, like this, and then call
ImageIO.write, passing in the image itself by accessing the ImageXObjects image
by calling getImage method and give the file format as jpg and the File object
to represent the file in the file system, passing in the path to the File. We
need to implement i's value to be able to generate dynamic file names inside the
for loop, and now we are done.
If you now call this method in the main class and then
expand images folder under resources,
you should see the extracted_images saved under it, like this.
Though the process was a bit complicated,
it actually is quite simple to be able to access
multiple images in a PDF document.
On the other hand,
if you have a full page image on your PDF, extracting it
would be much more simpler than these.
There is the PDFRenderer class that is capable of rendering a
PDF document into an AWT BufferedImage.
So if you create a PDFRenderer, passing the PDDocument,
and then call the renderImage method,
you should be able to get the image as a BufferedImage.
You need to pass in the pageIndex,
which is 0 based. This is the page where you have the image
that should be rendered, or in our case,
extracted.
And then simply, you can save the image object onto your file system in the
usual way, as you saw earlier, by calling ImageIO.write method. You can try
this out as well by simply following these steps and see what happens. With
that, we come to an end up this demo. And in the next demo, you will see how to remove a page from the PDF.