What are the capabilities of Apache PDFBox?
Let's take a look at its features.
It has some basic features, as well as more advanced features,
meaning we can use it to create, modify,
and extract content from a PDF document,
and to do more things like splitting a PDF into pages
and merging many PDFs together,
encrypting or password protecting confidential documents,
and even validating a PDF document to see if it is ISO 19005
compliant. Using PDFBox, you can also convert text into PDF and PDF to
images, and also create forms in a PDF document.
PDFBox also comes with these capabilities.
It has Unicode support,
which means we can use the Unicode forms in PDF documents. It is possible
to create interactive forms in PDF documents using the concept of AcroForms
that allow UI components in a PDF document.
It also comes with a set of common line tools to perform things
like encryption and decryption; overlaying,
which means covering the content of one PDF document with
another PDF document; merging PDFs; debugging; and a converting text to PDF and PDF to an image.