Now let's take a quick look at the main components and some applications of.
PDFBox.
The library has four main components.
PDFBox, FontBox, XmpBox, and Preflight. PDFBox is a library that contains
classes and interfaces related to content creation,
extraction, and manipulation.
FontBox consists of classes and interfaces that handle fonts.
XmpBox has the required classes and interfaces for handling document
metadata using the Extensible Metadata Platform, or XMP,
which is an ISO standard for working with metadata in digital documents.
Preflight is the part of the API that has classes and
interfaces to verify a PDF file to see if it complies with
the ISO 19005 PDF/A‑1 standard.
What are the applications of Apache PDFBox? There are two
Apache projects that use the PDFBox library.
One is Apache Tika.
It is a generic library that has been developed to detect document
types and to extract content from various file formats.
The Tika project in fact uses both Apache PDFBox and POI libraries.
The next one is a Apache Nutch.
This is an open‑source web search or crawl application written in Java that uses Apache PDFBox.