Before we wind up, let's do a quick recap.
You saw the dependencies required for Apache POI to work
with the OLE file format, in other words,
to work with XLS, DOC, and PPT file extensions, and also, the dependencies
required to work with the OOXML file format, that is, to work with MS Office
documents with file extensions XLSX, DOCX, and PPTX.
Then you learned how to configure your Java
development environment in two ways, first,
by downloading and setting up the JAR files as external
libraries and then using the pom.xml in a Maven Java project.
And now you completed the first step of the path to learning Apache POI API integration with Java.