Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
So in this one we're going to translate all the questions and all the answers separately into integers.
What does that mean.
Well let's take our clean questions for example the clean questions list here in this list you can see
that we have all the questions that are into text so can we make this quick rucks and Corinne and Andrew
Bart are having these are into text and we want to translate that into the unique integers that were
mapped.
Thanks to our previous dictionary that we created.
So basically we just need to translate all this into this new language of integers according to how
our previous dictionary was made.
And therefore we're going to have to make some for loops to loop not only over all the questions here
and then all the answers and then for each of these questions here we will loop over again all the words
of the question and applying the previous dictionary to translate each of these words into their unique
associated integers.
All right so let's do this.
And by the way now that you understand what we have to do.
Well again I recommend to try doing it yourself before watching this tutorial and the other important
thing is to understand why we're doing this.
We're only doing this because then we want to sort all the questions and all the answers by their length
and to sort that well these two lists of questions and answers translated into integers will be very
helpful.
And why do we want to sort the questions and answers by the length that I remind is to optimize the
training performance.
All right so let's make our two lists of questions and answers translated into integers and also while
making that list we're going to replace all the words that were filtered out by our token out.
So at some point in the loop we will need to add an if condition to check if the word was filtered out
and if that's the case will replace this word by the token out.
So let's do this now you understand what you have to do.
Try to do it before me but I'm going to start now.
So to start we have to understand that we're about to make a new list and this will be the list of the
questions translated into integers and I'm going to call that list questions on this court to underscore
and because we're translating the questions into integers so questions to end and then a pair of square
brackets because it is a list.
And now we are ready to start to fill up.
So as we said we have to do two four loops.
First we need to loop over all the questions here.
That's the first for loop.
And then the second for loop for each of the question we will loop over all the words of the questions.
So let's do this first for loop over the questions in clean questions to huge clean questions list of
all the questions and text.
So for all the questions and clean questions what do we want to do.
Well we want to translate all the words of the question into their associated words based on the previous
dictionaries.
So we need to make another for loop but we are going to create a new list for each question and the
question we're dealing with right now.
So since we're making a new list we need to introduce a new one and we're going to call it it's because
this will be the list of integers each of the integers will be the associated integer to the word in
that question.
So it's equals.
We initialize it as an empty list and there goes the second for loop and then the second for loop we
will loop over the words in the question.
So in question then don't forget we need to add that split to get these words separately and then colon
and then there we go.
Time for the if condition.
Because that's where we need to check if the word was filtered out or not.
If it was filtered out we will replace it by the token out if it was not filtered out who will just
translate it into the integer.
So let's do this let's make this if condition so we're first going to check if this word was filtered
out.
That is if this word is not in our dictionary.
Questions words too.
And remember that's the dictionary that maps each word of the question to an integer.
So that's exactly what we need right now.
If this word is not in this questions words do in dictionary.
Well what do we do.
We want to replace that word by the token out and more specifically we want to replace that word by
the integer that encodes the token out.
Remember that in this code section here there is three tutorials to go.
We also attributed a unique integer to each of the tokens here.
One of them is out and therefore out also has its unique integer and now not only we want to replace
this word by Alice but more specifically we want to attribute for this word the unique integer that
is associated to the token out.
And therefore I'm going to do now as I'm going to take my ENC list to which I'm going to append this
unique integer associated to the token out.
And how do we get it.
Well we simply need to take our dictionary questions words to it and from this dictionary we're going
to get the key to tokin out which is this way.
So going out is the key that will allow us to get from these questions words to in dictionary the unique
integer that was associated out.
And this is what will be returned here.
So this is exactly what we want.
Great.
So now other case if the word is in question were two in there if the were wasn't filtered out which
we can express here by else because this is complimentary.
Well in that case what do we want to do.
Well we simply want to add to our list of the encoded integers the unique integer that was associated
to this word we were dealing with right now and that was not filtered out.
So we're going to do that same thing.
I'm going to copy this Bazan here.
But instead of taking out here we of course need to take the word because the word is now the key identifier
which when we apply the questions word in dictionary will get us the unique integer associated to that
word which is exactly what we want.
So now that we have the question translated into integers we simply need to append this translated question
into integers to our questions to int.
HUGE list of all these translated questions and therefore what we simply do here is take.
We can this.
We take our questions to int list to which we append the question translated into integers and that
is contained in this list.
So in the append function I'm just adding It's all right and that's it.
That does the job for the questions.
Now we're going to do the same for the answers but as usual it's very easy.
We simply need to copy paste this whole section because this is going to be the same logic.
So paste and here we just need to replace all the questions by the answers.
So let's do this answers.
All right good.
So we did it.
If it's more clear for you we can even add questions into integers so that it is clear that this is
the translation of questions text into integers so just replacing that year.
All right.
And so now let's have a look at what we just made.
I'm going to select all this section and execute.
There we go.
I hope it's going to work.
Hope no error was made.
Apparently not.
Let's have a look.
So questions.
First let's have a look.
It must be right here.
Questions.
Yes and perfect this is exactly what we wanted.
Each of the question of the clean questions list was translated into the unique integers according to
our questions words to any dictionary.
And so perfect so let's quickly check.
Also the answers to int list but there should be the same.
Yeah there we go.
Perfect.
All the answers in the clean answers list where translated into their unique integers based on that
answer is words to any dictionary that we made great so.
Wow.
Now I'm getting super excited because we're getting two parts to building the sick sick model.
We only have one tutorial left to take care of but that's very important because that's the one where
we'll sort the questions and the answers by their length.
And to do that we will use what we did here.
That is these questions and answers and two lists that we will leverage to sort these questions and
answers by the length.
So let's do that in the next tutorial.
And until then enjoy typing on the.