Hello and welcome actually of course a deep natural language processing in today's tutorial we're going
to talk about the applications of what you will learn.
So we'll discuss some of the areas where you can apply your new skills and I think it's an important
hurtle because not only can you use these skills to build CHUGG we will be in deep focus which I Butson
this course but at the same time we can use the same skills methods and models in order to create many
many more things.
And that's why in this story we're going to broaden our horizons and see what is possible.
All right so let's have a look.
First one is speech recognition.
So I've got to put them in order of importance in order of how volume must application is how many how
often how impactful it is for a lot of lives how Look world changing these applications.
So speech transcription is a huge one.
Whenever you talk into your phone and try it out as text that is specious scription so taking in audio
form and putting it into text.
But not only does it stop there.
Remember previously on the Get excited story we talked about some of the chat boards that are or that
are like Siri or town or Alexa that are voice based.
Well that same technology goes in there to understand the wave forms and some of the sound we can apply
a deep natural language processing and then Reiji put in that second part which is the chat board in
order to understand what to do with that text what to do with those instructions.
So speech transcription as it can that is it's already very important is going to become more and more
and more important in the years to come.
And this can happen.
This can be done with deep language processing and how we actually have a case study down further down
the course.
Then comes Nature or now your own machine translation or NMT.
So a lot of us have used google translate most of us have to use google translate at least once in our
lives.
Well you see Google Translate used phrase based translation algorithms.
Now they have switched to your old machine translation which is powered by exactly the same models as
you'll see inside the scores.
Then we've got the boards which will be talking about in depth in the course and we create one ourselves.
Then we've got the Q&amp;A type obligation.
It's kind of like simle Joe childbed but it's not as intense not as in-depth.
For example you have a model which has access to us and resource our instance the Harry Potter books
and you can ask a question like What is the name of Harry Potter's mother and it'll spit out an answer.
So question answer question answer is no conversation going on.
But you can get very quickly information from volume volumes sources such as books or other sources
on the Internet like GPDA for instance you can get information very quickly.
Next one is text summarization another publication similar to both a Q&amp;A but less interactive has more
to do with like if you have a lot of text and you need to create a summary for instance you have a book
and you just create a summary of the book or if you have lots of medical documents and journals and
you need to write a synopsis for them then you can use text intercession as well.
But the concept is the same again we need to use the models that we've been discussing in order to assess
all of the input text and come on come up with an on actual image captioning.
And that is a bit trickier to like to see how the models were going to be creating or scutching can
be used in image capturing but it boils down to looking at an image and observing the dependencies in
the image to create a caption.
For instance you have like a dog jumping over a fence and it's like a black dog on the floor or a white
fence.
So the model needs to understand is remember that there's a dog it's a black dog is a fence and then
put all together the dogs above the fences jumping over the fence.
So again we'll talk about this a bit more of the course.
But basically what happens is the the model is able to assess what's going on in the image and then
spit out a text transcription or caption.
And finally we have video captioning so it's very similar to the image of him and takes it to the next
level and here.
Not only do you have information interrelations inside each frame like in an image you actually have
certain certain information that you need to look at through all of the movies installations through
time so you need to see how the part is progressing.
What's happening with the characters and so on.
So that's video captioning you need to kind of understand the conversation between characters that are
conveyed properly.
You need to understand what was going on in the previous friends.
And that's they are models to the next level.
So there we go that's a 7 applications all the things that will be discussing and learning in this course.
And as we go along we will actually mention the application here and there to put it into perspective.
So our goal is not only to show you how to create chat boards and what models go into into them what's
intuition behind them but also to help you come up with other ideas of where you can put to use your
newly applies fields.
And I hope this gets even more excited about this course.
And let's dive into it and I'll see the next intro.