Hello and welcome back to Part 3.
Training the SEC the SEC motto in this quick toil we are going to define a tense session on which all
the of flow training will be run.
So to open a session intensive flow we're going to create an object of the interactive session class
and that object will be our session.
But before we create this object we need to reset the dense flow graphs to ensure that the graph is
ready for the training.
So in general when you open intense a closed session to do some training you have to reset the graph
first.
So we're going to start by doing this resetting the graph and to do this we need to take the tenths
of the library and then applied the reset default graph function which is a function by sense of flow
that resets the tens of Faludi for graph.
All right.
And now we can define a session and to define position as I said we have to create an object of the
interactive session class and therefore we have to introduce a new object here which we're going to
call session because this is going to be this tense session and to create this object.
We're going to take first detents library because the class is from the technical library and the name
of the class is as we said interactive session.
There we go with some parenthesis.
All right so we have defined a session.
That's a good thing done.
We will of course use it for the training and now and the next it's oil we're going to load the model
inputs using our function model input that we defined in part two when building the second PSEC model.
All right so let's define the session effectively by executing the code section and I'll see you in
the next tutorial to load the model inputs until then and Joji been I'll be.