All right let's set up the chat between us and the Chatswood.
So we're going to start with a while.
True which will set the interaction between the jabat and us until we apply the break.
So we're going to start by getting the question we'll be asking to our chat and this question will get
it by using the input function which will take as inputs what we want to enter in the console when we
ask a question to the Shadbolt and therefore I'm adding quote here you which will be you yourself with
a colon and a space to separate you and your question.
All right so that's the first step.
We get the question then we're directly going to make that break to stop the interaction when we want
to.
And we are going to start the interaction when we say goodbye to Richard but that is when our question
is goodbye and therefore I'm going to say now that if our question is equally equal to Goodbye like
that.
Well in that case we are going to break and this will stop this while loop.
All right then now that we take care of this we are going to take care of the real conversation between
the jackboot and us.
So the first thing we need to do is now that we got our question that we're entering the console we're
going to do all the process of getting the question in the right format so that it can go into the neural
network and so that we can get the predicted answer and therefore the first thing we need to do is well
first update our question this way by using the convert string to and function that takes as we define
here the question and the questions word to the dictionary.
All right.
That will convert the string of that question into the list of encoding integers.
Great.
So that's the first thing we must do then we need to apply the padding.
We need to make sure that this question has the same length as the questions that were used for the
training and the questions that were used for the training remember have a length of 20 and therefore
now we must complete the length of that question with enough tokens and more precisely PetroChina IDs
so that this question has an length of 20.
And to do this we'll first thing the question and updated this way by taking it again and then adding
since.
Now our question is illis we're going to do a list addition.
We're going to add to our question list the following list.
That is the list of the pet tokens that need to be added so that our question has a length of.
And to give this you know the trick.
We first take our questions words to the dictionary to get the unique integer encoding the token.
And therefore here are mentoring the key which is the bad token and then we are going to multiply this
list by the difference of 20 and the length of our question.
And that will complete it exactly by the number of better ideas that will make the question have a length
of 20.
All right then next step now that we have the single question in the right format.
Well remember the essential thing we need to do when working with neural networks it's the fact that
this question must be into a batch the neural networks only accept batches of inputs they only accept
input batches and since now this question is by itself we need to put it into a batch and we're actually
going to create a fake batch which will contain this question and then some empty questions that will
only get zeros.
And that's why now I'm introducing this fake batch variable that I'm going to initialize as a number
array of zeros and then zeros function we need to specify the dimensions of this vague batch and that's
the only argument that has to be a couple of two elements.
These two elements being the number of lines of this array and the number of columns of this array.
So the number of lines is going to be of course the batch size because each line corresponds to a question
and the number of columns is going to be.
Well of course 20 because our new one was trained with questions of length 20 you can actually change
that if you want.
All right so that initializes this big batch but then now we need to include our question in this fake
batch and to do this we will simply include it in the first row of this fake batch and therefore I'm
setting this first row this big batch of index 0 to be called to that question.
And now that we have our batch of input in the right format Well we're ready to feed that into the new
network to get the predicted answer the chat but that is the output of the neural network and this predictive
answer to get it we're going to use our session.
Then the run method which will take two arguments the first one is our test predictions variable that
we made in part to building the second PSEC model and then remember the second argument is a dictionary
of two sets of keys and values.
The first one is the inputs which are of course our batch of inputs which we called fake that and then
keep probability that remember we set it equal to 0.5 50 percent.
All right so that's exactly we'll return a list of several elements.
And the one that we're interested in that is the predicted answer is actually the first element of that
list and therefore we need to add here some square brackets and then inside the index 0 to get that
first element.
All right.
Perfect.
And now now that we get the predicted answer Well we are ready to prepare the output will get in the
council so we could directly get this predicted answer but we need to post precess it if I may say you
know we have to predict the answer but we must turn it into a clean format meaning that will replace
for example all the lower case i buy capital eyes.
You know when the Chulbul is saying for example I am I am not I do not.
Wherever we will also replace all the US tokens by Dud's because that corresponds to the end of a sentence
and therefore it should be a dud.
Will Replace all that out tokens that correspond to the filtered out words by simply ours and for the
rest of the elements in that particular answer which I remind are the unique integers in the dictionary
mapping the tokens to the integer IDs.
Well we'll simply return the token associated to that unique integer Plus a space so that in the answer
we can separate the different words by spaces.
All right so let's do this let's introduce the final answer with an empty string like that.
And then we're going to do a for loop to loop over.
So here I'm going to use a trick non-pay tricks and get a number here and then I'm going to use the
ARG max function that is going to take as arguments are predicted answer and the axes which is 1.
And basically what this will do is get the token IDs in the predicted answer.
So I'll provide the documentation for the MAX function by name by.
But what you need to understand here is that I'm going to take the values of the different token IDs
in the predicted answer.
All right.
And so now we're going to make the replacements I mentioned starting with the lower case that we're
going to replace by a capital I.
So if the answer is it's two word dictionary of key that is key the unique integer idea in the predicted
answer is equal to lower.
I won that case.
We're going to replace that by capital and therefore I'm going to introduce a new variable token that
will be equal to capital.
I then next thing we can catch and replaced by something nicer.
Well first we have to use Ilive same we're going to take our answers in two word dictionary.
And so if the token we're dealing with right now is the end of string.
So can well in that case we're going to replace that by a dot incorrupt perfect then I'm just going
to copy this because this is going to be the same.
All right.
So this time what do we want to take care of.
Well we said that out to Ken outspoken and in that case well we said that the term is going to be out
all right and that's it.
That's the main things that we're going to replace.
And we're going to finalize this with an else meaning that if we get any other token well in that case
we will simply replace that token by a space plus that token we just got which is answers in two words
of key I which will return the token.
All right so we got all the conditions and now we need to increment our answer which so far is an empty
string by the token and therefore I'm getting here my answer incrementally by the token I sew the different
tokens in the predicted answer.
Cleanthe by everything we did here will be added one by one to the final answer we'll get in the council.
Great.
And finally we need to add the very important last condition which will end this follow up and we will
end it by a break it's that if the token is a adult Well that means that we've reached the end of the
sequence because of this condition here.
You know the end is marked by the end of string and replace that by that.
Therefore if we get that then that means that it's the end of the chat.
But answer.
And in that case are shut but is done talking.
All right.
And finally let's not forget to print the checkbook answer and to do this will specify for us that it's
to chat but speaking so I'm adding Shadbolt here then a column and then a space to separate this Jack
but string by the answer of the Jedburgh.
And speaking of the answer of the checkbook.
That's exactly what we're at here with plus answer which is the answer we formed here by adding each
of these different tokens we can get by going through the different tokens of the predicted answer.
All right perfect so we're done with this code that will hopefully allow us to interact with a chaplain.
And now guys congratulations not only you reached the end of the whole implementation but also you were
ready to interact with a job.
So now I'm just going to get a little less excited because remember Archibald's was poorly trained.
I just trained it while sleeping for a few hours.
So Chad what needs to be much more trained than that and therefore what we're about to get here will
be a very poor conversation.
I will actually just say one thing you'll be convinced of the answer and you'll be convinced that of
course we need to train the chat.
But more and not only that I will also try to improve them all.
I will tweak the parameters.
I will try to improve the data preprocessing but I also encourage you to do that as well.
You can provide your ideas and your implementations in this course so that we can together find the
best chat.
But and speaking of the best.
But after the Statoil I will show you the best one ever made on her and now show you how to execute
it and chat with it in an extra toile.
But before we do that I'm of course going to show you what you need to execute here to chat with Chad.
But well that's simple.
That's basically everything except the training.
All right so we're simply going to execute everything from here up to the top.
There we go.
So it's going to take like 10 seconds but we're going to get basically all the building of the model
and all the data pre-processing variables that we made together.
All right.
And now there we go we are ready to select this whole section that has the whole code section of Port
for to interact with the chad.
But are you ready.
Let's do this.
All right.
So a few seconds and there we go you starting the conversation with the chad but so don't expect miracles.
It was only train for a few hours.
It's going to say total nonsense.
But remember I'm training the chad.
But on my other computer during the whole Christmas holidays I actually am going on holiday tomorrow
for Christmas and my computer is going to stay here spending Christmas with the chad.
But and after I come back I should have some better wait.
And of course based on the results I will try to improve them all.
All right so let's just say for example hi and to get the Jaggar answer you just need to press enter.
Oh my God.
And our Chad bird replied kicked cases.
Ladies have no idea what this means but as I told you this doesn't make any sense.
So I think we should stop here.
I don't really feel like talking to the Jaguar right now so I'll see you in the next tutorial where
I'll show you how to chat with this best bird.
And besides you have an amazing article explaining how the check book works and of course this is based
on a sex sex model with a lot of common things that we did in this implementation.
So you will have no problem understanding this model if you want to choose it over mine.
I won't be offended.
My role here is just to explain how things work but I'm not of course the best developer in the world.
And that's why I'm very happy to show you the best implementations the best but by the best developers.
So I'll see you in the next tutorial to show you this.
And until then enjoy I depend up the.