Hello and welcome back to the course on deep learning now that we know a bit more about LACMA and how
they work and what their architecture is like.
Today we're going to look at some practical applications or specifically we're going to look at how
Ellis DMD's work inside practical applications and really quite interesting and at the same time a big
magical I would say so let's get started here we've got the system architecture and we are going to
be to start if we're going to be looking at this tangent function and how it fires up.
So according to some of the images we're going to be using are all from Andray card party's blog.
So thank you very much to Andre for doing all of this amazing research so you can see here it's just
incredible so there got some examples where they created some bogusly in your algebra using trained
up LSD.
And then lots and lots of stuff.
So here these are the images we're going to be looking at just now.
These ones as well.
And there's lots of information here lots of comments so we check it out.
We'll link to these at the end of the tutorial.
This blog is called than reasonable effectiveness of recurrent neural networks.
And the paper that Andrii published along with that will also link to that paper as well.
So basically we're looking at the tangent function to start off with.
And according to the paper minus one means it's going to be red plus one is going to be blue.
So let's get started.
All right so here's some text which was given to an R N N which learned to read text and kind of create
tests and predict what text is coming.
And here this is a snippet from the.
War and Peace the huge novel by Tolstoy.
And so here you can see that this neuron is activating.
Well it is sensitive to as it says here sensitive to position in line so you can see that when you get
towards the end of the line it's activating and how does it know when it's the end of the line.
Well in this novel you have about 80 symbols per line approximately So it's counting how many symbols
have passed.
And that way it's trying to predict when the new line character is coming up because the new line newline
is just a character.
It's an invisible character and trying to predict where that character is going to appear.
Then you've got a cell that turns on inside quotes.
Well this is inside because I think it's actually outside quotes because here you see it says you mean
to imply that I have nothing to eat out of.
On the contrary I can supply.
So basically somebody is talking and then say warmly replied Chicago.
She shrugged.
Chicago.
Haven't read that in a long time.
Who tried to buy who tried by every word.
So basically this is the inside the quotes is outside the quotes.
I'm not sure if this is correct but either case one way or another it's activating either inside the
quotes or outside the quotes and you can see how this one is keeping track of what's happening and so
very similar to what we discussed previously where we were keeping track of the subject when that would
help us understand if the subject is male or female or we would be able to understand things like if
it's a singular or plural and that would affect all verbs in our translation.
Similar things so it's important to know if you're inside or outside of course because that affects
the rest of the text.
And for instance the easiest way you can think of that effective text that if you're inside the quotes
then there has to be another quote to close the quotes so you anticipating another quote something that
here's another one where the what the input was the code of the Linux operating system.
And here you can see that a cell activates inside if statement so it's completely dormant everywhere
else.
But as soon as you have an if statement it activates if statement activates if statement it activates
so and if it is active you can say it stops being active over here at the next actual body of the if
statement so it's only active for the main part or for the condition of the if statement and you know
that that can be important because you are anticipating that the condition is going to close off a bracket
and then it's going to be a bracket curly brace to open up the body of the if statement.
That's pretty cool and then here you've got another one where this sensitive cell is sensitive to how
deep you are inside of a nested expression.
So as you go deeper and you get the expression because more and more nested this cell keeps track of
that so it's using this memory to keep trying and it's very important to remember that.
And none of this is actually hard coded into the neural network.
All of this is learned by the network itself.
There are thousands and thousands thousands of iterations.
It learns that OK I have this many hidden states I have and out of them I need to identify what's important
in the text to keep track of and the identifies for instance in this case that it has.
That's being understanding how deep you are inside and that statement is important and therefore it's
a science.
A One of its hidden states to keep track of that is so it has these resources hidden States or the actual
memory cells and it assigns them to keep track of certain things based on what it thinks is important.
So it's like it's really evolving like that on its own and deciding what's important what's not and
how to allocate its resources to best complete the task.
I think that's very fascinating.
And then here's an example of a cell that you can't really understand what it's doing.
And according to drake or Pathi about 95 percent of the cells are like this.
They're doing something but it's just not not obvious to us what is happening.
And it's like that example of CNN's where the filters or the features that we're looking out for there
by the time they get to the last Lehre they are completely unrecognizable to the human eye.
But they make sense to the machine.
Same thing here.
So most of the time line of time you can really tell what's going on.
But those five some of the time those were the exam.
So we looked at and they should be helpful to better understand what is kind of going on in in the neural
network when it's processing for instance text.
So again now we're back at our architecture.
And now what we're going to be looking at is are we going to be looking at the actual outputs so we're
going to be looking at this value.
So after it's gone through the tangent or evolve or the output gate and now we're going to be looking
at what's being produced over here.
So here's an example again from car parties or undertake her panties blog and we're looking at a neural
network that is reading.
So this is a bit this is a bit more detailed so here it's not just showing us if it's active or not.
You can see that you've got at the top if it's active or not.
Every first line and then another five lines it is saying what's the neural network is predicting that's
going to happen next.
What the letter is going to come next what symbols are going to come next.
So you've got the combination of the two here.
And just by looking at this what what do you think is predicting.
So I'm going to I'm going to like outline the colors green means for the top line.
Green means active and blue means not active and red means a very likely prediction and lighted means
like prediction.
So let's talk about the top line.
What do you think this specific hidden state in the neural network is looking out for when do you think
it's being activated.
Well I guess this one is pretty obvious.
It's activating inside your else.
So here you can see that inside w w w the hidden state is B is being activated just like we saw in the
previous examples foran piece and the Linux kernel.
Here you can see that it's been activated inside your house.
But now we have some additional stuff to look at.
Now we can see what it's actually predicting that's going to be next character.
So for instance under this w you can see that it's predicting that the next character is going to be
a W of the highest probability and it's correct.
It is doubly that under this bill you can see that predicting another W and it is correct.
And then under this w the whole this is what the whole neural network is predicting.
Under this w what you're seeing is a dot and that is correct.
It is predicted.
So that's that's how it's gone up to here and then after this dot if it thinks the next letter letter
will be a B.
But it's actual.
But now knowing that it's a why it thinks they're going to be in a now knowing it's an A and B.
And you can see that these are less.
These are not as red as these because it's not sure about this.
That's fair enough.
It could be absolutely any website.
Why would it be a B.
Could be any upside can't.
You can't tell.
Maybe it could.
Based on the context but still it's very hard.
But then when it gets to wide net new and E.W. it predicts and as if a very high likelihood and it is
indeed an ass because it kind of knows that the word after you have new very likely you will have an
s or based on everything it's learned before that in this particular type of text it's news is mentioned
quite often because this is actually as far as I understand this is Wikipedia text and then you have
a dot then after dot.
It predicts this.
See it is a C after a c prefix and oh it's an O After all pricks and it is an M and a slash and a slash.
So beautiful.
So and then it's done its job and it's not active anymore.
And then this is what but this is what the neuron that we're looking at is not active on anymore but
the neural network is still predicting things.
So here we can see then.
And so it's incorrect.
And then after the and after that is incorrect at the end.
So after he has eaten it predicts a G it's a G and then it's becomes more confident that it's a word.
English language you can see that the predictions become more confident so after the L it didn't predict
correctly but after the L.A. It's already predicting and G and so on and so on so on so it can actually
predict the whole word based on just a few first letters website on and so on to see the actual neurons
still dormant still dormant.
And then here you've got again off we go W.W. is predicting.
And this one is getting activated.
This one was pretty interesting because it goes see oh and then present and but it's not an M it's a
dot and it's like the neural network or this is the neural network is probably a bit upset at this stage
thinking Whoa Where's my M.
And then then it takes another shot it says OK.
So probably you because that code that you k that's that's UK websites.
But here instead of you it's got an eye and an L for Israel that code i l and therefore is kind of like
didn't guess this then but it probably is.
It's not even trying to guess because he's already been trying to guess and I because from what it's
learned that called that you k are made much more likely to come up than dot co.
I l and we're not even looking at these other ones here which you could look at them.
They are you know the second best guess a third best guess fourth and fifth which you can see that they
are not that red.
And what it would it will always put the highest likeliest guess at the top on the second line overall.
So there we go this is how to look at these pictures that Andray has created.
And for more check out his blog Carpathian get harder.
I know there's a couple more of these examples there and more of the previous examples I looked at.
And so hopefully this is helpful to show you what's going on inside the neural network when it's when
it's thinking and when it's processing information in terms of references and additional reading we've
got Andre her party blog and we'll link to it in the resources for this course.
This is this is your L otherwise.
And also we've got and raker Party and others research paper which was published in 2015 it's called
visualizing and understanding recurrent networks.
Very interesting read actually because like you if you're there's not too much math then you can probably
skip it.
But even the insights parts and chapters are very interesting they make you kind of feel that the.
And they say this in the paper that they like.
Neuroscientists trying to understand what's going on so they open up the brain of the neural network
and monitor what's happening in one specific neuron or other different or different neurons.
And you actually feel from the language the way that it's written that it's as if they're exploring
some alien as if they're exploring some kind of extraterrestrial being and how it thinks.
Because if you think about it humans created these LSD atoms and are and and these are just things that
work on our computers but because they are so advanced because they involve so many different elements
so many different parts to them and they're so complex we now need to after we've created them now we
need to study them as if they're separate beings separate something something that exists on its own
and it's just reading through it's kind of like if you think of it that way gives you this mysterious
feeling or magic if you feel like it's something magical is happening and sometimes you feel that a
few more years or maybe a decade from now these things are going to be able to think completely on their
own.
So if if you want to have some fun reading a research paper this one's pretty cool I think maybe you
know you don't have to read the math skip the math.
I didn't I didn't really dig into the math myself.
Yeah so that's pretty much it.
Hope you enjoyed today's tutorial and hopefully that gives you a bit of a better understanding of how
the architecture actually plays out in practice.
And I look forward to seeing you next then.
Until then enjoy deep learning.