Hello and welcome back to the course on the deep natural language processing.
And today we're finally talking about this sequence to sequence model and we're going to be discussing
its architecture.
All right so where did we stop last time.
Last time we stopped here where we were talking about the bag of words moral.
And as you can see here on the right we've got our bag and we discussed that there's two at least two
ways that you can go about it once you've got your 20000 elements long representations all of your sentences
or emails and you have all this training data you can fit it into a non deep learning model such as
the logistic regression and that will give you an algorithm over here or you can fit into a neural network
meaning a deep learning algorithm deeper and model and that will give you a deep natural language processing
model over here so both a bag of words but different types of bags of words.
And we said that there was at least one drawback one limitation and that is that this approach just
gives you a yes no response yes no type of response it's a good start.
But at the same time it's not going to get very far if you're trying to build the child but you want
to chat to people not just say yes or no to any kind of question or sentence.
They're saying you want to have a meaningful conversation so let's have a look at some of the other
limitations.
Issues with that bag of words model that are that make it undesirable for a chat board for a chat but
Project Number one is a fixed sized input.
So if we go back here you'll see that every single time we have to have the same type of inputs same
same level of input for this training to go well because on one hand if we get into a logistic regression
we want to be sure that the features are in the right columns in the right places and then among the
training data and the test or the verification data or with the actual data that we want to get a result
for.
So that's a limitation as that's why we have the 20000 that long or longer has that little limit that
size and also the input layer for the neural networks same thing you get like a certain number of neurons
you got to fit in the right words in the right spots into this neural network.
You can mix them up you can have a different size in order for it to work.
So that's a limitation fixed size impose a second limitation it doesn't take word order into account.
Interesting.
So what does that mean.
Well if we look back jumping back to this slide we here if we look back over here you'll notice that
we're just counting each occurrence of each word rather than looking at not just occurrences but also
where they are placed.
So for instance if you jumble up this this jumble up this email all the words in this email you will
still have the same representation.
And like we all know we all know that if we change our own words in a sentence they can change the meaning.
For instance let's say
for example is the cat shorter than the dog.
Right that's one sentence.
And the answer might be yes.
Usually cats are short and dogs and let's say we have an example that a cat is is cat shorter than the
dog.
If you just change the cat and the dog has two words around and becomes is the dog shorter than the
cat.
Exactly same words completely opposite meaning of the answer in that case would be no.
And so you can come up with examples where if you jumble up text in the emails words and emails even
though the representation will be the same your answer would have changed from yes to no.
But the model is going to get you the same answer.
So that's a significant limitation that basically what's happening is loss of information we're losing
information through the bag of words moral just the way it's constructed because we're not taking into
account the position of the words to fix as input.
It doesn't take word ordering takeout.
And the third one is what we talked about already fixed size output in this case is just one word yes
or no.
But basically that's not only yes and all we could come up with for more like a longer outputs may have
multiple words but it won't be variable.
That's that's kind of like even an even stronger statement that we don't just want we don't we just
want yes no.
Like even if we have more options and yes now we might have like five options or something like that
or they might be might be longer.
But what we want is we want variable sized outputs so depending on what we were asked we want to be
able to say a sentence or maybe five words or 50 words should be totally up to us.
The model should be flexible to give out a response not just limited to whatever number of words it
can be like a short response can be a long response just like as humans when we talk we don't limit
ourselves to we have to answer with five words so we have to answer with 10 words.
It has to be variable.
So those are the main limitations of size.
Input doesn't take world order into account and fixed sized outputs stations of that bag of words model.
So the question is What are we going to do.
How are we going to solve this puzzle.
And overcome all these limitations.
And the answer is our and thence recurrent neural networks.
So if you haven't had a look at that annex for this course on artificial neural networks and recurrent
neural networks now would be a great time to look at it and get into this space understand what recurrent
neural networks are and how they work what they're constructed of different types and so on.
What back propagation is to cast a gradient descent.
And so there's lots and lots of concepts that are going to be assumed going forward but that you are
up to date with them.
You know what what they are in the future.
Tauriel starting from now.
And further down in this course.
So if you haven't looked at the Alecs higher command to stop this video now and look at that Alex but
otherwise let's proceed.
All right.
So this is like if you've seen that X for the recurrent neural networks this is what Andrey Karpovsky
has come up with in his log on to get help of the different types of recurrent old network architectures
that you can and just a reminder recurrent neural networks here.
Every single box is not actually one cell it's actually a whole layer of neurons a whole layer of neurons
are presented by every single box just that here what we're looking at is unraveled neural network and
unravel time a loop of the recurrent neural network.
So this is the neural network feeding into itself through time like each one is different of course
but it's feeding itself into itself through time but if you look at it like from the top actually here
like it's going into the image you've got a whole layer of you know it's like a three dimensional image
that's why you can see it.
That's the way I imagine it.
We've got a whole layer whole layer everywhere is a layer of neurons.
So one way is like layer layer layer.
Another one is OK so layer one layer and then one too many so that they actually have titles and top
many to one.
So you have many.
And then you come one you have many many many too many this way.
So right away just based on what we're trying to build here we want we want a variable sized input and
a variable sized output.
So one to one would it work for us one too many would work for us.
Because we have we don't have just one word as an input.
So we're going to be actually going to put words into each cell and it will make sense as we go along.
It will make sense how this works.
But for now the way we're going to look at it so this one won't work this whole will work is always
work because it's just one on one.
We want more like this is kind of like if we have a yes no response this could work for us but we want
more than one.
So we're left with one of these two options.
Your own network with many many like this are made to you.
And the one we're going to go with is this one.
And the reason for that is because we not necessarily will have always the same size inputs and the
same size outputs.
So if somebody asks us a question or five words the we will have five words and that's so that's why
it was a terrible terrible terrible input and output but they might be different.
So that's like a short ex-lawyers into what's what type of neural network architecture we're going to
be aiming for.
It's going to be that way.
But now let's jump back to our text and we'll make much more sense from there.
So there's our 20000 element long vector which we use for the bag of words and we're going to just throw
it away because we don't need it.
In fact we're actually going to shorten the sentence.
It's not it's not something that's part of the algorithm of course we can work with any slam sentences
and emails and so on.
But just for simplicity's sake for us to look at look at the whole picture and be able to grasp it.
We're going to shorten it.
And that's just for educational purposes.
Again this whole this algorithm works for any live question or email or chat whatever we're creating.
And so yeah.
So what are we going to do is we're going to take these words each single word including the comma and
full stop and we're going to code them.
So we're going to create a different picture.
This time it's not 20000 symbols.
It's just going to have Word.
So like one way to create it is we take those you know from that big vector of 20000.
We just take the position of every word so say hello or was in position 5 so we're going to put a 5
here.
Carol doesn't have a position that 20000 vectors so going to put a zero because one of those non-English
words comma position 9.
So we're going to put a nine checking into instead of counting the recurrence of every word.
We're creating a vector which is as long as our vector as long as our sentence plus and a start of sentence
here is our senses end of sentence at the beginning and they as we remember they have reserve numbers.
So this was always going to be one this was always going to be two.
And then for every element we just replacing the word with the actual numerical version of the word
the number that's the position that's associated with that.
So like for instance if you had two of the same words like if we had if and if you'd have a seven and
another seven or you had like a comma and another column we would have a nine and another night.
So that's totally fine.
And that this is how we construct intersect.
And so as you can see there's the size the length of this vector will depend on how many words we have
in our email how long our email is.