Highs and welcome to this new tutorial.
All right now we're going to start the whole process of removing the nuns so much frequent word of our
corpus and we want to do that because we want to optimize the training and optimize the training we
need the essential words of the vocabulary.
So we're going to remove the words that appear from time to time less than 5 percent actually of the
whole corpus.
And the first step of this new process of removing the non-African word is to create a dictionary that
is going to map each word to its number of occupancies.
That seems natural we first need to get all the words separately and for each of these words we get
the number of and so that is the number of times they appear in the corpus of movie dialups.
So that's what we're going to do in this story or we're going to create that dictionary and they start
right now.
So to create a dictionary you know how to do it we first need to choose a name for that and we want
to set everything as clear as possible.
So we're going to call that dictionary word to count because it maps each word to how many times this
word appears there is a count of this word a word to count.
And now we need to initialize it with a pair of brackets.
And now we are ready to start the for loop to get all the different words and get their number of occupancies.
So we have two separate lists.
Now we have two clean questions and the clean answers.
And so basically we're going to get the words from both these lists and for each of the word we're going
to count how many times they appear.
So let's start with the questions we start with a for loop for question.
In clean questions of course.
Right now we're dealing with the clean questions.
CONAN And now let's go inside the.
So I remind that clean questions is a huge list containing all the questions.
Now what we have to do is go through all the questions in this clean questions huge list and for each
of these questions we're going to get their words.
So now we need to make a second for loop that will go through all the words of the question.
All right.
So second for loop here for and therefore this time it's going to be word in question all right and
then to get the words themselves we can add that split here so that we can get the words directly.
So if you were question that split Collon And now let's do what we want to do and what you want to do
is now count the number of times this word appears when we go through all the questions of the clean
questions list.
OK.
So right now we're dealing with a specific word in a specific question.
So for this word either it's the first time we see it or we've already seen it and therefore we need
to increment the count of this word.
And therefore I'm going to make an IF condition here to separate these two cases whether we see that
word for the first time or we've seen it already.
So I'm going to start with if.
If we see that word for the first time and to express this in code we can say if word if the word not
in our dictionary which we called Word to count.
Well if this word is not in word to count then what happens.
Well this word is going to get his first arguments.
We're going to count it once and therefore now we're going to take our dictionary word to count then
we need to enter the key which is the word because now make sure to understand that the key identifier
are the words and the values are the number of arguments says of these words.
And so the value for this word we're dealing with right now and that we see for the first time appearing
in the questions of the king questions.
Well that value is going to be one because it's the first time we see it.
But then other games if this is not the first time we see this word in a question well we can express
it with else because this is complimentary else and in that case what we need to do is increment the
count of this word increment the number of occupancies because we've already seen it before and therefore
we need to increment its number of Ah-Q answers.
And so what we can simply do.
I'm going to copy this because the way to increment in Python is pretty practical.
We just need to add here plus equals plus equals one that is equivalent to word to count word equals
word to count word plus 1.
So we increment it perfect.
So that's it was this double for loop here we count for each word appearing in all the questions of
the clean questions huge list the number of utterances of these words and now we're going to do the
same for the answers because there are some other words in the answers.
But good news it's going to be almost the same.
I'm going to copy this for loop here.
Pasted below.
And now we simply need to place a question by answer very simply it's the same logic.
So there we go.
Let's do that quickly.
Answer.
Clean answers.
For word in answer that split if were not in word to count that's the same we used the same dictionary
word to word word and word perfect.
See done.
Wonderful.
Perfect.
So now let's execute these lines.
This code section to create this dictionary.
It's going to take a while because well no not that long because we go through all the words of all
the questions and all the answers but there we go.
That's done.
We have this dictionary created which will be very useful for us to remove the words that are below
a certain threshold of frequency.
That was the first step.
Now we're going to move onto the next step which will be to actually choose this threshold and then
count the number of words that appear more than the chosen threshold and we will do that in the next
tutorial and so then and Jaideep an anti.