Hello and welcome to the final round of this part to building the sector model we now have all the tools
that we just need to assemble to build this final set to set moral.
And that's exactly what we're going to do.
And this is oil we will just use the previous tools we made like first of all of course the encoder
Arnon which is the first main part of the SEC to sec then the decoder Arnon which is the second main
part of the SEC to Sec.
And as we made things to these two functions here dico turning set and Dakotah set which we want to
have to use again because these were just used to make the decoder Arnon the decoder record new in that
work.
So basically we will just assemble these two and could Arnon and decoder Arnon and that will be our
final round for this part to building the same model.
So let's do it let's make this final function that we're going to call sec 2 sec underscore morrow.
All right.
It's the final ultimatum model that we will chat with during our testing phase in part 4.
Basically you got it.
That's the brain of our checkbook.
All right so this brain is going to take several arguments.
The first one is going to be the inputs which are of course the questions of the Cornell movie corpus
Dyalog data set and after the training these inputs will be of course the questions we'll ask to the
chair.
But when we check with it so input then target.
So that's of course the answers the real answer is that we have.
Because in our Cornell movie corpus Dyalog data set we have the real answers of the questions and from
which we will train the child to speak.
So that target.
And then we have all our other arguments that we've used before.
So the third one is keep prob.
Then we have the batch size of course.
We're working with patches as always with deep learning then sequence underscore length sequence length
then we're going to get our answers none words which is the total number of words in all the answers.
That's like our previous argument that we used before words here but this time since we're going to
use both the total number of words of the answers and the questions I'm specifying answers here and
in the next argument actually I'm going to specify the questions underscore no underscore words.
That's another argument answers words and questions.
Non-words.
All right then what do we have.
Then we have the and Khoder and bearing size.
And that's the number of dimensions of the embedding matrix for the anchor.
And then of course we'll have also the decoder and this core embedding and this core size which is this
time the number of dimensions of the embedding matrix of the decoder.
All right then we have of course the Arnon size which we used before.
Then the number of layers in our decoder cell containing the stacked LSD with dropout applied non-players
and then almost done we have a final argument to input and that's our questions.
Word 2 and dictionary are questions words too in dictionary which we'll use to preprocess the targets.
Remember if we have a look again at our preprocess target function right here.
Pre-process targets.
Well it takes where to end.
As one of the argument which is the dictionary.
And so the dictionary will use here will be questions words to it.
All right.
So we are done with the arguments that was the last one here questions words to end so let's add a colon
here and then let's go inside the function.
So this function is supposed to return in the end the training predictions and the test predictions.
That's basically what we've returned before.
But we want all in one package which is the sectors like model that will return at the same time the
training predictions and the test predictions.
And therefore that's why the best word to describe what we're doing right now is some blush like the
French word.
We're going to assemble the inquiry that returns the inkers date and the dickered returns the training
predictions and the test predictions.
But we also need to encourage Of course because in order for the decoder to return the training predictions
and test predictions it needs to take as input the encoder States returned by the encoder.
And that's why we need those two networks here.
And we actually need to start Of course with the encoder.
But before we get in good state we need the encoder embedded input and that's why the first thing we
have to do here is to introduce the encoder and embedded input.
We've already seen this very well and this are embedded in pursuit and again I will put the resource
for you to see how it works.
We're going to get it from the MBRD sequence by the layers module of the terms of the library.
I'll put that in the resource and therefore I'm going to do now is take for us tens of flow T.F. then
country of course as usual.
And then from country I'm getting this layer's module and from the sloes module I'm getting the MBRD
underscore sequence which will return the embedded input of the anchor and this and that sequence function
takes several arguments.
The first one is our inputs.
Of course that's the inputs we actually want to embed.
So that's of course one of the argument then the next argument is going to be the total number of words
of the answers so that answers none words.
And then we need to add a plus one because the upper bound in the sequence is excluded.
So answers words plus one.
Then the next argument is going to be the encoder and the ring size which I remind is number of dimensions
in the embedding matrix at the Inquirer.
So in Currumbin in size then next one that's going to be the initialiser which is going to be a random
uniform initialiser.
And to get it we are actually going to use tens of flow from tens of so we're going to get the random
uniform initialiser function and this function takes two arguments argument the bounds of these random
numbers we want to get based on a uniform distribution and these bands are going to be from zero to
1.
All right.
So we've got our initialiser and that's it.
That will give us the and color embedded in it.
So again if you want more details on this and that sequence in its arguments check out the resources
of this lecture.
Perfect.
Now let's move on to the next step which is to get our anchors to act.
I remind that the anchoring state is what is returned by the Inquirer.
That is the output of the anchor and what will become the input of the decoder.
So that's the natural next step to get the output of the encoder and we can actually get this output
the anchor state thanks to our embedded input.
So let's get it and coner state which we will get from of course the record and neural network of our
anchor.
We're going to feed the record neural network of our encoder with the encoder embedded input and it
will return the anchoring state which will then become the input of the Ticker.
So when girls date then we get our encoder underscore Arnon the record renewal network of the encoder
which is a function we defined previously and that function takes several arguments.
The first one is of course well our anchor embedded input.
That's basically the input could embedded in the right format to be accepted by the neural network and
embed an input and then a couple of other arguments.
The Arnon size the number of layers then they keep drub because of course in the uncurl we have the
inkers cell which is stacked LACMA with out applied.
So we have to include this key prob parameter that can the dropout rate keep prob..
And now one final argument in this could go on and function can have a look at the function made again.
But if you remember well the final argument is sequence underscore length.
All right.
Now we got our encoder state which is the output of our encoder record renewal network.
And now that we have the increased data we are ready to get to our final predictions the training predictions
and the test predictions.
But before that we need to get first the pre-processed target because we will need them for the training.
We also need to get the decoder embeddings matrix which is the embeddings matrix of the decoder.
And that will be used to get Deaker embedded input and then that's where we'll be fully ready to apply
to decode the Arnon function which represents the regular neural network of the decoder to get the final
training predictions and test predictions.
All right so let's get all these before we take our Dr. Arnon.
Everything we need together here is our free throw.
C'est targets.
That is our target.
Pre-process the right way to later on in the training.
Use it to back propagate the last between the politicians and the target.
So preprocess targets and these.
Well remember we made a function for that which we called prae pro sess targets and this function takes
several arguments.
The first one is of course our target because that's what we want to preprocess so targets then to preprocess
these targets.
Remember I showed that to you at the beginning of the tutorial we need two questions words in dictionary
so that our second argument word two in dictionary questions words to end and eventually the batch size.
All right so now we have our preprocess targets.
Perfect.
Now what we need is the decoder embeddings matrix the embeddings matrix of the decoder.
And so I'm introducing here this new variable decoder and beddings matrix which we will get by creating
a sense of flow variable.
So voidable is a class and therefore the decoder embeddings matrix will be an object of this variable
class and this variable class takes several arguments which are going to be mostly the dimensions of
this embedding matrix.
So remember how the embeddings matrix works well you have basically all the words in lines and then
in comes you have the embedding values.
So since the number of lines corresponds to the total number of words in the whole corpus.
Well this number of lines is going to be the questions no words.
That is total number of words of the questions and again we need to add a plus one.
And then for the number of columns the second dimension.
Well it's going to be one of the arguments of this sector segmental function which is the decoder amening
size the amening size of the decoder.
So basically you can have several sizes for the embeddings that is several number of columns and that
is determined by the embedding size.
And so right now what we have to do in this variable is initialized this matrix not only setting the
dimensions but also fill it with random numbers taken from a uniform distribution just to initialize
it and then it will be of course populated with learning numbers that will participate into the training
of the chat.
But to speak like a human but at the beginning we have to initialize it with random numbers taken from
a uniform distribution and to get these random numbers taken from that uniform distribution.
We're going to use of flow of course and then the random uniform function random uniform function which
will take as arguments the dimension of this matrix and the dimension of this matrix will have to enter
them in square brackets.
So as we said the number of lines is going to be the total number of words in the questions because
each line correspond to a token a questions word and therefore the number of lines is going to be here.
Questions not words.
And as we said plus one questions words plus one.
All right.
That's the number of lines.
The first time in Sion.
And then for the second dimension that's the embedding size which is one of our arguments and that's
of course for the record.
So we'll get the decoder embedding size.
Great.
And so now we get out of the square brackets.
We're done with the diamond JONES But we need to add two more arguments which are going to be the lower
bound in the upper bound of those random numbers that we're filling this matrix with.
And so we're going to fill this matrix with random numbers from 0 to 1.
And all these random numbers will be taken from a uniform distribution and that's it that initializes
the embeddings matrix of the decoder with random numbers between 0 and 1 taken from a uniform distribution.
Great.
Now we're ready to move on to the next step and the next step is naturally to use this decoder embeddings
matrix to get that decoder embedded input.
We're actually going to get these inputs.
Thanks to the embeddings matrix.
And so let's introduce this new variable decoder embedded input.
And we're going to get these inputs from a function by sense of flow which is taken from the end module
and the name of this function taken from the in a module is and then look up that's the function imbedding
look up and this and then in Look-Up is of course going to take as input.
The decoder embeddings matrix.
So I'm going to copy that to avoid any typo.
Copy.
And that's going to be our first argument in this embedding lookup function.
All right.
And then the second argument that this embedding Look-Up is going to need is of course the pre-processed
target because in order to get our decoder embedded input we need to pre-processed targets as they are
the answers to the questions.
So let's do it let's add the second argument pre pro SEST underscore targets and there we go.
We now get our decoder embedded input which means we are ready to get the training predictions and the
test predictions.
And the reason for this is that we have everything we need to apply the decoder arland function.
That is we have everything we need to feed the Recker a neural network of the decoder.
And therefore now we're going to get our two ultimate variables that will be returned which are our
training predictions and art test predictions are training predictions and our desperations which are
respectively the predictions of the observations used for the training and the predictions of new observations
that won't be used for the training.
And that will either be used for cross-validation to test the predictive power of the model on new observations
that won't be used to train the model more or some new predictions just to chat with the chad.
But all right so make sure you understand the difference between these two predictions.
And so now we're going to use our decoder because we have all the inputs we need to feed the doctors
who were ready to get the output of the decoder and therefore we were ready to get the decoder and then
the decoder record.
Neural Network.
And so now very easily We're going to just input all the arguments of this Daker Island function that
we made.
Starting with the decoder and bedded input that we just prepared here thanks to the record and beddings
matrix.
So decoder embedded input then next argument that's going can be actually the decoder embeddings matrix
then we're going to need of course the encoder state because this is actually the output of the anchor
that becomes the input of the decoder.
And so let's get it and color state.
All right the next argument is going to be the total number of words of the questions which we get with
the questions number words argument.
Then we're going to need the sequence lengths and after that the Arnon size then the number of layers
in the.
LS then are questions words 2 and dictionary then are.
Keep drub parameter controlling dropout rate.
And eventually last but not least the batch size all right and congratulations for your very last step
of this part to building the sectors like moral.
It's of course to return the training predictions and the test predictions are right.
Congratulations you completed part to building the sectors like morrow.
So now your child has a brain.
It's time to train it.
We'll do that in part three.
Training the SEC to say moral.
I can't wait to start.
I can't wait to teach our children how to speak.
Now that it has a brain and will do that starting from the next tutorial and now I'm going to close
this part two on a good note.
I am going to get our set to sec moral.
Here is your brain.
Time to train it.
And until then I depend on.