Estimation, velocity,
and timeboxing are three critical concepts that need to first be
understood before we dive into release planning and,
in particular, iteration or sprint planning.
I will be referring to these topics later in this module as I show
you examples of release and sprint planning.
To be clear, solid estimating skills are vital to the Agile team's productivity,
reliability, and predictability.
Reliable estimates enable a team to predict how much value
can be delivered in a certain time period,
such as a release or iteration.
Predictability enables reliable delivery.
So if an Agile team can reliably predict what it can do in a timebox,
then the team can more reliably predict what it might be able
to deliver over several timebox sprints,
or iterations, or releases, or for that matter,
an entire project.
Yes, estimation is critical.
Now let's see how quality estimation adds value to the
release in sprint planning process.
The time it takes your team to make estimates may seem
like overhead or non- value added work.
On the contrary.
Estimating provides considerable value for several reasons.
One, determining cost.
That is how much effort or resources will it take.
Two, establishing prioritization.
Estimates are used to support the prioritization process and thus
contributes to delivering value to the business.
And three, scheduling and commitment.
The ability to commit to near-term deliverables.
For example,
backlog items in an iteration or sprint is the key to building a reliable,
agile environment.
Now in order to estimate, you need a unit of measure.
Here are a few options.
Ideal days, in other words, how long would it take you,
and only you, with no interruptions to get something done,
and you have all the tools or whatever you need fully available.
Ideal hours are just like ideal days, except hours with no interruptions,
and again, all the tools and support you need is available.
Another unit of measure is story points.
They are quite common and recommended.
Story points are a unit of measure for expressing the
overall size of an effort of a user story,
feature, or task.
The number of story points chosen is influenced by complexity,
uncertainty, risk, volume, and work.
And plus,
they're very personal to you and your perception of what it would take to go do.
Now everyone understands hours,
so it may be easier to start with a unit of measure of hours since
story points can take a little time to get used to.
So use a model that everyone understands,
seems easy to apply, and try and use throughout the project.
But if the story point scale does not seem to be working,
then, by all means, change it.
Remember, we are agile.
Now let's look at some choices for story points.
First, determine the story point model your team will use throughout the project.
Those choices could be simple story points that people just
think of and conceive their own relative values.
Typical agile estimating uses abstract values,
which are based on a scale to determine relative values.
For example, an exponential scale begins at 0, 1, 2, 4, 8, 16, 32, 64, 128.
So those are the only potential values in estimating a story's number of points.
Or maybe a Fibonacci scale: 0, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 20, 40, 100.
Again, those are the only potential value in estimating a story's points.
Estimates are relative to you and not the full team.
They are what you believe is your interpretation of abstract effort.
We will talk more about story points later in the module. Next, how many story points can your team deliver?