Here are some simple guidelines for creating good release plans.
Flush out your release plan by using your product vision as your guide.
Plan about two releases in the future or so.
You are not planning all of your releases perfectly since you
don't know how many you'll really have.
Remember, we are Agile, not Waterfall.
Include the features that'll make up your minimum viable product,
MVP, per release, and please, just the minimum you need.
A minimum viable product is a development technique in which a new product is
developed with sufficient features to satisfy early adopters.
Not all users need all things on day one.
Now with the team, develop high-level estimates,
and use those estimates as guideposts to refine their priorities.
For example,
if a high-priority item was estimated at a much higher
estimate than originally believed,
it may drop down in the list based on budgets and schedules.
As necessary, decompose features, epics,
and large user stories into user stories that follow the INVEST
template that we described in the previous module.
And also, we will go into detail about user stories later in this module.
Here is a good guide to keep in mind when performing
release and iteration sprint planning.
Focus on high value lower-cost features and stories first.
Now let's see how we might want the layout of the release backlog.
Now here's a very simple release plan as an example.
We set up a simple grid.
First is release 1 of our MVP, minimal viable product.
Next is release 2, or 2-ish as I call it,
since maybe these features may change based on the sprint results of release 1.
Then we can place some of our ideas in the next column,
you know, features and things that might be coming downstream.
And lastly, more like a parking lot of ideas, features, and user stories.
Basically,
what we are doing is spreading out the backlog of features out into a timeline.
Please note,
this timeline of features may change at any time by the product owner typically,
but also by the Agile team based on velocity,
deeper understanding of user stories, and other issues.
Now, in release 1,
the product owner stated you just can't go live without these three features,
so we placed them here and put some features in release 2 as well.
Now here are the features for release ideas,
if you will,
and I used blue Post-its to more easily recognize their
significance different from release 1 and 2.
And lastly, at this time of our planning,
these things are kind of way out there, so I used green as an example.
To recap,
features are placed by priority left to right using high-level estimates.
Don't spend too much time here,
and try timeboxing your discussions to conserve time.
Your discussions should always consider highest value to
business with the lowest cost first.
Agile is iterative and incremental,
so these choices are all subject to change when we do
release planning and sprint planning.
All Agile planning is a dynamic activity.
Now let's look a little closer at one of these Post-its.
Now let's zoom in on a couple of our feature Post-its.
As the project progresses,
you will define and populate attributes for each feature,
such as story points, priority, etc.
So in this example for feature 1,
I have shown in the lower-left corner in yellow a rough estimate in story
points and in the right corner a purple icon with a priority.
Easy to see, easy to identify.
Notice the story point estimate is followed by a question mark.
That means I'm unsure,
and we need to decompose into smaller features or user stories.
You can make up any nomenclature that works for you.
Now in this example, it is 18 story points with medium priority.
As we discussed in the previous module,
you can define a variety of attributes to help you
make better planning decisions.
Hopefully by using a system such as Jira,
for example, you can easily track all of your features and their attributes,
which will enable you to refine your backlog and
improve release and sprint planning.
Now for a point of view.
Here are my thoughts on release planning.
Depth of release planning may vary based on the team and
nature of the features and stories.
I prefer to keep it very lightweight and high level and add
more effort in the sprint planning activities.
How many releases do you plan?
I would suggest two pretty solid ones,
and then the rest of the features and stories are in your backlog,
and at the next release planning meeting you can
solidify the next release even better.
Do you even need releases?
I have seen some organizations where they only have sprints and do
not group up several sprints into a release.
I recommend for larger projects you do use releases.
And for smaller ones, maybe the extra release layer,
if you will, is not necessary.
Can't decide?
Well, be agile.
Adapt to what works for you.
Try using releases, and then if it's too much overhead, then only do sprints.
But each sprint is treated like a release, of course.
Flexible planning over rigid planning.
Through reviews and retrospectives,
the team reflects on how to become more effective,
then tunes and adjusts its behavior accordingly.
Customers though want to know more.
You can't just say that you're agile and be patient.
You must have good, long-range planning skills and data such as delivery dates,
and by using your product roadmap or release schedule,
you can provide expected dates.
Budgets and costs.
Not only will some customers want to know how much remaining budget is required,
but what was the cost of what was already delivered and received.
Staffing or other resources.
Resources are always limited in companies,
so they may question the resources you are using and for
how much longer do you need them for.
So,
I'm a believer in releases because they help kind of collect up and package
information and what you're trying to do over the longer run,
which many times executives are more interested in.
How much is coming and when?
What's the rough schedule?
What's the cost and resources that are going to be needed? Alright, now let's tackle sprint planning.