What is technical debt?
It is the total amount of less than perfect design and coding in your solution.
We all start out by writing the best code we can,
but based on skills, requirements, and other situations,
our code will not be perfect.
Now let's see how it ends up in our solutions.
Now let's talk about where technical debt comes from.
Many times,
you need to make some last minute enhancements to
get something changed right away.
So you solve the immediate problem,
but in a sense potentially created a longer-term
problem with less than perfect code.
Quick and dirty bug fixes to get something changed right away,
and again, potentially leaving behind some technical debt.
Development practices that have not proved their worth,
like an API that continues to degrade in performance or where
an initial design worked great and over time it just doesn't
hold up to the newer requirements.
Left unchecked,
technical debt can grow and grow to ultimately overwhelm your solution.
Technical debt can propagate bugs over time.
When you have some not so good code,
sometimes it is hard to write good elegant code around it,
so it just makes matters worse over time.
Technical debt is not avoidable.
It will happen.
It is just part of the life of an application development project.
So don't feel bad it you have it, but you need to keep an eye on it,
and let's see how.
Now let's see how we could reduce technical debt.
Technical debt cannot be totally eliminated.
That is certainly a nice goal, but focus on reducing it.
So continuous code maintenance and refactoring in each sprint will
get you a long way in reducing technical debt.
So add technical debt to your backlog with estimates and how these
backlog items will provide value to the customer.
Value is not just delivering a feature,
but delivering the feature with a desired user experience
and with acceptable performance over time.
More typical is to use slack time to reduce debt and fit it in when you can.
Maybe in a daily standup someone says they finished their assigned stories,
and the team may recommend to the developer to whittle away at
known technical debt with their extra time.
Don't let technical debt build up until it's too late where you
have a mountain of bugs caused by the debt,
which may become blockers to implementing new features effectively.
This can cause your user story points to increase dramatically.
In my opinion,
iteration or sprint slack is the best way to reduce
technical debt since the product owner may not relate to
technical debt as a backlog item.
Some of my customers, that is product owners,
have understood technical debt, and some haven't.
If they understand it, place some debt as a backlog item and slack time as well. If they don't understand technical debt, fit it into your slack time.