Here's an example of a user story: Students can search for,
find, select, and enroll in classes.
Not too bad of a story.
For now, I'll call this my first pass at writing the user story.
Now let's see how it does against the traits.
So one idea is to go quickly around the room and get
everyone's rough and not so perfect opinion to see how the
traits score on this user story.
Independent.
Maybe the team says, hey, pretty good, seems to stand on its own.
Negotiable.
Pretty good.
Seems to stand on its own maybe is because it can be
pushed to another sprint quite easily.
Valuable.
Really good.
The customer says they must have this as early as possible.
That's value.
Estimable.
Good, maybe a little tricky.
I'm not sure of the full data model at this point says somebody on the team.
Small.
Not sure.
Maybe there's a ton of data.
Testable.
Pretty sure.
So the team may come to the conclusion to begin an estimation exercise or
maybe add a research user story for the next sprint to drill into the user
story deeper and gather more information.
Now, the English language has so many ways to say the same thing.
Will all user stories be written in the same way?
Maybe we need some sort of template to follow to try and ensure
that user stories have some sort of consistency.
How about a template?
Let's check it out.
Let's look at using a template to help us write better
and more consistent user stories.
As a type of user, I want some goal so that some reason.
They type of user is the who or the role.
Some goal is what you are trying to accomplish.
The some reason is the benefit or outcome of doing
this user story in the first place.
Now this was our first pass earlier.
Students can search for, find, select, and enroll in classes.
Now, here is our second pass: As a student,
I can search for, find, and select classes so that I can successfully enroll.
Now that's even better.
Plus, if we have multiple authors, we can normalize the writing styles.
Quality user stories are so important and imperative to get as
right as possible since they drive the estimates,
the requirements, and the project.
Now someone may say, hey, we're agile, so we can make corrections downstream.
Sure you can, but I really must say,
getting these pretty close upfront saves time and money.
User stories don't have to use a template like this,
but it certainly is a good idea.
Now let's see why templates are a good idea on the next slide.
Why should we consider to use a common template for user stories?
I have three good reasons, all of which will streamline sprint planning.
The first reason: Roles in the first person.
Something noteworthy happens when requirements are put into the first person.
Clearly by saying as a student, I can search for,
find,
and select classes so that I can enroll puts a person's mind
into visualizing he or she in that role.
Very valuable.
The next reason helps the product owner or development team
more easily understand the user stories.
Grasping the user story's intent is critical to the
entire Agile and sprint planning process.
Having a structure to the stories actually helps the product owner prioritize.
If the product backlog is a clutter of things,
then the product owner must work harder to understand what the feature is,
who benefits from it, and what the value is,
let alone the development team trying to do the same thing.
The next reason: Helps keep user stories concise and contained.
But if you think the template may at times suppress the intent of the story,
then correct it by modifying the template,
or come up with your own template.
Adapt and be flexible.
Now for one more idea about your backlog design.
Why attributes enhance user stories,
or I'd rather word it why attributes greatly enhance user stories.
Think about it for a moment.
What else would you like to know about each user story that
would help you with your discussions?
Let's see some examples.
One attribute may be the epic it belongs to so that you can refer to it and
understand the fuller context of that particular user story.
Another, priority, certainly.
This is coming from the product owner and a critical part of the user story.
Remember,
the reason why a user story is prioritized high is that it can
be more immediately applied to the business,
therefore, adding value.
Next, the estimate either in story points,
hours, or another unit of measure your team fully understands.
Maybe a target release or sprint number.
This will help you plan and schedule the user story.
Or even more,
if you think you want to add a few attributes that help you with the process,
please do.
Now that we talked about breaking down user stories into smaller,
more concise user stories, well, that's great,
but we do not want to lose sight of the higher level "user
story" that we're going to call the epic. Let's check that out.