Step 1 - Refine the Backlog.
The complete product backlog should always be available for
any release in sprint planning exercises.
The release 3 backlog is simply a subset of the complete backlog.
Revisit the release product backlog to ensure the list is still accurate,
remove items to be placed in a future release,
or remove some altogether.
What we are left with are the items for the second
sprint in release 3 for this example.
Always focus on the user stories and features that provide
the highest business value at the lowest cost at this
point in time in the project.
Now let's go through in detail the potential outcomes
of refinement and considerations.
There may be some leftover items from sprint 1,
and here's how you may disposition them.
Add them back to sprint 2, place them back on the release 3 backlog,
place them back on the whole product backlog,
or maybe the item is just not required, so remove it.
Now, for the sprint 2 backlog, which are the originally planned items.
Maybe place some back on release 3 backlogs since
they're no longer that important.
Place back on the product backlog.
Maybe they're even less important.
Or they aren't needed at all,
so we're going to go ahead and remove them completely.
Okay, so now we have a pretty good list of items for the sprint. Now let's make some estimates.