In this example,
I'm going to show a very simple 2-week sprint where we are
working 8 hours a day just to keep it simple.
Your hours per day will likely vary, and that's totally fine.
Here is day 1 and it leads off with a 2-hour Scrum planning meeting,
followed by daily work.
Each of the following days of the week is led off by
a daily scrum standup meeting.
It will likely last about 15 minutes with possible follow-on
sub-meetings to address any users or blockers.
And the next three days are basically the same.
Now the next four days of the sprint move along in a similar way.
On the last day, we perform a demo of working software,
and at the end of the day we perform our review and retrospective.
So to recap, a complete sprint is comprised of the sprint planning upfront,
scrums and daily work, and end with a demo,
review, and retrospective.
Of course, this is the perfect model, and life is not perfect.
You may adapt and be flexible based on your team, based on your environment, and things like that.