The sprint demonstration is focused on improving the product
and is attended by the extended team and,
in particular, the product owner.
So what you want to do is recap the feature and stories
that we're committed to in the sprint.
Maybe have a visible list of the features or stories to ensure
everyone understands and remembers them.
Next, mark those that were, in fact, completed.
Some of those features may not have been completed,
hence you want to set the expectation accordingly and also make it clear
that the features and stories not completed will be discussed in the next
sprint planning meeting and be either placed into the next sprint's backlog
or maybe even pushed out or eliminated.
Itemize additional features, if any,
that were added during the sprint to the backlog.
Now,
demonstrate the working code of those committed features to
all stakeholders and interested partners.
Be sure completed feature or user stories are demonstrated to
the level necessary to ensure everyone understands that they
work and that they have value.
The demo is not just for the stakeholders,
of course, but other interested partners and the full dev team.
Much can be learned by the team by listening to the product owner
and other stakeholders provide their feedback.
And lastly, shared feedback and recommended changes back to the product owner.
These sessions will provide absolutely invaluable information to
be used in the next sprint planning session.
And also, allow enough time.
Maybe it's 30 minutes, or maybe it's 2 hours.
Be flexible, and adapt the time to the amount of story points completed.
Demonstrations are critical,
and it gives you a chance to shine and show all of your great work to the product owner.