[Autogenerated] Okay,
so let's delve into what a dress code employed consists off.
First,
we're gonna have a look at an overview of the service and then some of
the prerequisites required to using the service.
Codedeploy is a managed service from AWS that allows you to
deploy toe over Service is from over sources.
So let's take a look at some of those components.
The address service is that you can deploy to ah Lunda D C to E.
C s on arm premise service.
Hold on a second, Josh.
You just said a duress service is there.
That's right.
You can install the CODEDEPLOY agent onto your own V EMS to manage deployments.
How cool is that?
You can deploy all sorts of things such as code packages,
executed ALS scripts and conflict files.
You will see more about this layer.
You can use code sources such as s three bucket,
get her on even bit bucket and it actually in the pipeline right now.
Toe also integrate.
Get up.
Codedeploy makes it so easy to deploy and it fits
perfectly into your automation.
Lifecycle on integrates nicely into codepipeline.
It handles all of the complexities of deploying your application on
going to play exactly how you want it to be deployed.
It makes deployments a safe and Seamus process for
your users on also your developers.
Okay, So who should use AWS?
Codedeploy Codedeploy is aimed at AWS developers,
develops engineers, architects and sis at Mons.
But this does not mean that it's so exclusive to the people in those jobs.
Codedeploy is for anyone.
He wants to use it.
So I recommend program Is engineers on anyone who
just wants to know more scared?
Take a look.
It's a fantastic service you use in your development life cycle.
AWS codedeploy can deploy to a multitude of
operating systems using the codedeploy.
Agent.
The agent is a service.
Your store locally on your V m codedeploy can be used with Amazon.
Lennox read her enterprise.
Then it's the bun, too.
On window seven.
Okay,
let's take a look at some of code to play security features that were in place.
They're going to keep your information secure.
Code employees in the boundaries of the AWS shared responsibility model,
which means that you know that eight of us has your utmost security desires.
Our heart I won't allow you to manage your data securely.
It supports encryption at rest.
So when your deployment configurations are created,
it will use Kms to encrypt the data stored in Dynamo Devi.
The code to play agent connects with codedeploy service using tear less,
which means that all of your data is encrypted in transit.
All of the codedeploy actions are monitored for a dress cloudtrail.
This means you can see how all actions happened on by WHO?
As cloudtrail logs all of the FBI calls for incident management.
You can use eight of US cloudwatch events to detect and
react to changes in the code of place.
Say, such as if a deployment happened,
you can create an alert to notify you a duress code if I has been ordered
it and vetted by third party auditors such a sock PC,
I fed ramp hipper and many more. So you know you're getting a highly secure service to use