[Autogenerated] Okay, so now we have everything set up on in place.
Let's look at how to update PCs with CODEDEPLOY.
In this demo, we're going to cover the following.
We're going to update the E.
C s service, which uses codedeploy.
And then we're also going to look at manually updating codedeploy,
which will end up day E.
C s.
And now let's have a look at how we can update that.
So if we jump back over to E.
C S ah, on go to our test definition, if we can create a new revision on,
let's scroll down to configure Very Jason,
unless edit some of this command that gets pumped into the container.
Let's edit something here so we can see the changes.
You just updated that contain it.
Run a bye, codedeploy.
We'll save that.
We'll create that.
Awesome.
So now we have a task definition number night with my case,
but you should probably have to Let's jump back over to the E.
C s dash boat on.
We're going to update our service.
Uh, you can see that nine is the latest in Unitas definition.
On that scroll down, next step deployment types will find on.
Then let's hit next step again on again.
That all looks brilliant.
Let's update the service.
So what's happening there?
So, actually, E C s is using Codedeploy again to create a new deployment.
Let's switch back over to Codedeploy.
Let's have a look at our deployment groups and you can actually see the
deployment here that's just being created by Easy s So Amazon.
You absolutely killed it on a so much automation here that takes
away lows of heartache from his developers.
We can see that's in progress, just like we did it.
The easy to won't on.
We can see what events are happening.
If we scroll up a bit,
we can have a look at this revision location and you'll
see in here similar to easy to that.
It's created the app Spec fours.
So let's let this finish on.
Then we can then just check that it's update it.
Okay, that succeeded.
Let's terminate the original test set.
All succeeded.
Fantastic.
Let's have a quick look.
Awesome.
There's the message that we just updated in our container.
Okay,
so you can actually update this manually to So if we jump
back over to our task definition on, We create a new revision again.
Scroll down.
Same thing configured via Jason.
Scroll down on.
Then let's update the message one final time.
Let's call it Final form Save.
Create Perfect on the next one's great.
So let's then jump back to our revision that we had a quick look at before.
Let's copy that app spect there.
Okay,
so let's go to our application that select our deployment
group that's already been created for us.
And that's creating new deployment here we can use on in line
up spec editor unless paste in the Jason that we just coffee
it from the original revision.
All we have to do here is up.
They attached definition number to a new one or a completely new one.
If that's what you wanted to do, scroll down on.
Let's create the deployment boom.
Is that easy?
Arifin is just don't foryou of codedeploy on its especially easy with
Easy s Let's scroll down and have a look at some of the events in
progress on advocacy and similar with when we deployed Too easy to
you can see the lifecycle hooks and events from the APP spec file If
we switch over to easy.
Yes, and we view our service,
we can actually see here a new test definition being created.
I'm running alongside our original codedeploy is actually blue Green to
playing our tasks and service is wants that new task.
Pass a health check.
It will lend.
Delete the old one.
Look at that.
It deployed the replacement test set on.
Now it's reroute it to the new one,
and then we just need to terminate the original one.
Let's have a look at that.
Any CS boot?
There we go.
It removed the original task definition and has just
replaced it with our latest current one.
So let's have a quick look and make sure that that's actually happened.
WeII, there it is.
So they go.
There's everything you need to know to deploy to E.
C.
S using codedeploy.
And it's especially easy when using fargate as every Finn
just builds upon that cloud free 0.0, mentality of platform as a service or, in fact, everything as a service