[Autogenerated] okay.
In our next section, we're going to look at working with code.
Apply in Lunda.
Let's jump right in and gets died in this demo.
We're going to cover the following.
We're going to look a TKO, deploy and Lambda.
You're going to download the package Sham app.
That's in the course documents that I've already pre uploaded for you.
Then we're going to deploy the Sam application on.
We're gonna look at what that involves,
and then we're gonna update some of the some app on with a failed
validation test so we can see how it fails on.
Then we're gonna update the London function on dhe.
We're gonna fix a test, and then we're going to redeploy it.
And then you can see how it all works in place with the right hooks on,
it's gonna be pretty awesome.
So let's go ahead and jump right in.
Okay, so let's start this demo off.
You've downloaded the course files from floor site on you
open them up in your favorite editor on.
Let's take a look was in there.
So here after the sum up.
Now, this app is essentially the Sam, innit?
Hello World on that you can create yourself on.
Do you can just do that by Crate in by going like this,
when your come on line and that'll just spit out
pretty much what we've got there.
Ah, them built on top of that app on added a pre traffic hook.
So this template file is similar to our app spec files in previous modules.
Now, this is what's gonna hold all of our Lambda functions together on dhe.
So what's gonna be read by cold Deploy and also confirmation?
So here we have.
The over two files are probably most notable in here.
We've got our actual little web service.
It just returns a hello world for us.
Ah, it's got a little validation.
Um, value on Also, it's going to return a stage cut of 200.
If it's successful on, then let's jump over to the next one,
which is a pre traffic hook in here.
You can see that we're going to call the first
function that abduct GS function on DDE.
It's going to get a deployment.
I d from codedeploy on.
Then we're going to call the Lambda function the 1st 1 on.
Then we're going to see if the result is what we want it to be.
If it's gonna return to status code of 200 we're
going to test our validation field, too.
And if that's a success than the pre traffic hook will be successful on,
it will deploy the code successfully.
And you can see down here that it's going to tell codedeploy that the test
was successful on then allow the deployment to go ahead.
So free drawn back over is a template we can see in here.
Here's all had a will function and up.
Jess.
It's going to deploy all at once just because it's a bit quicker for the demo.
But you can have over options in its which is this linear?
10%.
On that, I'll just transfer the traffic over 10% at a time.
Wants a minute.
So it was growing a bit further down,
and then we're going to see our pre traffic hook here,
which is actually referenced in the the first half a world apart.
And then, in the pre traffic hook section,
it's going to create a lifecycle event hook on dhe.
It's gonna create a nervous,
separate function that's gonna test the first function.
I've added a little output section down the bottom Here.
It's going to give out our you're out to test our updates as well, too.
So let's go ahead and build this app on.
Then let's deploy it.
So if we now switch over to the command line here,
I am at the root off the application folder on in Here.
We want to do a Sam build command.
Perfect, really simple, really straightforward on that.
The next thing we want to do is fact, it already tells you,
is you can I have a test it locally?
It's probably outside.
The scope of this course is that's probably more of a Sam tutorial.
We want to Sam Deploy that's gonna ask us some
questions because it's a guided deploy.
I'm happy with the original stock name of Sama on.
I wanted to be in my region in Ireland.
Ah,
that's fine as well on DDE yet out to create the resource role on
Also save our arguments to Sam Conflict Animal.
We can have a look at that in a second to fuel, so let's let that build up now.
This is currently building a cloud formation template of all of our
preferences in and all of our values for our Sam deploy,
you know, some super powerful.
It's a really interesting, um, service, I suppose.
Function.
That's pretty cool.
Really.
How it does it and you know,
a duress once again have built on that cloud free 0.0,
model.
So let's just let that create the required resources on Shouldn't take too long.
Okay?
So that just create all the required resources that we need.
So now we're happy with this change that let's have a quick look at what it's
doing is going to create both of our functions forwards.
And you can see here.
Ah, hello World function.
Also our pre traffic hook.
So that's hit.
Yes, let that fire away.
So this is now really in a confirmation template in the background.
And if we just switch over to the eight of us dashboard, we can see that here.
So let's have a look.
Sam up his the one we just created on its now created all of the different
components and service is for us to get this up and running on.
If we switch over to the lander dashboard.
We should be able to see both functions created in here.
That's the 1st 1 perfect.
And there it is.
So there's our go to play hook for pre traffic evaluation.
Now, if we switch over to Codedeploy dashboard as well,
we should also be able to see in applications the sum up that's created for us.
Senator.
How PCs works as well, already created Old Forest,
which is just so also so powerful.
And let's have a quick look at that.
So in here it's create the application on its creator deployment group, too.
And then it shouldn't have create any deployments just yet.
So it only tends to do that when you do so.
Once this is finished at the group's finished let's have a look.
We can find the You're all here for Orlando function.
So let's just copy that that switch over to a chrome or your browser.
I'll pace.
I didn't We should see hello world and a little bit of
Jason that we just create perfect.
So the next thing let's create an update.
So if we jump back to our application and we'll up it a hello world,
too, let's say that on?
Let's break the validation.
So let's say validation is zero.
Our pre hook traffic tests is looking for what?
So let's have a look down there where that is,
so we can see that the state is car's been 200 but
it's expected a validation value,
which could be an if it really any set of data you
want to return and voluntary on.
I've just use a really straightforward one for this example on.
It's gonna expect zero, but where I'm going to say we want one.
So now we've done that.
Let's switch back to bash.
Uh, let's rebuild the app on.
Let's deploy it once again.
So, Sam deploy guided.
It's gonna be the same name again.
A ll the same values so we can use it and toe,
um, settle the defaults for this, which is fine.
It's going up.
There are changes.
Create the new Clough information template forwards,
which isn't gonna redeploy resources and update them.
And it's also going to create a codedeploy deployment.
So let's to play that Yes, that switch back to our dashboard.
In our confirmation stat, we should see that run some new events.
Credit resources and progress.
And then let's switch over to code, apply it and see what's going on here.
So free school down.
We should now start to see a new deployment.
I d in here soon.
There it is.
Uh, let's have a look at that.
Look, it failed because of a pre deployment hook.
Failed.
It's validation.
So you gonna be able to see any Arizona near that you won't on?
Um, if you have any to debug benefit, this is probably the first port of call,
like in the previous modules that we talked about.
You would just go here and have a look at why it failed.
And you can also see is well, that it's because the update has failed in class.
Information is going to roll back to the previous one.
So let's have a look what's happening there.
We can actually go back to Deployments on.
We'll see.
That created another deployment for us to roll back to a previous version,
which was safe.
Look, that was all successful past all of the tests on DDE.
Yeah, that's perfect.
So let's go back to our code editor again on let's
fix this validation back to one.
In fact, before we do that, let's go to our browser and just see if update two.
Hello world, too.
It didn't so it wrote back, obviously, to the previous version on Dhe.
Let's go ahead now and create that third deployment that we want to do.
So let's go back to our code editor.
Let's change that to hello World Free because we know
that Number two was unsuccessful.
I will fix the validation value back to one on.
Then let's jump back to bash on.
Let's create the third and final deployment.
So we're gonna just once again build the Santa perfect.
And then let's do our final guided deployment.
We're gonna select all the default values again,
and then that's going to create the day of final vision for us.
That cloud formation is going to run perfect.
So let's go ahead and run that and let's see what happens this time.
Switch back over to our browser on.
We can see that we have another update in progress here.
Our London functions are still that and then let's go and have a look.
A cold deploy.
So here, in our deployments, we should be able to see.
Um Well, so go.
But applications set toe application and then go to deployments.
We can see here.
That's creating our new deployment.
Here we go.
So here's our new deployment on.
Then let's see it Testing our ah predeployment validation hook
that we created and made fix that really?
So that it should pass this stage again and then redeploy application.
Okay, Perfect.
That succeeded on past our validation tests on our update function.
So if we go ahead to our on hit the FBI for that function now,
we should see our hello world free on it past his validation. How cool is that?