Hey they're welcome to another session of limitless count use.
Today I want to talk a little bit more about rates of change.
So we already determined how to find the rate of change of a linear function is just the slope of the
line you get when you graph the function.
As we mentioned a linear function has a constant rate of change.
We put that here.
So a linear function has a constant rate of change.
So what exactly does that mean.
Well if it's constant It means that it's not changing.
So for example if you have a graph that looks like this.
So there you have the graph of a linear function it's just a straight line.
Let's say that the slope for this one is three.
So remember slope is given by m so am equals three.
That means that for every unit you move to the right.
So if you move one to the right you're going to go up three.
So one two three and you end up and the graph again you can do it for example here as well.
So if you start here you move one to the right and then you move three up one two three OK.
So it's rate of change it's three because for every unit that you move to the right you move up three
that is slow.
Right.
Overrun.
And just to repeat one more time.
That means that the rate of change of this function is three.
All right so that is for a linear function.
It's a straight line.
It's very easy.
Just count how many units you're going up or down as you move to the right.
But what happens when you have something like this.
What happens if your graph is a curve.
What if we want to find the rate of change of this curve.
Well it turns out that this is a much harder problem than finding it for this line.
And the answer to finding the rate of change of a curve will lead to some very smart people to invent
what we call calculus today.
So Slobo whole line very easy slope of a curve.
Not that easy.
Because think about it what if you want to do rice of a run for example here.
So you start here and then you move to the right and then you move up.
So you have this.
OK so you kind of have a line there but what happens here if you want to get the slope here you go here
and then you go down.
Well you have a completely different line.
Right.
So in this case when we drew two points you ended up in the same line here.
When you draw two points and try to connect them you don't have the same line at all.
Here you have this line.
But then here you have this line.
And if I drew two other points it's going to be a different line as well.
So we have to figure out a way to find the rate of change of a curve.
Now before we do that let's talk a little bit more about rates of change.
Let's say that you work as a finance officer for a company that makes 3D glasses.
Right.
Kind of like Google Glass.
So you have a meeting with your boss next week to talk about the current financial status of the company.
You have a graph that shows how profit is changing over time.
And it looks like this
LME market here this is a profit over time graph.
So let's say that this graph looks something like this.
Let's say that this is when the company started.
And from there on the profit kind of has you know gone up then it went a little bit down up again down.
Then it went up by a lot and then it went down by a lot.
OK.
So it kind of looks like this.
So the interesting question is how are profits changing over time.
Can we get a precise answer.
Well yes we can.
Now we can't really calculate the slope of a curve since the curve varies so much.
But let's start with the concept of average rate of change.
OK so what is average rate of change.
So what we can do is we can calculate in average how the profit is changing over a certain time period.
And the way to do that is with something called a c can't line
and what a second line does is that it touches the graph at two different points.
So it touches graph.
All right.
So that's what a second line does.
It touches a graph at two different points.
So for example let's say that we want to measure the average rate of change from this point up to this
point
OK.
So we want to measure average rate of change.
What we do is we draw a line.
So it touches the graph at two different points and then the slope of the second line is going to be
your average rate of change.
So slope of second line
that is the average rate of change.
Right.
So we have this point we have this point we can't draw a second line over here.
Something like this right.
So that's touching the graph at two points.
Now let's say that the slope of this line is
0.5
is the slope of this sequent line is 0.5.
That means that in average profit's changed 0.5 between this points in time and this point in time.
Okay.
Second line touches the graph at two points and it gives you the average rate of change.
Let's try to get another second line and see how it looks.
Let's say I want to get the average rate of change between this points and this point
will draw our second line over here.
So this second line is again touching the graph at two different points.
Notice that this one actually goes up as you move from left to right.
But then this line moves down as you go from left to right.
That means that the slope is negative and it makes sense because the prophets were doing well they were
up here and all of a sudden they just went down by a lot.
So it's changing in a negative way.
So let's say the slope of this line equals negative 3.5.
That means that from this point in time to this point in time the profits changed by negative 3.5 an
average over.
Just to summarize a secret line touches the graph at two different points.
Here's one secret line and here's another secret line.
So the slope of the second line gives you the average rate of change.
OK.
So the slope of this line is 0.5 we said.
So the average rate of change between these two points is 0.5.
On the other hand the average rate of change between these two points is negative 3.5.
And that's because the slope of the line is negative 3.5.
All right.
So this is average rate of change.
So it's not really accurate for a specific point in time.
You have to get two points and then get a line between them and find out the slope.
So it's really not that useful when you think about it.
What's really interesting is to get that instantaneous rate of change meaning how profit is changing
at a specific point in time.
So instead of having to pick two points I can say OK how is a prophet changing over here.
And to do that I don't want to have to get a different point and get the average.
I want to get it at that specific point.
So how do we do that.
Let's zoom in a little and I'll show you what happens.
Let's say they have this graph.
I'll make it big.
So it's very clearly noticeable.
So you have a graph looks like this
right.
And this one just goes on like that.
So again we want to get instantaneous
rate of change not average instantaneous.
So like we said a second line touches the graph at two points.
So let's try to get a second line.
From here to here.
OK.
So we have a second line right here.
Let's go ahead and graph it.
Right.
That's not really helping us get to instantaneous right.
It's still average because it's seconds.
However what happens if these two points get closer together.
So let's grab the upper points and bring it a little bit closer.
So instead of being up here it's going to be let's say here.
All right.
That gives us another sequent line.
Interesting.
So we have these two points.
Give us a second line.
But when the point is the closer we get a totally different secret line what happens if the points get
even closer.
So let's say that this other point actually comes down here.
Well what's going to happen is we're going to get yet another seek out line.
I know it's a little bit messy but just bear with me.
All right.
So we get the other point.
We get a closer and closer to the other point.
And as you can see we get different segment lines but they're changing in slope.
Right.
So here's the big secret about calculus.
Here's why calculus is amazing.
Check this out as these two points get infinitely closer.
And I'll explain what that is in a minute.
Then we get a better approximation of the instantaneous rate of change at this point.
The idea is to get as close as possible as to what is a tangent line.
So at tangent line
remember how a second line touches the graph at two points a tangent line touches the graph.
We only one point
OK
so the sequence gives you average rate of change then a tangent must give you instantaneous rate of
change.
So for example I'll just redraw this over here.
If you want to get the instantaneous rate of change at this point what you need is not a second line
uniting two points at this point and a different one.
What you need is a tangent line that touches the graph at exactly what point.
This is it
see how this line only touches the graph at this point.
This is a tangent line.
And the big secret is hope you're ready for this.
The slope of this tangent line gives you the instantaneous rate of change at that point.
Let me repeat that once more the slope of the tangent line gives you the instantaneous rate of change
at that point.
Just because it's so important I'll repeat it once again.
Remember the slope of this tangent line gives you the instantaneous rate of change at that point.
Now if you're not really aware of what's going on we just found a way to find the rate of change of
a curve right.
You just find a tangent line to that curve at that point and you're good to go.
And to you it might be like OK that's fine it's just math.
But this is an incredible discovery.
This is one of the most amazing things that a human being has covered.
This is incredible.
All right.
The fact that we know that you can get a second line and then get the point closer and closer and closer
until you'll get to a tangent line.
It's just amazing right.
And this is basically the foundation of all calculus and we're going to go into a concept called derivatives
in the next section all right.
For a quick summary.
A linear function has a constant rate of change.
We already saw this a couple of seconds ago.
It's just a straight line.
Now when you get to a curve that's where it gets interesting.
So to get the average rate of change between two points and a curve we use the second line.
Remember the second line touches the graph at two points and again it's not that useful.
It's only the average when it gets interesting is as the points of a second line get closer and closer.
It approximates a tangent line.
This is really cool.
A tangent line touches a graph at only one points.
OK and again this is the big deal.
This is the secret sauce in calculus.
The slope of a tangent line is a measure of the instantaneous rate of change at that point.
So if you have a curve and it looks something like this and you have this point and you want to find
the rate of change of this point all you need to do is find the slope of the line that's tangent to
that point.
So the slope of this line will give you the rate of change at that specific point.
Beautiful.
All right.
So don't get confused.
Sequent line is for average rate of change
and the tangent
is for instantaneous rate of change which is the really cool one
and obviously the second line touches the graph at two points.
That's why its average is the average change as you go from point one to point to.
So this is two points.
The tangent line however only touches the graph at one point.
That's why it gives you an instantaneous rate of change because it is at that specific point right.
So pretty cool stuff will formalize this concept in the next section with the derivative.
I'll see you in the next tutorial.