Hey there what's going on.
Welcome to another session of limitless calculus.
Today we're going to talk about exponential functions and we'll get to the definition of an exponential
function in a second.
Before that though let's talk a little about exponents.
So remember that and xponent just tells you how to multiply a base by itself.
It tells you how many times to do it.
So for example if you have two to the third power then the two is called the base
and the three is called the exponent.
So remember the exponent is always to the right of the base and it's a little bit higher and a little
bit smarter.
So this is how you know that this is not.
But two to the three began the exponent is up here and it's very small.
So what this expression means is that you're going to multiply the base by itself and the exponent tells
you how many times.
So two to the three is to times two times two right.
So we're multiplying the base by itself three times
and two times two is four times two is eight.
All right.
So two to the three is equal to eight.
Let's do another example.
Let's say we have four to the second power.
And remember that anything to the second power is also called squared.
So four squared is basically four times four so you are multiplying four by itself two times.
And that equals 16.
All right.
So that's all that exponents do.
All right so let's cover a couple of different cases of other exponents.
What happens when you have fractions as exponents.
So for example let's say you have four and the exponent is two over four.
All right so the exponent itself is a fraction.
How does this work.
Well there's a rule that says that if you have a base a to the exponents be oversee this becomes.
So we have base to the top of the fraction.
So a to be.
And then we take the route and the route is seat.
All right.
I know this might be a little confusing but let's take a look at the example but again where we have
if we have a base elevated to a fraction B oversee then what we do is we keep the aid to the B right.
Here we get a root the number outside of the root is c..
So let's apply this rule right here.
So again this is for the two or four.
So we keep the four to the second power
and we take the fourth root.
So that is going to be equal to the fourth root of four squared which is 16.
So this is like the inverse of exponent.
So we're looking for a number so that when you multiplied by itself four times you get 16.
And that number is two because two times two times two attempts to is 16.
So this is your answer.
Now what's really important here and what I want you to look at is the fact that we can solve problems
that have fractions in the exponents using this rule over here.
And again we'll do a couple of examples on that later on.
So for now don't worry about it.
Just make sure that you know that a stays with the B.
So that's a to the beat and then you put the roots and the number outside the root is C.
All right so another case is when you have negative numbers in the exponents
how do we handle these.
So for example what if you have two to the negative three we solve this.
It's kind of weird because this tells you this xponent how many times to multiply 2 by itself.
So you might think oh ashes negative two times negative two times negative two.
That's the way it works the way it works is this.
So if you have for example and this is the rule a to the negative b.
So you have a base of a.
And then the exponent is negative b then that means that you're going to keep your age to the B but
you're going to have a fraction and there's going to be a 1 on top.
OK.
So basically this a to the negative b comes to the bottom over fraction and you flip the sign on the
exponent.
So here we had a to the negative b.
That became a to b.
And again this is now the bottom of a fraction.
So we have one over to the OK so let's apply this rule over here before that.
Let me circle it so that you know it's a rule so let's apply it here.
There's going to be equal to one over.
So we always do the one over and then we bring this whole thing to the bottom but it comes in with a
flip sign for the exponent.
So instead of being to the negative three it is two to three.
All right.
And finally we have won over what is two to three.
It's two times two is four times two again is eight.
So this is one over eight.
All right.
So again if you have a negative exponent you can always bring down this whole expression to the bottom
by flipping the sign of the exponent and let's do one more rule.
So if you have something to the zero power
it's going to put a line through the zero just so that you know it is zero.
So as a rule you probably know this by now.
Anything let's call anything a 2 0 equals 1.
All right.
You might think it's 0 but it's not.
It actually equals one.
We don't have to get into the why does remember when you have anything to zero.
That is one I remember in our derivative rules sometimes we have for example the derivative of X right.
So that gives us like x 2 to 1 minus 1 x 2 0 0 and X of the 0 is 1.
That's why the derivative of x by itself is 1 and it doesn't matter if it's X or if it's a number.
So for example 3 to 0 is 1
22 2 0 is 1 etc. etc..
So in general anything to the zero power is one.
All right.
So we covered four things we covered exponents and how they work.
Remember that this number here is the base and the exponent is on top to the right.
A little bit smaller the exponent tells you how many times to multiply the base by itself.
Then sometimes you have exponents that are fractions.
In that case you keep the base to the top.
So in this case it's forward to the two.
Right.
And then we do roots and we do the fourth root.
So this bottom actually comes as a root over here then we have the case where we have negative exponents.
If you have a base to a negative exponent you can actually bring down this whole term bring it down
here and then you flip the sign of the exponent.
So instead of being negative 3 it becomes positive 3.
All right.
That gave us 1 over 8.
And here's the rule and again very important.
You have to switch the sign of this exponent.
Here it was negative.
But when we brought it down it became positive.
And finally the property of zero power anything to the zero power is always 1.
So with this in mind let's go ahead and visit exponential functions.