Hello there how's it going.
My name is Louis and I would like to welcome you to the limit less calculus course for Business Calculus.
Thank you so much for being here.
And thank you so much for putting your trust in me to help you pass your class.
To give you a little background.
My name is Lewis and I've been a tutor for Business Calculus for the past eight years.
I've tutored hundreds of students and I understand what it takes to be able to pass this class over
those years of tutoring.
I've accumulated a lot of knowledge when it comes to the best way of teaching this class.
And trust me I know this class is one of the most hated classes out there.
You're a business student.
Maybe you like marketing Maybe you like finance maybe you like management but calculus.
Hmm probably not always taking this class because you have to.
And I totally get that and also believe me I've heard every single thing about this class.
Why do I have to take this class.
Am I ever going to use this.
Why is this class so hard etc..
I've heard it all.
So if you're asking yourself those questions you came to the right place.
My goal is to help you understand the concepts help you practice them and eventually help you pass the
class.
So don't worry if you're struggling with pases calculus right now I am here to help you and take it
from me.
There is light at the end of the tunnel.
You can absolutely crush this class if number one.
The information is presented to you in a way that makes sense.
And number two you put in the work by practicing and I'm going to help you out with those two things
in this class.
So before we get into the tutorials Let's go ahead and review a couple of things about the course and
after that we'll dive right in.
So again thank you for being here.
And let's crush byssus calculus together.