Hey they're welcome to another session of limit last calculus.
Congratulations you've made it up to here.
You finished the first part of the course.
So we went over what derivatives are how they work the differentiation rules and even some applications.
Great.
Now we're going to go into the second part of calculus which is integrals.
So in essence you have this
you have calculus divided into two.
So we have differential calculus
which is the part that we just did.
So that's a part with derivatives.
And you also have integral calculus which is the part where we're going to do now.
All right.
So differential calculus actually makes up most of the Course integral calculus.
Well it's part of the course but is not as broad of a topic.
If you were to take calculus 2 then that's where you would see a lot of integration in calculus and
Calculus 1.
You just get a glimpse of integrals.
You'll learn what they are.
You'll learn how they work etc..
But you do not learn any advanced techniques for integrating that you actually do in calculus too.
Now if you're a student you probably won't have to take calculus too.
That's at least based on my experience.
Maybe your class is a little bit different maybe they do go deeper into integrals.
This course however will cover the main topics and integration.
All right.
So let's go ahead and get started with antiderivatives.
So like I said let's get started with the definition of an antiderivative.
We have that a function whose derivative is f of x is called the antiderivative of f of x and it's given
by f of x with an upper case f.
Let's read that again.
A function whose derivative is f of x is called the antiderivative of f of x and is given by uppercase
f of x.
So what does this mean exactly.
Let's go into an example here so I can show you what this means.
All right.
So let's say that we have the function f of x equals 3 x squared right.
And let's say we want to find the derivative of this function.
So prime of x.
So remember we have a three to a constant multiple.
We leave it outside.
We bring down the two multiplying.
That gives us 6 and we subtract 1 from the exponent.
So that gives us x to the one which is just X right.
So we have our main function f of x which is 3 x squared and its derivative is 6 secs.
All right.
So we went from f of x to the derivative f prime of x.
Now imagine for a second that this f of x disappeared.
Boom it's not there anymore.
All right.
It's gone now.
Imagine that all we knew is that there is a function out there whose derivative is six secs.
We do not know what the function is.
We do not know what it looks like but we know that there is a function out there who is derivative is
6 x so whatever that function is which we already know it's 3 x squared is called the antiderivative
of this function y antiderivative.
Because think about it instead of going down and getting more derivatives it's like going back up into
the original.
Right.
For example let's say you want to get the derivative of this one.
This would be the second derivative of the original Right which is just six
and let's bring back our APH of x
so if you have f of x and you find a derivative you get 6 X if you have 6 x and you find the derivative
you get six that's going down.
However if you're going up then what you're doing is you're saying OK for six there's a function out
there who's derivative is this six.
That function is the 6 x in the same way.
If you have 6 x you say OK there's a function out there whose derivative is 6 x that is 3 x squared.
So you see how this works an antiderivative is a function whose derivative is f of X..
Let's do another example.
Let's say we have a function whose derivative is
20 x
All right.
So we do not know what the original function is.
We just know that there's a function out there whose derivative is 20 x so that mysterious function
whose derivative is 20 x is the antiderivative of 20 x because when you differentiate that function
you get 20 x.
It turns out that that function is
10 x squared.
All right so 10 x squared is the antiderivative of 20 x
here in the same way 3 x squared is the antiderivative of 6 x.
I'll just abreviated of x x and guess what 6 x is the antiderivative of 6.
So it's like a chain.
This one is the antiderivative of the next.
And this one is the antiderivative of the next.
If you approach it from the other side this is a derivative of this one and this one is a derivative
of this one.
All right.
So 6 x is the anti derivative
of six.
So you see how this works.
So I mean think about the name of this antiderivative.
Instead of finding the derivative instead of going down and getting more and more derivatives you actually
go up.
So if you have 6 x instead of getting the derivative and going down what you do is you go up and you
find the original function whose derivative is 6 x that is a common problem an integral calculus.
You're going to be given a derivative and you need to find a function that produced that derivative.
Right.
So we need to find a function whose derivative is that function that you were given.
OK so we already know that if you're given a function and you ask to find it's antiderivative we need
to find the function that produced that derivative.
Now a good question is does every function have just one antiderivative.
We'll see that next.