OK so here's a little more formal definition of what I just talked about.
I'm calling it the input output relationship.
That's not a thing.
I just made that up.
But it helps you remember exactly what it is.
So is that a function only has one output for every input.
This is very important.
For example if you have a TiVo like this
where you have X input and here you have your y output if you have for example that.
So when you plug it in three it gives you five.
And then when you plug in three it gives you 10 well that doesn't make a lot of sense right.
Because for one input you can only have one output when I plug in three.
It gives me 5.
It cannot be that when I plug in 3 It also gives me 10 sometimes five sometimes 10.
No that doesn't work.
This is not a function.
OK.
Again a function can only have one output for every input.
Going back to the washing machine if you wash your red shirt with the Turgeon on Monday you will get
a red shirt back right.
It's going to be clean but it's going to be still the same red shirt if you wash your red shirt again
on Thursday.
Are you going to get your green pants back.
Of course you won't.
You will get your same red shirt.
So for each dirty clothing item that you wash will get the same item.
Now clean that is not going to change.
That is why when you have an input you cannot have different outputs.
It's always going to be related to one output and one output only.
OK.
So that's pretty much it for an intro to functions.
Now let's go over a summary of what we just covered.
OK so a quick summary of what we just covered.
A function is a machine that takes an input does something to it and returns an output functions are
pretty much washing machines.
And so whenever you see a function I want you to think of a washing machine.
So how are they similar.
Well in the washing machine the input is dirty clothes.
The processes that you apply to that dirty clothes washing and the output is clean clothes functions
typically have a form y equals f of x even though they could be other letters and when y equals f of
x x is the input and Y is the output.
If you're having problems remembering which one is X which ones y.
Think of it like this.
X is input
Y is output so if you organize them in an alphabetical order then X comes before a Y and I comes before.
Oh right.
So X and input both are first in the alphabet then y and output.
Therefore you know that x belongs to input and Y.
Is output right.
Alphabetical order again X is before Y is before 0.
All right.
And finally a function always has 1 output only for every input.
OK.
You can plug in a number into a function and sometimes get one result and some other times get a different
result for every input.
There's always only going to be one output.
All right.
So hopefully that wasn't too bad.
Those are functions again.
They are a foundation for calculus and we'll see them over and over again in every single problem that
we're going to do.
Once again thank you for being here.
Welcome to the tutorial and I'll see you in the next one.