All right.
So let's do a couple of exercises for identifying whether a function is a constant function or not.
So the first one that we have is identify whether f of x equals 10 is a constant function.
So these are basically yes or no questions.
It's either a constant function or it isn't.
So just go ahead and pause a video and write your answer down.
All right.
So identify whether f of x equals 10 is a constant function.
The answer is actually yes.
Yes it is a constant function.
Why.
Because f of x is equal to a number anytime that f of x is equal to the number then we have a constant
function right.
There are no axes no letters just f of x equals 10.
All right.
I'm moving on to the next one.
Identify y f of x equals Pi is a constant function.
So is it is pi a constant function.
This might be a little tricky because pi it kind of looks like a symbol and not really a number but
I'll let you figure it out.
So go ahead and pause the video and check it out.
All right so what do you think is f of x equals pi a constant function.
The answer again is yes it is a constant function.
All right.
It is a constant function because pi at the end of the day is just a number.
Remember that pi is approximately equal to three point fourteen.
Right.
So again f of x equals a number.
So this is just a constant function.
All right.
So let's do one more identify whether f of x equals x is a constant function.
So f of x equals x.
Pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so is f of x equals x a constant function.
So let's see.
So I remember it to be a constant function it needs to be equal to a number.
Here it's actually equal to a letter.
In fact in this function whatever you plug in is whatever you get out.
So the answer is no the y value is not always the same the y value actually depends on the input right.
If you plug in one you get 1.
But if you plug into you get two if you plug plugging three you get three etc. etc. for that reason
f of x is not a constant function because it's not equal to a simple number.