All right.
So before we get started with the course I want to go over a couple of things.
The first one is the course structure so the Course is divided into seven main calculus sections.
These are pretty much the same sections that you should see in your textbook.
And I made it like that so that it resembles your class the most.
So the sections are functions and graphing limits and continuity derivatives differentiation rules applications
of derivatives exponential and logarithmic functions and integrals.
By the time you're watching this video I might have other new sections so I'm going to have a section
for the introduction to the course where for example this video is going to be.
And any other section that I plan to add.
However the 7 will always be there because these are the main sections for Bessus calculus.
And then within each section you're going to have videos on different topics.
So in these videos I will go ahead and explain concepts go over mnemonics and do examples so that you
know how stuff works because applying what we just learned is critical.
That's why I do examples for each of the things that we learn.
Besides I also give you practice exercises which we're going to cover right now.
All right so for the practice exercises each section has practice exercises for you to do so as you
go through each section.
I'll have videos for you to practice what you just learned.
So the way the videos work is I give you a problem I give you some time to pause the video and do it.
And then after that you pause the video and we'll do it together.
That way you can see if you got the right answer and you can see if your process is correct.
Now let me say something very clearly you need to do these exercises.
All right.
You need to.
It's not that you should.
You need to do these exercises if you think that all you're going to do is watch these videos and then
you're going to magically pass the class.
I have news for you that is not going to happen.
The only way to learn math is by practice.
All right.
Let me repeat that again because it's critical.
The only way that you're going to learn this stuff is by doing so you absolutely need to get out a piece
of paper and a pencil and sit down and try to do the exercises in the tutorials.
I give you all of the tools that you need to solve exercises.
But even if you do not know how to do them you have to pause the video and give it a shot.
That is so so important.
I've tutored many students over the years that what they did was they took two hours of tutoring with
me and after that we went over some concepts.
We went over a couple of problems and they thought they were good to go.
Guess what those students didn't do well in tests.
The ones that did well and eventually pass the class were the ones that practiced more and more and
more.
All right.
So for every section do the practice exercises they're going to help you drill what you just learned
in your head.
All right.
And another point is you need to do your homework so whatever homework your professor gives you it's
for a reason.
Guess what those problems that you're doing the homework a lot of them will show up in quizzes and midterms
and in final exams.
So you need to do your homework.
So just like I had students that came to tutoring for two hours a week and then took a test and didn't
do well in the same way you cannot just come to the videos do the practice exercises that I give you
and then call it a day.
You also need to do your homework.
What better way to practice what you just learned than by doing your homework.
All right.
Let me tell you the mnemonics as good as they are they might not get into your head the first time you
have to do them over and over again.
So every single homework exercise that you get you need to do.
Sometimes it's going to be difficult sometimes it's going to be boring.
You might not feel like it but do you want to pass this class or not.
If you do you need to do.
Number one the exercises that I give you.
And number two you need to do your homework.
And again no excuses like Sheil above says just just do it do it.