All right so we have that functions have an infinite number of antiderivatives because of constants.
So an infinite number of them.
That's a lot.
Let me show you what this means for example.
So what is a derivative of x squared plus five.
It is 2 x Right.
Because a derivative of x squared.
We just use the power rule.
It gives us 2 x plus the derivative of a constant is 0.
All right what is the derivative of plus thirty four squared plus 34.
Well same thing.
The derivative of this one is to X and the derivative of this one is zero.
What is the derivative of x squared.
Mine is pi.
Remember pi is approximately three point fourteen.
It's just a number well same thing derivative of this one is to X and derivative of negative pi is zero.
So I hope you're seeing a pattern here.
The derivative of all of these functions is 2x.
So if I ask you to find the antiderivative of 2 x so the function whose derivative is 2 x which one
is it.
Is it x squared plus 5 or is it x plus 34 or is it x squared minus Pi.
It turns out all of them are antiderivatives of 2 x.
So in general the antiderivative
of 2 x it's not only one function because as you can see there are several functions whose derivative
is to X.
In fact there is an infinite number of them.
Because you could put here any number that you want it.
So in general the antiderivative of 2 x is x squared plus C right and that C is a constant.
All right.
So again I want you to pay attention because this is really important.
The antiderivative of 2 x it's not just one of these functions it's a family of functions.
In fact it's an infinite number of functions because again you could have x squared plus whatever a
constant and the derivative of that is always going to be 2x because a derivatives of constants are
zero.
So again the antiderivative of 2 x is x squared plus C and C could be any constant.
OK.
In fact we have a special name for this
and that's called indefinite integral.
Let's check that out next.
OK so here we have the definition of an indefinite integral.
So we saw in the last section that a function has an infinite number of antiderivatives.
So an indefinite integral is the family of antiderivatives of a function uppercase f of x plus C.
So when we say the family which is mean the group right it's a group of antiderivatives for a given
function and it makes sense that this is the notation because this is the generic antiderivative plus
a constant.
Remember though we have to add a constant because we'll find the derivative of this constant could be
anything but its derivative will be zero.
So let's do another example just to make it more clear.
So again let's find the derivative of
2 x squared plus three
a derivative of this is for X
and the derivative of three is zero.
Let's find the derivative of two x squared.
Again mine is 10.
So all that changes is the constant.
So that's going to be again for X because a derivative of the first term is for X minus the derivative
of 10 is 0 and 1 more.
Let's do
2 x squared plus 1 derivative of this.
And again it's just for X and the derivative of this one is zero.
So as you can see there is a group of functions whose derivative is Forex.
So if we want to get the antiderivative for X it's not just this one or just this one or just this one.
It's all of them and then some.
That's why we have the generic form where we say uppercase f of x plus C.
So we can say that the indefinite integral
I'm really great at writing with this pad.
Right.
Look at that.
And beautiful.
So the indefinite integral of 4 x
is what.
Well it's this antiderivative 2 x squared
plus C.
All right
cool.
So again this right here are the two x squared is the antiderivative because the derivative of 2 x squared
is for X.
But then we also have to specify this plus C which represents a constant.
Because you could have two X squared plus three or two x squared minus 10 or 2 x squared plus 1 x cetera
et cetera et cetera.
There's an infinite number of constants that you could add or subtract this to x squared.
That's why the indefinite integral is given in this form and this agrees with the definition we have
here.
It is a family of antiderivatives of a function.
All right.
That's why this concept is not specified.
It's not one or two or three.
It's just C in general because it could be any constant.
So again the antiderivative is just one function but the indefinite integral is the family of functions
whose derivative is for X and I'll say it one more time.
The reason we have a family is because we have constants.
All right.
So let's see how the process of finding indefinite integrals looks like.