Hey they're welcome to another session of limitless calculus this session will discuss the most important
topic in all of calculus.
The concept of a derivative derivatives are the foundation of calculus.
And we're going to talk about them here.
Now a derivative is connected to the concept of rate of change.
So let's summarize what we talked about in the last section about average an instantaneous rate of change.
So remember we have two types of lines.
We have a second line and we have a tangent line.
So a second line touches the graph at two points.
And again it measures the average rate of change.
So how function is changing on average from one point to the next.
On the other hand the tangent line touches the graph at only one point
and instead of measuring the average it actually measures the instantaneous rate of change.
Instantaneous rate of change that is for the tangent line
and the actual value for the rate of change for both of these lines is the slope.
So the slope of the sequence gives you the average rate of change and the slope of the tangent gives
you the instantaneous rate of change.
Now the whole idea behind calculus is to make the two points that a second line is connecting as close
as possible.
And if you remember from the last tutorial basically what we do is this
OK so let's say we want to find the average rate of change between this point over here and this point
over here.
Right.
So we would have pretty much a second line that touches both points and let's call this x zero.
So zero just means that it's a value of x.
We do not know what it is.
But right now it doesn't matter.
And let's say that this points has the value as 0 plus H.
Ok so things are getting weird.
Why 0 plus H.
So think about it like this.
Imagine that x 0 is three.
OK.
So for a second think that 0 is 3.
So what we're going to do is we're going to add h which is another number 2 x 0.
Let's say that H is 1.
So we have x 0 which is three plus H which is one gives you four.
So the x value for this one is just 3 x 0 and the x value for this one is three plus one which is four.
OK.
So let's draw the second line.
It's going to look something like this touches both points.
OK.
So what if we wanted to get the slope of this line.
Well remember that slope is AM and it is right over run
and if you're a member from the other tutorial that we did on slopes basically rice over run is basically
the change in why over the change in x.
So if you have two points and you want to get the slope of the line connecting the two points your formula
is going to be y to minus why one over x 2 minus x 1.
So you have two points right.
You have
X1 y one.
That's your first point and you have x to y to and again to get the slope.
All you need to do is grab the whys so y to minus y one and then divide that over X to minus x 1.
That's going to give you the slope of this line.
So using our notation for exit on h.
Let's try to find the slope of this.
So in our case we have two points right.
Our first point is
x 0 and f x 0.
Right.
Because we're plugging in zero.
And that's going to give us a Y value.
We do not know what those numbers are but again it doesn't matter.
And our second point is going to be well the x value is x 0 plus H.
And again we set H is just a number that you add to zero.
So the x value here is zero plus H
comma and then the y value is f x zero plus H.
Right because we're plugging in this zero plus H into f of x.
All right.
So this is point number one.
I'll put it over here that's points 1.
And this is point 2.
These are the two points that the second line is touching and they're both on the curve.
This is point to.
All right.
So let's go ahead and plug these in into our formula for slope.
So again we have point 1 and we have Point 2.
So let's plug these numbers into our formula for slope.
So what is why too.
Well y2 is the y value of the second points which is of zero plus H.
OK.
And then we do minus what does why one just add a vague zero.
All right everything over what is x 2 is the x value of point number two it is zero plus H.
And we do minus x 1 so x 1 is just the x value of point 1 which is zero.
Interesting.
If you look at the denominator here why do we have.
Well we have x 0.
Sorry I forgot the minus here.
We have x 0 minus 0.
What does that mean.
That means that they cancel out.
So this zero goes away and this zero goes away and we're left with equals f of zero plus H mine is half
of zero
over h.
This right here is the slope of the second line.
All right.
All right so let's go to the next screen.
Let me just rewrite what we have so far.
So we have that the slope of the second line is equal to half of zero plus H.
Minus Zero.
Everything over.
H OK.
So.
And let me just redraw the graph on the right here.
So it doesn't have to be exactly the same but we know that it was something similar to this and they'll
make it a little bigger so that we can actually zoom in.
So it was something like this.
All right.
Doesn't matter what's on the right or what's on the left.
This is the important part.
So we have the second line between these two points.
So we have this line connecting the two points.
Right now that's all well and good.
We have the average rate of change because the slope of the second line measures the average rate of
change and it's one more thing we have.
This is egg zero right.
This x value for this point and the x value for this other point is zero plus H.
So basically h is the difference between the x value here and the x value here.
Right.
Because we have x 0 and then we have X or a plus H.
It's like saying three gallons of water.
And this is three plus one gallons of water.
So the differences one.
Right.
Because you have three and four.
The difference is just one.
Now this is the second line average rate of change.
What happens if we want to find the instantaneous rate of change for this point over here.
Remember that instantaneous rate of change is given by the tangent line.
So when you add a line that's tangent to the graph and that touches a graph only at one point.
Well like we said in the other tutorial you can actually approximate a tangent line by getting the points
in a second line closer together.
So if you want to find the rate of change here what you can do is you can grab the other point and you
can make it closer.
So again let's say that we want to grab this point and want to bring it over here.
So we have another second line.
That means that age just got smaller because the x value is not here anymore.
It is actually here because here's where you have this other point.
And what if you got closer what if you had a point here and then the second line is between these two
well what happens is you get closer and closer to the tangent line.
So you see that first of all we're started with the blue line which was way over here then we got to
the green line which was closer but not enough.
And then we got to the right line which is getting closer.
So what is going on here as h gets smaller then the line resembles more and more a tangent line.
So right now zero plus age is over here.
But if you make H smaller then exurbia plus H is going to get closer and closer to Gero.
So you see that you start to get closer and closer to zero until it actually becomes what's called infinitesimally
small.
That means very very very very small in fact so small you cannot even measure it.
And at that point you do not have a second line anymore.
What you have is a tangent line.
All right.
So I don't know if you've caught on yet.
We're talking about making age smaller and smaller.
What does that mean.
It means that age is approaching zero.
What do you use when a variable is approaching a number.
Of course we use limits remember limits that we covered way back.
We use them again here.
So this is the slope of the second line.
Let's try to get the slope of the tangent line.
So let me write em 10 so we know we're working with the tangent line.
So what is this.
The slope of the tangent line is let's grab this same thing.
So just the CAn't of exit row plus H minus f of zero.
Over H.
But then what do we say.
We said that as age gets smarter smaller then we approximate the tangent line.
So instead of doing just this we're going to do the limits of all this.
As age approaches zero
this right here ladies and gentlemen is the foundation of calculus.
This little formula over here.
This is it.
It does not get any better than this.
Check it out.
Why is this so important.
This formula right here actually measures the slope of a tangent line and what is a slope of a tangent
line.
It's the instantaneous rate of change.
So this formula right here can tell you exactly how a function is changing at any point in its domain.
So with this formula here we know how the function is changing at this point and we know how it's changing
at this point.
And we also know how it's changing at this point.
So it's basically used to find the rate of change of a curve.
This is it.
So let me just read it here because this is huge.
This is the slope
of a line
tangent to a curve.
We put a couple of exclamation points because this is so important.
I hope you're enjoying this right now.
I hope you're going to throw a party because of this.
This is amazing.
All right.
This is a slope of a line that's tangent to a curve.
In other words it tells you how the curve is changing at a specific point.
All right.
Because remember the slope of a tangent line is that instantaneous rate of change awesome.
One more thing I'll do is I'll rewrite this and instead of saying egg's zero because remember F-0 was
as specific x value instead of saying x 0.
I'm just going to say X which is the generic formula.
All right.
So let me just put it down here.
And equals the limit of f of x plus H.
Mine is 5 x over h as age approaches zero
bang.
There we go.
And again the only difference between this one and the one we just did is that this one instead of saying
0 it just says X because it's generic.
And this ladies and gentlemen is called the derivative of f of x are riveted of f of x.
Right.
So word derivative.
My goodness you're going to hear that word a million times starting from now.
All right.
This right here is the derivative of f of x Let's go over this again.
So what do we have we have.
Slope is equal to the limit of f of x plus H minus f of x over age as h approaches zero.
That is your derivative of.