All right so here we have our first example.
It says find the intervals of increase and decrease of the function f of x equals 6 x squared minus
2 x.
So let's break it down step by step.
We do not have a graph for this function so we need to use derivatives first that is find the derivative
find and prime of X OK.
So what is a derivative of this function over here.
Let's finally put to use all of the rules that we learned in the last section.
So the derivative of 6 x squared minus 2 x.
So we have a difference of 2 terms 6 x squared minus 2 x for the first term we have a constant multiplying.
So the constant multiple rules says we keep the six times.
This is the power rule.
So we bring down a dictator so we bring down or 2 x and remember we remove one from the exponent.
So that's X to the one and it's two minus 1 becomes X to the one and then we have a difference so we
say minus constant multiple.
We have a two on the outside.
And then we have X to the 1.
So remember that an x by itself is X to the 1.
So it's going to be X to the 1 minus 1.
So let's simplify six times two is 12.
X 2 the 2 minus 1 is just 1.
So we don't market minus 2 times X to 1 minus 1.
But remember this.
So one of minus one is 0.
So x 2 0 is just one.
Remember that anything to the zero power is always 1.
So it's going to be two times one is just two 12 X minus 2 is our derivative our second step is going
to be to find the values that make the derivative equal to zero and the values that make it undefined.
So find the values where the derivative is equal to zero.
And where the derivative is defined.
Now in this specific case we do not have a fraction for a derivative.
The derivative is simply too well of x squared minus 2.
So there is no value really that's going to make it on the find.
We cannot have any division by zero.
That's why this case is only going to check for the first case which is the derivative is equal to zero.
So let's grab this and set it equal to zero.
12 X minus 2 is equal to zero.
So we want to solve for x.
First of all we have to move this to to the other side.
So we do plus two on both sides
cancels out and we bring down the 12 x 12 x is equal to zero plus two is to and then finally we want
to solve for x which is being multiplied by the 12.
So we have to divide by 12 on both sides over 12 and over 12.
So the 12 and 12 cancel out and we have X equals 2 over 12.
We divide this whole thing by two the two becomes a one and the 12 becomes a 6.
So we're just simplifying.
So X equals 1 over 6.
This one over 6.
When you plug it into the derivative It gives you a value of zero.
OK so this is your zero and there's only one.
Sometimes you have to or you have three in this case you only have one.
And finally or step three is test values left and right.
And do not worry.
We're almost done with this problem.
OK.
So we found a derivative we found their values and make the derivative equal to zero.
In this case it's only 1 over 6 so that's the only value.
So how do we know where the original function is increasing or decreasing.
Well we need to test.
All right.
That is the last step when finding intervals of increase and decrease.
So what you can do here is you can draw a number line something like this and you can put the 0 and
the 0 is the number so that when you plug it into the derivative it is equal to zero.
So you put this 0 1 over 6 and when you need to do is you need to pick a value to the left and you need
to pick a value to the right.
So remember one over six is a positive number.
And if you plug it into a calculator it's approximately point 16.
So we need to get a value to the left of point 16 and to the right of point 16 we can pick either values.
So to the left of point 16 is what is 0 because 0 is less than 0.16.
And to the right of point 16 Let's pick an easy value.
Let's pick one
swimmer repeat that again.
Once you find the values that make the derivative equal to zero you need to pick values to the left
of that value and to the right of that value.
And what you do is you grab those test values 0 and 1 you plug them into the derivative and you see
either a positive or negative or positive.
The graph is increasing and if it's negative the graph is decreasing.
All right.
So let's go ahead and plug these into the derivative and I'll mark this here because this is very important.
So this zero and this one you plug into the derivative
you always always always plug in these test values in the derivative.
You're not going to plug the men into the original function f of x.
You're going to plug them in into the derivative 12 X minus 2.
This is a source of confusion all the time.
And if you plug it into the original You're going to get it wrong.
OK.
So remember your test values always go into the derivative.
So let's go ahead and plug those in.
So first let's plug in zero.
So prime zero so we're plugging in zero into the derivative.
So 12 x so X is zero.
Mine is to 12 times zero is zero.
And we're left with the minus to.
OK so what does that mean.
That means that to the left of one over six the derivative is negative.
So you can just mark all of this as negative.
All right
and let's plug in the next value prime of what that is or second test value.
We're plugging that into our derivative.
So we have 12 times one
minus two 12 times one is 12.
Minus two is 10.
So this is interesting because this one's positive while the other one was negative.
So because we get 10 when we plug in one that means that to the right of 1 over 6 the derivative is
positive.
Aha.
So this is our answer.
The function is decreasing.
To the left of one over six because a derivative is negative and the graph is increasing to the right
of 1 over 6 because the derivative is positive.
So for the final answer we have to specify the intervals of increase and the intervals of decrease.
So from 1 over 6 up to positive infinity it is increasing so from 1 over 6 up to positive infinity
and remember this is not a point.
This is a group of x values.
In other words this is an interval.
So in the interval we have from 1 over 6 which is approximately point 16 up to all the values greater
than 1 over 6.
The function is increasing.
And why is it increasing.
Because a derivative was positive in that interval.
On the other hand in the other interval which is the numbers that are less than 1 over 6 it is decreasing.
So from negative infinity up to 1 over 6
The graph is decreasing
these two are intervals of increase and decrease.
And that is our final answer.
All right.
This probably might be your first example applying derivatives into a problem in that case.
Welcome to the world of the application of derivatives.
As you go on you'll notice a lot of patterns.
You know many times where you need to do is find the derivative and then set it equal to zero and then
find the values left and right of the zeros etc. etc..
So we're going to see a lot of different problems that require the same approach.
All right so let's go over what we just did.
We wanted to find the intervals of increase and decrease of this function.
So step one is to find the derivative of the function.
We found it right here.
Step two is to find the values that make the derivative equal to zero or then make it undefined.
In this case nothing really makes it on the fine because there is no division.
All right.
So we're only checking for the values that make the derivative equal to zero.
To do that we took the derivative 12 X minus 2 we set it equal to zero and we solved for X that gave
us that the derivative is zero when X equals 1 over 6.
Finally because we have a value that makes a derivative equal to zero.
Our third step is to test for values left and right of this zero.
So we picked easy values less than 1 or 6.
We pegged 0 and greater than 1 over 6 we picked one.
Again you could have picked any number.
Remember you only have to pick one number to the left and one number to the right.
You do not have to pick several.
All right so if your values one of six you could have picked negative 10 for example to test to the
left instead of that we picked zero up because it's an easy number.
By the same token to test values to the right or greater than 1 over 6 You could have picked any value
greater could have picked two we could have picked ten we could have picked 100.
It doesn't matter.
But again we want to pick easy values as much as we can.
So we picked one after that we took these two test values 0 and 1 and we plugged them into the derivative.
I remember this is critical that you plug them in into the right function which is a derivative.
If you plug them in into the original function it is not going to work.
It's going to give you an incorrect answer.
So your test values always go in your derivative.
That's what I wrote down here.
You have to plug them into prime of x.
So we went ahead and we plugged in 0 to test to the left to 1 over 6 that gave us a negative number
to the left of negative 1 over 6.
The derivative is negative.
That means that the interval is decreasing.
Remember that negative derivative decreasing positive derivative increasing.
There you go.
And then we test that by plugging in one into the derivative.
That gave us a positive number 10.
So to the right of 1 over 6 the derivative is positive.
All right.
And finally just to write down or intervals.
We had that from 1 over six up to positive infinity.
So from here to the right it is increasing.
And on the other hand from negative infinity to 1 over 6.
So you come from the left and up to 1 over 6.
The graph is decreasing.
Why.
Because we know that to the left of one of six the derivative is negative.
Right.
And the last thing I wanted to show you is that this actually works well we just did.
So for a function f of x equals 6 x squared minus 2 x.
If we draw the graph and again you don't really need to know how you draw it.
I'm just going to show you as an example.
It's going to look something like this.
All right.
So it's a parabola.
And this is the x value 1 over 6.
So like we said from negative infinity.
So as you come from the left up to 1 over 6.
Notice that it's actually decreasing right as you come from the left.
The graph is going down it's going down it's going down and up until one of six after one over six.
Check it out.
The graph is actually going up going up going up going up.
So what we determined with our derivatives is actually true.
I'll repeat it once again from negative infinity up to 1 over 6.
The graph is actually doing what it's decreasing because it's going down.
And once we get to 1 over 6 then what happens is it starts going up and going up and going up up until
infinity.
So from 1 over 6 up until positive infinity it is increasing.
Hey calculus works.
All right.
Perfect.
Now let's go into our summary for this section in which we're going to go over the process that we just
did and where we're going to cover everything that we reviewed in this lesson.