So continuing on with this problem we're about to determine the limit of f of x as x approaches 1 from
the right limit of X as x approaches one from the right equals what.
Well let's build another table.
So by the way when you're approaching it from the left that means that the numbers are getting bigger.
Right.
Because if you have for example a number line
and you have one here that means that to the left of one have 0.9 zero point nine nine etc. up until
you get to 1 and then to the right of one you have one point zero or one let's divide these over here
we go
Warrenpoint won etc..
So once here if you approach it from the left the numbers keep getting bigger and bigger and bigger.
If you approach one from the right then the numbers need to get smaller and smaller and smaller.
All right.
So that's why here we are approaching it from the left.
Then the numbers that we have we're getting bigger.
We went from zero point nine to zero point nine nine nine.
We're going to do the opposite.
When you're approaching it from the right so as x approaches one from the right well we can pick a couple
of values that are close so we can say WAHM point one one point 0 1 and 1 point 0 0 1.
So you can probably tell that these numbers are getting smaller and smaller because again we're approaching
it from the right.
And again I have the values ready for you and the values are.
So for a one point one it's three point two for a one point zero and one is three point zero two.
And then for a one point zero zero one it's three point zero zero two.
Check it out as your eggs gets closer and closer to one from the right.
In other words as the numbers get smaller and smaller and closer to one the y values.
What are they approaching.
Well first you have 3.2 then three point zero two and three point zero zero two Ha.
It looks like it's approaching three as well.
Right.
It's getting closer and closer to three.
So the limit of f of x as x approaches 1 from the left is three and the limit of f of x x x approaches
1 from the right is 3.
So the limits are the same if you approach this one from the left.
The value is approaching is three.
And if you approach it from the right the value is also approaching 3.
So the limit from the left and from the right are equal.
That means that the limit exists but that's something that will cover in a later section.
What I want you to get though is again as we get closer from the left the numbers get bigger and bigger
and bigger.
And as you get closer from the right the numbers get smaller and smaller and smaller.
All right.
So how is this going to help you in business calculus.
Well in business calculus you will sometimes be asked to find limits or functions.
Sometimes you'll have a graph.
Sometimes you won't.
And it really depends on what type of problem you get.
But this is a good introduction to what limits are and some of these problems are straightforward some
other limits problems.
They actually require some sort of manipulation.
I will go into detail in later sections.
So right now let's just go to our summary.
All right.
So a quick summary for the intro to limits.
Again a Limits is a Y value.
And again I emphasize that because it's very important Ltd's the y value function is approaching.
That's another key word here as it's x value approaches a number.
So again as the input approaches a number the output approaches another number for limits.
The keyword is approaching.
It doesn't matter what the actual value is at the point.
Remember we did the piecewise function.
Jump from one point to the next.
It doesn't matter that the function is not defined for that x value.
What matters is if it's approaching the y value notation for limits is the following that is limit or
a limb of f of x which is your function as x approaches c and c is again the number they are approaching
the x value then that equals to L which is a limit.
Limits can be found as x approaches a number from the left or from the right.
Remember we did two examples.
If it's from the left the approaching x values get bigger.
So you for approaching 1 then you want to try 0.9 0.9 nine zero point nine nine nine etc. that's approaching
it from the left and the values that you're trying out.
They are smaller than one but they keep getting bigger and bigger and closer to one from the right.
It's the opposite if it's from the right they get smaller.
So the approaching x values they are bigger than 1 but they are getting smaller and smaller.
So 1.1 one point zero one one point zero zero one etc. etc..
All right so that's it for the intro to limits.
We'll learn a lot more about limits on how they work and what their properties are in the next sections.
So I'll see you in the next tutorial.