Are right and there are just a couple of other things that I wanted to cover.
Number one is each concept has a summary at the end.
So sometimes you know I explain concepts in one video maybe two videos or three videos but at the end
of each concept there's a summary for the concept where I go over what we just covered and I give you
bullet points for you to review.
So the summaries are really good for for example when you're taking a test in three days.
So you've learned the concept in the past but you want to refresh it.
You can go straight to the summary so that it's even fresher in your mind so be sure to check those
out.
The second thing I want to cover is I'll repeat myself often I'll repeat myself often I repeat myself
often.
What am I trying to tell you with this.
So you'll notice that in the tutorials I repeat things a lot.
So if I'm talking about a concept maybe I explain it and then we'll do the problem.
I explain it again.
And after the problems done I explain one more time what we did and here's why what if I told you that
the derivative of a function measures the slope of the line tangent to a graph for a given point.
What if I told you that once.
Do you think you will remember in five minutes what I just told you now 10 minutes in an hour tomorrow
for the test.
Of course not.
There are things here that you won't remember.
If we only mention it once.
So as I mentioned concepts over and over they started getting into your head.
Yes.
It can be annoying but that's a way to learn.
And that's something that I've learned with my students over the years.
The more that I repeat concepts the more familiar they become with them and the better it is for everybody
because at the moment of the test you'll be ready.
So when I start repeating myself Please don't hate me it'll help you learn faster and better.
All right.
So third thing is learn only what's relevant to you.
So for example let's say that your class is a summer class so it's shorter than the regular fall or
spring class and maybe your professor says all right in this basic calculus class we're not going to
cover marginal analysis.
So what do you do.
You do not do the videos for marginal analysis.
Hey Time is precious.
There are twenty two plus hours of content in this course.
Learn only what's relevant to you.
I do not recommend you learning topics that are not going to be on your test that are not going to be
on your exams.
So it's funny because if you ask the professor if something is going to be in the exam they will tell
you.
Well if we covered it it's fair game.
So look at the syllabus.
Pay attention to what's done in class and based on that come to this course and then study what's relevant
is to not try to go over every single topic just on what's going to be covered in your specific class.
All right the next one is an interesting one.
So for some people I speak too slowly and for some others I speak too quickly.
So thankfully you can actually slow down and speed up videos.
So if my voice is getting too slow and too annoying or if I'm speaking too fast for you you can actually
just go ahead and do more work faster.
Whichever is better for you.
Also always feel free to pause the videos or rewind to take notes.
All right.
If I said something that didn't make any sense at all or if you need to take notes.
Go ahead and pause it.
Don't just place through the video into at speed.
All right.
That's not going to help you at all.
You can speed it up a little bit but you need to be taking notes at all times.
That is the only way to learn.
And quickly let me show you how to slow down or speed up the video.
So let's say you're watching one of my videos and let's say I'm speaking too slowly and you want to
speed it up.
You can actually go down here and you can say all right let me put the speed at one point twenty five
x and the video is going to be quicker and the same way if I'm speaking too quickly or you would rather
slow it down to take notes.
You can always go back here and press 0.75 X and again everybody's different.
Some people like to go quicker.
Some people like to go slower.
That's the beauty of an online course.
You can shoot it too which ever way you prefer but my point is just put it at whatever speed you feel
comfortable doing something else.
Let's say you covered a topic a month ago and then you have a test coming up where you could do is you
can go over the videos again and you can do it in 1.5 or maybe 2 x beat if it's comfortable for you
and you could do that just to review quickly what you learned one or two months ago.
All right.
So that is how you change the speed of a video right and for the last thing here when your topic is
not covered write to me.
So my goal is to have the most complete business calculus course on the internet.
I've made sure to include many many topics that are covered in your class.
However not every business calculus class is the same.
Maybe at your institution it's taught a little bit differently and there are topics that I did not have.
So please write to me and let me know if there are any topics that you do not see covered either.
I'm working on a video to include the topic or I'll point you in the right direction so I'll point you
to another video where you can actually learn the topic.
And it's not going to be a random videos.
They're going to be videos that I picked personally because I know that they teach it well like I'm
going to say a couple of times in the future.
I want this to be a five star of course.
So again if your topic is not covered I will definitely look for a way to help you out because I want
you to pass the class.
All right.
And one more thing I wanted to mention.
Didn't feel that it deserved its own bullet point but the Course is designed to be used with headphones
so it's 20:17.
You should have some sort of headphones or ear buds or whatever.
If you don't that's OK you can still watch the course without headphones but I can definitely tell you
that it sounds better and you learn better if you use headphones with of course.
So again thank you for being here and I'll see you in the next video.