OK.
So we actually just found the indefinite integral for a function and ready.
But let's formalize the process.
How do we indicate that we're finding an indefinite integral.
It turns out there's a special notation for this.
And let's see what this says right now.
By the way the notation is going to look a little bit weird a little bit different but as we do more
and more problems it will become very easy.
So to find the indefinite integral for a function it's going to look something like this.
So first you have the integral symbol which is kind of like an S but a little bit more deligated.
So it looks like this.
All right.
This is the integral symbol.
So always together with this integral symbol is the term dx.
All right so you always have this s DX right as d x always go together.
Then you have the actual function that you're finding the indefinite integral for all right.
So the function goes in the modal.
OK so this is read as the integral of after tax income.
So this is read as
integral
of fallbacks
and then we say that this is equal to.
Here we're going to put the actual indefinite integral.
So our briquets have X
plus C.
Right.
That is our actual indefinite integral
right.
So this is the notation.
So if you see what's on the left and you have integral of f of x then you know you need to find the
indefinite integral of this function.
And the result is going to look something like this.
This will be the antiderivative plus a constant OCHA.
So let's do a couple of examples to put this in practice.
So we already know for example that the derivative of x squared is 2x.
So we're finding the indefinite integral of 2 x.
Remember your dx what is there's going to be equal to so indefinite integral to x is x squared plus
C All right.
And remember something to verify that your answer is right.
You just need to take the derivative of the indefinite integral to check if it gives you back your to
X..
All right so with indefinite integrals to check.
Answer.
You simply find
the derivative of the antiderivative.
So uppercase f prime of X if that makes sense.
So remember it when you're finding an integral finding a function whose derivative is this function
that you have.
So if you differentiate the answer it should give you back this original function.
That's all we said here.
To check your answer just find the derivative of the antiderivative.
So let's take the derivative of this indefinite integral so x squared plus C and again it doesn't matter
the specific value of c..
It's just a constant.
So it's going to go away anyways because the derivative of a constant is zero.
So the derivative of x squared is to X and the derivative of a constant is zero.
All right so to X over here and 2 x over here.
So we did the problem right.
Let's do one other example.
So we have an integral and by the way drawing this line correctly it's probably going to take a couple
of tries.
Don't expect to get it right on the first time.
Again it's kind of like an --.
But Ellen gave it.
So it's a little bit longer than usual and it goes up kind of like this.
And by the way this is called the integral symbol.
OK.
And like I said this integral symbol always goes together with DX.
So another example is like we did before the derivative of 2 x squared is for X right.
So let's find the indefinite integral of 4 x.
All right.
So we do the integral for x dx and I don't like to give you extra information that you won't need.
We don't need to know why this side looks like this or the DX come from.
Just know that when you see this notation interval of 4 x dx that means to find the indefinite integral
of this function for X and you could also put it in parentheses it makes it clearer.
Sometimes you can do that as well.
All right.
So again we know that the antiderivative of this function is 2 x squared.
And then remember that for indefinite integrals we always put a plus C all right.
So you always put the seat.
This is very important.
If you just say OK the indefinite integral of 4 x 2 x squared in theory that is not correct because
it's incomplete.
You always always have to include this plus C for indefinite integrals because again remember you're
finding a family of functions not a single function by itself.
All right.
So let's go ahead and check her answer.
We'll find the derivative of this indefinite integral.
And let's see what that gives us.
Two x squared plus C the derivative of this is going to be a derivative of the first term is for X and
again the derivative of a constant is zero.
All right.
And by the way here I said to check the answer find the derivative of the antiderivative.
In theory that's correct.
But what we actually did here is we found the derivative of the whole indefinite integral.
So we're including the plus C.
So let me go ahead and fix that so that we are consistent.
In theory both ways are right.
But let's take out the prime from here and let's go ahead and add the plus the.
And we'll get the derivative of the whole thing.
Trying to remember this is a comma for this word and this is the prime for this.
So in other words what we have is to check the answer you find the derivative of the indefinite integral
of the antiderivative plus C and that's exactly what we did here.
The indefinite integral for example of two X was X squared plus C and then to check or answer it we
found the derivative of this x squared plus C.
All right so the derivative of x squared is just 2 x and the derivative of a constant is always 0.
So remember this plus see when you get the derivative of this.
It's always going to give you zero.
Same thing for down here.
We found that the indefinite interval of 4 x is 2 x squared plus C and remember you always put the plus
C and then we found the derivative of this indefinite interval of 2 x squared plus the derivative of
2 x squared for X and the derivative of the C is zero.
So it's just for x.
If the answer that you get here is equal to the original function then you're integrating then you know
your answer is correct.
Same thing here here.
The original function was to X and when we tested it we got back to X.
So we know that the answer is correct.
Now you might be thinking OK so for these functions we knew them by memory that the antiderivative is
x squared and that for 4 x the antiderivative is 2 x squared.
So is there a process for finding these indefinite integrals.
In other words if I gave you a function can we find the indefinite integral.
The answer for the most part is yes.
So next we'll go over some properties and some rules for finding indefinite integrals.
Now in case you were wondering why they're called indef. it's because you have as an answer a family
of functions so an infinite number of functions that have this form X squared plus C for example.
Is there such thing as a definite integral.
You bet and we'll see that later on.
But for now though we'll keep working with indefinite integrals.
So again this is the notation for finding any definite end to rule.
It's this integral symbol V.L. unjaded as this one always goes with the dx and the function that you're
integrating goes in the middle.
This is read as integral of f of x dx.
All right.
And then the answer to that is simply the antiderivative of this function f of x plus the constant c.
Right and we always do plus C we did two examples we found the antiderivative and we put it plus C and
then we checked our answer.
And again you can always check your answer by finding the derivative of the indefinite integral.
So you find the derivative of uppercase f of x plus C and that should give you back this function that
you integrate it in the first place.
Don't forget Always put your plus C.