So of course the derivative is a very important concept.
And we'll talk about it a little bit more.
But before we do that let's just dive in into an example.
Let's say that we're want to find
the derivative
of fallbacks equals x squared.
So we are given a function x squared.
And we want to find the derivative of that function to do that.
We have to use the definition of a derivative which is what we just cover now.
F of x plus H.
Minus 5 x
over h as age approaches zero.
That is the definition of a derivative.
So what we're going to do is we're actually going to go ahead and use f x.
All right so if we have for example f of x plus H That means that we need to plug in X plus H into f
right f as a rule.
Remember how we talked about functions and how this is the input.
So basically X plus H is going to be the input for x squared.
So this is equal to.
And again it will do limits as h approaches zero.
Of and let's Poyan X plus H into x squared.
That's going to give us X plus H.
Squared.
Right.
We're plugging in X plus H into this function and this function says take the input and square it.
So we're squaring X plus H.
All right.
And then mine is 5 x Well f of x itself is just x squared.
So we can say x squared.
All right over h o k is looking kind of weird but you'll see what happens just now.
So again this is equal to limit as h approaches zero of what what we'll do is we'll actually expand
this X plus H squared.
So remember we're going to foil if we have X plus age times x plus H.
In other words x plus H squared because you're multiplying it by itself twice.
We're going to go ahead and foil
we're going to multiply the first so X and X then the outer x and h and enter h n x and then the last
h h.
All right.
So first we're going to multiply the first X times x is x squared.
Then the outer X times H is x h.
Let's just write it as H.
X which is the same thing.
So that's a plus.
And then we have the inner which is H times x.
So we're going to do plus H times x again.
And finally we're going to do the last which is H times h.
So that's going to give us h squared right and let's simplify we have x squared and then we have H x
plus H X..
So you're adding something to itself twice.
That means you're going to have two of them.
So that's going to be two checks.
Right.
And finally we have plus H squared.
OK so we're going to take this and we're going to put it right here.
So what we did was we took X plus H squared and we just multiplied it.
All right so now we have x squared plus 2 H x plus H squared right.
This is X plus H squared.
And then we have minus X squared right
I know this looking really weird but we're almost there.
All right.
Everything over H.
Now what happens.
We have x squared and then we have minus x squared.
So these two cancel each other out.
All right.
It's like saying three minus three is zero.
So keep going.
And what do we have.
We have limit h approaches zero of what we have to H.
X
plus H squared over H.
Right.
Now what do you see here.
What you see here is that you have two terms on the top you have two H x and you have h squared and
you have an H on the bottom.
So what can you do.
Well you can actually do is you can actually factor the H on the top because both terms have it.
So it's going to look like this limits well limit as age approaches zero.
So what we'll do is on the tub we're going to factor out the h because both terms have it.
So we're going to put it outside right and then we're going to multiply.
So if this term is to H x and we take the h.
What do we have left to x.
And if this term is H squared and we take out one h.
What do we have left just the other H plus H.
Over H.
What do we have now.
Well we have h over h.
So the reason why we factored is that we can actually cancel out these two H's.
So if one goes away and this one goes away remember that if you have something on the top and then you
divide by that same something on the bottom both cancel out.
It's like saying 6 over 6 just becomes 1.
So you can cancel both of them out.
Now to finish up we have lym of
2 x plus H as age approaches zero.
By the way remember when we talked about limits are mnemonics says to find the limb just plug it in.
What would have happened if we had tried plugging this in here.
Well what do we need to plug in.
We need to plug in zero for H.
Right.
But we have an H on the bottom.
So if you plug in at zero on the bottom What do you get.
You get division by zero.
Remember that when you get division by zero and you get zero on the top as well.
Then at that point you need to try something else.
This is something else that we're trying right now so that you can plug in the zero directly but we
had to manipulate it.
Now however we don't have a denominator down here.
So to find the limb just plug it in.
So limit of 2 x plus H.
H approaches zero.
That's going to be equal to 2 x plus 0 which is equal to just 2 x.
All right.
So after all of that we have the derivative of x squared is given by 2x.
Interesting.
What does that mean.
Well this is a very awesome result.
And let me show you what it means.
So again the original function is x squared
it's derivative is to X.
OK so let's draw the graph of x squared quickly.
It is just a parabola.
So it's going to be a very simple graph.
So we have our parabola
Okay perfect.
So this is the function x squared.
The derivative is to X to remember how we talked about a derivative is a measure of the rate of change.
Let's go ahead and plug in three.
Just a random number.
Let's plug in three into this function so f of 3
equals 1.
So we do it three squared which is nine right.
So this point would be somewhere around here.
So this is three and let's say that nine is here.
And the point is right here right.
So what if I want to find the instantaneous rate of change at this point at the Point 3 9.
This is 3:9 How do I find that instantaneous rate of change.
Well remember that we said that the instantaneous rate of change is given by the tangent line to the
graph.
At that point so if you draw a line like this this is a tangent line that touches the graph at exactly
that point the slope of this line will be the instantaneous rate of change.
But hold up that's where the derivative comes in.
OK.
Remember that derivative is the slope of the line tangent at points.
So literally all you need to do to find the instantaneous rate of change at this point is to get the
x value and you plug it into the derivative so
instantaneous rate of change
at X equals three.
You just take this three and you plug it into the derivative.
So this is going to be equal to
2 x replugging and 3 for X is going to be 2 times 3.
That is 6.
Boom 6 is instantaneous rate of change here when X equals 3.
See how awesome a derivative is.
Once you get a function and you find it's derivative all you need to do to find the read of change at
any point in the graph is to plug the x value into the derivative.
What if you want to find it when X equals 10.
When you find the instantaneous rate of change when X equals 10.
Well we just plug it into the derivative two times 10 is 20.
Boom.
There you go.
See you don't have to deal with drawing lines.
You don't have to deal with getting a c k.
You don't need to deal with finding a limit.
Once you have the derivative all you need to do is you plug in the x value into the derivative and that
gives you the instantaneous rate of change at that x value.
See how cool this is Perfect's one quick thing I want to mention we're going to cover this in the next
section.
But the way to know it's a derivative.
There are several ways but the main way to do it is just like the original function f of x but with
this little apostrophe here this means a derivative of f of x and the way you say that is f prime
of X
right so f prime of X is the derivative of f of x that is just the notation and we'll go over a couple
of more notations in the next section.
There's one thing I would like to mention about derivatives.
So the derivative can mean one of two things.
All right so a derivative
can either be
a derivative function
or it can be the instantaneous rate of change.
All right so what does this mean.
So for example if I have a function which is f of x equals x squared which is the one that we did
it's derivative as we found out is actually 2 x.
Right.
So if we have the function f of x x equals squared and it tells you to find the derivative the answer
that I'm looking for is 2 x.
In theory though this is the derivative function.
OK.
Because it is a function that comes from another function.
And you can plug stuff into it but it's called a derivative as well.
However if I tell you find the instantaneous rate of change of x squared when X equals 2 while remember
instantaneous rate of change is given by the derivative.
And I want to find it at X equals 2.
So what I'll do is I'll plug into into this function.
So in 16 is rate of change I.R.S.
add X equals to we're going to go ahead and plug into into this derivative function.
So it's going to be two times two equals four.
All right.
So this is called a derivative.
And this is called the derivative.
You see the difference.
One is the generic function used to find instantaneous rates of change for the whole function.
And another one is the actual instantaneous rate of change at a certain point.
So if I ask you to find the instantaneous rate of change at X equals 9 you're going to go ahead and
plug in nine into this derivative.
If I tell you to find the instantaneous rate of change when X equals negative 5 you're going to go ahead
and plug in negative 5 into this derivative.
Etc. etc..
So again the derivative can either be the function or an actual instantaneous rate of change.
So how do you know which one to look for.
Well you always have to get the function somehow.
So sometimes in our problem you'll be asked.
OK.
Find the derivative of this function.
In that case we're going to learn about some rules that you can use to find derivative functions like
this.
But if in a problem you're asked find how this is changing when X equals something.
That means that first you have to find the derivative function and then you have to plug in the number
here if this is a make a lot of sense right now don't worry.
All right.
Just make sure that you know that derivative can mean one of two things either the function itself or
the result that you get when you plug in a number into the derivative function.