All right so let's put the constant rule into action.
So our first exercise says find prime of x so find the derivative of f of x if f of x equals three.
Right.
So go ahead and pause the video and do your thing.
All right so looking for a prime of X
and if we look at f of x it's equal to 3.
That means that it's a constant function and the constant rule says that the derivative of a constant
function is always 0.
Therefore the derivative of this is zero that is it.
Believe it or not we are done.
All right so our next exercise says find f prime of X if f of x equals negative twenty five thousand
three hundred and thirty one.
Go ahead and pause the video and try to do it
all right.
So we're looking for an Prime of X
and if you look at this function f of x it looks like a big negative number right.
Negative twenty five thousand 331 at the end of the day.
This is just a number.
There are no axes no letters in this.
So this is just a number.
Doesn't matter how big it is or how small.
If f of x equals a number then that means that the derivative is zero
so same thing.
Derivative of a constant is always zero.
Doesn't matter how big or how small the number is
all right.
So for our alast exercise we're being asked to find a prime of x 1 f of x equals zero.
Hmm interesting.
So go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so prime of X of the function f of x equals zero.
Well again 0 is just a number and the derivative of a number is zero.
So the answer here as well is 0.
So the function is equal to zero.
The derivative is equal to zero.
All right.
So just like we saw whenever a function equals a number with no letters its derivative will always be
zero.
All right.
And that never changes.
That is it for the constant rule.