All right.
So let's do a couple of exercises for functions.
So I'm going to give you a couple of functions and you're going to have to plug in a couple of inputs
into it and get the outputs.
So in this example it says if X equals x plus 3 Find f of to half of 10 and F of negative 20.
So you can go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
Once you have done the problems you can pause it and I'll do the solution with you and we'll look at
the solution together.
So go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So let's go ahead and get these done.
So function is X plus three.
And we're going to plug in these values over here.
So let's start with half of two.
So remember all we need to do is substitute this ax that we have here by the number where plug it in.
So in this case it's two.
So that's going to be two plus three
that equals five.
And actually if we build a small table here of input and output remember axes and put the Y is the output.
So for the input of two the output is five
right.
Great.
So let's move on to the next one of 10.
So again what we do is simply plug in 10 over here.
So that's going to be 10 plus three
and that's going to be 13.
All right.
So for the input of 10 the output is going to be 13
great.
Now let's plug in our last number so of negative 20.
So we're going to go ahead and plug it in right here.
So we have negative 20 plus 3
so if you owe $20 that's represented by the negative you owe money.
All right.
Oh $20.
And then you pay three back.
You're going to oh 17.
It's a negative 20 plus three is going to give you negative 17.
All right.
So for the input of negative 20 output or why value is negative 17.
That's it.
So we just plugged in these three inputs into the function and we got our corresponding outputs right
here.
All right.
So first second exercise here we have an example that's a little bit more interesting than just x plus
three we have x squared minus x.
So that means whatever input we give this function we're going to square it.
So we're going to multiplied by itself and then we're going to subtract the same input and go ahead
and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so now we should be good to go and let's work through the solution and see how you do it.
So first we're going to take this three and we're going to plug it into the function.
So half three equals what.
So we plug it in right here.
So we have three squared
minus three three squared is nine minus three is six.
There we go.
All right let's go to the next one.
Let's plug in zero
of zero.
We're going to plug it in right here.
So we have zero squared minus zero.
So zero time zero zero.
And then we have minus zero.
Of course that gives us zero at the end.
So plugging in zero gives us back an output of zero.
Of course this is not always the case with all functions.
This is just for this example.
Sometimes you plug in zero and you get some other numbers.
And finally let's play again are negative too.
So half of negative to equals we plug in negative to read here so negative 2 squared.
Mine is and then negative too.
So we do minus negative too.
All right.
So we have negative 2 squared so it's negative two times and negative to remember that a negative times
a negative is a positive.
And that's something that we'll talk about often in this tutorial.
So negative times negative is a positive.
So negative two terms and negative 2 is positive for all right.
And then we have minus negative too.
But it turns out that this mine is here.
It's like it's multiplying this negative to even though it's subtracting when you have a negative in
front of something that changes the sign of that something.
So negative times a negative gives you a positive.
All right.
So those negative times negative becomes plus to and that gives us six.
There we go.
So plugging in three gives us six plug in in negative two gives us six and plug it in zero gives us
zero.
All right.
So for the last exercise here's kind of an interesting one of x equals 45.
And we need to plug in three 11 and twenty thousand fifty nine.
All right.
So a pause a video and give it a shot.
All right so how is it a go with this one.
Or is it a little bit weird maybe knew what to do.
Maybe you didn't.
Well this function is in fact a little bit weird because if you notice there's no X..
So where do you plug in the input.
The answer is you don't.
It turns out that the output for this function is always 45 because it doesn't have an X..
You cannot plug in anything into it.
So if we do of three that's going to be 45.
All right half of 11 is also going to be 45.
And what do you think this one is going to be.
Twenty thousand and 59
a.
It's going to be 45.
That doesn't change.
So it turns out that all the y values for this function are always going to be 45.
This is called a constant function the y value never changes.
All right.
So good.
We just went over a couple of examples of plugging numbers into functions just to get you used to this
idea.
You're going to be plugging numbers into functions.
I can promise you until the day of the final exam.
So this is a concept that you'll be doing over and over and over.
Now as I always like to say I give you a couple of problems to get you used to it.
You need to do your homework.
So whatever problems your professor assigns to you he need to do it.
That is the only way you'll learn if you only do these three exercises and then you call it a day.
You're not going to learn basic calculus and I'm not just saying this.
This is true.
I've had students that take tutoring with me and they only study when we tutor.
So in that one hour that we just go over problems and concepts that is the only time they dedicate to
base his calculus.
Guess what.
A lot of those students do not pass because they don't like to put in the work to learn math.
You really really need to practice.
That is the only way of passing.
So I can tell you right now the problems that I gave you here there are not enough and I don't like
to give you too many problems because what I want you to do is to learn the concept do a couple of problems
and then do whatever your professor assigns to you.
The reason why is that whatever your professor or science see you is where you're going to end up seeing
and quizzes and exams.
All right.
So it's very important that you learn the concepts whether you want to do it in class or you want to
learn it here.
But the homework that you get you need to do.
All right.
That's going to be a theme throughout these tutorials.
You've got to put in the work.
And I'm here to guide you and to help you learn the concepts more easily.
All right.
So that was it for our topic of functions and I'll see you in the next tutorial.