Are right so let's formalize the concept and the definition of a derivative is so a derivative is a
measure of how a function is changing.
So that's what a derivative does it tells you how the function is changing at a specific point.
And again the word derivative can refer to either the derivative function or to the actual rate of change
at a specific point and to know which one you're talking about.
Well you have to look at the problem that you're given.
Again let me repeat this once more.
If you're told.
Find the derivative of for example f of x equals execute then its derivative will be 3 x squared and
you don't have to worry about how I got that answer.
We're going to we're going to learn that later.
This would be the derivative.
But this is also the derivative function right because you have one function.
And from there you get another function.
Now if I ask you to find the rate of change of x cubed at a specific point.
So for example I want to find the rate of change when X equals four.
What I'll do is I'll go ahead and grab the number four.
And we're going to plug it in to this derivative function.
So
rate of change
when X equals four.
We're going to plug in four into this function three times.
For squared
so that's three times sixteen and three times 16 is just 64.
All right.
So this is called the derivative.
But then this instantaneous rate of change at a specific point is also called the derivative
right.
And I'm repeating this a lot but I want to make sure that you get it where derivative can either refer
to the derivative function or to a specific rate of change at a specific point.
And the way to denote a derivative mathematically like we just saw is limits of X plus H.
Mine is for VAX over age as age approaches zero.
So remember to find them just plug it in.
However in this case we cannot just plug in zero for H because it is in the denominator plugging in
zero.
H is going to give us a denominator of zero which is not good.
So to find derivatives using this formula where you need to do is you need to just go ahead and plug
in these values into the formula and then at some point you'll be able to cancel out the H's one on
top and one on the bottom and at that point you can actually go ahead and plug in zero for each.
The really good thing is we have derivative rules so you don't really have to use this all the time.
That would be really annoying.
We're going to learn about derivative rules in the next section.
And basically a derivative rule allows you to find the derivative for any function that you want very
easily.
However your professor might want you to learn this formula so I don't really have a mnemonic for this
one.
This is just pretty much something that you need to write a couple times until you actually remember
how it looks.
And again it's really not that hard on the top you have f of x plus H minus f x everything over H.
And then you have a limit as h approaches zero.
We'll do a couple of examples on how to get derivatives using this formula.
But again we're going to get into derivative rules later on.
So one last thing before we go to the summary.
I just want you to be aware of a certain word and the word is differentiation.
What is differentiation differentiation is the process
of finding
a derivative.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
So when you're asked to differentiate something you're just finding it's derivative.
So for example if I tell you let's differentiate x squared
then we differentiate it and we get two x.
We just found it's derivative and again like we said derivative can either mean the derivative function
or an actual rate of change.
So if we say let's differentiate x squared to find the rate of change at X equals 5 then we have to
plug in 5 into this function.
That's going to give us 10 and 10 again.
Is a derivative
when X equals five
So differentiation it can either mean find this derivative function or find the actual derivative for
aspecific x.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
All right so let's go over a summary of this very important section.
So as the points in a second line get closer together the second approximates a tangent line.
This is a really cool thing because you have a second line.
It measures the average rate of change.
But as a point get closer or like we said as the H gets smaller then this line gets closer and closer
to a tangent line.
And remember the tangent line is what we want for instantaneous rate of change.
Then when you get your tangent line we have that the slope of a line tangent to a point in the curve
gives you the instantaneous rate of change.
So if you have a curve and you have a specific point of that curve and you draw a line that touches
the graph at that specific point the slope of that line will give you the instantaneous rate of change.
And then we have that a derivative is given by this formula.
Remember we have limits of half of X plus H
minus F X over h h approaches zero.
This my friends is a definition of a derivative.
So if you're given a function you need to plug it in here and you need to find the limit that's going
to give you back the derivative function with the derivative function.
You can find the instantaneous rate of change at any point for that function.
So as an example we did f of x equals x squared.
So once we plug in x squared over here we ended up getting
2 x 2 x is our derivative function.
So with this derivative function we can find the rate of change at any point of x squared.
All right.
So don't get them confused f of x is the original function to x is the derivative function of x squared
and derivatives measure what they measure.
Rate of Change
measure rate of change of a function
right.
This is what I derivative does and again derivatives are fundamental to calculus.
So you should totally know that when ever you're asked to find the rate of change of a function or whenever
you're asked to find oh let's find out how this function is changing.
You need to use derivatives.
Right now the word derivative can either mean the derivative function or the rate of change at a specific
point.
And this happens a lot or both definitions are used.
That's the case in most books.
So for example if you're asked to find the derivative of x squared first then you're always going to
do is find the derivative function right which is also called the derivative.
But if you're asked to find the derivative at a specific point first you need to find the function anyways.
The derivative function you always have to find it anyways.
And then you plug in your number here.
All right and finally to differentiate means to find a derivative.
Yes it's actually a verb.
Isn't that crazy.
But yeah that's the way it works.
All right.
So I have the last three points.
So number one is the tangent line to a point is the instantaneous rate of change at that point which
is the derivative.
All right.
So we were talking about instantaneous rate of change.
You find the derivative because that's exactly what it is.
All right.
And to be more specific the derivative is the instantaneous rate of change which is the slope of this
tangent line not the line itself but the slope.
Remember the derivative in general is just a value right.
It's a rate of change.
So it's equal to the slope of this tangent line.
Then to find the derivative function of f of x so if we're given a function f of x y you need to do
is you need to plug that function f of x into the definition of the derivative.
And then you actually go ahead and find the limit remember.
And we just did this.
But I'll repeat it again.
The definition of a derivative is a limit of half of X plus H.
Mine is fallbacks over h as h approaches zero.
This is the definition of a derivative.
So if you want to find the derivative function of f of x you take f of x.
You plug it in here you do some manipulation which will do a couple of examples off and then you find
the limit that's going to give you the derivative function then to find the instantaneous rate of change
of a function for a specific point.
You simply plug in the x value of the points into the derivative function which is the one that you've
found by doing this.
So once you have your derivative function you can use it to find the instantaneous rate of change at
any points in that function.
OK so going back.
All right so we just cover derivatives.
If this video didn't make a lot of sense please just go back put me in a 1.5 speed or whatever you want
to do but watch it again.
You passing this class depends on you understanding this video.
All right you need to understand what's going on here.
You need to understand what a derivative does is to understand how we get derivatives need to understand
where they come from.
And you need to understand in general what you do with derivatives.
All right.
We have a lot more videos for derivatives.
We're going to see the applications of derivatives.
So how they are applied to business and we're also going to see the different rules that we can use
to find derivatives of functions.
So like I mentioned before you don't have to use this formula all the time.
That would be a pain.
There are several rules that we can use to find derivatives of functions that make it easier for us
to find those derivatives.
All right.
So again super important topic.
I recommend you watch it again even if it is in 1.5 2x whatever you want to do.
Just go ahead and watch it again if it didn't make a lot of sense.
So I'll definitely see you at the next tutorial.