Hello they're welcome to another session of limitless calculus.
Today we're going to cover domain and range of a function.
So we already said that X represents or input so X is our input
and Y is our output
and here come into play the concept of domain and range.
So first let's start with domain
so domain of a function is the group of allowable
put in quotes allowable x values.
In other words the domain is a group of allowable input for a function.
You might be thinking.
Wait what.
What do you mean allowed.
Am I not allowed to plug in any number I want into a function.
Well not really.
There are certain numbers that you cannot plug in into certain functions.
And the reason for that is basically divided into three different cases.
And these cases are number one is division by zero.
The second case is
even root's
of negative numbers.
And number three would be practical applications practical.
OK so we're actually going to go into each one of these cases and see what they mean.
But just so you know if the function does not have division by zero if it does not have even rude of
negative numbers and if it's not limited by practical applications then the domain is all real numbers.
So let me put that down here.
So typically
I'll put D for a domain the equals all real numbers
except for the situations 1 2 and 3 which are again division by zero even root of negative numbers or
practical applications.
So except on two
so again the domain of a function is all real numbers except in the cases when you have one of these
three present and they could actually be together so you could see one in two or you could see one and
three etc. etc..
Now let's go over into division by zero.
So
division by zero.
Ha.
The infamous division by zero.
In case you've been living under a rock for the past thousand years let's get this out of the way in
math.
Division by zero is a big no no.
OK.
Division by zero is no bueno.
You cannot divide by zero.
It's not allowed.
And math.
So why is this.
Well let's say you have six apples sorry bananas.
I still love you and you want to split those six apples between three friends.
So six apples over three friends is two apples per friend.
But what if you have six apples they need to give away and you have no friends.
And I swear this is not based on my real life.
Please help.
So six apples over zero people think about that for a second.
Six apples over zero people.
That does not make any sense.
OK.
So you cannot divide by zero.
Now mathematicians their fancy and they came up with this.
Anything divided by zero is undefined not zero not infinity just undefined.
So division
by zero is undefined.
That is a name they came up with.
So since division by zero is not allowed.
What happens when you have something like this for example half of X equals 1 over X minus 3.
What do we do here.
Well we can plug in different numbers.
But let's pick a special number let's pick three to plug in.
So we have won over three because we're Xs we need to put it three now because that is our input.
Three minus three.
Ha.
Interesting.
So now we have what won over three minus three which is zero.
Ha.
So here we have division by zero.
This is then on the find.
That means that we cannot plug in three into this function.
It's not part of the allowable values for this function f of x therefore the domain of this function
right here domain is
all real numbers.
Except for
what do you think the answer is except for three.
Why.
Well because when you plug in into this function you get division by zero.
Therefore you can not plug in three into this function.
That is why the domain which is equal to all allowable input is equal to all real numbers except for
three because three makes it divide by zero.
And again we do not like division by zero.
If you're wondering what a real number is we'll go into that in the next section actually which is where
we talk about the even root of negative numbers.
OK so let's go over that even roots of negative numbers and see what the heck that means.
Even roots of negative numbers
OK.
So before we get into this let's go over all specific examples of square roots.
So when we talk about squaring a number it means multiply that number by itself.
So two squared is equal to two times two is equal to four.
Three squared equals three times three which is equal to nine etc. etc..
And remember you can actually square negative numbers as well and negative two squared is negative two
times negative to remember that a negative times a negative is a positive.
That is also equal to four.
So two squared is equal to four and negative two squared is equal to four.
And by the way if you do not remember this one and put it right here on the right.
Remember that a negative times a negative
equals a positive
and the negative over a negative also equals a positive.
And of course positive times positive positive and positive over positive is also positive.
So the only time you're going to switch sides is when you have different signs OK.
So this is all positive.
But if you have for example a positive times a negative
that gives you a negative and if you have a positive
over negative that also gives you a negative.
All right.
So again we have three cases either everything's positive in which case everything is going to be positive.
There's no negatives anywhere.
The second case is where everything's negative multiplying or dividing.
In that case you're going to get a positive.
All right.
So as a general rule if you're multiplying or dividing two things of the same sign that's going to give
you a positive that can be both negative or they can be both positive.
Now where things get interesting is when you have stuff with different signs.
So when you have a positive terms a negative or a negative times a positive or a positive over a negative
or a negative over a positive that's always going to be negative results.
So when you have different signs the result is negative.
When you have the same sign the result is positive.
OK.
So going back to our roots was one more example of a negative being squared so negative three times
negative three negative three times negative three is just nine.
All right.
The point is if you square something it's always going to be a positive number.
Here we have four here we have nine here we have four.
And here we have nine as well.
So when you square something it can never be negative.
So remember if you find the square root of a number for example the square root of nine it's going to
be what number gives you nine will you multiply it by itself the answer is actually three but not only
three.
It's plus or minus three because that three could be positive three times three equals nine and that
three can also be negative because negative 3 squared is also 9.
Now what happens if I ask you for the square root of negative 9.
Remember we're looking for a number so that when you multiply that number by itself it gives you negative
9 but is that even possible because we already said that when you multiply something by itself is always
going to give you a positive number.
It matter if it's positive or negative 3.
OK.
So there's really no answer for this.
You cannot get the square root of a negative number.
So just when you thought math cannot get any more weird mathematicians came up with a solution for this
problem.
Imaginary numbers Oh yes good old imaginary numbers.
So imaginary numbers.
That isn't weird stuff right there man.
All right.
Yes there is such a thing.
We don't need to go into details because you won't be using them in class but just know that you cannot
put numbers into a function that will give you an even root of a negative number.
Now when I say even roots what I mean is this.
So
remember that even numbers are 2 4 6 8 etc..
So you could have even roots like a square root.
Remember that if you do not put here a number it is assumed to be a to have the fourth root.
You could have six root etc..
This is an even root because the root over here is an even number.
OK.
So quickly going back to our imaginary numbers we say that the square root of negative 9 is 3.
I.
An imaginary number.
Again we're not going to go into detail.
It's pretty much the same as a square root but with a 9 next to it.
But you won't be using them in class.
So no need to worry about imaginary numbers.
OK.
So again if you haven't even root of a negative number which is this is an example of that because we
have the square root of negative 9 then that means that you're going to get imaginary numbers.
So this is not good.
So how does that all play into what we're trying to find which is domain.
Well let's do a quick example over here.
What happens if you have f x equals
X minus five.
All right.
So let's play in a couple numbers of five.
For example is the square root of five minus five that gives as the square root of 0 is zero.
All right so far so good.
What if we plug in 10
that gives us 10 minus 5 equals the square root of 5.
OK.
Also good.
Let's plug in to.
So we have to minus five to minus 5 is negative 3.
What do we have here.
We have the square root of a negative number.
Can we get that can it can we get a real number if we try to find the solution to this.
No.
Remember that when you have a negative number under an even rudes that's always going to be imaginary.
So if you have a negative number and the route is even that is going to give you an imaginary number.
So this means that for this function f of x 2 is not in the domain because when you plug into you get
a square root of a negative number.
And again that gives imaginary numbers which we don't deal with.
OK.
So let's try plugging in another number.
Let's plug in one.
So we have 1 minus five equals square root of negative 4.
And there again we run into the same problem.
We're trying to get the square root of a negative number.
Again this is not good.
We cannot use one as a domain.
So you can see that some numbers we can plug in five and 10 are OK but some other numbers like to 1.
We cannot plug in.