OK so we already know when we're being asked to find the indefinite integral of a function.
So it looks something like this you have to reassemble and then you have the function itself of X and
then you have dx.
So what happens if I ask you for example to find integral of x squared plus 5 x minus 3 DX how do we
do this.
Well to be able to find the indefinite integral for this function there are a couple of rules that we
need to know about integrals.
However out of all the rules there is one that's super important.
It is critical.
It is the most important rule for finding into rules and you're going to see it everywhere.
So remember how he had the power rule for derivatives where we bring down a dictator.
So for example if we have the derivative of x squared then remember that the mnemonic said to bring
down our dictator.
So we bring down the two and then we keep the X and we substitute by one of less power.
So this too becomes two minus one.
So that becomes 2 x and it's 2 to 1.
But when it's X to the one it's just x.
All right.
So this is the power rule for derivatives for power functions.
It turns out we have a power rule for integrals as well.
And this rule is actually opposite to this power rule and derivatives.
So as you know already integrating and differentiating our Abo's processes processes right.
When you differentiate something and then that derivative that you got when you integrate it you go
back to the original function.
Not exactly because you might have constants but in a way you do so because integrating and differentiating
are opposite processes than the power rule for integrals.
It's kind of opposite to the power rule and derivatives.
Let's check out the power rule for integrals and see why it is so important.
All right so power rule for entry rules.
So remember a power function has the form X to the end.
So it follows the power rule is used to integrate functions in the form X to the end.
So the power rule says the following.
So if you have the integral
of x to the end and remember this and it's just a number dx.
So we want to find the indefinite integral of this function x to the n that is going to be equal to
the following.
So we keep the X but then check out what we do with the exponents.
So the exponent that we have here is and what we do is we actually add 1 to the exponent.
So we say and plus one
and then we divide the whole thing by and plus one
and then plus see all right remember that plus he always goes there.
But check out what happened here.
The original exponent is n.
So what we do is we add one to the exponents and then we divide by the new exponent by new exponent.
I mean the original plus one.
All right.
So I went to the exponents divide by the new one.
Let's check out an example.
So the integral of x squared
X what is the indefinite integral for this function x squared.
So the rule says we keep the X
then we add a 1 to the exponent.
So the point here is 2.
So that's two plus 1.
And then we divide it by the new exponent which is also 2 plus 1.
And then we do Plus see what does this equal to.
Well we have x 2 the 2 plus 1 so that's X to the 3.
And then on the bottom we also have 3 2 plus 1 so x to the third power over three plus C that is your
indefinite integral.
That wasn't too bad was it.
It's really simple because once you add that to the exponents do you just take this new exponent and
you bring it down here dividing.
That's it.
And in fact to check or answer it what we'll do is we'll actually take the derivative of this and see
if it gives us this x squared again.
Let's put it here.
Checking
an all circle this.
So you know it's the actual answer.
So let's double check and let's get the derivative of execute over three plus a constant derivative
of that so see.
Now we're going to find the derivative.
So we're going to use the power rule but for derivatives.
This one's for integrals.
This one's for derivatives.
So power rule for derivatives.
Remember that we actually go ahead and bring down a dictator so we bring down the three and then we
have this three dividing already so three over three acts and we substitute by one of less power.
So the three becomes a two and then the derivative of a constant is zero.
All right.
So then we have three over three x squared.
However the three over 3 cancels out and we get x squared.
There we go.
There's x squared.
Is this x squared right.
So we've found the indefinite integral of x squared.
It gave us this when we differentiate this answer.
We get back this x squared.
That's how you know that the answer is correct.
And of course that tells you that again integration and differentiation arges inverses of each other.
Now of course you know I'm not mean all right.
I'm not going to make you remember these you know add 1 and then divide by the same one.
You know I'm going to give you a beautiful awesome mnemonic.
So let's go into that next.