OK so just for a quick summary of the properties of limits.
First there are certain properties you can apply to limits which are the ones we just covered next.
The limit of a constant is equal to the constant regardless of what egg's is approaching.
Remember that for a constant function the y values are always the same.
So it's always approaching that constant.
So if f of x again equals three then the limit of 3 is always going to be 3.
It does not matter what x is approaching conses multiplying functions can be brought outside of limits
multiplying.
So remember that for this one if you have something like three well limit of 3 x squared all you do
is you bring the three outside multiply the limit and then you get to keep the limit of x squared.
Only right next limits of two functions doing an operation can be broken down by applying the limit
to each.
So remember if you have two functions that are adding or subtracting that are multiplying or that are
dividing then when we put this here.
So its different from subtraction.
So again if they're adding subtracting multiplying or dividing then you can simply do the limit of the
first and then you do the operation.
The limit of the Second it's not only with two functions.
You could even do it with three four five etc..
So the limit of two functions that are adding is the limit of the first plus the limit of the second
the limit of the functions that are multiplying is the limit of the first times the limit of the second
etc. etc..
And finally the limits of functions with exponents or roots are simplified by putting the limit inside
the exponent or the root.
So this is what we discussed last.
So if you have the limit of x squared you can just do the limit of X and square the whole thing.
And same thing for the roots.
We'll do a couple of examples.
For you to practice so I'll see you in the next 45.