Hey guys what's going on.
Welcome to another session of limitless calculus.
Today we're going to talk about the most important derivative rule.
This is essential.
It is critical.
And the good news is that it's very easy to do and you'll be doing it a lot.
And that's the power rule.
So the power rule is very important because when you're doing other types of derivatives you're going
to have to incorporate the power rule in order to do those derivatives.
So you're basically going to see the power rule from now until the moment you finish the course.
It is absolutely everywhere.
You will use the power rule in the vast majority of problems you will encounter in business calculus.
So the power rule is used to find derivatives of power functions.
So let's quickly cover what a power function is.
And I'll give you some examples as well.
Power functions.
All right so power functions have the form f of x equals x.
And.
OK.
And here is a number
I'm sure that looks pretty familiar right.
I mean we have a common power of functions which for example we have quadratic functions which look
like X to the two or x squared that is a part of function.
In this case the end is equal to to remember and it's just the exponent of the power function.
So X to the two and equals two.
Then we have a quadratic function
x to the three and equals three.
And you can pretty much plug in whatever you want.
X to the 20th power you can do that too.
In fact you could even plug in negative numbers.
X to the negative 3.
Well what is x the negative 3.
How do you calculate that.
Well there's a really handy rule which tells you how to deal with negative exponents and the rule says
this If you have x negative and that is equal to 1 over X the.
So what this does is it takes this whole expression X to the negative and it brings it to the bottom
and it makes the end positive.
OK.
So again x to the negative n is equal to 1 over x to the N so using this rule we can convert this expression
into f of x.
And again what we do is we grab this we say one over this same thing but we change the negative three
to a positive three x to the negative three is equal to 1 over X or 3.
This is of course again a power function as well.
Finally you can even plug in decimals.
In fact let's plug in a decimal.
But let's do it in the form of a fraction.
So let's say X to the two thirds.
Well this is a rule number one.
And now we're going to go over a rule number to fruit and we're dealing with fractional exponents.
So if we have for example x to the Am over and right so x to the fraction and over end well.
Or are we going to do is we're going to keep the x to the M stays the same
and we're going to take the roots
and the actual route that we're gonna take is the nth root.
This goes like that again to repeat quickly we're going to keep the x to the M which we keep inside
and then we're going to get the nth root of this.
So let's apply that here.
And again this is our second important rule
let's apply this rule down here.
So we have a x equals.
So if we have X to the two thirds Well our rule says to keep the x to the numerator or the number top.
So we keep the XT to the two and we do the nth root.
So we do the roots.
It's going to be the denominator or the number on the bottom.
So we apply roots and this is going to be the cube root.
All right.
So why is it important to know these two rules.
Well it turns out that sometimes you're given a problem with a power function.
You need to convert it into this form X to the end or X to the M over and.
OK.
So first you need to convert you apply the power rule and then you switch it back to its last form which
would be the final form here.
One over x to the end or X to the YEM taken at the nth root.
These are examples of power functions.
Again issues X to the end where n is a number it could be an integer like two or three or 20.
It could be a negative number like negative 3 or it could be a fraction like two thirds etc..
All right how do we find derivatives of power functions.
Well for that we use the power rule.
And how do we apply the power rule.
Well let's first go into the definition of the power rule the power rule says that to find the derivative
of a power function you bring down the exponent multiplying and then you subtract one from the exponent.
I'll repeat that again to find the derivative of a power function.
You bring down the exponent multiplying and subtract one from the exponent.
So we know that power functions have this form of X equals x to the right.
So this says the derivative is bring down the exponent multiplying.
So we take this n right here.
That's the exponent.
Let's just write it down.
The derivative is equal to take this and and you bring it down multiplying the whole thing.
So a derivative is and times we keep the X and we subtract 1 from the exponent.
So for this and that was here we actually brought down.
We're going to put instead and minus one.
That is the power all again.
Well we just did was we have a function x to the n power function.
We want to find its derivative.
So the first thing we do is we bring down the n over here multiplying this is this.
And we keep the X and then we subtract one from the exponent.
For example
if X
equals x 3.
What is prime of x.
So let's find its derivative Well it's a power function because it's in the form X to the n the power
rule says grab this three.
So take the exponent and bring it down multiplying keep the X and subtract one from the exponent 3 minus
1.
So let's simplify.
We have 3 x three minus one is just to.
So we put it to a year and we are done.
We just applied the power rule to the function x to the three to another example.
What if we have the function x 10 was fine as derivative
again.
The power rule says we take this xponent we bring it down multiplying.
We keep the X and we subtract one from the exponent.
So that would be 10 minus one 10 x to the 9.
Believe it or not we are done.
See the power rule is very very easy once you start doing it over and over it's going to come like second
nature to you.
Now there's an easier way to remember the powerful.
And of course we're going to go into its mnemonic.
All right.
So now we have our mnemonic for the power room.
And it says dictator in power gets taken down and it's substituted by a less powerful leader.
You might be thinking well what the heck does this have to do with the powerful.
Well once you get it it's going to make a lot of sense.
OK.
So let's say that there's a country the world has a really powerful dictator.
All right.
I'm not talking about Sacha Baron Cohen and the dictator the movie I'm talking about like a real dictator
real evil guy who wants to take over the world.
I mean it's a problem it's a huge problem.
OK.
Typically happens to dictators in power.
I mean usually at some point they get either taken down or they get killed.
All right.
The point is they go away.
So that is actually the first part of our non-monic a dictator in power usually gets taken down.
And again the key to remember here is that dictators are in power right just like the power rule.
OK.
So dictator in power usually gets taken down.
That would be the first step.
Of the power rule so let's say you have a power function x to the end.
Let's say that n represents your dictator.
Right.
So we want to find the derivative.
So dictator in power gets taken down.
This is the equivalent of this and coming down here
so dictator is taken down.
That's when the end comes down multiplying.
And the second part is when a dictator is taken down what happens.
Well usually there's another person that comes in and gets into power.
Now this person is usually not as powerful as a dictator.
Right.
Because the dictator had you know all the connections that all the money the respect the person are
going to be a leader but they're not going to be as powerful.
So usually what happens again is that a dictator is substituted by a less powerful leader.
Well this is exactly what we're going to do in our power rule.
Remember we keep Vieques.
And then instead of having just an We're going to have an minus one.
This represents the less powerful leader.
So it's not the same as the dictator.
That person is now a leader but it doesn't have maybe the same respect the same army the same power.
OK.
So that's why we subtract one from it.
And that's pretty much it for the mnemonic let's apply it in a couple of problems.
OK.
So f of x equals x to the fourth power well power rule dictator in power.
So a grubbier dictator which is for we bring it down.
We keep Vieques and we substituted by a less powerful leader.
So it's going to be four minus one
we simplify for X and for minus one is just three.
There we go.
We just use the mnemonic to actually do a power function problem let's try doing another one
X one 100
Well again power function dictator in power OK.
So we grabbed a dictator which is the one hundred.
We bring it down and we substituted by a less powerful dictator.
Again we already know it's a hundred minus one.
So we can just plug it in directly.
It's going to be 99
to another problem here.
Let's say we have access to the negative 3.
So remember how we talked about that rule for negative exponents.
Let's apply it here
again.
Power rule the dictator in power.
First thing we need to do is bring our dictator down which is negative 3 and we multiply it by same
x.
And now what do we need to do.
Remember we subtract 1 from our exponent right.
We're substituting by a less powerful leader.
What is negative three minus 1.
Well if you owe three dollars and then you borrow one more dollar that means you owe now four dollars
right.
So negative three minus one is equal to negative four.
So let's just simplify we crabber negative three from the beginning which is our dictator that we brought
down keep the.
And again negative 3 minus 1 is just negative for go.
That is our final answer.
And by the way for this same problem so let's say you were given the problem like this.
Find the derivative of one over x to the three.
Well if it's in this form we can't really get it.
We can't really get the derivative right there right.
It's not in the ax to the end form.
So what we need to do is we apply the rule to bring up an exponent that's down here.
And again I'll write it again just so you have it.
We had said that X to the negative and equals 1 over x to the end
OK.
So we're going to go from this form to this form.
Right.
So we have one over X to that three.
This would be the one over x to the end and to bring it up.
We just bring the same thing but we change the exponent to a negative.
So 1 over X to that 3 becomes X to the negative three again.
All we did was take this and bring it up with a negative exponent.
And then from here you can just apply the power rule.
OK.
Which is what we did exactly here that is it again every time you get a power function.
I want you to think dictator in power what happens to dictators in power.
Well number one they get taken down.
And number two they get substituted by a less powerful leader in the same way in the power rule.
We bring down the xponent and we keep the ax and we subtract one from the xponent.
All right.
OK so now just to finish up with a summary of what we just covered.
First of all we know that power functions have the form X to the end.
So that's X to the nth power and it could be an integer.
It could be a negative number.
It could be a fraction etc. etc..
Power functions with negative or fractional exponents need some extra work.
All right so the power rule is used to find the derivatives of power functions.
Again where we just covered what a power function is X to the end to apply the power rule used the mnemonic
of the dictator as is one of my favorite mnemonics that mnemonic says dictators in power get taken down
and they're replaced by less powerful leaders.
And that's pretty much it.
And I'll see you guys in the next tutorial.