Hey there what's going on.
Welcome to another session of limitless calculus.
Today we're going to talk about logarithms and logarithms.
Maybe you've heard of them before.
Maybe not.
Maybe you've heard the word but you don't know what it means.
I got you covered.
We're going to go over a logarithms we're going to go over how they work and we're going to go over
some mnemonics so that it's easy for you to remember logarithms.
All right.
So when we think about logarithms it's kind of like the inverse of exponentiation.
OK.
So again in exponents you have something like this to two to three equals eight right.
That's because two times two times two.
So two multiplied by itself three times equals eight.
Now assume for a second that we do not know that two or three equals eight and we want to find the answer
to the following.
We want to know to which number do we need to raise to.
So why should the exponent here be if we want the results to be equal to 8.
So we're looking for this exponent right here.
We already know it's three.
But what if we didn't know and we wanted to find what this exponent of two should be.
So that to elevate it to this exponent equals eight.
This is the question that logarithms answer.
You have a base you have a result you want to know what the exponent of the base should be so that you
get to the final result.
So let's go into the definition of a logarithm.
All right so here we have a formal definition of logarithms.
So we have that the logarithm of X was base a is the number two which you need to exponentiate a to
get to X.
That is a tongue twister right.
Let's repeat that again.
The logarithm of x with pace A is the number to which you need to exponentiate a to get to X.
So think of it like this.
Logarithms always have a base OCHA this case we're saying that the base is a.
And remember this when you're asked to find a logarithm.
You're being asked to find an exponent because we're saying what is a number so that when you put it
as an exponent of a is going to give you X and let's do one example so that it makes more sense.
Now before we get into the example let me show you the notation for a logarithm.
So it looks like this you have the word logi right for log.
That is for logarithm here.
Very small.
You have the base
and next to a log you have the results.
All right.
So this says let's find a number so that when you take the base and you exponentiate it to this number
you get the result.
So the generic function for logarithm is y equals log.
Then we have the base really small down here which we set is a
and here we're going to have x that is our final results.
Y equals log of x with base a.
All right.
So the base is down here.
This is probably not making any sense at all.
So let's go over a couple of examples.
So
for example if I say log of base 2 of 8 What are we saying we're saying to which number do we need to
raise this to.
So what should be the exponent of this too.
If we want the result to be eight's but we know this already right.
Because two to three equals two times two times two which is eight right.
So the answer to this logarithm is simply three.
I hope you see why again two to three equals eight.
I told you when you're finding logarithms all you're finding is exponents.
Here we found the exponents so that the based elevated to this exponent gives you this result.
Let's do another one.
So log of Base Three
twenty seven.
So we're asking to which number do we need to exponentiate 3 to get the results 27.
So in other words 3 to the watt equals 27 Well let's see three times three is nine times three again
is 27.
So three 2 3 equals 27.
Therefore the log of 27 with Page 3 is equal to 3 because again three to the three right is 27
let's do yet one more example.
All right so another logarithm logarithm of a thousand with pays 10.
So we are asking to which number do you need to raise this 10 to get to 1000.
In other words tend to the what equals 1000.
By the way when I use this square over here it's just a placeholder.
Right.
It's because we're trying to find this number this exponent over here.
So we're looking for a number so that an exponentiate add to that number gives us a thousand.
What could this number be.
Well let's see ten times ten is a hundred times ten again is what is a thousand.
So if you multiply 10 by itself three times you get a thousand.
Therefore the exponent here is at three.
And the answer is also with three.
Now I gave you three examples and in all these examples the answer is three.
All right.
Because this pace to the third power equals what's in parentheses for each of these three.
Actually let's do one more where the answer is not three.
So let's do
here we have a log of 25 with base 5.
So again we're asking to which number do we need to exponentiate the base to get to 25.
This is an easy one
five to one equals 25.
Well five squared right.
Five to the two.
Therefore our answer here is to because the base to the two equals 25.
All right.
So hopefully that's a little bit more clear.
Again just remember when you're asked to find a logarithm you're being asked to find an exponent for
the base of that logarithm so that when you raise the base to that exponents it's going to give you
this result.
And this is the function right here for a logarithm.
Now this still might be a little bit confusing.
So let's go into the manege so you can remember the basic structure of a logarithm.