Hey what's going on.
So you've got the Course you're now my student and I am your online tutor.
My goal is for you to pass this class.
I want you to understand the concepts.
I want you to be able to do the problems so that you can eventually be done with basic calculus.
That's what I want.
Now I did invest a lot of hours into making this course as easy to understand as possible as clear as
possible.
I did a lot of editing a lot of recording a lot of voice overs etc..
That doesn't mean that everything will always make sense at all times.
There might be times where you get lost so sometimes you might have some questions for me.
So maybe watching a tutorial and something doesn't make sense.
Or maybe you think it should be another thing.
Maybe I made a mistake even though I double check all the problems.
Maybe gives you a different result and it turns out that it was my bad.
So if anything comes up there are two main ways to ask me questions.
The first way is in the general dashboard.
So if you go to the general dashboard for the course you can go to the Q&A section right here and here
you'll see that you can either search for a question or you can ask a new question.
So don't be shy.
If you have a question about the course about a specific problem about a specific topic.
I am here to help.
Now this is more for generic questions.
You can actually ask a question within a specific video
so let's say that you're doing marginal analysis and you have a question for a certain video.
So let's say you have a question about the mnemonic for marginal analysis.
So you're in the video.
Go ahead and pause it.
And here you see a button that's called Brough's Q&A.
You can actually click here and if other people have asked questions you'll see them listed here.
And you yourself can ask can you question about this specific video.
So if your question is about a specific thing in a specific video I would totally suggest for you to
pose your questions within the video that way.
Number one it's easier for me to know what you're talking about.
And number two other people can benefit if they have the same question as you.
All right.
So there you go.
You have two ways of asking me questions in the general dashboard.
And in this specific video.
So don't be shy if you have a question about anything please contact me if you need help.
I want to make sure that you pass this class so if something doesn't make sense even after you watch
the video once or twice or three times hey write me a question I'll be more than happy to help.