Pay there what's going on.
Welcome to another session of limit less calculus.
So we already covered the properties of limits.
Now we're going to go into how to actually solve limits.
OK.
And it's funny because once you know what I'm going to teach you now you don't really need to know the
properties the property to use.
You know you have to learn how limits work how they can be done.
Maybe your professor wants you to learn them so you can apply them.
However when we do what we're going to do just now which is a quick shortcut to how to find limits then
you don't really have to use the rules.
You only have to do one thing and we'll explore that right now by going straight to our mnemonic.
OK so here we have our mnemonic and very easy very short very fun.
It says to find the limb just plug it in.
Look at that.
It even rhymes.
What an amazing mnemonic right to find the limb.
Just plug it in.
What does that mean.
So for example if you have limits of x squared let's pick a simple one as x approaches three.
So we want to find this limit.
You know we have the property that says OK you can actually get this too.
And you can leave it on the side and then you're going to get the limit of X as x approaches 3.
Then we have another property that says that the limit of X is just going to be the number that X is
approaching etc. etc..
The point is you can forget about all that and to find the limb just plug it in.
That means that all you need to do is take this number that your ex is approaching and plug it into
your function.
So in this case the limit of x squared as x approaches 3 is just that three squared and that is equal
to 9.
Nine is then the limit of x squared as x approaches 3.
Boom you're done.
All right let's do another example limit of x cubed minus 2 x plus let's say 7 as x approaches 1.
All right.
So define the lim.
Just plug it in let's grab this one and let's plug it into this function.
I'll just put it in parentheses.
All right.
So we have excuse so that becomes one cubed.
Minus two times one right because 2 x becomes two times one plus seven.
So one cube remembers his 1 times 1 times 1 which is just 1.
Mine is two times one is to plus seven.
So we have one minus 2 which is minus 1 plus 7 is just 6 and that is your final answer.
See how easy it is to find the limit just plug it in whatever number you are approaching.
Just plug it into the function for which you are finding the limit.
Thats it.
Now of course limits are not always that easy.
What if I tell you to find the limit
of this function so we have X minus three over x cubed minus nine
as x approaches 3 right.
So again to find the LEM just plug it in we're going to get this three and plug it into this function.
So we have X minus three so that's three minus three on top.
All right so that's going to be zero again a zero on the top is OK on the top of a fraction.
That's not a problem.
The problem is when you have a zero on the bottom so do we have a zero on the bottom.
Let's find out.
So we plug in the three on the bottom that's three squared minus nine equals three minus three on top
is zero.
And on the bottom we have three square two three times three is nine minus nine.
What do we have here.
Zero over.
What's 9 minus 9 0.
Ha again 0 0 is no bueno.
We don't like that.
That's not good what does that mean.
What if you're trying to find the limit of a function and then you get something over 0 or even 0 0.
What happens to the limit then.
Well that means you're going to have to find another way of finding the limit.
You cannot just plug it in.
So depending on the type of function sometimes you're going to have to apply some tricks in order to
find limits.
It's not always going to be to find the LEM just plug it in.
However the first thing you're always going to try whenever you're finding a limit is to find the limb
and plug it in.
If you get a zero in the denominator in the bottom part then you have a problem.
So for example in this one here limit of x squared there's no denominator it's just x squared right.
That's not even a fraction.
Therefore the limit is just plug it in.
Same thing for the second one.
There's no denominator in this function.
And therefore you can just plug it in and this one we do have a denominator.
So we have to plug it in and check if it gives as a 0 on the bottom.
And I'll repeat that again.
The zero on top is OK the zero on the bottom is not OK.
So the fact that we get zero on top here no problem zero on the bottom.
Then you have a problem.
So whenever you plug in a limit and you apply the mnemonic to find the limb just plug it in and you
get a 0 on the bottom.
You need to find a different method.
So for this limit you need to find
a different method.
For finding the limit.
So there are a couple of tricks that we can use one of them is factorization which is something that
we'll cover in a couple of problems.
You can also do something called rationalization and that's something else I will see in the problems
as well.
But the point I want you to go away with for this specific mnemonic is that whenever you get a limit
you always have to try to plug in the number into the function.
That's the first thing always that you're going to try.
All right.
So this is first thing to try.
By the way we really haven't covered that much.
The limit from the left and from the right.
We did a little bit in a different section but we have a section just for that coming up.
So we're finding this limit of x squared as x approaches 3 that is both from the left and from the right.
So this is a general limit.
This is not specifically from the left nor specifically from the right.
OK.
When you're finding the limits from the right on the left hand you cannot just plug it in because the
limit from the left might be different from the limit from the right.
But again it really depends on the type of function.
All right but if you have just a generic limit then you can just go ahead and plug it in like we did
in these three examples and the first example in the second example we got numbers that's perfect.
And the third example we got a zero in the bottom again let me mark this so that you know it's in the
bottom and it's not necessarily the one on top is the one on the bottom that's the one giving problems.
So we need to find a different method for this one.
And again we'll cover that in a couple of different problems.
Just remember to find the limb.
Just plug it in.
OK so we really saw an example where plugging in the limit gives us a denominator of zero.
And one of the things that we can do whenever we get a denominator of 0 is to do some factorization.
So what does factorization so remember to factor something is to grab the terms though when you multiply
give you that results.
For example if I want to factor the number nine I'll do it on the right here.
One effect of the number nine number nine can be a combination of for example three times three three
and three are the factors of nine factors of 10 are two and five for example and the factors of 20 or
four and five because four times five is twenty and you can break down the factors of this for two to
and two because two times two is four.
So again you're just getting a result and you're seeing how the result was produced.
So let's go back to our other limit.
We just tried doing where we try to find the limit by plugging it in and it didn't work out.
So we had a limit of X minus three over
x squared.
Mine is 9 as x approaches 3.
So again we can quickly see what I need to do it again.
That if we take this three and we plug it in the bottom it's going to be three squared minus nine.
And that's going to be nine minus nine is going to be equal to zero.
So what can we do to this function to manipulate it so that it's actually not in this form but in a
different form.
So it's as we write it down here.
Limit of.
OK.
So how can we rewrite this function so that when we plug in three it doesn't give us 0.
Well we're going to factor using something called the difference of squares.
And this says basically that if you have something in this form A to the second power mine is beat to
the second power.
So you have something squared.
Mine is something else squared.
Then you can factor that into
a plus b times a minus B.
All right.
So that's one of the ways that we can factor
and you probably have seen this before maybe you don't remember but I'm pretty sure you've seen it somewhere.
If you don't remember or if you don't know it or if it seems weird Don't worry about it.
We'll do a couple of examples with this same rule.
All right.
But again it's a difference of squares and it makes sense that that would be the name because you have
a difference.
So remember you're subtracting of two things that are squared a squared minus the square.
So can you see this over here.
Where do you have a difference of squares.
You have a difference of squares in the denominator.
Right.
So let's just put the numerator again the top X minus three.
And let's factor out this x squared.
Minus nine.
Because again we have a difference of squares.
So it says that A-squared minus B squared is a plus b times a minus B.
So what would be your a.
In this case our A would be X right because X is a first term and it's the term that's being squared
so it says that X is going to be first here and then here so it's going to be something like this x
something times x something else right.
Because X is what a represent over here what's going to be our B.
Well you might say or B is going to be nine but that's not true.
Why.
Because remember B's being squared so B is a term so that when you square it you get nine.
It's not going to be 9 itself.
So what is the square root of nine.
You know this already square root of nine is three.
OK so 3 is our A B in this case and again and the first term here and the factoring we do plus B.
So we do plus three.
And finally in the second term we do a minus B which becomes X minus 3.
So again all we're doing is we're saying OK we had X squared minus nine we want to factor that.
First we have to identify our A which is X and R B which is 3.
And then just put it in this form a plus b times a minus B.
That's what we did explode three times X minus three as x approaches 3.
Now something interesting happens because you have X minus three on top.
And you have X plus three times X minus three and bottom because these two are multiplying.
You can simply cancel out the X minus 3 that's on top with the one that's on the bottom.
So you can just cross X minus three and you can cross X minus three both in the top and in the bottom.
So when you do that what happens.
We have limits of
well in the top.
We don't have anything.
So it just becomes one line over and on the bottom we only have now x plus three
as x approaches 3.
And now that we have it in a different form.
What do we do to find the limb.
Just plug it in.
So at this point we're just going to plug in this three into this function.
And that becomes one over we plug in at three into the X three plus three equals 1 over 6.
That is your limit so see how we went from a limit that gave us 0 over 0 to an actual number.
That just tells you that sometimes you can just find a way just plug it in.
You have to factor this or you have to do something else to it so that it becomes the same function.
But in a different form and then you can just plug in your three of course.
Difference of squares is just one example of how you can factor a function in order to get a different
form.
Once we get to the problems we'll see other types of factoring that you can do and that you will encounter.
So it's definitely great practice to just go ahead and try out some problems which we'll do after this
lesson.
And solving limits is over.