Of all right.
So let's go ahead and get started with identifying power functions.
So first exercise says Is this a power function f of x equals x to the five.
So what do you think.
Yes or no.
Go ahead and pause a video and give it a shot.
All right.
So what do you think.
Is it a power function.
Well the answer is yes it is a power function because remember power functions come in the form X to
the end and being a number right next to the N N and is a real number.
That means it's not imaginary.
If you haven't seen imaginary numbers yet don't worry about that.
Basically take it to mean that he can be any number at all.
So the 5 is definitely a power function.
All right here we have our next example.
Is this a power function f of x equals x to the negative 2.
So X not to the positive to put to the negative 2.
Is it a power function.
I'll let you pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so what do you think the answer is that yes it is a power function because again a power function
has the form at the end.
Right.
It's being elevated to a certain power.
So in this case the end is negative too.
It doesn't matter that it's negative it's still a real number.
So this is why this is a power function.
All right.
So our next example is is this a power a function of x equals to the X so to the X let's you pause the
video and give it a shot.
All right.
So what do you think is the X a power function.
Well the answer is that no it's not a power function.
All right.
That was kind of a trick question.
So if you got it wrong don't feel bad because it can be confusing.
So remember power functions have the form X to the end.
This is a power function.
So you have X elevated to a number.
In this case we had the opposite.
We had two a number elevated to X..
So this is completely different than X to the end.
This is and the X basically.
So here the input is actually in the exponents and in our power function the input is the base of the
exponent.
All right.
So this is not a power function.
This is actually called an exponential function.
But we'll take a look at that later on.
All right just make sure that you do not confuse the two power function x to the end.
Right.
So the number is here on top.
All right.
So for our last exercise is this a power function f of x equals x to the 3 over 4 I'll let you pause
and give it a shot.
All right.
So what do you think the answer is that yes it is a power function.
So maybe it looks a little bit weird because you have a fraction and the exponent but again it doesn't
matter.
Remember that a fraction after all is still a number.
If you go to a calculator and you plug in three over four you're going to get point seventy five.
So this is like saying X to the point seventy five.
All right so this is definitely a power function.
I will do an example in the next section of how to find the derivative of problems where they have fractions
in the exponent.
All right but just make sure you know this is also a power function because it's in the form X to the
end and being a real number.