All right.
So welcome to this lesson.
Right now we're going to talk about the heart and soul of this course and they are mnemonics.
So if you've never heard the term I have a definition here for you.
A mnemonic is a memory aid that helps you remember things easily.
All right so it's something that you think about that allows you to remember stuff when you need it.
And even if you've never heard the word mnemonic I'm 100 percent sure you have worked with mnemonics
in the past.
For example here's a famous one
pandas.
Ever heard of this.
Well pandas is a monarch used to remember the order of operations parentheses exponents multiplication
division addition and subtraction.
So what do you think is easier remembering each and every one of those.
Or simply remembering pandas and then getting it from there.
Of course Pandurs is way easier.
That's why it's in a Monnick and something that helps you remember the order of operation without having
to learn so many words in sequence.
Here's another mnemonic that we use in math and you've probably seen before foil
right.
So if you are from an English speaking country then most likely you've seen this at some point.
And remember a foil is a mnemonic that's used to remind people how to multiply something like this.
So for example if you have a plus b times a minus B
then A foil tells you how you need to multiply this.
It's first.
So this term and this term than the outer this term.
And then at the other extreme this term then you multiply the enter this one and this one and then you
multiply the last this one and this one will see that foil is a really awesome mnemonic because it tells
you right there what you need to do in terms of multiplying this and in fact mnemonics work.
If you don't believe me let me show you so here we are at Wikipedia and we have an article that's a
list of mnemonics.
Check it out.
There are mnemonics for all of these fields right.
We have mnemonics for art astronomy biology business chemistry computing all those things.
And it's for a reason they actually work.
So for example Check it out for arts to remember the elements of Arts base form texture shape line Valley
color.
Think about it how long would it take you to remember this.
And you might get confused at any point right.
But check out this cool mnemonic.
Spaceships fly through space looking very cool.
Isn't that way easier to remember.
Right.
And then every first letter of each word tells you what you're talking about.
So spaceships that's for space fly is for reform through is for texture etc. etc. you see that there's
a big big difference in how long it would take you to remember all of these and order versus remembering
this sentence.
And like I said we also have it for us Trauner me we have it for a biology basis in economics chemistry.
I mean there's a demonic everywhere.
And the fact that there are so many mnemonics should tell you something about them.
They actually work.
Do you think that if they didn't work there would be so many of them.
Absolutely not.
So what I'm going to do in the tutorial is for many key concepts I'll provide you with a mnemonic so
that it's easy for you to remember exactly how to do the problem or what a concept is.
For example the product rule says the derivative of f of x times g of X equals the derivative of f of
x times g of X plus f of x times the derivative of g of x.
Do you think that if I tell you that will remember in 10 minutes what I just sent Now of course not.
However if I give you any money that says for the product rule you grab the first three letters of product.
So you grab pro and this stands for place repeats and then do the outer derivatives and that's it.
Then I'm sure you will remember this right.
Not the first thing that I said which is the actual rule but you'll remember pro.
So that's the beauty of mnemonics.
They are simple.
They're awesome and they can help you recall stuff in the middle of a test that otherwise you would
not recall.
By the way if you're a student and you're coming just for a specific lesson like for example you want
to know more about the chain rule and you go directly to the chain rule.
You might hear me talking about different random things.
So for example if we're doing a problem or we need to find the power rule you're going to hear me talk
about bringing down a dictator and substituting by a less powerful leader.
That's because that's in a money that's earlier in the tutorial.
So if you jump into a specific lesson and you hear something that's maybe a little bit out of place
or something that doesn't make sense to you like place repeats our dictator or something like that just
go ahead and do the problem the way you know how to do it.
You do not have to use the mnemonic right.
I would say pretty much all of my students over the years I've liked the way I use mnemonics.
But if they're not for you you don't really have to use them.
All right.
And one last thing not every lesson has a mnemonic I need to have a balance between giving you too many
mnemonics I don't want to give you 100 mnemonics right.
That's a lot to remember but I do give you mnemonics for the things that are either number one key concepts
or number two a little bit tricky.
All right.
The last thing I want to say is every time there's a mnemonic in the tutorial it's going to look like
this.
Right.
So any time you hear that music and it says it's mnemonic time you know a mnemonic is coming.
All right.
So take advantage of the mnemonics.
I hope you like them and I'm sure that if you study them they will help you remember stuff a lot easier
than not having them at all.
So whenever you see a mnemonic remember to take notes and to use it while you're doing problems right.
That's going to drill it in your brain and it's going to stay there.
Don't think that using the Monnick three times will be enough for you to learn it.
You have to put it in practice over and over and over again.
Practice is critical to learning mnemonics.
All right so let me know how you like then.
Manics I'll see you in the next video.