So basically what you have is this X minus five within the square root.
And remember this X minus 5 cannot be negative.
So if we do X minus 5 and it has to be greater than or equal to zero.
What we can do here is we can solve for x.
All right so let's add five on both sides.
It's negative five plus five cancels out and we have x is greater than or equal to zero plus five is
five.
So what we did here was we said OK we want X minus 5 to always be greater than or equal to zero.
So we solve for x.
So we leave the x by itself on one side and we move the number to the other side and we get that x is
greater than or equal to 5.
Believe it or not this is our domain.
Well how do we know that this is our domain.
Remember the domain is anything that will make this under the square root to be 0 or greater.
So any number that's 5 or greater It's OK to plug in because it makes whatever's under the square root
is 0 or greater.
So notice that doesn't matter which number you pick from here x is greater than or equal to 5.
It's never going to give you a negative number under the square root.
So if you pick a number that's in this domain x is greater than or equal to 5 you are in the clear because
any number will work.
Nothing will give you a negative number.
All right.
Let's do another quick example.
What is the domain of f of x equals the cube root of x.
So let's try plugging then you know maybe something like 27
3 and 27.
Remember cube root which is 3 cube root basically tells you which number you need to multiply by itself
three times in order to get 27.
And that is number three because three times three is nine times three is twenty seven.
So the answer is three.
All right.
Now let's pick another interesting number to plug in.
Negative 27.
So which number do you need to multiply by itself three times in order to get negative 27.
You might say oh I already know this.
You cannot get a number that's going to give you negative 27 will you multiplied by itself three times.
Well you actually can.
And what is the difference between this problem and the last problem.
The difference is the root the root here is three three is an odd roots.
OK so you have a problem with the roots even two four six eight ten etc..
When you have an odd rule which it could be 3 5 7 9 accepter all of a sudden it doesn't matter if you
have negative numbers down here.
Why.
Because what happens when you have three I'm sorry negative three times negative three times negative
three so negative three times negative three is positive nine right.
So positive nine times negative three.
I remember this is positive nine because negative times a negative equals a positive.
Then we have nine times negative three.
Remember that a positive times a negative is a negative.
And nine times 3:27
ha.
So that gives you negative 27.
That means that the answer to this problem is negative 3 because negative 3 to the third power are multiplied
by itself three times gives you negative 27.
Notice that this is completely different from when you haven't even root because even roots look like
this.
And again let's pick an example let's pick for let's say that it's negative 16.
You're looking for a number that multiplied by itself four times gives you a negative number.
But remember that does not exist because when you have numbers multiplying themselves in even groups
it's always going to be a positive.
So if you have two times two times two times two that gives you 16 not negative 16 but also if you have
negative two times and negative two times negative two times negative two.
So that's four times.
Here you have a positive because it's negative times a negative.
And here you have a positive because it's negative times and negative.
All right.
So when you multiply this positive by this positive it's going to give you positive 16.
This is why for this the answer is two imaginary.
However when you have the odd root you're good to go because when you multiply something by itself an
odd number of times.
In this case three.
Right you're multiplying these negative three three times.
In those cases you are good to go.
All right so going back to the other example when you haven't even roots you need to make sure that
whatever is under the root is zero or greater.
It cannot be negative.
Let me repeat that again.
If you're finding the domain of a function of the Hasn't even roots then you need to find numbers that
when you plug in X it's going to give you zero or greater under the root.
OK.
For odd roots it doesn't matter.
You can get actual answers that are not imaginary for even rudes it's different.
I know the concept is a little bit odd of you know imaginary numbers even rudes odd rudes if you need
to go back and listen to this part again I recommend you do it.
It's going to help you out a lot probably.
And you can just put me on you know faster speeds so you don't have to hear me talk all the time.
You know it's going to be quicker.
But if this did him if this didn't make a lot of sense I suggest you just play it again.
It's going to take five minutes of your life and it's going to help you out a lot with this concept.
So our third case for domains is practical applications.
So what does this mean.
So in the same way you would not put your glasses in your washing machine to clean them.
Sometimes it doesn't make sense to put certain numbers into functions because of what the function represents.
For example let's say that I own a lemonade stand next to my backyard I sell lemonade on the weekends
and each class cause $2.
Also let's say that my fixed costs are five daughters regardless of how many glasses I sell.
Then my profit function would be
of X equals to X because remember I make $2 for every lemonade I sell minus five because five is my
fixed cost and then X here is the number of lemony glasses that I sell.
This is my profit.
So if I sell
three glasses during the day it's going to give us two times three.
Mine is five times three six minus five is one.
So we sell three glasses a day that's going to give us a profit of one sad dollar.
But what if we sell 30 glasses in a day well it's going to be two times.
Thirty minus five so two times 30 is 60 minus five is 55.
All right.
Fifty four dollars a profit.
Not bad.
Now what if I sell.
Negative three
glasses of lemonade.
Does that make sense to you.
Can you really sell negative three glasses of lemonade.
It does not.
Of course neither does any negative number.
They try to plug in in the same way that I cannot sell negative three glasses of lemonade.
I cannot sell negative 10 glasses of lemonade or negative 200 glass of lemonade.
So I think it's pretty obvious here that whatever you input into this function needs to be zero or a
positive number.
It cannot be a negative number.
So this does work and I think by now you are noticing how problematic negative numbers can be if they're
under an even Rood's than they not part of your domain.
And sometimes you cannot plug them in into certain functions.
And one more thing for the purposes of this example assume that you're not selling you know half a glass
of lemonade or three quarters of a glass of lemonade.
Let's assume that is.
We cannot do.
We can only sell whole numbers.
So one glass eliminate two glasses of lemonade three glass of lemonade etc..
All right.
So because it doesn't make sense in real life to put negative numbers into my function the domain of
this profit function is all integers greater than or equal to zero.
All integers
greater than or equal to zero.
I remember integers were just put this year quickly
integers are just numbers like negative 3 negative to negative 1 0 1 2 3 etc etc..
So integers are all whole numbers and they include 0 that the domain is going to be all integers greater
than or equal to zero.
So that's 0 1 glass of lemonade two glasses of lemonade three glass of lemonade.
Etc. etc..
So one quick caveat about this is that in theory I could plug in you know five and a half.
So 5.5 into this function and it would work well.
However that's why I said let's assume that you cannot sell you know half a glass of lemonade.
One fourth of a glass of lemonade three quarters to just simplify the example.
OK.
That's why our domain is only integers or whole numbers because we're not selling lemonade by a less
than a glass.
We're selling it by the glass itself.
So in this case the domain is not all real numbers because we cannot sell for example 3.5 or four point
a glass of lemonade or you know twelve point three glass of lemonade etc. only selling fool glasses.
And that's why we have 1 2 3 etc etc..
OK.
So we covered our three cases of when the domain is not all real numbers.
Number one is when you have division by zero.
Number two is when you have a negative number under an even root.
And number three is when you have some sort of practical limitation because you're doing an actual application
in real life and it doesn't make sense to put certain numbers.
OK so it follows that a domain is the eggs values
then range is y values.
So the range of a function is the group of all y values that are possible for that function.
So for example if I have of X equals x plus three
and we have our table of values x and y.
So for example we plug in two we get two plus three that gives us 5.
So for the plug in of two we get a y of five to another one for the plug in of three we get three plus
three which is six.
So when we play in three we get six.
And as we saw this function f of x he goes x 3 does not have division by zero or does not have any even
roots or does not have any practical applications.
So is all real numbers for the domain.
If you can plug in all real numbers in the domain that means that your range is also or we are numbers.
Why is that.
Well think about it if you can plug in any number here for X then you can get any y value that you want.
For example if you want to get a y value of 10 just plug in seven if you want to get a y value of 23
just plug in 20 etc. etc..
So this right here all these y values the range is also equal to all real numbers.
Now finding range you're probably not going to be asked to find the range of a function.
You might but we'll cover some examples.
And the problem section.
It's not as straightforward as domain because you kind of have to think OK what kind of y values I can
get.
We don't have any hard rules to tell right away.
But for now just know that the range refers to all the y values that are possible for a given function.
And now let's go into our summary.
All right so let's go into a summary of what we just covered.
Again the domain of a function refers to all allowable x values or input for the function.
It is typically all real numbers the domain that is.
But for three cases it's not when there's division by zero when there's an even root or by limitations
of practical applications.
Negative numbers under even roots which can be 2 4 6.
Again remember even means divisible by 2 under even rudes give rise to imaginary numbers which we don't
like.
And finally the range of a function is a group of numbers that the function can output.
One more thing I wanted to mention is if you forget you know which ones domain which one Drange x y
input output you can actually summarize it here by alphabetical order.
So the X which is the input
which refers to the domain and then on the other hand we have Y which is the output
and refers to the range.
So if you ever forget which ones which are you need to do is put each pair into alphabetical order and
you'll have it ready.
So X comes before y input comes before output and domain comes before range.
I'm talking of course about the first letter of each.
How it plays out in the alphabet.
So X comes before Y.
Input comes before output.
And domain comes before range.
So this way you know that everything on this side is related and everything on this side is related.
So that's a quick way to know that you know X is the input and the allowable x values are the domain.
On the other hand why is the output and whatever the function can output is the range.
All right so I'll see everyone in the next tutorial.
Remember we're going to have some problems for you to practice and I'll see you around.