All right.
So let's go ahead and do some exercises for indefinite entry rules.
First one says find the following indefinite integral integral of x squared DX go ahead and pause the
video and give it a shot.
All right.
So as you can see we're trying to find the integral of a power function.
It's a function in the form X to the N.
So for that we're going to use our mnemonic for indefinite integral which is I in d increase and divide.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So let me rewrite it again.
Integral of x squared.
So we increase and divide.
So this will become X to the two plus one we're increasing.
And then we are dividing by the new exponent which is also two plus 1.
Don't forget the plus see and we have two plus one is three.
So that's X to the third over two plus one is three three plus C this is our answer and that is the
indefinite integral of x squared.
In fact let's test that out.
Let's make sure that when we get the derivative of this it gives us back x squared.
So what is the derivative of X cubes over three plus C.
So we have a constant That's one third.
So we put it outside 1 over 3 times then we use or dictator rule.
So we bring our dictator down comes on multiplying three X and substitute by one of less power.
So that gives us a two plus the derivative of a constant is zero.
All right.
And so we have three over three.
So it cancels out and we have x squared plus 0 which is just x squared and x squared is what we have
over here.
So in fact this right here is the indefinite integral of x squared and we just verified it down here.
Let's do another one.
All right so here we have our next problem find the following indefinite integral integral of one over
x to the fifth power.
Go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so let's go ahead and do it together.
So first thing you'll notice is we have 1 over x to the 5 so we can't really do it in the way it is
right now.
We need to transform it into something else.
And remember that any time we have X elevated to a power here in the bottom of a fraction we can actually
bring it up by flipping the sign of the exponents.
So this integral of one over x to the 5 dx we can actually rewrite it as integral of x to the negative
five dx.
So what are we doing.
We're taking this x to the five and we're bringing it to the top and we have to flip the sign of the
xponent.
So when it comes up it comes up as negative five instead of five.
Right now though we have this we have a power function so we can apply our power rule for integrals.
Remember it's increase and divide.
So we have X to the negative 5 and then increase.
So we add 1 to it plus 1 and then divide by this same New exponents negative five plus one.
Don't forget Plus see.
All right.
So what is negative five plus one.
Well think of it if you go $5 and then you pay one back.
Now you only owe four dollars.
All right.
So negative five plus one is negative for.
Same thing on the bottom.
Negative five plus 1 is negative for and then plus Plessey.
All right.
And now the last thing is remember as an answer we do not like negative exponents.
So we're going to go ahead and just like we brought it up.
Now we're going to do the opposite and bring it down.
And because the exponent has a negative sign we're going to have to flip that sign in order to get this
extra negative for on the bottom.
So when we continue down here on the top we'll have one because there's going to be nothing else here
in the top over the four that's already there.
And then we bring down the x to the negative 4.
But again we bring it down as a positive.
And remember this whole thing is negative right.
If the bottom here is negative then the whole fraction is negative.
So it's negative 1 over 4 x to the fourth plus see.
And this right here is our answer.
All right.
So remember any time you have this one over X to something at that point you're going to have to bring
it up by flipping the sign of the exponents.
Apply the power rule for integrals and then when you get your answer like we did here bring it down
again and that's it.
All right so here's another problem.
Integral of x to the 15th dx.
So go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so let's go ahead and do this one together so we have a rule of X the 15th dx.
So again we have a rule because we have a power function.
Our mnemonic says increase and divide.
So we take this x to the 15th and we increase the exponent by 1.
So that's 15 plus one.
And then we divide 15 plus one as well.
And then plus see remember we always put a plus C on we're doing indefinite integrals.
Then we have X to the 16th right.
Because that is 15 plus one and we divide by 15 plus one which is also 16 as you might have noticed
this xponent is always the same as this that you're dividing by because you increase and then divide
by the same thing.
All right.
And then plus the.
And that is our answer.
Very easy
right.
So here we have one more find the following indefinite integral integral of x dx and I'll give you a
little tip.
Think about what is X being raced to.
In this case I'll let you go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so let's see be able to do it a little bit tricky but not too much.
So we have integral of x dx.
Now what is X being raised to.
Well remember that I said several times over the tutorials that if you have x by itself that is the
same as saying X to the one right so x equals x to the one they mean the same thing.
So in this case we have access to the one we have a power function and we can use our mnemonic for the
power.
So this would become X to the increase and divide.
So we increase by 1.
This is the current exponents and we're increasing it by 1 and then we divide by the same thing.
One plus one plus see.
And finally we have one plus one is two.
So that's X to the 2 x squared over one plus one two as well plus see.
And this is our answer.
All right.
And let's see the last one and again I'm giving you a lot of these problems so you get used to the power
rule for integrals.
So find the following indefinite integral integral of x to the sevens dx.
Go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so let's go ahead and check it out.
So we have integral of x to the 7th dx.
And again we have a power function so we can use our mnemonic for the power rule for integrals increase
and divide.
So we have X and we increase the exponent.
So it becomes 7 plus 1 and we divide by 7 plus one as well and don't forget we do the plus see and then
we have X to the seven plus 1.
So that's X to the eighth power and seven plus one on the bottom that's eight as well.
And here we do plus see.
So it's X to the 8th over 8 Plessey.
And that is our final answer.
All right.
So we did a couple of problems on the power rule for integrals.
Not too bad.
All you need to remember is increase and divide.