Hey there what's going on.
So I want to talk to you about something that's very very very important to me and that is reviews for
the course.
So as it says here I designed the corps to be a five star course.
And when I say that let me back it up let me show you the amount of time I've spent making sure that
the Corps is amazing.
So right now we're sitting at about 22 hours of constant So that's 22 hours.
Now this is edited content.
So that means that for every hour of edited content there was another hour of recording behind that.
So we have 22 hours of content.
And then we have approximately 22 hours even though it's a little bit more because there are things
that I didn't put in the tutorials of recording
then after that I had to write the script of what I was going to say in each video.
That definitely took a while because that is for every topic that you cover in a business calculus course
which last fall semester so that took me approximately 12 hours
I was just writing scripts
and then of course there is the whole organizing it online uploading the videos put in descriptions
putting titles updating my profile etc etc..
So theres a lot that goes there as well and that one took me approximately five hours to get everything
ready.
So five hours of set up.
All right.
So this is like the minimum time I've spent on these tutorials.
That is approximately 61 hours.
So my point here is not that you should care how much work I put into it or you should care about is
whether it's helping you achieve your goals of passing this class.
But I do want to make a point that I've spent a lot of times a lot of weekends a lot of mornings and
a lot of nights making sure that this course is a five star of course making sure that the Course explains
the concepts in a way that's easy for you to understand making sure that you have problems for you to
practice making sure that the mnemonics make sense and then they're easy to remember.
I mean there's a lot a lot a lot of work that went into the course.
So this is not a five star course for you I would like to know.
I would love to know why you think this course is not five stars and you know there could be valid reasons.
Maybe you don't find it really helpful.
Maybe you expected something else.
I mean whatever it is I'm always looking for ways to improve the course.
So this is not five stars.
Please let me know.
So I wanted to say if this course helps you understand concepts easier and faster than you doing class
practice problems to help you gain confidence in your business calculus skills improve your score and
quizzes and test and of course this is the most important one.
If it helps you pass the class I will ask you to please leave me a review letting me know how much you
like the course.
If you feel it's a five star course then great.
Those five star reviews mean the world to me.
If you feel that it's less than five stars Remember you can always leave me a review.
But please let me know why you didn't think it was a five star course.
Again I put a lot of work into this making sure that this course is the best business calculus course
on the Internet.
So if it's not worth five stars I need to know why.
But if it helps you do any of these four then I would love to get a five star review from you.
All right.
So why are these so important to me.
Well number one is if you'll give me a five star review I know that what I'm teaching and the way I'm
teaching it is working.
I love helping students.
I've tutored hundreds of business calculus students throughout the last couple of years.
I can explain to you how happy makes me feel to see them pass the class at the beginning you know they're
struggling they don't know what to do.
They're stressed by this class and all those things.
But it's a great great feeling when they finally start improving their scores.
They start understanding the class and eventually pass it.
So that is number one.
So if I get a five star reviews it gives me confidence in my ability to keep teaching other students.
Number two is it actually helps the course rank higher in the search results that allows me to reach
more people and to help many others.
All right.
So that is also very important because it doesn't matter if I invest that 60 80 or 100 hours into the
course if it's not in the search results on the top then it's not going to help a lot of people right.
So please if you think the Course is helping you out and you feel it's a five star course.
Please go ahead and leave me a review.
All right.
I would really greatly appreciate it.
And by the way the Web site will ask you often if you want to leave a review or not.
So if you're not ready to leave review then please don't keep taking the course.
Keep learning more do more problems etc. but once you feel that the Course has helped you enough to
warrant a five star review.
If you think that's what it deserves then I'll ask you to please go ahead and leave a rating.
You could also out of the description in the review which is something that I greatly appreciate any
sort of feedback is completely appreciated.
But if you don't want to leave a description of why you gave me that rating then that's fine.
Even if it's just marking the number of stars then that is great but any sort of feedback is appreciated.
All right so I hope you like the course.
I hope that my teaching is beneficial to you as it's been to other students and I'll see you in the
next video.