Hey they're welcome to another session of limitless calculus.
This is going to be a short one.
I just want to go over quickly the different types of notations for derivatives.
Now before we do that I want you to remember one thing remember that y equals f of x.
This is the typical notation for a function.
Right.
So we have that why is the output
we have that x is the input
and that is the rule that you apply to the input to take this input X you put it through a rule f and
then that gives you a result.
Why.
Remember we talked about this in the first last and I think it was the very beginning where we were
talking about functions.
So knowing that y equals f of x we can jump in into the notations for derivatives.
So we have three main ways of denoting derivatives.
So the first one is the prime notation
that is number one.
So how does a prime notation look.
Well if we are given a function f of x then its derivative is f prime of x so f prime of X is just f
of x with the apostrophe in between.
That's called the prime.
Kind of like Amazon Prime.
So this is read as if Prime of x
so when it looks like this f prime of X this is a derivative function if you want to find the derivative
at a specific point you would just say f prime and then you would actually plug in the x value.
So for example Prime of 3.
All right.
Prime of 10 prime of 0.
So remember what we talked about where derivative can either mean the derivative function or it can
mean the specific rate of change after you have found the function.
So you either find the function or you find the function and then you plug in an x value.
Also because we know that y equals f of x we know that the derivative of this can also look like y prime.
Right so f of x is the same as y.
So instead of saying f prime of X we can say y prime.
OK.
So this is a prime notation.
All you do is you put an apostrophe in between the F and the x or you just put it at the end of the
Y and that gives you your derivative.
That's how you know you're dealing with derivatives the second one is the differential notation.
You don't really need to know the names of each of each of these.
All you need to know is OK to have a prime to have a differential.
OK I'm dealing with a derivative.
All right.
So the differential notation
looks something like this.
Do you why over dx.
All right.
So D-y over dx it looks like a fraction but it really isn't.
We don't really need to get too technically into what it is and what it isn't just know that this means
that you're finding the derivative of Y.
So here finding derivative
of Y.
All right.
By the same token because y equals X we can also say the f of x and we'll put this in parentheses over
the X right.
This means pretty much the same thing.
So you have D and instead of Y we put at the actual f of x over dx.
Now if you want to find the derivative at a specific x value with this notation what you do is you can
say something like D-y dx
and you draw those vertical line and then down here you say when X equals three for example this means
find the derivative function and plug in three.
When you find that derivative function this would be the same as what we have here Prime of 3 is the
same as D-y over dx at X equals 3 Inka.
So don't get confused if you see something like Deal dx of x squared remember this is the derivative
of x squared and we know already that the answer is to x.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
We'll do a couple of examples in the problem section so you can get acquainted with each of these and
then we have the last one.
This one we don't really see a lot.
Personally I haven't seen this one in our calculus courses that I've taken but I'll throw it in just
in case.
And it's called Euler's notation
and it looks something like this.
So dx with a small x right there of f of x.
All right.
So here we're saying find the derivative of f of x.
But this one again is not really used at all.
All right.
So the main thing I want you to take away from this is number one and number two.
So the prime notation and the differential notation.
So again the prime notation you have this apostrophe whenever you see an apostrophe that means you need
to find a derivative.
So if you see for example f prime of X that means find the derivative function.
However if you see f prime of 3 that means find the derivative function and plug 3 into it.
OK.
And prime of x can also be called Y prime.
Right.
And for the differential notation the main notation is D-y DX which again kind of looks like a fraction.
This just means find the derivative of Y.
All right.
And this can also be written as d of f of x over DX right because f of x is the same as y.
And finally to find it at a specific point you just say Do y x x x equals 3.
And here's an example D over dx of x squared is just a derivative of x squared which is 2 x.
Very quick summary of what we just covered.
Like we said there are three main notations for derivatives.
You have prime you have differential and you have Euler's.
So just to put them here again in prime.
You have this little apostrophe.
And that's what's called the prime.
So it can look something like a prime of x which is the same as y prime.
Right.
Or you could have to add a specific points.
So prime of 5 for example.
All right.
Then you have the differential notation which is the one that looks like a fraction.
So the Y over DX which can also be written as d dx of f of x
and we know this because we know that y equals f of X..
So instead of using Y we can also use F X.
OK.
And if you want to find it at a specific point you do D-y dx at X equals whatever X equals 11 for example.
Right.
And finally we have Euler's notation which again we don't really use it where you have it in the form
of for example DX f of x that means find the derivative of f of x and that's pretty much it.
So the main ones like I said are prime and differential.
Those are the ones that you will see in your textbook all over the place.
And the main takeaway is whenever you see an apostrophe or a D-y over ADX you know you're dealing with
derivatives.
So you know you need to find some sort of derivative function.
Maybe you need to plug in a number into it.
Etc. but it's very important not to get confused between f of x and its derivative.
One thing is the original function f of x something else is its derivative.
If you plug in a number into the Runk function.
So for example if instead of plugging it into a derivative you plug it into the original function.
It's not going to work.
All right.
So that's pretty much it for annotations of derivatives you get acquainted with these notations very
quickly because we'll be doing a lot of derivative problems.
So again there's nothing to worry about and I'll see you in the next tutorial.