OK and so the second technique that we can use is called rationalization.
And basically what this is is working with roots in order to be able to evaluate the limits.
So for example let's do a quick problem here.
I say that we have limits of
square root IVAX minus six over X minus 36
as x approaches 36 OK.
So again to find the limits plug it in.
First thing you do.
So this becomes you plug in square roots of 36 minus 6 over 36 because it's X minus 36 again.
Oh look so we have a problem.
We get discarded of 36 is 6 minus 6 0 on top which again is ok but then we have 36 minus 36 on the bottom.
So we get zero zero.
Again no bueno.
Let's give that a shot.
So let's say limit of just rewriting it again.
Square root of x minus 6 over X minus 36.
OK.
So we definitely need to manipulate this in some way so that we can actually evaluate the limit.
And as you can see there's nothing really to factor.
So what do we do.
Well we rationalize.
So how do we rationalize we basically multiply this whole fraction on top and bottom by a conjugate.
I'll explain what that is for rationalization.
We multiply
the top and the bottom
by a conjugate.
OK so what is a conjugate.
Let's find out.
So to rationalize all we do is we look at the term with a square root and we multiply by the conjugate
the conjugate being the same expression.
But with the changed sign.
Right.
So the conjugate is
the same expression
with different sign.
Here are some examples of conjugates for example.
If you have a square root of x minus 6 conjugate it will be square root of x plus six.
So we just went from a minus to a plus.
That's it.
That's a conjugate.
Again another example is the square root of x minus nine the conjugate of that will be square root of
x plus 9.
Again we're just changing the sign in the middle.
All right.
So actually this first one here is the one that we need to use.
So again we multiply the top and the bottom by a conjugate.
So the conjugate of this square root of x minus 6 and again let me repeat once more you get the conjugate
of the expression with the square root.
All right so what we're doing is we're manipulating this function in order to be able to evaluate the
limit so we multiply by the conjugate of the expression that has a square root.
So the conjugate of a square root of x minus 6 is
X plus 6 and the same thing on the bottom square root of x plus 6.
All right all of that as x approaches 36.
All right so what does that equal to.
All right.
So remember what we're doing here is we're multiplying fractions so we multiply the top Times the top
and the bottom times the bottom.
OK.
So it's this multiplied by this and this multiplied by this.
When I say this I mean this whole thing by this whole thing.
And the same thing on top right.
So let's multiply the ones on top and see what we get.
So we have screwed of X times square root of x.
Remember if you multiply the square root of something again by itself it's going to give you that something
for example the square root of 9 is 3.
So square root of nine times square root of 9 is 3 times 3 which gives you back 9.
So it's pretty much removing this square root.
All right.
The square root of x times square root of x is just x.
And if that didn't make a lot of sense.
Don't worry I will go into more problems later on.
And remember here we're doing foil.
Remember foil so foil it's funny foil is actually on a Monnick but I didn't come up with it.
Of course I'm sure you've seen it before.
It stands for first
outer
inner and last and again foil is used when you're multiplying something like this when you have for
example
a plus b times c plus D.
All right.
So the first you multiply the first which is the f.
So you have a the first one here times.
See the first one here.
Then you multiply the outer the outers are a over here and over here then you multiply the inner the
inner R B and C and then you multiply the last which are B and D.
And that is foil.
So that's exactly what we're doing here.
So first we do the math which is for first so squared of X times square root of x then we multiply the
outer.
So we have a square root of x will do plus square root of x times 6.
And actually all we would write is instead of saying is quoted of X time 6 I'll say six square root
of X..
That's usually how it's written.
OK.
So that's first then we did our.
Now we do enter.
So negative six times square root of x.
So we do minus six quarterbacks.
And then finally we have the last which is negative 66 which is negative 36 right positive times a negative
is a negative.
All right so we multiply this whole thing on top and to finish up this limit we're actually not going
to touch the ones on the bottom.
We're just going to leave it as multiplying.
OK.
So I hope you're seeing how this works.
You rationalize by getting the conjugate of the term with the roots and then you actually go ahead with
the multiplication of this conjugate on top.
You do it explicitly.
You actually do foil on the bottom you just leave it as an expression on the bottom are going to leave
it as X minus 36 times square root of x plus 6 right.
And let's see what happens down here.
So check it out.
We have six quarterbacks minus 6 square root of x.
So you're actually subtracting something from itself right.
This six square root of x is positive.
And this six quartet of x is negative.
So these cancel out.
Interesting.
That is why we do rationalization.
See we just got rid of this square root and now we're going to do something else.
So we have actually continue this in the next page.
So let me rewrite what we just had.
So we had limits of
X plus six x
minus six quarterbacks
minus 36 and everything over
remember.
On the bottom we leave it the way it was.
And we do not multiply.
So we are multiplying but we're not actually doing the multiplication of X plus 6 as x approaches 36.
So like we said this part on top cancels out the six scores of X and the minus 6 quarter of X..
Just to give you a visual.
That's like saying three minus three that's going to be equal to zero because you're subtracting something
from itself.
That's exactly what we're doing here.
Six square root of x minus 6 Karoon of X is going to be zero.
All right.
So what do we have left on top.
Well we have X minus 36 that's all we have left.
And still on the bottom we have X minus 36
and square root of x 6
as x approaches 36.
So what happens now.
Well interesting because we have X minus 36 on top.
And we also have X minus 36 and bottom.
Multiplying this.
But remember you're dividing this over this whole thing.
So you can basically do is you can take this X minus 36 and cancel it out with this X minus 36.
Let me give you a visual of what's going on here.
So if you have two over two times three
well you have two over six right because two times three is six.
However it is factored down here so we can do is we can say to over 2 these cancel out and all you have
left is one on top.
And three on the bottom.
That's your answer.
So that's exactly what we're doing here because we have X minus 36 and both top on the bottom we can
cancel widow
and then we have just one on top because you know there's nothing else
and on the bottom all we have left is square root of x plus 6 a right to the limit of that as x approaches
36.
All right.
So interesting.
It looks like if we plug in 36 now it's going to be OK.
Let's give it a shot.
So to find the limits plug it in.
It's going to be won over and by the way when we get to this point we don't see a limit as x approaches
36 because we're actually evaluating the limit.
So when you plug it in at that point you're done.
All right so one over.
And then we plug in 36 down here.
So we have square root of thirty six plus six
one over square root of 36 remember is six because six times six is 36 plus this other six that we had
here.
And that's going to be one over six plus six which is 12.
Guess what that is your limit.
That is the answer.
So see what we did.
We rationalized so we multiplied by the conjugate of the expression with the square root then we do
foil on that expression with the square root being multiplied by the conjugate.
The other expression we leave it as multiplying so we multiply this through.
We only do it on top because the top is where you have your square root initially or your roots.
In general and after that we can cancel out the common terms and the top on the bottom and that's going
to give you an expression that you can actually work with.
So at this point you just go ahead and plug in there 36 and you don't get 0 0 0 anymore.
You get 1 over 12.
That is it.
I know this example was probably a little bit complicated but we'll do a couple more in the example
section so guess what.
Not all limits exist.
Some times you're going to bump into limits that do not exist.
And when it doesn't exist we just say D and E does not exist.
So how do we know when a limit exists and when it doesn't.
Remember that sometimes when you plug in a number into a function to get a limit then you get a denominator
of 0.
Well there are two cases.
Either you get zero over zero or you get a number.
Over zero.
So if you get zero zero I'll go back to the example that we did which was limit of square root of x
minus 6 over X minus 36 as x approaches 36 so we would try plugging in 36 over here.
We're going to get squirt of 36.
That's six and six.
Minus 6 is zero.
So that's going to give you zero on top.
And you plug in 36 on the bottom you get 36 minors 36 0 on the bottom.
So here you get zero on both the top and the bottom.
When that's the case the limit might exist.
So at that point you're going to try to either factor
or rationalize whichever actually applies to whatever you're doing.
And the more limits you do the better you get at determining whether you can factor or rationalize.
So it's a matter of practice pretty much.
All right.
So 00 you can still keep looking.
Our second case where we have a number over 0 at that point we say that the limit does not exist.
All right.
So this is like the topic in general.
First case the limit could exist.
Number over zero the limit does not exist and was doing example limit of 1 over X as x approaches zero.
So what happens when you try to plug in zero into this function.
You get 1 over 0.
So again for 1 over 0 we say that the limits of one over x x x approaches zero does not exist.
So limit might not exist for a couple of reasons.
Maybe the limit from the left is not the same as the limit from the right.
So at that point it doesn't exist.
And the other case is where a limit tends toward infinity like positive infinity or minus infinity.
Which is a topic that will cover later on.
Right now we're just focusing on regular limits.
All right.
So what I want you to get out of this is if it's 0 0 0 you can still try to do something else to try
to get the limit.
If it's a number over 0 then the limit does not exist.
And by the way there is such a thing as for example limit being positive infinity or negative infinity
or as x approaches positive infinity or negative infinity.
The point is that there can be infinite limits.
However we're not going to cover that just now.
We're going to cover that in a separate tutorial later on.
So if your professor starts showing you infinite's in this sector for limits just feel free to skip
to that other section so you can learn the material together.
All right.
If not you're good to go for now and just go over what we learned which is limits without infinity.
And then we'll later learn it later.
So whichever way your professor gives the class then that's the way you should study
for
five.