So let's do a couple of problems on critical points or first one says find the critical points for F
X equals to x squared plus 2 x minus 5.
So I'll let you pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So remember that to find critical points.
First we need to find the derivative.
So let's find the derivative of f of x.
So first term to x squared constant multiples so we leave it on the side.
We bring down a dictator which is a 2 and new leader is one and we do plus the derivative of the other
one which has 2 x so constant multiple We put it on the side and the river of of X is just 1 because
we bring our dictator which is 1 and x 2 the 1 minus 1 and then finally minus the derivative of 5 which
is 0 because the derivative of a constant is always zero.
And let's simplify.
So two times two is four.
So that's 4 x at the beginning.
Plus two times 1 is two and then times x 2 0.
Remember that X to the 0 is 1.
So it's two times one times one which is just two.
And then the minus zero we don't market because it doesn't do anything all right.
So we found our derivative.
How do we find the critical points.
Remember that there are critical points whenever the derivative is zero or is undefined.
However in this case it cannot be undefined because there is no fraction.
So we're going to do is we're just going to set it equal to zero.
So we'll just set it equal to zero down here for X plus two equals zero.
And remember that we need to solve for x to find those values that make this derivative equal to zero.
So let's start by moving this to to the other side.
So it's adding.
So it'll go as subtracting
two minus two cancels out.
Bring down the 4 x and 0 minus 2 is negative 2.
All right.
And this 4 is multiplying.
So we need to divide by four on both sides.
Over four and over four X equals negative two over four.
But we can actually simplify this and we can divide by two on top so two over two is one and by two
on the bottom for over 2 is two.
So negative 1 1/2.
All right.
This is your critical number
so critical number.
Remember that a critical number is basically a value that makes a derivative either equal to zero or
undefined.
However are being asked to find the critical points.
I remember a points is both an X and a Y.
So we have the critical number.
Now we need to take this number and plug it in where it actually goes remember on the original function
because we're looking for critical points of the original function we know that there's a critical point
when X equals a negative 1 1/2.
So we just need to find the y value that corresponds to this x value.
If instead you plug in this negative one half into this derivative you'll get zero because that's exactly
what we solve for.
So remember to find critical points you once you know where the x value is of the critical points.
Then you just plug in this value into the original.
And by the way negative 1 have is as negative zero point five.
All right so let's plug it in as such.
Negative 0.5 So we have to times negative 0.5 squared
and then we have plus two times negative 0.5 mine is five.
You're right.
So we have negative 0.5 squared.
That means it's negative 0.5 times negative 0.5 negative times a negative is a positive.
Remember that in general anything elevated to an even root is positive.
2 4 6 8 x cetera so negative 0.5 squared is positive.
Point twenty five so it's going to be two times
points 25.
Let me put this here.
Half of negative 0.5.
Right.
And then we have plus two times negatives are 0.5 so positive times a negative equals a negative.
So two times negative 0.5 is mine is one.
And then we have at the end.
Mine is five.
And let's see what we get.
Of negative 0.5 to a Times point 25 is Joe's point five point five.
Mine is one minus five minus one of minus 5 becomes minus 6.
Right.
And positive point five minus 6 is negative five point five.
So this negative five point five is the y value that corresponds to this negative 1 1/2.
In other words are critical point is negative 0.5.
That's the x value comma.
Negative five point five.
That is the y value.
And this right here is our answer.
So again very simple to find critical points find the derivative set it equal to zero or undefined.
In this case there was no undefined.
So it was just equals zero.
We know there's a zero at negative 1 1/2.
So we take this negative one half and we plug it into the original to get the corresponding y value.
After that we have X and or Y and we are done.