All right so it turns out that there is a special kind of logarithm called the natural logarithm.
So in the previous video we saw the common logarithm which has a base of 10.
This one though is another type of logarithm called the natural logarithm.
So you have two special cases the common logarithm and the natural logarithm and do you remember that
pesky little number that we talked about.
That is approximately equal to two point seventy one.
Remember how that's called e e is approximately equal to two point seventy on.
So let's say for example that you have the log of let's say 10.
All right just to say number and let's say that the base is this number here.
All right.
So we have a log of 10 with pace.
That means or we're looking for a number so that when you exponentiate e to that number you get 10.
In other words this means that E to the something equals 10
something is the logarithm.
And of course we already know that this is nothing new.
What's new is using E as a base.
And it turns out that when e is a base of a logarithm then that's called a natural logarithm.
So let's go into the definition for natural logs.
All right so natural logarithms.
They are logarithms with the base e.
So I have a logarithm has base e.
It's called a natural logarithm.
It's just a special type of logarithm.
So you know how logarithms we usually say for example log of base to ants let's say 16 something like
that right.
So log of 16 with base 2.
This is how we usually denote logarithms for natural logs.
They are denoted with instead of the word L O G with the word l n so natural logs use l n so for natural
logs you can forget about this because for natural logs we're going to say for example Ellen of three.
And guess what.
For natural logs we do not specify the base because the base by definition is always right.
So putting an e here is actually redundant.
We don't really do that.
We just say L-N of 3 or L-N of 20 or y equals L.A.X..
If that's the actual function etc etc..
All right.
So when you see L.N. you know you're dealing with base e not any other base.
It's just like when you see a log by itself the base is 10 and by the way this is the equivalent of
saying a log of base e.
Of 3.
But again we don't really use this notation when the base is e.
We use the notation l n.
All right.
So this is not used at all.
And when you're calculating natural logarithms Well you're going to have to use a calculator right.
Because as we said that is an infinite number.
It never never ends.
It has an infinite number of decimal places.
So if you want to calculate something like this then you definitely need a calculator.
Let's do an example in Google and let's do a line of 20.
This one here.
So I plugged in Ellen of 20 into Google and it gives me two point ninety nine approximately right.
So we have that line of 20 is approximately two point ninety nine.
All right.
So in other words this means that the elevated to the two point ninety nine
is approximately 20.
All right so two point seventy one to the two point ninety nine is approximately 20.
OK.
That is it.
So again this is a very special logarithm because you'll see it a lot.
OK.
So logarithms with base e They're called natural logarithms and their notation is l n.
And you do not specify the base because the base is always e.
And in fact these natural logarithms are so important.
I want you to remember them very clearly for that reason.
Let's go into another mnemonic this time specifically for natural logarithms.