All right.
So this is one of my favorite mnemonics.
It's on a Monnick to remember how natural logarithms work.
So it says that the natural logarithm is equal to the Canadian logarithm.
All right so we're calling this natural logarithm with base e.
We're calling it the Canadian logarithm and that's because of two reasons.
Number one is when you think of Canada what do you think about Ellis when I think of Canada I think
of landscape's I think of a huge country with lots of beautiful mountain ranges lots of greens lots
of mooses lots of nature.
All right.
So to me Canada equals nature and that goes hand-in-hand with the name of this logarithm because it's
natural so natural nature pretty close.
So Reason number one.
Well we call this natural logarithm the Canadian logarithm is because of nature.
All right.
So when you think of natural log Oh Canadian log that's nature.
OK.
Got it.
And then the second reason is something that Canadians say a lot.
I actually went to Toronto and that was last year and I was surprised by the number of people that said
this and I know that's a Canadian thing you know.
They do say this but a lot of people that I talked to said this.
So Canadians are famous for saying A At the end of some questions.
So for example they would tell you it's a pretty nice weather a or this is the coldest day of the year
a.
And that they should remind you that Canadian logarithms use IE as the base.
All right.
So the first word of that A is that don't care.
So second reason why natural logs are called Canadian logs is because of the A.
Right.
And I hope you knew this.
I think this is common knowledge right that Canadians say a lot.
So this is why I thought it was a good idea to put it as part of the mnemonic.
Right.
So this is what will remind you that natural logs use IE as a base.
If you're actually Canadian this mnemonic should be really easy for you.
So an example of a Canadian logarithm led to Ellen of thirty three.
All right.
So we look at this.
OK.
So it's a natural log.
So we know it's a Canadian log.
Right.
Because natural logs equal Canadian logs.
Why.
Well number one because natural reminds us of the Canadian nature all the beautiful landscapes they
have over there.
And number two we know the base is e because they say hey I know this is so silly but I'm sure it's
going to help here remember this in case you do forget it.
So let's go ahead and find the answer to this natural log of 13:3.
And again we'll do this in Google.
And here we have it.
Thad Allen of 33 is approximately 3.5.
Let's round it up to 3.5.
OK.
So again it's not an exact results so we're going to say approximately equal to 3.5.
All right.
This is it natural log Canadian log nature an A.
I hope you liked this one.
That is it for natural logs.
That was a pretty good mnemonic.
A.