All right.
So here's a second problem for critical points.
It says find the critical points for f of x equals x squared plus for everything over x.
So go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So how did it go.
Let's go ahead and do it together.
So to find the critical points again we need to find the numbers that make the derivative of this either
zero or undefined.
So first of all let's find the derivative
and because it's a division that means we need to use the quotient rule the mnemonic for that is pro
minus the B-S.
So pro stands for place repeats.
And then the derivative of the outer.
So let's place our repeats x squared plus four
times x x.
Let's repeat it again x squared plus four times x derivative of the outer here and here and then mine
is then over the B-S.
All right so bottom squared would be x squared.
So let's go ahead and get the derivatives.
So the derivative of this is bring down a dictator to and less powerful leader becomes X to the one
plus the derivative of four for derivative of a constant is zero.
Then that times X than mine is.
So we have x squared plus four times the derivative of x which as I always say you bring down a dictator
which is 1 times x.
To substitute a less powerful leader.
So to 0.
So that becomes a 1 everything over again x squared.
Let's go ahead and multiply through so the zero cancels out doesn't do anything.
So we just multiply 2 x times X so X to 1 times x to the 1 is 2 x squared.
Then we have minus.
So it's going to be X squared plus four times whatever's here.
But all of this is just equal to one one times x to the zero which is 1 to 1 times 1 is just 1 and x
squared plus four times 1 is x squared plus 4.
Now remember we have this negative sign which definitely distributes to each term so it distributes
here and here it's a minus x squared.
And it's a minus because it's negative times a positive.
And then we have another negative because we have negative times a positive minus negative times that
positive for is negative 4.
All right everything over x squared.
Alice go ahead and simplify.
So we have two terms with x squared.
This one here and this one here.
So we keep the x squared and we work with the coefficients.
So two minus one remember there's like a one here even though you don't market to minus one is one.
So that's one x squared which is just x squared right.
And then the minus four over x squared.
All right.
So this is our derivative.
Then let's find out the critical numbers for the derivative
and those We're going to be the numbers that number 1 make it equal to zero.
And number two make it undefined.
So first let's find the ones that make it equal to zero.
And to do this we're going to set the top equal to zero.
All right.
So this is x squared minus four equals zero.
If you remember this is what's called a difference of squares.
So we can factor.
Just to refresh your memory this looks like this.
If you have A-squared mine is B squared and that equals a plus b times a mine is B.
So what do you need to square to get x squared.
Obviously the answer is X that is a.
Why do you need to square to get four.
Obviously the answer is 2.
So that is your B.
In other words this will become X plus two times x minus two.
All right.
This is a difference of squares.
So we've covered this in the past.
And again this is basically just factoring out this a.
Mine is B squared.
Funny thing is once you've seen a lot of these problems they all look the same and you identify them
right away.
That's how you know right away that X squared minus four can be factored into this.
So we're setting this equal to zero so because we have two things that are multiplying X plus two an
X minus two.
If either of them are zero then the whole thing is zero.
So why is X plus two equal to zero.
Let's find out x plus two equal to zero.
So we're going to solve for x.
So we move this to to the other side.
We subtract two from both sides cancels out on this side and we have X equals negative 2.
We'll do the same thing for this over here.
So we have X minus two set it equal to zero and solve for x.
We add two on both sides because this is negative
cancels out.
We bring down the x x equals zero plus 2 which is 2.
So both x equals negative 2 and exit calls to make this derivative equal to zero.
The top right.
And then let's go check for the second case which is when the bottom is zero.
So the undefined case
and then when those x squared equals zero.
The only way for x squared to equal 0 is when X is 0 right.
0 is the only number.
So that when you multiplied by itself gives you zero.
So the last one here is ex-secret zero.
These are critical numbers.
All right these two make the top equal to zero.
In other words they make the derivative as a whole equals zero.
And then this one here makes the derivative undefined because it makes the bottom equal to zero.
So we have a critical numbers but we're actually looking for the points so remember what we need to
do is plug in the critical numbers into the original.
So what we do is we plug in negative 2 and 2 into the original and that's going to give you the corresponding
y value for these critical numbers.
Now something funny happens with this function so 0 makes the derivative undefined.
But we still should have plugged it in into the original to get y value for when X equals zero.
However it turns out that 0 also makes the original a function on the find.
Because if you plugging 0 you're going to get a zero on the bottom.
Therefore this exit equals zero.
There is no critical point there.
Let me repeat that again the number that makes the derivative undefined also makes the original undefined.
Therefore there's no critical points.
Most of the time this is not the case.
Most of the time you get a number that makes the derivative undefined but not the original.
In this case this point makes both of them undefined.
Obviously if the original is not defined for 0 there can't be a point there.
Right.
There cannot be any sort of points because we cannot even plug in the Zero to get a y.
So that's how we know that there's no critical points when X equals zero.
If this had been any other number that you could plug in into the original then yes there's a critical
point there.
In this case there's nothing.
So there's no critical points.
In other words what we need to do is plug in this negative to and this to into the original function
and get the y values for the critical points and I'll put that here.
So let's go ahead and plug in negative to so plugging in negative 2 into the original.
That gives us negative 2 squared which is four plus four
over negative two.
That gives us eight on the top.
And negative two on the bottom positive over negative is a negative.
And that over two is negative for.
All right let's put in the second number which is just two so two squared plus four is four plus for.
And then we plug into the bottom as well.
So that's two and we get four plus four is eight over to eight over two.
Everything positive is four.
So one gives as negative four.
And the other one gives us four.
So these are the y values corresponding to these two x values.
Therefore are critical points and I'll put it down here.
The critical points are at negative 2 negative 4.
Right.
It's negative 2 is the x value and negative 4 is a Y value corresponding to the negative two ends.
The other point is two which is the input and four which is the output of that two.
So you have critical points that negative to negative 4 and add 2 for we are done.
And these are our critical points.
Like I said zero there's no critical point at 0 because we cannot even plug it in into the original.
If we did we would get zero on the bottom or in other words undefined.
All right.
So that's it.
Go out there do some homework do some practice just get it going and they'll see you in the next tutorial.