So one more thing I want to cover before we go is the vertical line test and the vertical line test
is used to check if a graph belongs to a function or not.
As we mentioned before by definition a function can only have one output per every input.
Going back to the washing machine analogy washing your Michael Jackson T-shirt on Tuesday and washing
it on Friday will give you back the same result.
A clean Michael Jackson T-shirt.
You're not going to get you know green pants on Tuesday.
And Michael Jackson T-shirt on Friday.
If you always plug in one thing you're going to get back the same results if you plug something into
a function.
You're always going to get the same Y for that x.
Therefore if a graph has one or more points above or below an existing point it cannot be a function.
Let me show you what I mean.
So let's say you have a graph that looks something like this.
So this is a curve as you can see it looks very similar to the ones we did and will do the vertical
line test to determine if whatever produced this graph is a function or not.
So the vertical line test says if a vertical line touches the graph at more than one point then it's
not a function.
Let me repeat that again.
If a vertical line touches the graph at more than one point then it's not a function.
So for example let's try drawing a vertical line here.
So this vertical line here touches the graph only at this point.
So we're good.
Nothing nothing bad there.
Let's draw another vertical line.
Let's start for example here.
Yeah that's supposed to be a vertical line.
You get the drift.
OK.
So again this vertical line only touches the graph at this point.
So again no problem there.
However what happens if we draw a vertical line right over here.
Ha ha.
So it looks like this vertical line is touching the graph here.
Here and also over here so this vertical line is such in the graph at three different points.
One up here one in the middle and one below.
And again the vertical line test says if a vertical line touches the graph and more than one points
then it's not a function because this vertical line touches the graph at three different points.
This is not a function
OK.
It's not a function.
It does not pass the vertical line test because it's touching the graph at several points.
Let's try another example.
And we'll see if it is a function or not.
Let's do it very simply.
This graph over here.
OK so let's use a vertical line to us to the chairman if it's a function or not.
Well this was actually pretty easy because if you try to do a vertical line even right here then what
happens.
It's touching the graph at two different points.
It's touching it here and it's touching it here as well.
So because it's touching the graph at more than one point with a vertical line then it's not a function
either.
So just like the first example this is not a function.
All right.
So again very easy.
You can use vertical lines to determine whether a graph is represented by a function or not.
So in our first example this vertical line touched the graph at three different points.
So that makes this not a function.
And in the second example our vertical line touches the graph at two different points which is also
not a function.
So by the way for the vertical line test if you had only checked here then it would have been a function
right because it's only touching the graph at one point.
So that's why it's important to know how the graphs of function look.
OK.
So again in this example over here we were good.
And over here we were good as well.
However here we were not good in this one.
Pretty much any single vertical line touches a graph of two points.
So that was a lot easier.
All right.
Let me quickly show you why the other graphs that we drew before were functions so for example a parabola
looks like this.
All right.
So the parabola looks like this.
Here you can draw all the vertical lines you want and you're not going to find a line that touches the
graph at two points.
OK.
See how they always touch it.
At one point here here and here.
Same thing for the cubic
looks like this.
And again you can draw all the vertical lines you want.
You're not going to find a line that touches the graph at more than one point.
So this one touches a graph here.
As one touches it here and this one touches it here but it's only one point.
So these two are actually functions OK.
That's good for the vertical line test.
All right.
So a quick summary of what we just covered.
Functions can be graphed by the x and corresponding y values in a Cartesian plane.
Remember the Cartesian plane looks like this.
There you plot your function and the Cartesian plane the horizontal axes for x.
So this is X and the vertical axis is for y.
This is why so a point X Y represents the input X and the output y.
So if you have something like 1 3 1 is your X 3 is your Y.
That means you move one to the right because one is positive and 3 up because otherwise positive.
So this would be somewhere around here.
Linear functions which we cover next have that are always straight lines and we'll see that in the next
section we'll see how they are where they go from left to right.
Sometimes they have positive slopes negative slopes etc. besides linear functions other functions have
graphs that are curves or both curves and lines.
You could have that to graphs are useful to determine the behavior of a function.
Again you can see if the function is going up if it tends to go down and how it works in general.
And finally you can use a vertical line test to determine if you're looking at the graph of a function
or not and the vertical line test says that if the vertical line touches the graph at more than one
point then it's not a function.
So again if you draw a vertical line somewhere in the graph and it touches the graph at two or three
or four or five points etc. then that is not the graph of a function.
OK so remember the vertical line.
If it's true then it's not a function.
If it touches the graph at more than one point it is not a function that's pretty much it for graphs
of functions.
Again later on we'll see how the graph functions with more detail in the next section actually we'll
go over how to graph linear functions.
And then after that in other sections We'll look at how to graph curves which are more complex functions.
All right.
So remember to do your problems that are coming up and I'll see you in the next tutorial.