All right.
So let's go ahead and do a couple of indefinite integrals using the rules of integrals.
So let's start with the power rule here I'm giving you three problems for you to do.
So it says find the following definite integrals integral of x cubed integral of x to the negative 2.
And and third rule of x to the nine.
Go ahead and pause the video and give that a shot.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do these integrals.
So remember because we're doing the power rule on each one then we can use our mnemonic increase and
divide.
So starting with the first we have X to the let's increase the exponents.
So that's three plus one over three plus one that's a divide part plus C and then that equals x to the
fourth
over three plus one in the bottom four as well.
Plus C and that is our answer.
All right so moving on to the second one again power to increase and divide so x to the negative two
plus one over negative two plus one plus C so if you two daughters and you pay one back.
Now you only know one daughter right.
So that's X to the negative on over negative 1 plus C.
All right.
And remember we don't like negative exponents.
So what we need to do is we take this x to the negative one and we bring it to the bottom and how do
we do that.
We have to flip the sign of the exponent so we're going to have a one on top.
And we're bringing down this x to the negative one with a flipped exponent sign.
So instead of being X the negative one it will be X to the one or just X because remember that X to
the one is the same as X..
And very important.
Let's not forget that we had a negative one on the bottom.
We don't have to mark that one but we do have to make everything negative because if the bottom is negative
then the whole fraction is negative or if the tops are negative the whole fraction is negative as well.
Now in this case the top wasn't negative the top itself only the exponents of the top.
But that doesn't make the whole thing negative.
However on the bottom we did have this negative one which makes whole fraction negative.
All right.
And then we finally add our plus C and that is our answer.
And let's do the last one.
So increase and divide.
We have X and we add 1 here.
So that's the increase part nine plus one.
And on the bottom we have nine plus one as well.
Plus see.
All right so what is nine plus one it is 10.
So we have X to the tenth over 10 plus C and that is our answer.
All right.
So very simple problems just power roll which we covered in the last exercise video.
All you need to remember is increase and divide.
All right.
So moving on let's do a couple of problems using the constant rule for integrals.
So find the following indefinite intervals integral of three interval of 10 and this one down here is
an interesting one because you do not see anything but whenever you don't see anything.
What does that mean.
What number is there.
All right go ahead and pause the video and give these three a shot.
All right so again the constant rule is very easy.
It tells you that whenever you're integrating a constant all you do is you take the constant and you
multiplied by X and then you do plus C..
And the reason why we do this I'll show you in the first problem at least.
So remember that integral of three is the same as saying integral of 3 x to 0.
Right.
So as to the 0 is 1.
Because anything to zero power is one.
OK.
But if we have X to the 0 then we can do increase and divide.
So we have the three we increase and divide here.
So that's X to 0 plus 1 and 0 plus 1 on the bottom plus see and that gives us 3 x to the 1.
So we just put X and then over 1 we don't have to mark the over 1 because it gives us the same thing.
Plus see this is why the integral of a constant is that same constant multiplied by x.
Because if you look at it it's actually 3 x to the 0.
And when you do increase and divide on the X of the 0 that gives you this X..
So it's a row of three is three x plus C.
Let's do the second one.
Again same concept.
I'm not going to do the x to the 0 again.
I'm just going to do it directly.
So integral of a constant is the same constant x plus C..
All right.
That is the answer for this one.
And this is the answer for the first one.
All right all right.
So what does this last one here.
Kind of looks weird because what are you integrating.
There's nothing in the middle.
Well remember that when there is nothing what it really means is there a 1.
So this is the same as saying integral of one dx.
So again we're integrating a constant.
All we do is we take the constant and when multiplied by X so 1 x plus C.
Now remember that one x is the same as saying X.
Right.
Because 1 times anything is that anything by itself.
So 1 times X is just X and then plus see and that is our answer.
All right.
So again we use the constant rule for integrals or we need to do is take the concept that you're integrating
slap an X next to it and add the plus C and you're good to go.
Right.
So now let's move on to the logarithmic rule.
We have find the following indefinite integrals integral of one over X and the integral of x to the
negative one.
Go ahead and pause the video and give them one shot.
All right so let's see what we have so remember our logarithmic rule for integrals says that the integral
of one over X is L-N of the absolute value of x plus C.
And in fact there's nothing else that we need to do here.
This is the answer.
That's literally what the rule says right now.
Moving on to the next one.
Well you might have remembered that actually x to the negative one is the same as 1 over X right.
Because if you have X elevated to a negative exponent you can bring that down by flipping the sign of
the exponents.
Right.
So this is the same as saying one over x to the one because we brought it down sine changes and X so
the one is just X so 1 over X right.
So at this point this is the same problem as this one.
Right.
And the answer is a line of absolute value of x.
Now typically we're going to solve problems.
If I give you a problem in this form one over x to the something what I typically recommend is for you
to bring it up and then find the integral.
So basically one over X would turn into X to the negative one.
And from here you would do the power rule for integrals.
Now remember that I mentioned X to the negative one is the only power function has integral.
We did not use the power rule for.
We actually just use a logarithmic rule.
In fact if we try to use the power rule here what happens.
So if we increase and divide we have negative one plus one.
So that's increase and then divide
x to the what is negative one plus one.
If you own daughter and you pay them back.
Oh nothing right.
So that zero extra zero and oops why do we have on the bottom.
We have division by zero.
So because this breaks down we do not use the power rule when we have X to the negative one.
So for example we had X of the negative 5 x and the negative 7 or X or the negative 10.
Then we can use that power rule.
But for X axilla the negative one there's this special rule that says that the integral of x to the
negative one.
Or in other words the integral of one of x which is the same thing is natural log of the absolute value
of x plus C
and that's it.
All right so let's finish up with the exponential rule for integrals.
So we have find the following indefinite integrals integral of each of the X and to grow of E to the
4 x integral of E to the negative 2 x and E to the 10 x.
Go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do these four problems.
So for each of the X remember that in general the integral of each of the X is just e to the X right
X never changes remember that non-monic.
So each of the axes that special function where the derivative and integral are the same as the original
function.
Now let's actually just apply the rule to see how it works.
But we know that the answer needs to be to the max.
So remember that the exponential rule for integrals says that if you have E to the K x in this case
k is just one.
Because nothing is really multiplying the X just one that is equal to 1 over a K but k again is 1.
And then we keep this e to the X.
So we keep that each of the X and then plus C so 1 over 1.
We can actually take that out and we have each of the X plus C and that is our answer.
All right.
So moving on to the next one.
So here we have each of the four acts OK.
In this case is four.
So remember that we divide by K.
So that's 1 over 4.
And then we keep the same thing.
We're integrating the two the 4 x plus C.
All right.
That is our answer by the way.
When you have one over four times each of the four X is the same as saying each to the 4 x over 4.
All right.
So don't let this one over four for you is just saying that you're dividing by four.
This whole thing.
So another way of writing it is like this.
All right but either way is correct.
All right so let's do the third one.
We have that K is actually negative 2 to remember K is always this number that's multiplying the X..
So we divide by k 1 over negative 2 and then we keep this original one the to the negative 2 x and then
we do plus C and again and let's rewrite it.
So we're dividing by negative 2.
So the whole fraction becomes negative so that's negative to the negative 2 x over 2.
And again this sign for the negative two just went to the whole.
Fraction because of the bottom or the top is negative.
Then the whole thing is negative then plus C and that is our answer.
But again if you left it as this then that's OK and let's do the last one.
So what is k k is 10 right.
So we divide by 10.
So that's one over 10 easy to the 10 x which is right.
What we have here plus C and again this is equal to to the 10 x over 10.
So we're just dividing by 10 and then plus C and at that point we are done.
All right.
So we used our exponential rule for integrals.
Again what we do is we divide by k ks the number of multiplying the X and then we just put this again
the function that you're integrating and then you add the plus C and you are done.