Hey they're welcome to another session of limit less calculus.
Today we're going to cover relative extrema.
So as we always do let's start off with the graph of a function.
So let's say we have a function whose graph looks like this.
All right.
So definitely lots of curves going on.
As you can see this function is a curve and it has parts that are increasing.
So here it's going up and then it starts to go down and then it goes up again and then it goes down.
And finally it goes up.
All right.
As you might have noticed by now these functions that look like curves have high points and have low
points.
Now we're not talking about the highest point in the graph because for example this point over here
is not the highest point because you have points that are even higher over here.
However compared to the points that are nearby it kind of looks like a mountain right.
So this point here is high compared to the point nearby in the same way this point down here is low
compared to the points nearby because you're going down you're going down you're going down then you
get to the lowest part and then you start going up again.
Same thing happens here.
This is another point that's high and this one here is another point that slow.
And again it's all relative to the points that are nearby.
It turns out we actually have a name for these points.
So the points that are high are called relative max.
So for example here we have a relative abbreviated as raúl relative Max but then down here we have a
relative minimum.
And then as we keep going.
We have another max over here as is also a relative Max.
And then as we go down here we have another relative min.
And if you think about the names of these that kind of makes sense it's relative because again it's
a high point compared to the points that are nearby in the same way.
This one is a relative of men because it's a low point relative to the points that are nearby.
So I like to think of these as mountains and holes.
So if you look at this at this Max it kind of looks like a mountain.
Right.
And if you look at those men it kind of looks like a whole a way to think of these is max points.
Are mountains
and midpoints
are holes.
So let's go deeper into the definition for each of these.
All right so here we have relative maximum.
And like we said it's a point that's higher than other points nearby.
And again it looks like a mountain because you pretty much go to the peak of the mountain and then you
come back down and just another example of this.
You have this function.
All right.
So let's identify the relative maximums here.
Where are the points that are higher than other points that are nearby.
So as you go up.
All right so it kind of looks like you have a point here a relative Max.
And then you started going down and then you go up again.
And here you have a no other point relative max and you go down and then it keeps going up.
So here we have two relative maximums.
And by the way the way to call a group of relative maximums is relative
Macsyma
so relative Maxima is a group of relative maximums.
I'll put together.
All right.
So for example the relative Macsyma of this graph let's say that it's this point and this point I would
just give them random values.
So let's say that the first point is at 0 and then you go up 3 0 3 and for this one let's say that you
go to the right 8 units and then you go up seven units.
So your point is eight seven.
This is a relative Macsyma.
All right.
Relative maximum
on the other hand.
Let's go and visit a relative minimum.
All right so here we have the counterpart to relative maximums.
This is relative minimums and a relative minimum is a point that's lower than other points nearby.
So again let's do an example.
All right.
So let's identify the relative minimums in this graph.
And remember we think of them as holes maximums or mountains and these are holes.
So you go up this way and then you have a max over here and then you come down and you have a min right
here.
See how it's lower than all the other points nearby.
All right.
So then we keep going up.
We have a max we go down and it seems that we have a man here as well right.
So just like we have relative Macsyma which is a group of relative maximums we also have relative
minima.
Which is a group of relative minimums
Let's go ahead and assign some values to these two points.
So the relative minima for this function would be let's say that this point is negative 5 3
and let's say that for this point it is four and negative for.
So this would be the relative minima because we have more than one point of this function.
All right.
So we have relative Max relative men.
We actually have a name for the combination of all Macs and all men together.
And let's see how that's called.
All right so here it is relative extrema relative extrema refers to all relative maximums and relative
minimums of a graph.
So again if we have this graph of a function
and we would like to identify all relative extrema it would be all the relative Max and the relative
Mint's.
So here we have a max that we go down and we seem to have a man over here.
We go up again and we have a max then we have a man and that's pretty much it.
So we have two axes and two minutes.
So whenever you hear the word relative extrema again as does all the relative Max and mennes put together.
So it's basically all the mountains like this one and this one and all the holes like this one and this
one as you might have guessed we did not always have a graph to know what the relative maximum amount
of homes are.
So we need a way to find relative Maxson means mathematically.
How do we do this.
So there's a very cool connection between relative extrema and critical points as you might remember.
Critical points is one the derivative either equals zero or is undefined.
So something interesting about relative extrema is this.
Check it out.
If you draw a tangent line on all of these relative extrema what happens.
So here we have a tangent line right here.
Then you have a tangent line right here and you have a tangent line right here and you every last tangent
line right here.
So I hope you're seeing the pattern what is common with all these lines.
They kind of look like horizontal lines right.
None of them have any heights so they seem to have no slope at all.
That's the case for this one here for this one for this one and for this one.
So actually none of these lines have slope.
So that means that the slope for each one is zero.
Slope here is zero slope here is zero.
And the slope here is zero.
So going back to critical points.
So remember that by definition critical points have two checks and in the first check you check where
the derivative equals zero.
But what does a derivative measure the derivative measures the slope of the line tangent to the graph.
Therefore if the slope of the line tangent to the graph equals zero that means that the derivative equals
zero.
So in other words relative extrema occur when you have a critical point.
And this is very important.
So write this down.
So relative
extrema
only occur at critical points.
All right relative extrema only occurs at critical points.
Very important.
So in fact this right here is a critical point.
This one is also a critical point.
And this one as well.
Why.
Because one of the conditions for a point to be a critical point is that the derivative equals zero.
Since the slope of the line tangent is zero that means the derivative is zero.
All right so not only are these relative extrema.
These are critical points as well.
Now you might be thinking OK so for critical points one of the conditions is that the derivative equals
zero.
But there is another condition where the derivative is undefined.
Remember that critical points either the derivative is zero or it is undefined.
So there are some cases of graphs where you have for example something like this.
So it turns out that for something like this the derivative is undefined at this point.
We don't have to get into the reason why but a derivative is undefined.
Even then it's still a critical points because again by definition if the derivative is undefined at
a point then it makes it a critical point.
And at the same time it is a relative Min Right because it's down here.
It doesn't look exactly like a hole but this is a special kind of graph.
The point is it is lower than other points nearby.
See that.
So this tells you again and I want you to remember this relative extrema only occurred at critical points.
So when you're finding relative extrema the first step is to find all the critical points of the function.
Now the remaining question is once you find the critical points.
How do you determine if it's a relative Max a relative men or neither.
Well that's an interesting question.
And there are several ways of finding that out.
There's the first derivative test and the second derivative test and we'll look at those and other sections.
I just wanted to give you an intro to relative extrema.
Let's go into our summary.
All right so this lesson was more a concepts than anything else.
But these are critical.
No pun intended for your learning of what's coming next.
So let's go over a quick summary so graphs can have points that are higher or lower than nearby ones.
So if you have a point that's a little bit higher than the ones close to it or a little bit lower then
you have what's called the relative Max and relative min.
So relative maximums are higher than points close to it and they look like mountains.
So a relative Max looks something like this a group of relative maximums is called relative Maxima.
All right.
On the other hand relative minimums are lower than points that are close to it.
So they kind of look like holes not always exactly like this.
They could also look something like this.
The point is no pun intended that the actual moon is down here or here.
And by the way the max is up here.
Now just for being thorough.
You can actually have a max here as well.
All right.
And the point would be up here this one with a straight line is a very special case.
Most of the ones you're going to see are going to be either this you or a whole or this malintent over
here and a group of relative minimums is called relative minima.
So you have relative Macsyma all the maximums and relative minima all the minimums and then relative
extrema refers to all Maxson ments of a graph.
So all the relative maximums and all the relative minimums make up relative extrema and then we have
the last point which is the most important point here.
We have that relative extrema can only occur at critical points.
So as we know critical points occur when the derivative is zero or undefined.
So let me repeat that once again relative extrema can only occur at critical points.
So if you're asked to find the relative extrema of a graph the first step that you need to do is to
find all the critical points.
All right.
So basically when you're finding relative extrema there are two steps.
Number one is find the critical points and number to classify them as relative Max relative men or is
neither.
And that's what we're going to do in the next section with the first derivative test.
So this is set and I'll see you in the next tutorial.