All right.
So let's go ahead and quickly cover the properties of integrals.
Now using these properties combined with the rules that we just covered you'll be able to do a lot of
simple integrals and of course you could think of these as rules as well but I wanted to call them properties
to differentiate them from the actual rules for finding integrals.
All right but you'll see that these two actually resemble a lot the constant multiple rule for derivatives
and the sum differential for derivatives as well.
Very similar.
All right.
So let's start with a constant multiple.
By this point you already know what a constant multiple is.
It is a constant That's multiplying a function.
So the rule says the following.
If you have the integral of a constant k times a function f of x then you can simply take out this k.
You put out the constant outside and then you keep your integral with the function only to see all we
did.
We took this constant k to the outside multiplying and then we just leave the integral of f of x so
we get the integral of of of X and we multiply it by this k.
Let's do an example.
Let's say that we have integral of 5 x to the second power dx so check it out.
We have a constant multiplying this x squared.
Constance 5.
So that is our AK.
We're going to take this constant and put it outside so we do 5 and then we do integral of whatever's
left which is your function f of x which is x squared.
DX right.
So again we have a five on the outside and let's find the integral of x squared.
As you know what we do is we increase and divide.
So we add 1 to the exponents.
That's X to the third and we divide it by the exponent which is 3.
So the 5 is multiplying this execute over 3.
And then we have the plus C at the end.
And this is our answer.
One thing is we're multiplying the five by the whole integral.
So you might be tempted to multiply the C by the 5 as well.
You don't really need to do that but to be honest it really doesn't matter because C already stands
for any constant.
So if you multiplied by 5 it's still going to be a constant and its derivative will still be 0.
But in general the way we do it is we just multiply the five by this first part and then we do the plus.
See.
All right.
Let's do another example.
Integral of three over x dx.
Right.
So we have a constant this 3.
So we take it outside
and then we have to row of we only have a one left within the integral So that's 1 over x.
Right.
So if you're confused as to why it's 1 remember we had a 3.
We took it outside.
That leaves a 1 because three times one is three.
All right the D-Backs and let's continue over here.
All right so we have three times what is the integral of one over X we just cover this and it is L-N
of the absolute value of x.
So it's being multiplied by this 3 which we took outside and then we do plus see and that is our answer
right.
That's it for the constant multiple.
You take it outside.
You do your integral is regular and then you multiply it back in.
Now the sum of difference property it's very similar to the sum and different SRU and derivatives.
It says that for example if you have the integral of a sum or a difference of two functions
then this equals to the roll of the first plus or minus whichever one you're doing.
The integral of the second.
So that is equal to integral of x the X plus or minus the integral of the second function of x dx.
All right
and of course it doesn't have to be only two functions and could be three four five six seven whatever
whatever number of functions.
What you do is you take the end a rule and you keep the sine in between them exactly like we do with
the sum and different rules for derivatives.
Instead of finding the derivative we're doing the integral of each.
So let's do an example
integral of 3 x squared for
all right.
So we're adding two functions.
We have 3 x squared and we're adding that to 4.
So what we do is we break it apart using this rule and we take the integral of each.
So for the first couple of problems I'll do the whole thing.
But later on we'll just abbreviated and do it directly.
But for now let's break it down step by step integral of three x squared.
That is your first function right.
Plus integral of four right.
All right.
So let's take the integral of this first one.
Well what do we have.
We have a constant.
Right.
So this constant three That's multiplying the x squared.
We can take it outside.
So that's three on the outside integral of x squared DX
plus.
So we keep the plus.
And then we have the integral of four.
Remember that the rule of a constant is the same as saying the constant times x.
Right so the integral of four is basically going to be 4 x plus C we cover that in the last video right.
So we still want to do this integral right here.
Let's see what that is.
So we have three times.
What's the integral of x squared.
Remember increase and divide.
So we have x 3 right.
So we increase the exponent by 1 and divide by the new exponents.
Now here's one thing when you have a sum or difference of different functions you don't need to add
the C on each single integral.
You only added once at the end.
All right.
So you don't need to do it several times as long as you have a plus C at the end then that's great.
So for example for this first integral we don't need to say 3 x cubed over 3 plus C and then add there's
4 x policy again.
That's going to give you two C's.
So since we already have this plus see here we're not going to add it to this one.
We're just going to add this whole part.
So plus 4 x plus C.
And here we have three over 3 so that cancels out and the final answer is x cubed plus for X plus seat.
All right.
So we got the integral of the first one.
We added that to the integral of the second one.
And then we added a plus C at the end.
Right.
That is our answer.
Let's do one more.
But this time let's do it subtracting.
All right.
So we have the integral of x to the fourth minus X squared dx.
So let's go ahead and do it.
And what we'll do is we'll use the rule to break it apart.
So we have the end row of the first minus the integral of the second.
So that's the rule of x to the fourth dx and that's going to be minus because we keep the sign in the
middle.
The integral of x squared dx and again these two are different problems.
So let me separate them here.
All right.
And let's get the integral of these two.
So again what we do is increase and divide for the first one.
So we have X to 5 over 5 minus increase and divide for the second one.
So X to the third two plus one over three plus C and there we have it.
This is our answer.
So see how easy it is when you have a sum or a difference of different functions you take the integral
of each and then you keep the sign in the middle.
If they're adding then you put a plus or subtracting then you put a minus.
And again if you have not only two but if you have for example four functions two of them are adding
and two of them are subtracting.
You're going to find the answer Rolovich and keep the corresponding side of each function.
All right.
So armed with these two properties and the other rules we can actually now do a couple of examples where
we put everything we learned to use.