OK Guys welcome to another session of limitless calculus today we're going to cover instead of one rule
we're going to cover two rules.
And the reason we're doing that in the same tutorial is because they're very similar.
They're called the some rule and the differential.
Like I said the sum and difference will look very much alike.
Often you will have to use these rules together in the same problem actually.
So let's sort of with the same rule.
Many times you will find functions that are composed of other functions and these other functions can
be adding subtracting multiplying dividing etc..
So we used the same rule to find the derivative of two functions that are adding.
So let's say that we have a main function and that function is f of x.
Let's say that f of x is composed of two other functions.
First one is Globex
and the second one is Age of X
OK.
So we have a main function f of x and it is equal to the sum of two other functions.
These two other functions are g of x and h of X..
This is function one and this is function to.
In fact you could have more than two functions adding You could have for example
g of x
h of X
and let's call this one.
I have X remember the letters really don't matter.
Doesn't matter if you call that GeoEye X of H of X or it really doesn't matter at the end of the day.
Let's say these are all adding.
Well as you might have guessed we want to find the derivative of f of x which again is and we're talking
about this one now instead of the one on top.
But again it's the same concept.
So we want to find the derivative of f of x which is the sum of three other functions g of x h of x
and x.
So let's go into the same rule and see how these derivatives are found.
OK so now we have a some rule that some rule says that the derivative of a sum is the sum of the derivatives.
Again the derivative of a sum is the sum of the derivatives.
What does that mean.
You might be thinking Lewis.
What the heck is this.
Is this even calculus.
Well yes it is.
Let me show you how it works.
So let's say again that you have a function called f of x and x is composed of g of x x x plus X
so the rule says the derivative of a sum here if you want to find the derivative of vivax in essence
you're finding the derivative of a sum right because you're finding the derivative of g of X plus H
of x.
So it says the derivative of a sum is the sum of the derivatives.
That means that you're going to find each individual derivative and add them up.
So the derivative of f of x is going to be a derivative of the first function.
Q Prime of X plus the derivative of the second function.
That's the rule again.
Let me repeat.
If f of x is composed of two functions that are adding g of x and h of X the derivative of f of x is
just the derivative of G plus a derivative of h.
So you basically go into the function and you find all the terms that are adding together and you find
the derivative of each.
Let's do a quick example here.
So if x equals X to that 3 plus 2 x to the two well this is a sum of functions right f of x is equal
to the sum of two functions which are x cubed and 2 x squared.
And they're adding because you see a plus sign in between.
So if you want to find the derivative of fallbacks again if we go back to a rule it says that the derivative
of a sum is equal to the sum of the derivatives.
So we're going to find each individual derivative So first we're going to find a derivative of x cubed.
And again if you don't remember one of the ways of saying that you're going to get the derivative is
by putting in parenthesis and then adding this apostrophe over here.
So this is a derivative of x cubed Plus a derivative of two x squared.
Again you know how to do this already what is this.
Oh it's a power function right.
X to the N so the derivative is.
Remember a dictator rule.
We bring down our dictator we keep the X. we subtract 1 to substitute for one with less power.
So three minus one is two great.
Now we do plus and we find the derivative of this.
Here we use the constant multiple rule because you have two constant multiplying the x squared.
And for the X squared we're going to use the power rule because as a power function.
OK.
So the constant multiple rule tells you you keep the two and we bring out and we bring down our dictator
multiplying.
So this to the exponent comes down multiplying that two that was already there.
This too is the constant.
This too is the exponent that came down.
Keep the X and you subtract 1 from the exponent so to 1 is 1 is just 1.
And finally let's simplify.
We have 3 x squared plus two times 2 is just for an X to the one remember it is X because 1 is implied.
And this is your answer
pretty easy right.
Again when you have a function that's composed of the sum of two other functions just find the derivative
of each and add them together.
That is the sum rule.
Let's look at the differential which as you might guess is the same thing but except you're adding you
are subtracting OK guys.
One quick correction.
I notice I missed something in the last problem that I showed you.
So the problem I have F X equals x cubed
plus 2 x squared right.
And we want to find the derivative.
So we use the sum rule.
A derivative would be the derivative of the first one plus the derivative of the second one.
So in the other video I had execute prime which is OK but I missed the prime.
On the second function.
So it should be like this
put in parentheses and with the apostrophe.
So I miss the parentheses in the apostrophe.
So it looks like we're not getting the derivative but in fact we are getting the derivative of both
of these terms of the execute and 2 x squared.
If you're taking notes and you really should we can go back to your notes and add the parentheses and
the apostrophe on this second term.
And of course now let's go to the difference rule.
OK so now for the differential.
You'll see that it's very very similar.
That differential says the derivative of a difference is the difference of each derivative.
And again let's go over a quick example.
If I have a function f of x and that function is composed of g of X minus H of x so remember in the
some rule we apply it when there is a plus between the functions.
There is a minus then it's a subtraction.
And by the way I don't know why but mathematicians have sometimes like two names for the same thing.
So a difference
is the same as a subtraction.
By the way
when you see the differential it's because you're subtracting something from something else which is
exactly what we're doing here.
F of x equals G of X minus Age of X.
So what would be the derivative of.
I can't spell today.
What would be the derivative of f of x
Well it would be each individual derivative of the functions that compose it with the minus sign in
between.
So it's basically you find the derivative of g of X minus the derivative of HMX.
OK so derivative of f of x equals G prime of x.
So the derivative of g of X minus H prime of x which is a derivative h of X.
Again very simple just like the some rule.
Let's do a quick example here.
So if f x equals 4 x to the 5 minus 10 x 2 3 and we want to find the derivative of f of x Well you just
take each individual derivative and you keep the sine.
So you find the derivative first of first of the first function which is for X to the five prime minus
the derivative of the second function.
An X to the three prime
Let's actually so I'm getting ahead of myself here.
Let's do it on the side.
A derivative of the first function.
Again we do a constant multiple rule.
So we keep the four we bring our dictator down 5 x and minus one on top so that's four minus.
Again a multiple rule.
So we keep the 10.
We bring our dictator down comes down three X and subtract one for one with less power that's going
to give you two.
Finally we simplify.
We're going to get four times five is twenty.
So we have 20 x 4
minus 10 times 3 is 30 x squared.
All right.
So again very similar to the sum rule.
Instead of doing plus you're doing minors that is the only difference.
OK so now we have our mnemonic for the sum and different true.
So the mnemonic is actually based on the sum rule but it applies to both the sum and the differential.
And before we get into it what happens if we have one plus two we are adding one plus two right.
So we say that the sum of 1 and 2 is three.
Telling you this because we're going to use it for our mnemonic so when we have some we are adding numbers
right.
So some equals add.
And the reason why I'm doing this is because I couldn't come up with an acronym for some.
So I had to move it over to ADD or ADHD whichever way you want to call it.
And here in ADH is where we get our mnemonic.
So basically it says that add or ADHD is equal to add different derivatives.
OK.
So let me take this out.
So again if we have fullbacks equals G of X plus H of x.
So again we have a function f of x this function is composed of the sum of g of X and age of x so using
our mnemonic we know that the derivative of
fallbacks where we need to do is you need to add the different derivatives.
So you basically get the derivative of each term and then you add them together.
That's what add different derivatives means.
OK.
So we're going to get derivative of g of X plus the derivative of age of X and this right here is your
answer to a derivative of f of X..
OK.
So again all we do is f f of x is composed of other functions that are adding we add different derivatives
of each function.
And then we are done.
So this is for some for the differential is exactly the same thing.
So you can think of the same acronym add put instead of add the different derivatives you subtract the
different derivatives.
OK.
So again let's say we have a function that's f of x equals G of X mine is h of x
so the derivative of f of x is going to equal again.
Think of the same mnemonic add add different derivatives.
But instead of adding we're going to be subtracting the different derivatives.
So we grab the derivative of each term derivative of g of X minus the derivative of H of x and there
you have it.
That is a derivative of f of x G prime of X minus H prime of X and again some difference there are the
same thing.
The only thing that changes is the sign in between them for the sum of course it's a plus sign.
And for the difference it's a subtraction sign a minus sign.
OK.
That's pretty much it.
Let's do a quick example here.
So if x equals 3 x squared
plus
4 x to that 3
those 5 What is a derivative of f of x.
So we have a sum.
So we're going to use the Add mnemonic and it says to add the different derivatives.
So you grab the derivative of the first one plus the derivative of the second one plus the derivative
of the third term.
OK the derivative for the first one again.
We keep our three bring down a dictator times to an X to the WAN is just X because we subtract 1 from
the exponent.
We move on to the second term.
Again we keep the plus sign.
So we keep our constant multiplying at the beginning as a constant multiple rule will bring down a dictator
for the power rule.
X and so substitute by a new leader.
It gives you two plus.
OK we have five here.
So what does that mean.
Well it's a concept.
And what is a derivative of a constant.
Remember constant rule constant temperature is not changing.
Therefore the derivative of a constant is zero.
This gives us your answer.
Let's simplify.
Three times two is six x plus four times threes 12 x squared.
And in the yet we have PLO's 0.
We don't really have to do anything there.
So we have our final answer.
Go right.
So that was an example of some rule being used on the next section.
We'll do an example of both the sum rule and the differential being used together because sometimes
you're going to have a function f of x that's composed of some functions that are adding some functions
for.