All right so now that we know about relative extrema In other words max and Menz let's identify them
and graphs.
So go ahead and identify other relative extrema in the following graph.
So I wanted to point out the max and the mens in this graph so go ahead and draw it out.
Pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So let's see this one shouldn't be too bad we're identifying relative extrema.
So all the relative Max and the relative minutes.
So let's start with the Maxxis.
These are.
Remember at the top of the mountain.
So we have a max here and then we go down.
And we have another max here.
And of course these are relative Max because that's all we've learned so far relative.
And what about the mints.
Remember we're finding relative extrema.
So we need to find the men as well.
So let's see.
Looks like we have a man right about here and relative men
and it looks like we have a men also down here.
All right.
So we have to Maxxis this one and this one and two men's this one and this one that is all the relative
extrema that we have in this graph.
Just a reminder that Maxxis are at the top of mountains and men's are at the bottom of these holes and
the names themselves say it Max.
Top high right men low.
That's pretty much it.
Let's check out another graph.
All right so here is our second graph.
Again identify all the relative extrema in the following graph.
Go ahead and pause the video.
Draw it out and give it a shot.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do it together.
And again this should be pretty easy.
So here we have a relative men because it's down there even though this one does not look like a traditional
men.
So this one doesn't look like this but that's OK.
It's still a point that's lower than all the other points that are nearby.
So that qualifies it as a mint.
And as we go up seems that we have relative Max right there.
And then we keep going down.
We have a men over here
and then we go up again and it looks like we have a relative Max right here.
Finally we have a men right here
and it looks like that's it.
So remember it doesn't have to look like in you all the time for it to be a man nor like a mountain.
For it to be Max as long as a point is lower than all the other points nearby it can be relative men.
Same thing for the max as long as a point is higher than all the other points nearby that it can be
a relative Max as well.
All right.
So for a last example now we have two graphs.
So identify all the relative extrema in the following graphs.
We have a parabola that opens down and the parabola that opens up.
So go out and pause the video.
Draw it out and give it a shot.
All right so a little bit of a trick question not too much though.
So for this first graph.
So we go like this and we have a max summary here.
Relative Max not only is it a relative Max is actually an absolute max because it is the highest point
in all of this graph.
So to the left it goes down and to the right it also goes down.
So it doesn't get any higher than this but we haven't this cause absolute extrema so we don't need to
get into that for sure though it is a relative max.
However what would be the relative men in this graph.
Well it's kind of hard to tell right.
This goes down forever and ever on both sides left and right.
So it turns out that this graph does not have any mens so no Men's
I want you to be aware that this is possible.
Some times graphs will not have any relative Max or any relative mennes.
So for example if a graph is always going up then it's not going to have a max.
And if a graph is always going down then it's not going to have a min.
In this case it goes up up to here.
But after that we did not have any mindes because it always goes down.
Let's check out the example next to it.
So for this one.
Well if we go down it looks like we have a men somewhere around here.
Right.
Relative min.
But after that is the graph just grows and grows and grows.
So it keeps going up for that reason.
This graph has no max
Maxxis I guess we'll say.
All right.
So this one has no means again because after you get to the max it goes down forever never comes back
up.
And this one has no Maxxis because as you get to this point it just goes on and on and on up forever.
So there's not really a relative Max because it grows infinitely.
All right.
So if you're asked to find relative extrema sometimes your answer will be there are no max or no mins
or neither.
Sometimes there are neither Max or Mint's and this is not part of the example but I'll put it here just
in case.
So what if you have a line like this.
Do you have a man.
Well not really because the graph is always going up.
So what happens with this one is this graph is always increasing but then it never goes down.
It's not like this one where it increases a lot and then it goes down forever.
Nor like this one where it decreases and then it increases forever.
This one Joh's increases infinitely.
Therefore this line over here has no relative extrema.
It doesn't have any points that are higher than the ones above.
So if you picked for example random points over here the points on the left are lower but the point
on the right are higher.
So it's neither a man nor a max Maxxis have points that are lower on both sides to the left and to the
right and many have points that are higher to the left and to the right.
But for example this points is lower on the left and higher on the right.
So no relative extrema.
That is it for relative extrema.
Later on we'll see how to find relative extrema using derivatives.