Hey what's going on.
Welcome to another session of limitless calculus.
So continuing on with the topic of limits we're going to cover one side it limits one sided limits remember
our limits that approach from the left or from the right.
So we touched on this topic a little bit before but now we're going to go deeper into it.
So let's say you have a function that looks like this.
So maybe it looks something like this.
And it goes up to here.
And then we have something like this.
And finally we have something like this.
All right.
So you might be thinking to yourself what the heck is this.
Why do we have three callers and why are things just jumping around from place to place.
Well we actually talked about this a little bit and this is called a piecewise function.
And in a piecewise function you have different functions for different inputs.
So different functions different offense for
different.
So for example this function could be represented by a VAX and then the way we do piecewise functions
we actually open this up like this.
And we say
so for example we can say that this is F X.
This one is g of X and this one is h of x.
All right so we have these three different functions.
Let's mark some x values here.
So for example let's call this three and let's call is negative four.
All right.
So we use effervesce when x is greater than three.
That's why you have this jump when you get to X equals three.
Then you start using F X which is the Green function over here.
So what happens when X is less than three.
Well it depends because from 3 up to negative four we use this other function of x so we use g of X
when X is less than or equal to three and is greater then negative for.
All right so do you see what we're doing for differing inputs of facts in this case forgive X when X
is between negative 4 and 3 including the three but not the negative 4.
Then we use this blue function of x.
So how do we know when we need to put you know greater than or greater than or equal or less than or
less than or equal.
So this point here because it's failed then it tells you that this function is blue function actually
includes the three.
All right.
However by the same token this blue function does not include negative 4 because it is not shaded in
so if it's shaded in means it includes
If it's not shaded in and it's just an open circle.
It does not include
all right.
This is why as well for this green one f of x we only use f of x when x is greater than 3 because it
does not include the three.
However this blue function includes the three but not the negative four.
And then we have our last function of x which actually includes the negative for it because you have
this shaded circle and everything less than negative 4.
So finally we have each of X
when X is less than or equal because again we are including this negative for negative for.
OK so we have three different functions.
Each one works with a different input.
OK in this age of X only works when values are less than or equal to negative for this g of X only works
from values between negative for not including up to three including the three.
And finally this green function includes inputs that are greater than three but not including the three.
All right.
So why are we going over this.
We're going over this because we're going to find one side limits.
So for example limit of of x.
I remember f of x is the piecewise
on you know what.
I made a mistake because we have three functions f of x g of x and x.
So the main one should not be called F X as well it should be called something completely different.
So we can call it for example of x.
All right so I went ahead and deleted that and we'll call it.
I have X so we don't confuse it with this f of x.
All right.
So let's try to find the limit.
Of I have X as x approaches let's say three from the left.
And remember a limit is a Y value that a function is approaching.
So threes over here as we come from the left the y value is going to be up here.
Right.
So let's say that this y value is three and this y value is negative 6.
All right so as we approach this three from the left as we get closer and closer and closer the y value
approaching is at three.
All right what if we approach it from the right
limit of I have X
as x approaches 3 from the right.
So as we approach this 3 x value from the right it looks like a Y value is going to be what.
Well looks like it's going to be negative 6 when you get there right.
So that's negative 6.
Let me remind you it doesn't matter what the value actually is.
So if you plug in half of three what does a y value associated with this input.
Well according to this graph it's going to be three right.
So when you plug in three you get three.
Notice that the limit from the right is not 3 is negative 6.
So let me repeat this once again limits don't care what the value is when you actually get there only
what it is approaching.
All right.
So let's try to find another limit here.
Let's try to find the limit as x approaches negative for
limits of IVAX as x approaches negative 4 from the left.
And again remember we mentioned this before but just again if you want to approach from the left you
put a minus so minus means from left
and a plus is from right
I'm not talking about this minus because this is the minors for negative 4.
I'm talking about the minors or the plus.
That's to the right of the number.
So this little sign here on the top right of the number that means from the left or from the right.
Again if it's negative it's from the left and if it's positive you're approaching from the right.
So what is IVAX approaching as x approaches negative four from the left.
So let's say that this is for
as we approach this negative four from the left we get closer we get closer it looks like the y values
are going to be four.
Right.
So limit is for on the other hand let's approach it from the right.
So the limit of X as x approaches 4 from the right I'm sorry not for negative for.
OK so this is negative 4 from the right.
So again negative 4 is already here.
We go to our function and we are approaching it from the right from the right from the right.
It looks like it's going to be whatever y value is here which again let's call it negative 7 for example.
So as x approaches negative 4 and this piecewise function the y value is approaching negative 7.
And again if we try to plug in of negative 4 this is not a limit.
This is just the actual value.
So when you plug in negative for is it defined for this function.
Where is it defined for this function.
All right so it is defined for this pink function because this is where the shaded circle is.
And this one does not include the negative for it.
This one does.
Olga So when you plug in negative 4 into this function you actually get four.
All right.
So something to note here is
taking that out that the limit from the left is not equal to the limit from the right.
So for three the limit from the left is three but the limit from the right is negative 6 and for negative
for the limit from the left is 4 and the limit from the right is negative 7.
So when the limit from the left and the limit from the right are not the same then the limit does not
exist.
So we can say that
I'm just going to do this one first and then this one.
So the limit of I have X as x approaches 3 and here it's not from the left or the right.
It's just delivered in general we can say that it does not exist.
How do we know this because the limit from the left is different than the limit from the right in the
same way if we have limits of IVAX as x approaches negative 4.
And again not from the left or the right.
Just in general then the limit also does not exist.
Because the limit from the left for is different than the limit from the right which is negative 7.
That's pretty much it for one sided limits.
So for most functions the limit from the left is going to be equal to the limit from the right but for
piecewise functions and some other special functions.
This is not always going to be true.
And again if the limit from the left is different than the limit from the right as x approaches a specific
number then the limit as x approaches that number in general does not exist.
And that is how you determine limits graphically.
So if you're given a graph you can just pretty much run through the graph and start figuring out limits.
So if again for example if I'm approaching this guy from the left as you go from the left the y value
looks like it's going to be 4.
But as you come from the right the y value looks like it's going to be negative 7.
If you hear as it approaches from the left don't just go oh let's go left.
It's actually the opposite.
If you're approaching from the left then you're going right because you're coming from the left.
So if you're approaching this guy from the left you're actually coming right and you're getting closer
and closer right.
This is the left right here and that's where you're coming from in the same way if you're approaching
from the right then you're coming from the right which is here and you're getting closer and closer
and closer.
All right.
So that's how limits from the left and the right work.