Hello what's going on.
Welcome to another session of limitless calculus.
We're going to continue the topic of linear functions linear functions is something that we touched
on a little bit on the graphing functions section but now we'll go a little bit deeper into what a linear
function is and how it works.
So as we learn before graphs of functions let us have a peek into how a function behaves.
In other words we can see how a function is changing as we know a function can be trending upward quickly
aboard that very slowly downward quickly or maybe not that quickly.
It can be unchanging etc..
So basically there are a lot of things that could be happening to a function at a given time.
So let's talk about linear functions and how they're changing.
First let's go into the definition of a linear function.
So here we have the definition of a linear function Ellenor function is a function in the form y equals
AirMax plus B where M is a number and B is another number.
And I'll give you a mnemonic for you to remember it's going to be very easy for now just know that it's
y equals maximal speed.
If it's in this form then you know it is a linear function and something very important about linear
functions is that exponent.
Their highest exponent is always 1.
So remember if X does not have an exponent it's assumed to be 1.
So if this were a 2 or 3 or a 4 then it would not be a linear function.
So that's why it's always y equals max plus b and x is the same as x to the one and we mark that here
x is equal to x to the one OK.
So whenever you see an explosion that's not one you're not dealing with a linear function.
And something interesting about linear functions is that its graph is always a straight line.
So so we have some examples here of linear functions.
So 2 x plus three is this a linear function.
Well it definitely looks like one because we have X plus B So remember the M is a number multiplied
the x y multiplying the X here is a 2 so m equals 2 and B would be the last number at the end which
is 3 b equals 3.
Another example of a linear function would be 5 plus x.
So what's different about this one.
Well the X is on the right but it really doesn't matter.
It could be on the left over here or it could be on the right as well.
So in this case remember that the number multiply the X is the M.
Here the number multiplying the x.
There's nothing there so it's just the one because one times x equals X and equals one
and B is just a number by itself that constant at the end.
Which in this case is at the beginning.
So that's five
while the example of a linear function would be 3 x minus 2.
The fact let's make this negative 3 x minus 2.
Is that a linear function.
Sure is why it's in the form y equals m beat.
In this case the M the number multiply and the x is negative.
So is negative 3 and B is just the number at the end which would be negative 2.
All right.
And the second point its graph is always a straight line.
Well interesting because to graph a straight line all you need is two points.
So for example let's pick the graph of this one to X plus three.
So we'll do this over here.
We have a plane
X horizontal y vertical and since we only need two points what we'll do is we'll get a little table
for our function and we'll plug in two values into this function so half of X equals two acts plus three
let's plug in easy values like of 0 so that's two times zero plus three
times zero is zero plus three is just three.
So our first point is going to be 0 3 and let's pick one.
Again we're picking easy values so we have two times one plus three two times one is two plus three
is five so our point here is 1 5 OK.
So now we have two points.
Again remember to graph a linear function you only need two points.
OK.
So we have two points over here.
They are 0 3
and 1 5.
All right so let's plot our first point in 0 3 again X is 0 so you don't move left or right and you
go 3 up because it's positive 3 y value.
So we go one to three.
That is our first point and our second point is 1 5.
So the graph 1 5 we move one to the right because X is one and it's positive and we move 5 up because
Y is five and it's positive.
So this is three.
You do two more four and five.
This would be your second point.
So again we know it's a straight line.
We have two points.
And I'll repeat myself to graph a straight line.
All you need is two points and to join them together.
So we go ahead and we joined these two points together.
Something like that.
And this is the graph of lie equals 2 x plus 3
OK.
That's pretty much it for the graphs of linear functions.
Later on we'll move on and we'll see how other graphs look.
We'll have parabolas we'll have different types of curves etc..
That's where it really gets interesting.
As of right now a straight line it's not very exciting but we'll move on.
For now though let's move on into money.
So you remember how to identify linear functions.
OK so here's a quick mnemonic for you.
It's actually two of them and they relate to linear functions.
So the first one is remember that the equation for a linear function is.
Y equals max plus B.
So how do we remember that.
Oh I invented this really cool mnemonic which is actually very easy to remember and that is why Mexico
abro So why Eco's exploits b.
Think of it like this.
So obviously the why is why this why over here this is why emacs is the abbreviation for Mexico so why
equals emacs plus B and B stands for the bro.
It's that simple.
You might be thinking wow this is so silly it is silly.
But precisely because it's silly is why you will remember this.
So linear function y Mexico bro.
You're not going to forget y equals emacs plus speak.
All right.
So think about it.
Think about it again.
It's going to go into your head and at the moment of truth during a test you'll be thinking to yourself
why Mexico bro.
And that is amazing.
All right and the second thing is remember that I said that the graphs of linear functions are aligned.
How do we remember this.
Very easy.
Just think of the name Lennier contains the word line.
OK so graphs of linear functions are always lines.
So this line refers to this line.
OK.
So graphs of linear functions are always lines.
Like I said to graph a line.
All you need is two points.
That's it.
So if you want to graph a linear function you pick two x values.
You plug them into the function like we did in the last example.
You get your two points.
Then you just graph your two points and unite them together.
That's it.
You have a line for a graph of a linear function.
So before we move on I want to mention a special case of a linear function.
So again a linear function has the form why Mexico bro.
Now what happens when M is 0 y equals zero times x plus B Well zero times Exiguus zero so you just have
equals B.
In other words y equals b a b is a number.
This is called a constant function
will actually look at those later on when we do the derivatives of conc and functions.
But for now just know that a constant function is a function in the form y equals B.
So there is no axes.
It's only a number.
An example of a constant function is.
Y equals 3.
And if we try to build the table for this check this out
x and y.
So let's try plugging in zero into this function right.
So f of 0
Well is there really anything to plug in here.
There is no X..
So pretty much it's going to be equal to 3
right so no x nothing to plug in.
I just put this number that's there already is half of 10 again.
There's nothing really to plug in.
So it is again equal to three and three.
And I hope you're getting the point.
It doesn't matter which number you plug in you're going to get a three.
All right.
So for a constant function the y value is always the same.
By the way don't get confused.
We talked about how for every input There's only one output.
This right here does not violate that because for every input for example 0 there's only one output
which is three for another input 10.
There's only one output which is also three.
So it doesn't matter that they have the same outputs because they are different axes.
If you had that one x equals zero then why equals three sometimes but then seven other times than that
is not a function here.
It's OK because again you have one output for every input.
All right so that is a very special case of a linear function.
And again the form inches y equals B B's a number.
All right.
So a couple of other examples of constant functions y equals eleven point two.
It's only a number y equals pi which is approximately three point fourteen.
Y equals negative 2 etc..
These are all constant functions.
Because they are equal to a number with no variables no letters.
And that is what a constant function is.