Now this only works when you're given a graph.
So what if you're not given a graph and you're not asked to build a graph you're just told approximate
the limit algebraically.
How do we do this.
Well it's actually very easy.
So for example let's do a simple function here and we actually did this before but just to refresh your
mind we'll do let's say we want to find the limit of X plus 3 as x approaches 1 from the left.
So what we can do is we can actually build a small table
of values that are approaching this one from the left.
And if you look at the number line
and one is here then as you approach from the left
you have values that are close.
For example you have 0.9 zero point nine nine x cetera.
In the same way if you approach from the right you have 1.0 on one point one etc..
OK.
So let's actually use these values to plug them in here.
So we have from the left 0.9 zero point nine nine and zero point nine nine nine.
So these numbers are getting bigger but they're still less than 1.
So they're approaching one from the left.
We plug them in here of course we're going to get for zero point nine.
We're going to get 3.9
for zero point nine nine.
We're going to get three point nine nine and four zero point nine nine nine.
We're going to get three point nine nine nine.
So as these x values get bigger and closer to 1 the y value is getting closer to what well it's getting
closer to 4.
Obviously it goes from three point nine then three point ninety nine and then three point nine nine
nine.
So it's obviously four.
So the limit from the left is going to be for on the other hand.
What's the limit of X plus 3.
As x approaches one from the right and again will builds another table here of x and y.
So now we're approaching one from the right.
So from here.
So we have to pick values that are getting smaller and smaller and closer to one.
So let's pick one point one one point zero one and one point zero zero one.
So we just plug them into this function and see what we're approaching for 1.1 we get 1.1 plus three
is 4.1 4.1
for 1.0 one in the same way it's just four point zero one and for one point zero zero one is four point
zero zero one.
So as the x values get smaller and smaller and closer to 1 the y values are getting closer to what.
Well it's 4.1 then a four point zero one and then four point zero zero one.
So it's obviously getting closer to 4.
In this case then the limit from the left equals four and the limit from the right equals four because
the limit from the left and from the right are equal.
This is equal to this.
That means that the limits of Expo's 3 as x approaches 1 in general not from the left or the right.
Just in general exist and it is equal to four.
Right.
This is our answer.
So again just to recap what we did was we found the limit from the left as x approaches 1 and from the
right as x approaches one as well for the function x 3.
So for the left we pick values that are getting closer to 1 which are these.
And from the right we're pick values that are also getting closer to 1 but they're getting smaller.
So if you approach from the left the values get bigger and if you approach from the right the values
get smaller.
In both cases left and right they both approach a four because the limit from the left and the one from
the right are equal then the limit in general exist and it equals four.
And let's go into our summary.
All right.
So for a summary of what we just covered limits can be evaluated from the left or from the right.
That's what's called a one sided limits and a minus means from the left and a plus means from the right.
So if you have a limit as x approaches 3 with a negative here that means it's from the left.
And if you have a limit of x x x approaches negative 2 with a plus or rehear that means it's from the
right
so the sign at the beginning is just a sign of the number itself the sign on the top.
Here is a sign of where are approaching from left or right.
Piecewise function has different functions for different inputs with jumps at certain values.
We did an example of that at the beginning where we have IVAX and it's composed of f of x g of x n h
of X..
Each one has different inputs.
Then a limit from the left is not always equal to a limit from the right.
We saw an example in the piecewise function.
Sometimes you approach a valley from the left and it gives you a certain a y value and then you approach
it from the right and it gives you another Y value.
So they're not equal to evaluate one side it limits graphically.
That means when you're given a graph follow along the graph from left and right.
So for example if we have something like this
let's say that we have a piecewise function that looks something like this.
All right so if we're approaching the limit here as you approach it from the left you start on the left
side because it's from the left and then you get closer and closer and closer.
So the limit is whatever y values are over here.
If you approach it from the right however then you start at the right because it's from the right and
you get closer and closer and closer and then the limit would be whatever y value is defined over here.
And remember that circle that's shaded in means that it is defined for this function.
And if the circle is not shaded in then that point is not defined for this function right.
It's approaching it but it's not defined as the X when you actually get there.
And moving on to evaluate one side it limits algebraically pick close values from left and right.
This is where we build our little table of for example 2.9 two point ninety nine and two point nine
nine nine.
And then from the other side would be three point one three point zero one and three point zero Israel
one.
Both of these examples are approaching three but one is doing it from the left and the other one from
the right.
And finally this is probably the most important point in this lesson is the limit from the left and
the right are different so they're not equal to each other than the limit in general does not exist.
All right.
So limit from the left has to be equal to the limit from the right for the limit in general to exist
if they're different.
The limit does not exist.
So that was it for limits for now.
Later in the future we'll look at limits with infinity.
But that's going to be for later on.
So after this we're going to go into continuity which is related to limits but it's a little bit more
than that.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next tutorial.