Are right so let's go into a quick summary of what indefinite integrals are and how they work.
So calculus is divided into two branches differential calculus which deals with derivatives and integral
calculus which deals with integrals.
So the antiderivative of f of x is a function whose derivative is f of x.
So if I give you a function f of x and I tell you what is the function so that when you find the derivative
of that function it gives you this f of x that's the antiderivative.
And it is given by uppercase of x so uppercase X that's the antiderivative and the derivative of the
antiderivative gives you the function that you're working with vivax.
All right.
Next we have that functions have an infinite number of antiderivatives because of constants and we know
this.
And we did a couple of examples for example the derivative of x squared is X but the derivative of x
squared plus 3 is also 2 x and the derivative of x squared minus 5 is also 2 x the derivative of x squared
plus 10 is also 2 x etc. etc..
So when you add a constant to the antiderivative you're still going to get f of x.
When you differentiate it because the derivative of a constant is always 0.
That's why there is an infinite number of antiderivatives.
Next the family of antiderivatives of a function is called the indefinite integral of the function.
It is given by uppercase f of x.
Plus C.
So remember this C actually stands for any constant.
It could be two.
It could be 10.
It could be five.
It could be negative 10.
It could be negative 20 etc..
It really doesn't matter.
It's only a concept.
It represents a constant.
And then this f x is then the antiderivative of lowercase f of x.
Right.
So this upper case f of x plus see represents the infinite number of antiderivatives that a function
can have.
Next we have a notation for an indefinite integral is the following.
So we have elongated s half of x which is the function for which you're finding the indefinite integral
remember that next to that we also put DX right.
And the answer to that will be uppercase f of x plus C.
All right.
This is a notation for an indefinite integral and then to find antiderivatives for a power function.
You increase the exponent by 1 and divide by the new exponent.
Again this is the most important integration rule there is because you're going to see it a lot just
like the power rule for derivatives.
This is the power rule for integrals and it's opposite to the power rule for derivatives.
Instead of bringing down a dictator and substituting by one of less power we actually increase the exponent
by 1 and divide by the new exponent.
So quick reminder if you have for example x to the 3 DX then we're going to increase the exponent by
1.
So that's X to the fourth and we divide by this new exponent which is also 4.
And then we do plus C..
All right.
So increase by 1 and divide by the same thing.
We actually have a mnemonic for this which is indefinite integral with the I and D in uppercase this
I Andie's tense for increase and divide.
So again if you have x cubed you increase the exponent by 1.
So that's a 4.
And then divide by the same for all right.
And we actually went over a couple of rules for integration.
The first one is the power rule which is the one we just covered with this mnemonic.
Then we have the constant rule that says that the end rule of a constant is equal to that same constant
multiplied by x.
And of course plus C logarithmic rule.
This one tells you that the integral of one over X or in other words of x to the negative 1 which is
the same thing is equal to the natural log of x.
Now remember this X has an absolute value in the answer.
If you need to review that please go back to that part of the video.
Finally we have the exponential rule which says if you have the integral of E to the K x that's going
to be equal to 1 over a k.
So you're going to divide by that constant in the exponents and you're going to keep the of the K x.
All right.
Finally we have integration properties.
We have two main ones the constant multiple rule.
This one says that if you have a constant multiplying a function inside of an interval you can take
out the constant get the integral and then multiplied Bacchante.
This is very similar to the constant multiple rule for derivatives.
Take out the constant Do your thing and then multiplied back in.
And then finally the sum and difference rule again very similar to the sum and difference for all four
derivatives tells you that if you have an integral that's composed of a sum or a difference of functions
you can take each individual integral added up or subtract it depending on what's the sign and then
that way you put it together.
All right.
That is it for indefinite integrals.
I know it's a little bit different from derivatives but hey at the same time it's a breath of fresh
air.
So hopefully you enjoy doing integrals instead of derivatives for a change.
I'll see you in the next tutorial.