So let's do another example and let's find the slope of a different function.
Let's say we have the linear function
of x equals 3 X minus 2 and we want to find the slope of this function.
OK so let's use that formula.
Slow
equals.
But wait we don't have the points yet.
So let's get are two points so we can actually plug them into the slope.
I'll do this on the right.
So again I expect easy numbers.
Let's plug in one into this function.
So three times 1 is 3 minus 2 is 1 and lets plug in to
it three times two is six minus 2 is for.
So we have 2 points 1 1 and 2 4.
OK.
So let's call this point 1 over here and let's call this point to remember formula is why to mine is
why one over X to minus x 1 so the y value of the second point is four
minus the y value of the first point which is 1
everything over the x value of the second point which is to
mine is the x value of the first point which is 1
for minus one is 3 to minus 1 is one right over run your slope is 3
right.
Perfect.
By now you might have noticed something for the function f of x equals 5 x this globe was five for the
function 3 X minus 2 the slope is three.
It kind of looks like the number multiplying the X is actually the slope.
It turns out it is.
Do you remember how we have this equals AirMax plus B It turns out that M is the slope of the function.
This m this number multiplying the X is the slope.
So if I give you this function f of x equals 5 x you know that without plugging in any numbers that
the slope is 5.
If I give you this function f of x equals 3 x minus 2 and it's in this form then you know that the slope
is 3.
You don't really need to plug in anything here.
Sometimes you'll be asked to do this depending on what type of problem or what type of function you
get because you don't always get it in this form.
We call them exploit speak but if you do get it in this form the slope is always going to be M which
is a number multiplying the X.
So again for 5 x the slope is five and for the function 3 x minus 2 the slope is three because three
is a number multiplied the X and here five is the number of multiplying the X..
All right.
So just to finish up equals slope
OK so let's cover it one more thing about slopes.
So for example what if you have the function y equals negative 3 x plus 4.
So we just said that the number of multiplying the x is a slope.
Right.
So the slope of this function I remember we can use for slope because in the in the equation that we
have.
Y equals and max plus B.
This is a slope to what we use and slope then we know right away just by looking at this that the slope
of this function is negative 3.
But wait.
Can the slope be negative or slopes only we're positive.
Well no they actually can be negative.
Let's try to grab this function.
So let's pick quickly.
Couple values here.
In fact we only need two.
So what happens when we plug in on so negative 3 times 1 is negative 3 negative three plus four.
I'll write it down.
Times 1 plus four which is negative three plus four which is equal to 1 and again an easy number let's
pick zero.
It's negative three times zero pull us for negative three times zero cancels out and we have just four
so we have two points 1 1
and 0 for
let's try and grab this.
See what we get.
So first we have a point one one.
So that means it's one to the right and one up.
So about here and we have another point which is 0 4.
So the Xs 0 would move left or right we just go up by 4.
So this is one for would be around here.
All right let's draw a graph.
This is interesting because this graph is actually going down as you move from left to right instead
of going up like the other ones we've seen which kind of look like this.
Right.
Or maybe something like this.
This one is just going down.
So this is an example of a negative slope.
So it's a negative Rice overrun basically means.
And by the way we know that the slope is negative 3.
So let's see how that plays out.
If you start here for every unit you move to the right instead of going up you're going down.
So one to the right one two three down one to the right.
One two three down one to the right.
One two three down etc. etc..
So the difference between a positive slope and a negative slope is that as you move to the right in
a positive slope like these two you go up.
So move to the right move up move to the right move up.
Same thing for this one.
Move to the right move up move to the right move up etc. in the negative slope you actually go down
as you move to the right.
So you move to the right go down move to the right go down etc. etc..
So yes it is totally possible to have a negative slope.
And this is an example of it and we'll do a couple more examples in the problem section.
For now let's go to our summary for the linear functions and slopes section.
All right so going to a quick summary of what we just covered linear functions are in the form y equals
m exploits B.
This is called the slope intercept form.
Not sure if I mentioned that before.
So there you have it this y equals m Expos B is called the slope intercept form and is a slope as we
said this over here represents the slope of the graph of this function the mnemonic for y equals m expletive
p.
So you can actually remember this is why Mexico abro the graphs of linear functions are always straight
lines.
You only need two points to graph a line.
And again the way to remember that the graphs of linear functions are always straight lines.
Just go to the name
Lynnie or this is the line right here.
OK.
Slope is a measure of the inclination of a line.
So how steep the line is which actually measures the rate of change of the function represented by the
line.
So again you have a function the graph of that function as a line the slope of that line measures how
the function is changing and the slope could be positive.
Or it could be negative linear functions have a constant rate of change.
So again going back to the lemonade example if I sell five lemonades per hour I'm not selling more than
five or less than five.
It's always going to be five therefore my rate of change is always constant it's always five.
So it never changes given two points in a line you can use a slow formula to the trim and the slope.
So if you're only given two points and no equation which again stands for slope y to minors is one over
X to mine is x 1.
So you just pick one of the points to be point number one.
The other one is point number two and just plug in a way.
Remember the answer can be positive or it can actually be negative as well.
A function in the form of X equals C where season number is a constant function.
Notice that there is no m x which is have the number here and constant functions have a slope of zero
because there is no rise again.
There is no number of multiplying the X.
So that's all 0 and the function is always at the same height because it doesn't matter what you plug
in for the function it's always going to give you the same Y.
Therefore it's going up or it's going down.
All right.
I know we covered a lot in this section but I'll give you some problems for you to work for and I'll
see you in the next tutorial.