All right so here we have our summary.
Let's get started.
The logarithm of x with base a is a number to which you need to exponentiate this base a to get to X.
So remember when you're asked to find a logarithm you're being asked to find an exponent and that exponent
is such that if you get the base A and you exponentiate it to that exponents you get the results x.
All right so the logarithm is this exponent over here.
OK the notation for logarithms is the following.
So we have log
of x x is the whatever result we want to get to.
And then we have the base a.
All right so a log of x with base 8 that's how you read that.
So then you have come a logarithms that are written as a log of X..
So remember it when you see this log of X and no base then the base is implied and it's 10.
This is called a common logarithm.
So come a logarithms look like this with no base.
They have a logi at the beginning and the base then is always 10.
That never ever changes.
All right.
And we actually have a mnemonic here to remember what each of the components of a logarithm are.
The mnemonic is let's be real and then let's be real stand for Al B.R. which is log Beys result and
if you look over here does what we have.
We have a log then we have the base and then we have the results on the other hand.
We have natural logarithms they're written as a line of X and remember when you see something in the
form of X.
It is a natural logarithm and the base of a natural logarithm is the number each.
And again that's implied you never write e down here.
We just look at it and say OK it's a natural log.
The base is easy and we have a non-monic for natural logs.
They're just Canadian logs first because of Canadian nature.
That's what I think about when I think of Canada.
Beautiful landscape lots of nature lots of green lots of beautiful places.
So nature gives away the natural log.
And then what Canadians like to say sometimes at the end of a question the A tells you that the base
of these are actually OK.
So when you look at a logarithm I want you to think Is it a Canadian log or is it not.
If you the term that it is a Canadian log right then it is a natural log.
And the base is then exponential and logarithmic functions are inverses of each other.
So remember they actually cancel each other out and we went over the three steps to solve an equation
involving an exponential nation or a logarithmic function.
So the steps to solve these types of equations are first of all we isolate the logarithmic or the exponential
function.
Whichever one it is.
So we isolate it on one side of the equal sign.
Number two is apply the inverse process.
So if you have a logarithmic function you're going to exponentiate.
And if you have an exponential function you're going to apply a logarithm.
Right.
So there are just inverses of each other.
And after you've done that you shouldn't have any more logs or exponentials with X at this point you're
just going to go ahead and solve for x and that's going to give you your answer.
And finally there are four main properties of logs.
You can use them for multiplication division exponentiation or finding the root.
All right so that is it for now for logarithms.
I know we covered a lot.
Logarithms can be a little bit weird in the beginning but they should be making a lot more sense to
you.
I don't see you at the next tutorial.