All right.
So let's do a quick example to check if a function is continuous at different points.
So let's throw a piecewise function
so we'll have it looking something like is up to here.
Then we'll have our next function.
Looking something like this and a third function looking like this
right.
So let's say that this is negative too right.
Because this is the X-axis.
So to the left is negative to your x value and let's say that this one is three positive three because
it's one to three to the right.
And let's do one more let's say that this is five.
All right.
So we're going to check for continuity at these three x values.
Negative 2 3 and 5.
All right.
So remember our mnemonic says that the equals L.
That's how we're going to check if the function is continuous.
So let's start with x equals negative 2.
So remember it's three conditions.
The first one is f of x defined for negative 2.
So when you plug in negative 2 into half of X. What do you get.
Well it actually is defined.
And if you remember when the circles shaded in.
That means that that's where you get the actual y value.
So when you plug in negative to the point is not up here.
It's actually down here.
So let's say that this is negative 3 because you're going three down.
OK.
So when you plug in negative to your y value is negative 3.
All right.
That's a good start.
The function is defined for negative 2.
Then we do our second check the L.
So we have to make sure that the limit from the left equals the limit from the right.
So limits of X as x approaches negative 2 from the left is what right.
So let's run through here.
This is negative 2.
By the way.
So as we approach it from the left it looks like the limit is going to be let's say that this is three.
So the limit from the left is three.
Let's find out about the limit from the right limit of f of x
as x approaches negative 2.
But this time from the right
so negative 2 is over here let's approach it from the right as we approach it from the right it looks
like the y values are going to be negative 3.
OK.
So the limit from the left is three but the limit from the right is negative 3.
That means that the limit from the left is different than the limit from there right.
And this is how you say that limit of X as x approaches negative 2 from the left is different.
So this is a sign for different.
It's basically an equal sign with a line crossed over it.
So the limit from the left is different than the limit from the right approaches is negative two from
the right.
Therefore because these two limits are different.
That means that our second condition which is that the limit exists is not true.
Remember that if a limit from the left is different then a limit from the right.
Then we know that the limit does not exist as x approaches that number.
Therefore because a limit does not exist we know the function is not continues for X equals negative
to.
So this is no knock continues.
We don't even have to check if the definition equals the limit because at this point the lever doesn't
even exist right.
So we can say no and it's not continuous over there.
Right.
So let's try our second point and that is when X equals three.
All right.
So first thing we're going to do is on I forgot to number these.
So this would be condition number one and its starts condition number two and we never checked for number
3 because if the limit doesn't exist there's nothing to check for.
All right so number 1 is again D is the function defined for X equals 3.
So when you plug in F of 3 What do you get.
So when you plug n f of 3 here.
Well it looks like we have a problem right here.
3.
So in the blue graph the three is not included because it's not shaded it.
However in the green graph it looks like also it's not included.
Right because it's an open circle.
Actually in both of these is an open circle.
What does that mean.
That means that when you plug in three there's nothing that you get back because three is not defined
for this function.
So of three is actually undefined.
And again let me repeat.
It's undefined because both circles are not shaded in this other case this one down here was shaded.
That's why when you plug in negative 2 you get negative 3.
However here both of them are open circles.
Therefore when you plug in three there's no y value associated with it.
That's why we have this jump and it's why we have to open circles.
So actually in this case the first condition isn't even true F 3 is not defined.
Therefore this is not continuous either.
So you see how the process works you start checking for the three conditions.
D l if one of them is not true then you can stop checking at that point and you can say that it's not
continuous So in your first example the limit does not exist because the one from the left to the right
are not equal.
The second example of three is not even defined.
Some part of the domain.
And we know that based on the graph here and because it's not defined it's not content is because it
doesn't pass the first condition.
Let's do our last number here when X equals 5.
So first condition is f 5.
When we plug in 5 what do we get.
So when we plug in 5 it falls over here the point.
Let's say that this is one okra.
So we do have a point.
So for five equals 1 it is defined.
Everything looks OK.
Now let's do limit of X
as x approaches 5 from the left so five is already here.
As we approach it from the left it looks like the y value is going to be one good
now let's approach it from the right
as x approaches 5 from the right.
That's going to be sorgen 5 is here as we approach it from the right.
It looks like the y value is going to be one as well.
Very good.
That means that the limit exists because as you approach it from the left is the same as when you approach
it from the right.
They both equal one.
Great.
So we have already defined.
We have l.
The limit exists now that d equals L is a third condition.
So does d equal L.
So the question is does f of 5 equal this limit in general.
So we have that f of 5
is it equal to limits.
F of x as x approaches 5.
Is that true.
OK so what is f a 5.
Well we said F of 5 is 1.
So is one equal to what is the limit of f of x.
X approaches 5.
Remember this is not from the left or from the right.
This is in general and like we said if the limit from the left is equal to the limit from the right
then the limit in general is equal to whatever those two are equal to.
All right so the limit from the left equals 1 and the limit from the right equals 1 than the limit of
general equals 1 as well.
So in this case that is true.
They're both equal.
So the limit of 5 x x approaches 5 in general is also one hey what do we have here.
F four 5 equals 1 limit is X or bridges 5 also equals 1.
This means that in fact after 5 the definition equals the limit.
So the third conditions also true.
OK.
One equals one.
This means that the function is continuous for X equals 5.
OK.
Great.
So just to recap we tested three points and the first point the limit from the left is different than
the limit from the right.
Therefore it continues on the second point.
X equals 3.
The function is not even defined for 3.
So it's not continuous either.
However for X equals 5.
All three conditions are true.
It is defined for 5.
The limit from the left equals the limit from the right and the definition equals the limit in general.
Right.
So that's how you know it continues.
And remember you can do the pencil test to test it quickly.
So if you try to draw that is when you get to here you definitely need to lift your pencil to keep on
doing the function.
So you get to hear you lift your pencil and you go down here.
That's why it's not continuous at this point because you have to lift your pencil and same thing here.
Here you also have to lift your pencil.
All right.
So that's how we know that the function is not continuous everywhere but to be more precise and to check
at a specific point.
We use the D equals l mnemonic which is a test for continuity.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
I know that three conditions can be difficult to remember but hopefully with a D equals L Do you know
how to do them.
So you can check that out in the examples section.
And let's go into our summary.
All right.
So a quick summary of what we just covered.
You use the pencil test to test for continuity everywhere and the pencil test says if you can draw a
graph without lifting your pencil then the function is continuous everywhere.
And when we say continuous everywhere that means for all x values.
So if you can draw the graph you don't have to be lifting your pencil to like make a jump or do something
else then it is continuous.
On the other hand if you do have to lift your pencil and the graph is not continues.
Remember when you think of the word continues or continuity then think about interruptions.
Right.
If it continues it's not meant to be interrupted.
But again if you're drawing your graph and you need to interrupt it by lifting your pencil then it's
not continuous that's for checking continuity everywhere to check for continuity at a specific point
where X equals a.
There are three checks.
So again those checks are number one that f of a is defined.
So it's part of the domain
and again remember we talked about domain a long time ago.
Basically you cannot plug in anything that gives you division over zero.
Also you cannot plug in anything that's going to give you a negative number under an even root.
Also if you're given the graph on the graph there is no definition for that.
A like we saw in the last example for one of the points then it's not defined.
Number two is that the limits must exist as x approaches that number a.
So that means that the limits of fallbacks as x approaches a from the left must be equal to the limit
of X as x approaches a from the right OK.
So the limit from the left must be equal to the limit from the right.
That means that the limit in general exists and when we put this here this means that the limit of f
of x as x approaches A exists.
Right so if these two limits are different the one from the left and the one from the right.
Stop looking for continuity.
It is not continuous.
And finally and very important.
Number three says that number one must be equal to number two.
So f of a
has to be equal to the limit of f of x as x approaches a.
And again this limit is not from the left or the right.
This is just this generic limit and you know it exists.
If the one from the left equals the one from the right.
OK.
So those are your three conditions for ways to find the limit exists and the definition equals the limit.
And finally we have a favorite.
We have a demonic for remembering these three d equals L and again a way to remember this is.
Driver's license is continuous.
Once you get it you don't need to get it every day.
It's valid for a good amount of time.
So therefore the initials of driver's license or DL and you just say d equals L So we d equals L.
What you have is the three conditions.
First one is D.
So D is defined right.
So the function needs to be defined for the point that you're checking.
Number two is the limit of every x x x approaches that number A exists.
So the limit from the left must be equal to the limit from the right.
And finally you have a third condition which is the whole thing.
D equals L So the y value that you get when you plug in a definition equals the limit as x approaches
a.
Basically in other words Number one equals number two.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
I know continuity is not a favorite topic for business calculus students but hopefully that makes a
little bit of sense.
We'll do a couple of problems so you get more used to it and I'll see you in the next tutorial.