All right.
So let's go ahead and find the relative extrema for a couple of functions.
Now I want to remind you you need to use the first derivative test.
The problems themselves only say find their relative extrema of f of x but the point is for you to use
the first derivative test there's another one called the second derivative test.
But we haven't covered that yet.
All right.
So one more time to find all these relative extrema.
You'll be using the first derivative test.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do a couple of relative extrema problems find the relative extrema for f of x
equals negative x squared plus 2.
So we need to find the relative maximum and the relative minimums.
Go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do it together.
So remember we're finding relative extrema.
So the first step is finding the derivative for IVAX.
So let's find a prime of x.
So we have a constant multiple which is negative one way to mark the one right.
So let's just keep the negative on the side and let's bring down a dictator which is to negative times
to remember again this is like negative 1.
So X and less powerful leader that's going to be a 1 so we don't market plus the derivative of two which
is zero because it's a constant.
So plus 0 equals negative times a positive is a negative.
So negative 2 x
and then the plus 0.
We don't market because well it's zero.
All right let's go ahead and find the critical numbers for this derivative.
So remember of critical numbers.
Either make the derivative equal to zero or undefined because we do not have a bottom here.
We do not need to check for undefined.
We're just going to set it equal to zero.
So we're only checking for negative 2 x equals zero right.
So how do we solve for x.
Well we need to leave it by itself and it's being multiplied by this negative 2.
So we can divide by negative two on both sides.
It goes away here.
So we only have X equals zero over negative 2 0.
So this is a critical number.
Now what we need to do is pick a test value to the left and to the right of the critical number and
see what the signs are.
Let's do that over here.
And as always we draw our number line so 0 is here.
Let's pick easy values and negative one to the left.
And one to the right.
And again what we do is we take these two values and we plug them into the derivative.
So prime of negative 1
derivative is negative to x.
So this will be negative to times negative 1 so negative times a negative is a positive and two times
one is to.
All right.
So it is positive to the left of the zero.
So we market as positive to the left of our zero because for the negative one is and when we plug in
negative 1 into the derivative we get a positive number.
Great let's try now on the other side of the zero.
So to the right of 0 on by the way I've mentioned this before but I'll mention it again.
Remember that in this number line we go from smallest to largest.
So on the left you have the small numbers and on the right you have the larger numbers so the zeroes
on the middle on the left you have negative 1.
And on the right you have one you can put one here and negative one here.
All right.
It's always from less to more.
Great.
So let's test out the other value which is one and we'll plug it into the derivative so negative two
times one
negative times a positive is actually a negative and two times one is two so negative two.
That means that to the right of the zero we have a negative derivative.
All right.
So remember relative extrema can be either a men or a max.
And how do we know which ones which.
Remember we have a mnemonic for this.
The mnemonic says that we actually have to draw both a max and a min.
So this would be a max over here and the men over here.
And you can look at the sign of the slopes to the left and to the right of each one.
So if you had a line here and here and a line here and here.
So for all Maxxis to the left you have a positive slope because it's going up and to the right you have
a negative slope because it's going down for all men's.
You have a negative slope to the left because you're going down and you have a positive slope to the
right because you're going up.
So what do we have here.
We have positive on the left and negative on the right which looks like a max right.
Positive on the left positive here and negative on the right because you're going down.
So it turns out this is actually a max.
We have a max when X equals zero.
Now the only last tab that we need to do is to go ahead and get the y value for this Max.
We already have the x value which is zero.
Let's get the y value and to get the y value.
Remember we plug in the 0 not into the derivative but to the original function because we want to find
the relative extrema for the original plug in and zero into the derivative just tells you how it's changing
at that point.
And again we know that the answer if we plug in 0 into the derivative is zero.
Right.
Because that's how we got the 0 in the first place.
So let's go ahead and plug in the 0 into the original.
So we have half of zero by the way this is the mnemonic remember this or here.
So after 0 equals negative 0 squared
and then plus two
so zero squared is zero negative zero is also zero.
So we only have the two.
So we have our answer which is there's a max at 0 comma to
this is the relative extrema of the function.
We only have one relative extrema and it is a max and it's located at this point 0 2 and we are done
again.
That was a really easy problem because the function was pretty simple.
And again to find relative extrema all we do is we find the derivative we find the numbers that make
the derivative either zero or undefined.
And then we test to the left and to the right of those critical numbers.
So here we test that with negative 1 and 1.
Then we got the signs to the left and to the right of the 0 we classified based on our mnemonic because
in this case we had positive on the left negative on the right.
This is a max right.
Positive on the left and negative on the right.
Finally we plugged in the 0 into the original to get the corresponding y value for this Max.
And it turns out to be two.
So we have a max at 0 2 that's it.