Hello everybody welcome to another session of limitless calculus in this session.
We're going to cover a very important rules called the product rule the product rule is used to find
the derivative of functions that are multiplying.
So in some rule the derivative of a sum is equal to the sum of each derivative.
Same thing for the difference rule but with subtraction.
What happens when we're multiplying functions.
Is it the same.
So for example if we have 4 x is equal to g of X times h of X and by the way if you're wondering how
do you know that these two were multiplying g of x and h of X..
Well there's nothing in between them.
So that means that they are multiplying.
That could be a weird concept to you because maybe you're used to seeing you know three times four.
And then the X means multiplication.
Well however in calculus remember we cannot use x for multiplication because X is typically used for
the input of a function.
Right.
So this is not good so in calculus there are three ways to denote multiplication.
Let's go over that quickly because again we're doing the product rule.
So it's very important that we have this clear.
So for multiplication
it can either be nothing in between two things.
So for example if we have a VAX g of X that means that f of x is multiplying with g of x
we could have a dot.
So you could have something like Active-X dot g of x.
That means that you're multiplying and finally you could just have parentheses
and instead of doing F X and Audiovox let's do it with numbers.
So if you have parenthesis three close parentheses and parentheses for and close parentheses that means
that you're multiplying.
So again three ways.
When there's nothing in between.
Surprisingly yes they are actually multiplying.
When there's a dot in between them means are multiplying and parentheses.
That means that they're multiplying as well.
OK.
So going back to our original function we have f of x equals G x h of x.
So these 2 g of x and h of x are actually multiplying.
So you know like in the sum rule if you want to find the derivative of two functions that are adding
you simply add the derivative of each one.
Same in the differential.
How ever is it true that the derivative of f of x is just a derivative of the first times the derivative
of the second.
Like in the sum rule and the differential it is not.
So this is g prime of X times h prime of x.
That is wrong.
That doesn't work.
That's not how calculus works.
It's not right.
So be very careful not to think oh we're multiplying two functions.
Let me just find the derivative of each and multiply those derivatives together.
That does work.
That's why we have a product rule and the product rule tells you exactly how to get the derivative of
two functions.
Two or more actually functions that are multiplying.
So let's go into the product rule right now.
OK so here we have the definition of the product rule.
All my you are going to love this one the prog rule says the derivative of a product of two functions
equals the derivative of the first times the second plus the first time is a derivative of the second.
What's.
Yes that's what the pro-tobacco says.
Again do not worry we have mnemonics to come to our rescue.
I know this sounds like really difficult.
So let's try putting it in practice.
So you see how it actually works.
OK so first of all let's get our generic function f of x and we're going to make that equal to the multiplication
of two other functions.
So g of X times h of X
and let's find the derivative of f of x.
OK.
So let's go by the definition itself is the derivative of a product of two functions.
Remember by the way in case you do not know this or you forgot a product
is it product is the results
of a
multiplication
OK.
So the product of three and four is 12.
12 is the product.
So the product is a result of multiplying a couple of things together.
So when we say the derivative of a product of two functions it means that the two functions are actually
multiplying the derivative of a product of two functions equals the derivative of the first.
So in this case we're just going to call the first the one on the left.
So the derivative of the first
times the second.
So the second would be h of x.
It looks ugly right.
All right.
You know it's parentheses X parentheses to be like that.
Plus
the first.
So that's g of X
times the derivative of the second.
So the second is h of X.
We're going to get its derivative h prime of x y.
All right so now we got this big beautiful mess.
So we have the two regional functions g of x and h of x.
So here we have the derivative of G times h plus G terms a derivative of h.
So they're kind of like opposites because in the first term over here you get the derivative of the
first and then multiply by the second and you get the first multiplied by the derivative of the second.
OK this is the product rule.
And again do not worry we have a mnemonic coming up you're not going to have to remember this you know
without any references.
OK.
Just for the sake of it let's do a quick example.
Let's say that our function is as market as an example.
So let's say that our function is 2 x squared times 3 x 3 OK.
So here we have two functions.
We have 2 x squared is one function.
This is function 1 and 3 x cubed is function to right.
So I mean typically a function it's going to be a constant on the on the front and then some X to some
power.
That's typically what a function looks like.
So that's how we know that 2 x squared is one function and 3 x cubed is another function.
So let's try and find the derivative.
I'll do it on the side here because I don't have a lot of space.
All right derivative of this function f of x.
All right let's apply the product rule.
Because we're multiplying two functions.
So the overall size we're going to get the derivative of the first
times the second three x cubed
Plus the first
two x squared times the derivative of the second derivative of three x cubed.
All right you you're getting long right.
I know.
So the derivative of the first.
Again we have constant multiple So we have to leave it on the side.
We bring our dictator down to X to the first power so we don't market that is going to be times the
second three x cubed
and now we're going to do plus
two x squared times a derivative of this constant multiple because we have a three.
So we leave it on the side.
We bring our dictator down which is three acts submitted by a less powerful leader that gives us a two.
And finally we'll just go ahead and simplify this is two times two is four times this three is 12
and then x times x cubed is X to the four so just as a quick rule in case you forgot if you have a little
put it over here if you have a multiplication of powers.
So if you have for example x to the M times x to the end the result is going to be X to the AM plus
and.
OK that's just working with exponents as an example.
If we have X to the two times X to that three that's going to be equal to what.
Well they have the same base which is x.
So we can definitely add exponents.
That's going to be equal to x to the two plus 3 x 5.
OK so that's exactly what we're doing down here.
Again we multiply the numbers two times two is four times three is twelve.
And then we multiply the axes x to the one and again remember we did not market times x to the 3 is
just x to the one plus three or X to the four and now we're going to do our second part over here.
And again we just multiply the numbers together two times three is six times three is 18.
And then we multiply the axes so x squared times x squared is X to the four.
Interesting.
We actually have two terms 12 x to the 4 and 8 next to the 4 and check this out because they have the
same base to the same exponent.
We can actually simplify this whole thing and add the numbers 12 plus 18 that's 30 x to the four that
is our answer
and we are done.
So the product rule is basically the start of calculus where things get you know the problems get big.
You have a lot of terms a lot of multiplication a lot of adding a little subtraction going on.
So if you think this is you know if this is long then you better get used to it.
Calculus problems can get really long because of all these rules that we need to apply some rule and
different true and you know constant rule.
Those are the easy ones.
This is where it gets you know a little hairy but again do not worry we'll go over each step.
We'll teach you how to do it and you'll be good to go.
And again just to mention something here.
We can only add them the 12 x to the 4 and 80 next to the four because they are adding and they have
the same ax to the same power.
OK.
If this had been X to the three and this is X or the 4 we can not add them.
You can only simplify like this when they have the same base and the same exponent.
So again we just added the 12 on the 18.
That's 30 and we keep the x to the fourth.