All right so let's go ahead and do some problems for continuity.
So the first one says use the pencil test to determine if the following graphs are continuous everywhere.
And here we have six graphs of functions that you're going to use the pencil tests on.
So I'll let you do your thing.
Go ahead and pause a video and give it a shot.
All right so were you able to use the pencil test or the chairman of the graphs are continuous.
Let's go ahead and do it together.
So remember the pencil test tells you that if you can draw the graph without lifting your pencil then
yes the graph is continuous.
If you have to lift your pencil then the graph is not continuous everywhere.
So let's start with the first one here.
So for this one it looks like there are no jumps no discontinuity just flows nicely.
Right.
So this one is continuous.
All right.
Getting to the second one it looks like that as we go up at some point we have to jump from this point
to this point.
So we have to let her pencil in order to keep drawing.
Therefore this second graph because of this jump is not continuous.
All right let's go to the third.
So for this one let's start with this part.
So we go down and we go down and we go down but hey what happens here.
Well it looks like to keep going with this part.
We need to lift our pencil from here and then bring it all the way over here and then keep drawing.
So there's definitely some sort of jump in there and we can say that the graph is not continuous.
All right.
Next.
All right so this one is a tricky one because if you go ahead and do this and you started going up you
might think oh I can actually draw this circle and then keep going right without lifting my pencil.
But if we zoom into it what will notice is this behavior.
So I'm going to zoom in on this part.
Basically it's going to look like this.
And then remember that the open circle means that the graph is not defined for that points.
So at some point the graph stops here.
Then we have an empty value there.
And then it jumps to this value.
All right.
And then it keeps going.
So this is a zoom of this.
Remember that we use the open circle notation to say that there's no value there.
So when you start drawing it you might think oh yeah for sure I can just go around the circle and then
keep drawing.
But no this notation means that there's no value in there.
OK.
That means that there is a small jump from this to this.
So you do have to lift your pencil.
And this means that the graph is not continuous.
So again remember this open circle means that there is no value at that point.
So this x value whatever the x value here is is not part of the domain of the function.
All right.
And then let's do the last two.
So for this one seems pretty simple I just go like this and then I go up and sure enough I can draw
it with my left and my pencil.
So this one is continuous
and then go into the last one.
So for this one it looks like there's no graph to the left over here.
But it doesn't matter if this is the graph then this is the graph.
And sure enough I can draw it without lifting my pencil.
Not a problem at all.
So this one is also continuous.
And there we go.