All right.
So we'll do a couple of exercises for the product rule remember that a product is a result of a multiplication.
So the first thing we're going to do is for a couple of functions we're going to identify with the multiplying
functions are remember that we know the two functions are multiplying.
If there's a dot if there are parentheses or if there is actually nothing in between them
so pretty much any of these three tell you that two functions or more are multiplying.
So I'll let you pause the video and give it a shot.
So the best way to break this up is to have a coefficient the X and then exponent.
All right.
So we're going to call that combination a function.
So again it's coefficient X and exponent and you have seen this often.
So for example if you see something like you know like three x squared plus five x to the three Mine
is 22 x etc..
These are called terms.
So this is one term three x squared.
Then there's another 5 x cubed.
This is another 22 x etc..
I notice they are composed of this coefficient the coefficient is a constant multiple.
All right.
It's also called a coefficient.
It's just this number here at the beginning.
So these terms are composed of the coefficient of an X and exponent and let me take this out because
it's not part of the problem.
All right so we're going to identify what the multiplying functions are for this f of x.
So as you might have noticed there are no dots nor parentheses in here.
So your first function is going to be what.
Well it's going to be this for X to the negative to write coefficient pace and exponent.
For x to the negative to and your second function is going to be whatever's left 35 x squared.
So this up here is basically function number 1 being multiplied by function number 2.
And again we know this because there's actually nothing in between them that implies a multiplication.
All right let's check out another exercise.
All right.
So here we have a next function f of x equals x squared plus three Everything times 2 x cubed minus
five.
So notice we have parentheses.
What does that tell you.
I'll go ahead and let you pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So there you go.
Let's find out what would be the first function.
Well because we have parentheses this actually tells us right there which one is the first and which
one is the second.
Right.
So our first function is between these two parentheses.
And our second one is between these two.
All right.
So first function is just x squared plus three.
So notice here in this case our function is actually x squared plus a number.
Right.
So it's not simply like the X squared by itself and again in this case it was pretty clear because it
has parentheses around it.
But in the other case we just did.
We had to break it up.
So we decided to go ahead and grab the first term and the second but then here they actually tell you
what the first function is and what the second one is.
So here we know the function.
The first function is this whole thing.
Same thing for the second function.
We have 2 x cubed minus five.
All right.
So we know that this is our second function because these two functions are multiplying.
Remember though what you're doing is you're looking at this and saying OK which function is multiplying
what.
In this case again it's pretty obvious that this first function is multiplying.
This second function.
All right.
So here we have another example which is more like the first one.
We don't have any parentheses we don't have any dots so we have to break it apart.
We have to say which are the functions that are multiplying.
So go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So let's see it once for the first function.
Well let's see what we have here.
Maybe you notice that instead of having two functions that are multiplying we actually have three right.
So we could break it up with three functions and let's see how like I said when it's in this format
then the way to break it up is to say OK let me grab a coefficients a base and a exponents and I'll
call that a function.
So here it's pretty clear that the first function would be 10 x to the 9
right.
Let's keep going second function.
What would it be.
Well it would just be this x to the negative one.
The coefficient here is implied to be 1.
That's why it's marked right.
So we just say that our second function would be x to the negative 1.
And finally our third function must be what's left which fits in nicely because it's just a coefficient
a base and an exponent.
So it's five execute.
These are three functions that are multiplying up here.
And remember our mnemonic only works with two functions.
So in this case we would have to regroup and say for example that one and two multiplied is the first
function and then the number three is.
The second function will see an example of that in just a bit.