All right so here's a quick mnemonic for you to remember which one is concave up or concave down.
So look at the word concave.
So the last four letters are cave.
Right.
So all you have to think about is where does this cave open.
Does it open up or does it open down.
And again let's go to our graph so we can see this in action.
All right.
So what do we have here.
We have a graph.
And again remember this is only one graph just two different colors so that it's easier to see.
So the pink parts are actually concave down right.
I want you to look at each of these little mountains and the holes as caves.
Right.
So this is a cave but this for example this first cave where does it open.
It's close on the top so it's opening down right.
It's open.
And the bottom part therefore this is concave down.
Then we go to the next.
So it's concave down and then it changes.
And now where is it open towork.
Where does the cave open.
It opens up so it's concave up
right.
And then we have this little mini cave over here.
Again where does this one open.
There's nothing on the bottom so it's open down.
And this one is down as well.
And finally we have our last cave which goes down like that.
And where does it open.
Well it's open on top not on the bottom.
So it opens up as well.
All right.
That's pretty much it for the mnemonic.
It's super easy.
So again when you see the word concave.
Think about where does a cave open.
Does it open up or does it open down.
And to remember that just look at the actual shape of the cave.
If it's close on top and it's open on the bottom then it opens down on the other hand if it's close
on the bottom but then it opens up then it opens up so it opens down concave down open up concave up.
That's it.
So he said that to find a concavity we need to use the second derivative.
Let's find out what the second derivative of a function is.