All right.
So let's go ahead and get started with the Prochnik rule.
Let me remind you of what our mnemonic is.
So remember for the product rule we grab the first three letters of product.
So that's pro p r o.
And this stands for place repeats.
And then our All right.
So if you do not remember what this is please go back to the mnemonic where we actually look at this
with an example just putting it here so you can give it a shot.
So remember place repeats just means they are going to take the multiplying functions write them and
then write them once more.
That's what placing the repeats means and then you're going to get the derivative of the outer.
Right.
And again if you have no idea what I'm talking about please go back to the mnemonic.
Otherwise go ahead and pause the video and give this problem a shot.
All right so how did it go that one wasn't too bad was it.
Let's do it together.
So we have that we want to find the derivative of this function f of x.
We know that these are multiplying because there's nothing in between.
And we're going to use our mnemonic.
So we're going to place our repeats.
So we're going to put it once and then put it again this function.
So it's going to be 10 x to the ninth
3 x squared.
Now we're going to place our second repeat.
So that's 10 x to the ninth
3 x squared.
So we're just copying this function twice.
That's it.
And then we have for the second part of the mnemonic that we take the derivative of the outer.
So remember we have this whole expression the outer is the first function and then the last function.
These are the outer ones.
So we take the derivative of this first 10 x to the ninth and the derivative of this last three x squared
and then remember that for product rule we actually add in the middle.
All right.
So we take the derivative of this over here 10 x square to the ninth.
So a constant multiple We have attended the beginning times Power Rules so we're bring down a dictator
nine x it by less powerful.
So that's eight on top.
We multiply this by this three x squared
and then we do plus bring down the 10 x to the ninth
and we multiply by the derivative of three x squared.
So that's a 3 constant multiple we bring down a dictator which is a two and substitute by less powerful.
It gives us a win over here.
So we don't market.
All right now let's multiply coefficients so 10 times nine is 90 90 times 3 is 270.
And now let's deal with the axes.
So we have X to the eighth times x to the two.
So remember when you're multiplying access like this what you do is you keep the X and you add the exponents.
So I'll just mark it here.
So you see how it's done.
It's X to the eight plus two.
We're just adding this exponents and this exponent right.
And then we do plus then we have this other side let's multiply coefficients as well.
So we have 10 times three is 30.
Thirty times two is 60
and let's deal with the Xs.
So we have X to the ninth and X remember this X is to the 1.
So we have X to the nine plus one.
All right.
So we have to 70 X to the tenth plus 60 x to the 10th and remember what I've said before that if you
have the same base and the same exponents so extra the 10th and next to the tenth you keep the x to
the tenth and you just add the coefficients to 70 plus 60 is 330 X to the tenth.
That is our final answer.
All right.
So I've mentioned this before but I'll put it here again.
When you have for example x to the a times x to the B that's equal to x to the A plus B to remember
when you're multiplying X's like this you just add their exponents and you keep the X. You're going
to have to do this a lot with the product rule.
OK.
Just like we did here.
So for example here we're multiplying X to the 8 times x to the two that becomes X to the 8 plus 2 or
X to the tenth.
All right.
So this rule really comes in handy for a product rule problems.
And finally at this step we were able to combine this term and this term because they both have access
to the tenth.
So we just keep the x to the tens and we pretty much add the coefficients.
And that is our final answer.
All right so here we have our second example.
We know that these two functions are multiplying.
And as a whole f of x equals 2 x squared plus three times x to the fourth of minus 1.
So we know they're multiplying because of the parentheses.
So here you have your first function and here you have your second function.
Go ahead and use the pro mnemonic to find the derivative of fallbacks.
So go ahead and posit and take a shot.
All right.
So let's do this one here.
Derivative of f of x.
So we use our mnemonic Pro.
So we place repeats and then we do the derivative of the outer.
So let's place our repeats.
So we have the first repeat to x squared plus three
and x q.
I'm sorry X to the fourth.
Minus one and then we have same thing 2 x squared plus three and x to the fourth.
Mine is one.
So that takes care of her place repeats part.
Now we do the derivative of the outer.
So we do the derivative of this one here.
And this one here hopefully at this point it's made sense why these two are the outer if it hasn't.
Well think of it like this.
So if you have like like like a string like this the outer parts of the string are this and this right
like the extremes.
So when you look at this whole thing the way we have it the extremes are the first function and the
last function.
So that's why we say outer right.
Let's take this out.
Perfect.
And remember that we do plus for the product rule.
And I didn't put this as part of the mnemonic but if you forget which sign goes in the rule.
So the name tells you product plus.
OK.
So if you're have a product you're going to put a plus in between these two same letter P for product
B for a plus.
All right.
All right let's try to solve this one.
So we have the derivative of this one here.
What would that be.
Well we have some.
So we're going to have to get a derivative of the first and added to the derivative of the second derivative
of the first is just we have a constant multiple So that's it to bring down a dictator to X so to bail
as powerful leader.
That gives us a one on the X or we're not going to market plus the derivative of three a constant is
zero.
Times X to the fourth.
Minus one.
All right.
And then we have plus we're just going to copy this one so to x squared plus three and then the derivative
of this one over here.
So it's just the power function.
So we bringing down a dictator as a four X and we substitute by a less powerful one.
So that's going to give us three.
Then Mine is a derivative of 1 0.
So that is zero.
OK so there's zero goes away and this one too because they don't do anything at all.
And let's go ahead and simplify.
So we have 2 times 2 x 4 X
and we have 4 x times x to the fourth.
Mine is one that is this part over here and then we do plus 2 x squared plus three right this time for
execute.
All right so after this you're just done with the calculus part.
It's all algebra from here.
So if you have for example this part this 4 x times the x to the fourth minus one remember distributive
property.
You just need to distribute this to this term and also to this term.
All right.
So you pretty much take this for X and you multiplied by this and then by this let's do that now for
X times x to the fourth.
So to do this we're first multiply coefficients.
So it's four times the coefficient of this one which is just one.
So that's four times one is for X..
And remember that we add exponents when we multiply stuff like this.
So X to the one times x to the fourth is X to the one plus for so we'll do it step by step.
All right.
So we multiplied this one times this one.
Now let's multiply the 4 X times the negative one.
So we have positive times and negative.
That gives you a negative and 4 x times 1 is just 4 x 8
plus.
And we're going to do the same process here.
There's 4 x cubed is going to multiply this one here.
And it's also going to multiply.
This one here.
All right so let's multiply that to x squared times a 4 x cube.
So we have first the coefficients two times for eights and then we have the axes which we add exponents
for x squared times x cubed is X to that two plus three.
All right.
We're just adding the exponents.
There's one here and this one here.
And finally we're almost there.
We have plus because a positive times a positive is a positive.
So we have three times four execute.
So three times four is twelve and we just keep the x cubed.
All right.
Now let's simplify this a little more.
So we have 4 x and this x is elevated to the Rumple's four.
So that's 4 x to the five.
Mine is 4 x
that we have plus 8 x 2 the 2 plus 3.
So applause 8 x 2 the 2 plus 3 is just the five.
And then we have plus 12 execute.
All right last step of this is to go ahead and simplify.
So remember we can only simplify the ones that have the same exponent.
The only ones that have the same exponent are 4 x the 5 and 8 x to the 5.
So we're going to simplify those two.
And remember when we're adding them up which is pretty much keep the x to the five and we add the coefficients
for plus 8 is 12 x to the 5.
And then we have plus 12 x cubed
and then we have minus 4 x.
So maybe you notice that I switched the order of the 12 x cube and the 4 x.
So the 4 x was first and then the 12 x cubed was last.
It's typical practice to put them in descending order.
So from the highest exponent to the lowest.
Really doesn't matter.
At the end of the day your answer is not going to change is going to be the same but it's something
that's typically done.
So here we have the highest power on the left than the second highest and then the third highest which
is just one all right.
And at this point we have our final answer.
I know you're thinking Prato rule problems can get kind of long.
This is one of them.
It happens sometimes you just gotta make sure that you know exactly what you're doing with the exponents
and the coefficients and you'll be OK.
So what we did here with these two terms is we actually simplified the 4 x to the 5 and the 8 x to the
5 because they have the same exponent.
So remember one thing is when we're multiplying exponents at that point you add the exponents.
Here are not multiplying.
We're adding two terms with the same exponents.
So we keep the x to the 5 and we just add the coefficients for an 8 which gives you 12.
All right that's it for this exercise.
Let's do another one.