All right.
So for our last exercise what do we have.
We have F X equals three x cubed times negative 2 x times 10 x squared.
I'll give you a chance to pause the video and try this one out.
By the way let me give you a hint.
Notice how many functions were multiplying here.
Is it true or is it more than two.
All right.
Pause and give it a shot.
OK.
So let's see how you did.
So I asked you how many functions were multiplying.
In reality the answer is three.
We're multiplying three x cubed with negative 2 x and we're also multiplying 10 x squared.
So remember that our mnemonic only works with two functions.
So pro is play repeats and then do the outer right.
So what we can do before getting the derivative is rewriting this so that it's only two functions.
And the way we do it is we can grab any two functions here and multiply them together and then call
that the first function and then whatever's left is the second function.
All right.
So for the sake of this example let's grab these two multiply them together and then do the derivative
of the whole thing.
So this is still f of x.
Right now the derivative we're just rewriting the original.
And those multiply these two.
So we have three times negative 2 is negative 6 and then we have X and remember what we do when we're
multiplying X as with exponents which is add the exponent and we keep the X..
So the exponent here is three and the exponent here is 1.
Remember we don't market but it's one.
So it's three plus 1 which is 4.
All right that times are second function 10 x squared.
All right there we go.
There we have our second function.
Now we have a function number one and function number two.
Now we can definitely apply the product rule and we can use our mnemonic for that.
So in case you struggle with this problem I'll let you pause it again and apply the mnemonic to this
to find the derivative.
All right so let's go ahead and find our derivative using our mnemonic Pro.
So we're going to play repeats.
So we're going to play this function once and then we're going to do it again.
So negative six x to the fourth times 10 x squared.
Notice I drop the parentheses.
You can put them if you want to but it's not needed at all.
All right.
And then we're going to do negative 6 x to the fourth and x squared.
When you're doing these problems I don't want you to put for example if it's a negative and then thing
that you're just subtracting this from this.
All right.
Remember we have this empty space because here comes a plus after that.
So I'm just going to put it now not to confuse it with this negative.
And again you remember it's a plus because product plus both start with P.
All right.
So we placed our repeats.
We put a plus sign.
Now we're just missing to put our outers.
So for the Outers we're just going to get the derivative of the first function here.
And of the second function here.
All right now is go ahead and find the derivatives a derivative of this we have a constant multiple
which is negative six.
So we're going to multiply this negative six times our dictator which will bring down that 4 4 x substitute
by less powerful.
So the new exponent is a three way multiply this by 10 x squared which is this.
And then what do we have.
Well we have plus negative so positive and negative is just a negative.
So we can put negative from here already.
All right.
So we have 6 x 2 the fourth and we'll get the derivative of this last one.
So a derivative of this.
We have a constant multiple That's a 10.
We bring down a dictator.
Times two.
And then you xponent it becomes a 1 so we don't market let's simplify a little bit.
So we have this whole multiplication let's multiply the coefficients negative six times four is negative
24 negative 24 times 10 is negative to 40
and then let's go ahead and multiply the axes so x cubed times x squared.
Remember we add the exponents three plus two is five.
So that is x to the five and then we have minus here is to the same thing.
Let's multiply the coefficients.
So we have six times 10 is 60 times 2 is 120.
So that's mine is 120 x and then we have X to the fourth times x to the one we add the exponents that
gives X to the 5.
All right.
And can we simplify here.
What do you think.
Well we have X of the 5.
And we have X of the five.
So we definitely can.
We know that the answer is going to be something extra 5 because we're just simplifying.
So we have a negative number.
Mine is something else.
That means that the answer's going to be more negative.
As I like to say if you go two hundred and forty dollars and then you spend 120 more now you're going
to owe much more.
Right.
So the answer is going to be negative negative to 40 minus 120 is negative.
all right that is going to be our final answer here.
All right.
So again for example we had to group two functions together by multiplying them.
This one time this one.
And after we read wrote the original function then we went ahead and got the derivative using our Parow
mnemonic.
That's pretty much it for the product rule product rule problems again.
They can be long.
Same thing for the quotient.
But hopefully this practice was good for you and remember practice practice practice and do your homework.