See.
All right so here's a fun one for you.
The second derivative is the derivative of the derivative interesting right.
You remember that Christopher Nolan movie Inception with Leo DiCaprio and Tom Hardy and those guys.
And in that movie you had a dream within a dream and that's when it started to get complicated.
Well here we have something very similar.
So it's a derivative of a derivative.
Let me give you an example.
So let's say your function is f of x
I would say that it is x to the fourth.
All right.
So we're going to find the derivative of f of x.
It's going to be as prime of x.
So again it's a power function.
So we bring down a dictator for X and we substitute bailout's power for a leader that's going to give
us a three on top.
Now what if we wanted to get the derivative of this derivative.
So this is the first year of it if so this is with two primes instead of one.
The second derivative and the second derivative is just a derivative of the first derivative.
So we take the derivative of this constant multiple We have a four.
So we leave it outside times we bring down a dictator.
That's at three X and subtract one from the exponent that gives us a two.
So that's going to be four times three is 12 x squared.
This right here is your second derivative.
Now notice this second derivative is the second derivative in relation to the original function.
Right so f of x is the original the first derivative of f of x is f prime of X and the second derivative
of f of x of the original is double prime of x so again this second derivative is second in relation
to the original derivative.
It's kind of like if you have a grandparent
and that person has a child
which is a parent's
of another child
so check it out.
You have grandparents that person has a child but that child is a parent of another child.
All right.
So this child has this parents but this child also has this Grandparent the same relationship.
So again to find the second derivative all you need to do is find the first derivative and take the
derivative of the first derivative that's going to give you the second derivative.
And in case you're wondering yes you can get a third you can get a fourth you can get a fifth you can
get however many levels you want of derivatives.
Now the third derivatives not really use that much and anything after that.
Not at all.
But the second derivative does have some applications.
Now one thing I want to mention is remember that if you have a function f of x then the derivative at
prime of X measures the rate of change of f of x right.
So it follows that if you have a function f prime of x which is a derivative and you get the derivative
of the derivative.
So if you get the second derivative then this second derivative measures the rate of change of the first
derivative.
All right so it's like a chain.
This one measures the rate of change of this one.
But then this one the second measures the rate of change of the first.
So I'll put it right here.
Second derivative actually measures
rate of change
of the first derivative at prime of X
because that's what derivatives do.
They measure rates of change.
OK so now we know what the second derivative is.
Let's go ahead and find concavity for functions.