Hey there what's going on.
Welcome to another session of limitless calculus.
Today we're going to cover the counterpart to the product.
And it is called the quotient.
BILL
So it's called the quotient rule.
And I have a little bit of a weird sound to you.
The word quotient the word quotient just means the results of dividing two things.
So remember how product is a result of multiplication of two things quotient is the same but for division.
So I'll put that here on the side the quotient
is the results
of division.
And so just looking at the product rule we're trying to find the derivative of a product of functions.
Here we're trying to find the derivative of a division of functions.
So you're going to have something that looks like this half of X equals Giovanni X first function over
h of x.
So we have x is equal to the division of g of X by h of x.
And how do we know they're dividing.
Well it's actually there's no question about it.
OK.
It's the dividing line right here.
This is how you know that they are dividing.
So if there is a dividing line like this there's a division.
This means
there's a division.
That is how you know they need to use the quotient rule just to give you an example of a dividing function.
It of looks something like this 3 x squared is 5 x over 3 x OK.
So f of x is equal to 3 x squared plus 5 x 3 x plus 5 x is called the numerator right.
Remember fractions in a fraction you have a top part and a bottom part right.
A B and the top part is called the numerator
or the top and the bottom part is called the denominator
which is the bottom
OK.
So for simplification purposes I'm going to refer to the numerator as the top and the two that denominator
as the bottom.
All right.
So in this case our top is going to be 3 x squared plus 5 x that is our top function and our bottom
function is going to be 3 x.
So the question is how do we get the derivative of f of x which is composed of two functions that are
dividing for the quotient rule comes in.
OK so here we have the definition of the quotient rule.
If you read this you're going to be like What the heck is going on here.
Why is it so long.
Etc. etc..
Let me just tell you right now that the definition of the quotient rule is probably the longest in all
of this is calculus.
So bear with me you know we'll go over it step by step.
We'll go over some examples.
We have some practice problems in another video for you to take a look at and hey you're going to get
it.
OK.
So remember it's all about practice.
You know the first time I go through a problem you might not know what's going on in that case.
Just go ahead and rewind it and try taking a look again.
If it still doesn't make sense we'll keep going and then come back to it tomorrow for example.
Also go through the practice problems.
OK.
So everything is practice until it's easy.
So let's go over the quotient rule.
But right before let's go over the product rule because they are similar.
It's just the cushion or was something different.
And then it has an extra step but it's very similar to the product.
So when the product rule
we have two functions that are multiplying right.
I'll do it here on the side.
So we have the product rule for example if we want to do derivative of f of x and f x is a multiplication
of two functions.
So if we want to get the derivative
remember that what we need to do and I'm not going to use the mnemonic here because we're not doing
the mnemonics for the quotient rule.
I'm just going to go over the regular definition which is get the derivative of the first times the
second plus the first time the derivative of the second.
Right.
That is what we do.
For the product rule.
So now let's go over the definition of the quotient rule and see how similar they are.
So the derivative of a quotient and remember a quotient is just that division is equal to the derivative
of the top function.
That means the numerator times the bottom function minus the top function times the derivative of the
bottom function.
Everything over Bodum squared.
All right.
I know that was a mouthful.
Let's go over it step by step.
So we have fallbacks it is equal to the division of g of x and h of X..
When I get the derivative of f of x.
All right.
How do we do this.
Well again let's go over the rule derivative of a quotient is equal to the derivative of the top.
So this is the top function of x.
So we'll just say G prime of x.
All right.
So we have derivative of top times the bottom function bottom function is h of X
and then we have minus
the top which again the top is g of X
times the derivative of bottom the bottom is h of x
and so everything over bottom squared.
So we're going to get.
And we're going to divide this full result that we have here.
Over the bottom squared.
So the bottom is h of X right.
We're just going to square Age of X boom.
There you have it.
That is your quotient rule.
And I know it looks very messy looks really big.
You're wondering what the heck is happening here.
Well that's why I wanted to go over the prog rule first because I want you to see the difference and
the similarities between the two.
So in the product rule we have derivative of first times the second well in the quotient rule.
We have the derivative of top times the bottom.
So see how it's similar.
Instead of being first and second we have top and bottom.
So this would be like the first g of x and h of x would be the second.
So again pro-tobacco derivative of first time second here and the quotient derivative of top times the
second and then then the actual difference between these two rules one of the two differences is that
the product rule we use a plus and in the quotient rule we use a minus.
So after you get the derivative of the top times the bottom you have the same minus instead of plus
then the second part if we go back to the product rule we have the first time the derivative of the
second.
Here we have pretty much the same thing.
The top time the derivative of the bottom.
So this top part of the quotient is pretty much like the product rule.
The only difference is that instead of plus we use a minus We have derivative of top Times bottom minus
top Times derivative of bottom.
OK.
And then the only other difference and this is actually a very easy to remember is that you're going
to divide this whole thing.
So this whole numerator this whole top over the bottom function squared the bottom function is h of
X right.
So we're just going to divide everything by h of x to the second power.
So the main two differences
between
the sorry the product rule
versus the quotient rule
number one is we use a minus instead of a plus.
And the second one is you need to divide everything by the bottom squared.
If you look for a textbook they're going to go into this hole probably like proof of why this works
where this came from.
That is interesting to nerds like me.
But you do not have to know this typically for a business calculus.
All you need to know is what the rule is and how to apply it.
You do not need to know like where I came from.
All right.
So because this is so messy what we're going to do is we're going to go into our favorite mnemonic and
figure out a way of actually remembering this whole big beautiful mess.
All right.
So let's go into our mnemonic
right.
So here we have our mnemonic for the quotient rule.
This is very interesting.
It's one of my favorite mnemonics as well.
I feel that it is very easy to remember also very funny.
It says the quotient rule is like the product rule minus the B S and that's literally minus the abs.
We'll see why in a second.
So to remember this is just think about how the product rule on the quotient rule.
They kind of go together because they're opposites.
So you know like you have multiplication and division are opposites right.
And then for multiplication functions you have the product rule
and then for dividing functions you have the quotient rule
OK.
So again multiplication and division are opposites.
So product and quotient they kind of go together because they're opposites as well.
And we know that for the product rule we use the mnemonic pro just like we learned in the last session.
So for the product we'll use Pro for the quotient rule.
Again it's kind of like the product minus the B.S. And let's see what we mean by that.
For example let's say we have a function that's composed of two functions that are multiplying.
Right.
So we need to use the product rule.
And again I know we just went over this how the product rule in the quotient rule are similar in the
last section but let's just go over that again so that we can see a live example of that a Monnick working.
So the derivative of f of x for two functions that are multiplying is remember mnemonic prope.
So we have placed repeats.
So we're going to do g of x x and again repeated g of x h of X and we separate them by a plus sign.
All right.
That is the mnemonic for the product rule.
So what happens if we have a division.
So we have half a VAX equals G of X over each of x.
Ok so let's find the derivative of f of x so let's go to our mnemonic.
It says it's like the Perata rule minus the b s.
So we're still going to use Parow the mnemonic for the product rule and that says to place repeats.
Now the only difference here is that instead of having the first function and the second function we
have the top function and the bottom function.
But like we said before the top function would be one and the bottom function would be to.
So again place repeats.
We're going to have
g of X age of x g of x h of X.
Right.
So for the same thing as the product rule.
OK.
Now we did the first part of the protocol.
The place repeats.
Now let's do the outer remember the outer is just to the derivative of the outer functions.
So the derivative of this one and the derivative of this one.
All right first function and last function perfect.
So we did the product rule we did or non-monic pro players repeats and then our derivatives.
What's next.
Well what's next is the minors the B-S.
So remember the probe rule where you would do is you you would put a plus sign in between these two
repeats.
However in the quotient rule because we're doing minors the B-S this part over here we're actually going
to say Maia's OK.
And that is the minus here.
Instead of doing a plus like we do in the product rule we actually do a minus and we have the biggest
part remaining.
What's that.
Well remember that in the quotient rule you need to divide by the bottom function squared.
Bottom function squared is the B-S.
All right so first we say minus because the minus device repeats.
And then we do everything over the B.S. which is the bottom squared.
All right.
Let me put that here.
Baez is not the typical meaning is going to be bottom squared
perfect.
So we just put our bottoms squared here.
Remember the bottom function is h of x.
So we're going to have h of x to the second power.
There you go.
There you have your quotient rule which was very easy to do because number one it was based on the product
rule.
The first part and then number two we have this really easy to remember mnemonic which says minus the
B-S.
And again what is the minus that B-S mean.
It means number one that instead of putting a plus in between the repeats you're going to put this minus
and then you're going to say B S which is bottom squared.
So you are going to divide this whole top part by B-S which is the bottom function squared.
Remember the bottom function originally is h of X.
We're just going to do h of x to the second power.
That's what squared means.
All right.
Up next we're going to do a quick example of the mnemonic for the quotient rule.
We're actually going to see it in action.
We're going to play it.
And after that we'll do a couple of problems get you settled then you'll know this in no time.
All right.
So let's go to our problem.