OK so now that we have our mnemonic for the quotient rule let's try it out in a problem.
OK so f of x is going to be
3 x squared is 5 x over X minus 1.
All right so that is going to be your f x we want to find the derivative of prime X
and first thing we do is we identify OK which rule do we need to use.
The main operation here is a division we know it's the division because we have a dividing line over
here we have the function on top over the function on the bottom.
So for that remember we use our quotient rule.
So for the quotient rule we use the product rule minus the b s.
So remember our mnemonic which is
Hoopes.
All right let's try that again.
Pro mine is
the B-S.
All right.
OK so first let's through pro process that we're going to do place repeats.
And then the derivative of the outer So place repeats.
We're going to grab the top function 3 x squared plus 5 x times the bottom function X minus one.
And we're going to place it again.
So we have three x squared plus five x
times X Minus One
Remember we're just getting the top function and the bottom function and putting them side to side.
And we're doing that twice because it's plage repeats again.
It's the top function times.
The bottom function we put it once here and then once here again it's nothing new.
It's just the place repeats from the product rule right.
And then after that we go to the O which is a derivative of the outer.
Remember the outers are the first function and the last function.
So we get the derivative of this first function and we get the derivative of X minus one.
All right.
So we have our product rule our pro.
Now we're going to do the minus the B.S. part.
So remember the minus means is put a minus sign in between and you divide this whole thing.
All right and everything here.
Oh that's bad that line.
Let's try that again.
All right.
It's a little bit better.
So we divide the whole thing on top over B-S which is the bottom function squared.
What is the bottom function.
It is X minus 1.
So we'll do X Minus One squared.
All right so now we move on to simplify this beast.
How do we do this.
Well give it a shot prime of x.
First thing we do is we're going to get the actual derivatives of the outer which we actually already
marked.
So the derivative of this what do we have.
Well we have a sum and then we have some power rule with a constant multiple rule.
So let's take care of that.
Let's start with this term 3 x squared.
So a constant multiple tells you that you're going to have a 3 multiplying on front.
Then we do the power rule.
We bring down a dictator times 2 x substituted by a less powerful leader.
That gives us a one on top so we do not market that and move on to the next plus because we're doing
the sum rule because we're adding 5 x seconds to a multiple We have 5 on the front.
Then we have x 2 1 right.
Oh by the way this is prime.
Don't confuse it with a 1.
All right.
So we have this x x to 1.
So when we take one from the exponent it becomes X to 0 which is 1.
So basically is five times one.
OK.
Close here.
Then we have multiplied by X minus 1
minus.
We just copy over this function to be X squared plus 5 x
and the derivative of X minus 1 all the derivative of x.
Remember that x is equal to x to the first power.
Right.
Same thing.
So a derivative of X will bring down a dictator.
One
times x to the substitute by a less powerful leader.
So it's one minus 1 is 0 minus the derivative of a constant is zero.
So is mine is zero.
Remember we do everything over X minus 1 squared.
By the way you might be asking yourself whether you should expand this term here.
Maybe you can do something like foil and do X minus 1 times X minus 1 and then calculate that.
We typically don't we just leave it as it is.
So for the bottom part of the quotient rule don't worry about it.
OK.
If it's something like this you can just leave it like that.
Typically that's OK.
All right so let's finish up simplifying.
So we have three times 2 x is 6 x plus five
plus five times X Minus One minus.
By the way so one times x to the 0 just one time to one because anything to the zero power is one to
one times one is one.
Mine is zero still one.
So this whole thing becomes a one
right and we multiply one by this.
It's going to be equal to this by itself.
Mine is 3 x squared plus 5 x
and everything over
X minus 1 squared.
All right.
So you can see this is kind of a long problem.
Sometimes they get like this you might have like a whole page for a calculus problem.
You just need to make sure that you know you go detail by detail.
You make sure you carry over signs you multiplying.
Right.
They actually get in derivatives etc..
So the real long problems.
But don't fear if you do it slowly and you know what you're doing and you practice that.
It'll come to you right away.
All right.
So typically for a quotient rule problems we simplify the top here.
We're not going to do that for this problem.
I just wanted to demonstrate the concept of the mnemonic which is Preux.
Mine is the B-S that is in a Monnick for the quotient rule.
When we get to the practice problem section you'll have a lot of practice will actually do some huge
big problems.
We'll actually do some problems for the quotient rule up until the end.
So you can see how it actually works.
We'll apply that mnemonic that will simplify and we'll get a final answer.
All right.
So that's coming up next on the problem section.
Now we're going to go to the summary and be done with the quotient rule.
Okay perfect.
So let's go for a quick summary of what we just covered about the quotient rule.
So first of all the quotient rule is used to find the derivative of a division quotient of functions.
And again how do we know there's a division.
Well there's a dividing line.
So it's always going to be something like 5 x over g of X..
OK.
Also the kosher rule says that the derivative of a quotient is a derivative of top Times bottom minus
tab times a derivative of bottom.
Everything over bottom square.
Boring.
Who wants to remember that nobody that's for we have our next bullet point which is our mnemonic mnemonic
says like the product rule minus the b.s..
Remember just like in the product rule in the quotient rule you're going to place repeats and get the
derivative of the outer and then you have the minus the B.S. part that means the B.S. part means that
instead of doing a plus in between the repeats like you would do in the product rule.
You actually use a minus and then remember you have to divide everything in top by the bottom squared.
That is the B.S. part.
All right.
So product rule minus the B S.
And finally for quotient rule problems you can typically leave the bottom squared as is without expanding.
So if in the bottom you get something like you know like X squared plus two squared.
And here it doesn't matter what you have here in the bottom you don't really have to expand.
You don't really have to do foil.
Typically you can just leave it as it is.
I mean if you're in doubt always check with your professor if you see that he or she does it differently.
But again typically that's how it works.
And that's pretty much for the quotient rule.
Now the question rule is going to take some practice.
So you have to sit down and you have to do the problems there long you know they're going to take you
a while you might you to make sure you make it right the first couple of times you might not get it
right.
You might forget the minus sign you might forget to square the bottom etc..
That's why practice is so important.
OK.
So just make sure that you do the problems and the next section will actually have a couple of problems
for the quotient rule for you to try out.
And for you to do.
OK.
So I'll see you in the next tutorial.