All right so for the quotient rule we're going to do the same thing that we did for the product rule.
But instead of finding the functions that are multiplying.
We're going to find the functions that are dividing we're going to identify what those functions are.
Now this should be pretty easy because the top function is always on top and the bottom function is
always on the bottom.
But just to get you into the habit of saying OK we're dividing here's a first function and here's a
second we'll do a couple of examples and let's start with f of x equals 2 x cubed plus X everything
over X minus 2.
So go ahead and pause the video and let me know what the dividing functions are.
In other words what's dividing what.
All right.
So there should have been pretty easy.
So function on top again.
It's whatever's above this line so that's to execute plus X and then the function on the bottom is just
X minus 2.
All right.
So these are the two dividing functions.
That's pretty much it.
Let's go to the next one.
All right so here it is we want to find the dividing functions for this f of x and x equals on the top
X plus 1 times X minus 1.
And on the bottom just 3 Remember that a function could be just a number.
In this case it's only 3.
So go ahead and pause and give it a shot.
All right so let's identify the two functions that are dividing.
Then on the top it's again x plus 1 times X minus 1 because that's what's above the line.
So the first function X plus 1 X minus 1 and then the bottom function is going to be whatever's down
here which is just 3
again whatever's on top is the top function and whatever's on bottom is the bottom function.
Now let's stop identify let's start doing some quotient rule problems.