All right so let's get started with our quotient rule exercises.
Now remember a question is just a diversion.
So whenever you see a division of functions then you know you need to use the quotient rule.
And the best way to know if two functions are dividing is if they have this line in between them that
tells you right away if they are dividing and remind you once more.
We have a mnemonic for the quotient rule.
It is pro
minus the b.s..
Right.
So if you've never seen this please go back to the quotient rule videos and there you'll find where
this money come from and how to apply it.
So I'll leave that for you right there.
Our first function is f of x equals x squared minus 1 everything over X minus 2.
So we need to find the derivative of this function.
So we need to use our quotient rule.
All right.
So go ahead and pause it and give it a shot.
All right so let's see how it went.
Let's find the derivative of this function.
All right.
So just like our mnemonic says it's Parow just like the product rule minus the B-S.
So pro means place repeats.
And then get the derivative of the outer.
So let's go ahead and place repeats x squared minus 1.
And remember when we place repeats in the quotient rule what we do is we just put them multiplying the
top function times the bottom function.
So again it's just like the broader group.
So this is sort first function which is the top one.
And then we have the bottom function X minus two and then we place our second repeats.
So we just write it again.
X squared minus 1 and X minus 2.
All right.
So in the product rule what we do is we put a plus in between.
But remember this is the quotient rule.
It's a distant cousin.
So what we do here according to the mnemonic is instead of putting a plus we put a minus.
That's where the mine is here in the mnemonic comes from.
And then finally to finish up.
Remember that we do this the top over B-S.
So bottom squared the bottom squared is the bottom function X minus 2 to the second power.
So again product rule minus the B-S minus means there's a minus in between.
The place repeats and B-S just means the bottom squared.
All right.
So we just missed actually to put our outer derivatives.
So we're going to have a derivative of the outer on top.
So the derivative of this one here and derivative of this one here.
All right.
So remember place repeats.
That's what we did derivatives of the outer.
So the derivative of the first and the derivative of this one here.
Then we do a minus and between.
And the bottom squared is X minus two to the second power.
Let's go ahead and start doing this.
So let's get the derivative of this function.
We bring our dictator down so that's 2 x to the first power.
So that's just 2 x.
And then we have mynahs derivative of one derivative of a constant is zero.
All right.
So we don't market at all
that times X minus 2
then we do the minus and we have x squared minus 1
times the derivative of this.
So it's derivative of X number derivative of X is just one because you bring the dictator which is one
and then the exponent becomes 0 1 time to 1 is just 1 and then derivative of this two is zero.
So we have one minus zero which is just one
everything over the bottom squared.
All right let's go ahead and simplify the top.
Now that we got derivatives so we'll multiply again this 2 x times X and then times the two.
So this is distributed here and also distributed here.
So we have 2 x times x.
So that's two and then X and remember xponent Here's one point and here is one.
So we add them up and we get to all right.
Now we have 2 x times negative to positive times a negative is a negative and 2 x times 2 is for X and
then we have minus X squared minus one times 1.
So that gives you x squared minus 1.
Right now something very important here.
This mynahs distributes to both the x squared and to the negative 1.
This is a common source of confusion.
So this negative sign applies here and also applies here.
OK.
So what we're going to do is we're going to say negative times a positive is a negative.
So that's mine is x squared right.
Then we distribute it to the next one which is negative 1 and a negative times a negative is a positive.
So that's going to be negative times negative one is plus one.
All right everything over X minus 2 squared.
And finally we can go ahead and simplify let's look for the ones that have the same exponents.
That's going to be this one here too x squared and negative x squared.
So 2 x squared minus X squared we subtract the coefficients two minus one is just 1.
So we don't market.
And we keep the x squared.
So it's basically one X where.
But we don't mark the.
All right and then we have minus 4 x
and then we have plus 1 everything over X minus 2 squared.
And that is our answer.
All right so we just simply applied our mnemonic to get the derivative of this quotient.
And again we'll see this and more examples but I need you to know that you distribute this negative
sign to everything on the right.
So it's attributed to this x squared and is distributed to this negative 1.
So this negative sign changes the sign basically of all this the positive becomes a negative and the
negative becomes a positive.
All right.
So here we have our second example we have of X equals 3 x cubed minus 3 over X and we want to find
the derivative of that.
All right.
So go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
So let's see how it works.
Let's go ahead and get the derivative of this function.
And again we know it's the quotient rule function because there is a line dividing the top on the bottom.
So you have two functions that are dividing and we need to use the quotient rule.
So let's in our Monnick for the quotient rule.
So product rule minus the B-S.
So the product rule says we're going to place our repeats.
So that's going to be 3x cubed minus 3 times X and same thing 3 x cubed minus three times x.
All right.
And then the minus B-S part.
So we have instead of a plus like we would do in the product rule we put a minus and the B-S just means
bottom squared.
So everything over the bottom squared and again don't forget we need to get the derivative of the outer.
That is the 0 in the pro and a Monnick for product rule.
So here we do derivative here and derivative here.
All right let's see what this gives us.
So we have derivative of this function over here.
So we have a constant multiple of three.
We bring down a dictator which is also a 3 X substitute by a less powerful leader.
That gives us a two and then mine is a constant derivative of a constant Al-Jazeera.
So we don't put it that times X minus then and we have this one here.
So three x cubed minus three times a derivative of x and y is a derivative of X..
Well again remember that x is x to 1.
So we bring our dictator down.
So we're bring down our 1 X. And it's going to be one minus one.
Right.
So actually zero.
I know I repeat this one a lot but again the derivative of X or 2 x or 5 x is typically a source of
confusion because the one is not written.
Just remember that when you have X you have an exponent of 1 and this is going to be over x squared.
So let's go ahead and simplify.
We have three times three.
Those are the coefficients.
That's 9.
And we have x squared times x.
So we add the exponents to 1 to 1.
That's going to give us X to the third power that we have minus.
So this part over here will become a one right because X to the one when is 1 is X to 0 anything zero
equals 1.
So we have 1 times 1.
It's just 1 so therefore when you multiply this which is 1 times this you're just going to get this
right.
And you think times 1 equals the anything again.
So this is what we have on this side.
Mine is 3 x cubed minus three over x squared.
Now remember what I said this negative sign distributes over here and over here as well.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we have 9 x cubed
minus and then remember negative times a positive is a negative.
So that's going to give you negative 3 x cubed and then a negative times a negative is a positive.
So it's going to give you that positive three plus three and we have x squared on the bottom and finally
we can simplify because we have two terms that have the same exponents 9 x cubed and 3 execute.
So I remember when they have the same exponents you know you're going to keep the exponents because
you're just adding or subtracting.
And what you do is you take the coefficients and you work with them.
So nine minus three is six.
That's it.
All you have left is a plus three and everything over x squared.
That is our answer.
You see how easy life is with mnemonics.
You just go OK product minus the B.S. and you just get it right away.
All right great.
Let's do our last example.