All right.
So I know it's been a long section but I wanted to give you the details on everything on how concavity
works and very important.
The second the money that we did which differentiates between first derivative and second derivatives.
So you know which one does what.
So let's get started.
So concavity describes the shape of a curve.
Concave up means it opens up a board.
So this is concave up.
Right.
It opens up like concave down opens downward.
So it's like the opposite of up.
It opens down.
All right.
So a graph can be concave up for some intervals and concave down for others.
We've seen examples of this.
So so now looks like this you know how House changing concavity.
So it's opening down here than up here.
Then down here etc etc..
Then we have a mnemonic to remember concavity.
So think of the word concave concave up or concave down.
So with then the word concave you have the word cave so then a Mark says where does this cave open forward.
Does it open towards the top or does it open towards the bottom.
So for example here and concave up it's close in the bottom but it's open towards the top so it's concave
up.
Same thing for a concave down.
All right then let's go to the second derivative.
So the second derivative of f of x is a derivative of the first derivative.
So we have a function of of x you get the derivative of f of x and then you find the derivative of that
derivative.
That's called the second derivative of the original f of x.
Right.
And it's typically denoted as double prime of x.
Of course this also means that it could be called Y double prime
remember that y equals f of x.
So if you can call it a double prime of X you could also call it y double prime.
Now there's a third notation that I don't know if you remember where we talked about the D-y dx.
That's a way of specifying derivatives.
So D-y dx is the first derivative a way of specifying the second derivative is
d to y.
The x squared and I know it looks very weird.
Very different.
This kind of looks like you're squaring something and it's red as to why over the x 2.
I just wanted to mention it in case you ever see this.
This is just telling you find the second derivative of y and notice that the two is in the middle for
the top part but then it's at the end and the bottom part.
For some reason that's the way it is.
All right.
So what is the relationship between the second derivative and concavity it's very similar to the relationship
between the first derivative and increasing and decreasing intervals.
So we have that if the second derivative is positive for an interval then the grab is concave up on
that interval.
All right in the same way if the second derivative is negative then the graph is concave down.
Remember how similar this is to increasing or decreasing functions.
And the first derivative.
Let me draw this out for you.
All right so here's a quick summary of pretty much first and second derivative increasing and decreasing
intervals and concavity.
So when the result is positive if you're dealing with the first derivative that means that the function
is increasing.
If the result is positive.
But we're dealing with the second derivative then that means it's concave up.
So notice how all the positive terms are lumped together.
So when it's positive it's increasing it's up.
Right.
So when I say positive terms I don't mean greater than zero.
I mean like good terms right.
All the good terms are here.
When something's positive then it means it's good.
It's upbeat.
It's nice.
Right.
If your profits are increasing then that's good right.
So positive.
Increasing up all of these are good quote unquote terms.
On the other hand we have negative.
Right.
So the result is negative and you're dealing with the first derivative then the graph of f of x is decreasing
on that interval.
The result is negative.
What you're dealing with the second derivative than that means that the graph is concave down and in
the same way as with the positive here we have lumped the negative terms right so negative decreasing
down right although these are not good.
And that's kind of a way to remember it.
All the good terms go together and all the bad trim that goes together and also remember this test that
you do with the first derivative to check where the function is increasing and decreasing is the same
test that you do with a second derivative to check if it's concave up or concave down.
Remember how we have to find the numbers that make it either equal to zero or undefined.
We do that with both the first derivative and the second derivative.
And then remember how we find like the test values we try a test value to the left and to the right
of each number that we got.
If you're using the first derivative for that then you're finding intervals of increase and decrease.
But if you do it with a second derivative you're finding intervals of concavity where the function is
concave up and concave down.
But it's the same process for both.
I'll put it here.
So you remember
same process right.
Find the derivative whether it's a first or the second derivative.
Find the numbers that make it equal to zero or that make it undefined.
Test one value to the left and one to the right of each number and then classify based on this good
trims go to gather positive increase up and bad terms go to gather negative decrease and down.
And let's go to the next page where we'll actually see the mnemonic that we learned to remember what
the first derivative does and what the second derivative does.
All right.
Here we have the last part of our summary.
So remember a point of inflection or inflection point is the point where the concavity changes.
So a graph goes from concave up to concave down or from concave down to concave up.
And remember this occurs only where the second derivative is zero or where the second derivative is
undefined just like relative extrema only occurs where the first derivative is zero or undefined just
that in this case we're used in the second instead of the first and then to find intervals of concavity.
Remember this is exactly the same process that we use to find intervals of increase and decrease.
The only difference is that instead of using the first derivative like we do for increase and decrease
we used the second.
So to find intervals of concavity find the second derivative find the numbers that make the second derivative
equal to zero.
And by the way you might be wondering why I used to equal signs.
That is the programmer in me in programming to see if things are equal.
You need to use the two equals.
So maybe I'll use the equal sign sometimes but I might slip and just use these two but that's OK.
You know that it means that it's just equal to something else.
So equals equals means just equals.
All right however in your notes you might want to put it as just one equals two so you don't get confused.
Right.
But that's pretty much it.
So one more time to find the entrails of concavity.
So then we need to find out where the second derivative is zero or undefined.
And then we classify intervals.
So remember we put test values one to the left and one to the right.
And this test value process we do it one to the left and one to the right for each number that makes
a derivative equal to zero or undefined.
OK.
Each one.
And then if the second derivative is positive then that means that it's concave up and if it's negative
it means it's concave down.
And finally one of the main takeaways of this whole lesson of concavity is how to differentiate.
No pun intended between what the first derivative does and the second derivative does.
I don't want you to get confused and start thinking 0 is the first derivative use for a concavity or
is it the second.
Do I use the second derivative for relative extrema.
I don't want any of that.
I want you to know right there boom.
Exactly which one goes with which.
So for that again you just grab the first three letters of first and second.
So if I are of course this means the first derivative is used for i.
Stands for increase and decrease
and also for relative extrema.
And remember this increase and decrease intervals is tightly related to relative extrema because relative
extrema only occurs where their graph goes from increasing to decreasing and vice versa.
All right so that's the first derivative for the second derivative as E.S. again as is for second.
Is again like I said think of it as inflection point
and it rhymes with reflection
and refl. has an e.
It rhymes with inflection.
So the E is for inflection right.
And finally the C is for concavity.
So you use the second derivative to find concavity and inflection points or as I like to call them sometimes
inflection points.
That's not my accent.
That is the way we say it.
For this mnemonic.
All right.
So I know we covered a lot.
Best thing to do is to practice a lot of these problems with inflection points and concavity and see
when you use the first derivative and the second etc..
I promise you that it does get better as you do problems.
There's going to be a point hopefully where you just go ahead and know exactly what to do once you see
one of these problems.
The trick of course is to practice.
So I'll give you a couple of problems in the problem section so you can practice and I'll see you in
the next to Tauriel.