All right so here we have it.
We have that f of x equals 2 x squared over three x cubed plus four x.
So go ahead and pause the video and give that one a shot.
All right.
So let's see how you did.
And actually I'll call this one D-y over dx.
You know I need to switch up the notation every once in a while so that you get used to seeing this
D-y over dx.
Remember this means derivative right.
So derivative is going to be equal to what.
Well it's a quotient.
So we need to use the quotient rule and we use our mnemonic pro minus the B-S.
So the pro says to place our repeats.
So we'll do this once to x squared the top function times the bottom function 3 x cubed plus four X
and then we have two squared.
So just repeating again times 3 x cubed plus four X remember the next step is the oh so take the derivative
of the outer.
So the derivative of this one here and the derivative of this one here and then minus the B-S.
So we put a minus in the middle
and then divide by B as.
Which is bottom squared.
Three x cubed plus four x.
All right.
So let's keep it going.
Do you why we're Dayaks equals.
Well a stick the derivative of this one.
So it's constant multiple.
So that's two times bring our dictator down.
That's two x to the ones that we don't market that times 3 x cubed plus four X
minus.
Then we have
this 2 x squared and then the derivative of this one that's going to be constant multiple three times
dictator down.
So we bring it down is 3 x new exponent is going to be one less.
So that's two plus derivative of four X constant multiple four.
And as you know a derivative of X is just one right.
We bring down one then the exponent becomes one of minus 1 and that is x to the 0 times 1 which is just
one.
So this is four times one
and by the way I forgot to square the bottom here.
So this is bottom squared.
Here we go.
So bottom will be 3x cubed plus for X to the second power.
And finally we'll go ahead and let's simplify the derivatives that we got and that's it 2 times
2 x 4 x
4 x times this over here so that's 3 x cubed plus 4 X minus 2 x squared
and then three times three is nine x squared
plus four.
And then on the bottom again we have just this 3 x cubed plus 4 x to the second power.
All right.
So let's go ahead and finish this problem over here.
This is the last step that we had in the other slide.
So we'll just continue it.
So remember we already got our derivatives.
What we need to do is just multiply through and then simplify.
So for example this 4 x multiplies here and multiplies here as well.
And then this 2 x squared multiplies.
Each of these terms.
All right.
So let's go with the 4 x times this.
So for X times 3 x cubed we multiply the coefficients 4 times 3 is 12 and then x to the one times x
to that three is X to the fourth and then for X times 4 x is four times four is sixteen and x times
x is x to 1 times x to the 1 is X to the two because we add those exponents right.
Then we have minus
and then we multiply through the two x squared by these two.
So 2 x squared times 9 x squared two times nine is eighteen
and I'm putting of rather this is here because remember this negative is going to change the sign of
everything here right.
Not just of the two times nine but also of the two times for Inka.
So minus in general.
And then we do the multiplication inside of here.
So again two times nine is 18 and then x times x squared is X to the fourth.
All right.
And then we have two X squared times four.
So it's just two times four is eight.
And at this point it's positive still because we have positive times a positive right.
So two times four is eight and we just keep this x squared
everything over what we have which is three x cubed plus four x everything to the second power.
All right.
So let's go ahead and distribute this negative to each of these terms to this one and to this one.
The 12 I'm just writing this part 12 x 2 4 plus 16 x squared and then we do minus times a positive is
a negative.
Right.
So negative 18 x to the fourth
and we distributed again negative times a positive is a negative.
So minus 8 x squared everything over the same thing 3 x cubed plus 4 x to the second power.
All right.
And now all we have to do is simplify.
So we have 12 x to the fourth and we also have 18 x to the fourth.
All right so we're going to have xtal the fourth and we just work with the coefficients 12 minus 18
is negative 6.
Right.
So if you have 12 dollars then you spend 18.
Now you 0 6.
So that's it for X or the fourth.
And now we have the x squared.
So we have 16 x squared minus 8 x squared.
So that means we're going to have an x squared and we have 16 positive minus 8 is positive 8.
So that gives us negative 6 x to the fourth plus 8 x squared everything over
3 x cubed plus 4 x to the second power.
And this is our answer.
So maybe you are wondering do we always have to simplify this.
Well yes you do because most professors like to see it that way and in fact if you leave it like this
you might get incomplete points.
So it's definitely worth going the extra step and just simplifying like terms.
So the extra the fours like this one and this one and then the x squared is like this term and this
term right.
So this is our final answer negative 6 x to the fourth plus 8 x to the second power.
Everything over three x cubed plus four x to the second power.
That is it.
This was a long problem and that was on purpose.
I want you to get used to doing long problems for the quotient rule.
You'll see those a lot and once you get a problem in an exam I don't want you to choke.
I want you to know what to do.
I want you to know that these problems tend to be long and that you need to make sure they have your
signs and your exponents right.
So as you already know Practice makes perfect.
Go ahead and do your homework.
All right.
Practice practice practice.
I'll see you in the next tutorial.