All right so here it is.
Here is the most feared derivative rule there is the chain rule says the derivative of f of g of X is
f prime.
Evaluated a g of X times g prime of x.
Wait what exactly.
That's why people do not like the chain rule.
I mean look at this only by looking at it.
I'm confused already.
What's going on here.
So what's going on here is.
So we have g of X the inner function plugged in into f of x right.
This says you're going to find the derivative of f of x with g of X applied and then you're going to
multiply that by the derivative of g of x.
The inner function and I think this is better shown with an example.
So let's say that we have f of x equals x cubed and g of X equals
5 x plus 3.
All right.
And let's say that there is a third function of x and this function is equal to the composition of these
two.
So we're going to take g of X and we're going to plug it into f of x so h of X equals f of g of X
and that's it right.
So again this third function here H of X equals to plug in and go of X into f of x.
So let's go ahead and do that.
F of x says.
Are you going to take the input and cube it.
So you will have an input and you're going to Kubit and that input is g of X right.
This is the input also called the inner function.
All right.
So we're in g of X into f of x and g of X is 5 x plus 3
OK.
So we want to find the derivative of H of X.
In other words we want to find the derivative of this composition.
So what is a derivative of the composition.
Let's use the chain rule.
It says find the derivative of the outer function so the outer function is execute.
It's a function that's wrapping the other function.
So the typical derivative for this is we bring down a dictator.
So that's three
right.
And then we substitute balas powerful leader so that's two.
Now what goes inside is g of X..
So you see that we got the derivative of the outer but we don't put X here as usual.
We put g of x which is the input and g of X is 5 x plus 3.
All right.
And then we need to multiply that by the derivative of g of x.
So the derivative of the input.
Is a derivative of giove x.
So we have constant multiple odds of five and then derivative of X is just one.
So we don't market plus the derivative of a constant which is zero.
So at the end of the day the derivative of 5 x plus 3 is just 5.
So finally we simplify and we say three times 5 is 15.
And within the parentheses we have 5 x plus 3 squared.
All right.
And this is our derivative.
That is a derivative of the composition.
But I mean check it out.
It's kind of messy right.
You have all these f of G over and then you have f prime of G VAX times a derivative of g of x.
This is complicated.
Nobody wants to do this.
All right.
Once something easy one something that's far easier to remember for easier to apply.
So you know it's coming.
It's our mnemonic.