All right so we are ready for our mnemonic for the chain rule.
Now let me warn you this is going to be the most random mnemonic that we've done in the tutorials.
So for example for product rule we take the first three letters P R O and then for example for some
rule we know that some is ADD.
So we take those three letters a d d and stands for different derivatives and so on and so forth.
That's a typical mnemonic now for this one.
It has nothing to do with the chain rule but it is so memorable that you will remember it and I know
that because I've taught this before to dozens of students over the years and they always tell me that
is so random that I actually remember just because it is so random.
So let me show you my personal mnemonic for the chain rule.
All right.
Here it is our mnemonic for the chain rule is you dx.
In other words ugly daily X-Box.
Again it's ugly.
Daily X-Box.
I know what you're thinking.
LEWIS What the heck is this.
Are you crazy.
I want my money back right now.
Well before you tell me that I can assure you that this is so random that you will remember this.
If we do a couple of problems this thing tends to stick in your mind.
And again I know that because dozens of students over the years have told me the same thing so ugly
daily X-Box.
All right.
That's funny that's great.
But how does that relate to the chain rule.
So the initials for ugly daily X-Box are edX and UTX tells you what the steps are for solving a chain
rule problem.
So let's break it down.
All right.
So we have you the x.
So what does this stand for.
Let's do it step by step.
The first step is you.
So what does you stand for.
So this taps says we're going to set you equal to that enter function.
So remember how we talked about Enter functions.
You know when you have one function within another.
So the enterer function is the one that's being wrapped around the other function like we saw in the
examples.
So first step is literally saying you equals the inner function you're just going to set them equal
to each other.
Right.
And then for step two step two is typically where people get confused.
Actually not bad at all.
So let's go into it right now.
So the D stands for derivatives.
Remember that I said that in the chain rule you end up multiplying derivatives right.
So that's exactly what we're going to do here.
So this step is called derivatives because all you're doing is you're multiplying two different derivatives.
Now before we do this one let me remind you that when we say something like D-y over GX
remember that D-y over dx is another way of saying find the derivative of Y.
Right.
We mentioned this before
to you I overdye axis means derivative of why we're going to use something similar to D-y over ADX over
here.
So here's what we're going to do.
Do you guys always on top and D-Backs is always on the bottom.
They're going to stay that way but now they're going to be across from each other.
So we have D-y on top here.
And the cross from it like this is DX right.
And then in the end we just populate this part here and this part here with the you see you on the bottom
here and you on the top here so you see that the overreacts it's crossed and do you and you are crossed
as well.
OK.
And what the heck does that mean.
So what we're doing here is we're saying find the derivative of why in terms of you multiply that by
the derivative of you in terms of x and this might not be making any sense but I'll show you what it
means in a minute.
All right.
So this is how you remember it but the final form looks like this D-y over you do you over DX right.
I just put these lines here so that you remember that the D-y and DX which usually go together they
go across from each other D-y on top and the X on the bottom and then the use go across from each other
as well.
But this is the final form.
And what are these two derivatives doing.
They're multiplying.
Right.
Because there's nothing in between them.
So we have a derivative of y in terms of you times the derivative of you in terms of x.
I remember that you enter a function because we set it in step 1.
All right.
So I'll put this in parentheses.
Because this is a real deal.
But again the way to remember it is think about the D-y over DX which we covered are ready and put them
across from each other.
All right.
So I put it down here across
DUI over ADX across.
And then you fill the rest with two use one down here and one up here.
All right.
And finally we go to the third step.
Which is the X and this is pretty simple.
It just says Put
in terms
of X..
All right.
So again we have a three step process given by you the x you is set you equal to the enter the stands
for derivatives you are multiplying two derivatives this one times this one.
And finally you have X which says put it in terms of x.
Believe it or not this UTX is going to come in very handy when you're doing problems.
And in fact let's jump into a problem right now.
So you see how it works.
So let's say that I have a VAX equals
x squared minus five to the third power.
And I want to find the derivative of this.
So what is a prime of x
so by now you should be looking at these types of functions and thinking to yourself well what do we
have here.
We have one function x squared minus five with then another function that means that to find the derivative
of this of f of x I need to use the chain rule and then in the middle of the exam you're going to be
like whoa aguy daily X-Box I remembered.
Yes.
And then after that you're going to say OK.
Ugly has a U.
Daly has a D and x box has an X..
So you dx and we apply our process here.
So let's go through the UTX to solve this problem and all divided here to avoid any confusion.
All right so step 1 step 1 is for you and it says said the you equal to the inner function so you equals
inner function.
What is the inner function.
Remember the inner function is a function that's wrapped around the other function.
Right.
So in this case the inner function is x squared minus five x squared minus 5.
All right.
And see we're done with our first step.
So close to number two so we need to multiply the derivatives and always you need to write this down.
So remember we have D-y over ADX but cross.
So I have you over here.
And D-Backs down here right.
And why do we fill it up with next.
Which is do do you.
And do you.
All right.
So what is this going to be equal to first derivative says derivative of y in terms of you.
All right so what is y remember y equals f of x right.
So why is this whole thing X squared minus 5 to the third power.
However here's a deal where we say in terms of you we're saying that Y will be written using you only
Arite right now.
Why is written using X right.
X squared minus 5 to the third.
But we want to rewrite this y in terms of you.
So think of it like this.
And again once you get this you're going to think OK that was really easy.
If you is equal to the inner function and the inner function what you're doing with it is you're taking
it to the third power.
Isn't this the same as saying you to the third.
Think about it.
So we set X quarter minus five is the inner function which we set equal to you and what we do here is
we say enter to the third power.
But you enter.
So this is the same as saying you to the third.
Right.
That's what we mean when we say let's get y in terms of you instead of using X we substituted this inner
function by you because in step 1 we did say that you was equal to the inner function.
All right.
So remember it what we're doing is derivative of y in terms of view.
So this is a why in terms of you know we need to get the derivative of this
so derivative of you cute.
And then we're going to multiply that by the derivative of you in terms of X. you again as the ener
function.
And it is already in terms of x.
So there's nothing else that you need to do you just say derivative of you
like this.
All right so let me repeat once more.
Here are multiplying two derivatives.
The top tells you why you're differentiating and the bottom tells you in terms of what you're going
to put the top you to the third is why expressed using only you and you in terms of x is you expressed
only using x.
So we have you to the third find the derivative times squared minus five derivative of that.
All right so how do we find the derivative of this you.
Well guess what.
Where are you going to do is you're going to treat it as if you had an X here.
Right.
Same thing.
So is this where X to the third.
How would you get the derivative of that.
Of course it's a power function.
So we bring our dictator down and we substitute by a less powerful leader.
That is exactly what we're going to do.
But instead of X we're going to use you so dictator rule let's apply it here.
We bring down a dictator that's three we keep the you and we substitute by a last powerful leader.
Three you squared right.
That's it for that.
That is the first derivative.
We're going to multiply that times the derivative of this and derivative of this is a derivative of
the first minus the derivative of the second.
Right.
It's just a difference of functions.
So are you going to get the derivative of each one and subtract those derivatives.
The derivative of the first one.
You know this already is just 2x right.
Well bring our dictator down.
Substitute a less powerful leader that gives us a one which we don't mark.
And finally mine is derivative of a constant you know zero.
So we're not even going to market.
All right.
So we have this weird looking thing which is three use squared times 2x.
Once we have this and we found our derivatives we go to the last tab which is put in terms of x.
So we want to put this result in terms of x this 2 x already has x.
We need to do is wherever there is are you were going substituted by whatever we got.
And step 1 right.
So we said you was equal to x squared minus 5.
So instead of putting you here we're going to put x squared minus five.
So we have three times you squared.
So again instead of you were going to use X squared minus five
to the second power times 2 x Arite and last is we can simplify this 3 times to X is 6 x
times x squared minus 5 to the second power.
And guess what.
This is our derivative 6 x times x squared minus five to the second power is our answer.
All right.
So see it's not even a long problem.
It just takes getting used to.
All right.
And we're going to do a lot of problems in the problem section so that you truly understand how this
chain rule works.
Not only that so that you can put this interesting mnemonic to put it that way to use ugly daily X-Box.
So let me summarize quickly what we did here.
We had a function x squared minus five to the third.
We know we need to use a chain rule because we have one function within another function.
So remember a derivative ugly daily X-Box That's you the x to check get out.
DX actually tells you right away set in terms of you find a derivatives put in terms of X..
All right I put the descriptions here but I mean just by looking at it you kind of know what it is right
away.
So you is set you equal to the inner function.
That's what we did over here.
We know that the inner function is x squared minus five.
So we say you equals x squared minus five.
That's it.
First step one step two derivatives again remember we're multiplying two derivatives and the way to
remember this.
Like I said is to start with D-y where ADX but you do it cross right.
So D-y on top here and cross you have the X on the bottom and then you fill the rest with a D you and
another do you.
So at the end of the day you're crossing D-y with DX and the do you with the other do you.
Like I said this means refining the derivative of y in terms of you and the derivative of you in terms
of x.
So why is why why is this right.
The whole function that we're finding the derivative for.
But we're trying to set y in terms of you so we don't want to have any access like we do originally.
But since you is equal to the inner function and what we're doing here is where a cubing the inner function.
Then why in terms of you simply you to the third.
All right.
And of course don't forget.
Very important.
We're getting the derivative of you to the third.
So it's derivative of y in terms of you so you to the third which is a derivative of that and then times
derivative of you in terms of X..
Remember you is simply the enter function.
It already is.
In terms of x.
So we just write it in terms of x x squared minus 5 and we get the derivative of that.
Finally we get the derivatives and we multiply them together.
So the derivative of this like I said you'd treat it as an X right.
Just like if you had an X instead of a you save you had x to the third.
What would you do.
Oh you would apply the dictator rule.
So you bring down your dictator and you substitute a less powerful leader.
That's what we did.
That's how we got the three of you to the second power.
And then we multiply by the derivative of this which you should already know is just to X.
Let's finish the summary of what we did in the next video.