Hey they're welcome to another session of limit class calculus.
Today we're going to cover a very basic concept of basic calculus.
So you're very likely to see this topic in your class.
Does it matter if your class is six weeks.
Does it matter if your class is four weeks is four months.
Marginal analysis in general is taught in our basic calculus classes based on my experience as a tutor.
Now there's nothing to worry about.
Marginal analysis is actually very simple and you just need to remember one thing and we'll see that
in the mnemonic.
So let's start with the question what is marginal analysis right.
So here we have the definition.
So marginal analysis is using derivatives to estimate how profit revenue and costs change on production
level changes by 1.
Let me repeat that once again using derivatives to estimate how profit revenue and cost change on production
level changes by one.
So what the heck is this talking about.
So the first thing I want you to notice is the word estimate that means we're not getting exact answers
we're getting estimate approximations right.
Marginal analysis is all about approximation.
We'll see how that plays out just in a minute.
But let's keep going.
So something else interesting about this definition is that we talk about profit revenue and cost.
Whenever we do marginal analysis we're pretty much going to talk about these three quantities profit
revenue and cost.
And finally it's an estimation of how these three change when production level changes by one no production
level changes by one.
We've seen that before or you remember that in slopes we have a rise over run right.
So for every unit you move to the right than the slope is however many units you either move up if it's
a positive slope or down if it's a negative slope.
So in other words marginal analysis is estimating what the derivative will be at a given point.
Right.
Because when production level changes by one that's like moving one to the right.
So we want to know how it changes once we move on to the right.
And again all of this is just slope.
So when we're there I want to mention before we go is that profit revenue and cost.
Like I said are the quantities are you going to be dealing with in marginal analysis.
And you might have functions for these three so you might have a profit function
of x you might have a revenue function of x
and you might have a cost function SIEV-X.
All right.
So X is whatever value you plug in.
Which is the production level.
So for example if you're selling lemonades you might say okay X is a number of lemonades that I sell.
And once I plug this in into the profit function I'll know what my profit is.
And the same way we have revenue.
So when I make X amount of money then my revenue is whatever and finally costs.
Same thing.
So if I make X amount of lemonades then this function tells me what my cost is going to be.
Now I know your business to business.
But in case you forgot the difference between profit and revenue.
So profit is where you get to keep and revenue is everything that you make.
So in other words and this is important to know profit equals
revenue minus costs.
All right.
So for selling lemonade.
I knew one day you made a revenue of hundred and twenty.
But then the costs stuff like buying the lemons buying a pitcher buying the ice etc. the cost of all
that was $20.
So you don't get to keep the whole 120 while you get to key for your own pocket is 120 everything that
you made minus the cost that you went through to make the 120.
So that's going to give you a profit of a hundred dollars.
All right.
I know this is very basic but it's very important to know.
And just like we say profit equals revenue minus costs you can also say that in terms of functions.
So in other words the profit function
equals the revenue function
minus the cost function.
All right.
So this way you know that if you're asked to find profit and you're given the revenue function and the
cost function you can just subtract cost from revenue and that's going to give you the profit function
and we'll do an example of that so you can see how it works.
All right.
So again profit equals revenue minus cost.
And there's one more thing I want to mention.
So you have these three functions right now profit function the revenue function and the cost function.
So what happens when you get the derivative of each.
So if you get the derivative of profit that's going to give you the price of X right.
If you get the derivative of revenue it's going to give you our prime IVAX how the revenue is changing
and finally a derivative of cost see Prime effects.
So it turns out these three derivatives they have names and the names are just basically the word marginal.
And then whatever quantity you're dealing with.
So for example the prime of x is a derivative of profit.
So that's called marginal profit.
And the same way we have revenue.
So the derivative of revenue is marginal revenue.
And finally for cost the same thing that the derivative of cause is called marginal cost.
All right.
That's pretty much it.
That is a good introduction to marginal analysis and now we're going to see how is it that we actually
saw problems.
Just to summarize once more marginal analysis is used to estimate how profit revenue and cost change
from production level changes by 1.
So you have your three quantities profit revenue and change.
If you get the derivative of these three functions then you get the marginal profit margin revenue and
the marginal cost correspondingly to each one.
The last thing to cover is that again profit equals revenue minus cost.
So if you have one of these two quantities then that means you can get the third.
So obviously again if you don't have profit you have revenue on cost.
You can just subtract these two.
And that's going to give you profit but also for example if you want to find revenue and you have profit
and costs then you can just move cost to this site and that's going to give you revenue.
Right it's going to be profit plus cost equals revenue etcetera etcetera.
And by the way there's one more thing I want to cover and that is revenue itself.
So we have revenue our of X right
remember that revenue is basically all the money that you get for selling your product.
Now what happens if we don't have the revenue function and we don't have the profit function and we
do have the cost function but we still want to find revenue.
So remember that X is a level of production.
So the number that you plug into the revenue function is a number of units that you sold that's going
to give you your total revenue so what happens if you have the prize function which tells you what the
price is depending on the number of units.
And I'll put this up here.
PLX is a prize function.
Now you might be thinking wait a minute isn't P of X profit.
Well yes but Abra case.
All right.
So when we're talking about profit we're talking about an upper case P
What we're talking about price.
It's a lower case p.
All right.
So just remember that profit revenue and costs go together and all of these are apprecate.
So price is the black sheep is by itself and it's a lower case.
That's why it's different.
So make sure you don't get confused between profit uppercase and price lower case.
All right.
So let's say that we have a piece of X. let's say that we have lower case p of X..
So we have price and we want to find the revenue.
Well let me put it to you this way.
If the price of each lemonade you sell is $2 and you sell 10 of them what is your revenue.
Well it is $2 per eliminate times 10 lemonades.
Right.
Going to give you 20.
In other words we're multiplying the number of units that we sell times the price of each unit.
And that's just simple math right.
There's nothing weird about that.
You know Wal-Mart sells a thousand shirts in one day and each shirt costs $5.
Then the revenue for shirts is going to be five thousand.
A thousand shirts times $5 each.
So it turns out we can still get the revenue that way.
So we have P of x which gives you the price of each unit times X which is actually the number of units
and to make it look better we can just say x x
All right.
So this is X times P of X and again that's going to give you more revenue because X is the number of
units that you're selling and P of X gives you the prize for X number of units.
So again this is another way of getting the revenue in case you do not have profit or cost.
And again each problem is different and some problems are going to be given the profit on the cost.
But sometimes you want.
In that case if you need to find the revenue you will very likely be given this price function and all
you need to do is multiply X by that function and that's going to give your revenue.