All right so how do we solve marginal analysis problems.
It's actually very easy.
There's only two things that you need to do.
So remember we're doing marginal analysis right.
So number one we need to find the marginal function of the quantity so that quantity can be either profit
it can be revenue or it can be cost.
Those are the three that we mentioned and the other section.
So you're going to find the marginal function that means they are going to find the derivative.
All right.
So if you're talking about cost then you're going to find the derivative of cost that's going to give
you a marginal cost.
All right so that's step 1 and step 2 is the secret sauce to marginal analysis.
This is where the magic happens.
So check this out.
It says you plug one less and the unit of production into the marginal function.
So you plug in one last
than the unit of production.
All right.
So marginal analysis is used to estimate quantities right.
So for example if we're asked let's estimate the revenue that producing a tenth unit would bring.
So we want to estimate the revenue that the 10th unit will bring.
So the unit is 10 and the quantity is revenue Right.
So is this the first step would be to find the marginal function of this quantity revenue.
So we would find the derivative of revenue that's marginal revenue
and then we would go ahead and plug in one less than the unit or production.
So if we're trying to estimate what the revenue you're producing the TENS unit will be guess what you
do not plug in 10.
You plug in nine.
You always plug in one less.
So this would be given this estimation by our prime of 9.
Right because we need to plug in one less than the unit that we're looking for into the marginal function.
And this is fundamental.
So for example if you see tens unit you know let me get revenue and the derivative and I'm going to
plug in 10.
No that is wrong and I was going to give you the wrong answer.
That is why I said this.
Step two is the secret sauce to marginal analysis.
You need to remember to plug in one less not the unit itself and to help you remember that of course
we're going to do a very simple mnemonic.
All right.
So here we have our mnemonic for marginal analysis.
This is probably the simplest mnemonic I've ever made.
And you got to give him some credit.
It doesn't rhyme 100 percent but it does.
Right.
And it says when doing marginal It's minus one marginal minus one marginal minus one.
All right.
I just want you to drill that into your head.
Marginal is minus one.
That means that if we're estimating the seventh unit
we plug in six.
That also means that over estimating how the revenue will change when the production level goes to 33
units.
Then why do we plug in.
Remember marginal mine is one we plug in 32.
What's that you want to find out how cost changes when production level goes to four.
So you want to find for the fourth unit marginal mine is one used to plug in one less.
All right.
So again not a lot more to talk about here.
Marginal minus 1 marginal minus 1.
Repeat that to yourself barge in all minus 1 marginal minus 1.
That's how you'll know that when you're doing marginal analysis you need to plug in the unit that you're
estimating minus 1 into the marginal function into the derivative of whatever quantity it is that you're
working for profit revenue or cost.
Now in marginal analysis sometimes you might be asked to find the actual amounts not the estimate the
actual amount.
And in that case something else that you need to do for that.
But it's very common sense and we'll do that in no problem.
All right.
So again for marginal analysis.
So when you're doing an estimate or approximation
or the problem says hey estimate the revenue when the production level goes to 9 or we might say approximate
how the profit is changing when the production unit goes to 125.
So this is for estimates and approximations
So remember again you're either estimating or you're finding the actual amount and that will cover the
problem finding the actual amount.
So for estimating approximating something what is the keyboard marginal.
Mine is one.