All right.
So let's go ahead and do some exercises on the chain rule.
So for this first section what we'll do is we'll say whether finding prime of X requires the chain rule
when f of x equals a certain function.
So we pretty much want to know if you have this function like this then are we going to need to use
a chain rule to find its derivative.
So the answer is either yes or no.
For this specific one say whether finding f prime of X requires the chain rule if X equals x squared
plus five to the third power.
I'll let you go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So remember that the chain rule is used whenever you have one function with another function.
So you have a composition of functions.
In this case it's very clear that you have this function here X squared plus five with then this other
function that takes it to the third power.
So we have here an inner function.
Remember that to the terminal whether you need to use a chain rule or not.
First you're going to look at the function as a whole and you're going to think Is there an inner function
here.
In this case there is it's X squared plus five.
So in this case this one does require using the chain rule.
All right let's go to another example.
All right so this is an example number to say whether finding f prime of X requires the chain rule if
f of x equals x to the seventh minus 3 x plus 9.
Go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so does it require the chain rule.
If you look at this all we have is X to the seventh minus 3 x plus 9.
So this is one function.
However this is not Rabs and any other function right.
We do not have you know like this.
To the second power we don't have like the square root of this or anything like that.
So is there really an inner function here.
Not really.
This is just a regular function.
And in fact to find this derivative you know how to do this all you do is take the derivative of the
first one minus the derivative of the second plus the derivative of the third and that's it.
There's no need for the chain rule here.
So the answer is no no.
Jane
All right so here we have the next say whether finding f prime of X requires the chain rule f f x equals
3 x squared times 5 x minus 3.
Go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
So what do you think.
Do we need to use a chain rule here or we don't.
So if you saw these parentheses and you said that kind of looks like a plug in this summer or else than
actually that's not the case.
If you think about it all we're doing here is we'll multiplying two different functions.
We're multiplying three x squared times 5 x minus 3.
So when we multiply remember we use the product rule.
There's really no inner function here.
And if that's not very clear Think of it like this let's say we had parentheses here and here.
All of a sudden it's a lot more clear that we're multiplying two functions.
This one here times this one here there is no inner function.
The only thing being squared is this x.
So no change needed for that.
Just regular power.
So for the reason that we're just multiplying two functions this does not need the chain rule.
All right so here's another example.
Say whether finding f prime of X requires the chain rule.
If f of x equals the square root of 2 x go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right so do we need the chain rule.
Is there an inner function that basically is the question.
So the answer is that whenever you're wrapping up a function that's not X under another function then
you need to use the chain rule here.
We do not have just x we actually have 2 x therefore we do have an inner function.
This inner function u is 2 x right.
So in this case we do need to use the chain rule
so if I had told you for example find a derivative of a square root of x then here you do not need to
use the chain rule because it's just X.
However here because we have a square root of 2 x so it's not x by itself.
Then you do need to use the chain rule.
All right so this would take out and we stay with this square root of 2 x has an inner function of 2
x we do apply the chain rule.
So here's a kind of a tricky one.
Let's say whether finding a from of IVAX requires the chain rule if f of x equals 5 over execute minus
1.
Everything squared.
So go ahead and pause the video and give it a shot.
All right.
So I said this one was kind of a tricky one because if you look at it what are we doing.
We have a division right.
So we have this top function over this bottom function.
So we definitely need to use the quotient rule.
If you said to yourself OK this is just a quotient no chain rule then let's look at it together because
eventually for this one we will need to use the chain rule.
So remember that to find the derivative of a division we use the quotient rule and that quotient rule
says that we place our repeats.
So it's five
x three minus one squared.
And then we just place the other repeat.
So that's five times X to 3 minus 1 squared.
And then remember that we take the outer derivatives so derivative of this and derivative of this
and then we do minus the B-S the bottom squared.
So it's X to the third minus 1 squared and we're squaring that again right.
So this would be a derivative.
So at this point we've only done the quotient rule right.
We just applied that.
However what happens if you look at this especially this part
it turns out that this is X to the third minus one to the second power.
And we want to get the derivative of that whole thing right.
So for this part you will need to use the chain rule because you have this inner function x cubed minus
one and you're elevating that to the second power and you want to find the derivative of the whole thing.
So what I want you to understand is sometimes in the course of applying other differentiation rules
like the product rule or the some rule or anything like that you might have to use the chain rule with
then using those other derivative rules.
And I know this is kind of confusing.
So we'll do a couple of examples now of using the chain rule and combining it with other things.
The point is that the answer to this is originally No we do not need to use a chain rule but eventually
we do because we run into something like this.
So yes this one requires the chain rule at some point.
All right.
So let's stop it with a theory.
Let's go do some actual exercises.