All right.
So here we have a summary of marginal analysis.
So Marjoe analysis is using derivatives to estimate how profit revenue and costs are changing one production
level changes by one.
So remember at the end of the day what we're doing is we're estimating.
So if you're asked to estimate how these quantities are changing then you use marginal analysis.
And next is just a quick relationship between profit revenue and cost.
Remember that profit is equal to the revenue minus the cost.
So profit is what you get to keep revenues what you make in total and the causes why you have to pay
as part of you know expenses.
But you're a business student so you already know it's a marginal function is a derivative of the original
function.
So the marginal profit derivative of profit margin or revenue is derivative of revenue and marginal
cost is just the derivative of the cost function.
All right.
So whenever you hear the word marginal You know you need to get a derivative then to solve marginal
analysis problems.
You need to do two things.
Number one is to find the marginal function.
So whatever function you're working with profit function revenue function or a cost function you find
the derivative of it which is a marginal function.
And after that you plug in one or less.
And again this is a critical one no less than the unit of production that you're looking for into the
marginal function.
So once you get the margin into a function if you're looking for example for the level of production
when the number of units equals five they need to plug in for it to estimate it.
And we actually have a mnemonic for this.
And again it kind of rhymes.
So give me some credit.
Marginal equals minus 1 marginal minus 1 marginal minus 1.
This is for you to remember that you did not plug in the actual unit that you're looking for.
You plug in one less.
So if I tell you estimate the cost as you go from Unit 22 to unit 23 you're estimating unity 23.
Right.
So you're going to have to plug in units 22 into the marginal function which by the way don't let that
catch you off guard.
In the example we did we just say find for example the revenue for Unit 101.
But sometimes it's written as like the example I just gave as you go from the 20 second unit to the
23rd so at the end of the day you're really estimating at 23 that means you need to plug in 22 into
the marginal function.
All right.
And sometimes you're going to get asked a different type of question.
Maybe in the same problem maybe in a different one but if you want to find the actual quantity arrive
you're not estimating anymore you're not approximating if you want to find the actual quantity of profit
revenue you're a cost for unit n whatever that unit may be.
Then you need to go ahead and plug that number and into the original function and then subtract and
minus one plugged into the original function as well.
And remember this is just common sense.
So whenever you get these problems in Business Calculus I don't want you to think Oh my goodness I don't
remember.
I don't know which ones which.
Think what you're doing for finding the actual quantity you plug into the original function.
You're not estimating anymore.
Like I said for example you know what let's use his example over here.
Let's say that we want to find the profit as we go from 22 units to 23.
We want to find the actual profit.
So what we do is we find the profit of producing 23 units.
So we find profit of 23 and we subtract the profit of producing 22
right.
What's left is going to be the profit of the 23rd unit by itself.
All right.
Just think about what you're doing.
Don't just blindly try to plug in numbers into derivatives and original functions and don't start crying
in the middle of the exam because you did not know what you're doing.
You do know what you're doing.
You're just nervous.
Think about what it is that you're trying to find.
All right you got this.
Next is remember it's just a quick distinction that P IVAX with an upper case P is profit and P of X
lowercase P is price.
Just remember that profit revenue cost costs go together and these are all capital P R and C so don't
confuse P of x and x.
In any case in our problem they're not going to trick you and you know just make you guess which ones
which they're going to tell you.
This is the price function or maybe they'll call the price function something else but I just want you
to be on the lookout that if you see a B you need to make sure that if it's a briquets it's profit and
if it's lower case it's price unless a problem tells you otherwise.
And finally here we have an alternative formula for revenue.
So you know if you want to find revenue and you have profit and cost you can solve for our IVAX and
then get it.
But if you're not given profit nor cost and you want to find revenue and you're actually given the price
function then you can just multiply the number of units X times that price function and that is going
to give you the revenue function.
All right.
So that is it for marginal analysis.
This is probably the most business ish lesson we've done so far is just an application of business calculus.
So hopefully that's not too bad.
And again we'll do a couple of problems for you to get used to this and I'll see you in the next tutorial.