All right so this is our next problem.
So it says find Ephriam of X if X equals x cubed square root of 2 x.
So this one might be a little bit tricky.
But again just relax and think about what's going on here.
What's happening.
Go ahead and pause the video.
Try to give it a shot and we'll do it together.
All right.
So how did it go.
Let's do it together now.
So what I said before is try to figure out what's going on in this function.
Maybe you noticed already that we have two functions that are multiplying.
We have x cubed multiplying squared of two x.
And how do we know they're multiplying.
There's nothing in between them right.
So that's a way you know that they're multiplying.
There's not a plus sign or a minus sign.
It's just this.
So first let's go ahead and start with the product rule because that's how you find the derivative of
functions that are multiplying.
So then a Monnick for our product rule is remember pro.
So place repeats and derivatives of the outer.
So let's go ahead and place repeats.
So we have x cubed square root of 2 x and let's place our second repeat x squared and square root of
2 x and after we placed our repeats we have the O which stands for outer derivatives so derivative of
this one and derivative of this one.
All right
so let's keep going let's find the derivative of x cubed again this is pretty easy as the power rule.
So we bring down a dictator X less powerful leader is a two times this square root of 2 x on.
By the way I forgot the plus sign here.
Remember that when you're doing the product rule you do a plus.
And the way to remember that is product starts with P and plus starts with P right.
So product plus great.
So we have this first part plus x cubed times the derivative of the square root of 2 x.
Square root of 2 x.
Here we actually need to use the chain rule because we have this inner function to X being wrapped by
this square root function.
So let's do this on the side and we'll put it like this.
Chain Rule.
For square root of 2 x.
All right.
So let's give that a shot here on the side.
So let's go ahead and find the derivative of this square root of 2 x.
Remember we have our mnemonic ugly daily x box so that you x.
So for step one we have you equals to the inner function right.
So you equals two X then for step 2 D we have the derivatives right.
And I'll put it here you d x.
That's what we're doing.
So step 2 is derivatives.
So remember we have cross D-y over ADX and then we have you on top and do you on the bottom here.
And so what we need to do is we need to said why in terms of you and find the derivative.
So this is why in this case.
Right.
So why in terms of you would be the square root of you right.
Because remember the whole thing is square root of 2 x 2 x we said it was equal to you.
So this is corrido to x is the same as saying the square root of you are right.
So we're going to get the derivative of this times derivative of you in terms of x so you equals 2 x
so derivative of 2 x.
All right.
Now how do we get the derivative of square root of you.
Remember that when you have a square root and you want to get derivatives you need to change it into
fractional exponents.
Right.
So let me do it down here.
If you have a square root of view that is equal to you to the one half.
Right.
Because this is you to the one and we're getting the square root.
So remember we do you two the one over two.
That's the way the rule works.
And we've covered this many times in the past.
So we're really finding the derivative of you to the one half.
So how do we get the derivative of you to the one half so again what we do is we treat you as an X.
And we just go ahead and proceed to do the derivative.
So if you had access to the one half How would you get the derivative.
Again very easy powerful because you have a power function.
So you bring down your dictator there's one half you two and substitute by a less powerful leader.
So that's one half minus one.
Why does one have minus one.
Let's do it together and I'll put it over here.
One half minus one and I'm sorry.
I know.
All over the place in this exercise.
But there are several parts to it.
That's why I'm doing it this way.
So one half minus one.
How do we do this.
Remember that to subtract two fractions they need to have the same denominator the same bottom right.
So the bottom for this one for this one is just one right.
Because one over 1 is 1.
So if you have a number by itself you can always say that that is equal to that number over 1.
So 3 is the same as 3 over 1 here.
One is the same as 1 over 1.
So now they both have bottoms but they are not equal.
So to get from one to two what do we need to do.
We need to multiply both the top and the bottom by two.
Right so now we have 1 have
minus one times two is two and one times two is two and let me separate this.
All right.
So what is won over to minus two over two.
Remember that the bottom stays the same.
So we get a bottom of two and we just work with the top one minus two is minus 1.
So the point is one half minus one is equal to negative 1 1/2.
So this is the same as saying one over to you to the negative one half.
Now remember something else when we have a negative exponent like this what we do is we can actually
bring it down and flip the sign of the exponents.
So this is equal to 1 on the top because there's nothing else 2 on the bottom which was already there.
And then we bring down this you to the negative one half.
But we bring it down by flipping the sign of this exponent instead of it being negative 1 1/2.
Now it's only one half.
All right.
So that is finally the derivative of you.
So the reason why we did all this is because we wanted to get the derivative of the square root of you
which we already have and it's this so derivative of a square root of you is won over to you to the
one half times the derivative of 2x.
So we have a constant multiple to and the derivative of X remember is always one.
So we have one over to you to the one half times.
Let's go ahead and bring that over here.
So one time is to us just to over to you to the one half but what do we have we have to over two.
Right.
So this becomes one over you to the one half.
And I just realized I had a lot of space here and I didn't use it.
So now we have to do like arrows pointing everywhere and so a little bit crazy but it should be a little
bit more organized in your notes hopefully.
All right.
So this is the end of our second step.
We multiplied our derivatives and we got this.
So for the third and final step which I'll put over here remember is the X step it means to put this
you back in terms of x.
So this will be equal to 1 over you to the 1 1/2.
Well now that's going to be 2x because we're substituting you by 2x to the 1 1/2 and of course we never
leave fractional exponents.
So that will be one over square root of 2 x.
All right.
So this right here 1 over square root of 2 x is a derivative of this.
Remember we're not done yet.
We need to go back and plug this derivative into this.
So see this happens sometimes you'll have a problem maybe it's a product maybe it's a quotient maybe
to some but at some point you will need to start doing the chain rule.
One of those terms and you will do like all of this just to go back to the original problem and plug
it in.
So let me separate this to avoid any confusion
all of this that we did over here is simply the derivative of a square root of 2 x.
So now we go back and we put the derivative that we found over here because remember we have x cubed
times the derivative of square root of 2 x which is 1 over square root of 2 x times 1 over root of 2
x.
And actually we'll just go ahead and leave it like that.
So let me write it again three x squared
square root of 2 x plus.
So here we have x cubed times 1.
So that's x cubed on top.
Over the square root of 2 x.
That is our derivative for the original function which was this one here.
So all of this got complicated because we had to use the chain rule on this term.
If this had been some other term like X to the two then it would have been a lot easier.
Right.
But again this happened sometimes times I wanted to show you an example of how sometimes you start doing
one rule and you have to sidetrack and do the chain rule and then come back to the original problem
with the answer from the chain rule to keep doing the problem.
All right.
So again we went ahead and did the mnemonic UTX on the square root of 2 x because it is a composition
of functions.
So we said you equal to the enter we find the derivatives and we multiply them and then we set back
in terms of x and see this problem even got a little more complicated because we had to get the derivative
of a square root.
So then you have to change it into one half.
Then we had to do a subtraction of fractions etc. etc..
So this problem Halik all the bits and pieces of a complicated problem and I cannot just give you the
easy problems because guess what.
When you sit down on a test and you get something like this you're going to freak out if we haven't
done anything even similar.
All right.
So I know that was a little bit long but that's the way it is with the chain rule.
Just remember to keep on practicing.