In this demo,
we're going to see how we can use some of the new features in JUnit 5,
AssertJ, and some other practices to write test cases that are more readable.
There are 2 steps we must take to use JUnit 5.
First, we need to update our IDE.
If you are using the Spring Tool suite, you will need to update to 3.
9.
1 and make sure you're also using the 4.
7.
1A or later version of eclipse.
Note that 3.
9.
1 of Spring Tool Suite also works with Eclipse 4.
6, which does not offer JUnit 5 support.
The second thing we need to do is to update the Maven POM
file to include the new JUnit 5 libraries.
As mentioned when introducing JUnit 5,
JUnit 5 has been broken into several different modules instead
of being shipped as a single monolithic JAR.
For this demo, we will include these libraries.
The first two libraries, jupiter-api and jupiter-engine,
allow us to use JUnit 5's new programming model.
The second two modules, platform-engine and platform-launcher,
support Maven plugins.
And finally, vintage-engine offers backward compatibility for existing tests.
In our test class,
marking a test remains superficially unchanged from JUnit 4; however,
note that the @Test instead points to org.
junit.
jupiter.
api test instead of org.
junit test.
This is only when you want to use JUnit 5.
In the JUnit Vintage library, there is still the org.
junit test class.
In our test we will simply be verifying that a room can
be returned from the room service.
While this first test is fairly simple, it does have some heft to it,
with about 15 lines of code being executed.
By adding Given, When, Then comments to the test case,
it can make it easier for other developers to understand
what is going on in this test case.
This can definitely be very helpful in more complex tests.
In the Then section, we will use AssertJ to write out our assertions.
Using AssertJ is much easier to read what exactly is going on in a test.
One thing that can be annoying when having multiple assertions within a test is
having to cycle back and forth each time an assertion fails.
So even though two assertions fail, for and weekday price,
it would be much nicer if we got informed of all assertion
failures in a test instead of just one at a time.
Luckily with JUnit 5, that is much easier.
With the new assertAll assertion and lambdas,
we can wrap all these assertions in a single call.
Now when we rerun our test,
we are shown both assertion failures instead of just the first one.
While generally the default assertion errors provide enough information,
sometimes it can be useful to provide a customized error message.
Maybe the reason a test would fail would be because of a
context issue or something that would require a bit more
understanding of the system.
AssertJ makes this a bit more straightforward than with normal JUnit assertions,
which takes an extra string parameter.
AssertJ uses withFailMessage.
The failure message isn't super helpful here,
but the idea of providing a custom error message is clear,
and it can be seen that shows up instead of the usual message.
Note the withFailMessage reference must be before
what you are asserting against.
Once the assertion failure is hit, AssertJ drops out of the method call stack.
So if we put withFailMessage after our assertion,
we'd just get the default message.
Back to JUnit 5,
typically using method names to give a descriptive name
to a test isn't too hard; however, JUnit 5 added the DisplayName annotation.
Within the DisplayName,
we can write out a string to claim however we want to test the name to display.
If we rerun that test, we can see that name is now displayed.
This string is fully unit-code compatible,
which means even emojis can be included.
While it might sound silly at first,
if you have internationalization requirements,
you can use the flag of the country you are translating to,
or perhaps an emergency light for really critical tests.
For example, something involving money.
Another area that can be quite frustrating to test,
but AssertJ makes much easier testing, is a list.
In this test, we are getting back a list of rooms,
and we want to make sure all the rooms in the list are correct.
We still start with assertThat, but then we use the extracting method.
With extracting, we declare the field, or fields,
we want to retrieve from the list.
Let's first get the room types.
AssertJ provides several different options for validating a list,
from very strict asserts, like containsExactly,
which verifies the actual list matches exactly what the
expected list both in number of elements,
values of elements, and the order they are in,
to less strict like contains,
which only makes sure the actual list has the expected items in it.
The order doesn't have to match,
and the actual list could contain additional items.
So this works well.
But what if we want to validate multiple values within each element in a list?
Again, AssertJ makes this easy with tuples.
Simply add the other field we want to extract,
and in the contains we can call the tuple static method and pass in the values.
So as you can see, AssertJ and JUnit 5 makes tests much easier to read and write.
We will be looking at a few other features of these two libraries in the other demos in this module as well.