There can be times when there are many different paths through a
section of code that need to be covered; however,
the setup for running through each of those paths is largely similar.
In this case, using parameterized tests can be very beneficial.
Without using parameterized tests, a test file could quickly become unwieldy,
copying and pasting test cases over and over again to
run essentially the same scenario.
If there are enough scenarios, the class can become difficult to read.
And if the code is refactored,
you might have to spend a lot of time updating all the tests.
Parameterized tests improve upon this process by
being able to use the same test case, but using different test data each time.
JUnit 5 has made some updates from JUnit 4 as to how parameterized tests work.
In this example, the method source is being used,
though there are several other options as well,
like ValueSource, EnumSource, CvsSource,
among many others.
In our demo,
we're going to use a parameterized test for checking code that handles the check-in and check-out date for a booking.