Returning again to the testing pyramid,
acceptance testing sits at the peak of the pyramid.
Acceptance tests are very high-level tests that will typically test your system
from end to end to ensure it meets business requirements,
and even possibly run many of the tests written in the below layers.
So how do we write automated acceptance tests?
Again, let's look at the status quo.
A common pain point when developing a new system or feature is the
communication between a developer and a business analyst.
A developer asks a business analyst a question on how the system should behave.
The business analyst responds,
but it can be difficult to know if the developer
asked a question in the correct way, or understood the response,
or properly coded the business requirements into the system.
The Gherkin syntax is an attempt at addressing this problem by
creating a common language that developers and business
analysts can share to develop a system.
This gives confidence to both the developer and business analyst that the
system being developed is meeting business requirements.
The cornerstone of the Gherkin syntax is the given, when, then.
Given these preconditions to a scenario,
when these actions occur during a scenario,
then the system should produce this result.
We covered given, when,
thens a bit in the previous sections on writing readable tests as a
way of clarifying what is happening within a test.
While these descriptions are accurate within individual tests,
when writing an acceptance test, these given,
when, thens are at a higher level, often covering one or more tests themselves.
A way of utilizing acceptance testing in a development cycle is
through the application of behavior-driven development,
or BDD.
If behavior-driven development sounds like test-driven development,
that's because it follows a very similar pattern,
just at a higher level.
In behavior-driven development, we start with a failing acceptance test.
We then move into a test-driven development phase and begin
writing tests and production code that fulfills the
requirements of the acceptance test.
Once we fulfill all the requirements of the acceptance test,
we start the process over again by writing another failing acceptance test.
This process continues until a feature or system is complete.
To get a more concrete idea of how this process works, let's look at an example.
On the left side, we have our acceptance test.
This acceptance test is going through a scenario of
an existing user booking a room.
Given this user is an existing customer,
Joe User, the user books room 123 for 5 nights.
Then the user should receive a message confirming that
they have booked room 123 for 5 nights.
In BDD,
we would take this acceptance test into the TDD phase and
start writing out tests for each step,
creating tests for looking up a customer by username,
looking up a room by room number, creating a booking,
and then looking up a booking by ID.
If BDD is followed rigorously when developing an application,
then the resulting application should not only be well tested,
but well documented.
Cucumber is a popular polyglot tool for reading in Gherkin syntax,
creating tests, also called glue code, and then running those tests.
And we will explore using Cucumber to write acceptance
tests in the demo following this section.
There are a few things to keep in mind with BDD.
Writing effective acceptance tests, like any type of tests,
is a skill; however,
it is a skill that both developers and business analysts must learn.
And like any skill, it takes training and practice to learn it.
And when writing acceptance tests,
it takes a lot of up-front understanding of a feature being written.
Having a poor understanding might mean a lot of wasted
time writing code and tests that do not actually represent
how the system should behave.
All this is to say, you're not going to get it right the first time; however,
as mentioned before, if BDD is closely followed,
the end result is a system that not only should
follow closely what business expects,
but also a system that has extensive living documentation. Let's take a look at BDD in action.