In the module on leveraging dependency injection,
I introduced a testing pyramid.
In this module,
we'll be moving up the pyramid to the component integration testing layer.
As I mentioned when introducing the testing pyramid,
component integration testing is a bit of a fungible term,
and it is why I have a dotted line between it and unit testing.
When talking to some colleagues while developing this course,
some still felt component integration testing could
still be considered unit testing.
If you're more comfortable with that term for this layer of testing,
that is fine; however,
as I'm defining component integration testing within this course,
component integration testing is tests that focus on how your
application interacts with the libraries it depends upon,
as well as testing of cross-cutting concerns,
like logging and security.
In many of these instances,
these tests also require in part or in total initializing your application.
This contrasts with how I view unit testing,
which are tests that are heavily isolated and exclusively test application code.
For more on how I define unit testing,
you can look back to the module on leveraging dependency injection.
So with defining what component integration testing is,
what are the goals of it?
At many places I have worked,
I have often had a feeling of being locked into the libraries the
applications depend upon at the time the project was written.
As a greenfield project,
writing code for the application felt new and exciting; however,
it wasn't long before the dependent libraries started becoming out of date.
Libraries couldn't be updated because it would introduce risk,
as well as requiring a full regression test of the application.
While Pivotal and other library developers often strive to ensure their
libraries are backwards compatible and free of bugs,
no process is perfect.
At the most innocent,
this meant not getting to use some of the cool new features introduced
in more recent iterations of the library; however,
of much more concern,
applications became more vulnerable as time went on because they were not
bringing in the latest patches that addressed security exploits.
A recent example of this, as of the producing of this video,
is the Equifax hack.
The problem wasn't that Equifax was using Struts,
but an out-of-date version of Struts.
So a goal of component integration testing is to help prevent library walk in.
Another goal of component integration testing is to test
cross-cutting concerns like logging and security.
An example we'll be using in this module of cross-cutting concerns is a logging
aspect that captures request information coming in to a RESTful endpoint and the
response that endpoint sends back to the client.
While this can obviously be handled within the controller itself,
it's much more efficient to handle such functionality with an aspect.
Instead of manually adding logging statements at the start and
end of every method that defines an endpoint,
for example a practice which can quickly pollute your code base,
as well as having inconsistent coverage,
an aspect can be written and configured to weave around your endpoints.
Not only does this greatly reduce code bloats,
but also typically allows for safer and/or more complex logging,
as logging statements no longer have to be copied and
pasted into every method endpoint.
However, while this aspect of aspects of great,
testing them can be a bit more difficult.
Luckily when it comes to testing aspects and other
areas of component integration testing,
Spring has provided a lot of tools to make testing easier,
and we will be taking a look at these tools in the demos in this module.
Within many of our test classes, we will be adding the JUnit RunWith annotation,
and using the SpringRunner class.
This will stand up the Spring container.
With Spring Boot 1.
4, the Boot team added a lot of testing tools.
One example is the DataJpaTest.
This stands up the data layer of a Spring Boot application,
as well as providing tools that make testing the data layer easier.
With the Spring container activated,
Spring can also hand our test class's dependencies as well.
So to review,
the goals of component integration testing are verify cross-cutting concerns,
for example logging or security,
keep our application secure by keeping up the latest security patches,
and keep developers happy by keeping up with the latest library features. So let's start looking at some component integration testing in action.