There are three major benefits to writing automated tests.
The first is to verify the correctness of the code.
When I say correctness I mean, does a code do what we expect it to do,
given a scenario?
If a null value is passed into the method,
find users by last name, should the method throw an illegal argument exception?
Should it return an empty list?
Should something else happen?
What constitutes correct behavior will vary depending
upon the needs of your business, but by writing the test,
we have an opportunity to verify the code is behaving correctly.
On the subject of behavior,
the second major benefit of writing automated tests are the
test service documentation of system behavior.
Tests are an opportunity to describe our system when it's in motion,
or in other words, how our system behaves.
So it is important when writing test cases we take time to make sure
we are giving the test cases meaningful names.
A bad test case name would be, test find users by last name failure,
as there could be several reasons why find users by last name could fail.
A much better name would be return empty list for a null last name,
as that not only describes the scenario,
but the expected result as well.
The final major benefit to writing automated tests is to detect regression,
and this is only possible if we are automating our test.
While the two previous goals can be fulfilled at the
instance when the code is being written,
only when tests are automated will we be able to
ensure that as code is modified, we are not breaking existing functionality.
So if automated testing provides so many benefits,
why isn't automated testing a more common practice?
So there are three major impediments for why tests are not written.
The first major impediment is, it takes too long to write tests.
Developers who are already struggling to deliver new features and bug fixes
to production don't feel they have time to write tests.
A couple of common reasons for this are finding test data that's difficult
or the code into test requires a lot of complex setup.
The second major impediment is tests are difficult to maintain.
While a test when first written passes, it's not long before it begins to fail.
Sometimes it's difficult to determine why the test failed,
or even if it's known it may be difficult to fix,
or finally,
the test needs to be heavily rewritten because it changes the downstream code.
The final major impediment is tests do not provide enough value.
This impediment is more the result of the first two.
Because it takes too long to write automated tests,
and because it takes a lot of time to maintain the tests,
both managers and developers often feel that automated
testing does not provide much value.
Much of the source of these impediments can be traced back
to poor design choices when writing code.
So let's explore some design principles and patterns
that will make writing tests easier, faster, and more reliable.