Spring Cloud Contract is one of the many tools developed by the Spring Pivotal
team that helps with the development and testing of software.
Spring Cloud Contract works on the concept of contract-first development.
Rather than starting to write an application by building
up just low-level implementations,
such as database calls and building business logic out first,
and eventually writing out the endpoints,
contract-first development inverses behavior by starting
with the contract and working from there.
This better allows for parallel development,
as well as hopefully pushing forward business decisions.
Let's take a look at how Spring Cloud Contract accomplishes this goal,
as well as some other problems it seeks to resolve.
Imagine we're making some changes to Service A over
in the top left of the screen.
Service A talks to Service B, and Service B talks to the database.
Service A also talks to Service C, and Service C talks to Service D,
which subsequently talks to Service E.
Running integration tests locally,
in which Service A talks to real instances of Service B
and C would be time consuming to set up,
as well as taxing on a developer's machine.
TestContainers, and containerization in general,
as great and lightweight as they are,
still wouldn't be an effective solution to this issue.
Spring Cloud Contract attempts to address this
problem by allowing you to call stubs.
Calling stubs instead of live services allows tests to run faster,
and removes all the difficult setup of recreating an environment.
But how does Spring Cloud Contract ensure that the stubs we are
calling are honest representations of the services our service
will be calling in production?
This is where contract-first development comes in.
Spring Cloud Contract, using the Groovy language,
has a domain-specific language, or DSL, for defining contracts.
In that contract, you will define a request,
the HTTP verb used, endpoint called,
and optionally a body or headers that will be sent as well.
You will also define the response that will be returned for that request.
One final note on this.
These contracts are being written by the consumer of a service.
While it might be odd to have consumers telling a producer what to do,
following a consumer-driven contract development cycle
ensures that you're following the, you aren't going to need it,
or YAGNI, principle.
Instead of producers guessing what a consumer of their service might want,
they are explicitly told,
the producer is explicitly told what needs to be written,
ensuring producers don't write a bunch of useless endpoints.
Moving on,
these contracts are then stored in the code base of the producer's service,
as that's the service that ultimately has to implement the code,
and thus the source of truth.
Then, using the contract written,
Spring Cloud Contract generates tests that verifies that the producing
service is fulfilling the obligations of the tests.
This code is the simplified example of what these
generated tests would look like.
While in a demo we'll be walking through shortly,
we'll be doing all the development locally,
in most real development workshop environments,
the developer of the producer code will check their changes into a
repository once they have finished implementing the contract.
Once checked in, if good CICD practices are being followed,
this will kick off a build.
During the build process,
Spring Cloud Contract will produce an artifact that simulates,
or stubs out, an implementation of the producer service.
These stubs will then be stored in an artifact repository,
Nexus, Artifactory, etc., which can then be pulled down to a developer machine.
The developer of a consuming service would then write a
test that looks something like this.
In the test class, the autoConfigureStubRunner would be added.
The ID section would then have the Maven coordinates,
group ID, colon,
artifact ID of the producer's service of the stubs artifact that was built.
The plus sign notes to always get the latest version of the stubs artifact.
Finally, a port number the stubs will run on can be optionally specified.
Within the test of course,
you will call the code that will then make calls to the
producer that verifies that contract.
Because you're getting the latest instance of the
stubs from your artifact repository,
and because every time the producer service is built
the stubs artifact is updated,
and because the stubs artifact is only updated because the producer
service has passed tests created off the contract,
you can be confident that these tests are faithful reproductions of
how this service would interact in production.
Using Spring Cloud Contract greatly assists in integration testing,
as you are no longer relying upon test data being present,
or a test service being available in order to execute an integration test.
This leads to tests that are easy to write and more
reliable so that when tests fail,
it's because either the consumer or producer is breaking the contract,
not test data going stale or our service becoming unavailable.
In the next section, I will give a demo on how Spring Cloud Contract works,
and we'll go into more depth on some important points I glossed over in this section.