One testing practice we will be exploring in this
course is test-driven development, or TDD.
TDD is the practice of writing tests to guide development.
When developing a new feature, or when making change to existing code,
the first step in TDD is to design a test that
asserts against a desired outcome.
For example, if you're writing a method to look up a room,
an assertion would be that a room object is returned.
As a code that actually executes this behavior has not yet been written,
the test will fail, or so read.
At this point we would implement the code that would return a room,
and as you're implementing the code,
you will continue the run to test until it turns green.
This is the fundamental tenant of TDD called red/green development.
Write a failing test, implement the feature, get the test to pass.
As new features are added, so are new tests.
When changes are made that causes a break,
the unit tests are there to detect that regression.
The large suite of tests would then allow a
developer to refactor with confidence, knowing regressions will be,
or at least should be, caught.
TDD provides a lot of good guidance when developing a project,
and as tests are being written as the code is being developed,
the application being written should be following many of
the principles of single responsibility,
dependency abstraction, and dependency injection covered in the previous module.
While there are many benefits of the TDD process,
there are a few drawbacks as well,
or at least difficulties that I've experienced when trying to follow it.
Some features might be complex or require patterns that a
developer might not be familiar with.
At that point, it can be difficult to determine what the test should look like.
Arguably, this can mean a developer shouldn't be writing the feature yet.
They could also increase a mental burden on a developer.
Having to think both about the design of a feature and how to
test it could lead to mental fatigue or burnout.
Tests in TDD also have a tendency to be more tightly
coupled to the code they are testing.
While this shouldn't be much of an issue in doing minor refactoring,
significant refactoring could be more difficult as it could require a
large number of tests to be rewritten or thrown out.
Whereas tests written after a feature, or at least its public API has stabilized,
could be designed to be more resilient to changes in the design of the feature.
TDD is a great process whose strengths far outweigh its weaknesses,
which is why I'm highlighting it in this course; however,
it's not without its difficulties as well,
and these often seem to be glossed over when TDD is discussed,
which can lead to frustration when developers new to TDD attempt to put it into practice.