The previous module was all about LDAP. We used LDAP for both
authentication and authorization. In the module before that,
we did the same thing with a MySQL database.
instance.
We used the database for both authentication and authorization.
Well,
in almost all the production implementations of Spring Security that I've done,
we've had to authenticate from one and authorize from the other.
The combination of LDAP plus a database is one of the wider
used approaches that I've experienced when creating a Spring
Security‑based application.
You may recall in one of the previous LDAP demos,
I had left my configuration set up for the database, and this
is the reasoning as to why. This is also where we begin
customizing our Spring Security object. Let's look at that configuration now.