To understand the end‑to‑end solution that we're going to
build, let's actually see the demo first of what we're
going to build in its entirety.
We're going to walk through gathering registration information,
submitting the request, sending the email,
confirming the account, and, finally, logging in with our
new account. You can see on our index page I've added a
Create Account link at the top, which will take a username,
first name, last name, password, and a confirm password,
as well as an email address.
Now I have created for me a sample just test account on
Gmail that I can send this stuff through.
You'll want to use your own or create one like I have for this.
When I click Submit, it'll go through a round trip to the server,
and it's created the account.
And if I go over to our test email address that I've set up,
you can see we've already received our registration confirmation.
When I click on it,
it'll take me back in the app and tell me my account has been confirmed.
Now if I pull up a new page and go into our conference app here,
it will allow me to log in with that new account that we've created.
So if I click Add Registration and put in the username
and the password that we created, it'll log me in.
And, in fact,
it's going to bring up our Password Manager and see if
we want to save that for our app.
So you can see we've gone through all the pieces,
had the correct username, email address,
password, and walked through that entire round
tripping process of creating the account,
storing it in the database, having that send a
confirmation email that we click on,
have the account confirmed, and then be able to log into our app.
Let's start adding that functionality to our application. Now we're going to start with the UI where we gather that account information.