I've shut down my server and closed all my files so we could start
from a fresh workspace while adding this new ConferenceUserDetails
object that we're about to create.
I'm going to go down into src, main, java,
com.pluralsigh.conference, and underneath our model directory,
we'll see we have Registration and User. I'm going to
right‑click on model and say New, Java Class.
We'll call this ConferenceUserDetails, and it's a Class,
so we'll just hit Enter on that. Now, inside of here, make sure
your package structure looks the same as mine.
Say that this extends, and we're going to fully qualify
org.springframework.security.core.userdetails, and inside
of here, we want the User object.
Now this is going to give us an error by default because it wants
a specific constructor that we don't have yet.
So if we hover over our red line, and click the down arrow, it
says to Create a constructor matching super.
And so we have two choices here. we have the simpler one,
which takes the string, and the string for password, and a
collection of authorities, and then there is a larger,
more complex constructor for all of the attributes.
I'm going to choose the simpler one, which is the first one listed here.
Click OK. And then I want to add a member variable of private, and
this is just a String, and we'll call this nickname.
Save that. Now one last thing we want to do here is generate our getters and
setters, and we can just use the keystroke for Command+End or Option+End,
depending on which machine you're running on, and I'm going to say Getter and
Setter, and we're going to choose nickname:String, and we'll click OK. And
there's our custom UserDetails object.
So it's under the com.pluralsight.conference.model package,
we've extended and fully qualified our path to the Spring
Security userdetails.User object.
We've added our basic super constructor in there, and then we've added our private variable for nickname.