I've closed down everything that we had open from our previous demos,
and I am ready to now start adding the docker‑compose file to our application.
And like I mentioned before,
to have Docker running, all you need to do is go to docker.com and
download the specific version for your operating system,
which I've already done.
Now, at the root of our project under conference,
I'm going to right‑click and say New, File, and I'm
going to call this docker‑compose,
and you need to name yours the same, .yml, so just like
xml, but with a y, yml, and hit Enter.
And it does offer some context sensitive help for us in
IntelliJ Ultimate, and some of the other IEDs do as well,
but if you don't have one of those,
it doesn't matter, you can write this in a Notepad. So I'm going to say
version, and then give this 3.8, because that is the current version as
of writing this course. And down below there,
I'm going to say networks and we're just going to choose the default network.
And then for services, we want to have the database service,
so db, and we're going to have an image of mysql: version 5.7.
Now I do know that there are later versions after this, in fact,
MySQL 8 is out. You may go, oh,
that's a big jump from 5 to 8. Five is actually the
most stable one that's in production,
and 8 has some naming convention things that actually break with a lot of
applications, so for our image we're going to use MySQL 5.7. The
container_name we're going to just call conference_security, and then for
ports, and this is what we're going to export from our application to the
inside of the container, we'll say 3306, we'll be exposed to 3306. We could
map different ports if we wanted to,
but this works just fine for what we're doing.
And then we will want to have a volumes, and for the volumes we'll say
that we want a "./.data/db:/var/lib/mysql, and this is kind of a
standard naming convention for where it's going to store the data at.
You'll notice that mine turned green, and that means that it's been
entered the correct way for us.
Then we'll say environment.
We're going to add some environment variables underneath here, and
we're going to say MYSQL_ROOT_PASSWORD, and we're going to just have
our password be pass, you could obviously choose something more
secure if you want; MYSQL_DATABASE, and we're going to call this
database conference_security.
This is everything we need to have Docker inside of our application.
Now I've switched over to our terminal, and I have started typing in
here the command to start up Docker and run that image that we've just
created, and all I have to do is type in docker‑compose space up space
‑d. When I hit Enter, it will go through and fire it up and run our
project for us.
So my Docker instance is actually running now, and if I
launch my Docker desktop and look at it,
I can see that it has fired up our instance for us, and
you can see that everything is running.
It's got its ports, tables, all that stuff is created for us. My application is up and running and ready to go.