To start up the test server that we created the dependency for and
referenced in our ConferenceSecurityConfig file, we need to add three
properties to our application.properties file.
The first one is the spring.ldap.embedded.ldif, which we're going to add
to our classpath with the name of test‑server.ldif.
This is not how you would typically populate a production server,
but we have to have a starting point to test
something inside of our application.
So we're going to add this test‑server.ldif file inside of our code,
and that will populate our server with some default users that we can
run against. The next one is the same properties and appending .base
to the end of that for our dn,
which will contain our directory context or our structure,
which will be pluralsight and a context of com.
And then, lastly, our port, which is 8389.
So let's add these three properties in there, and then we'll go ahead and start creating our test‑server.ldif.