Picking up where we left off before,
let's create our ConferenceUserDetailsContextMapper,
and we're going to do this in a new package.
So I'm going to right‑click on com.pluralsight.conference,
and say New, Java Class, then inside of here,
we're going to say service.ConferenceUserDetailsContextMapper.
We want to make sure we get that CamelCase,
hit Enter,
and this is going to implement the
UserDetailsContextMapper interface.So we'll say implements,
the UserDetailsContextMapper,
and this is going to give us an error because we need to implement some methods,
so we'll click OK.
And really, the only one that it really cares about is this first one.
The second one is if we're going the other direction,
and we don't care about that for the code that we're writing,
so we're going to be working in this one here.
Now to do this, we need to do a handful of things.
First, we're going to start with autowiring in a data source.
So we'll say @Autowired, and we'll put in here private DataSource,
and we want to choose the javax.sql package,
and we'll save this.
The next thing that we want to do is create a SQL statement for
retrieving our username out of the database,
and we're going to do that by saying private static final String,
and we'll call this loadUserByUsernameQuery.
You could call this SQL, it doesn't have to be named this,
or whatever else you want, and we'll have a select username,
and we're going to name all the columns out,
password, enabled, and the column that we just added,
nickname from users where username =?, and we'll put
a semicolon on the end of there.
Now let's make this break over to where you can see it easier all in one line.
We'll save that there.
This is the statement we're going to use in a JdbcTemplate
that we're going to create here in just a second to load
those users from the database.
So inside of this mapUserFromContext method,
we're going thio create a JdbcTemplate,
and we'll call this just JdbcTemplate = new
JdbcTemplate, and we'll pass in the dataSource.
You could, if you wanted to, create the JdbcTemplate as a being and share
that being inside of here. That is a great approach as well. Either works
well. Now because we're going to create an anonymous inner class in here,
we're going to create this instance as final.
So we'll say final ConferenceUserDetails, and we'll
just call this the userDetails object.
We'll say that is = new ConferenceUserDetails object,
and it's going to want all those parameters that we just created passed in.
Now, this is going to seem a little bit odd to start with,
and I'll walk you through what we're doing here.
We're going to put in here this dirContextOperations object .getStringAttribute,
and that stringAttribute is uid, and that's the user ID,
and you probably don't remember it,
but that's what we created inside of our testserver.ldf file.
Now the next one we want to put in here is the password,
and I am actually going to put the string fake inside of here because we don't
want to be passing around the password inside of our application for other
people to grab and be able to hack our session with.
So, once they're authenticated,
we have a token, we don't need to pass that password around anymore,
so I'm actually going to just put that placeholder of fake in there.
If we needed it later, we could come back through here and edit it,
but not going to for now.
And then the last thing I'm going to put in here is an empty
granted authorities list because we're not using it right
now, and we're going to later.
So we'll say Collections.EMPTY_LIST. And now we have our
ConferenceUserDetails object, this variable to store the user details,
and its final, so we can access it in this next piece.
We're going to use that JdbcTemplate that we just created,
and I'm actually going to paste in this line because it's a little error prone
for type errors. Inside of here, we have our JdbcTemplate,
and we're going to do a query for object and pass in that
loadUserByUsernameQuery string that we just created up above.
We're going to do an anonymous inner class using the new RowMapper
ConferenceUserDetails, and that's going to require us to override this
mapRow method that we have here, and you can see inside of that it executes
that query, and we grab that nickname column out of there, and assign it to
our userDetails object, and return that.
Then inside of here,
we can finally return our userDetails object back to the UI. So, a
little bit of a hairy piece here, but we have this all defined, we
want to do one last thing inside of here,
and that is define this as a service.
We haven't done that before in this class.
So we're going to say @Service,
this being where object will now be registered
inside of Spring as a service object,
we can go ahead and grab this and use it anywhere inside
of Spring as a fully‑registered being.
Now, a lot of times you'll also see @Transactional here, we don't need
to do this because one, we're just doing reads, and everything is
contained in the site, the scope of this one method. We're almost
ready to use our newly‑created mapper, we just need to go ahead and
configure our conference security object to utilize this new mapper that we've created.