A major change that was just beginning in the previous release of this
course was the migration from XML in our application.
It started first with not having XML in your Spring code,
and then other standards pushed for it as well.
More recent serverless specifications have even
called for not having it a web.xml.
XML is often thought to be more complicated and at a minimum is more
error prone for copy and paste errors. Not using XML,
though, can be a little bit black box feeling, and what I mean by that is,
if you start using it but do not understand what's going on behind the scenes,
it can be a little confusing.
So this often leaves developers confused about how their
application is working and, furthermore,
left wondering what to do when something breaks.
Since this is an update to an existing course,
I wanted to show you the old security‑config.xml,
and if you go look at other examples,
you may see XML configuration code that was written this way,
and so you'll see we had an authentication‑manager and a ‑provider and a
user‑service inside of here, and the username is bryan, and the password is
secret. And I have the authorities or roles inside my application of a
ROLE_USER. That same thing can easily be written in Java code now. Here you
can see we created a user with the DefaultPasswordEncoder scheme. We added
the username "user" to it and the password "password" to it and the roles
of "USER", and we build this object.
So it's a standard builder pattern if you're at all familiar with
that. Now that we've shown you a couple of techniques,
let's go write this code into our application so you can now see how to utilize this.