Since this is a new schema, I'm going to have to create a new connection to it.
So, opening up my MySQL Workbench, I'm going to click the plus sign,
and I'm going to give this connection name just conference, and localhost
3306. It's going to ask me for the password is we go, so we'll click OK. And
we have our basic schema set up in front of us here, so now I can insert a
couple of records into the database.
I'm going to right‑click on conference_security and say set as default
schema, and that way I don't have to prepend any of my statements with
anything saying put it in this schema.
So we're connected to that database and now have this set as the default
schema. Let's start off by creating a table named Users.
It's going to have a username and a password and an enabled column. And the
primary key will be username. I'm going to execute this, and we can see by the
green output at the bottom that it was successful.
The next thing I'm going to do is create the authorities table,
and I can highlight that one statement and execute it, and you
can see that it was successful.
Now I'm going to create an index between those two.
If I highlight that same thing,
I can execute that one statement, and now is where it gets tricky.
I need to insert a user and a role inside the table. And I'm going to
grab both of those statements and paste them in here, but I'm going to
show you how I got one of those values.
You'll notice that we have the values bryan and this weird long string that
is my password, and that is the encoded version of pass.
Let me show you how I got that. Switching back to the IDE, if I exit
full screen and I go to src, main, test, java,
com.pluralsight.conference, and open up this
ConferenceApplicationTest, I can auto wire a bean inside of here
because this class is already annotated as a spring boot test.
So we want to auto wire in that bean we created
before, which was the PasswordEncoder.
I'm just going to call this encoder and save that. And then inside of
our contextLoads, I can do a real simple System.out.println. There
are much better ways to go about this,
but this will work for what we want to do, and we'll say encoder.encode.
And if you remember, we used that string of pass,
and we can close off that method and just simply print it out.
So we'll save this, right‑click and run it, say run
contextLoads, and when it scrolls off the screen,
you'll see it load up spring, and we'll come back to
the statement at the very bottom.
You see it dumped it out there for a second, it was really quick.
This string right here is pass encoded using our password encoded.
So that's literally that character sequence that we have
encoded using our password encoded bean that we had defined
in our ConferenceSecurityConfig.
If we go to the bottom of our ConferenceSecurityConfig,
you see the bean that we have created here, we're just using
that BCryptPasswordEncoder to encode that.
So if your password is not pass,
you've done something else, you're going to want to go to that test and put in
whatever your password is in there and run that test to get that value out,
and then go back over to MySQL and inject that value in there because your
statements will check encrypted passwords,
not cleartext passwords.
It never decodes them, it only uses them in an encoded fashion.
Now, back over to our MySQL Workbench.
You can go ahead and paste in whatever your password is here.
I've already done that to mine, and you can execute those two statements.
And when you're all done with that, you can run a select* from users,
which I've already done here,
which will show me that I have my user in this database.
So if I execute that,
I will see that I've got Bryan and my password in there like I think I would.
And also, before we leave this,
let's run a commit statement in here. So, type that in there,
commit it. You'll see the commit was successful.
If you don't do that,
you'll leave your MySQL Workbench with these changes working in your
Workbench, but it won't work inside your application,
so don't forget that very important step.
You can select users, but if they're not committed,
it won't show up outside of this transaction. Let's switch back to our IDE.