All right.
To begin adding security to our application,
I've gone ahead and closed down everything we did to running a
sample app and any of the previous demos and just got it down to
the default workspace as close as possible.
I shut down the servers and everything else.
We're going to start by opening up our pom.xml file.
We're going to add three dependencies inside of here. So
I'm going to go below my org.hibernate.validator, and if
you're starting from my example,
you should have the same exact code inside of here. I'm
going to paste in these three dependencies.
Now,
I realize you won't have the same dependencies that I do to paste in
here because you don't have anywhere to copy them from.
You can actually go grab them from the Exercise files, or you can type them in.
It's actually not that hard to do so because the context sensitive help
will help you do that with any ID that you choose.
I will point out three things here,
one, that we have the spring‑boot‑starter‑security dependency.
And there's not a version tied to that because we
are using dependency management.
If you don't know what that means, it's a Maven term that it chooses
the correct version based off of our parent POM.
I have spring‑security‑test inside of here,
and it has a scope of test that you can see defined there on
line 48, and no version because that's also being pulled
through that dependency management.
The spring‑security‑test gives us some sample libraries to
create an in‑memory database or LDAP server, that type of
thing, so we'll use it for that.
And then I've added one for some JEE stuff, the java.serlet, jstl
library, javax.servlet, jstl library that allows us to do some simple
navigation things inside of JSTL like including and excluding fields
and some binary logic that way.
So these are the three dependencies we need. Now let's go
ahead and start by opening up our registration page and
selecting all the code inside of here.
So I'm just going to do a Cmd+A, Cmd+C, or if you're on a Windows machine,
Cntrl+A, Ctrl+C, right‑click on jsp, and create a new JSP/JSPX file.
I'll call it login.jsp, hit Enter. And I'm just going to
replace all the code we have inside of here with that
registration page that we just copied.
I want to add a new tag library at the top,
so I'll give myself a little space there and do an <%@.
I'm going to choose taglib, and the prefix of that, we're going to choose "c".
The uri="http://java.sun.com/jsp/jstl/core." I'll choose that one.
I'll give you a second to look at that.
And if you don't want to type all this stuff in there, again,
you can grab this out of the Exercise files and just copy and paste it
as you go and walk through so you're not hung up on the syntax but,
rather, looking at the semantics of it.
Or you can go ahead and pause and type it all in there as well.
I'm going to scroll down and change line 11 from Registration to Login.
And then we're going to go down a little bit further, and on line
41, I'm going to change this to Login as well.
And then I am going to replace this form completely.
You may want to go ahead and change the fields that are in there.
But I would not like you to make a typo or miss a step that's doing that.
So you may want to completely delete it because there are a bunch of
things we're going to change in here, and I'm going to walk through
that right now. Replacing mine, I'm going to highlight that and paste
in a new div on lines 44 and 45.
And this is utilizing that tag library that we just put in there of
the core or c taglib that it looks for an error in our response and
displays that error if there is one.
The example will work just fine without that.
But if you get any errors, you won't be able to see them.
And then I replaced our form with lines 47 through 52 where we now have an
action="perform_login" and a method="post", and this will all tie into what
we're doing on the back end here in a minute.
And I'll pull both files up side by side so you can see what's tying to what.
If there is an error on line 48, we're going to display it with a form:errors
path= all of the errors that are out there.
Use this cssClass="errorblock" and then do the element="div" for that div
element. Then we have two input boxes‑‑a User Name and a Password.
Very simple,
just standard input fields, and then a submit button. That's a just role button,
and it will go ahead and post that back to the server.
So very simple.
A two‑filled input form with a submit button tied to login
and display an error if it's there. Now we can save this and exit out of full screen.