Now we're ready to add that post back to our controller.
So let's go back into that file,
and I'll shut our server down to give us a little
more real estate for full screen.
I'm going to put in the method signature here,
and import the classes that we need to use now.
Then I'll close off this method here,
and it's going to return us back to eventually the string
"redirect:account," and if you're not familiar with what this is,
it is a Spring MVC technique to execute a redirect back
to the page that you want to go to.
And I'm going to pseudocode out a couple of things here in the
comments just to show the layout of how you could actually
process things inside of your application.
To add every single step in here would make our application be way too large.
So one thing we could do is check for errors,
and we're going to actually do a lot of these steps.
We'll check for errors in the binding result so we can
look to see if result has any errors.
The next thing that we should look for is we should check for the account
to see if there is already one existing in this system.
So we should verify that the account and the user don't exist in our system,
and then we should also verify that the email address is valid as well.
And we could use a regular expression to' do that or a
couple other techniques to do that.
So those steps in there, and then from here,
we need to also encrypt the new password coming in,
as well as we want to then create the new account,
and then we're going to fire off an event for the
account creation to have us verify it.
That is all of these steps that have to take place for
us to go through and do this post.
So let's save this, and I'm going to start our server back up,
and now we can navigate to Account, and enter in some information,
and once we hit Submit,
it will go to our server and redirect us back to this page.
So it has gone full trip from the get to the JSP page,
back to the post, and then redirected back to this page.
Let's now go ahead and look at starting to flush out all those
comments we put inside of our controller, and fill in the pieces where we talk to the database.