This module really encompassed what I feel like a lot of people run into
problems with when adding security into their application,
and that is authenticating against one resource and authorizing against another.
And so we covered authentication and authorization from LDAP and MySQL, or
a SQL database, it doesn't matter if it's MySQL or not,
and we customized that user details object, and we just added a nickname,
but you could add whatever fields you want to be pulled
out, and stored in that object, and passed around as part
of your Spring Security session.
We did that by creating a custom context mapper that intercepted that
LDAP call to then authorize against our database, and finally, we
added a couple of configuration items in there, in that we created
that context mapper as a service and autowired that into our
conference security config,
thus injecting that resource and making it available to us inside of our app.
Let's look at how we now customize our login page to utilize some of these features that we've now implemented.