I wanted to take a second and show you one tip or trick that
you might need throughout this course, and it doesn't happen very often,
but it's one I get asked enough in the discussion
forums that I wanted to show it to you.
If you have a problem with the deployment of your project or something
doesn't seem to be working quite as you had expected it to,
you may want to go over here to your Maven sidebar and click the
clean goal and have this go through and completely delete all of
the resources associated with your generated files in your target
directory and then compile it.
That's often enough.
I actually like to do a package or even an install.
If you're unfamiliar with those terms,
you may want to go through the Maven course that we
have out here on Pluralsight, it's actually another course of mine,
that will explain what's going on when it does this. And, essentially,
it's going to go through and completely rebuild your whole
deployment artifact that you send to your Tomcat server.
So if something stuck, and I see this more with Windows
machines than I do other machines,
not just with them, but that does seem to have a resource every
now and then that gets hung up because it's stuck in a
deployment or something is not quite right.
If you're having problems, try that clean and compile or package.
I will say that I see this more often if you are using GitHub or
a source code control repository, and you're checking out
versions of code, and you might have a file that's newer than
what you had before or vice versa.
So it doesn't look to force a compile on it because the
timestamps have changed on that file.
So if that's a problem,
something seems stuck, just click that Maven sidebar clean,
compile package, and 99 out of 100 times, it cleans up any problems you may have going on in your workspace.