The first step in creating our service tier is to create our
AccountService interface. And I'm going to stop our server to give
ourselves a little bit more real estate to work with here.
If I go down to our service package that we have created,
and right‑click and say New, we can click Java Class,
although we're going to choose Interface, and we'll call it the
AccountService, and click Enter. And this will give us our blank
interface that we can start putting those methods into. And we're
going to add three methods in here, a public Account create,
which takes in an Account as the method signature; a createVerificationToken,
which takes in an Account and a String token; and
then eventually a confirmAccount, which will take in the String token as well.
So let's save this interface.
Then I'm going to exit full screen for a minute here and right‑click on
our service package again, and say New Java Class,
and this time it will be the Java Class. We'll say AccountServiceImpl,
and this will be annotated as a Service, and it implements the
AccountService interface. And this should give us an error, and
if we hover over that, we can choose to implement the methods,
and we'll select all three.
This gives us our basic signature of what we want to
create for all of these methods.
So now we have our Service in place, it's annotated as a Service.
We can access it through the interface, we need to tie that into our
controller here in a minute, but since we're here,
let's carry out the next step, and that is the repository as well. So this
needs to talk to the database, and a service will talk to a repository, and
the repository has the actual database code in there.
So let's add those pieces as well.
The repository will be in a separate interface and class,
so we'll want to create a new package. And we'll do that by going to
com.pluralsight.conference, right‑clicking and saying New Class, and we can
type in repository.AccountRepository and select Interface,
and that will create the AccountRepository interface. And inside of
here we're going to have one signature to start with,
and that is the create account.
I will be honest with you, the AccountRepository is going to be the
more complex class that we have to deal with in this,
because it's going to do all of the interaction that we have with the database.
Now this is almost the same exact thing,
if you choose to use Hibernate or JPA. I've used Spring JWC to not add
yet another dependency inside of here. And it's pretty straightforward,
and generally people understand the database side of it, and have to
work with an existing data model, which,
if you are working with an existing data model, Hibernate can be a little bit
more complex, so we'll go through the Spring JDBC route. And I'm going to
right‑click on Repository and create a New Class.
And that will be the AccountRepositoryImpl, and this will be annotated as a
repository, and it will implement the AccountRepository interface. And the same
as we did with the service, if we hover over this,
it will give us the option to implement the methods that we have so far,
which is just the create.
Now we can inject the dataSource that we have and create a
JdbcTemplate to inject that first account into our database.
Let's go back to our AccountController and start injecting in all the
resources that we want to use inside of our application, from the
controller clear back to the repository.
We'll start off here by saying @Autowired. We want to put in a private
AccountService, and we'll put that in a variable accountService, and then
we'll also do an @Autowired private PasswordEncoder.
And this is so we can encrypt the password that we have inside
of our account object that gets passed in.
Now that we have those two in there,
we'll go down to our post, and we can encrypt that password.
So we'll just say account.setPassword and we'll say encode account.getPassword.
So we're going to encrypt that password that was passed in and reassign
that back out to our account. And then, down below here,
we can use that service that we just created and say account is equal
to accountService.create, and pass in our account.
Now you may be asking why I am returning account and
assigning it when we already have it,
and that's because a lot of times on our back end, not always,
but it's a good habit to get into, on our back end we may modify
that object and return it, so we may assign an auto‑incrementing
field out of the database or modify it in some other way, and we
want to return that back.
Not always, but it's a good habit to get into.
Now that we have that assigned on our accountService,
though,
we can go to the actual service implementation, and inside of here we
can Autowire in our repository that we just created.
So kind of the same thing, we'll say @Autowired, we'll pass in a private
AccountRepository and assign that to an accountRepository variable.
And inside of our create here,
we can call accountRepository.create, and pass in account as well, and
save that. And now we have everything wired up. All the things that we
need to do inside of our application are wired up as far as the post is
concerned, to create the account.
We still have a lot of work to do,
but it's wired from our controller to our repository tier, so now
we're back to the repository tier that we created.
Now we can start implementing the JDBC call to actually
assign that account into our database,
to where we can then work on the verification process.
Now it's a little bit of which one is better to do first or the other.
We have to create a database table to write this account to,
but I already have the code here handy, so I am
going to Autowire in our DataSource.
We'll just assign that to a private DataSource, and we'll call that
dataSource. And that's already defined through our Spring Security
configuration that we have set up.
We're going to utilize the same one, and inside of this create statement,
I'm going to replace that with this JdbcTemplate that I have already
written. And I'll walk through what I'm doing here with you.
We create an instance of a JdbcTemplate.
Then we are going to execute an update statement, that's how you do
an insert, that will be an insert into the accounts table, we're
going to go create that here in a second,
and that has a column username, password,
email, firstname, and lastname,
as you can see from that SQL statement. And then we're just
using a simple prepared statement approach where we use a
varargs to pass in the username, password,
email, firstname, and lastname.
And when that's all done, we're going to return the account.
Now, as I mentioned earlier,
sometimes you will update that with things we actually haven't
changed anything on account, we're just going to return back the
one that we have back to that user.
So, this is all of the pieces from front to back, from the
UI, to the controller, to the service tier,
clear to the repository writing to the database.
Now I'm going to go ahead and switch over to the MySQL
workbench to create this database table.
Switching back to my MySQL editor, you can see that I've
got the SQL in here to create a table named accounts. And
I've got in there a username, password, email,
firstname, and lastname,
all with their respective sizes in a VARCHAR 50, 100, 100,
50, and 50, and I've established that the PRIMARY KEY in
here is the username column.
So I'm going to go ahead and highlight that SQL and execute it,
and it completed successfully.
And then I'm going to highlight that commit statement and execute that.
So now our table is created.
We can switch back over to the IDE.
We're actually going to give this a test run end‑to‑end. It's halfway
through our confirmation process, but we don't really want to go too much
further in case something isn't quite wired up right or we're going to have
a lot of troubleshooting to do, so let's make sure that this piece is
working how we expect it to so far.
Let's start our server up. That'll take a second to run.
And now, back in our app,
we can go up to the address bar and type in account
and put in some garbage data.
We're going to delete this record anyway.
I will put in a valid email address just so you can see it go through to the
database, it's not going past that yet, and click Submit.
It's going to redirect back to this page.
It was actually successful.
Let's go back over to our MySQL workbench and look to see if that record
completed end‑to‑end to the database. If we go ahead and give ourselves some
space down below here, we can do a select statement from the accounts table
and run that to see if our record was just inserted, and you'll see that it
was. We have our username of asdf; the password, which was encrypted using
bcrypt from our controller; the actual valid email address that we inserted in
there; and then a first name and last name of asdf that we pasted in there as
well.
So everything is going end‑to‑end, clear from our controller
coming in and directing back to the account.jsp page, us
gathering data, submitting to the post, encrypting that password,
passing it through our service and repository tier,
which finally inserts it into our database.
If you're not seeing this now,
you'll want to stop and make sure that you don't have any errors in your
console or anything else, but if you followed all these steps,
you should be to here.
Next thing we're going to do is look at firing off the event that sends the actual email to you to confirm your account.