This was a very complex module.
We had a lot of things going on here to go through the entire
confirmation process and registration process.
We started off by creating your account and gathering all of that
information and storing it in the database correctly.
We then configured an email server to handle the asynchronous
sending of emails from our application.
Remember that that's why we fired off an event and used the
event listener so that it was non‑blocking in your
application. Your user could register,
and if the email server was down it wasn't going to block anything in your app.
It would fire it off when it was ready to do so.
We created verification tokens that made it to where we could safely and
securely go out and send people new account information without having it
require you to do anything else inside of your app.
And, by the way,
one thing we didn't mention then is this is the same thing that
we will do if you have a forgotten password.
We then went through the entire confirmation process of
once that's all saved and stored,
sending them an email, having them click on that email, open it up, and
verify that they are who they say they are, and moving data from your
account tables over to the user details tables. And the same process would
work if we were using LDAP. It's a little bit more complicated just because
interacting with LDAP can be a little bit more complicated, but it would
work just the same.
And then when we were all done, we went through and cleaned up everything.
So we deleted out of the verification tokens and the accounts tables,
those leftover pieces of data that's out there.
And I would say one of the most complex things in dealing with this
process is as you go through to test it you have to go through and
delete from those tables if you have messed something up. So as you
go through that process, you're going to have to clean that up.
So it's good that our app cleans up after itself as well.
You could schedule a cron job with your database that would go
through and remove those expired tokens as well, but it's kind of outside the scope of what we're reviewing now.