It doesn't matter if we implement this functionality
before or after our login and remember me.
It will all get built the same way.
I'm going to go to the end of our configuration.
But before that closing semicolon,
I'm going to move that down a couple of lines, and I'm going to
start typing in here and say .and. From here, we can start adding on
all of our functionality for the logout.
So we'll say logout, and then we want to do the logoutSuccessfulUrl.
And in our instance,
we want to send them back to the login page, and we want
to add a parameter of logout=true.
And then on the next line, we're actually going to do a .logoutRequestMatcher,
and that will enable us to do a GET instead of a POST for our logout function.
And I'll show you on the UI what I'm talking about here in the next demo.
But for this instance, it will make it to where our UI configuration is simpler,
and it's only one more line on the back end. From here, we can say
that we want to .invalidateHttpSession equal to true.
Then, we want to delete the cookies, and this is all caps. We'll
say JSESSIONID, and that is case‑sensitive.
And then, last, but not least,
we're going to throw on the end there a permitAll. Now
before I move on to the next step,
I want to show you one other line of code that we are not going to
use. Because we are using that logoutRequestMatcher,
we do not use this line,
which is the logoutUrl. You may look at some other examples
that are using .logoutUrl, and this would be some performed
login or logout functionality, whatever.
We're not using that because we want to use a GET.
So if you see examples with that and you're wondering what the
difference is, we have opted to not use that because we're going
to do the logoutRequestMatcher. Let's look at what the UI aspect of this same call is.