The annotations we're going to use are already included in
the JARs that we have in the application,
but we need to enable them.
First, we need to actually annotate our code to use annotations, and
we're going to enable this by adding the @EnableGlobalMethodSecurity
annotation to the top of our security config.
This actually allows us to then configure specific attributes.
These attributes are the prePostEnabled, which we can use aspects to
affect our method before or after it is going to execute.
Next, the securedEnabled, which is the one that we are going to focus on.
This will just allow us to wrap our code with a secured element. And then
finally, jsr250, and this is just a different way of us doing the same
thing as Secured. Jsr250 is Java's way of adding the Secured annotation
that is generic across frameworks. Either way, it works the same.