To add security to our RegistrationController, let's open up that
file. I'm going to go to controller and then open up the
RegistrationController, and we want to do it on the Post.
We could actually do it on the Get as well, we could do it
on any of the methods that we want to prohibit somebody
accessing, but for the Post,
let's say that we won't allow them to submit back to this file without
having a role of ROLE_USER. So we'll say @Secured, and inside of here it
just takes a string. And you can actually do an array of values as well,
but for our case we'll just say ROLE_USER, and save that. Now, I'll tell
you when we run this it's going to execute successfully, and the reason
for that is our user does have that ROLE_USER already assigned to them.
So if we start up our server, give that a second to refresh,
we'll go through the Add Registration process.
So here we are back to our home page again, and if we click on Add Registration,
it's going to ask us to log in, which that's what we want.
Put in a valid username and password, and Login, and now we're a logged‑in user.
If we click Add Registration again, we can put in a registration and
click Add Registration and it'll go through successfully.
Well,
the reason it goes through successfully is we do have that ROLE_USER
already associated with our account, and we can verify that by going
over to our MySQL interface and looking at the roles associated with
that person. If you'll remember, we have an extra table in there for that.
Looking at our MySQL console, if we just run a select * from authorities,
you'll see the results that come back are that we already
have a ROLE_USER associated with the current logged‑in user
that I have inside of there.
And if we didn't have this,
it actually wouldn't allow us to log in, so that's why by
default we've assigned this to everybody in here.
If you'll remember, when we confirmed our account,
we did add that role in there. Let's run an example now that doesn't have that, and see what it returns.