Switching back to our IDE, if we change our ROLE_USER to ROLE_ADMIN,
or honestly,
anything else because we don't have another role for
anybody stored inside of our application,
if we do @Secured ROLE_ADMIN, and then restart our server,
this is going to fail when they access that page. If we go through
the same steps again of Add Registration, Login because we have
restarted our app, and now go to the Add Registration, it will
fail because it's forbidden.
In fact,
you can see in the error message right there type=Forbidden,
status=403. So, even though we're logged into the
application, and we can view that page,
it won't allow us to post back to it because we do not
have a ROLE_ADMIN. So we've effectively locked down
methods inside of our application,
and anybody logged in and going through that process,
you can go ahead and tie down any specific application piece that you want to prohibit them from accessing it.