A lot of the heavy lifting is done for us now,
but now that we've actually gone out and fired off the email,
and verified that it's gone to that email address,
and comes back to our application, we need to go ahead and verify that token,
and then display the page that we want them to enter the new password on.
So we're going to add some stuff to our controller,
add another UI page that will post back to that
controller to then write to the database.
So,
let's begin implementing that by modifying our controller
and then creating another JSP page.
This error message is because we have nowhere to go inside
of our app once they've gone ahead and clicked the
passwordReset link in our email.
So, let's switch back to the controller and add a path for that to resolve to.
Our controller just needs another GetMapping that will
resolve that URL that we just passed in.
We're going to do this a tiny bit different,
we're going to use a ModelAndView object,
which will enable us to grab that token and display it back to the
user because the difference here is that we want to make sure
throughout that process that we capture that token and verify it
through all of the steps that we're going to.
So,
we're going to grab this token off the URL string that comes in from our email,
store that in a password object that's going to be
the backing form for our JSP page, and return that new ModelAndView,
which will be the resetPassword JSP page that we need to create right now,
and back it with the model of the password object.
So that's what the ModelAndView object does here,
it's a little bit of Spring MVC,
but you get the idea that's a little different than what we've seen before,
so I wanted to point that out.
The resetPassword page that we're going to create is very similar
to the password page that we've already created.
This is probably one of the biggest complaints that people
have about JSP pages and HTML in general.
Let's copy that, right‑click on our jsp folder,
and say New, JSP, and call this resetPassword.jsp.
And I'm going to highlight all of that and replace it with the
password JSP that we've already created,
and then we'll just change the few relevant fields
that we need to inside of here.
We have a Password, and it is of type password,
and its name is actually password out of that object.
And then we have the Confirm Password, and its type is also of password,
and its name is matchingPassword.
I went ahead and grabbed the confirmation that we had
from our account‑confirmed JSP page, and I'm going to pace that in here,
that just allows us to go ahead and show a Twitter
Bootstrap alert of successful,
and you can see that Your passwords has been reset
when we redirect back to this page,
it'll look for that parameter and display that green bar,
and you'll see that here in a second when we do our demo.
This page will post back to our PasswordController,
since we just created that GetMapping,
it's going to post back to that same GetMapping because we
don't have a different URL specified,
which is the exact behavior we want it to do.
So let's create a PostMapping method inside of here for the passwordReset,
and it will take a RequestParam of Token and the
ModelAttribute of password associated with that.
Make it where you can see this all on one page.
And this is one of the more complex methods that we
have to create inside of it here,
so let's flush out some of the details inside of here.
The first thing that we want to do is we should match
the password and verify the token,
so let's create a couple of comments in here to stub that out
so we can see the steps that we need to do.
So our password should match, and we'll verify that token,
and to verify that token,
we want to go ahead and grab that out of our database
to see if those two tokens match, and doing so,
we're going to actually inject our PasswordRepository into this controller.
So let's scroll up to the top here, say @Autowired,
and we'll create a private variable, we'll say PasswordRepository,
and we'll choose passwordRepository,
and we're actually going to need the passwordService as well,
since we're already up here, let's just go ahead and inject that as well,
and that is our PasswordService, we'll say passwordService,
and save both of those.
And then we have created the skeleton for this,
but we haven't flushed it out yet, so let's just say ResetToken,
resetToken = passwordRepository.findByToken,
and that's going to take that string token that we
have in our method signature already, and we have the contract for this,
but we haven't created the actual implementation of finding that yet,
so let's go ahead and go into our PasswordRepository and finish that out.
And that is a simple queryForObject,
which we have done in our account repository,
if you don't want to type this all out,
feel free to grab that and change the appropriate pieces there.
So I'm going to import everything we need for this.
And we have our SQLException, resultSets,
and everything else, and this is a simple queryForObject where we grab the email,
username, token,
expiry_date from reset_tokens where the token is equal to the
token we passed in from our URL string,
and that goes through and grabs one object,
and if you have multiple objects here, it's going to throw an exception,
and we should only ever have one object for this,
so it'll map that row out to the email, username,
token, and expiry_date.
So if you do copy that other one over,
make sure you change these fields to match that.
And that will return our token,
which will then go back to our PasswordController.
So, let's go ahead and go back to our PasswordController,
and we'll see that that's now returning our token.
And let's finish out the rest of this implementation.
We want to look to see if that token is still valid.
So we can say if resetToken.getExpiryDate is after the current Date,
and if it's not, we will take our password object,
and we will encode the password that we have,
so we'll say password.setPassword, and we haven't used our encoder yet,
so we need to import the password encoder that we already
have defined inside of our application.
Let's scroll up to the top of our injected resources,
and say @Autowired, and we'll do private PasswordEncoder,
and we'll assign this to a variable named encoder,
and we want to do encoder.Encode,
and we'll use the getter on our password to just say password.getPassword.
Now we should've made sure that those match and all the
other stuff that goes with it up above.
It would become a very complex, long example to do that,
and it's just tedious work, that's Spring MVC stuff,
not necessarily Spring Security.
And we can come down here now, and since they've matched,
and they're not expired with the token, we'll say passwordService.update,
and that will take our password object and our resetToken.getUsername,
and this has the contract there, but we need to implement that actual method,
so let's open up our PasswordServiceImpl.
It's the service tiers where our business logic resides.
We have the opportunity to put some more business logic in here,
but for our example,
we're just going to call passwordRepository.update on this password,
utilizing this username.
We need to finish out the implementation of that JDBC
query in our PasswordRepository,
which we can do here in the actual implementation.
And this is a JdbcTemplate that just uses the UPDATE method to execute a
UPDATE users SET password equal to this password that we're passing in where
the username is equal to this parameter as well.
So we have those two objects that we pass in, the password and the username.
And this is all we need to do to update that table.
We can save this, we'll go back to our Controller,
and finish out this method with the return variables,
and then we're done with this example.
The last line of this if statement is that we want to return a redirect to
the passwordReset page with reset=true as a parameter,
and we set the token=0, and this is just to clear it out of the URL string.
Somebody can't use the back button as easily to go back
in and try and reset that password, which really shouldn't be an issue anyway.
The token would expire, but we set it to true,
and token to 0 just to clean up things a little bit.
And we can throw an else statement on the end of here,
and return a string of tokenExpired.
And we haven't created this page,
but it doesn't require it to be there for our example to run,
but you can have this if you wanted to inside of your application,
so that if their token is expired,
you would show them a nicer error message than just a 404 or a 500 error.
This will enable you to navigate things a little bit cleaner inside your app.
And we're now ready to test that second half of our demo.
So let's restart our server, and that email that we had,
we should be able to just go in there and click on that one,
and it will redirect us to this page, and have us enter a new password,
and save that back to our user interface.
If I open that email back up, if it hasn't been since the expiration date,
which in my case was just a little while ago,
I can click on this URL again,
and it will direct us to the page to get a new password.
I can put in my new password, click Reset Password,
and it will go out, write that to the database,
and give us that nice green bar telling us our password has been reset.
So Let's look at that code again real quick.
Our href that we have on our login page will request a getPasswordReset page,
which is redirected to our UI from our GetMapping
here that just returns password, that page will gather our information,
we'll go ahead and click post back to here to send an email to reset,
which will fire off an onPasswordResetEvent.
The onPasswordResetEvent will go through and just store a URL and a password,
and fire that off on the event model that's already
available to us through our Spring application,
which is listened by this PasswordListener.
The PasswordListener does a little bit of heavy lifting in
the sense that it creates a resetToken,
which essentially goes through our service tier and
eventually to our PasswordRepositoryImpl,
which is our saveToken method inside of here that just inserts that
into our reset_tokens table with our username,
email, the actual token, and an expiration date on it.
When that is done executing,
that PasswordListener will send an email message out through the
configured email server that we enabled in the last module,
and that will go to your inbox.
When that returns, we go back to our Controller,
which our PasswordController will then take this
passwordReset or getNewPassword page, and display that,
and it backs it with the password model object that we have
and also assigns that token to that object.
When we have gathered the new password from them,
we post back to save that new password, and it will verify that token,
and then encode the new password, and update that through our PasswordService,
which is very simply a call to the PasswordRepository eventually that
will update our users table with that new password.
And then when it's all done,
it will redirect us back to that passwordReset page
with that reset=true and token=0,
and that just makes it so we can display that nice UI
message in the green box on our page.
So, when you break it all down, the steps aren't that complicated,
but it is done asynchronously,
which is a little bit confusing to you sometimes and can add
another degree of difficulty in there, but it's disconnected,
and safe, and secure,
and it has to be executed to the registered password on file.
So,
we now have all of those pieces and a working example to reset our password inside of our application.