Hi I'm Edwin Diaz.
Welcome to the course.
Now before we go on and started of course there are a couple of things that I need to tell you.
First of all here's some of the things that we are using in this course we're using zap lamp or map
any of these local environments should work for the course as long as you can run ph be in my ask.
You know we're good to go.
Now I'm going to be using sublime as a cool weather too.
But you can use any cool editor you want.
Now there are a couple of things that you should know before you start the course.
You should know some basic BHB a minuscule L and I think I wrote this very clearly in the description
of the course.
If you don't please understand that you won't be able to follow the course and understand it 100 percent.
You will be able to code with me and follow every line but you won't be able to understand it 100 percent.
Just keep that in mind.
OK now here are some tips and what I expect from you in the course.
I expect you to write code.
This course is meant for you to learn and the best way to learn is writing the code.
Now when you get stock I want you to try your best before you ask a question in the course I want you
to get stuck for an hour or two.
Two days is ok.
Don't worry you will get through it and you can.
You're going to become a lot better than what you are right now.
But if you need help immediately I want you to come and tell me abody would pose the question in the
discussion.
OK but after you have tried it enough now I want to thank you for taking the time for you know for investing
in discourse I'm here when you need me and if I don't deserve my stars let me prove the course and let
me know before you give me any ratings.
Again thank you so much for joining me and let's have some fun in the course.
Ellis learned some really cool stuff.