All right welcome back my student.
So hopefully you took my advice from the best lectures and let you know when I told you that this is
not a beginner's course.
All right.
And if I didn't say that now I'm saying this is not a beginner's for BHB course.
So if you don't know basic BHB you're going to get lost.
Let me just remind you that right now holding you to lunch by the hand on this course like I do in my
older beginner's courses right.
Because I'm assuming that you already know this stuff just to be clear.
So anyway on the last lecture we connected to the database we make sure that everything was working.
Take that out of there right here inside.
We need that BHB we are going to be initializing some other stuff.
So right now we're going to be initialising Olby on this on the score start.
This is a predefined function that will turn on output buffering.
We're going to use this for redirection.
We are also going to start our session here because we wanted this to be available in all our application.
Right so we got to start it in in it that BHB just to make sure that we have this right.
So you don't have to make sure that you do now.
Now we're going to start working with some you know making our our life a little bit easier when we
do functions database functions or stuff like that.
So if we go to our D-B right here all right we can actually have some mom some of these functions here
put it on DVD or BHB if we wanted to where we can put it in functions.
Let's do it right here on the B that BHB and the functions that I'm talking about is like the equerry
functionality you know the fetching arrays you know redirecting things like that.
All right things have to do with a database we want to actually put it right here.
All right.
So the first thing is that Querrey right let's just create a function here and this just let me show
you what I mean.
So usually when we are acquiring the data base we have to do something like this might ask you like
where we are right and we've got to put that connection went down we got to do the query right.
This is kind of a pain right to do this all the time.
And I just want to make sure that you know we take care of this.
All right.
So here on the Querrey what we're going to be doing is we're going to of course pass the Querrey
just to Kohary here just to make it more understandable.
All right.
And then we'll grab the connection with these cases right here.
But we have to put global because this is a flaw a function so a global icon right there then will say
my issue lie.
Connect not connect.
Sorry.
Querrey
again we'll pass in that connection and then we'll pass it where we are right and all we're got to do
is return this.
So now every time we want to make a query we just use this function like this Kohary quote like this.
And then you will make everything for us.
We don't have to be typing in this two parameters every time.
All right.
Beautiful.
What else do we need.
Well it's also very good to actually clean your database escaping.
Right.
We're going to be using mice you realize.
So let's actually create a little function that will allow us to clean our data and actually scaping.
So let's just do it right here let's use scaping
you know what let's do it.
Yeah.
To help us find do scape.
We're going to put the string here.
We're going to pass in the string is going to do everything else for us.
All right.
So we're going to say my AS A lie is real escape string.
We'll pass in the connection it will.
We've got to put that on on a global by the way.
And then here we are passing in the string right.
Let's do that.
All was well
OK but let's do a little bit something else here.
That's fine.
That's OK.
Let's all return.
So this will escape the data for us.
OK.
That's fine.
Let's also use another function.
Usually we do which DML entities to clean up like strange characters when we're putting stuff on like
when we taking stuff from.
Any input.
Type on input type ttes we get some HDMI sometimes in there.
So let's create a function to clean that up as well.
So let's just say function clean and you know what I think we should leave this for the functions that
BHB file because we want everything to do with the database here.
So let's just do fetch data here.
Or let's just say Fetch array.
All right we're going to take in our result from here.
And I was just going to say real quick here.
I was going to say my secure line
fetch rate this is going to be fetching data for us.
All right.
So this is going to grab the resoled and fetch it for us.
All right it's going to grab everything.
Now we can fetch call this like fetch or date I'll fetch one data you know whatever we want to fetch
from it.
So that way it's just a very handy way of doing things right.
Actually you know what.
That's fine that's fine.
Let's just leave it like that.
They don't we can modify this and make it better.
Let's also create a confirmed full function here just to confirm that all the information from the database
is good.
The query is good.
So let's just grab the normal here real quick.
Actually we don't need all to make sure that actually we do.
Sorry we do because we can provide some other errors notification.
So my is a lie actually if we pass an assault here.
So if not sold
then we can just say die we can say where we failed and I know this is a lot of writing here guys.
A lot of coding but believe me this is going to make our lives a lot easier later on.
All right.
We'll pass in the connection here real quick.
Beautiful.
All right.
We're got to leave it at this here.
And if we got some more functionality from the database We'll continue in the next lecture.
Now we'll continue with our regular functions.
But anyway thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.