All right welcome back my students so we have created a couple of functions here let's make sure that
they work right because we don't want to keep writing and writing and then find out later on that they
don't work.
All right.
So let's go to our BHB admin my oddment And let's go to our logon app lawyer and squaddie right here
and you'll see a user real quick.
All right let's go let's go users.
Insert first user of course is going to be myself.
And when the last user named Rico and password 2:59 validation code is empty and actif is zero that's
OK.
All right let's make sure that we or we can pull that data out.
All right.
So let's go to let's go to our.
And that's that BHB Let's try it out.
All right.
Right below this Jumbotron here.
This used to be.
All right.
So we want to pull information from the database.
Right.
So let's just do as well here and let's just say select all users should select all from users.
All right.
And this is find out right now as you Querrey here and we're going to send this guy in here.
Right.
And we can assign this to a variable if we wanted to.
So let's just sign this to like a variable like result.
Right.
And then we got something call fetch array right which is a function that we created fetch the score
array.
And we just fetch the results and we can fetch it and apply it to a variable called row.
All right.
Before that we saw here let's make sure that we do confirm to use the function confirm make sure everything
is good.
Are with a semi-colon.
So we're going to select all from from users and we're going to display.
So it's going to come into something like this.
Let's use display the user name.
All right.
Cool.
Beautiful.
Let's check it out.
So this is the index and we got some unexpected errors like 36 on the B.
Let's find out real quick.
So the line 36 What we forget to do to do.
OK.
This is not a coma this is a dot for concatenation refresh.
And now you can see the user name right here Rico.
All right.
So we are able to pull information from the database using our custom functions which is pretty cool
right.
That way we don't have to write a whole bunch of you know things in here.
All right.
So now this is working.
Let's jump into the functions that BHB and start working there.
Right.
But I want you to make sure that you get this right before you continue.
OK let me just give you a little bit of overview before we go on.
If you used have problems I want you to watch this video if not you skip go to the next one.
All right.
So we've got these inat file that we starting everything right everything we start in a right here.
We are including that the database connection so it's available to not only they in it that BHP but
is available to functions at BHP and is available to every application out there.
Because we are including it in the header.
So right here in it everything is available even though our connection to our database is available
if we wanted to end this file right here in and headed out BHP in that everywhere else everything does
here.
And inside these files he's available to everything in our application.
So make sure that you've got this correct.
Correct.
Make sure that you've got your functions correct.
I'm going to scroll down a little bit so that you can copy anything that might be wrong with yours.
All right remember that these files are available to you.
All right so you can reference them but I don't want you to copy them.
I want you to do the work yourself so you can get used to writing it and everything becomes just easier.
All right.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.