Welcome back my student on the last lecture we create some helper functions here for our D-B that BHB
file that's going to be where function ideas of the database.
And on this lecture we are going to be creating soan general functions that are going to help us do
other things in functions that BHB our file.
But before we do that let's create a function here another D-B function for the database that is going
to count the rows of Row Records inside the table of the database.
So let's call this rule count per right like this right and we're going to take a resort
and we are going to be returning.
My eyes are lying numb rows and then we'll put the results in here like this.
All right super simple super easy to do.
All right.
All right so once we have that let's jump into functions that BHP.
BHP tag's if you don't have it open already and they start creating other functions here oops we go
all right.
So the first function that I wanted to have here is something to clear you know with stuff coming from
the form like if you put something in input type ttes.
Sometimes they could put I don't know greater than symbols or crazy symbols like this.
We want to clear all that out.
All right and we do that with something called H the entities.
But we're going to create a function that's going to help us do that is going to be easier to use so
we can say function let's call it clean and we're going to clean string.
All right.
And we are going to be returning a predefined function from BHB already called of male entities.
In the end is going to clean that string.
All right.
Beautiful.
That's the first one.
Second one would be something called the hetter function that's to read Areca So we're going to call
it redirect cause is easier to do it like this.
And I'll show you in a minute why.
Well first of all keep in mind that we aren't actually creating these helper functions for a reason.
That means if we do it especially here if we are using let's say another type of API for the database
like instead of mice you know we use something for both grass for another database.
We could just replace the coding here for that specific database API and we can change the whole thing
the whole obligation instead of you know having this specifically be to my ask you apply every every
function that we have.
So we have like little plugins that we can plug in to our application and if we use some type of other
data bases API later on we can switch the coding here and if we apply to the whole application is easier.
Right.
But anyway.
So for the redirect here we're just going to do the location and we're going to return the header
which will help us redirect.
All right.
So here we just put the curly brackets in here and say location and I use this curly brackets and you
don't have to use them just to make sure that you know that let.
Whoever has seen my code know that this is a variable in my cell was.
Well you know once I see the curly brackets I noise a variable but if I leave this like this you know
sometimes it's hard to distinguish especially if you have a lot of code and I can also do a raising
here you see.
So this is for complex coding.
Right.
Make sure that you're in it you have your Olby on the score start on top and your session here.
All right.
So want to make sure that.
But anyway and that's for the redirect.
That's why we have this function here orby on the score start.
And you fighting tell you to put that in there make sure that you have it right right on the first line
and then session start.
I want to make sure that you have that because if you don't have that you don't have a lot of problems
later.
All right.
So we have this what else can we create.
Another useful thing is to set session messages.
All right.
I don't want to be doing it all that time to let the user know that something is going on like user's
password was updated or something like that because if we use akele to do some things like that to encode
messages if we redirect to another page we would lose that value and we can't actually use echo if we
really are recked right.
So let's create a functionality here where we can set messages in sessions and that way we can see it
anywhere in our site.
All right.
So let's set some messages here.
Some functions that would help us with that.
So we're going to grab a message here.
This function is going to take a parameter a message write a string and we're going to set a session
with it.
But first let's check to see if this is not empty then we can do it because if it's empty we don't want
to deal with it.
So the message is now empty then we'll grab a session.
All right.
And let's call the message and then we can apply whatever we put in that message variable.
Beautiful else we don't want to get any errors on the screen so we are.
We'll set the message variable to an empty string.
All right.
That's the first and this function here we'll put it or as before the redirect.
When we are actually inside a function.
Right.
So we set the message.
We put some type of string.
We send some type of string and we save it in the session and we can Agway later.
So let's actually create a function to equity.
And this one will be called a set message.
Message like this doesn't take parameters because what we wanted to do is just echo the message right.
So we'll say if it's set
and what if it's sent the session message then we'll actually write
and write and then after echoing.
Then we can on set.
So that way the message doesn't stay there all the time.
Right.
Those are pretty cool functions that you're going to see.
We're going to be using a lot.
All right.
Pretty cool stuff.
Another function that I want you to have which is pretty cool is a function to make our forms really
secure.
And we're going to use this later.
I call this a talking generator function is going to be pretty useful.
This is to create some type of strength like this.
All right is going to be like an encrypted string and then we can put that in the session and then we
can use it to validate the function.
All right.
I'll show you in a minute what I mean.
But anyway let's create a real quick because we're going to need it I'll show you later why generator
you are talking generator.
These are some pretty advanced stuff.
But I want you to know it.
All right is very useful.
So we'll use a couple of functions here to create this one is called a unique ID.
And in this unique ID we can use.
Inside here we can use another one called empty random and you can look this up.
While they do.
But basically you can see this one is going to produce a unique ID and empty random I believe is the
name is going to provide some random values.
I'm going to send this to true right and then I'm going to I'm going to put this encrypted in the empty
five function is going to encrypt all this for me.
All right and there is a website I believe that will give you this.
That if you look for unique ID in google or something would tell you exactly what it does.
But HP on their Web site we would show you exactly what it does.
All right.
So you can find some more about it there.
I'm not going to go into details here.
I'm telling you right now he's going to produce an ID and empty random is going to pull some random
values and then we said that's true just to make it bigger.
All right.
It's just going to be more.
And let me look for the description here.
So that way you can unique ID.
Let me see if I can find it where he is or where I can show you what it is.
Real quick.
Right here.
Unique ID
example something like the LMG
unique ID to show you right now
right here there we go.
All right.
So here you can find that if we said this too true it creates a unique ID with a random number as a
prefix more secure than a static prefix.
All right.
But anyway you can find out some more information about this.
But anyway we got this going here.
All right.
Now not only are we setting this to a variable where we can send this to a session right here
and we'll call this session talking.
All right.
True true true.
And then we can just return the whole day in here.
Beautiful.
All right.
You can play around with this.
You can grab this and create a variable in an empty file and then return and you can see that every
time you refresh you're going to create some random values and it's going to be pretty cool right.
I'll show you later on where we can start this but this is going to go in the hitting input inside the
form and we're going to use this just to make sure that the form is coming from that specific page.
Now it's playing some more later one when we get to the form.
But anyway we're going to use these functions here just to make things a lot more secure is going to
be really cool anyway we are done with this helper functions for now.
We should be done.
Make sure that you write your comments here and you can say something like helper functions
right.
Beautiful.
Then here will will create the next functionality.
I think we're going to work with validation next.
All right.
Just have this in place because we are going to be using it.
Thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next lecture.