All right welcome back my student.
So now that we are done with then general helper functions in functions are BHB.
Well we are done for now but we'll create some more function later.
What we need to do is we need to go to register that BHB and inspect this functionality right here.
All right let's go to our
Peachi my HP log in.
And then we'll go to register.
Let me show you the form.
Now we know that we have more columns in the database so we need to update this form of the name and
the last name field so let's do that real quick.
Right.
So we need two of these.
All right.
So this one is going to have the first name
right and we'll have this here
for a little bit of update to this.
All right.
And this one we have the last name
last name and let's get these user these placeholders.
Well my last name does.
All right let's look at that real quick.
All right now we've got those.
They're in place.
Make sure that your form has the required.
All right.
This is just to make sure that they don't leave any blank space input fields.
Beautiful.
All right.
So this for me is going to cement itself because it has no action.
Actually you are right.
Perfect.
But we want to validate the data too.
Right.
Just in case.
So we want it we are validating here already with javascript as you can see we can submit our last day
or complete but we this is the MFI I'm sorry now javascript page 5 but we also need to validate the
data.
You know let's say for example they use the first names too long or something like or they use a name
too long or too short.
That would be cool to validate.
Right.
I'm not going to bother too much with checking to see if it's blank because I'm L5 doing that or I'm
going to show you how to do it anyway but I'm not going to be doing that too much in this course since
most of the Web sites out there applications are running HD 5 anyway.
So.
But anyway I want to show you how to do it anyway.
So let's go to functions at BHP and right below.
Here is common that we create a validation functions.
We're going to create a function right and this function just Cannavale the it's going to validate the
user.
All right.
So let's create a function validate user registration.
Right.
And some of you already know that we can do something like this if it's set right and we check for that
name value in the cement right here.
We could do that right
right here like this.
And then we can check to see if our form was submitted right.
But we were checking to see in the POSSO pro-global if this is available if he said.
Right.
I like to go another way.
What I'd like to do is I like to access the server array server variables and I like to check to see
if we have any post requests at all.
And when we do we pull out the values and I show you how to do that is actually a more compatible way
within browsers.
Right.
I think my and explorer has a problem when we use the last one this one here.
All right but anyway just to make sure that everything works writing our application we use a server
here and we use this guy right here and you can find out some more information about a specific array
that has a whole bunch of variables.
So he has one request and method.
All right.
So if the request is equal to post and he could be get and I think it also could be put them Patchen
and all that good stuff.
But right now we're detecting from post.
So if the post requests is equal to posts we want to do something I'm going to just echo something out
and say he works and then we're going to grab the phone the name of the function and we're going to
go to that specific register that BHB and right here where he says he has his little role here.
It's a little deaf with a class of call hyphen.
LG it's going to put the funk I'm going to call a function like this.
Let's check it out real quick.
See if he's working.
I'm going to put instant stuffing here.
Make sure that I have my e-mail register and you can see now that he says it works beautiful.
So he's working were able to make that work.
That's a first step.
And after that we need to actually pulao the values one by one so we can use post-Super global for that.
Right.
And the first thing is first name right.
That's the first value.
We don't have to do it in order but I think it's a little bit more organized to do it in order and we
can assign a variable right away to that value and we can use our one of our helper methods.
Not meant as functions to clean this up so we can say clean and now we can remove any unwanted characters
from there.
All right and this is the dove the method that we are going to be using going to separate is a little
bit.
This is the technique we're going to use for all of them.
I believe we have like five of them so I'm going to copy and paste a couple of times and I'm going to
start from the left to right.
And if you find you can you know pause a video into yourself and see if you've got the same thing last
name and paste that in here.
I hope you see my method there.
All right.
The next one will be user name.
Copy this.
You don't.
It doesn't have to be the same.
But like I say I like to make it the same.
Remember these other values coming from the form coming from this value Neema from the is the value
of these attribute name right here.
The postal Biglow is going to pick up these value and that's what we're getting right here.
All right.
And then we can assign many variable name if we wanted to.
But we are signing this one.
You guys already know that but I just want to make sure that for some reason if one of you join these
cause and don't know much about it to learn something but remember that you should only be here if you
know basically.
And this is basic BHB password.
All right.
And then we copy this one here see how easy this is.
Once you get everything in place.
Now we have to purge the mail entities there all the time and that's not a very good password.
Let's just call it confirm password.
That's big.
Let's go to the registration that BHP raised that BHP make sure that this field is the same confirmed
park pass we're not sure.
All right so it is the same.
Make sure that yours is the same Morais right here.
All right we save it and we are ready to go to the next phase.
All right so in the next lecture we are going to actually do some evaluation here and make sure that
these are the the type of size that we want and they are we do certain things and there now we do certain
things.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture on the next lecture.
We'll continue with this functionality.
Take care.