All right welcome back my students.
I hope you're really excited.
We are learning something really cool here.
And when this is finished you're going to have are you going to have a full complete application.
Really events really secure really flexible.
We're going to be pretty cool.
You're going to be learning how to do this.
Pretty soon you're going to know everything.
But anyway.
So once we pull out the values from the form and we clean them up a little bit then it's time for us
to check them.
So we could say something like this and we can use a pre-built BHB function SDR Lenn to check how many
characters each of these is.
So for example if we want to find out this is
the size of this we'll write this we put the first name inside this function.
And now this function is going to have the amount of characters that the user puts in this input field
right here.
So if I put three characters that is going to be equal to three.
All right.
So I'm going to say if this is equal to three That's more than three.
I want you to go.
No you like this.
For example I'll show you just to show you.
So I'm going to put it equal to two because that is less than 3.
Email
Cliggott.
And now says no.
Well of course we're not going to this play.
No what I want to do is that I want to set a variable to contain a value a set default a default size
value for my minimum minimal function ID and my maximum functionality what I mean with that is that
if the first name is less than a certain quantity I want it to display an error.
So any fees over a certain quantity I want it to also display an error.
So I'm going to set this like this.
The minimum is going to be three and the maximum is going to be 20 for example like this.
And then we're going to display an error.
But for that I also won an array.
Then I use an array to save all the errors and they have the end of this validation.
I'm going to display all the arrows that we encounter when we were validation of validating.
So this is going to be an empty array like this.
Right.
So if this is less than men then we have a problem right.
Let's say your first name
first name can not be less than.
And I do this curly brackets because I want to you don't have to.
This is for complex operation.
When you have double cause you can put this curly brackets and you can do great if you want but I like
to it like this.
That way I can know that this is a variable.
And it's very it's it kind of helps me distinguish words from variables.
But anyway your first name cannot be less than minimum characters or example like that.
Right of course.
Like I said I wanted to save this into my array.
So I don't do it like this.
All right.
Now that this is like this I want to actually write a function real quick here.
I'm going to check to see if my arrays empty now empty.
Then we know we have an error right.
So if he's 90 I'm going to loop through that array and display each individual value.
So I look through errors as error
this and aquittal.
All right
ladies.
All right.
Let's go into this real quick.
Let's see what happens.
Refresh Ponzo river anjing.
Make sure there's an e-mail.
Register your first name can be less than three characters.
But if we wanted to now we do this to the last name and you'll see that we have a function out of today's
really flexible.
Right.
And we can say the last name here and watch this.
And it's going to there's no one to want to
register.
And now we get both messages your first name cannot be less than three characters and your last name
cannot be less than three characters.
Of course we have to fix the how this looks but you can understand now how this is going to work and
we're going to do that for user name right and then we're going to do something different we pass one
confirm.
But I just wanted to show you how to do that.
Another thing is if you wanted to show to also learn how to do this by how to check for empty spaces
is super simple as well.
All right.
We can say something like this.
F and D.
And I'm not going to be using this but I'm going to show you how to do it.
If you don't know a first name is empty then we do something like we'll say the error in the array and
we when we can say your first name can be empty.
All right like this if you want to go ahead and do that.
It's up to you.
I already have some H the m l 5 validation.
That's good for me.
All right.
So if you want to go adding that extra layer of validation is up to you on the next lecture.
We're going to complete this.
And I want you to create a validation for user name.
Oh and another thing is that if we go over of course.
All right.
So this is what I want you to do in the next lecture and I take this out on one this.
So we're we are checking for first name and last name for the minimum I want you to create the same
thing here in this in-thing for this one but checking for maximum value right and displaying a correspondent
string something that corresponds to a max value functionality.
All right so in the next lecture I want to see that.
And we're going to compare code to see if they are the same or right.
Pretty easy stuff.
But I want you to start coding right.
Thank you so much and I see you in the next lecture.