All right welcome back my students.
The Last Lecture I should I actually challenge you to do a simple task basically was to complete this
right to do the math and minimum of all of them.
And also you can use do the username.
All right.
So I already completed mine you can compare your code right here.
All right for the math.
We changed that.
Less than symbol to a greater than symbol.
All right because we're seeing here now a first name is greater than math.
Then we have a problem right.
So let me show you how that one works.
So I'm just going to write some crazy string here.
Two and two
right now on this lecture we will show these in a better format.
But you see your first name cannot be more than 20 characters.
That's the first error.
And then your last name cannot be less.
You see my arrows are working 100 percent.
Now what I want to show you is that you can go to get Bushrod that come which is the Web site for the
framework that we are using.
And we can get some really cool components there.
Let me show you.
So this is Gebal sure that com let me see if I can click on to see SS and then Nye's not in the CSX
components and right of component you're going to go to alerts and write on alerts.
We're going to find this little guy right here that I like and copy this guy and instead of this plane
is really empty errors.
We're going to play some really cool errors.
I'll show you right now.
Single quotes because when I have a lot of stuff is going to have double quotes inside here and we don't
want that.
We want to take that off because we have some single coaching here that is breaking our mouth.
Well our BHB and they say this one here.
We just want to display there like this.
All right.
But anyway I'll show you a better way of doing this.
We can bring these down if you want.
I like that.
All right let's see if this works actually.
Let's check it out.
I don't remember if we single cause we can see the variable.
Let me make sure that it works.
Let's go to our form and I strive to display that real quick.
Make sure you save it right anyway.
Register.
OK.
It's not working with single cause but you can see the message right.
Pretty cool stuff.
Anyway you can make this work with single quotes and you can put a string in a variable inside single
quotes.
You can concatenate those like this.
That's why I like to use double quotes.
All right well we can do that because we have a lot of double quotes there.
So what we need to do is concatenate this.
We can break it like this and break it like this and then do this all right.
And now if we go back to it.
Whatever.
And 2.
Now you can see your first name cannot be more than 20 character and name thinking be less than three
characters.
Pretty cool stuff right.
We want to change the color of it.
All we have to do is change this class to from warning to danger.
All right.
So that way gives us like a little reddish color.
Now what I want to do something a little bit better than that to be honest with you.
I don't like this because I got to be concatenating here this if we had double costs like I said before
like this and you're going to see me using this a lot we can do we can put the very well writing side
without doing concatenation but we have a lot of double counting that we can do that.
So what I'm going to do is create something called a delimiter.
Actually
something like this the limmer you can put whatever name you won here.
But I call it the limiter.
But it does have a name and I from the top of my head right now forgot echo and delimiter BHP.
I forgot the name of it.
I forgot the name of it but anyway you read it like this.
You write your message in a variable you save all this in a variable and then you write whatever name
you want.
And we're just going to create the limiter here.
We put this less than symbols 1 2 and 3.
All right and then you write the same word again and you put it right at the end here and you put the
semicolon right there.
All right.
Now make sure you have more space here because if you do if you have some space this is not going to
be that is not going to work.
So I'm going to command zero control Z and you're going to see that now all we got to do here just echo
the message.
It does.
All right.
And you can pull whatever you want seeing with codes as you can see.
Look to that double cords or whatever you want.
All right.
Let's go in short in the form to see how we can make up.
And I write a really long string here a small one and my mind just went blank all the name of that functionality
to be honest so you register and right here your first name can be more than 20 character and your last
name can be less than three characters you see as working.
Now we came back when we went to the command Z I believe it is danger class that gives us a nice color.
Danger right here.
All right.
Let's try one more time because I want to see the color
go.
Go register.
There we go.
See that beautiful.
So this is working.
And I just show you another way of doing this.
Besides they're just using.
All right.
I think this is a better way.
And you can do whatever you want here.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.