All right welcome back my students.
So there are a couple more things that we need to do to finish this.
I know that we were almost finished but I think we should add some more functionality to our application
before we continue.
All right.
So what are the functionalities that we want to add.
Well very simple if we have a user name that is the same as the person that's typing it in the form
we don't want to register that person we don't want to register two people with the same username or
we don't want a race or two people with the same email address.
So let's go to our application.
I'm going to open another window here real quick if I can get to it in the register here.
Let's go to it.
Re-instill that BHB does have that available there.
All right.
So we want to actually give them an error if this exists or if this of the e-mail address is.
So let's go and make two functions that will help us with that.
All right so let's create the first function here.
Email exist and we can make it better late later.
But right now I think this is the best option you can come up with something better probably in the
future once you see me doing it.
All right.
So the first thing is that we get to say well we're going to get our Querrey going here we're going
to say select ID from
users where e-mail equals what their e-mail coming in right here.
What we need some single calls here email right now.
I'll show you how to do something real quick.
It's going to be.
It's going to be fun.
So let's use our Querrey function that we create in a DVD BHB Let's send it square.
And we save this square with whatever comes back in this resort.
All right.
So now we can say if row count and you know with is comment this is coming from this is another function
that we created right here in the BHB to count how many rows are coming back.
So ero count we got to passing the risotto equals one that means we got something from the database.
And what do we do if we got something we return true.
If not
we return
false.
Pretty cool stuff right.
Very easy to implement.
And you know what we can implement almost ascending for username.
So we copy and paste that one and we'll just change the name here user name change the variable here
to a user name.
And change is here to use a name and change this to username.
Super simple right can really can be simpler than that.
So now we can use is right below here when we are checking for email first we check the email just
so we say if email exist and we pass in the mail.
All right.
Well
we can display an error right here the errors
sorry that email already exist is register
right.
And for the user name copy the same thing here and we create something for the user name.
Real quick
if user name I just
repassing the user name right here and then we say Sorry that user name
is already taken.
Right.
Let's check it out real quick.
All right.
So we know that in the end it's you my admin.
We already have an e-mail called Etling according fact with the dot com or whatever e-mail you are using.
I got to use the name of Rico.
Let's check it out real quick to see if this works right.
So let's go to the register that BHP refresh this and I'm going to use one D.S. username.
We go an email address Edwyn and quoting faculty that come that way you e-mail that exists.
I want those two arrows.
1 2 and 3 1 2 and 3.
So we got to make this fail and this failed that the register.
So that user name is already taken.
Sorry that e-mail is registered your e-mail cannot be more than 20 characters.
I think this is wrong.
Let's check it out.
The email one.
All right we messed up on the e-mail
SDR lenth
is.
I don't think we can measure that e-mail right there.
That was a very small e-mail let me see.
Should that it is longer than 20 character because it's there.
So emails are different.
We don't want to mess around with e-mail.
Let's just do a minimum for the e-mail.
All right.
Like this.
But you do minimal.
But anyway
you're going to have to probably set a max for him.
E-mail a lot longer than 20 characters.
Maybe something like 50 characters for e-mail.
But anyway as you can see we were able to display was available and was not available.
Rico last we're one two and 3 1 2 and three.
I'm going to use another
e-mail address just to display one error register.
Sorry that user name is already taken.
You see that beautiful.
Anyway hope you see how this is going.
I think we're done with this functionality for now for validating.
And now what we need to work on is on the register user function that registers the users and inputs
all these data in the database right in the Users table.
Thank you so much for watching.
Hope you are enjoying this very much like I am joined to teaching to you and I hope you I wish you the
best in life.
Just make sure that you always always practice practice practice and learn learn learn.
See you in the next lecture.