All right.
Welcome back.
Am I the student.
So now in the last lecture we wrote all this code here and we are detecting if we find a roll with this
same e-mail and when the validation that we're getting from there you are.
Pretty cool stuff.
And we find one we chose a queen a success message book.
We can do that unless we first date the user right.
So let's make a Querrey real quick here and Elisha's create a query real quick to update the user to
unlock the active state.
Right.
So we're going to say of the users and we're going to set active column active equal to 1.
And we're also going to grab the validation call the call on we're going to send it to zero because
we don't need it anymore.
They're users active and we're going to need a body they can call later.
When we are doing something else right when we are validating you know maybe a forgotten password or
something like that.
So now we're going to do that zero where email is equal to email and we're going to concatenate here
because we are going to be scaping this and you could write a scale function even when you do your Querrey
and your helper functions if you want to do that.
So that way every data you put in here is already scaped even before you put it.
I like to do like this because I like to show you how he's done as well.
But if you want to go ahead and do it escape it before it comes to this area here you can so that what
you how to do what I'm doing concatenating here all the time.
All right.
So now this is a female so we need some single quotes around it.
And that's about it.
That's all we're going to do here.
Nobody can actually.
They use a segue active where everybody they called actually said users active and then they go to zero
away e-mail equals they e-mail and we can make this a little stronger as well and we can say and the
validation code equals the variable and it's concatenated as well.
To escape it and we're going to say validation code.
And this is this right here.
All right.
So beautiful.
It should be very strong right now and I'm going to grab this and paste it right here and we can say
you know what we saw too.
So that way we can distinguish these two and rescue two and two.
All right.
All right perfect.
Now we can decode the message right.
But I said that we were going to have probably said this in some type of session before right.
So let's do that let's just said this thing.
A session has a message like this.
And we don't need to pass these paragraphs.
They write
do we.
Let's look at the message
display message it's just echoing in the masses like that so we might need that
paragraph.
That's OK.
All right.
But then after they sending the message we want to redirect the user to logon log in BHP.
And what we want to do is that on logging that BHP we want to use the other function that displays a
session.
So let's go to log in and right here.
All right.
Remember I have a container with a class of row that's just a rows is going to separate.
This row this container or this element from this row right here.
This class is in Bootstrap separate content array which is separate into a different area.
And this will make it 50 percent on all the media Querrey.
All right.
Anyway let's use and I have a really good course on Bushrod by the way is a very short course it we
show you the basics here.
We're going to use a function that displays session if it's set.
All right so now let's try this.
We go all these parameters here as a matter of fact.
I already have it here but I got attached to as well.
All right.
I'm going to copy it and this is this guy right here one and we got his validation code.
He's active he's active right now he's at zero.
All right.
So if we go here and we type that in Enter we have an error on expected down 371.
Let me check on this real quick.
Three seventy one.
We have one expected.
Oh we forgot the semicolon So we're here with the not 371 set message your cause being activated Please
log in and oh we forgot this parentheses.
Let's check to see and BHB my admin if this account was activated or ready refresh and is as being activated
so I didn't go through.
Let's do it again.
All right.
Enter your account has been activated Please login and he takes us to the log in that BHB page.
All right let's go here let's refresh and look at it.
If you're if you see right now you see the difference the validation code is zero.
And they act active stay active.
Call them is set to 1.
All right.
Beautiful
beautiful All right.
So we were able to change that on the user and we're doing pretty good.
So in the next lecture we're going to continue building on this and we're good.
Oh by the way if it doesn't find a resoled.
All right.
That means that something went wrong here.
That means you couldn't find the user so we can set another message here saying something like
we're going to set this to danger and we're going to say your account
sorry
your account
cannot cannot be activated.
All right.
And we can take this person to Mavie to log in that BHB that's OK.
If for some reason the e-mail address.
So let's try to do it now again because the e-mail exists already so it would try to do the activity
to see if I have it on.
Here is the story.
Your account going to be active cannot now be activated.
All right.
Perfect.
So he's working good and you can modify it and make it better on your own terms.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.