All right welcome back my students.
So it's time for us to go and build this logging system so let's look at it.
First let's look at a call so let's open our editors Let's see what we need.
We first need some type of validation right.
We have a validation we're ready for our registration system.
So our whole system is going to be very similar but we're going to have less inputs to deal with.
So let's go ahead and open the browser and let's see what we need.
If we go and click on logon we go to the logon that BHB page and we have two inputs here used to validate.
All right and you can do whatever you.
If you want to validate with BHB You are welcome to but these inputs are already validated where the
male 5 would require attribute just like I showed in the past.
But you can of course validate them with an empty functionality that I showed you how to do in PH.
Right.
And we can validate them with minimal emet if we wanted to.
I'm not going to deal with that on this lecture here I'm going to do the empty one just because the
email is very hard to validate an email with a lot of character C.
We might use some other advanced validations in the future.
But right now are actually five validation is good enough for these two fields.
So let's do some empty validation and PSP and let's put some arrows from here on top let's make sure
that we have that in place.
So let's go back.
All right.
So we got this value they use a registration going to copy this actually and right below here this is
active user.
Let's put let's fix this a little bit.
And you're going to punch in Little coming down here would be nice.
Let me take it from this function right here.
Right.
And they either Logan
All right so first let's see if this works so I'm going to do an echo here real quick and let's grab
the value they use or logon and let's go to log in that BHB And let's look at it.
All right.
We have already we already displaying a message here.
No.
PH be right below here and going to
put my call at function.
All right.
One thing that I want you to make sure is that on pages like ad man you can if you won you can put your
pages like admin pages that have this little container here you can put that display message there just
in case you one to display some sessions in the future.
Right.
But if you want a way for me that's OK but if I forget make sure that you have remember that this display
a function here is the one displaying the messages there the session messages.
But anyway now that we have that in place when I save it.
Let's go back and let's see if it works ok.
Oops for one functions.
Where did I forget this time.
Curly brackets right here.
All right.
That's not it may seem to do to the downturn.
F
line for one of our next showing.
There we go.
All right.
So there's this and it works.
All right so we're getting something out of it.
Beautiful.
All right.
So we got the mini match there but we're going to we're not going to use that let's see if we can grab
some of these values as well from here.
We won the e-mail on the box where I believe that's the only two fields that I have here email and password.
OK.
We grab that we
scaping.
This is Razor actually is escaping it we should clean it right here.
Can I grab this too.
And instead of scaping I'm going to clean it.
All right.
Beautiful.
So once we clean it and we have these validation in place then let's get the rest of it
right errors right.
Right let's check for the e-mail on the password.
So we already have one here for.
No let's do MT actually let's make up some new ones.
So I'm going to make some new
with this a little bit more this way.
And we go let's create a new one let's just say it's empty.
Email.
I'm going to use the errors array.
I was going to say email field cannot be empty.
All right.
And this would be password.
We're not going to do else right now but because else would be the function.
But let's just say no errors here just to make sure this is working even though it's not going to work
because we have those required fields anyway.
But
we should see something with errors or errors if we type this correctly no errors.
All right.
Perfect.
All right so now that we have some type of validation in place I think this is good for now.
All right we need to log in the user.
All right.
Now I want you to remember something we have a functionality that we are going to be adding here pretty
soon.
And is this session functionality this cookie functionality basically when we click on remember me we
want this application to remember us because right now the way this works is if we close our browser
right and we are able to log in but we close our browser and we are still looking to our application
when we open the browser again I'm going to ask us to log in again is going to forget about us.
So in the future we're going to remember the functionality I'm going to explain to a little bit more
later but right now what we need to do is log in the user and then we start working on this functionality
a right because that's kind of extra for now.
All right.
So.
So on the next lecture we're going to start working on the log in user functionality.
And then once we log in the user then we're going to start working on this remember me and we're going
to start working on the Forgot Password functionality.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.