All right welcome back my students on the last lecture we created this functionality right now to select
the password and the idea from users where the email is the same as the e-mail that we're getting right
here right now.
So I told you that we need to pull the password from the database so that way we can use our five function
to be coded so that we can compare it with password from the form because if we try to do it like days
just comparing the password from the D.B and the form without using them the FI function is not going
to work because we need to decode it ways in encrypted remember that.
All right.
So I'm not going to work like that so let's let's do it with them.
The five function.
All right so now that we have are we getting the password.
The idea here and we're getting something here we know that the user exist right.
We know that we're finding those but let's go ahead and do something here so we we are fetching here
but what we really need to fetch is not as well we need to fetch the result.
So we need to change this to resort like this.
That way we can get the real password out.
All right.
So if I had this to ask you in the last lecture make sure that you have a right to have to be salt.
So let's do this.
I hope you're having a lot of fun this is really fun.
So we're going to use them the fire in the if statement.
All right because then the fight is going to return either yes or no if we if we are able to match it.
So a password from the form the code that he coded is equal to the password then we are golden.
Right.
Then we can just return TRUE
else.
We just you know what we turn false but we're going to do a little bit more than that.
I just want to show you that it works right.
False.
There we go.
So let's go ahead and try it.
I already have a user here that's called one and I think he's passed.
Password is 1 2 3 from the form but you can see here that he's already encrypted and this user is activated
now right.
Make sure he's activated because we're checking for those things.
All right.
Actually we're not checking for those to make sure that you are.
I don't know if you are.
Maybe I did on The Last Lecture and I took it all from this one.
But make sure that it is an active equals one.
I think I already did in the last lecture and for some reason I took it off.
Right.
OK let's try this.
Now let's go back to it and let's just do the e-mail one.
One two and three.
Logan oops unexpected 5:22.
What could that be.
Now I don't remember.
Right here there's a little guy right here.
See the 5:22 right here.
So put a semicolon there if you don't have it.
All right let's refresh.
Let's try it again.
1 1 2 and 3.
Log in.
Oops on point two and three logon.
There we go.
So it's working all right.
So if we had the wrong password doesn't work let's just try with the wrong password just in case just
to make sure we won and is just Dreisinger stuff log in and you can see that he says your credentials
are not correct.
So even our credentials arrows are actually popping up.
Really cool stuff right.
Really a flexible.
All right.
So this is beautiful like this right.
Now on the next lecture we're going to build and we're going to build a function that would take care
of the logging for us right.
We already know that we are logged in but we need to actually record this in a session so that when
we can detect it from other places in our protection we don't want to just depend on a static function
IP where he'd allow us to log in.
But then he doesn't remember us.
We need to actually let our application know that we are logged in and if we are logged in it should
allow us to be anywhere in our application.
If we're not logged in the shooting allow the user or the administrators of course Bill to that place.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture I hope you're having a lot of fun and learning
a lot of stuff and I'll see you in the next one.
All right.
Take care.