Welcome back my student.
So this is working really good for us for now.
Now we need to go to our core that Ph.D. page and make some validation there.
We're got to work on the arrows here later on you know displaying some things.
Now if we are able to actually send an email to the user we want to be able to display something here
like check your email or anything like that.
Right.
Right now we try to do this one game all we get.
Actually it's a great speired.
That's why he's doing that to us.
So let's go here real quick.
And as you can see
if he's already inspired a cookie cookie
is getting a redirect.
So he cannot detect it talking or he had a session talking.
All right.
So let's go to that we cover page recover HP.
There we go.
Anyway let's do this one.
That e-mail come
right e-mail cannot be sent.
This is the only thing that we are getting here.
All right.
Now when this is sent we want to redirect the user somewhere else right.
And maybe instead of having the user here we can just redirect them to him that says something and say
you know what.
Go check your e-mail for an activation.
We don't want to keep the user here.
So I'm just wanted you to see that we can do this detective the e-mail was sent or not but really we
want to reiterate these are somewhere else.
Right.
So
let's do that let's if they e-mail was not it was not sent.
We're is not going to do anything but
we're going to redirect anyway.
All right.
So we can use this if not send e-mail
back and I'll show you right now.
That helps
right.
All right.
Let's do it.
Let's do a smarter right time like this.
And you see that same thing shorter code.
Right.
So not saying email we do this but in reality this is going to work anyway.
So what we want to do is redirect the user.
So let's redirect that right here.
We're going to send a message first.
We have a function to do that.
And
let's put some paragraphs here.
All right let's give it a class of maybe B.G. said Sas
and say please check your email.
Your your spam folder or spam folder for an activation
password reset.
You see that's what we're doing right here right.
Cold.
All right.
And then we're going to redirect the user to.
And that's something like that.
All right.
So please check your e-mail.
E-mail or spam folder or password reset code and shoot me.
I think we already had this thing in that BHB we displayed the message there so let's check it out quick.
That works.
G-mail the
please check your email was about for the four we said cold.
All right that works.
Let's just put it's on top of
that center.
Just make that call a little bit more straight of course we refresh that's not going to work.
But anyway we know it works.
We're sending a message we're redirecting the user.
Beautiful.
All right.
So now that we got that done let's go and work on the function that is going to detect all this real
quick.
All right.
All right here
called validation.
So this page here is called validation function.
We got to think about what it's going to do.
All right.
What is the best approach.
First we need to check to see if we are able to access if the cookies set basically the tab is called
Cookie.
So that's the first thing that when we need to check here because if it's not said We don't want that
person to be here.
So Tim as we said then we do whatever we have to do.
If not we will wrecked
and we redirect to where the recovery is so they can do it again will recover that BHP Well we set up
some type of message here and we say that message right.
And let's just get something from here let's just grab this guy right here so we don't have to write
that again.
All right.
And we can just say
sorry your buddy nation cookie was expired.
And we might want to do something else.
I want to go into the database and give him a different validation cold or something like that.
I.
Well that's fine.
Let's do it like this.
So if the cookie is set then we also want to check to see if we're getting anything from the server
like any get requests right.
So would a server get the request method calls to get
my.
And then here we can check to see if it's said
We're doing a lot of the nation.
But this is very good.
All right.
Don't get scared the more the better.
And he said code.
Remember we're getting those parameters as well.
And we want to do something with this person.
All right.
So in the next election we continue with this but we've got to test it and make sure that everything
is valid.
And if he's now that of course we're going to redirect the user somewhere and tell him.
But right now we're doing good.
We are doing very good if you're following me.
Very good.
Pause the video if you have to when I'm doing it too fast and make sure that you understand every step
that we're doing here.
I'm doing a little faster now because by now you should know this.
All right.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.