All right welcome back my student.
So we got all these verifications here right.
Why don't we just check it out before we write any more code.
Let's see if this is working right.
Let's go to our cold BHB and make sure that you got your function that you're calling your function
right here right.
So let's make sure that we are putting this there and calling it is go back to functions and you know
what I want to learn and do I really I think we're making we overkill in this a little bit because we
would check if we get requests and then we are checking to see if some specific request is set.
Let's just take this off here.
That way we got less cold here.
And if email and code get requests I said we'd do something we can also do this if they're not set.
All right.
And we can also do.
Let me see we can also do an else f here and check to see if they're empty right.
So else if I get requests is empty and I mean with just a little bit you know I like to do this like
this is personal reference I think it would be good for you to also do this.
All right.
If it's empty or cold it is empty then we do certain things right.
Right now we're doing that we go.
All right so if we're not getting anything set we're going to redirect to that baby or something like
that.
All right.
I'll do this right here as well.
Else I mean something is good right.
I mean it's good.
We can do something here we could check to see if the port is set.
All right so I'm post
code is set.
If it's said then we are going to be doing some really cool stuff here.
All right.
So don't get confused by all this if statement.
Just make sure that you have that correct.
All right.
We just want to make sure that all this is good this is copulated validations there that we need to
verify.
But anyway let's just say getting post from form here.
Now if we go back our attempt at this code is going to be expired so we're going to probably go here.
All right.
So let's go to our call that BHP is opening up a little bit.
And let's go this is a reset page.
I don't know why we are there but I go to court BHB and we got some errors here and 670 to expect inspector
curly bracket 670 to doing
that because we're missing one of these and.
All right let's do it now.
There we go sorry your validation cookie was ex-spy of course one and probably say something else.
Now any nation cookie maybe validation code or something like that but we'll fix that later if we have
to or change it right.
Anyway let's just get something for one female dot com Antar and.
All right.
Perfect.
So now let's go to our call that CHP and now we were able to access it.
All right.
So if we type something here continue it says getting posts from the form from form and this post code
that P.H. this code right here is coming from the form from the input right here in code that BHB.
All right.
Perfect.
So if we're getting that we can clean that up a little bit.
Right.
We can also clean this up a little bit as well here if we're going to use it later.
But all right so let's.
Of course we've got to clean this up a little bit.
That would be nice.
We can use a function.
Clean it up a little bit just in case we've got some crazy characters there and just call this validation
code on validation code like this.
All right that's perfect.
All right.
So now what are we going to do.
Well we got to make some queries happen here.
All right so let's say first of all we need to find out this code existe and compare it to what we have
in our database table.
So let's say select ID from users where validation code
because there's validation calls coming in.
But we are going to scape it just in case.
One edition called there we go.
We can make a little bit more secure and we can get
the get request right here as well.
All right.
So we can clean this up a little bit.
And
I guess next hour will work for us.
We get e-mails as well.
All right.
So where validation code equals
and email because they e-mail skate of course.
All right let's see if we get some type of resort with this.
All right with cleaning it up and we are also scaping.
So what do we do with a lot of work here.
Hopefully this will work for us.
If not we'll fetch you don't worry.
So let's so let's do it here let's send it in
and let's also confirmed
beautiful.
You can probably put this confirmed inside the Querrey function and that way you don't have to be confirming
all the time.
So you can go to your D-B that BHB right here but the equerry actually we are confirming.
I don't even know why we keep doing this.
So we are confirming we don't even have to confirm it guys.
All right.
So we just do overkilling that real reality.
So whenever you have a confirmed take it off.
We don't need it anymore.
You probably were asking me asking yourself why is he confirmed every time he's doing inquiry.
But anyway I'm going to take that off from the rest later.
But right now we're good.
All right.
So anyway once we have this is being confirming everything is being sent and all we have to do is check
to see if we have it.
So if Roe count
is equal to one that we're good to go we found something right.
And then we can redirect the user to our we said page by page B page else we can display some bad validations
so we can go validation errors and we can say something like
Sorry wrong validation code.
So onto later.
All right.
So I'm going to leave it the way it is right now on the next lecture will test this and see where we
at.
And to see if it works.
Right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture.
I'm so glad you are here my course.
And if you have any questions you can ask me all the time anytime and I'll be try to answer your question
as soon as possible.
See you in the next lecture.
Take care.