Welcome back my students.
So it's time for us to take our application to the web.
Now I always recommend my top company for hosting.
Now you don't have to have a hosting right now.
You can just watch this lecture see or learn how to do this.
But if you're curious to find out how to do this with a live server what company is the best then I
can only recommend one company and that is.
If you go to the US DOT com that's my personal web site and you go to resources right here I have a
special link for my students.
This link was provided to me by Go Daddy.
And basically this link will give you.
All right.
Crazy crazy discount is going to give you coasting for $1 a month.
It's going to give you a free domain and you're going to have C-SPAN installed which is a software that
we use to do a whole bunch of things.
All right.
And we set it up like this.
We click on the first one and it says for one domain there but don't worry about it because in one domain
we can set up multiple applications just by using folders.
We know that right.
So what you can say something like this.
Right.
This is how we can set it up and I'll show you right now that this is really truly an amazing thing.
We get it for 12 hours and 18 cents.
All right.
Pretty cool stuff right.
And then they also have we saved like 86 dollars.
That's what they saying.
If we are new we click here and we write our information and then we can even use paypal.
We want to.
All right.
And we don't even have to use our credit cards.
Pretty cool stuff.
Anybody would do this.
So anyway that's why I recommend going to logon right now because I want to show you logging in there
on the screen because I don't want you to see my information and now because I don't trust you.
It's just because I don't know you.
So that's the whole reason why I'm doing this.
All right.
So don't get upset with me if I'm doing this you know this side.
That's OK.
All right.
So anyway I'm logged in right now.
Once you log in you click on view my account with Go Daddy Go Daddy I think once you pay and they got
to send you your credentials by e-mail as well.
But once you pay you can you're looking automatically and you look for my account and web hosting you
have some tasks like this and you click on web hosting manage right here and ask them to tell you listen
go to your.
You want to go to your see band or you're going to say oh yeah sure let's manage it.
And then we're going to go to a see panel right here and this is where the magic happens is a whole
bunch of things that we can do.
All right.
You can set up FTB accounts or you can log in to their to your applications or have somebody the people
game can set up application.
One click has a whole bunch of things.
Some companies are charging big money for this and Bill within my special link that I have on my web
site for you you only going to get charged $1 a month.
But anyway.
So I'm going to go to file manager because this is where I have this is where everything is.
Now some of the applications are under this same domain.
Right.
As you can see right here.
So I'm going to create a new folder.
As a matter of fact
let's compress everything.
So I'm going to compress everything right here and I'll show you in a minute.
We have this log in here and I'm just going to compress it.
I'm going to right click and compress it is using my Mac and compressing everything.
As a matter of fact I'm going to compress everything here.
Sorry about that.
And it's going to be called archive.
OK that's fine archive.
And then I delete this one.
If you are using Windows you can just right click and zip it using some application there from windows.
They we also have I think 7 zip is an application that you can use to zip it seven zip.
It does seem that you can use this which is free is a program that will zip the files for you just sipping
it so that way I can make it smaller so that I way I can upload it.
All right.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a for there here I'm going to click folder because I
mean my root directory and that's where I want to be on public that underscore the mail create a full
they're going to call this logon underscore score app
and create a new folder and my logging app right here.
So now I'm going to go in overload that file.
All right.
So then I say oh load.
I'm going to choose where I want to load my find my logging app and is inside logging archive.
Open
all right so that's complete.
Another thing that we need to do is we need to go to the database.
So let's go to the HP my admin
and let's go to Logan underscore logging logging to underscore the users let's just click on the logo
on this court TV and export.
All right so it's exported.
I'm going to put it in my desktop
right here I'm going to come back to my SEE panel right.
This is their home page of my C panel and then I'm going to go to my databases that I raised with her
I'm going to create a new database I'm going to call this mine.
On this whole login app the B and then not copy this because I'm going to need this information later
and I paste it here and I'm going to put some comments database set up.
All right.
Next step
right.
And use a name.
Mind you Logan pap user Whoops.
He's going to call this guy my logging user that's fine.
And I make sure that I put him here.
And just going to put the baby name in there
when I hear.
But here
and
here.
OK.
And then the pass we're going to use a password generator.
They're going to copy it.
I have copy it and use password good create user.
Now I'm going to put a password right here password.
All right.
Beautiful.
So I'm going to say all privileges and next step.
All right as has been completed on the next lecture we're going to hook it up.
All right so we're going to connect it and make sure everything is working and test our applications
is going to be pretty cool stuff.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.