All right welcome back my students.
So there is something that I would like to change here and the application so I'm going to go to where
we can find an already old data.
All my code here.
So I got all those links that are being sent in the email I got to replace with the local host.
I got to replace with my web site that I'm using.
All right so what I want to change is this.
If not send e-mail.
I want to change that.
And I just want it because I know he's working to use me.
And I just want to change that.
All right.
I wanted to show that in the local hall.
But right now I don't want to show you here.
All right so we change stay here and we make sure that we change it in the live server.
For those of you that have this in the life server or I so remove that.
And this is the good one.
Here are some things to make sure and save it.
All right.
Beautiful.
Make sure that you put your comments here right guys.
So this is the function that BHB the server.
By the way right there is where all our function is anyway.
Thank you so much for watching.
And that's all I wanted to change and this one here and you know the more we change things the better
we make or our application.
So if you have any suggestions you're welcome to let me know.
Take care.
See you in the next lecture.
How fun.