Welcome back my students so in the last lecture we starting started to set up this configuration here
for BHB mater and this lecture we're going to go to a male trap.
I hope you register already.
And I got a free account you can see here.
Nothing much.
And I'm going to grab my username
and I'm going to place it right here.
Let's go back and get the password.
Simple as that.
OK.
There's not much else that we need here.
Let's see.
So we got the hose.
We got this.
I always like to have this lake somewhere down here.
I like to have my meaning formation on top.
So we got the hoes who got to use a name.
The port
true to your list that's fine.
We got the subject the body.
You know what.
You know what I like to actually set.
Where is that e-mail coming from.
That's something.
So bring porn right.
So I think they do have a set.
From there we go.
Now I'm going to say it's from courting faculty OK.
And I even put my name here I think as the second parameter that works very good for not mistake it
should be good.
I haven't used it in a while since I got this set up with templates and all that stuff and I use a lot
of frameworks but that's because I know what I'm doing Guys if you are new to BHB I don't recommend
using a framework right away OK.
Working at an address here and at
that could be whatever address is coming through.
Basically that is the recipient.
And so I have this tool here.
What else.
As you can see the method to my the they are actually highlighted in green.
OK.
And the properties are just white.
So I got the subject I got the body I got some body is for non HD mail clients if you want it if you
want that you can have it that's fine.
So now this looks like our Mac function is ready to send a e-mail.
OK so now everywhere we have this we can send an e-mail right.
Well let's try this is actually create some type of test file you know are Logan somewhere.
So let's see if let's see
that BHP let's open these
and let's include our functions right.
So require
to remember where it is is and where it was and functions and then functions are BHB.
OK.
And what else we need we need the
we need to require super porn.
The vendor shows me autoload I would go to order low class
and now we can go ahead and send the email
and let's see the parameters that he has email subject in message.
So in reality we don't need to put this now because we are sending as you can see we've got all these
static tests here and and so on and so on.
And
I know I'm going to send everything
static for now because we're I'm going to be doing later on is going to be setting up a classes directory
with a class sign that we're going to be required because that's where we're going to be putting our
configuration.
We don't want to put configurations in the function files.
Ok so later on we're going to do that.
But for now which is going to do Tess G.M. whatever Right now we're just going to test things out and
see if they work.
OK.
So as a matter of fact I'm going to leave this to you.
Go ahead and try to make this work.
I want you to run through some issues maybe hopefully not but if you run through some issues try to
figure that out by yourself and I'll see you in the next election to see if we can get this to work.