Time will come back in this video we're looking at data structures and answering the question what is
a data structure and what are we going to be looking at a sample data structure here.
The first question to answer is Why are data structures important.
And we're going to be looking at that actually.
But just know that first and foremost even if you don't use many data structures in your job when you're
a software developer you are going to need data structures to get a job because most interviews are
about algorithms and data structures.
So this is an important topic not only because it's useful but also because you're going to need it
in the interviews.
If you do do any but nevertheless it's still interesting to know.
So a data structure is just a way to store data.
It kind of makes sense right.
We've looked at some ways to store data in a computer program.
I don't mean store data in a computer like a database would be but rather to store data in a computer
program.
We've looked at some such as the list before.
We've looked at a dictionary and when we've looked at the set which is actually another one.
So these are three ways that we can store data in a computer program and so far we've only looked at
those three.
However there's plenty more and different data structures exist because some are faster than others
or more suitable for some tasks.
We're going to look at an example of a data structure right now I'm going to give you some description
about this data structure and hopefully you'll be able to guess what the District structure is.
I'm going to have a list.
And in this list there are a few constraints.
When you add an element to the list it gets added at the end of the list so the new element becomes
the last element of the list.
When you remove an element the element gets removed from the beginning of the list so new elements come
in at the back.
Elements leave from the front.
What is the structure called that how is it called now.
I'll give you a bit more information now about this data structure.
We've got the data structure here.
This is your list right now.
It has I think 16 spaces maybe a bit less.
Doesn't matter.
And you have that first element there which is in orange and you're going to add a new element at the
end which is the first element in this case because there are none so far.
So the end of the list is the first element in this case.
So you and your element and then you going to add another one at the end.
And now the end now becomes the second element and then another one and another one and another.
Now when it comes to removing elements as I said they're going to be removed from the front.
So the first one to go is going to be the 15 which was the first one that we added right.
The first element we added was 15 and then at the end we added 31 and then at the end we have had 151
then 13 then 65 than 1.
So the first element we added was 15.
And that's going to be the first one to go because we remove from the start to remove the 15 then we
remove the 31 and so.
So once again the mystery the structure elements get appended at the end and elements get removed from
the beginning.
Take a couple of moments in front of gas try to relate this data structure to something that you might
see in the real world and you might come up with a name for it.
And if you don't don't worry
hopefully you will be able you were able to guess and the name of the data structure is at the Q.
And if you didn't get it now it's probably clicking just like in people an actual Q For example when
you queuing for the bank and the first person in the queue is going to be the first one leaving that
you and you when you join the queue you will join in at the end.
So they say the structure is called the queue and we can create this in programming.
We can create a list that has these constraints.
We can only add elements at the end and remove them from the beginning and why.
Why would you do that.
What would you use a Q.
I'm going to give you one example.
A web application under heavy traffic might use a Q to determine which requests to respond to first
.
For example say you have your Piscean application which is a web location like we made previously and
there's a million users going into your application at the same time.
But your application can only respond to 64 requests at any one time simultaneously.
So what you would do is you would say OK the first 64 people that entered the application I'm going
to answer their request first I'm going to give them my HDMI code first and then I'm going to get the
next 64 people and I'm going to give them HDMI code and then I'm going to get the next 64 people in
jail so that's a cue the people get put in a queue waiting for your application to respond to their
requests.
So the first request will get responded to first and then the second and so.
So you might see why a queue could be useful and there's plenty of other uses for queues cuter.
Probably one of the most used data structures right now.
Other common nigger structures apart from the queue are the stack which is similar to a queue but only
in reverse.
We're going to look about very soon.
The set which we've looked at already in Python and they are very easy to use.
They're used for calculating the commonality between different unique elements and also one important
one is the binary tree and we've actually used that when we were using Pascola sequel.
The indices in Potter sequel are constructed using binary trees and we're going to look at exactly how
they work and why they're useful.
Excuse me as well throughout the next few videos.
So thanks for watching.
Hope you learned something and I'll see you in the very next video.