One will come back in this video we're going to talk about classes in Python.
In the last section we created a program that allowed us to create students at marks to the students
and calculate the average marks and we make that and it works.
However there are a couple of things that could be improved.
And one of those things is this student data dictionary in general when you are modeling with data something
that could exist in real life.
It is best to use a class for that.
And here's the reason why using a class for these would be better than using a dictionary.
And the reason is using a class allows you not only to have properties and values for those properties
like we do here but also actions that the model can do.
Here's what I mean with this.
The student data has a name and a set of marks and inside a dictionary we've got values for the name
and values for the marks as well.
However we have a separate method used to calculate the average mark.
Now this method acts on the dictionary and therefore it would be ideal if we didn't have to tell it
which dictionary it is acting on.
What I mean with it is it would be ideal if I could do in this dictionary something like this.
Average mark and here put a method that when Rand
this doesn't work but put a method that when run calculated the average of the marks inside the dictionary
.
And what that would allow us to do is NOT have to go looking for the dictionary to calculate the average
of instead the dictionary itself would hold the ability to calculate to the average of itself and what
that simply means is that it simplifies the entire process instead of down here selecting the student
of which we want to calculate the average.
We could just say student calculate your own average and then it would print it out so it would simplify
things a bit.
Creating a class for the students is actually really simple and using and creating the classes is the
best way to learn about them.
So that's what we're going to be doing in this video what we're going to convert this program into a
program that uses classes because that's the best way for you to truly understand what I mean with what
I've just said in the last couple of minutes.
So let's do just that.
Let's create a class and that class is going to represent a student just like this dictionary here represents
a student.
We're going to create a class that represents a student as well.
So I'm going to create the class by saying class and then the class name.
So in this case a student and then a colon.
And here we can define what a student looks like now just like in this dictionary where we find that
it has properties of name and marks the class also has to define what properties a student has.
And we do that inside the special method which is underscore underscore in that underscore underscore
.
Notice these are two underscores separately there and this method gets called whenever we create a new
student of this type.
And what we type in say this method.
Let's just type that first and then I'll explain what it does is we'll say self dot name equals John
.
For example self dot marks equals an empty list.
So what this is doing is it's saying when we create a student it's going to give us essentially a new
new student data with the name John and the marks empty list.
It's not a dictionary however it is an object and they behave in pretty much identical ways.
The student object to the class also has properties just like the dictionary we've got name and marks
just like the dictionary has name and marks and the self just means the student that we aren't talking
about.
So for example we could have two one called John and one called Anna and self means John.
When we are in the context of John.
So let's use it.
That will surely make things clear.
This student data instead of creating a dictionary what we're going to do is say student OK.
Notice that we're not using the name just now and we're going to get exactly to how we can use the name
in a moment.
So student data is now a student object.
It is no longer a dictionary.
Now whenever we want to interact with one of the properties of an object we don't do it like we did
with a dictionary with a dictionary we had to access the keys using this square bracket notation but
with objects we use dot notation.
So it would be student dot marks dot a pen and similarly down here.
We're also accessing the property and it would also be the dot and here as well.
Here we're accessing the name of the student.
And once again it has to be that dot
and that's it.
That's the only places where we're accessing properties of the Shoot-In dictionary and we've changed
the dictionary to be an object now.
But notice that the students always have the name John.
So let's run the app and I'm going to add in you student and we're going to enter a name like Anna and
then we're going to print the student list and notice how we get John and the average market zero.
But we can add a mark.
We're going to enter zero and the market's going to be 90 and then we can print the list again and the
marks are there.
And that's really the student is called John because we've specified the name of the object self dot
name to be John.
However when we create a specific object like we do in here student and then open and close brackets
we can also specify that object's name we can specify properties to be passed to that object.
So we're going to put the name in here and then in the init method after cells we also put the name
in there and that gets passed in as a argument as we know.
And finally we can also use that.
So let's rerun the app now and add a new student like so.
And there we have Anna appearing because we've passed the name.
And when we create that object the name that we passed gets use.
Let's create another student just to make sure that that is working.
And when we print we get banner and then John it's important to realize now that the class the term
means the structure of the data and all of them of the thing that we're modeling in this case it determines
that it has a name and that it has marks.
But when we create an object that instantiates a new set of data and there we can specify a name for
that specific object and a set of marks for that specific object.
They are not shared amongst objects.
So what else can we do with this.
We've got a method calculate average mark which takes in a student object and then calculates the average
mark for that student.
Let's move this method away from here and instead put it inside the class because that's part of the
power of objects the object itself the student itself.
Like John or Anna can tell us their average mark so I'm going to define a method inside the student
do notice that that's indented to tell them that this is inside the class.
And now because the method is inside the class it has access to self and Self is the currently being
used object.
So we if we ask John for his average mock self not Marks is going to be Jones Marx if we ask Anna for
her marks or her average mark self-doubt market is going to be and as marks so we can use this generically
without worrying about which object we are talking about.
So what we're going to do here is get the calculate average market contents copy them put them in them
but now instead of Shoot-In dot marks we can refer to the current student so self-taught marks and that
would refer to John's marker and Asmara.
Or whatever students marks we're talking about and now we can delete calculate average marks from that
.
And now the more interesting part comes when we print the student details and we want to print the average
mark instead of doing this cumbersome calculate average mark and then passing in the students that we
want to calculate the average mark of we can just say student don't average mocke and that calculates
the average mark using the student's data and we know that because it uses self.
The aim of this video was just to show you what classes are and sort of the power of them.
But it is by no means a complete view on everything.
Object oriented programming related.
That's what we're going to be covering throughout the next section.
So please if you're not 100 percent sure on what I'm talking about don't despair.
Bear with me in the next few videos we're going to be constructing an app that uses classes from the
ground up we're not going to get started with any other code and we're going to build on that slowly
but for now I just wanted to show you what the relationship between a dictionary and a class can be
.
A dictionary can be used to store some data a class and objects can be used to store data but also to
perform actions on themselves.
And that's part of the power of objects.
Without further ado let's move onto the next video where we're going to be as I said building an app
that uses classes.
But starting from the ground up.
So what are you in the next video.