Find will come back in this section we're going to be talking about it.
And in this video about what is it.
Well normally when you write your code it is in your computer and then you keep writing and then you
keep writing and your code is progressing nicely and then suddenly your hard drive dies and you lose
everything.
I mean that's happened to everybody.
And it is never nice.
So what do you do you put it in Dropbox for example and then you have your code and Dropbox and whenever
you make changes in your laptop when you can be in your computer you overwrite the dropbox version and
so on and you do that for a number of days and then eventually you realize that what you've written
over the last five days is bullocks and it doesn't work.
So you want to go back to what you had five days ago but unfortunately you can't do that in Dropbox
because what it stores is the current version and it doesn't store a history of what it was like five
days ago.
So what can you do.
Well you can use something like a time machine on a Mac that saves versions every hour.
I'm sure there's something in Windows for that.
But what that does it is saves the entire disk every hour and now and at that moment sometimes I plugged
in my time machine disk on my computer and it's synchronized 90 gigabytes worth of stuff.
And just to keep your code safe you don't really need to be doing that.
So that's where it comes in.
It helps you solve both of those problems and a few more so get is a version control system and what
it does is whenever you make changes you can commit those changes to get.
And that saves a snapshot of those changes.
And then you can optionally upload them to a site for example get hub is a place where you can upload
your kit projects and there's a few others and that means that you'll get Project Safe in the cloud
.
So if your hard drive dies you get project is in get hub or there's a couple more like a bit bucket
and get lab you'll get product is safe so you can then buy a new hard drive and download your kit project
from the Internet.
Another thing that it does is because you can commit your changes whenever you make changes.
It also keeps a history.
So if you realize that for the past couple of days you've written things that don't work.
You can go back in time and you can go back to a specific snapshot of the code and that's nice and you
can also if you realize that in one specific snapshot you wrote something incorrectly.
You can go back and remove that snapshot or you know and backtrack a few snapshots.
There's a lot of things you can do with it which is why it's so nice.
And one more problem that I solved that you may not have had yet but nevertheless it is a large problem
is working together with other developers.
If you use Dropbox or you send your code developers zip files with your code they make some changes
you make some changes and there's a few people making changes at the same time synchronizing those changes
and making sure that everybody has the latest version of all the files becomes really difficult.
So get kind of solved or at least helps to solve that.
Now it is not a perfect system.
Nothing is but it works really well and is really popular.
And this wouldn't be a complete course if it didn't go into some of the ways that you can collaborate
with other people and not only collaborate but also showcase your projects and put them online for companies
that you're applying to for jobs to see.
And that's also important to get is going to allow you to upload your project to sites like good hub
and then make them public for companies to see.
You can optionally also contribute to projects that already R-IN get up and they are commonly known
as open source projects and you can also make sure your project safe in the cloud and you can also go
back in time if you write things incorrectly or you make mistakes and things like that.
So good is really useful and I would encourage you from this section onwards to always have all your
projects in get just because that means that companies can look at it.
They are safe.
You can go back in time and people can help you with them.
If somebody is looking for a project to contribute to in this section we're going to be looking at what
Gates is and how we can use it and and how we can use get hub to put our projects in there.
So without further ado I see you in the next what you