We'll come back in this video we're looking at how to create your get up repository.
The first thing you have to do is sign up pick a username and email address and a password and sign
up for get help.
I'm going to just sign in into my profile
and then you will be received with something like this.
Naturally you may not have this history on the left all these repositories that you've contributed to
or your own repositories it'll all be empty but that's OK.
Let's go into a new repository.
And here you can choose a repository name.
This should be descriptive about what your project does.
So for example it could be a sequel analytics app for example.
And here you can write a description if you want.
Finally whether it is public or private.
Initially you may want to send it to private while you do some work on it and then change it to public
later on if you want people to be able to see it or you can just leave it as public from the beginning
.
And that way everybody can see that sort of work you're doing on it.
Finally you can also initialize the repository with the read me.
And if you do this then sort of the stuff we've done already with Kate gets a bit nullified.
To some extent not not really but to some extent.
Let's not do that and we're going to go into creating a read me over the next few years.
Finally just press create repository
and then you get some information
you can create a new repository.
You can push to an existing repository or you can import code from another report.
Let's forget about this option and look at these two to create a new repository on the command line
.
We've already seen how to do this with get in it and then they do a bunch more things like create a
read me File.
We're going to look at that and then they do commit and then they do a couple more things to add this
sequel analytic app repository as the remote repository will look at that as well or from an existing
repository which we have then we could just do the last two options.
This is how you create the repository in get and we're going to be looking at the next steps in the
next few over the years.
I'll see you there.