Homework and back in this video we're going to be creating a menu for our app and this menu method is
going to be the longest method out of all of the ones we've created so far.
And it's going to allow us to interact with a user or rather for the user to interact with the app that
we've made.
Lance first of all create a method called menu and that is going to actually execute a program let the
user interact with the program.
So what we want the user to be able to do is add a student to student list
and also add a mark to each student and print a list of students and also probably exit the application
.
So these are the four different choices that the user might want to do.
And we have to make a menu in such a way that it allows them to do everything here.
Now I think you can do nearly everything that's in here except for this one.
And we're going to go into why you can't do exactly that one just yet.
But what I would recommend once again pause if you and think about how you might want to structure this
menu so that when we move on and I start showing you how I would do it you've got some sort of baseline
that you can compare your thought process against mine.
And that way it will help your learning.
So I would recommend porting given a bit of thought if you want to implement it by all means go ahead
and then then we can move on and it will be a lot better
once that's done.
And I hope that you manage to maybe implement something or at least give it a bit of thought.
And now we can continue with our different options.
The first thing we want to do is ask the user for what they want to do.
So we might want to see the user selection ease input and we may want to see and to pay me to print
the student list
as to add a new student a to a mark to a new student to a funeral or q to quit.
And this is a fairly large list and we can just break it down here and this doesn't affect the way it's
printed out at all.
So we can just break it down and make it a bit easier on the eyes.
And now what we want to do is if selection is then print to the student list Princeton list where the
list is student list if selection is equal to.
Then create student.
And remember that this returns a student dictionary and this student dictionary we have to put in our
student list.
And I think you can do that.
You can use the append method to police this dictionary that gets returned by this method into the student
list.
Then you can do that and I would recommend taking the time now to try that out and implemented yourselves
.
Once that's done and if you remembered correctly then shouldn't on the school list don't append will
append or add something at the end of a list.
And what we're adding into that list is to create student.
Remember this is going to ask the user for the shouldn name as well.
Elif selection is a we want to add a student Mark and this is where the problem lies because we can
do either mark but now we need to pass and mark a student not a student list but rather to a specific
student.
How is the user going to get a specific student from the student list.
We haven't given the user the option to interact with one specific student.
We've given them the option to printout the student list or to add a new student but they don't have
an option to select one of the students for it to be passed to at Mark.
What we have to do is allow the user to somehow identify each student individually where we have to
do for that is give each of the students I am an idea and identify
we could do it two ways we could in the student data dictionary have an ID.
But the ideas would probably be 0 1 2 3 and so on.
So we might as well give the ID here when we print out the details.
We can also print out an ID and that ID can be the position of the student in the student list.
So for example if the student is the first student that has been added to the list that would be id
0 if it's the first.
The second student would be ID 1 and then the user here can say for sure and ID one I want to add Mark
and student ID one is the second student in the list the way we're going to print out the IDS is by
using the numerator method.
What we'll do is say for I call my student in numerate students and what that does is it not only gives
us the student value which is each of the elements of the list.
It also gives us the index of each of the elements.
So student the first student is going to be the first element on the list.
And we're also going to get zero as the first index and then the next student is going to be the second
June.
And we're also going to get in next one actually.
And what we can do here is say printed in details but also print ID dot format.
And then the student can sort of the user can then see OK I want to modify student with ID 3.
For example naturally in our selection we also have to allow the user to type in which ID they want
to interact with which ID they want to add a mark to.
So let's say that student on the whole index or ID is input and to the student ID to add a marker to
.
And now this will get us the student ID and we can get the specific student that we want to watermarked
to a student is going to be student list student IAB and that's going to get us the specific student
that the user is wanting to interact with.
And finally we can say Neumark is
input into the Neumark to be added.
And finally we can say the mark for student Neumark now I've missed out a couple of things deliberately
.
So you guys can see I can see if you guys are on the ball.
What is the problem with this bit of code.
There are two problems and there are.
I'll give you a hint.
They're both related to data types.
So what do you think the problem might be.
The poem has to do with the input method and what it returns
to give you.
If you had the input method returns a string and we know from previously that the index that we gets
from a list has to be an integer index 0 the next one to three and so on.
Therefore if student ID is an integer then this is going to give us an error.
And similarly the new Mark also returns a string.
And when we add the mark in here it's going to put in a string and that's going to be fine.
But then when it comes to calculating the average it's going to try to divide strings by a number and
that's not going to go down well you guys know how to convert these things to numbers I'm sure.
So let's do that real quick.
How would you make sure that student ID and Neumark are integers as opposed to strings.
And the solution as I'm sure you've got it is to simply wrap the input method with it and that will
convert temporarily this return type to int and it will associate that with student ID.
And similarly down here and now what we're adding is a number.
And what we're accessing is a number as well.
And we're not really banking on the user not piping a for example where we're banking on them typing
a number.
And if if they type a then the integer conversion is going to fail because a cannot be converted to
an integer.
But we'll deal with that later on.
OK.
So I think we've got everything except exit the application.
Let's give this a go and see what happens.
So if everything works I'll run them on you and then and and play it.
And here we've got our prompt and Pete and assumed list as to how the new student ETU Almagro a student
or q to quit.
And also you know we can see that the combers and these quotation marks are very close together.
So the first thing I'm going to do is just fix that in terms of usability adding a space at the end
and I will just make it a bit better and potentially I'm also going to enter your selection do that
.
So the user knows that they're made to type.
So let's P and we don't get anything which makes sense.
We don't have enough students yet.
And the program is finished.
So in order to go again we have to press play.
And.
Now when any space that let's add a student type s.
So we've added the student but then the program ended because that's what we've told it to do really
the selection was.
As we've appended something to the student list and that's it then the program comes on and so what
we want to do is say while selection is not equal to Q which is the thing we reason to quit.
We're going to indent all of that and put it into the while loop.
And once selection is not cue we're going to be doing that.
However remember at the end of the while loop we're going to have to ask the user again for his selection
so that we can then restart the loop with another.
Another option for the user.
So let's do that.
And now our press play and now we've got a selection.
We're going to add a new student.
And now we get the prompt again asking us to enter more things and we can print the sheet and list and
we get zero.
And then my name average mark is zero.
So let's add a mark and the ID that we want to add two is zero which is the idea there.
And remember all that that's doing is accessing the zeroth element of our student list and the zeroth
element is going to be the only element to that in this case.
And then you might be at eight ninety nine and now we can print it out and we can see ID 0 the average
marks ninety nine.
Let's add another one to zero.
Mark 15 we can print it out and now we can see the average marker seventy four point five
and I.D. one is now Rolf.
The one I've just added average mark is zero.
And we can keep going with that.
Let's see if we type Q Does it exit.
Yes it does.
And I realize this was a bit of a longer video but it's important that you guys realize of the importance
of iterating and testing your program and making sure that it's usable and making sure that you're going
through everything that the user might want to do and verifying that everything works in your hand.
Once you know the input method returns a string.
It's important to realize what is going to happen when the program gets to this place.
The input method winners on a string that's going to be associated with an.
And then we're going to access a string in here which is going to give me an error.
So therefore I need to convert it to an integer in my hand while I'm developing I'm always going over
what the computer is going to do when it gets to this line.
What is going to happen in this line and when what is going to happen in this one and then what's going
to happen in this one.
And just thinking what would the computer do.
And that really helps me figure out a lot of errors before they actually happen.
So that's important that you guys start thinking like a computer when it comes to developing.
With that said we've got this program working and we've actually learned quite a lot of different things
.
We've learned a lot about some method in calculating averages.
We've learned about the numerate method used for getting not only the value of a list but also the index
as well.
And we've also learned about dictionaries creating them advantaged dictionary usage putting lists in
dictionaries and dictionaries in dictionaries and returning them as well.
And also we've created a slightly more complicated or complex rather menu which allows the user to to
interact with our app.
So we've done quite a few things.
I think that now we're ready to really move on to the very foundational aspect of software development
which is object oriented programming and that's what we're going to be doing in the next section.
I'm really excited about that and I hope you guys are too.
And in the next section we're going to be moving on to that object oriented programming.
It's the next stop.
So I'll see you there.