Final comeback in this video we're just quickly looking at the limit command the limit command is used
to just to that limit the number of rows returned by query.
So I'm here with a last query that had zero rows returned and I'm going to remove the WHERE clause.
Just so we are not doing any filtering.
If I press play then we get 5 customers back which is all there is in our table.
However after the from customers part of the Select I can put a limit.
For example if I only wanted three customers back or potentially just one customer back I could do limit
one.
And then they'll give me just the first customer in that tape.
Normally this is not very useful just by itself but it can be especially useful if you are looking at
for example the first customer with a specific address or phone number or e-mail address.
For example in an application that allows users to log in you may want to allow users to type in their
e-mail.
And then you'll find the first user that has that e-mail and you log in with that is just a way to make
sure that you're not selecting multiple things at the same time really.
Also there's ways to implement paging nation using limit so you can for example select 100 elements
and then in the next query you can select the next hundred elements.
And we're not going to really get into how to implement pagination in this course but that's a couple
of uses for limits.
So it's good to know that this command exists and you can use it.
OK.
So that's it for this video.
I'll see you in the next one.