Hyde will come back and there's really we're going to be creating the users.
I recommended that you try that on your own first.
In the last video so please do.
If you haven't already made sure that you are able to do that or at least attempt so you can enhance
your learning that way.
Now we're going to be going into the sequel creating the new table and then saving our users here.
Let's go into P.G. admin three
and then connected in here.
And it's going to be fairly simple just open up the learning database and here would be drop table users
.
I've already dropped it.
So it's not going to be there but.
And you should do that just to drop the table and then create table users.
And we're going to be doing is making sure that we have an idea which is going to be a real primary
key.
We have an e-mail which is going to be text.
We have a first name which is going to be text.
You can always use character varying there as well if you prefer.
And last name which would be text.
They're all they're both the same auth token and auth token secret to thing when you do anything else
.
First and last name that's it.
Later on we may add in a password there as well boss.
Now we've got that.
So we've got our table now so these queries should work.
And that's everything we have to do really in Pascola sequel so we can close that down and then come
back to work in the loggin dopy why file.
We managed to ask the user to log in.
They gave us the pin We called the access token and they we made the request.
We were able to get data out of Twitter which means that the access token was valid.
So now all we have to do is once we have the access token save the user to the database.
OK.
So let's do that we've got the access token here.
We're going to print it out and then we're going to create our new user in here.
So we're going to see user and we're going to have to import that.
I'm just importing from user import user.
We're going to make sure that that's not and that the comment is a bit confusing and we go from using
import user We're just importing the user class from our user Doppie file.
That's all we're doing.
And now we have to put in here email and so on.
So let's ask the user for their email
list as they use it for the first name.
Let's ask the user for the last name.
Make sure that is equal sign there and that's it.
I think e-mail first and last name and then these two things we have.
And the ID is automatically generated.
So that's all we need.
And here in the User we can say email first name last name and here we can put an access token auth
token access token auth token secret and none for the ID.
The ID gets generated automatically.
So now we have our object going to say user equals that user don't safe to DBI.
OK let's press play and see if that goes in the database or not.
We might need Peachi admonitory again when I authorize the app.
Copy that button and.
We're going to enter or e-mail a first name last name none type object has no match up you'd get corn
.
We found this before and I'm sure you know how to fix that.
That is something we really couldn't.
But in all honesty I forgot.
And it's totally acceptable to forget to do this just as long as you know that the era means something
.
It's not something wrong with our code.
Well it is.
It's just we forgot to do something.
And if you know what that is I would encourage you to go and do that.
Solve this problem.
And if you don't just wait for a couple of moments and we'll do that here.
OK.
I'm sure you got it.
But just in case you didn't.
Let's go over it here.
What we forgot to do was initialize our database so we have to do that.
So let's go and import from the database import database and then database not initialize.
And what we have to pass in here.
If you remember correctly are the properties that we need for that connection.
So for logging in to our database and if I remember correctly where we need our user which is postscripts
password which is 1 2 3 4 host which is local host
database which is learning.
I can't recall if there's anything else.
Let's try and run that.
See that's it.
Another option will be to check the code from the last section
but it seems that was all that was necessary.
So now we have our tweets.
Again we haven't stopped printing them so they're still coming out down here.
We're still requesting the computer images tweets and we're still printing them out.
But now we would expect them to be a user in our database at least one road.
So let's launch BGM entry again.
Maybe it should have closed it in the beginning.
Connect to that and now launch the learning database.
And there we indeed do have it.
This auth token and or in secret as well as the email the first name and the last name.
So now there is actually a lot we can do.
And I would encourage you to do stuff with this code now that you know a bit more about Python you know
how to retrieve things from a database and you have your off token saved there.
What I would encourage you to do is ask the user for their e-mail when they start up the application
see if they have an e-mail in here.
Retrieve the ortho can and Ortho-K and secret create the token and make a Twitter request.
With that we're going to be doing that in the next few videos.
But I would really encourage you to try that on your own.
Well we have now is the data saved to the database.
Now we need to be able to retrieve it and use it.
So as I said we're going to be asking the user for their e-mail and then we're going to be just skipping
all of this stuff if we have an e-mail already.
But we're not going to do that in this video because once again it is a bit long so I'll be seeing you
in the very next one.
Well we're going to be doing just that.
But again try that on your own first if you can.
It's a lot better for learning.
OK.
I'll see you in the next video.