Hi welcome back in this video we're looking at S-sh keys and how we can add them to our get her account
.
First of all however we have to learn what an S-sh key is.
It is each keys are extremely popular things nowadays for security and the way they work is that there
are two keys a private key and a public key.
I'm not going to go into specifics as to how they work but anybody can generate a pair of keys and they're
always in pairs a private key and a public key whenever you want to send data away.
You encrypt the data using your private key.
And again I'm not going to go into how that happens but you encrypt your data using your private key
and anybody else can decrypt your data using your public key which is the key that you give away.
Naturally it's important that your public key doesn't become really known or else it's not really as
safe.
So what we do is we give our public key to get a job and then we encrypt things with our private key
.
We give them our public key so they can read our traffic.
The stuff we're sending them and like that.
There's a lot of other communication on the Internet that behave with the S-sh keys for example connecting
to remote servers.
Usually happens like that you have your private key and you put your public key on the server you're
connecting to and then the communication can be encrypted like that.
So the the key in this video is generating those keys in Windows.
Remember to use the get bashed to get shell that we installed originally in order to run this command
or else it won't work.
The command is S-sh that can just run that and just accept the defaults for the file in which to save
the key unless you already have other keys then you may want to choose a different place.
If you've never generated a key before then just accept that default then you can enter a passphrase
which is just a password.
So that whenever you use your key you have to put the password in that's useful.
So that here when you're committing when you're pushing things to get to them you'll be asked for the
password for this key.
You can leave it blank if you want.
And if you leave it blank.
Just make sure that nobody steals your computer or else they'll have access to go get an account.
OK so let's press enter and then enter again I'm not going to put a password in.
And then you get this stuff here.
Which I appreciate is blurred out.
But you'll see something like this.
And finally we want to do that.
And then the till the slash dot S-sh slash ID dot underscore R-S.C. dot pub.
And when I copy that and always blowdown but just copy your own then going to get up into your profile
and edit profile.
Go to S-sh and GBG keys add a new stage.
Don't go down there.
Don't either Noojee PTG just add a new key.
You can call it whatever you want and then you can paste it in something important if you're working
from windows.
It is possible that there is a new line that there's a new line in there.
Make sure to delete new lines so that everything is in one line.
Even the way I appreciate is shown in multiple lines but there is known no and Turkey be impressed.
Notice that I can press enter there and twice and then I can delete the enter there.
Make sure it all in one line but make sure that you're not deleting any characters.
If you delete a character then it won't work.
So if you delete the oh by accident then just put back in and thus everything you have to do.
Then you can give it a title over to your app JCL at hoagies MBP dot home.
That's why I'm calling mine.
You can call it whatever you want again and then finally at it and not it.
Now if we go back into it we can now do the get push that you origin must
and that's it.
Then it comes to the objects that we're pushing which is 3 and writes them up to get hub.
And then it creates the new branch in the remote repository which is called M..
Just as it is in our local repository and then it says the branch master was set up to track the remote
branch master from origin.
That's what the dash you flag does.
And now whenever we modify things or make any commits in our master branch which is our default branch
we can just do get push.
We don't have to do that.
You origin must.
And that's it.
This is how you create your S-sh keys and how you make sure that you have access to pushing to get her
.
Remember don't have any newline characters in your S-sh key and don't delete any characters from yours
as each key and you'll be fine.
Without further ado I'll see you in the next video.