Hiawatha Mack in this video we're looking at to the like command and wild cards wild cards are really
useful because they let you select data only based on part of the field as opposed to the entire field
.
For example let's say you're running a promotion on your customers that you want to give them a discount
if they have the letter O in their last name.
Probably not something very realistic once again.
But nevertheless this will allow us to show you how this works.
You know how to select everything from a table select stock from the table name.
So I'm going to run this query select stuff from customers and that gives me about five customers.
I only have one customer that has the letter O in the name.
So just pick a different letter.
Let's pick the letter T because that's for customers to have the letter T and and nominee.
So there is no way to do that.
We what we already know we could do with when where and then what do we do.
The pythonic way would be to say something like t in last name but this doesn't really work.
And this although it does exist in sequel it doesn't do what we want.
So that isn't the best thing.
What we want to use is the like command which allows us to compare a field with a pattern.
So I'm going to see.
So let's start from customers way last name like.
And then I put in a pattern.
So the pattern can use a couple of wildcards.
It can use the percent wild card which if I run this I get everything.
Now explain why that is.
And I can also use the underscore wild card and if I put four of them and I run this I only get Adam
as the last name.
OK so now let's remove that number for underscores.
Get me Adam and 1 percent symbol gets me all of them.
So if I run this again take a wild guess as to what each of those mean.
What does a percent symbol mean and what does the underscore symbol mean.
You may have guessed the percent symbol is just like the asterisk symbol up here.
It means anything any correct.
What is the underscore symbol means.
Are you single correct.
So when we use for underscores we got Adam because that's the only custom of the has a four letter surname
.
And when we use the percent symbol we got everything because it matches everything.
So there you go.
So it's like to start from customers with any last name like.
And here we're going to use our first pattern and we wanted those customers that have the letter T in
their name.
So what we're going to do is say I sent t percent.
And that means any Kanak to any number of characters before 80 minutes.
And then any number of characters after the t show when we run this you would expect to get those four
users there for customers.
That's what happens.
So you've got all those customers there and that's fantastic.
What would happen if I replace this Pisin symbol after the T with an underscore
which customers would get.
And the answer is Smith and Scott because those are the only customers that have one Kanika after the
T.
The other customers have multiple characters so they don't match this pattern.
So that is how we can do a like selection or like filtering which is not the fastest thing to do.
So unless you require that this sort of filtering I would potentially try to avoid it.
And is always faster to filter by specific things just because it decreases a bit of the power requirements
of the server.
But nevertheless this does exist and it is very useful.
So please do use it when it is required and that is how you can filter based on a pattern.
Remember the percent symbol means any character any number of times and the underscore symbol means
a single character.
With that said I'll see you in the next few