Hi and wel come back in the city we're talking about binary trees a binary tree is another data structure
that is not sequential like lists or stacks or cubes.
So what is a binary tree.
Well as I said is unlike any other data structure it is unlike a sequence of items or a group of items
.
It's a branching structure just like the tree would be.
For example when you look at a tree out in nature I mean like a real tree it has branches and the branches
then divide into more branches and that branch divides into more branches and so on.
It is not never ending but it can branch a few times or also at the end of the branch you have leaves
or nodes in the case of programming.
In the case of programming binary trees have two branches in each part in each section where they branch
out.
So what is a tree could have one branch dividing into 10 other branches a binary tree each branch divided
into two branches and then each of those branches divide into two more branches and so on.
So at each division point we have a node and each node points to two other nodes which right child and
its left child nodes are ordered with a key that we can select when we program our tree.
And in all cases the right child will have a greater key than the parent and the left child helps apologies
the left child will have a smaller kid in the parent.
So to recap each node points to two other nodes the right node has a greater key on the left node has
a smaller key.
Now how does that work.
Why is that important.
Well let's imagine we have our tree out in nature and it have a trunk a sort of root and that root grows
up.
It's a single thing and then it divides into a few branches and then each branch divide into more with
a binary tree.
It is the same way.
We also have a starting node and root node and greater nodes larger nodes always go to the right.
So you can see the numbers are increasing and smaller nodes always go for the left.
OK.
Next Slide is going to have a smaller and a larger node as you can see 13 is larger than 10 and 8 is
smaller than 10.
So for any given node larger nodes always go to the right and smaller nodes always go to the left.
Now when you see a tree out in nature each of the branches doesn't have a different size or weight or
value so it's not exactly like a tree but the binary tree is useful.
And we're going to see exactly in which scenarios it is useful.
So a node and node points to to node it's right.
Child and it's left child and the nodes are ordered with a key that we select the right child always
has a greater key and the left child always has a smaller key.
Let's look at why this can be interesting.
Let's look at adding a new node.
Let's say we have this tree here and we want to add a node to it.
Let's say we want to add at the node 16.
I'm sure you can already see where that node should go.
But the computer cannot.
So it's important that the computer knows how to get to the place where 16 should go.
Let's make this larger for your convenience.
And remember 16 is the nodo we're adding and we are at the root.
We always start at the top of the tree or the bottom depending on which direction you want to go.
But it doesn't matter where we stand at the root node larger nodes are to the right smaller nodes onto
the left.
So is 16 greater than 15 number 16 is the one we're adding.
Well yes.
So we go to the right now we are at 17 is 16 greater than 17.
No.
So what to do is now we go to the left.
So everything shifts apart and we add another child child under 17 which is on the left and then we
put the node 16.
So my traversing the tree we have found or the program has found a way to put the node 16.
This is a bit weird and a bit kind of surreal I would say am.
How does the program know how these nodes are structured or which one is the child of which or how does
it travel from one note to another.
And we're going to be looking at all of those things in the programming video so please don't worry
about the implementations or how the computer does things.
Just what about you yourself understanding how a binary tree works.
Again to add the new node we have a node that we're trying to add.
And if it's key is greater than the current node such as the top node at the beginning then we go down
to the right and we stop at the next node.
And that now becomes the current node.
If the key is smaller than the current node then we do the opposite.
We go down to the left and make that the current node and then we check again and then we maybe go to
the right or maybe go to the left again.
And so if the key is the same we stop and we give an error because we don't want X in this tree.
And finally if the current node is no then we can make that equal to the node that will it.
So once we reach an empty node somewhere where there isn't a node then we can say OK there is no node
here but there should be because this is know that we're trying to add should go there and then we put
that new node in there.
We're going to look at exactly how to do that soon.
Finding a node is similar to adding a node.
Once again if the key of the node we're looking for is greater than the current no we all to the right
.
And if not we go to the left and if the current node at any point is null it means that we've reached
a branch but we haven't found that no.
We're looking for and if at any point in our search the current nodes key is equal to the No the key
of the node or trend we're looking for then and we have found the node.
So to find just traverse the tree as normal looking for a value going left or right and eventually you
will arrive at a node has of the key that you're looking for or you will not arrive at anoda has that
key that you're looking for in which case you have not found a note to add a node just traverse the
tree until you find an empty slot where the new node could go and put it.
And that's everything for this video.
Just wanted to quickly introduce to you the concept of binary trees how they're structured how they
work and remember always go to the left if they're smaller.
Always go to the right.
If it's bigger.
There's always going to allow some order in your tree which is great because computers love order it
allows them to be very quick when doing things.
When I look at how exactly that order affects us and affects our programs in the very next video.
So I'll see you there.