Heineken back in this video we're going to be looking at creating a user profile.
Let's once again go over what's happening.
The first thing that happens is that users are going to log in slash Twitter.
We get a request token store in a session and then send them over to Twitter dot com to authorize our
app.
Once they've pressed the button Twitter sends them back to us with an author verifier as part of the
query string parameters.
We then retrieve that or the verifier and we get an access token using the stored request token in the
session and the verifier will then see if we have an existing user in that database that uses that verifier
.
And if we do then sorry that use of that screen name.
And if we do then we are just going to use that user.
And if we don't we create that user and leave it to the database.
Finally we return the screen name of the user which is nice we can see that it works but ideally we
would want to send them to their user profile.
So we're going to do in this video is send them to the user.
The first thing to do is create the Profunds or app don't root profile for example.
And then this is going to be a profile method.
And now we can here write code that is going to evaluate when the user arrives at the profile endpoint
and then we can return for example a template.
So that's what we're going to be doing.
Return the render template.
Now we need the profile dot HVM l template.
So let's break that template right click your templates folder and create a new DML file called profile
.
If you don't have the ad there's a bit of an error.
If you don't have the e-mail file thing there.
Just create a new file and call it profiler each.
As we can see this looks very similar to our home file home nights demo.
Our home doesn't have the language specified and that's something you should do but it's not really
required.
Here we can specify the language of the page in this case it says English and the characters set which
is UTF 8.
You see if it is just a a character set it basically allows you to display Chinese Russian characters
as well as English and Western languages.
So it's nice to specify that as well.
It's not required in the title we're going to say a user profile and here in the body we can say whatever
we want.
But what I'm going to say is open double bracket double curly brace and inside we're going to put screen
on the school name.
So open double curly brace screenname PLO's the blue curly brace.
This is a special type of command that is only available in flask.
It is not available.
If you write which DML Normally this is part of a flask and language essentially flossed uses a template
language so we can use some special code called Ginger to when we are rendering templates using flask
.
But normally unhedged you cannot do that.
So it's only in flask.
So we're using here a.
This is the way to print out a variable in Jinja too.
So what we're doing is we're printing out the variable the screen on the school name.
However we don't have that variable unless we pass it in.
So here in the run the template after profiled are actually M-L we can pass in variables for that template
.
So I'm going to pass in screen name and that's going to be equal to the session screen name that we've
got saved.
OK.
So what do you think is going to happen once we do this.
What sort of difference are we going to see.
Well let's run through it and I'm going to stop and kill that and restart the app.
We're running with a debugger but that's fine it's fine to run with a debugger we don't have any breakpoint
set.
So let's go over here and log in with Twitter.
And you're going to be doing this over and over again authorize the app and no difference.
We don't see any difference at all what is happening.
Have we done the right thing.
Have we served the correct page.
Well we're going to have right click on that and press inspect element.
If you don't have that you can enable that in the Safari preferences or in the preferences of your app
and navigate our choice and hear what we've got is essentially nothing just the body same school of
code dump me.
So did we render that correct thing.
And the answer is no we don't have for example a title.
We don't have that title up here.
So what happened.
Well we need to think like a computer in these instances and remember to think like a computer run through
your code and see where it went wrong.
We created the endpoint.
We defined the method then we rendered it right.
So that we had to do that we would do that in the home page we were doing essentially the same thing
.
So let's run through it once we come back to our Twitter.
We get the verifier we know that works.
We get the token we know that works.
We get the user We know that works.
If it's not if it doesn't exist when we create it that's fine.
We said in a session then we return the screen name.
Now is that what you what we should be doing.
Should we be returning the screen name.
How do we end up in the profile.
When are we telling the user to go to the profile because the user still stuck here in Author Twitter
.
All we've done is return the screen name so I'm sure that you realize that we have to send the user
over to the profile page.
And the way we do that is with a redirect.
So we're going to redirect the user to the Profar.
Now we could do that easily by doing the colon slash slash 171 open only one call on 8:56 five slash
profer that would be an option.
However instead of that as a much better way of doing it we can just redirect them to the endpoint that
is associated to this method.
So this method here has the slash profile and point associated with it and we can just redirect the
user to the endpoint associated with this profile method and the way we do that is using another Flast
method called URL for.
So we're going to say Europhile profile which is the method name not the end point name the method name
.
And we have to import that let's go to the very top and import you are L4 from the flask set of imports
And now we can restart our application go back here.
1 2 7 1 0 1 1 Twitter logon which with our sorry log in Twitter.
I'm going to leave this open just for now.
Authorize the app
that we have exactly the same thing.
But if we now look in the head we have a title and if we look in the tab we have a title.
So we've succeeded in redirecting the user over to the correct page which is the profile page.
Now we could show any other number of things we could for example make a Twitter request using that
username and display some tweets relevant to the user for example.
And we're going to be doing that but not in this video.
All I wanted to show you in this video is remember to think like a computer.
And to introduce you to the you are L4 method and to some extent to the Jinja to templating language
we can pass variables to the rendered template method and then we can use those variables within the
DML code using the double curly brace.
OK it does everything for this video.
Hopefully you learn something and you enjoy that.
Thanks for listening and I'll be seeing you in the very next one.