I will come back in this video let's download it and install it.
The first thing to do is if you are on Mac or Linux go to get bashed CM dot com then go to the download
section and here you can download the package for Mac which will install get on your Mac.
If you are on Linux then you can install it using your package manager and simply execute these in your
console in your terminal if you're in Linux.
And depending on which distribution you're using.
So if you're using Ubuntu which is probably the most popular then just open up your console and run
apt get install get your windows.
Then there's some special instructions for you that is going to make your life a lot easier.
Let's switch over to Windows and I'll show you exactly what I mean.
Normally in Windows when you open up the CMB command prompt you get something like this.
And to be honest the Windows Command Prompt just isn't very good.
So we don't want to use that.
It doesn't really support it very well.
So what to do instead is we're going to install another command prompt that is meant to emulate that
of Linux and Mac.
And it also includes it and it comes under the name of get for Windows.
Just go to get dash for Dash windows doc get hub doc I O and then download it and once that's downloaded
you can run that and I'm going to speed up through this bit and then continue once it's finished
.
OK.
Now that's downloaded.
Let's just go and open it up.
You can tell I don't use Windows very often because I've still got that user access control.
So just press.
Next this is the license you can read it if you want.
And then wait to install it.
I'm going to leave it at the default and I recommend you do the same unless you have a specific reason
not to.
And then here is what is important.
I would take both of these checkboxes and get Basheer get gooey here.
These are just going to make your life a bit easier when it comes to integrating with Windows Explorer
is going to let you right click on a folder and open a get graphical interface or a get to bash which
is a shell like a console in that folder.
That's quite nice.
You can put an icon on the desktop if you want and leave these checked.
This is quite important especially associate dot s h files to be run with bash and bash is a sort of
language slash thing used in Unix console's the Linux on the Mac terminals the console.
And what you get for Windows does it installs and lets you run bash at least some of it in the program
that it installs.
So it's important that you associate doc S.H. files to be run with bash because that's the only thing
that can be run with really.
And finally you don't get config files with a default text editor that's something you can do if you
want but you can leave the unchecked if you prefer to use a different text editor than the default.
OK you can also create a start menu and then this is also important.
You can use get from get bash which is the program that this is installing.
You can use get from the windows command prompt which is the program that we saw earlier.
And this allows you to use some get commands in the windows console and that can sometimes and overwrite
some of the things that are already there.
And finally you'd get an optional Unix tools from the windows command prompt.
So what this does is it allows you to do more things that are available for Mac and Linux users from
the windows command prompt but it overrides some other things that are already there as well.
So up to you which when you want to do and what I'm going to do is I'm going to use get to from get
back only because I like console better.
And I would encourage you to do the same.
You can open up this program when you want to use it.
And if you want to use the Windows command prompt then you can use that for other things.
And this is also important.
Check out windows style commit unique style line endings.
Leave this checked and that's just because a Windows adds a special character at the end of every line
.
And Unix doesn't.
Or rather it adds a different character.
And if you commit Unix style it means that people are using a Mac or Linux are going to be able to download
your code and look at it and run it.
Whereas if you commit as is then I am the one who tells you that choosing this option is not recommended
for Krotz but from projects if your users or rather other developers are going to be using Mac or Linux
then they're going to have problems.
So leave this one checked like that.
And finally you've got a couple of things here.
You've got Mindy D-y or the windows the FULDE console window mentees.
Why is just an emulator so emulates a console in Linux or a Mac.
And I would leave that checked.
And finally these things I'll just leave them checked they are just for convenience.
And there you go.
Once that's done you can proceed.
And as you can tell or just left everything as a default and this instance that the defaults are good
options.
And that's not done.
So we're going to just launch it so I can show you what it is and what it's like.
And that is what it looks like.
This is the Minniti y emulator that we installed and it's essentially the get shell.
Now when I'm recording I'm going to be recording on the Mac because that's my operating system.
I'm running Windows in a virtual machine.
So it's just easier for me to to record on the Mac.
So when running on the Mac but if you use this console here that's when interest and then you're going
to be able to do everything I'm doing on the Mac.
If you use the Windows command prompt the CMB
then you will not be able to do everything.
So for example in here I can do VI and that launches a text editor.
And here I can do VI because it doesn't exist in Windows.
So use this control that in work use this console when you want to go along.
What I'm doing in the course and you can use the Windows command prompt for Windows things if you know
about it and just don't use it if you don't have a reason to.
So again stick to this console and you'll be fine.
And also you can watch video