Hi and welcome back in this video we're looking at the sequel sequence which is going to allow us to
give our user IDs incremental values without us having to do anything.
Let's once again revisit the contents of our users table
and notice how we've got to use them.
We've got ID one and then 82 and we've got our two names there as we remember.
The problem came because we wanted to be able to enter user data but not have to remember which ID we're
entering.
So once again insert into public don't users name I only want to enter the name because that's the only
thing that I know values and we know that this doesn't work because we're trying to enter null as the
ID by default.
So when we do this this doesn't work because the default value for the ID column is null and we cannot
enter null in a primary key.
So what we have to do is change the default value of the ID column to be something other than null.
But we also have to remember that it has to be unique which is where the sequence comes in a sequence
in Pasqua sequel is not available in many other sequel management systems.
So use it carefully in other systems you have things like auto increment but we're not going to look
into them because it doesn't exist in post-race impossible sequel.
We have to create a sequence and the sequence is just that it's a generator of numbers sequentially
and the numbers are unique because one comes after another.
So the first thing we have to do is create the sequence and give it a name.
So we're going to a create sequence and then we're going to give it a name.
Normally you call these things for example the table name which is uses the column that you're going
to be applying the sequence to which is the ID column and then you usually put CEQ at the end for sequence
.
Now if we do this this would create a sequence starting at the value 1.
Because that's what's normal.
You start one and then you've got two and three and so on.
However we've already got some users in our table.
So if we start with the value one the next time we try to use this sequence it's going to try to put
in a one and that's when I give it an error because one is already there.
What to do is to start at 3 and that will start of the value 3 which makes sense and that's it.
Then just execute that and return successfully with no result.
And that's created.
And then what we have to do is change the default value of the ID column in our users table to do this
.
We're going to introduce another thing which is alter table alter table is used to do that alter table
and change it.
So we do alter table.
Public Art uses that I'm going to put a new line but again that is not required.
And then when we do we can do a lot of things with ALTER TABLE.
And the one we're going to look at in this video specifically is alter columned.
And then here we can alter a specific column inside the public top users table.
The column we want to alter is ID.
And then what we want to do is set a default value and the default value.
We're going to put it could be something like nine.
And then all new users would have the value 9 unless we specified another value.
But again that would be problematic if we had multiple users with the same ID.
So what to do is use the sequence and to use the sequence we say next vowel.
And this is a possible sequel function and that gives us the next available value in the sequence and
where we put in here.
Is it the sequence name the sequence name inside quotation marks and that equals name as you remember
.
We call it user's ID sec and then we put in a semicolon at the end and that's it.
And then we execute this and it says that that's fine.
And finally the last thing that we want to do is to tell Pasco sequel that although the ID column is
using that sequence that the ID column owns the sequence and what that achieves is that when we delete
the table for example this you can you will also get deleted.
And that makes sense because we're probably not going to want to use reuse the sequence in another table
because a sequence will be for example at 15000 and there's not really much use for that.
So let's tell postgrads that this sequence is owned by the ID column of our table so that if we delete
that column or with the table then that can cascade into the sequence.
So we say alter sequence and then we put in the sequences name and we say owned by.
And this is public use users dot ID because that's the schema.
The table and the column name and that works as well.
And naturally we haven't seen any output.
We don't know if this is doing stuff.
So let's try that again.
Let's go into our previous queries and select this one insert into public don't use this and we're going
to only enter a name and the name is going to be my name in this case.
So not as we're not putting in an ID and the value that is going to go in the ID is the IDs default
value and we know that a default value of the ID column is now the next value of the sequence because
we've just said that when we pressed play.
Now this works.
So what do you think is going to come up when we select from our table.
As you would expect we get the ID 3 which is the next value under the name which is what we've put in
.
If we weren't to run the thing again.
Believe me the value would be 4 and that's how you create a sequence and how you apply it to the column
.
And that allows you to do auto incremental IDs like this one.
That's it.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next video