And will come back in this video we're going to be talking about dates.
Dates have always been a problem in databases and there's a few reasons for that.
The first reason is that dates can be formatted in many ways.
For example the American way to format a date would be something like this where 2005 is the year 10
is the month.
October 10 is the day so I will be the 10th of October 2005.
They can be formatted like soap where 10 is the day 10 is the month and 2005 is a year that can also
be formatted like so where 10 is the month 10 is the day 2005 is the year.
And many other ways like this one and so on.
Anyway that's one of the problems some of those formats are ambiguous which makes it a problem.
The second problem is that dates can have a time zone attached to them.
For example the data right now is 21st of May 6 o'clock but if you were watching this live which you
evidently are not the date for you could be different.
It could be 21st of May 8:00.
If you were in GMT or it could be 9:00 if you were in Russia in time.
I think so.
I'm not really good when my time comes but nevertheless I hope you get the gist of it which is that
the current time is not the same depending on the user.
So that's also a problem.
Your database and doesn't necessarily know which timezone is correct for the user.
And the third is a big issue which is daylight saving and when the clocks go forward or backward for
an hour which is done so that we have more daylight and during the day so we can save money and electricity
will lose or gain an hour there in the middle of the night which is unaccounted for.
And our data base doesn't know that that's going to happen.
It doesn't know what to do with an extra hour or without missing hour.
So during those days whether daylight saving occurs you're going to suddenly have a gap of an hour.
And your data or you're going to suddenly have double the amount of data for that hour.
And because you can the hours won't happen twice.
So these problems are reasonably large problems and they make dates a bit of a pain to deal with in
databases.
I recommend that you store dates in your database without timezone information and then when a user
retrieves data from the database the database or your Python application can convert that times on with
and that that time and date without a timezone information into a date and time with time and information
.
Here's what I mean.
Say that I am in British time which I am which is an hour ahead or behind I think I think as I had it
which is an hour ahead of the universal time at least right now.
When I save a date to the is the date Icesave is going to be an hour earlier.
So if I were to see the current date which is 6 o'clock I would want to say 5:00 because that is the
date time without a time zone attached to it.
When I retrieve the data it should say six o'clock but if I went to Russia and I retrieve the data then
as you say 9:00 or 10:00 or whatever it is.
So that's a solution to the problem of time and depending on where your users are your application can
convert a naive date time a day time without time zones into a date time with times.
OK the other two solutions we're going to be exploring throughout this video possible sequel has a few
data types that are used to store dates and times and they are things like time stamp date time and
interval.
These are the four main data types.
Let's say that I want to select a timestamp I can do select timestamp and then I can give it am which
time it should convert from.
So what I'm going to do now is I'm going to see possible sequel give me a timestamp coming from this
day.
So the day that I'm going to put in is 2005 of October 10th and it's going to be for example 5 am at
16 minutes and 45 seconds
and here's where we got exactly what I put in naturally.
But I'm telling you that this is 2005 October 10th but it could equally be 2005 10th of October if these
days we're different.
So to make it clear this is the 8th of October and not the 10th of August.
So this is the format that you should be using.
This is ISO 8 6 0 or 1 which defines the standard of dates stored in databases which is year month day
hour minute second and optionally milliseconds they add are the but that's optional.
Ideally if you can use this format and that it's going to save you a lot of trouble because possumus
sequel is going to use it by default as well.
If you want to use a different format then you're going to have to do a bunch of changes.
So I recommend that you stick to the format that is by default even though it's the American format
.
If you're not in America it may feel a bit strange to use this but nevertheless it is the default.
And I would recommend using it this is part of the standard AM and it's one of the least ambiguous dates
.
OK let's talk about and how you can convert a timestamp into a more readable string.
Here's how you save or how you figure it out and read timestamped.
But now we want to convert a timestamp into a readable string that isn't necessarily like like this
.
So the first thing is to select now.
And what that does is it gives us the current data and time.
So you can see it on 16 May 21st six 15 15 seconds and a bunch of nanoseconds there were milliseconds
.
If we want to display this string in a nice format for example because I'm in the UK I would like to
see the days first.
We can do that.
We select now which is the current time and we can enclose it in a to underscore car to character.
And this is going to convert the NOW function into a character but naturally we have to tell it the
format that we want to display it as.
So after that now we put it coma and then inside quotation marks we're going to type in the format that
we want the date to be displayed.
As I said I'm in the UK and I won the days first.
So I type D in caps and that stands for day of the month.
So if I pressed play then I get 21 which is the current day of the month.
And then I can say Dasch or indeed any other separator M M and I press play and that's going to give
me 21 0 5 which is the 21st of May.
And then I can do dash Y Y Y Y all in caps and that's going to give me the year as 4 digits.
I can also only use two if you prefer although that's a bit confusing.
Now if it was 20 21 then it could be the 16th of May of 2021 depending on what sort of data you are
using.
Ok then we can do something like ours and that will give us the hours and I'm going to separate my hours
and minutes and seconds using a colon.
But it doesn't have to be a colon if you don't want an eye for minutes.
Next to me 17.
And finally as as four seconds and that gives me the number of seconds
optionally I can also do day like so just day.
And that gives me an error.
Now we go now.
Gives me the day off of the week and notice how there's a space after the AM Saturday and before the
coma but there isn't one up there.
And that's because the longest day of the week is Thursday I think Wednesday probably Wednesday and
that is one character more than Saturday.
So in order to make it so all the days of the week are the same length Pascua adds a space at the end
of those weekdays that are not as long as the longest weekday and we can get rid of them by adding em
in front of day FM and that just removes the fill mode and it removes the space at the end so that you
can see I've pressed play and that's disappeared.
And there's this a few other things you can do.
For example month and then you get to May and once again and probably September or maybe December or
November are the longest months.
So we can put him there again.
And you know we can Saturday AM DD th and TH and simply substitutes into now the appropriate ending
for DD.
That's quite smart.
So is Saturday Twenty-First me and so on and so we could now remove the day in the month and we could
end up with something like that.
So as you can see it's not difficult to convert these dates into a correct.
Not correct but rather more readable string or character.
So that's quite useful.
And also we can do it the other way around.
So I'm going to copy all of this if I can.
And what I'm going to do is the opposite just to show you how it's done.
Instead of two car.
When to say to timestamp to timestamp like so and instead of now we're going to put in here the timestamp
that we got from here as you can see because I printed out this timestamp using this format then you
should be able to reverse itself and read a timestamp using this form.
And naturally it doesn't look like it unless I retype it.
So there you go.
Now it's home selected the appropriate time stamp thing.
Notice how it says plus 0 1 because I am in use in BSD which is British Standard Time which adds an
hour.
And on top of UTC.
So that's why that's happening there.
OK.
So this is how you can select the current time stamp using And now the function.
Now how you can convert it to a string and how you can do the opposite.
As long as you provide the correct format as the formatting string and a string which displays the time
in the correct format.
So once again we could do 2015 10 10 or 1 or 2 or 3.
And if we run this we get an error because this format here is not in the correct form any.
So from what we've seen so far you should already be able to recall how you could convert this to a
time stamp.
What is the format string that should go in here in order to be able to convert this timestamp there
.
And the answer is Y Y Y Y for the year M M for the month DD for the day H.H. for the hour am I for a
minute and s s for the seconds and then as you can see we get the time stamp and that's everything for
this video.
But we have attached a PTF that has a bit more information for you to download and printout or have
a look at and it shows just a bit of a reference as to how you might go about this.
And also has some information about operations that you can do and functions that you can use on dates
.
I'm not going to go into it in the video because I haven't really found much use to it but nevertheless
I wanted to give you a document that outlines some of the things you can do and just for your benefit
.
So with that said Thanks for watching and I'll see you on the next video