Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to be looking at installing psycho PGE 2 on Mac Cyclopedia
two is a library for Python that allows Python programs to communicate with Pasqua sequel.
So let's do that in this video.
Let's install that library first thing to do is to find out way post-career sequel is installed now
on Mac.
I've got post-career sequel here installed in my applications but this only includes a few of the already
sort of functional applications such as PG&E and three we've already executed.
If you install POS with sequel 9.5 then it will be in the same location as mine which I'm going to show
you where that is.
If you didn't install it when nine point five.
So just a different version.
Maybe a later version or an earlier version.
Then the location may be slightly different.
OK let's.
Right click on Posawatz equal nine point five and go to Macintosh HD here as you can see.
I've got a bunch of sort of greyed out folders which are hidden folders.
We want to go into one of these non hidden folders which is a library.
And in here we want to find the Pasko sequel folder then the appropriate version.
In my case nine point five percent said if you've installed a different version then it will be different
.
And then they've been folded in so there's been folder there is a lot of programs that Pasqua sequel
depends on.
And more importantly there is one that is used to config the Patreus sequel and make sure that I can
communicate with it.
And that is pg underscore config so let's make sure that we know this path.
And now let's go into a terminal window which I'm going to open here and we are going to do the following
.
We're going to do export path equals and whether this is going to do it is going to set an environment
variable.
We don't really know what that is.
And we will cover more of the terminal and how it's used later on in the course.
But for now let's just do this to make sure that we've installed the program and that we can communicate
with policy.
So export path equals dollar path colon.
And then we're going to put in the path.
So the way we can get the path is by finding a Finder window that has this path selected and then going
over to the terminal make sure that we've written export path equals dollar path code on.
And then click on hold on this folder and drag it over here and then press enter.
And now we are ready what to do is type Pipp 3.5.
If you installed Python 3.5 if you sort by the entry point for it be Pipp 3.4.
And if you install Python 2.7 it'll just be Pip Pip 3.5 install dash dash upgrade wheel
and then Pip 3.5 install dash dash upgrade.
Set up tools
and finally get 3.5 install psycho Peachi too.
And once that successful it'll tell you you've successfully installed Sanko OPG to then congratulations
you are ready to proceed and we are going to be in this section constructing an app that will allow
us to communicate with possible sequel just to see how that works.
Without further ado.
See you in the next video.