Hi and welcome back and it's really we're looking at creating users and databases in postgrads in Windows
.
The first thing to do is locate where you installed postscripts.
I'm going to go to the Windows Explorer and on my PC my local disk Program Files Pasqua sequel nine
point five.
So this is where I installed Pasqua.
And this is the default location so if you didn't change the location the most likely to be here.
And then we want to go to been been Stansel binary and usually contains everything that we can execute
and the post-race Administration panel is one of these things we can execute.
And then there's loads of different things here we can run.
Now I've been having a play around with this and most don't seem to work in Windows.
For some reason but we don't care.
And what we care about is running the PGE admin 3 which is a visual interface to Potter sequel which
is actually quite nice.
In other systems like Linux or Mac we're going to be using the terminal but lucky for Windows users
we can use the graphical interface so just run that and then you get greeted with a very 90s sort of
graphical interface which nevertheless works quite well.
What we've got here is the Pasqua sequel server that we've installed and this is as you can tell it's
running in local host which is your computer and port five four three two.
The port is always denoted by that colon there and port 5:42 is the default port that we chose when
we were installing.
Let's just connect to that right click it and press connect and then you need to put in the password
you chose during the installation.
So I'm going to put mine which is one two three four and then press OK.
Then you have database's which is where you store data.
You've got table spaces which we're not going to worry about at all in this course.
And then you've got log rows.
Logan rolls are your users and we are going to be creating one to allow us to log in the postscripts
user.
He essentially has access to doing anything you want and that can sometimes be a bit dangerous.
So we're not going to use the postscripts user when we're dealing with data instead we're going to use
our own custom user just for security purposes for example so we don't delete the server or things like
that by accident.
That's right click logging roads and go to new log in roll.
And here you can put in the name.
I'm going to put my name but you can call it whatever you want.
So I'm going to put my name in and then you're a Y.D. is not something that you can change it gets generated
for you.
You can write in a comment if you want.
No not necessary.
And then definition here we can put in a password and I'm going to put in the same password again am
just for security purposes.
One two three four.
That's fine.
And again you can ignore that if you want.
The account is not going to expire in my case and also it's not going to have a number of connections
but it is limited to if you do determine the number of connections that it's limited to then your account
won't be able to interact with Pasqua sequel more than for example 10 times simultaneously ten connections
simultaneously.
I'm not going to worry with that for now.
But for example if you were making an account that was being used by our web site for example you might
want to limit the number of connections.
So your server doesn't run out of random access memory.
That's potentially an option.
Roll privileges.
This is an important section.
We can choose can create databases.
We're not going to choose country roles.
We're not going to do any thing else just can create databases because we're going to be creating a
database for this use to rule membership.
You can sometimes create roles and then members can be assigned to those roles.
So it's certainly a bit easier to reuse the roles.
And not going to work with that in this user.
Similarly with variables and security labels and in the end you can see the sequel code that is going
to run to execute this user.
So it's going to create a roll called Jose which has the ability to log in with a password on that.
And then this is a password that is encrypted using M.D 5 which is an encryption algorithm and then
it's going to allow it to create databases and that's valid forever.
Ok then press OK.
And your logon Role gets created.
And then we can go into databases and see there's already one big prosperous.
This is for some system stuff and we're not going to be using that when we're instead going to create
our own for learning purposes.
So I'm going to call it learning.
And then once again we can look at the definition and the encoding is what sort of character set we're
using.
UTF 8 is the most expensive.
So we were going to use that no template that the full table space is fine.
And then we've got a collection which is how it's how the characters are encoded or something I'm not
really sure to be honest.
I'm going to go for English United Kingdom as a default sort of locale and the character type as well
.
You can choose your own there.
And that's it can I should limit.
Not going to select.
I think there are variables privileges that all fines you use a little sort are fine.
And this is the sequel code once again that what I've been running when we create this database so it's
going to create that database learning with it being coding UTF 8 and then the collation and types are
for United Kingdom.
And there's no conics limit.
So let's press OK and then we get our database here.
So the spread on it and we get the connection so we can then see what we've got here.
We've got catalogs.
We're going to look at we've got extensions we're not really going to be using much of that.
And we've got schemas which is the most important thing a schema defines and where your tables and your
data your views and things like that live.
So here in the public schema which is a default and the one we're going to be using we've got tables
and views.
Those two are the most important parts that we're going to be looking at in this course.
So in the next video we're going to be exploring how we might go about interacting with all this stuff
.
So I'll see you in the next few