Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to start looking at dictionaries in Python.
We've looked at sex and we know that a set is an unordered collection of items with no duplicate.
A dictionary is actually really similar to a set.
However in a dictionary instead of a dictionary containing elements like numbers it contains key and
value pairs.
This means that in a dictionary each of the elements in the dictionary is a key and each key has a value
associated with it.
It's kind of difficult to just understand straight away.
So let's work with an example.
The first thing I wanted to do is here and my charm go to the student project and the students folder
.
And if you name your project differently then this will be called whatever you call your project right
like that.
And create a new python file.
And I'm going to call this file app and.
Now then we are received with the editor and the amped up file appears here on the left.
Here we can write Python code and then we can reichlich app and run the code whenever we want.
The first thing we want to do just to verify that things work is I'm going to print hello world which
is a very common example.
And then I'm going to run app and we can see that down here we get the words hello world.
So we know it works what to do next is print out a set.
So you guys can see the similarities between a set and a dictionary since we've looked at sets before
.
I think you guys can create a sets that contains three or four numbers and then print that out if you
want to pause the video and attempt that yourself just as revision then please go ahead and do that
.
And if not I'll just proceed and create a sample set and to get a sample set this sample on that concept
is going to be the variables name.
And then I'm going to put in that variable put in that box the set value which as we know is just like
that between the curly braces we can put any number of numbers and there are samples that will contain
them and then we can print out the sample set.
Notice how now that we're using an ideally an integrated development environment we get nice things
like autocomplete.
So as you start typing PI chan will suggest things that you can that you may want to type and then you
can just press enter and then that completes it for you.
So let's press play down here.
The bottom line is how we get the set in this case it turns out the set is ordered.
It appears in order.
But notice how when we created it it is not in the same order as when it got printed out.
Also remember what happens if we put another one.
What do you think is going to happen when I press play.
What is going to be printed out.
What I would expect is exactly what happens here.
The same thing gets printed out but without the two ones.
So the one only appears in this specific sense.
It only appears once because the set does not contain duplicates.
So even though we've put two ones up here one of them isn't included because it's already there.
We looked at or I mentioned earlier that a dictionary is a set of key value pairs.
What I mean with that is that each of these values in the set we can call a key and we can associate
with that value.
So with that key a value apologies for example the key three could have the value 7 associated with
it.
Now this is not very useful.
I'll agree with you.
And the key to could have the value 25.
I agree.
This is not useful because now we've got a key which is three.
But actually the value that is in that key are associated with that key is a value number 7.
If we print the sample set which no longer is a set.
Notice that we get to is 25 and 3 7 and I'm going to rename that.
And the way to rename things are using Pancham is press shift and F 6 the function 6 key.
And then you get this little window here and you can change this or sample's dictionary and it will
change in both places where you use it or more places if you use in a more places are really nice too
.
So we get to is linked to 25 and 3 is going to 7.
So what is going to happen if we say print sample of the three.
What do you think will happen when we print this out.
Just guess what comes out is the number 7 because that is the value associated with the key that we
are accessing.
And naturally this is confusing it doesn't have any meaning to us.
However we can use strings instead of numbers as our keys and that now suddenly becomes a lot more useful
.
I'm going to erase the contents of the sample dictionary and instead have something a bit more useful
I'm going to have name is Jose and Mark is 70 and now you can see why this might be useful in some instances
.
Naturally if I press play now what is going to happen is an error because we get a key error.
This is an important type of error because the key 3 is no longer in our dictionary.
The Keithy was there before.
Which is why it worked.
But now the Keathley is no longer there we've only got two keys name and Mark and neither of them is
three.
So if we wanted to access one of these keys how do you think we would do that.
Take it I guess Scrabble.
Take a guess as to how we could access the value Jose from this dictionary.
Some people might be tempted to do this.
However remember that anything in Python that is not a number plate and thinks it is a variable.
So this works if name is a variable.
If we say name is something then this is fine and it we try to access the key.
That is nothing.
However just like that Python thinks name should be a variable but it's not defined.
So it gives us an error.
And as you can see programs has unresolved reference because it doesn't know what name is.
So remember whenever we want to access a literal representation of something we have to use the quotation
marks which can be single or double and it doesn't matter.
But they have to match.
And if we do that now my name comes out which is fantastic.
This can be used as a data storage we can use it to put information about our users or about items that
are shopping stocking or information about transactions or information to be sent over the internet
.
Jason which is essentially what this is a python dictionary is very equivalent to Jason.
And you'll you'll find that shortly in this course this is very widely used across the entire Internet
to send data from one web site to another.
And these Python dictionaries there's this format where you have a key and a value is extremely popular
.
So we've quickly looked at what the dictionary is and remember that a dictionary is a set of key value
pairs you and therefore you cannot have two of these things because it has to be a set.
And the key is that the set element and this and in this instance we've got a duplicate key and that's
not OK.
So the dictionary is a set of key value pairs a set of keys that has each key a value associated with
it and we can access the keys by just like we can in a set.
Accessing the specific key that we want to access inside the square bracket.
So this is everything for this video.
We've looked at quite a lot of stuff but we've reviewed and we've learned what dictionaries are and
they are going to be extremely useful throughout this section in the app are going to be building.
So I'll see you the next video