Hi come back in this video we're looking at how we can execute sequel code here in the P.G. Atman 3
.
Once you've selected your database this ball up here becomes active and you can execute arbitrary sequel
queries because the aim of this course is to teach you how to use sequel code and how to write it and
how to understand it.
We're going to be doing most if not all of the interactions with the server the sequel code as opposed
to the graphical interface.
Nevertheless this interface allows you to run the Queenie's and see some output and even this explain
button here or there can help you understand what is going on as well.
So whenever we want to execute sequel code we're just going to type it here and then we're going to
press play.
There's a couple of other buttons that we can use the usual copy and paste.
We can save the result we find if the result is very large.
In some cases we may want to do that.
And then we can also explain the query and explanations are not naturally aiming to teach you sequel
but rather that can explain what's going on behind the scenes and sometimes back in.
Also remember this is a database that you are writing to and that's the learning database on postgres
at localhost.
So this is what we are interacting with.
Finally you've also got a history of previous queries which is empty for now.
Here's.
Just in case you want to re execute something in the past the next few videos are going to be about
installing and running post-grads on Mac bots.
Naturally you don't have to worry about those.
If you're using Windows you can skip straight to the video that starts explaining sequel code and just
write your secret code in here and then press play and will interact with the server via this sequel
code.
So with that said I'll be seeing you in the video that starts explaining sequel code.
So either