Find Welcome Back in this video we're looking at numbers and strings.
In some cases we want to be able to add numbers together.
For example when we want to calculate that the average age of our users we may want to add all their
ages together divided by the number of users age in this case with a is a number.
And then we add all the numbers together divided by another number and Python understands that numbers
are things that have that meaning they're just symbols that we can add or multiply together.
However in some cases we may not want to add numbers together or multiply them or divide them or do
any mathematical operations with them.
For example the case of telephone numbers you're never going to want to add a telephone number to another
or multiply it or anything.
So it doesn't make sense to treat a telephone number which is a set of numbers the same way you may
treat a number that you want to do arithmetic with.
Do mathematical operations with.
So that's why Python has as many other programming languages do.
The concept of a string a string which is also sometimes called literal is just that it's a literal
representation of something and that something can be anything you want.
So for example you can have the string which is devastated by these two quotation marks such as the
string to and the string to is something different from the number to the number two has that meaning
.
It means two units the string two just means the symbol two.
So it has no other intrinsic meaning.
If you add the string to to the string two Python understands these are literal representations of something
it no or what but it knows that its the symbol to use know what the symbol means.
So what did the Lu is it'll do the most logical thing to do when you have two strings which is it will
concatenate them.
It will add them together.
It doesn't know that they have any meaning so I cannot give you back for.
So it just concatenates them and joins them together.
OK so here's a small question for you.
What would happen if we get the string to and multiply it by a number in the last video.
I mentioned that when you multiply a number by another what you are getting to is a certain number of
units.
That is the result of that multiplication.
So take your best guess at what is going to happen when we do this.
And the answer is that we are going to get three sets of the unit string 2 and then it's going to give
us to do two because that's the the string two multiplied by three.
And here is a slightly trickier question for you.
What happens if we add the string to to the number two.
Remember the number two is something that has meaning the addition symbol means we want to add to the
units represented by two and the string two does not have any special meaning it's just a literal representation
of the symbol.
So take your best guess at what will happen and it might surprise you.
Some would say you would concatenate the string.
But actually what you get is a lot of read text.
So what it's saying is that you can't convert int which is an integer an integer and the whole number
is the same thing.
So basically what it's saying is you can't convert the two which is a whole number to a string.
Implicitly Python is saying you want me to add these two things together but I actually just don't know
how to do that.
So you can't do it.
So it gives you an error back which is fine.
And that's kind of the main difference between strings and numbers.
Numbers are things you might want to do mathematics with.
You might want to add them or multiply them and strings are literal representations of things.
So you can have the string Jose which is my name.
That's just the string.
Jose you can have the string.
One two three four.
Which is just the string.
It doesn't have any special meaning.
Notice that Python does not care if you use double quotation marks or single quotation marks around
strings.
So this string here with two quotation marks and and this one here with single quotation marks are both
equally valid.
And Python does not make a distinction between those.
OK.
So we've looked at strings and numbers and what happens when we add the two together you get an error
.
And that's something that you may encounter.
What a lot of times and during your Python development career.
It's a very common error to try to add strings and numbers together and we'll see exactly when that
happens very soon.
OK.
So this was the video about numbers and strings and I'll see you in the next one we're going to be looking
at variables