Hi will come back in this video.
We're going to be looking at the time method the filter method is one of various Python methods that
are extremely useful.
So let's start by looking at the filter method.
And as you may guess the filter method is used to filter things out from a list.
The first thing I want to do is move it forward with the objective of this app which is allowing the
user to keep track of what movies they've watched in order for the user to know which movies they've
watched.
Naturally the movie has to have a property say in whether it has been watched or not.
Alternatively the user could have a list of movies that have already been watched.
So the user could have a list of movies and then a list of watched movies or the movie can have a property
which he's watched and then it is true if the movie has been watched and falls if it has not been watched
.
Those are two possible ways of implementing this.
I'm going to opt for setting whether the movie has been watched or not.
So I'm going to add another property here watched and then I'm going to say self-taught watched is watched
and what this will do is if self-taught watched is true then I'll assume that the user has watched this
movie and if self-taught watched is false then I'll assume the user has not watched the movie.
OK so now when we come here to our apt up he why.
Notice that Pitre gives us a faint yellow background on this bracket and it says that prompter watch
these on field.
So we have to say here whether it has been watched or not.
And you know I'm going to say false because it has not been watched.
OK.
So this allows me to specify what that movie has been watched or not.
But it doesn't let me get which movies the user has watched or which movies the user has not watched
.
So that's what we're going to be doing.
Now
I'm going to create a method in the User class that will give me the movies that have been watched and
I think you can do this already using a for loop and a list.
Let's I'll get you started.
Watched movies and what I want this method to do is calculate or gather the A list of movies that have
been watched.
And I'm going to give you a couple more hints.
You may want to initialize an empty list then iterate over self-dual movies.
If the movie watched is true add it to the list return the list.
A few hints there for you.
What I would recommend now is to pause the video and give that a shot.
It's the best way to learn.
Honestly
once that has been done let's implement this method here.
There are two ways there are many ways but two ways to implement this.
The first way which is the way I would expect you to have implemented it and there is a second way that
is the aim of this video that's first implemented the first way we define a list of watched movies which
is going to be an empty list and then we're going to iterate
over self-taught movies and say if movie top watched then watched movies sliced up and movie and then
return watched the movies released.
This is the way that I would have expected you to complete and implement this method.
First the fist and define an empty list and then iterate over self-edit movies check for each movie
it has if it has been watched and then append the watch to movie to this list.
And finally the list
naturally if we then print huge or not watched movies we should get nothing.
And indeed we do.
Because the movie has not been watched.
If we change this to true which says that it has been watched and we press play again we should get
that movie print it out and we do.
That's great.
The aim of this video was to introduce the film method which is really useful for doing exactly this
.
So let's go over how we could implement this using the filter method.
The way I do this is say movies watched is filter and the filter method is a builtin method in Python
.
And then what it requires is first a function and then the list that we want to filter the function
here is a lamp but the function lammed x x watched and then Safdar movies.
So let's explain exactly what's going on here.
The filter method takes in a list of movies that's fine.
And it also takes in the Lumb definition a lambda function is just like a normal function but it is
defined here in just one line without the death and things like that.
A lambda function also doesn't have a name.
So you cannot save it and then call it again later.
This lambda function takes in one parameter which is X just like the init method takes in name.
There's lambda function takes an X and then it returns true if X dot watched it's true and false if
X dot watched is false.
So this lambda function returns whether the parameter passed to it is watched or not and X is each of
the elements in self-taught movies
and then we return movies watched and we get a small error.
But let's go back to our app and run that and what we get is a filter object not very useful.
What we have to do is go back into user and convert this filter object to a list.
And now when we run the app again we get the movie The Matrix.
Let's once again go over this.
The film that is extremely powerful because it is so short it has essentially compressed the method
that we wrote before.
By a factor of three.
What it does is it takes in a list.
In this case movies and then passes each of the elements in that list to the function that we defined
previously.
This function takes in one parameter which is that movie and I'm calling it X but you can call it movie
if you want.
That may be simpler.
Sorry about that.
Each of the movies goes into this lambda function and the lambda function then returns whether it has
been watched or not.
The filter function removes from this list all elements that match this to be false.
So all elements that have not been watched then get removed from the list with the filter method and
reconvert that then two ways we can then further decrease the size of this by just returning this there
.
OK.
So if we go back to our app and run this again we get the matrix if we change false we should get nothing
.
And indeed we do.
While I appreciate the VCs a bit more complicated it's just a bit more strange and abstract than before
.
I think you guys can get a hold of that and grasp that each of the elements in the movies is past the
function and then the function performs a check if the check returns false the element gets removed
from the list and that's all there is to the filter function.
Really useful function with that said we now have a method that returns the watched movies of the user
and now we can use that to show the user some more relevant information.
OK.
So with that said let's move on to the next video see you there