I will welcome back in this video we're going to be talking about dealing with files.
I'm just going to go into the Test folder here so you can see that my video 0.60 file has been created
.
And now what I want to do is I want to rename the file because video Dotti XTi no longer is an appropriate
name.
There is actually no native way of renaming files.
The only thing we can do is move the file and move it from video Dr. 60 to another file with a different
name.
And then it going to rename the file.
So I'm going to do M.V. for move.
And then because I am inside the Desktop folder I need to go into test and then into video that takes
me and then I can move the file to a different location.
For example I could move it to video not the XTi only and naturally that's going to move it from past
slash video or text me into it up to 60.
So the file is going to disappear from the text folder and into the parent folder which is where I am
currently at.
So you can see the video.
This appears there and it appears in the desktop.
Let's undo that and do M.V. video that takes the test and this is going to move the video RTX the folder
into the Test folder without changing the name.
So it moves it there.
And finally to rename which is what we originally wanted to do video on site test slash video dot DXi
into past slash.
Hello Dottie XTi and that is going to move the file from video that takes me into hello Dottie XTi.
So what it's doing really is renaming it.
And as you can see the name has changed there as well.
In some cases you are going to want to extract or read the content of a file but maybe you don't want
to launch vim because it's a bit too heavyweight just for reading the content of a file.
So for example if we wanted to read the content of halloed ATX t we would have to do vim haloed on takes
the test on DST rather and then we'd have to read the content and then we'd have to press call on q
to quit.
It's just a bit of a hassle.
And also to remember while you are modifying test slash halloed actually XTi in a computer.
Nobody else can modify the same file or the same type.
So even if you are opening halloed RTX the only for reading.
Nobody else can go into that file at the same time.
This is not important if you're using your own computer.
But if you're using a shared computer then that might be an issue at some point.
So instead of launching vim.
If you only want to read content use the command called cat and cat is used to concatenate things.
That's where the name comes from but it can also be used to read things.
So just do kept and then the file that you want to read and the contents of it come out and get displayed
.
So this is how you can move files or rename them and also how you can display the text contents of a
file and that's everything for this short video I just wanted to show you how you can deal with files
and move them about and stuff and that's it.
As you the next video