I will come back in this video.
We're going to do two movie operations.
Both of them.
Y'all really know how to do so let's get started with the first one.
The first operation that I'd like to be able to do as a user is to add a new movie and tell the system
that I have or own a movie.
I'll give you some structure and then you can continue the implementation
here too.
And a new movie you would simply append the movie object to self-taught movies because we are currently
inside the user which means whoever is calling the ADD movie method must be doing so in this way.
My user object or some variable name dot and movie and then we obviously need some movie parameters
name and genre.
For example movie name and genre.
When this method gets called it is going to get called in this way some user object dot add movie with
a name and a genre.
Therefore the user object is going to be somebody with a name and a list of movies which means that
we can then append a new movie using these two properties to self-dual movies.
Also remember the movie has a watched property and we are gonna see that the movie has not been watched
by default.
OK so go ahead and post a video and try that.
And a new movie using this name and genre and see that it has not been watched.
And add that movie to self-taught movies
once thats been attempted lets go over a how I would recommend to do it.
First thing to do is say the new movie is going to be a movie which will have to import and I'm just
going to import them here through Pinetree I'm with a name and a genre but it also needs whether it's
been botched or not.
And I'm gonna say no it could be false and that's what that means.
You know we created the new movie object which has a specific name and a specific genre.
We don't know what those are in here.
But we know that they've been passed in from somewhere else and that has not been watched.
And then we can self-taught movies top and movie and that just adds the movie at the end of the list
.
If you wanted to simplify this further you could just put this in here
like so whoever however for the sake of readability I'm not going to do that and I'm just going to keep
it like this.
I think that's slightly easier to read.
However I do remember that doing it this way is slightly less performing because you have to initialize
a variable.
It doesn't really matter much.
I think it is more readable to leave it like that.
The other thing I want to do is to delete a movie
and in this case we going to delete a movie with a specific name.
We're going to pass in the name of the movie we want to delete.
And that movie is going to get deleted from self-taught movies.
I'm going to let you implement this.
Whichever way you see best you can do it in two ways really just like the watched movies but remember
self-taught movies must end with the movie with that name deleted if it exists and that is you may want
to use the filter method.
Or you can also build up a list that doesn't have this movie in it.
Post a video and try that and I recommend taking your time.
If you understand the implementation and how you're going to do it and then implemented and then come
back and watch.
OK I hope you did well in that.
Let's implement this using the simpler method which is the filter.
What I'm going to do is say the new movies the ones without that movie name are filter Lamda movie where
movie name is not equal to name and then I passed and self-taught movies.
So this is going to filter from self movies all the movies where this is true.
The movies where this is true are going to get removed from self-edit movies.
But remember we have to say self-direct movies equals that it doesn't happen automatically we have to
reassign self-taught movies to whatever this returns and over a number just like below.
We have to convert this to a list.
If you're using Python 2.7 you won't have to do this conversion.
But if you're using Python three point three or later you will have to use this list in.
OK so to recap what this does is it goes over iterates over self-doubt movies and even the movie name
is not equal to the name we pass in.
It keeps that movie.
If the name is equal then it does not keep the movie and what that means is that the movies that match
this name get deleted.
OK so that's everything for this video.
We've looked at how to append a movie and also how to delete a movie.
Do remember to add onto the leads movies.
We're going to have to pass in these values from somewhere else probably.
I use a menu with which the user will interact.
But again that's everything.
So I'll see you in the next video.