Hi We'll come back in this video we're looking at the nested select and the nested select is extremely
useful because it lets us nest queries inside other queries and you're probably wondering.
That sounds a bit like complex and I agree it is.
But let me give you an example as to why the nested select is useful and how you might go about using
it.
Going to give you a couple examples in fact.
Let's see if we want to find out what items we own in our business which are above the average price
of our items.
For example we could do this if we wanted to figure out whether those items sell less well here's how
the English language would try select store from items where price is greater than the average price
.
And I agree it would be very nice if this worked but it doesn't.
And now you're probably wondering well what about that having construct was having not useful in these
scenarios and having is not useful in this scenario because having is to be used with put up by.
And here we don't have a group by just selecting from one table.
So having is not the answer the answer is the nested select.
We want to make sure that price is greater than the average price.
So how do we calculate the average price
and we put that inside brackets down here.
So how do we calculate the average selling price of our items.
And I may just look weird and wrong to do this but we just do what we've done before.
Select average items price from items.
There you go.
So what that's doing is it is executing this select average items range from items and is putting the
result in there.
So we're going to see a select start from items where price is greater than the result of this query
.
And these are the items that are above average price.
It's quite nice but I mean it's nice we can put it in the where.
Which means that we can do more advanced filtering and based on values of other tables or indeed the
same table and that's nice.
What else can we use it for.
Well let's find out for these items or indeed for any item.
How much above or below the average price they are just really give us a bit of a deviation from the
average.
We're going to do select items name items price and the price we want to subtract from it the average
from items.
Okay.
So let me explain what went on here.
We're going to select items not name and items not price from items but we are going to subtract from
items on price.
The average selling price of our items and we know how to do that we're just done it in the last query
.
It's just going to be as you know select average items price from items
pego expenses some of them are quite expensive but that is how you would go about that.
And notice how I've put everything in one line and here.
But again you can put it in multiple lines if you want it doesn't matter.
This would be the normal way to put it in indenting the sub query.
OK.
One more example for you.
Let's create a view for luxury items which also tells us the price difference from the average luxury
item.
So as you know luxury items I'm going to or rather expensive items I'm going to call expensive items
those items that are above $100.
So the first thing to do is to find out the average selling price of items that are over $100.
I think you can do this.
It is what I mean construed a complicated thing to explain but the average price of items which are
over $100 in price.
Okay.
So that would be select average of items not place from items when the price of the item is over 100
and that gives me 725.
So that is the average price of my sort of quote unquote expensive items.
Right.
And now I want to select
the expensive items and the difference between their price and the average price of expensive items
that would be select stock and items not price minus this query
from items where price is greater than 100.
So once again what is happening is that I'm selecting all of the columns from items and I'm also selecting
items on price which is the price of the item from selecting the price twice.
But this price I'm going to subtract from it the result of this query which is 725 and I'm going to
do this for all my items with their price is over 100.
So this of Queenie's giving me the result of the average price of items over 100.
And this query is only getting those items that are over 100.
So as you can see this laptop is the most expensive.
That's right.
The screen is the cheapest and then the volume is the most deviated from the average downwards.
And then this one is slightly less so.
And finally we could also create this into a view just to recap we could create view for example expensive
items diff as all of this and now we can do select star from expensive items.
And there you go.
Notice how we have not named this Colan So he has a question mark.
Call question mark which is not the best name.
So let's go back and fix that drop with you and then let's go in here.
And this item's price minus the query of the end we can give an alias as
average beef for example.
And where is how because this is a column name I can use double quotation marks and then we can select
start from expensive items.
And now that has the name vair average if.
Also notice that because the price was created in the table as a numeric type of 10 Colmar 2 it is limited
to 2 decimal places but this is a calculation.
And so it is not limited to two decimal places.
And that way it has all these decimal places.
There's ways around that.
But for now it doesn't really bother us that much.
So we're going to leave it at that.
And that is how you might go about creating some queries.
Remember you can use a squeeze in the WHERE clause or you can use them in the select part.
You can use them essentially anyway.
And my suggestion to you is if you think that you need a subplot they should query just put it in and
see what happens.
And that is the best way to learn and get acquainted with sequel and make sure that you know everything
that we've been talking about just by watching the videos.
It is not enough.
You need to go in here.
This is why I've gone into installing posh grenades and using it all that stuff so that you do use it
and that is my recommendation.
Don't stop at watching the video even though that's good.
Make sure to try it.
Program it.
Write it test it in as many combinations as you can because that's what's going to make the difference
and that's what's going to let you learn a lot more.
OK so with that said now it's the end of this video.
So thanks for watching and I'll see you on the next one.