Hi we'll come back.
Hopefully you've managed to attempt and successfully implemented your linked list.
Remember once you have implemented your list all you have to do is right click the test file and run
unit tests in Tests.
Once you do that you should see this bar go green and no tests failed.
Well we're going to be doing in this video is naturally implement these two methods and tell you how
I would go about implementation.
It is possible that you've implemented them slightly differently if the tests pass.
It means that you've done a good job and if you think that something is substantially different and
you're not sure how it works or you think your solution is better which is a possibility or you think
your solution is worse and you want some tips on how to improve it please do post it to the forums.
I've always interested in looking at what you've done without further ado let's go about implementing
this linked list.
The add to list method as we know from the lecture should add at the beginning of the linked list.
This means that the root should become the new unit.
The root is always the first node of the linked list.
So this method should make sure the root is now the new node that is the parameter.
How do we make the root equal to the new node.
Well it's fairly simple self-doubt on the or on the root equals node.
This we make the root equal to the new node.
However what happens if the root already had a value.
Well it will get overwritten and the old root deleted or lost and we don't want to do that.
We want to make sure that the new node becomes the root bought the new node points to or has as a next
node the previous root.
So how do we do that node.
Don't sent next self don't on this one particular route.
And what this does is it says send to the next node of the new node to be the current root and then
we sentence the roots to be equal to the new node.
The root may be none but that's not a problem because the next node of any node can also be none.
And that just means there isn't a node there.
So this is how we would implement the add to list method.
Although if you want to be explicit and clear you could do if self dot underscore underscore root and
then do that.
It's not necessary.
I like this because it kind of makes it a bit clearer that we are checking that the root is set before
setting it so set is not necessary because we can set the next to be none and that's fine but I like
this better because it kind of makes a bit more sense to hear what we're doing.
If the route currently exists.
Make sure that the new nodes next node is the root.
So it kind of joins in at the beginning and then make this variable here.
This route to be equal to the new node.
So the route will now point to the node we're adding and that node will point to what was before the
root.
I know this is complicated and it is a bit of a sort of mind twisting concept at this pointing between
classes and objects but due to your time to understand it and do ask any questions if you have any.
The find method apologies are deleted at ibiquity.
The find method should find a node in the linked list with the given name.
Remember each node has a name which is the name of the student so the parameter name which is described
here is the name of the node to find in this list and it will return the node found or a lookup error
if no node was found with the given name.
OK let's delete that and try to implement this find method.
We have to iterate over each node so we have to start at the root and then we need a way to move on
to the next node and then into the next node and then to the next node and so on.
So what to do with that is create a martyr a variable called marker which is going to be initialized
to people root this marker variable is what I'm going to call each of the nodes in sequence in my list
.
So while marker this means while marker is not none remember while marker.
Same thing then I'll do if Mark or dot name equally will name return marker and what this does is it
first it sets a variable marker to be the root and then it initializes a while loop which is going to
repeat the contents of the loop for as long as marker is not known if root has none.
Then this is not going to run at all.
If root is a node then this will run at least once and the first time it runs is going to check if the
marker name is equal to the name we're looking for the parameter.
And if it is it's going to return the marker which in the first instance would be the root in the next
instance.
We want the marker to be the roots next node and then the next node and then the next minute.
So what we do is marker equal marker get next to what this does is and the first time the while loop
runs.
This will be the route it will check for the Monken name and return it if it's necessary.
If it's not then we will set the market to be equal to the markers next so the marker now will be the
second node of the list and we will run this again.
Then it will be the third node and we will run this again and then will be the fourth node and so on
.
If at any point we find the marker we are going to return it and that's going to exit the loop and the
method.
So we're only going to go as far as finding the name in the list.
Do remember that we could have multiple students with the same name and this is only going to find the
first student with that name and not all of them.
If we exit the while loop it means that we have not returned.
If we've not returned it means that we've not found a node with the name that we are looking for.
So if we do reach at some point the end of the is why loop we have to then to the code.
Then here we raise a lookup error and we see name was not found in the linked list
like so if we exit the while loop that means we have not found a node and then we raise the lookup error
and we say as an error message that the name we were looking for was not found in the linked list and
that's all that is the find method.
And now once you run the tests they should all pass and you should see all six tests passed on the green
bar there.
If you do things like get a bit of the code such as a raising then the tests will not pass fully.
So make sure to include all of the requirements that I wrote in the assignment text.
Hopefully you were able to do something like this and your tests did pass but if they didn't then that's
absolutely fine because you have now learned how to implement a linked list and how it works over the
next few data structures.
We were going to be implementing this knowledge is going to be essential for you to continue developing
the data structures that I'm going to be suggesting.
They are all fairly similar except the last one.
So for the next two more data structures you can reuse this knowledge that you've gained here and that's
going to be essential for you to be able to implement those new data structures.
The next day the structure is going to be looking at is the queue which is going to be using a linked
list is going to work slightly differently but a lot of things are going to be similar.
So please do move on to the next video.
Well we're going to be looking at Qs and I'm sure you will quickly understand that and be able to implement
it.
I'll see you in the very next video.