Hi welcome back in this review we're going to look at the in key.
We've already seen the in keyword in our four loops.
It's right here in orange but we've not really understood what it means.
So what we're going to do now is try and use it outside of a for loop and see what happens.
So let me give you a sort of hint I'm going to type 10 in numbers and what do you think is going to
get printed out when I type 10 in numbers it sort of follows.
English language convention.
What gets printed out is false.
And you know why that is.
Now you can join the dots together.
Ten is not inside that list than is not in numbers.
So it prints false.
Now I can also say 10 not in numbers and then that Prince group as you would expect.
OK.
The not keyword can also be used in other contexts as well.
For example if not three greater than five print this is weird
if it is a bit strange you would never use this.
You would rather say three less than five for example.
But nevertheless you can use it in front of any boolean expression and it just inverts it.
So true is true.
Not true is false and that's the way Python thinks about it.
You've got your boolean expression ten in numbers three greater than five.
True.
And if you put not in front of it it just invert it and gives you the opposite.
So in this case it would give you false.
In this case it would give you true.
And in this case it would give you true.
OK.
So now we can proceed with our magic numbers app.
Now we're going to be developing in this section.
Let's create a magic underscore numbers list that contains a couple of numbers and our user is going
to guess one of these numbers.
So for example I'm going to type 3 or 9 and now that's inside our variable we can ask the user for a
number which I'm going to just pretend a user on the school number is going to be 4.
And then we're going to tell the user whether they got the number right or not.
So essentially whether the number they gave us is inside this list or not.
You can do that.
You know the key word and there's two variables there.
So you can get whether this is true or false
the way you would do it.
You say use it on the number in magic underscore numbers and that would give you false.
But it's not very good if we just add the user false.
So we want to tell the user this number is not part of the magic numbers for example and you can do
this with an if statement and with a print method.
So go ahead and try and do that.
If you use a number is not in magic numbers print you got it wrong.
So there's two ways we could do this.
If use a number in magic numbers print you got it right.
Which it doesn't print anything or if user Andreyko number.
Not in magic numbers print.
You got it wrong.
Which does print something.
However if they do get it right this version is not going to print anything if they get it wrong.
This version is not going to print anything.
So if we say user on this call number is three and then we say this he's going to copy and paste it
then that doesn't print anything which is what you would want.
And this one does print something which is that you got it right.
So that's fantastic.
And in the next video we're going to look at how we can simplify this a bit more and make sure that
the user is getting the feedback that they want.
So I'll be seeing you in the very next video