Hi all come back in this video we're going to be looking at writing to a file.
And this really is not going to be related to the app that we've created so far.
I just wanted to introduce you to how you might open a file right to it and then close it so that in
the next few videos we can work on saving our users and our movies to a file in life and it's actually
really simple to open a file and write to it.
The only thing you have to do is use the open method.
In fact what we're going to do is use the special construct and the reason we're using the special construct
that I'm going to show you in a moment is because of the need of closing files when you've finished
writing to them.
If you open a file and you don't close it.
Python may not finish writing to it.
What you told it to write therefore it is especially important that when you open a file and then write
to it you close it at the end.
And this plays in nicely with a special construct that I'm going to show you because this construct
takes care of closing the file when you're done with it.
So you don't have to remember about closing the file if you use this construct and the construct is
as follows with open.
And then your file name my file Dotti XTi comma w as F and then you can here do something.
Let me explain exactly what this does.
The key part here for opening a file is this bit of the line here.
Open my file are tasty and w it has to be w if you want to write to the file because write starts with
a W if you want to read from the file you would use R and there is a number of other letters you can
use to do different things.
No going to go into them here because we simply don't need either w anything other than w r.
Finally as F. says open this file using the writing mode and call it f and the file is going to be called
f.
So now when we want to interact with the file we can say F dot right and then hello world for example
.
And f is the file we've opened.
Now because we've used the with constructor when we reach the end of the indented code the code that
is below the colon and inside the with block when we reach the end which is here.
And then it goes down and stops being indented Python.
OK that's the end of the with block we no longer need f.
So now let's close it and then you don't you don't have to say after PLOS which would be what you would
have to do if you didn't use a with block so that I quoted it for you.
And if we run app you why.
Notice how my file actually appears there.
We can open that and it shows.
Hello world.
Similarly if we use our we can read so we can say print.
If not read line.
And when we run that we see Hello world coming out.
The purpose of this video was just to introduce you to this with construct.
The fact that we can open files using the open command we give it the name and the mode which we have
right and read as well as a number of others and ask f simply tells us that the file is called F..
Inside this context here and here we can either write to the file or we're using W or read from it if
we are using our Without done.
Let's move on to the next video we're going to be working on saving our user to a file.
I'll see you there.