Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to look at a pending to a list in the last video we were
able to create a student with this Creech student method that encapsulates and contains that functionality
that allows us to ask the user for the student's name and then it returns a dictionary that represents
the properties of a student the name and the marks and it could have more if we wanted.
And also remember we no longer need this thing up here.
So I'm just going to delete that to clean it up.
Now we in this with you I wanted to make sure that we could make this more useful by adding marks to
each student.
So what we have to do is somehow get this list and then modify it and add another element.
Let's let's work from the beginning let's forget about the student itself first and just worry about
how do we add an element to the list.
How do we add a number to a list.
Because I don't think we've done that before.
So let's create a list which I'm going to call my list but you can call it whatever you want and it's
going to be an empty list.
And at the end of the last video I give you a subtle hint as to what the method to append to a list
might be called that if I just gave you another hint right there.
Yes.
So it'll be my honest goal list and then full stop.
And as the first one never mind I was going to ask you if you could guess but it is the first one.
So you can just do my list not append five.
So my question to you is since I didn't ask you that what is going to happen when I do this when I print
my list append 5.
What do you think will come out.
What do you think is going to get printed out.
Is it going to be a list with the number five.
And what comes out is none.
And well that's surprising.
And the reason why it comes out as none is because these Penda method that we call on that list we're
saying my list we're going to call this apan method that you own.
That's where the full stop means.
This list Ohmes and contains this app hand method.
So we're calling the append method of that specific list.
This specific empty list and what it does is it puts the five in the list as you would assume that it
would do.
But it doesn't return anything doesn't give us back the list.
It simply modifies the list in place.
And now my list should contain the number five.
I'm going to run this again.
And indeed you can see that the number five is now in it.
So even though the append method didn't return anything it did modify the list and that makes sense
because appending things does not involve returning what's been appended or the thing that has been
modified or pending is just appending it isn't giving you anything back.
So I deleted too many things.
So I just delete the print method.
And now we can append something to my list.
And notice how when we do this Pinetree was actually quite smart and it tells us this list creation
could be rewritten as a list literal.
And what that means is it's asking is What are you doing that you are clearly not very smart because
you could instead just do that and it's right we could do that but that's not the point.
That's how we can append elements to a list.
And this is going to add to the five as a new element into that list.
And that is exactly what we want to do with the student data.
We want to get that list and then append to it.
What I would ask you to attempt is to create another method that will do that.
Now that's going to be a bit more difficult because the method that it being a separate method it won't
know about the student that you've created here.
But nevertheless if I just ask you to try and create a method that will allow you to append to the marks
list of a student see what you can come up with just to have a think about it and then we'll move onto
the next video.
Well we're going to be implementing just that.
So give it a give it a bit of thought try it and then we'll move on to the next video and all your doubts
will be solved there.
So you were