Find the Mac in this video let's talk about creating the good repository.
Remember when we're talking about get all of your files are in your file system and then we can use
get on top of that or the file system is your sort of base layer.
And you never lose the content of files in your file system unless you use specific get commands that
were going to be covering.
Remember that if you lose things from your file system and you've not put them in it then you've lost
them.
So good is not a safe for everything and but it does provide some safety anyway.
In the first video let's create the depositary which as you know is going to allow you access to the
other layers.
The staging area the commits and pushing to a remote repository later on the first command that we need
is inside the folder that we want to convert into a repository.
This is the folder that we want to take snapshots of the files that are in it.
We can do get in it and that initializes the get repository in this folder and notice what happens when
I press enter.
I've got the same folder open here in the Finder for you to see
the don't get folder appears.
And inside this not get folder.
We have the staging area which is a physical folder as well as a history of snapshots that we have done
which so far we've not done any.
This is what I meant with the layers of physical layers that are stored inside your dot gatefold.
Therefore it is important that you do not delete your dot gatefold.
Don't think this is some crap that you can delete don't delete your don't get folder unless you are
sure that you want to delete your project.
You know all the files related to it.
The files in our project are going to be outside the docket folder.
But when we add them to the staging area parts of the files get copied over to the docket folder.
When we commit them that is create the snapshot the snapshot are also added to the docket folders.
Don't get folder has the history and all that stuff.
And if you delete it you'll lose the history unless you put them in a online service like get up.
Once you've created your get in it you'll get repository you have access in this directory and in other
folders inside this directory to get commands.
One such get command is good status which is a very useful command that I would encourage you to use
often get started tells you the status or the status of your files within the gate ecosystem.
Let's press enter and we can see a bit of information we have on Branch master and we're not going to
be looking at branches in discourse that's a bit more advanced topic but nevertheless I would encourage
you to explore it later on.
There is an initial commit.
This means we haven't done any commits previous to the one that we could do now and then it gives us
a list of untracked files.
These are files that get knows nothing about because we've never added them to a snapshot before and
it tells us.
Use get and file to include it in would we be committed.
We're going to look at how to do that in the next video and then it has nothing added to commit but
untracked files present.
This is the untracked files and it tells us that we've not added anything to the staging area yet.
We're going to be looking at adding things to the staging area and committing them in the next video
.
Without further ado let's go there.
So to your