Hi will come back in this video we're talking about adding files and committing them before we can add
files and commit them.
We need to create a file.
We do have the dot D.S. store file but this is a file that is created by the finder in Apple and is
not really useful for anything.
So let's not add that to our Snapshot.
In fact I would recommend that you never add that to your snapshot.
It's not a very useful thing to add.
Let's create a file called app Doppie Y.
And as you remember we can do that using vim.
Do you remember the command that we have to use to create a new file with vim.
The answer is vim and then the name of the file that we want to create at IPY And this as you can see
creates a new file.
Something interesting to notice is that we also create a file even before saving the file that we created
.
And this file is called dot dot dot as W.P. and you won't see this normally unless you've got this show
hidden files and folders option activated in your computer.
But nevertheless what this file does is as I've mentioned before and of course prevents other people
from accessing the apt IPY file while you're modifying it the swap file and essentially tells the system
that the file is being currently modified by someone.
So that's what that file is.
Anyway that was just an aside.
Let's press I to go into insert mode and then enter some Python code like print hello world then press
escape to leave insert mode colon WQ to right and quit.
And that now deletes the swap file and creates apt y in there.
Now let's press get staffer's again and see what the difference is.
As you can see the only difference now is that it adds app Doppie y to the untracked files.
Let's follow the recommendation and use get add to include it in what will be committed so get ADD and
then apt.
Why that doesn't seem to do anything.
And now get status will show us a bit of a difference now as well as the untracked file in datt the
store.
We also have changes to be committed and in them there's this new file that we've just created called
app Doppie Why get says this is a new file because we've never included it in a previous snapshot before
.
And so this is why it says this new file at IPY there.
And we also can unstaged files and remove them from the staging area which is what we've done so that
they will not be committed when we do we commit.
Remember we can only have one staging area at a time.
So when you're doing a commit you may want to include some files but not others.
And if you add a file by accident to the staging area you can unstaged it.
This will not change the contents of the file.
You can do that with get r.m dash dash cached and then up top you might notice how Abdul was still in
my folder.
But if we do get status nowadays untracked again let's add it uncommitted.
So I'm going to get ADD at Doppie why.
And now once again get stato shows that this is going to be committed.
And I would recommend that you get into the habit of running get status after every command just to
make sure you're not doing anything incorrectly.
It's a bit of a hassle if you commit something that you didn't want to commit although you can go back
and change history.
It does take a bit of effort actually.
So it's better to run get starters and make sure you're doing the right thing to run a commit that will
save a snapshot of the file and it will essentially just get that file get the contents of the file
and saved them in saying that don't get folder.
And then it will and remove it from the staging area because you've already committed the exchange.
Let's do get commit and now an important part of the commit is a description of what the commit is for
what it does what it contains essentially good is very useful because in the future you can go back
and look at a list of commits and it's useful if each commit has a message that tells you kind of what
happened in that commit.
It's good to be able to quickly glance at a history so you can locate the correct commit more easily
.
The way we add a message to commit is by doing dash em and then here at the end we can in safe quotes
put in a short message for example added printing of Hello World to the app and then we press enter
and then we get a few things we get.
This first line tells the committee that was created in M..
It is the route Committee which just means that is the first commit that we've ever done.
And then it gives you a short code which is the commit ID identifier and then it gives you the commit
message that you've added just so you can verify that this is correct.
Then it tells you who made the commit.
In this case it's me and also it gives you my email although this is not my e-mail address.
And after it tells you a bit of an error or a bit of a warning rather it says your name and e-mail address
were configured automatically based on your username and hostname.
My laptop is called Joses dasht MBP.
Please check that they are accurate which they are not.
You can suppress this message by setting them explicitly.
Run the following command and follow the instructions in your editor to edit your configuration file
.
So basically get has smartly tried to figure out my name and my e-mail address to save those along the
commit so people can then see who made the commit.
However it wasn't smart enough to figure out my real email address naturally.
So we have to go and change that.
Never the less the commit has happened.
So if we do get status we will see that the file has now disappeared from the staging area.
And now the only thing that remains is the untracked files.
So the commit has happened.
We're going to look in the next video at how we can tell that it has happened.
But in this video let's also access that config by just running this command here so we can copy that
and paste it in and then it damn it has the config file here and we can just remove the hash symbols
by going into insert mode and deleting each other has symbols and then going and changing the email
address to whatever you think is reasonable which should be your email address.
However you can set that to whatever you want if you don't want people looking at your e-mail address
.
You can just leave that as null or a fake e-mail address your name should probably be correct.
OK.
Once that's done you can escape and press call on WQ for right and quit.
And that's that.
You now have saved your e-mail address in there.
And finally if you want to change the commit so it doesn't show as an incorrect e-mail address you can
run this Kamandi.
And I'm going to run it just to make sure that it is correct.
And here this is the commit message that we can also change but we don't want to change that so just
press call on WQ and that's that changed.
OK.
So for a lot we've covered in this video like how to add to files how to stage them how to commit them
at the commit message sent to your get config and change the author of a previous commit.
And also as part of that we've also looked at how to change the commit message of a previous comment
although we haven't changed the commit message.
That's it for this video.
Then the next one we're going to be looking at some more.
Get goodness See you there.