Hi and welcome back in this video let's look at the input method.
In the last video we created a program that would sense the age to be five and then it would tell the
user that they've lived for a certain number of seconds as an extension.
I suggested you may want to tell the user how many years that correspond to and that is simple enough
.
You just have to add something more.
This corresponds to SDI age years.
So when we do that and save it and then we can you have left for that number of seconds.
This corresponds to five years.
So remember the only thing we have to do is add in this string.
This corresponds to and then adds that the string representation of age which is five and then printout
years aswell.
However this is not necessary if the user tells us the age.
So that's what we want to achieve in this video.
We want the user to give us the age first and then we will calculate the seconds from that.
So therefore we don't need to tell the user how many years this corresponds to because they've all told
us the age before.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to make small changes to this program.
The first thing I'm going to do is actually remove this line just for this video.
And the way I'm going to do that is instead of deleting it I'm going to do what's called commenting
it out.
So I'm going to change this line into a comment and what a comment does is it simply does nothing.
So we can make this line a comment and then it won't run.
So Python won't execute this line the way we do that in Python it's by putting a hash symbol in front
of it.
That small sort of hash or sharp if you study music that's the shops as well.
So that's Simbel there.
And now this line is never going to run.
So if we save this and run the module again we don't get anything back because we've only declared the
variable and not printed it out because this doesn't run OK.
So instead of age equals five.
What I want to do is say input and in here and your age OK.
So any guesses as to what this is going to do.
What are we going to get out in this program when we save and run it.
So what happens now is that we get a small prompt and the prompt says enter your age and then we've
got a blinking carrot where we can now pipe in our age.
So I'm going to type 10 and naturally nothing happens because if we go back to our program we've only
set the age to be something and we've not actually done anything with it.
OK.
So let's uncomment this line and save that and run it again.
And now I'm actually a bit scared of running this program.
And before I type anything and run the program I'm going to tell you why am I scared.
Let's go back to the program and look past this input method.
So we're asking the user to enter their age.
That means the user can type something that means the user can type a letter A for example or a string
.
They can type the name or they can type their age.
That means they can type anything they want.
Which means that Python is not going to be able to extract meaning from that which means that most likely
the result of this.
The thing that the user types is meant to be stored in age but it's probably not going to be an number
.
It's probably not going to be an integer because a user can type anything they want.
So therefore I would assume that the output of this method is going to be a string.
Ok so assuming that 80 is a string what is going to happen when we do this.
And if you recall the second video I believe we talked about what happened when we multiply the string
by a number and what is going to happen is I'm not going to run the program because it will crash my
computer.
Is that it will give us 365
units of the age is going to multiply the age string by 365 which is going to give us 365 numbers and
then we're going to multiply that by 24 and they're going to multiply that by 60.
Then when I'm older brother Mike 60 so if we type the number 5 in here we're actually going to get a
long string made up of fives.
Now we don't want that because there are so many that it will crash.
So let's not do that.
And instead let's turn do something else.
So how do we convert a string to a number so we can use it in here.
And that's exactly what we're going to be looking at in the next video.
And if you decide to run this program do it at your own peril because most likely your computer will
crash momentarily but it's easy enough to stop it so you can run this if you want to you can just close
the window after and it was not the problem.
OK.
So let's go into the next video and look at how we can convert the age into a number and see you there
.