Hi welcome back in this video we're going to be looking at loading from a CXXVI file in the last video
we looked at saving to a file and this video we're going to load from it.
The first thing I'd like you to do is to create a method that will open the file for reading and get
the username out just that username don't need to create a user or anything like that.
Just get the user name that's written on an arbitrary file out.
So I'll give you a head start.
And inside this method you can open the file for reading and get the user name out pause the video and
go for that.
Once you've done that let's look at how I would do it.
I would say with open file name in read mode as if the user name is f. Daltry line and that's how you
could get the username out.
Now we could read the next few lines and get the movies from the user and that would be fine.
We could simply say don't read line and that would give us the next available line.
And so on.
However it's easier if we just do f don't read lines and then see the file content is Avodart read lines
and then you can get the username because after all realigns gives you a list of lines knowing that
if not read lines give you a list of lines where the first line is line 0.
How would you get the username out.
The simplest way is to say username is content 0 and that would be the first line which has the user
any minute and the movies oh
this is where it gets slightly more complicated because now each line is a movie but it has the name
the genre and whether it's been washed or not and it's separated by commas.
So it's not really simple to load up all the movies in just a single line.
So what I'm going to do is open and close square brackets and then say for line in content.
And what this does is it gives as each line of the content of the file.
Then we're going to do movies not a pen.
And what we want to happen here is a new movie and what we want to put in here is a name the genre and
whether it's been watched or not and the way we would get that is by separating the string into three
pieces each piece containing one of these things is really simple to split a string the way to do it
is movie data equals a line don't split on the comma and and now movie data will contain a list of name
John-Roger watched.
That's what movie data will be.
And now we can put that here in the movie.
So it will be Movie day to zero movie day to one.
And finally the last one could be movie data too but it shouldn't be movie data too.
Is there any reason why you think I would say it shouldn't be movie data too.
Let me explain.
When we write things to a file we are writing the literal characters we are writing strings to a file
.
So when we load that up from a file even though it is false it's the string falls.
So we don't want to put in a string there where we want as a boolean we want the actual true or false
value.
So then Python can tell us whether something is true or not.
So what we want to put in here is not MoVida to but rather we want to put in then whether movie date
or two is equal to true.
If movie that two is equal to true we want to put true in movie data two is not equal to true.
We want to put falls in.
So basically this comparison is doing is seeing whether the thing that saved in here is true or false
.
If this is true that means we've watched it and true is equal to true.
So we put in true there.
But if this is false false is not equal to true and therefore we put false in there which means we haven't
watched that which is what we want.
And that's how we could load up the movies and put them inside this list.
Finally what we have to do is the last thing which is actually put to the States at this username and
these movies inside a user.
And the way we do that is say return user with that user name and the movies but we can't do that in
here.
So it's a user equals the user.
Not movies equals.
And finally return use.
And what this does is let's call it again.
Load up the contents of the file with this get the user name as being the first line.
Then create a set of movies which is an empty list.
Iterate over each movie over each line of the file and then calculate the split.
Each of the elements in that cxxviii using lined up split.
So we will get a list of name Jean-Robert and true or false and then it's going to append that to this
list up here as an object.
And finally is going to create the user and set the movies to be what we floated and return that to
use.
That is one error in this code.
Can you spot it.
I'll give you another hint.
The error is in this line.
Finally the era is.
We've loaded the user name and content zero.
The first line of the content and here were iterating from line 0 onwards.
Which means Movie Data is going to be line split on the comma.
But the first line that we're going to be loading in this for loop is actually going to be the username
and has no comments.
And then we're going to try to do this and we're going to be accessing zeroth elements of something
that's not a list.
And then we're going to be in the first element second element is not going to work because the first
line doesn't have the same data as the remainder of the file.
The only solution to this is to start iterating on the first line as opposed to the zeroth line.
And I think you know how to do this.
You can do this slicing.
Which would be like this.
What this does is it has content starting from Element 1 and finishing in the last element.
And that's what this content would do.
It would get you the list but starting at the first element and because there's no number here it would
finish at the end.
If you put a number here this would give you the lines between 1 and 5.
If we omit the 5 it would give you the lines between 1 and the last line.
Basically it would start iterating in line number 1.
With that done that should allow us to load the user from file.
So let's go in the open and see if that works.
The user is going to be something and then we're going to say a user.
Don't load from file I was aimed at 60 and we want to say user is the user loaded from the file.
Finally I would say print user don't movies.
OK let's run that and see what happens.
And there we have it The Matrix and the interview naturally.
That is one last problem which is that we've had to initialize a user called Jose and then loaded the
data from a file which means we have to overwrite user which mean this line isn't really useful.
However we have to do that if we want to call the method because that method is inside the user and
we cannot do user with a capital you don't download from file that doesn't exist.
It has to be a small user of the object itself and it has to be that unless we do something special
up here.
And what I'm going to do is introduce the concept of class methods a class method doesn't run on an
object it runs on the class itself.
And instead of self this has to be called CLX.
And now if we go back into an app we can now do remove that line and say user Dalwood from file with
a copy.
I'm not running that method on the class itself.
And we can do that because none of this content was using self dot anything.
This wasn't related to a specific object.
So we could just not use self and instead make it a class method.
So what is this CLX What does that stand for.
And that stands for the class the classes user.
This method this class method is inside the user class.
So what we can do is instead of using user with the user name then we can use copy CLX and put it in
there.
And that gives a user because this method is inside the user class.
Therefore CLX is the same as user which is a path.
So what this does is it gives the user one second.
So if we run this again we see once again the matrix and the interview and not only that
but we also get the name of the user in there too which is great
that's enough for one video.
I'm sure you guys are pretty full of knowledge by this point.
So let's wait and in the next video we're going to be looking at saving in Jason format which is also
extremely useful.
I'll see you there