One will come back in this video we're looking at getting the access token from the user.
Now we've got the request token and we've gotten the oil to verify it which is the pin code.
This very file would be sent to us by Twitter.
If we had a web application instead of a control application in console applications we need the user
to give us the pin code.
And in web applications Twitter can send does that so the user doesn't have to enter it himself.
The next thing we're going to do is we're going to create a token and the Torgan is going to be just
the request token but made into an object.
So it's not really anything complicated it's just an oil to sort of object knobs that comes from the
library.
So let's do that let's say that the token is going to be wealth to token.
And what we put inside that token is the request tokens of our token and the request tokens or token
secret.
And that just essentially binds these two together and puts them inside one object which is called a
token so that we can do a couple of operations with that.
The first operation we want to do now that we've got this request to can put into an object if we have
the most different strings it's a bit more difficult to deal with.
So that's why this object exists.
Now we can also say token don't set very far and we can sense the verifier to be very high.
So nothing complicated is going here.
Don't overthink this at all.
Just remember that a token object is used to combine the token and the author can see it and to either
verify it to it.
OK if here I'd just print tie and I set a breakpoint there.
Let's look at what this token really looks like.
OK.
So I've run the debugger and now it's telling me to go to this site and put in the pin code.
I'm just going to go there authorize the application and get my PIN code and then go back to my project
and put it in here.
Another the debugger stops and we can look at what the token is.
OK the token object is just an object that has a few properties.
It's essentially like a data store and the properties it has is the key which is the token that we put
in a secret which is that Otakon secret and the verifier and the all out to Liberty now can use this
token to perform requests with it.
So it's just a way of the oil to liberty creates this token to simplify its inner workings of really
delusional stability ball.
So this talken just think of it as it stores the off tokened the off book and secrets and the verifier
.
And now we can create a client which is wealth to dot client and like we did above here we created our
client parting from the consumer which was our application the consumer and the consumer secret are
used to identify our application in to them.
Now we're going to use the consumer again but we're also going to use the talken that's going to do
is it's going to set this client a bit different status.
It's no longer a completely unknown client to Twitter.
Now Twitter knows that it has a request token And also we verify it with it.
So now we can use this client to get the access token and the way we do that is just as we did above
here to get the request token.
We're going to decline that request but it's going to be accessed.
Can you tell instead of request can you
keep.
And now just like we did here where we parsed the query string and they converted it to a dictionary
we're going to do the exact same but for the access to can notice this content.
Now is this variable here because it got overwritten as we defined the value again.
So the content variable gets defined up here and it gets the content of this request the request and
your request and then we parse it and we said it to be the request token and then down here we overwrite
it.
So now this contains the access token data and we then parse it and put it inside this other variable
called access token.
So let's print that out and see what it looks like when I press play.
Go into the site of the app.
Copy that pasted in there.
And there we go.
Now we've got this data back from Twitter and this is the access token that we've printed out and in
here now it has more information such as the screen name.
That is my Twitter username for example and it has also a bunch of token and or token secret token orthogonal
to configure it and that is what we now can use to do requests to Twitter.
So just like we did here we created a token for the reader for the access token for that solely for
the request.
We are not going to do the same but for the access token instead.
OK but I wouldn't want to confuse you any longer.
So let's do it in the very next video.
What we've done here created a request to can and set a verifier.
We're going to do the same but we no longer need to verify it because the access token does not need
a pin code which is going to be that.
But with the access logon that but with the token that we create for the access token and then we can
set up a form in request I see in the very next video and we're going to be just quickly looking into
that and see C-Leg