Find will come back in this with you we're going to be looking at returning values from a method.
Let's look at our program right now.
I think we've got quite a nice program here.
We've got two methods one that asks the user for the number.
The other one that runs the program a number of times.
And then we've got something that asks the user how many times they want to run the program.
And finally a line that runs it just in order to make things a bit nicer.
I'm going to copy that and put it up here of the top and either some whitespace there that just makes
it just a bit nicer.
But it does not affect the running of the program at all.
The next thing I want to do is look up the name of this method.
This method is called Ask user and check number.
But there's nothing in that method that really tells me that this method is going to communicate with
a user it's going to tell them whether the number was right or not.
It just tells me I'm going to ask the user or something and then I'm going to check whether the numbers
are right or not.
It doesn't say and I'm going to tell the user about it.
So we have two options either rename the method or make it do less instead of printing out.
We're going to make it just do a bit less.
So I would remove the printing and instead we're going to replace this my return statements.
OK.
So let's look at what a return statement is when the method runs.
It is now going to ask the user something and then he's going to check whether the user number is in
the magic number is valuable or not.
If it is it's going to return the string here.
That means that this method essentially will be either this string here or the string here which means
we can assign this method to something we can assign this output to a variable which I'm going to call
message.
So now message is going to be equal to the return value of this method.
Remember this method gets now replaced by whatever it returns.
That's how all methods work.
They do something when they return something and then they get replaced by whatever they return.
So in this case message is going to be one of these two strings appear.
So finally we can print the message out.
OK.
So let's press save and play.
And what will happen is exactly the same as before we now get to enter the number of attempts and then
we get to enter them and that's it.
We can simplify this slightly however instead of printing the message and assigning the method to a
variable called message.
We can just print the methods output straight away.
So if we run that we get exactly the same.
OK.
So what do you think will happen if we enter a letter here instead of a number.
When it asks us for the number of attempts.
So basically what is going to happen if I enter the letter A in there.
And the answer is probably something you would expect by now we get an error.
We are calling the input method on a letter.
Notice how we're calling the method here on the input the input is the letter A.
And Python doesn't like that because the method cannot convert a letter to a number.
It needs to be the string of a number.
So this is exactly how you would return something from a method we've looked at what a lot of things
in this section we've looked at and lists we've looked at random numbers defining method defining methods
passing parameters returning things from methods and.
And essentially we've got everything we need now to really kick start our Python programming career
.
Essential if you want to think about it like that.
We've got all of the foundations now to actually start developing larger or more complex python applications
and eventually in this course we're also going to be getting into interacting with our data base as
well.
So I'm pretty excited to guide you through this learning.
So if you wish.
Join me in the next section where we're going to be diving further into more advanced Python topics
.
I'll see you there.