Hey guys.
Welcome back to the course so in this lecture I'm going to give you probably one of the best business
tips I have ever gotten with regards to running a development firm.
Now I actually heard this previously in a marketing class because I heard that it applied to marketing
companies in ways that you market yourself but it's not necessarily something that I think applies to
every single business but for development firms specifically it is kind of the law of the land it's
kind of the golden rule that I always follow and I always consult people to follow.
Now one of the biggest things that will make a difference between whether or not you're successful and
whether or not you fail at this business is whether or not you understand what your value proposition
is.
Now value proposition if you're not familiar with the term basically just means that your product offering
or your service offering what exactly can you deliver to the customer.
Now a value proposition for let's say a taxi cab that would be that they can get you to your location
cheaper and faster than if you walked.
Or if you owned your own car.
So value propositions are just like the simplest way of summing up what exactly you are offering in
your service offering.
Again it's kind of what do you offer with your combination of skills and products.
So now with regards to a development firm you have to realize that there's a lot of other development
firms out there a lot of them don't realize what they're good at and what they're bad at.
You're always getting a leg up on them for that.
The best way of thinking about your development firm and your product offering and your value proposition
is that there are three main things you can be.
One is good.
Another is cheap and another is fast.
Those are three things that could describe your business or your service offering.
Now here is the key thing.
You can only pick two of those.
It is impossible to be all three.
Now let me explain how that's possible.
So imagine that you deliver your websites or your mobile applications quickly so you qualify as fast
if you're delivering it quickly and it's obviously is a relative statement to what the person would
otherwise expect with another firm then you're probably cutting corners somewhere either you're cutting
corners on quality and spending less hours on it.
So therefore it's harder to qualify as good or you're working with people who are extraordinarily efficient
and you have to pay them more.
So you don't really qualify as cheap now as you're trying to qualify for good.
Well then chances are it's going to be very hard for you to deliver it quickly because good typically
means that you spend a lot more time on it.
Also good kind of implies that you can be paying your people more.
Working with people who have more experience and thus are going to have a higher rate.
So very hard to be cheap and then the last will and if you're cheap that means you're probably cutting
costs somewhere right.
So probably you're saving money by having a loose timeline delivering it later than usual and using
techniques like using off hours or lean time to kind of save money that way or you're cutting costs
by focusing on lowering the quality of your actual output.
So now don't worry you don't have to just be one.
You can be two out of three.
But three out of the three that's just impossible.
So to give you an idea here at Sprint.
We are good and cheap.
We are not fast.
That is our biggest problem.
We take much longer than what most people would expect.
We actually only work with people who do not have strict timelines.
And this is something that just took us a long time to figure out.
We tried to kind of put together our team figure out what we're good at figuring out what our clients
were happy with.
And that's kind of what we figured out is that fast is just something that we cannot compete on.
And so we focus on being good and we focus on being cheap.
That's how we get our clients.
That's how we keep them.
But it also lets us know that there's just certain projects we cannot keep and certain promises we cannot
keep.
So this framework applies to a lot of different things but web development mobile development.
It is seriously the best way you can possibly look at it.
Don't expect to be all three.
You're not going to deliver the best possible product every single time.
But if you focus on optimizing two of these three you can actually end up with a very appealing and
competitive product offering and then you can focus on ways to de-emphasize the one feature that you're
not good at.
So you know if you if you can't focus on being good then you should focus your message on how cheap
affordable and quick you are and you'd start looking for clients that have you know things that are
not necessarily quality centric need you to update something very quickly and they want to do it affordably
you can make a very big business around people who need maintenance work.
You can also make a really good business around people who are on a budget.
People who don't need the creme de la creme the absolute top 1 percent of Web sites.
They only need something that's going to function and somebody doesn't look terrible.
So that's a great opportunity there.
Say you want to skip the whole fast thing and this is what we do.
So we only look for people who have aspirational projects or companies that have projects that are not
necessarily dependent on other sections of their company.
So if you don't care about your time line we can take our time focused on keeping the costs down and
keeping the quality high.
BI just kind of going crazy on the timeline and then cheap obviously if if you can't focus on being
cheap because you have to hire the best people then focus on people who want top quality work and they
want it done quickly but budget is not a concern for them.
That's an entirely different segment of people that you can go after.
So keep these three in mind.
You can only pick two.
So when you're formulating how you're going to build your strategy for this development firm keep this
in mind use that going forward or seeing the next lecture.