Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So in this lecture we're going to talk about a pretty common strategy that freelancers use and often
development firms use as well.
Now this is kind of along the same vein that we talked about in the previous lecture where we talked
about giving away something of value for free.
Well this is very similar to that what this strategy is called is the tutorial strategy.
OK so what I mean by a tutorial anybody who's been on YouTube sees all the time that there are people
who are screencast showing you how to do almost anything.
Mow the lawn color correct an image.
We're you know buying the book tutorials on how to write Gaelic lettering tutorials and pretty much
anything.
Now there's a reason why people make these they're very very popular and besides the fact that YouTube
people typically make those because they get paid off the ad revenue.
It's a great way of promoting yourself and promoting your brand.
So it's not really a big surprise that some freelancers and some freelance firms will actually use video
platforms to drive traffic back to their site.
Now in the same way that any random person who wants to show off a tutorial of woodworking does that.
Not only because they want to give to the world they also want people to recognize their name.
They might be paving the way for more videos later.
They might actually have a Web site that they get linked to.
That is something to do with woodworking where they sell something that they can actually make money
off of.
Now the same thing works for development businesses a great way of optimizing your time when it comes
to advertising is to pick something that you are very good at and try to create a tutorial about it.
Now you don't necessarily have to just use YouTube you can use obviously Vimeo or any other video platform
but could also be a content strategy.
You can write in-depth blog post about how to do something.
OK so how do you determine what that something is.
There's two ways of going at it.
There's one you pick something that you are an expert in and two you pick something that your specific
client base or your specific knish cares about.
OK.
So the first one you pick something that you're specifically good at.
Now in this scenario you would make a YouTube video or a blog post or a guide and it would be around
something that you are really good at.
Probably something around development.
So if you're someone who's a master of making some script work you can make a tutorial on that if you're
master of javascript you could create javascript tutorials.
You could even teach beginners how to learn javascript.
You can pretty much teach any generic technical skill that you can think of that somehow relates to
what you do.
Now the reason why you do this is not only this is what you're good at.
Right.
So it should be easy for you.
You can literally have one of your contractors if you're not a programmer and have them make a tutorial
on something that you think might be popular.
They could cover a brand new framework that came out they could cover a big platform update.
They could even explain something that's very technical and explain it in a way that non-technical person
can understand.
Maybe they'll explain some technical system of how Facebook works or something like that.
Now the point of you doing it in your specific skill set is because it establishes you as an authority
figure in that specific skill kind of realm.
If you are a front end development firm you only do javascript each or whatever.
If you make tons and tons of tutorials about ways to write your code better on the front end ways to
use funky scripts or integrate something that's really popular.
People are going to trust you more.
And the second thing is that it also just generates a lot of traffic.
Now all of a sudden people are coming to your Web site for reasons other than looking for web development
getting done.
Now there's an important thing to understand here.
When someone comes to your Web site for some value added reason other than the fact that they're willing
to purchase from you that's actually a positive thing.
Now let me explain why.
So if someone comes to your website and the only reason they come there is because they're interested
in getting development services.
There's actually a much higher barrier for you to jump over in order to get them to purchase something
from you at that point your or just any other product or any other service firm.
It's really hard to distinguish you from any of the thousands of others out there that do the same thing.
But if they come to your site for another reason they come they see a tutorial they like tutorial.
Now all of a sudden they have positive thoughts about your company and also they hold you in now kind
of like a positive connotation.
They think this is the company that I got a sweet guide from.
I learned a skill from.
They did this out of the goodness of their hearts.
Now if that person is interested ever in the future with web development services they might come back
to you and the barrier for them to actually paying you money and taking you on for a service provider
is much much lower.
So barrier to purchase is a very important concept in development businesses.
If the reason why they know you is not because you're a service provider or you do development services
they're going to hold you in a much better light.
And if you then after the fact somehow introduce that you do web services they're actually going to
be much more likely to purchase from you.
It's like the difference between a cold call and a warm call a cold calls when you contact someone that
you have absolutely no connection with and it's immediate immediately obvious what you're trying to
sell to them.
Whereas a warm call is there is context to you talking to them right.
So if someone comes to you and they've used your tutorial guides they've heard about you that's more
of a warm contacts they actually have positive thoughts about you and they hold you in a positive light.
So it's much easier to close a deal in that scenario.
Now the other way of creating tutorials is to pick something specific that your niece wants.
OK.
So what you got to do is you have to think about your needs and think about problems that they have.
Now you have to think about what are these problems might be technical in some way or what are these
problems are things that I could solve easily and publish how to do that.
Now you'd be amazed how many people just out there in any business vertical or any neige are constantly
looking for ways to do really simple things and they just don't know how to do it because no one's published
a very simple easy to follow guide.
So to give you an example let's say we were doing a nice That was like a vertical and we have a real
estate company.
So maybe if it's a real estate company what you could do is create a guide that shows them how to install
a popular plug in on WordPress that helps them do some real estate function.
Maybe it's something that helps them email all of their prospective clients.
Maybe it's something that helps them embed images of their properties into email.
You didn't necessarily have to make it technical.
You could even do something like a guide on how to do advanced searching.
On some real estate database anything that's going to get the attention of that specific group of people
that's what you're going for now it's not even necessarily under the context of where a development
service firm and we're presenting this to you.
They just think that you're a technology company that knows things that they don't know and you're there
to help them.
So again you're establishing warm context and in that case you can kind of get your foot in the door
and you wouldn't be surprised if later down the road you have a contract with someone and they had actually
heard of you before simply because they saw that you have a lot of tutorials online.
So don't underestimate the YouTube and video blogs and even text content blogs and their ability to
attract people to your business use them correctly deliver a value make something that only takes you
honestly 30 minutes to make and that thing gets a thousand views or 2000 reads over the next year.
Potentially you're going to generate some buzz around your name.
You might establish yourself you might show off that you're good at something and those very often turn
into leads which turn into contract so it's all about getting your first batch of clients.
That's a very successful strategy.
You can utilize it.
Any other questions is posed in the group scutcheon.
We'll try to get into it.
Otherwise I'll see in the next lecture.