You guys will come back to the course so in this lecture I'm going to talk about a distinction you should
make with your clients which is rich versus successful.
This is a big problem that I had when I first started this development business.
I often would go after clients that had big budgets and I thought that should be the number one thing
I should be looking for more money I thought better projects.
I thought it also meant that I'd have more future growth options and that hopefully they could refer
me to other people who are just as rich now that I've had quite a bit of experience running and growing
a development business or realize a very important distinction that should be made.
Some clients are rich and some clients are successful and kind of what I learned was that you would
position yourself to align with this client that is successful and has a track record of being successful.
Whereas if you just focus on rich clients you actually are doing yourself a disservice.
A rich client simply has lots of funds.
You don't know where they got the funds.
They could have inherited it.
You don't know what they did in the past to produce those funds.
Just the existence of funds does not mean that this person can create more funds in the future.
It's very possible that they had a very high up position in the past and whatever that was is completely
irrelevant to what they're doing now.
Now a successful client is completely different.
This is someone who has a track record of successful projects.
They're not just someone who has a gigantic budget.
They have a portfolio of their own so to speak and you can tell that they consistently pick ideas that
have actual potential to them and they've shown that in the past they were able to take things and do
something with it.
Now a rich client might be really hands off and they might be a really enjoyable client to work with.
But just in general these are not the types of clients that are going to grow your business.
Rich clients might create large projects but those large projects do not have a very long life expectancy.
It's much better to work on a medium project that goes on for multiple years than a large project that
fails right out of the gate a successful client is going to launch something that brings you consistent
business consistently for a very long period of time.
They're going to refer you to similar people.
These are the types of people that in the future they'll ranch separate ventures as well and they're
probably going to be a similar level of successful.
If you look at this from a portfolio perspective it's really important to take into consideration how
successful a client's been in the past because the best portfolio items are companies that are out there
that are actually doing well getting customers and getting seen that dramatically increases the value
of your portfolio.
Someone looks at your portfolio and they see something they actually recognize.
That's a huge huge plus.
How many development studios out there have a portfolio or have an application they've built that you
actually recognize.
It's probably a very very small percentage.
So guys take this into consideration.
You should be vetting your clients just as much as they're vetting you.
Is your client someone who has a very large budget but you have no idea where it came from no idea whether
or not they're going to be successful and you have no idea if six months from now the project's going
to stick around.
Focus on clients that have a track record of success.
Try anything you can to hitch your wagon to them because they're going to bring you a lot more money
in the long term.
And a lot better referrals they going to bring you the momentum that allow you to grow your business.
All right guys.
Any question posed in the group discussion otherwise seen the next lecture.