You guys will go back to the course.
So in this lecture we're going to talk about what's the benefit if any of delivering your product to
your project early.
Now a lot of you might have thought when I said under-promise over deliver that might mean for instance
giving a lax timeline and then delivering it early.
Now while that is an example of over delivering that just gives you the wrong impression unfortunately.
So let me just answer the question.
Just delivering early benefit you in some way.
No not really.
And if it does it's very marginal.
Personally if I have the office of delivering really I actually will work on the project more internally
do more testing do more deep dives try to fix more bugs that might be cosmetic.
Spend more time on it and deliver on the deadline that I promise.
Now why is that.
Well just in general when you tell someone this is the deadline.
Not only do they plan for that deadlines if you give it to them early it might actually just sit for
a couple of days so you're not giving them more time to the organization any real benefit.
Really the only benefit to giving it to them early is that you appear as if you're a good vendor and
that is really about it.
But in all practicality there's very few benefits.
In most cases we're talking and delivering something early median a week early.
Maybe it's a couple days early.
It's not going to really matter if you give it to them on July 1st and they're expecting on July 3rd.
What exactly are they going to do in those two days.
You saved the money or gave them an extra feature or did something really well that is important to
them that affects their bottom line delivering early doesn't really actually mean anything to them because
that time they didn't plan to use and they probably don't have anything.
They could use it for.
So if you have the option of delivering early maybe you overestimated.
That's great spend more time working on the project try to spend a little bit more time on line testing
and making sure that when you do give it to them it does have kind of a wow effect so it's usually a
good thing.
It means you're efficient.
It means that you give yourself plenty of breathing room.
So take that time and really perfect the project and keep in mind there's really no real benefit to
delivering early.
It's not like a lot of other industries.
All right.
If you have any questions about this.
Any examples this ever happened to you were you ever thrilled that you got a project back early.
Just post the group discussion let me know otherwise see the next lecture.