Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So in this lecture we're going to talk about what are the biggest factors in whether or not you have
positive client relationships and whether or not you can run into a problem in the middle of your project.
Now one of the biggest things that I've experienced and I've figured out through the last four years
is that the way to you talk to your client is really important.
Now that's kind of obvious right.
You don't want to be rude and you don't want to be you know flirtatious or anything like that.
But one of the things I found out that is probably the most important is confidence.
Now what do I mean by that.
Well people who are your clients are typically one of two things.
Usually they're small business owners or entrepreneurs and on the other side they're probably account
managers or some type of a decision maker at a larger company.
In all of those cases those people are taking on a lot of risk by hiring you to make their project.
An entrepreneur is probably risking a lot of their own money.
So the same story goes for a small business owner now even an account manager at a company that could
be their job on the line.
And they're kind of gambling with someone else's chips.
So the point is that they are kind of anxious about the relationship.
They have a lot on the line.
And for you you don't typically have a ton on the line.
I mean in the worst case scenario you might lose some wages.
So the most important thing that they want is to feel as if they're in the right hands.
Now the best way of doing that is by being consistently confident whenever you originally speak to them.
Be confident in the estimate you're giving them.
Obviously I'm not saying don't hedge your bets and say this could change but you just say that this
is what our estimation will be.
This is where we expect variation.
And that is that don't ever try to insert unnecessary questions or question marks what you generally
want to try to avoid is appearing wishy washy and in any way they want to know that you are the authority
figure.
You know what you're doing.
And even if it's this is completely unrealistic they want you to always feel like you know everything
in a weird way it's almost kind of like a parent child relationship.
They just gave you a lot of money and you could potentially ruin their week.
So it's really up to you to constantly keep them feeling assured.
Now what happens when a problem happens and this happens all the time.
A problem could be a miscommunication a problem could be a scheduling issue.
And most likely that a problem could be is a bug or something in your development time line gets delayed.
Now a normal way of responding to that outside of the development business would be to explain what's
happening.
Apologize and probably just tell them every single thing that's wrong and leave that open ended.
Now that's a reasonable way of explaining what's happening if you're just talking to someone and not
in a professional relationship.
The problem with that is the open ended this at the very end.
So how would you be confident in a situation like that if you have a problem.
You let them know it's a problem and then let them know how big you think of a problem it is and then
tell them this is how long it'll take before it's fixed.
Now if you don't necessarily know how long it's going to take to get fixed.
Give them a definitive answer as to when you will know it's going to get fixed right.
So it's like a timeline for a timeline.
The point is that there's a lot of ambiguity when it comes to projects something that could be wrong
when it's going to get fixed.
But you can always focus your communication and reword your communication in a way that is always definitive
even if you don't know if there's a scenario where you don't know something.
You're always something that you do know.
So focus on the thing that you do.
Never ever say in a project that here's a problem and it cannot be fixed.
There's too many times in my experience where we've run into problems that even after three days of
looking at it we have no idea if this can be fixed.
What would be poison is if we told them we don't know if it's going to be fixed.
That is the worst thing your client can possibly hear.
Remember they trusted you.
They gave you a lot of money and you could potentially take all of that and nullify it.
So never tell them that you don't know if it can be fixed.
Always say it can be and give them a timeline on when it can be fixed.
If you have no idea how long it's going to take you just tell them that it's a big time line before
you can even get back to them with a timeline and getting it fixed.
Now one thing that can help you if you do run into a really really big snag and you're kind of at a
loss for how you can reassure them.
One thing you can do is combat this with specificity.
So what I mean by that is you have an the issue tell them exactly to the T what the issue is.
Show them why it's hard and eventually they'll empathize with you and they'll say yes this is actually
quite difficult.
Explain to them why it's a difficult technical problem explain to them how experienced the person is
looking at it and they've never seen this before.
Explain to them that it's a problem with the platform you used or it's a problem with this certain technology.
Something that's almost so big that it can't possibly be your fault.
But most of all be confident when you say that it's a hard issue if they believe you can keep trust
with them and then they're going to believe you when you say it can be fixed.
That's the most important thing.
I always start I like to think of it like you know you are the North Star to your client.
You always have to know what you're doing and where you're going.
There always has to be a plan on the table even if you have no idea what you're going to do.
You'll find out very quickly that by using language correctly by always appearing confident they'll
trust you and you can essentially buy yourself enough time before you have enough information to correctly
answer their questions in development.
It's always just a matter of time.
No problem can't be solved in some way.
And if it is the case then you should have seen that way before.
Now how does apply to other interactions that your client would never call and ask you a question and
you just have no idea what the answer is instead of saying I just don't know.
Say hey I don't actually know but here's a timeline for how long it's going to take for me to figure
it out.
It's really easy.
You can just say I don't know this but I know that I can figure it out.
That's always better if they know it's something that you're not aware of.
But the difficulty of that question is not so ridiculous you could never answer it.
They'll usually just kind of let you have that one.
They always want to know that you could answer any question and at minimum give them a timeline or a
rough idea of when you can figure it out and give it to them.
Now this is something that helps with experience.
You'll figure out that some questions are a little bit harder than others.
Usually I just give a pretty wide or vague timeline.
I can usually just say give me a couple days or let me look into it when we're at this section.
Really there's a lot of ways you can kind of work it around.
OK so the big takeaways from this lecture is confidence is key.
You kind of have to feel like you're holding their hand throughout the process.
You need to understand that clients typically are very poorly equipped to handle problems and they're
very poorly equipped to tell the queen who knows the right path and who's completely wrong what they
can tell is they can tell your tone and they can tell your confidence an issue with no solution.
That's Bell's sinking ship to them.
But an issue with someone who's confident that they can figure it out even if that doesn't mean fix
the problem just figure out what it is that is always an infinitely better solution.
Try to be their North Star try to be confident and try to analyze your language a little bit.
Don't ever leave open ended answers that make it sound like I just don't know what this is or this is
an issue.
Always give some kind of a conclusion or some kind of summation.
This is a problem and it can be fixed this quickly or tomorrow we'll know how to fix it or something
along those lines.
OK guys like always any questions posed in the group discussion.
Otherwise you can always send me a message.
I'll see in the next lecture.