Hey guys we'll come back to the course.
So in this lecture I thought it be helpful to go over some other web development firms just so you can
get an idea of what they look like how they structure their information in their web presence and what
do they choose as important information and what are the things that they kind of skip over.
So this entire section we're going to talk about how you can get up and create a web presence that looks
good and do that with a minimal amount of effort investment and money later on.
We're going to talk about how you can improve your web presence.
But if you listen to the 80:20 lecture we talked obviously about how you need to just start with what
you can and there's a lot of really cool kind of loopholes to getting up a web presence that looks quite
good and cost you kind of nothing.
So I thought again it would be helpful to show you guys what they look like so that going through the
next lectures you're not completely lost.
So what I did is I pulled up three Web sites and so we can just kind of take a glance at these.
I pulled up my company which is Sprint kick shameless plug I thought brought up thought bought which
is a popular design and development firm out of Boston.
And then I brought up sapient Nitro sapient is a company that's been around for ever.
They've been they were a big agency even back in the dot com days in 99 2007 and they've grown pretty
much exponentially since then but they still kind of made their mark and they're still known for being
a web agency.
So we're going to use these three to kind of look them over and go over what are the kind of consistent
things you'll see across the board.
As you look at popular Web sites that bring up one other one which I think is worth looking at there
are a smaller group out of Chicago.
I think these guys are also worth looking at.
You'll realize very very quickly that there is a pattern across the board.
Now the first thing I want to point out it's actually more or less a trend.
It's something that's become popularized in the last four years.
Three years ish for a lot of good reasons but it's not necessarily something that you have to follow
it's something that you should be aware of and it's a very effective page design.
So now what I'm referring to is that all of these Web sites have what we call the long page design meaning
that when I hit this page right now do you see obviously what they want you to see they see a navigation
bar at the top but what happens is all I have to do is scroll down and it will show me the same information
that I would have seen if I clicked on these buttons.
Almost so you can see this across pretty much all of them.
So if I go down on thought bot see how it goes who we are then it goes well we made what we think it's
a long page design meaning that below the fold of the Web site.
There's a lot more content.
You can see this an octopus.
Well we can just keep scrolling down and we kind of receive their entire pitch and at the very bottom
we catch their information.
And honestly if we were to just pull up any random design firm you probably would see something very
similar or we could just say Florida web design or web development sorry
OK and so this is pretty much a random one that you've seen I've already seen this one before.
But again they use that long page design like we can just keep going all the way down and they'll hit
on the same types of information.
OK the exception obviously is our Web site.
We decided not to do that.
We thought it was just a little bit too cliche but if you want to fit in with the other web development
firms it's definitely something to think about.
Now there's something to be said about imitating other Web sites especially at the beginning of your
business.
People are pattern recognizing creatures meaning that they always look for patterns whether or not they're
doing it consciously or not.
So if the majority of web development firms out there like to use a long page design where the majority
of very well designed agency Web sites like this format then you can't really go wrong by emulating
it and using something similar because a lot of people will subconsciously associate this design with
quality.
And they might subconsciously associate it with web agencies or web development firms.
OK so let's try to dissect these Web sites just a little bit more so you can kind of understand that
they all pretty much have the same information.
The only thing that changes is really what they're saying and how they actually design their Web site
what colors they use what graphics they use.
And there's a little bit of variability but not a ton.
So first off what you'll notice is that every single web agency or web development firm as soon as you
hit their page you pretty much have whatever it is that they want you to first know about them.
Now I call this the hook.
Now what do I mean by a hook.
Typically what that just basically means is when you hit the front page they have one big sentence that
they want to get across to you.
It's usually a distilled message about their company.
It's exactly what they want you to think about them in one sentence.
So we did that as well with the exception of this.
This was a new service that we launched about a year ago and started promoting it.
But previous to that it was like this.
This is what you would see.
You'd actually hit our front page.
What we said is we design and build beautiful scalable apps and Web sites every day.
So that was the first thing we want you to know and this is a picture of a Web site that we had created
about a year and a half ago.
Similarly you'll notice this and thought but let's design develop and grow your product.
OK.
That's a hook.
That's the first thing they want you to think.
Then they have a subtitle that kind of elaborates on that pretty much all of them use this technique.
If we hit Octa what they'll do is they'll probably show you their best portfolio item or they'll put
some kind of a line that intrigues you.
Really the first thing they see should be something that's a little bit glamorous something that is
interesting to a random passer by something that really gets their attention.
Now any of you guys out there that do content marketing or e-mail marketing know that the first element
in all of your email should be something that's Attention getting.
So I call it a hook.
And so a lot of that's because a lot of people will use some catchy settings or catchy distillation
of what they believe about their company as the first thing.
And some people take a different strategy towards it.
Like with sapient nature you can see the first thing I see is something really high resolution something
really pretty something that they've been working on that's really popular.
You'll notice also what something that's very common is this it'll be a hook that automatically scrolls.
And the reason why people do that is because they want you to think that there's a lot going on at their
firm.
They also don't want to lose your attention.
So if I hit this page and I'm not entirely sure if I want a higher speed nitro or I'm sure what they
do they want to make sure that while I'm processing that information staring at this image they're going
to be able to show me something else and to keep me staring at it.
And it's a basic kind of technique to keep me on the page longer.
OK.
So pretty much all of them will try to show off either a hook or something they're really really proud
of as the first thing you see.
OK so the second element that you'll notice is almost all of them with in you know at least either zero
or one click away from their front page.
They will try to explain to you in some way what their value proposition is and this is a little bit
harder to kind of tease out.
But previously we talked about how you're going to plan out your value strategy.
How are you going to figure out what you are.
Remember good cheap and fast.
You'll notice very quickly that these people want to very quickly give you a pitch at what they're good
at what they do.
And you know why do people trust them et cetera et cetera.
So like right over here.
So in the case of thought but we can see right here it's actually in their subtitle focusing on user
outcomes and simplicity we minimize risk and increase your product success with quality and called humans.
OK so what are they pushing they're pushing that they are user focused.
That's kind of a buzzer buzz word a little bit today.
That's opposed to client focused that's opposed to business focused they're more focused on the end
user experience or really what that means is that they're kind of pitching that hey we really put a
lot of thought into user experience.
A lot of development firms focus on technology first.
A lot of them are more graphic design kind of focused and in this case basically what they're saying
is we are user experience focused simplicity.
That's another one they're kind of pitching at you.
Some people like to pitch simplicity that means that they probably like minimalist design they like
things that are simple and good and they're obviously looking for people who find that interesting as
well.
And then right here we can see we minimize risk and increase your product success with quality code
and quality humans all focus on this section the sentence first we minimize the risk and increase your
product success.
What they're basically saying here kind of in between the lines is that they're trying to pitch themselves
as more of an integrated firm.
Now what do I mean by that they're saying when we work with you we're married to your bottom line.
We don't just build something handed off you launch it it's your problem what they're saying is we focus
on you as an organization and whatever we build is going to be in line with whatever we think is going
to make you successful.
That's really what they're going for.
We're saying you know we minimize your risk why would a web development agency CARE ABOUT YOUR risk
and increase your product success.
Again that's something you don't hear all the time in web development agencies are really focusing on
your success because at the end of the day if you're not successful they're saying that we're not happy.
I know they say is quality code quality code quality humans.
They're just kind of be trying to be witty by comparing code to humans and blood.
People say quality code.
So it's kind of funny to say quality humans.
Haha I think it's a play on them being thought bot like they're a robot.
Yeah I mean this is literally just kind of jibberish But what they're trying to say is we are a high
end firm high end firms focus on code quality and so whatever we build is beautiful and in a later lecture
we talk a little bit about what is code quality and why does it matter.
Because it really just at the end of the day doesn't really mean anything.
It's something that clients really kind of hang on to but they don't necessarily always know what it
means.
And then quality human is just talking about hey you're gonna have a great experience with us because
we're great people.
OK.
So really that's their value proposition.
And we would get little bits of it more as we read down the list.
You can see right here value proposition.
They're basically saying hey we're experts we do all three things iOS Android and the Web.
OK so that's their value prop.
They do multiple platforms multiple types and then right here we know that they're very experienced
as you notice 100 plus organizations.