Hey guys welcome back to the course in this lecture.
We're going to cover some of my favorite kind of tips and hacks for growing your portfolio much faster
at the very beginning and to close that gap between established firms and you your upstart and a much
quicker amount of time.
So this is one of those things that like you would not have the slightest idea about this unless you
had some experience in development already.
So what are the very biggest issues when you're starting out your development business is that clients
almost immediately will ask for a portfolio or some kind of statement of work something that shows what
you've built before.
Your response probably is going to be something along the lines of Oops.
Now a lot of people they just quit right there because realistically if you can't prove that you built
something before well then it's really hard to land a contract.
Now what a lot of people don't realize is that there are some really easy ways to build out a portfolio.
We're going to cover more techniques later in this section but we're going to go over a couple of my
favorites right now.
So number one this is one that no one realizes this.
You can list your own projects.
Now what do I mean by this.
You probably have projects from the past that you were part of you built yourself you had built for
you.
You were part of the team for now you can list those as your portfolio.
Why.
Well because presumably you had an intimate relationship with the application and the final product
quality had a lot to do with you.
Now why is that acceptable.
Well when people list portfolios they list their portfolio items in totality they list a Web site that
they worked on.
Right.
But you don't know exactly what they did on that Web site.
A lot of times they'll annotate it.
That's probably what you should do as well but you have to understand if you participated in that project
it's worth posting it just to show you're part of that team you are at least high enough caliber to
work with that group or at least to show that you know at least this portion of it is from me.
Now you can list on your portfolio what exactly you did but you also don't really need to scream that
you didn't build it yourself from scratch.
Ninety percent of the time clients won't even really ask you because it's not a huge concern to them
if they ask you just specify what exactly you did or if you want to avoid that entirely and then just
post it along with your portfolio.
Now I did this with my side projects when I started.
I'd done a lot of outsourcing projects previously and so obviously I can show off what I've built because
clearly I'm capable of rebuilding that in the future.
That's the point.
Portfolios are basically snapshots of what you're capable of making.
Now if you follow the sub contracting path.
Another thing you can do is that you can use your contractor's portfolio they personally have things
that they have built.
And so it's realistic to say this is something that I can build assuming that you're going to be using
that contractor at the very beginning of Sprint.
I worked with a firm and the firm would tackle entire projects for me.
So it made sense to show what they can build considering that what I'm offering is them plus me.
Again what's important is that you show what you can do not necessarily what exactly you have built
yourself.
Now at the very beginning this can be kind of a growth hack.
It's something that you can use to out of the gate have something to show.
Obviously it's not going to be perfect right unless you're working with a contractor for the long term.
They have an amazing portfolio but it's something at the very beginning that'll do it's kind of a stopgap
strategy over time.
Realistically what you should do is start curating your portfolio start cycling out the items that you
did not do the entirety of and focus more on better projects projects that you did kind of in totality
over time also you going to start pruning it a little bit to look for consistency in your portfolio
items.
You're just getting really picky as you build more and more projects.
But the very beginning this is perfectly fine.
It's great to get smaller contracts or lower pressure contracts pretty much upfront.
Okay guys so those you're out there that are totally worried you have nothing to show you do have something
to show you just got to think about it.
So any questions posed in the group discussion.
Any other suggestions that worked for you posted in there.
Otherwise to see in the next lecture.