Hey guys.
Welcome back to the course so in this lecture we're going to talk about what are the things that you
should look for in a long term contractor and a long term partner.
So obviously it's very important if you pick a long term partner that you focus on the ones that are
good and that you have a good rapport with them.
But there are three things that I want to kind of get across to you that you should look for above everything
else.
So number one is responsiveness.
What are your responsibilities.
How quickly does it take them to respond to a question or a problem that you bring up.
Now why is that important.
Well if you're working with a contractor and they're separated from your main group people their ability
to get work turnaround and deliver work is going to be crucial for you.
There's a lot of great contractors out there that if they don't respond quickly and they can't turn
around work quickly you're going to inevitably have unhappy clients and they're not worth working with.
Responsiveness is also indicative of how much they value your relationship and just how good of a contractor
they are in general.
You want to know that if something happens or you need something done or you need an estimate that when
you contact them they'll respond quickly.
They don't you're going to lose clients you're going to miss deadlines and you're going to have project
complications throughout the entire process.
Now the second thing is maturity.
A lot of contractors you'll meet will never admit they've done something wrong and they also will never
admit or talk about honestly things that don't work out or talk about their weaknesses or disadvantages.
If you want a long term partner you need someone who recognizes the mistakes they make and moves to
remedy them.
Immaturity is one of the hardest things to work with with a contractor.
It will break down communication every single step.
Mature contractors also know what it takes to get work done.
They're willing to put in extra time when they need to.
And you don't have to spend tons and tons of time arguing with them or trying to get them to do something
correctly.
They should have done the first time.
Now the third thing is you need to find a contractor that you see eye to eye with on quality.
So what it basically means is you need to have similar standards.
You could have a fantastic contractor that meets all your metrics for a good subcontractor.
But if they think something's ugly is pretty and you don't understand that you're always going to have
issues and that's something that unfortunately is unsurmountable.
You want to work with a contractor that naturally knows what a good quality product looks like.
So when in doubt and when you start backing off and not managing them so much you know they can deliver
what exactly you need.
Now if they don't even know what good is and we have a lecture on that you're just going to run into
problems you're never going to allow them to become autonomous and you're never going to allow yourself
to shift your resources to other parts of the business which is crucial if you want to grow your business.
Just in general that's number one of the number one problems you'll have with contractors.
What they think is good is different than what you think.
That is an unbridgeable divide.
And unfortunately the only way you can address it is that with more and more of your time which is exactly
what you don't want to be doing.
OK guys take those three into consideration you're looking at long term contractors obviously pay attention
to the other things that we cover in this course for selecting them.
But if you're looking at someone and wondering if this is someone who's going to go the distance and
someone that you know is safe a solid choice and you know they're always going to be there for you.
Focus on those three things.
Look for responsiveness.
Look for maturity and look for similar standards of quality.
All right guys see in the next lecture.