All right.
So let's talk about integrating this into your project.
The easiest way of doing that kind of like I explained previously in the last lectures to quite literally
get the email address of your contractor or your freelancer or whatever and immediately invite them
in and then add them to your project.
If you have a private project what you can do is you can physically add them in.
It's like an ad project members this is public but it make private work the same exact way to do that
and then add them in the way that I would suggest setting this up is that you divide out your kind of
work area into three different sections.
And the first section what I usually do is create this as a template before or even on board a contractor.
So I'll take the first section and I'll call it Section 1 or build tasks or just tasks or whatever it
is that you're actually doing.
And I'll make that the first section.
OK and then right over here I give a description because a lot of people are not immediately aware of
how a sauna works.
Some people use it.
Some people haven't.
So people are used to base camp or something else.
So what I do is I put up here and I say here we're going to list out all of our all of our tasks.
Okay.
And then what you are essentially going to do is ask them to list all of the tasks that are going to
be involved in your project.
Now I can't obviously make a template that's going to fit every single project so you're just going
to think about your project if it's a mobile application you then going to have to ask them to list
out every single section as they see it.
Usually these are going to be user centric.
Now what I mean by user centric they're not going to say okay finished the database or have this one
section upload code to this other section and make that a task to make the tasks user centric so what
a user sees this screen will be done this button will be done this function this feature will be done
because as they update it something visually should be happening to someone who's using your application
or using your product.
That's the easiest way of doing this especially for you the project manager if you're non-technical
even if you are technical you're not going to be so integrated into this project you're going to know
exactly what's going on in the back end and so you're not going to really be able to tell what's up
and what's down if they try to use esoteric kind of the confusing jargon as explaining back and functions
in the second section.
What I typically like to do is set off a section where I put additional tasks and I'll usually call
this one just additional tasks
even task and features OK now what do I mean by this section right here.
What I mean is I'm going to remove this due dates or sorry.
So what I mean by this now an additional task and feature what I typically do is I list out any additional
tasks that were not included on the project or the task list.
You previously agreed on.
Now if you guys got someone off of either answer oDesk or wherever then you agree to some kind of a
work specification.
So slightly fall the previous section where we made work specifications.
They're going to follow that.
This is the section where you add anything that's an additional to that as they're building it out you
might see additional things you want or additional tasks that you didn't anticipate needing that's where
you're going to list these out here and again because of Ossana the way they do threads this is a fantastic
way of doing it so I could say you know maybe I wanted to add a feature maybe I said like I wanted to
add a notification feature so I could say notification feature to x section.
OK obviously it doesn't really make sense because we don't know a project we're talking about but what
we can do over here then is I can give a drill down description of what exactly I mean is it like e-mail
notification a push notification a text notification.
Who is getting message who clicks it or does it display etc. etc. and then right here you can have a
discussion going down the thread with the person you're working with until they get to the point where
they understand what exactly it is and they can give you an estimate.
Now previously we talked about whether or not you work on project price or whether or not you work on
hourly price if it's hourly will give you an estimate in terms of hours if it's project price I'll give
you an estimate based off of just that that one section or the bundle sections together.
If you use our technique which is that we use a hybrid where we do day rates half day rates and things
like that then they'll give you an estimate like that.
And you've clearly set the tone previous to that so they'll know exactly what type of estimate you like
to get.
And they'll put it down here and you can ask them estimate it.
I also like to put that up in the scription estimate out this section.
You know here's the description please give me an estimate or ask any questions.
Now the third section I like to create is just bugs on us.
It's it's literally just an ongoing section or where I list out issues as they happen.
Now when you first start you're not going to have anything built so you're not going to have any bugs.
But as they start building out tasks and we start clicking through them you will start noticing them
as you test.
You know something doesn't load correctly something looks wrong.
This button is broken.
Something is awry something.
Maybe they didn't follow the specifications correctly and maybe didn't understand the project perfectly.
This is where I started listing off sections down here.
Now this is helpful because this task this section will start to be very large and as it starts to whittle
down this section will grow.
Also what I think are best practices for using this section using a bug section is to only list out
general bugs general meaning something some bigger picture issue is happening.
This whole section just looks off.
This section is going to the wrong page et cetera et cetera.
Now if you want to leave bug feedback for a specific task what you actually do is say we had a task
and say This task was to generate email based off user information and pre populate it pre-populated.
OK so that was our task and say they built that and they checked it and say you're looking at the completed
list.
What you could do is you could go in here and add what's called a subtask.
So you could do is at a subtask and this is a useful way of adding bugs.
If they're only helpful if you can assume that this bug is the only part of this.
OK so if that e-mail was pocketing incorrectly I could say you know generated email has just put on
like jargony code at the beginning of e-mail.
And then if you saw another one we could say that generated.
You know whatever the actual bug is doesn't work on you know Apple Mail or something like that whatever
it is you can individually list them out have a conversation down here and as they fix them they can
click this through.
Now that's one way of doing it and that's helpful if you have a specific problem with a specific function
and that bug is only related to this.
Now if you had a bug that you don't really know it's related to.
Or it could involve multiple task.
It's actually a problem putting it on here because of the freelancer might miss it or they potentially
just if they wanted to find it they wouldn't be able to find it.
Granted we do have a search bar up here so you can search for things but maybe they didn't know exactly
what you called it.
So if that's the case I like to put them down here so like bigger bugs if I want to say like there's
a large section that doesn't work say you know the photo capture tool in my mobile application.
It's crashing in different sections like.
Or I'd say like it's slow.
Chances are up here we wouldn't just have creative a photo capture we would have separate sections so
integrating the camera.
And then you'd have a section that says for instance like installing the actual layout of where the
camera buttons are or the flash buttons are using filters.
You do have a section as a separate one so it's a more generalized bug we can put it down here.
It's up to you how you do it.
Personally I like to use these I like to just list my Bugg's list in a massive list because once that
person is done with their individual task or the entire task list then they just immediately move here
and just start knocking them out.
And as you start playing with it you can literally just have this open as a tab as you're playing with
your project or whatever it is and you just start listing out bugs.
We do have a section on bug hunting.
That's something that's very helpful to go back and read watch or watch if you skipped it to just to
talk about where are the most common areas to get bugs where are areas people don't think to look for
to find bugs.
What tools you use to find them.
You don't need to be a web specialist or a mobile application specialist to find bugs.
Literally anybody with a mouse and fingers can find bugs.
And again and with any project there are always going to be bugs.
Don't obviously judge your contractor or your freelancer based off of that.
That is just something that is a reality of web projects.
OK.
So I think that is kind of the ideal way of creating your first project.
I do suggest if you do have design assets or wire frames remember you made wire frames to go in and
load them into like say the section over here because it'll show up in the attachments that you can
move them to individual tasks as you have the freelancer populate them talked about that previously
in the last lecture.
That's also very important.
Right you don't want to dictate who builds out the task list you want the other person to do it and
then you can kind of have the editorial review look at it and say no that doesn't make sense.
No that takes too long.
Or no I want this to be in a different hierarchy.
I want you to work on this section first because I need to use that sooner or show this off sooner or
whatever.
But if you build it out like this and guys feel free to just to copy this this is the most effective
template We've used to just build out as much as you can make sure you have all your design assets or
wireframe in it.
Make sure you have descriptions make sure you've listed out anything that you can think of that you
wanted to add if you have questions right off the bat.
You can create a little section and add a question and have them edit it.
Make sure that you get them to pick the due dates.
Don't be sticklers on that.
That can actually kind of kill a project but make sure that they are using some form of loose due dates.
Now you know if you are running a big project or a project that has a large budget and you're paying
a premium for people then it might be OK for you to set strict deadlines for each individual task but
just in our experience it's easier to be loose.
You know it also if you if you're using an agile system you can build these out instead of saying build
asks you can say Sprint one sprint to Sprint three sprint four take suggestions from the people that
you work with honestly.
We've had people say day one day to day three day four things like that that breaks this system just
a little bit but it doesn't really matter.
Whatever they're comfortable with what they understand the entire point of this is to be able to track
your progress and create transparency also to be able to kind of put a laser focus on what exactly you're
talking about what exactly they're talking about and what exactly you have issues with which is one
of the biggest problems that we have in general with project management for web and mobile projects.
One other thing worth noting is that as you do this it's worthwhile that you keep logs of what's happening
in Assata builds logs for you that you can export.
That's very helpful if you are hiring someone off of Elance or up work or freelancer.
They have their own contract system so it's helpful to occasionally take those logs and upload them
there.
If you do choose to use those companies to control your payment methods which a lot of people are doing
smaller projects will do it's a good idea to keep logs of your progress of your questions of what the
application looks like through its individual stages.
Always if you have the option of having more documentation versus less documentation always pick more
documentation that's going to help you if there is ever a conflict in the future.
And if you are using those payment systems freelance or other platforms they get to be the final arbiter
of who gets the money who who made an error who screwed up or who made the mistake.
So make sure that you're not in a situation where there's no documentation of their work on their system.
There's only documentation over here make sure that you do crossover occasionally.
OK.
So that pretty much covers a sauna.
Guys it's free.
Sign up for it.
It's great if you have any suggestions for tools that you want me to cover posts in the group discussion.
This is the one that I like because it covers pretty much everything and it's free and it's fast and
it's multi-platform so see you as an ex lecturer.