Hey guys welcome back to the course so in this strategy lecture I want to talk about a technique that
has worked pretty consistently through our history and works for a lot of different design and development
groups out there.
So the strategy is just called sponsoring groups.
Now there's a lot of different ways that you can do it.
It obviously helps if you know who exactly you want to go after.
But there's definitely ways you can test this with different groups to see how it works.
So really it's pretty quite simple.
If you've followed the strategy that we talked about with the perpetual discount.
This works especially well but the general idea behind it is that you really just want to go after groups
of people that might fit your potential client profile and then offer to sponsor the group or give discount
offers to the group.
So either way works.
One is that you sponsor and it's a way of getting advertising.
So that's probably not something you want to do at the very beginning and it could be very expensive
to test.
But what's more effective is to offer discount development services to groups.
And so essentially you're co-opting their email group.
So what you typically would do is find a group that fits your category and then you'd really just end
up reaching out to them.
Now the most effective way of doing this I have found is actually through meetup dot com believe it
or not.
So they have tons and tons of groups really all over the world for all sorts of things.
They have millions of groups and really all you do is try to find an area that's local or try to find
some group really anywhere that has some sort of relevancy to what you're trying to do.
And then what you do is just so I just search for San Francisco.
You know if I was interested in startups so maybe we can just take a generic on a CTO school maybe for
some reason I wanted to run a campaign based off a CTO score or maybe I wanted to do something that's
nice Should I say real estate.
So here what I could very easily do is just pick a real estate group so let's you know just pick this
one this one's a group of 569 people.
So right off the bat you can see on the left hand side.
These are all the stats about the group.
You can see what they're interested in and you can make sure their interests somehow align with what
you're offering.
And then really the easiest way of getting in contact to them is just get in contact and then you can
just email them and say hey I'm interested in what your group does I'm interested in offering a discount
services to your group and just really kind of take it from there if you are willing to offer a discount
to their group.
They are more often than not willing to promote that to their group because it's usually a value added
type of situation.
How much of a discount you want to offer is up to you.
It depends on your business model and it kind of just depends on how aggressive you want to be with
this strategy.
For a while here we were sponsors of you know almost 20 different groups and it always consistently
created a steady trickle of people.
So one other way that can help with your using meetup specifically is that use the word Pearch.
And the reason why is because meetup lets you use these things called perks.
And so what that basically means is small businesses or any type of business interested in Meetup groups
can offer perks and perks can range from really anything anything that you offer as a service could
be a discount it could be a free something it could be free consultation or whatever it is.
That's typically what this would fall under.
Now meetup doesn't offer the perks feature any more but the vast majority of people still look for perks
and they just do it informally.
So if you contact them and say hey I'd like to add a perk to your group.
That's typically the way that you would start the conversation and you'd say you know I'm willing to
give it 30 percent discount or whatever it is.
You could even say things like willing to do free work for the group in return for some kind of sponsorship
or offer free services to the group.
That's another strategy you can use.
OK.
So another way of reaching out to groups would just be to actually look for conventions now conventions.
You would have to go.
You could either go again either pay for a sponsorship or pay for a reduced rate.
This one is really kind of up to your ability to find convention.
So you know again if I was interested in real estate I would want to say real estate conventions and
then you know it's up to you whether or not you would want to put a modifier past that I don't necessarily
need to say California but at the same time if I look for these and I just say real estate Convention
right here we have a one by real tired out or we have the r e convention these are all very big groups.
If you contact them you could very easily get put into contact with anybody who handles any of their
sponsorship.
So it's really going to be up to you to message them and figure out what exactly they would find valuable.
It's also up to you whether or not you want to get really really specific with it.
I had brought this one up because this was a group that we have been back and forth with.
They fit our customer profile quite well because these are non-technical entrepreneurs who are looking
to develop their skills as non-technical entrepreneurs so that fits our group quite well.
And so this has to be ideally something that we could target whether or not it's sponsor emails whether
or not it's paying for visibility whether or not it's just offering our discount to their group and
being listed somewhere doesn't really matter.
You could also do similar things like offering free services.
Another way of looking for groups in general that I've found successful is you can use.
Here's one.
This is actually just a web site so aggregators are quite helpful for organizations.
Meetup is an aggregator for organizations but they're also meet ups.
What I mean by that is a meetup is very different than just a normal organization they're usually created
on the meet up web site and they stay on the meetup website.
They're not organizations outside of this typically But if you go to this Web site and I'll put it in
the resources career one stop DRG here is a great resource for finding just lists and lists of different
groups by occupation.
So if I really really wanted to go after graphic designers I could type in that so it would be an occupation.
Here's an example what happens you search real estate.
There's 65 professional associations professional associations are typically easier to get into contact
with because they are not as used to being pitched.
They're less concerned about being pitch too if you went to a large convention.
It might take a lot of back and forth and you might have success with smaller conventions at first and
then your budget grows or your ability to kind of say you have a brand grows then you might go for larger
ones but with professional groups are always very hyper local and they're always very engaged.
And so it's it's a very easy way of offering kind of a win win situation.
Here's a graphic design just pulls up a hundred and three and these are all pretty much across America.
And what I'll do is literally link me to their Web site which is fantastic.
And then I can just go from there find someone who's in a role of communications and contact him that
way.
Another way you can do it is actually to just take the area that you're in.
So we're in San Francisco.
So what I could literally do is search for the San Francisco Chamber of Commerce.
Now whatever city you're in.
Search for that part of what's Chamber of Commerce is do.
Also economic development groups are usually related to it.
They list out business organizations and business groups and it's part of their responsibility to connect
you to them.
Typically you can't say typically because every single Web site is a little bit different but typically
you can hit their page and after some messing around you can usually find it.
San Francisco allows us to look through business profiles.
It also allows us to look through groups that are associated with the Chamber of Commerce and all of
these are here so literally you could just look for upcoming events look for who runs it contact them
and see if you could set up a basic kind of sponsorship sponsorships in general or just a very easy
kind of one off things that you can do that are very they bring in a small amount of leads but it lasts
a long period of time.
So the last way that if you are still kind of stuck searching for organizations or groups to sponsor
it honestly just go to Google and here's a great example of that.
So if I had a specific need so take my niece Plus Association or professional group google find a lot
of the ones that aren't picked up here and then you could very easily just finds group and contact them
about sponsoring their group.
Anything that has membership anything that has a group that meets regularly.
Those are the type of people.
And those are the types of groups that are typically open to some sort of a sponsored discount or a
group discount and they're very easy to target because they have specific needs and they're very open
to the idea of offering discounted services to their group members and usually almost always that never
cost anything so.
OK so sponsoring groups is a technique that you should definitely look into.
It's one of those ones that if you offer a discount service upfront that doesn't actually cost you anything.
So it's really just free exposure at the very beginning of your development business when you're starting
it.
It's really important to focus on things that have little investment and potentially high are why this
is a great opportunity to essentially put nothing on the line in terms of cash because resources are
very precious at the very beginning and only focus on things that bring in leads and bring in potential
clients.
So this is one of those things that's really just a win win opportunity and it's a very easy to find
these groups and to contact them I typically suggest running a template e-mail and changing it depending
on whether or not you it to a meet up group or a professional association or whatever and use that and
just you know if you spend an hour you can very easily get into contact with four or five six different
groups that are probably interested and really just take it from there.
So like I said we ended up sponsoring several groups and we've been doing that for quite a while.
And that's actually been a pretty good steady stream of leads.
If you guys have any other questions just post in the group discussion.
Otherwise all seen the next lecture.