Hey guys.
Welcome back to the chorus in a structure we're going to talk about how does creating a development
firm work if you're a programmer and how does it work if you're not a programmer.
Hopefully this isn't redundant but I wanted to elaborate a little bit more on this so that you can kind
of understand how you should tackle this given what your skillset already is.
OK.
So if you are a programmer you have experience with programming perhaps you can freelance in the past.
It's a lot simpler.
So the best way of handling this is actually similar to the way that a non-programmer would.
You're still going to focus on subcontracting out your projects.
But the bigger question is what is you're going to be your participation in the projects that you do
actually claim and the projects you actually need a building.
So previously you might have worked on projects or built projects for your own clients.
Now if you're going to turn this into it's your own business or turn it into a development firm you're
going to be able to take much larger projects on and then it's a question of how exactly are you going
to get those projects made.
You're going to have to decide whether or not you're going to have to act as the lead developer on each
of your projects or whether or not you need to have some kind of a hybrid solution where you say you
work part time on each individual projects and the other time you're spent looking for projects or managing
the projects you already have.
Now the third option obviously is that you could not develop at all you could actually use this as a
way to transition out of being a developer.
And so you can actually transition more into a role of a project manager and a client manager.
You're obviously at a huge advantage because you're going to be able to understand the technology at
a much more granular level.
When something bad happens you'll probably understand the project well enough to coach the contractor
or coach the person you've hired into fixing it or what direction to go.
That's something that a non-programmer is not going to be able to do very well.
So for you really the whole thing kind of works the same way.
I think at the very beginning it's easier for you because you can build the projects you bring in if
you're not ready to some subcontract it out.
But it's going to be up to you over time how you position yourself in this business.
Are you going to build it yourself or are you going to give it entirely to someone else and oversee
it.
Or are you going to be a little bit of both.
It really just depends on how you see this if you really love programming and being in the trenches.
Maybe you want to build it out yourself and then hire people around you so that you can take on larger
projects or maybe you're sick of programming and you'd rather transition to a point where you're actually
managing the programming and you're spending more time looking for clients and managing clients.
OK.
So let's say you are not a programmer if you're not a programmer you're going to follow this pretty
much the way we laid it out pretty much the way that I started sprint.
You're just going to look for subcontractors that are good you're going to work with them and you're
going to give them test projects and test accounts to see how they perform.
It's very much a trial and error process.
Once you find someone who's good who's reasonable in price who can deliver on time you're simply going
to keep that person and add that into your expertise that you can offer.
On the other side to your clients now are non-programmer really are going to be limited to being a project
manager or being a client manager at the very beginning you're going to have to be both.
You're really going to have to manage the client manage your expectations give them their updates talk
to them regularly and also be able to coordinate with your contractors who are building the app.
The application that you're being paid to built.
It's a little bit harder.
When I say a little it's like only a slightly bit harder as a non-programmer mainly because at the very
beginning you might feel like there's not enough people to do all of the work that's necessary you might
feel a little bit stretched as you're looking for clients and looking for subcontractors at the same
time.
A programmer can look for clients first build whatever it is that they actually land and then once the
demand exceeds what they can actually supply themselves then start hiring out and start multiplying
themselves.
So most of the lectures in this course are going to be relevant to both of you.
One of you has a bigger advantage in the other but the entire course covers both scenarios.
Programmers you're going to take the skill you already know and you're going to multiply it.
You're going to make it so you can take much bigger projects make a lot more money.
And if you want to transition out of being a programmer now if you're not a programmer Well you're going
to focus more on being a project manager or client manager.
And as you get more clients and as you get more picky and as you raise your prices you're going to transition
into whatever role you prefer to be whether or not that's just the CEO the president or the project
manager or in a lot of cases sometimes people actually work all the way down and they learn to program
this way.
So it's really up to you.
Make sure that you follow pretty much all of the advice in the course that's going to make sure that
you don't run into the problems that we ran into when we started.
And also give you a lot of advice on how you can make sure that you're making money how you can make
sure that you're bringing in a steady stream of clients and make sure that you're running this entire
operation smoothly.
All right.
See you in the next lecture.