So with that being said we can actually go over to theme Forest which is another fantastic source for
templates.
Another one that I like considerably.
I like this on a lot better than template monster.
They don't have as many templates technically that would fit within what we're looking for but they're
still incredibly useful.
So like so like template monster you can see that everything's divided off into sections.
We typically would just pick if we are using a platform you'd pick a section and then just go to it.
They have a distinction here between PTSD and HVM.
What does that mean if you're not familiar is the Dotsie extension for Photoshop and it just means Photoshop
design file.
And so what that would mean is that they're going to give you a photoshop file.
If you're someone who uses Photoshop has a little bit of design skills or is planning on making a significant
amount of edits to your photoshop file.
Then it's a good idea to come over here and just download it here.
Now if you do not want to say make a ton of graphic edits to it and you would rather have something
that's ready to upload on your own web site then you can use HDMI.
And then the last thing obviously is if you want to install this onto another system you can pick Wordpress
or any of these other generic CMOS systems.
OK so they've done that for you that's incredibly useful for us.
You just use it virtually the same way.
I mean I could just say web design and that's going to give me a significantly large group of very good
designs that are very helpful.
And so like typical monster here we can actually you know pick our price.
This is helpful because on thin forest they allow their designers to pick their own price.
That's why you see such a massive fluctuation.
This guy wants $8.
This guy wants $43.
There's even a ratings to as well to see if there's something wrong with it or down the line if something
doesn't work or if something in the advertising isn't what it should be.
So this works very very much in the same way.
You can also go and pick based off of a category and what you can do is quite literally just pick whatever
format you want.
So let's say we're looking at Photoshop files you typically want to get creative because creative in
this case is going to sum up any type of consulting business any type of design business.
They consider development businesses under Creative not under technology.
Do you go to technology to get a lot of templates of server pictures and just things that are way too
generic typically around like hardware.
So we're actually going to create.
So there's plenty of ones in here that work really really well.
You know right off the bat Here's one that's perfectly made for anyone who wanted to do a minimalist
design.
The biggest benefit you'll notice here is if you go ahead and you won't want the photoshop file and
not the HD mail or the wordpress.
That typically means that the person who uploaded this had to put less work into it.
So what I'm looking at this you'll notice the prices are consistently lower.
Never over 12 dollars.
That's why you would go after a photoshop file.
Obviously you also get to edit it on a much more deeper level.
But it's also significantly cheaper so if you really are trying to pinch pennies go for this option
just to give you a quick kind of view of how their UI works.
It's very very similar to template monster.
You can just do screenshots.
They also do live demos.
So right here you know this is a great example of another page that could be really retrofit for anything.
They've already made it sound like you're a studio as you can see it has a portfolio section it allows
you to put a hook and even allows you to have a call of action button if you want to you know promote
something else that's going on whatever it could be.
It also put sections here for if you want to add in a blog and testimonials and contact us you'll notice
these are all very much kind of within the same kind of realm.
This is helpful if you wanted something else very very minimalist.
OK so the last thing I want to show you with the theme forest is that the forest allows you to attach
certain adjectives to your search results which is incredibly helpful.
So over here what you have are called tags and tags are just very helpful because you can get much more
specific with what you're looking for.
On theme on template monster you would have to physically search for it and it's then a question about
whether or not it's designed or tagged correctly.
So why is this helpful.
Well if you're really picky about the design you wanted for instance minimal.
OK if you want to say that was very minimal very simple and that was something that you kind of wanted
to promote as one of your value proposition points then you pick this flat if you wanted to flat design
if you specifically thought that design was the best looking or you wanted to convey to other people
that your trendy kind of up on it you could use flash and flash is you know very kind of controversial
in the design community but if that's something that you specifically wanted to convey try it out these
templates are so cheap that honestly you can test with them.
You can try one thing test it with the message and try another one and just see what the response rate
is.
Now it's worth noting that once you actually have these on your site and you've completely changed most
of them there they are virtually indistinguishable from templates.
Now the only downside right was that you can't change every single part of it but to the naked user
they have no idea that this site is a template.
Once you've changed everything out of it so don't worry about people thinking that it's going to look
generic or mechanical or what have you.
So the last thing I want to point out is I'm going to do this over here in the resource section.
This is just someone who went ahead and actually curated some of the best design studio Web site templates
and some of these are actually free which is quite helpful if you guys are for some reason just absolutely
stuck with regards to which one you think looks better.
Try to dwell a little bit more on what exactly you want to convey.
Go back to the previous lectures where we did some of that planning that will definitely help you.
You can always post in the group discussion.
We can talk about it but you can also just go and resort to Google and just look for highly rated templates
and just see whether or not that's something that other people already like which is helpful because
if someone has already said this design template is very nice then you know that it already has a positive
effect on people looking for it.
So the last thing I want to point out very very quickly is a service that is incredibly helpful for
changing this.
So a lot of times when you are updating a template and there is just something that is beyond your skill
set but it's something that's very simple to do.
Let's say you wanted to take an image and customize it for you.
You want it to take your logo insert it or change something in the image and say you know there's a
stock image of say EMAC and you would like to change the iMac to have an image of your website or something
of your portfolio but you don't have the photoshop skills or whatever to do that what you can do is
you can use.
And I love using the 9 designs dot com if you guys are already familiar with my other courses we cover
99 designs quite a bit and tasks and what you basically do is you pay $20 and anything that a graphic
designer can do in an hour will be done in an hour and sent back to you.
So like anything else out there you just give a very basic description of what it is.
Over here you would upload your template or link to it up here and then you would say this is exactly
what I want it to change.
This is the image I have I want it to look like this.
What you can also do is say there is an icon set in my template and I want to change it to do to look
like this or customize it to look like this.
And you can use this and for $20 you can fix you know 10 different icons because it's something that
a graphic designer could do very very quickly.
So use this whenever you're absolutely stuck.
Most of these templates give you a modest amount of the ability to change everything on it.
Sometimes you get stuck with regards to oh I want to customize an image swap on an image but I want
it to look professional.
But you just simply don't have the time or the skills to do it.
This is typically what I use so whenever I'm using a template or we're using a template for a client
we'll put it up and then we can actually if we need to rapidly outsource something we use this quite
often actually and they're almost guaranteed to return this in an hour on average usually comes back
for us 20 25 minutes.
OK guys so go to these Web sites.
They're fantastic just for browsing around and getting some inspiration find something that you like.
Try not to be overwhelmed by how many templates there are out there.
If you're really having trouble with it.
Like I said before go back look at the value proposition lectures where we talked about deciding what
your strategy is what you're going to be good at what exactly you're going to sell and then try to build
something around that.
And that will help you considerably when you then go and pick something that will at least help you
whittle it down quite a bit.
OK guys if you have any questions just post in the group discussion otherwise I'll see in the next lecture.