Well let's talk a little bit about how you can know when you should go outside the country.
Outsource your job or stay in your country.
I'm putting this up kind of as a bonus edition because a lot of you have been asking I'm not sure if
I'm ready to outsource or maybe I should stay in house.
And so I'm doing this kind of to give you a little bit of guidance what I think there's only two factors
that I think apply to picking outsource one.
What are your resources at your disposal.
HOW MUCH CASH DO YOU HAVE.
How much are you willing to allocate towards your project.
And then to what's your experience with this.
Have you outsource before.
How technical are you.
You only know how to operate a Web browser.
Then outsourcing might be a little bit harder for you.
Do you know what a program is the programming language you know is that age TMLC.
SS is that when you consider programming or do you actually know how to do some server side and you
done some code cademy or really anything if you write a book.
Those are two factors and they are inversely related.
The more money you have and the more money you're willing to spend would imply that you can stay in
your country.
You can and refer previously to the temp.
I said before about finding off hours developers you can use that trick to get someone who speaks your
language you can talk on the phone you can even call them because it's a local area code and you can
get them on the cheap.
They're still going to be more expensive than an outsourced firm but not significantly.
I mean not five times what you'd expect if you went to a traditional studio and one of the big cities
if you have less money to crack at this then I would say that you probably are going to lean towards
outsourcing.
They are the best bang for your buck and you just need to know in your head if you are spending less
money.
How are you going to make up for it if you answered equity slap yourself in the face.
You make up with effort effort was the correct answer.
That's what you need to do.
You need to put a little more sweat into it a little more effort into the details.
You need to watch the developer a little more closely.
You need to check in more often that's how you make up for having a lower budget to your familiarity.
Why does this matter if you are green if you are completely new to this whole technology thing it might
be a little bit difficult for outsourcing.
You're going to run into a lot of problems where you describe something that you wanted to do and they're
going to say we can't for whatever reason because of a language barrier or just a communication barrier
or an information barrier or you don't understand how technology works.
And so you that's going to create some issues I've had this many times where I have a developer who's
outsourced say they can't do something or they would prefer to do something else.
Back in the day I didn't know anything about technology and so I made the wrong decision.
Now I know a lot more about technology.
I understand where they're coming from and a lot of times I can predict those problems ahead of time
and a lot of times I can give them directions.
I can say no actually you can do it this way.
I've done it before.
It'll work just do it.
And then if you have experience maybe you were an I.T. director or maybe worked with developers before
you are used to communicating with them or you have some basic familiarity with how programming works
and how web applications in general work what's good standards for development what are bad standards
then you should be much more confident outsourcing then you can really reap the benefits of keeping
it cheap.
Using the price parity advantage price parity just yeah I was referring to is how in other countries
cost of living is lower.
Things are cheaper therefore they get paid less for the same amount of work.
You can really reach that price parity advantage so if you got a lot of money and little familiarity
with technology then you definitely have the luxury of staying in the country.
If it's the opposite have a lot of skill and it's an experience with with technology or at least project
management and you don't want to spend as much.
Then it's obvious you should go outsourcing.
If you're a mix between the two.
Honestly it's you you're just going to go with who you have the best relationship with whether it's
the person in your country outside of your country and refer back to the sections or we talked about
qualifying your freelancers or your studios and that's how you can kind of determine by and far which
direction you should go because it's going to depend on the individual person or the individual contracting
firm.