It you guys will come back to the course.
So in this lecture we're going to talk really really quickly about how much do you customize your proposals.
So an issue probably run into if you've already started issuing proposals is that you kind of probably
wondering how much of the proposal needs to be custom tailored to the client and how much can a get
away with copying and pasting predefined content and information.
Now this is something that a lot of people ask about and a lot of you guys who haven't made proposals
are probably wondering why you're copying and pasting any information to begin with.
Well the reason why is because when you actually get to the point where you are actively taking in business
you will start to notice that if you customize every single proposal you're going be underwater pretty
quickly with how much time you would be spending on this.
Now there's a period of time with Sprint Qik where I was spending half my days sending out customized
proposals and that is just not an efficient use of time.
It did get a lot of conversions but it's not very efficient and you can definitely spend your time in
other places that will actually in the long run help you more.
So the question is how much do you customize and so I'm just going to be a little bit of thought for
myself on the subject.
So the first thing I think that you should consider is just how big is the project.
Right.
So larger projects typically.
So the first thing I think that you should consider is just how big is the project.
Right.
So larger projects typically.
So it's kind of a paradox.
Larger projects you would think that maybe you should spend more time on them.
Right.
And smaller projects maybe you should spend less time customizing them.
Well it's actually a little bit more complicated than that.
You might think that more customisation is better for big projects because that's the one that's going
to make the most money.
Well the problem with big projects is the sales cycles with those are longer takes longer for you to
close big projects and you probably see fewer and fewer of them.
Now on the flip side small projects they come and go quite rapidly and there's a lot more of them.
So it's really up to you to decide what you think is worth it for you.
Do you want to get a lot of small projects or do you want to focus in on three to four large projects
that can kind of carry you for the next period of time.
So really I think it's a judgment call.
If you customize a proposal for my small project.
You're very very likely to get the project.
Now the tricky part about this is that it's kind of reverse scale with a small project if you customize
a lot of your proposal you're in a better position to win that project than on a big project.
Now why is that.
The reason why is the convention is that bigger projects typically will have more customization.
People typically spend more time on big projects big projects typically have a lot of competition.
Now if you are a small project or even a mid-sized project and you customize a lot of it really impress
the client.
They might not even shop around for anyone else and you can close that the way that I suggest you go
about doing this is that you customize as much as you can efficiently and at the very beginning of your
process I generally suggest you customize more.
The reason why is because that's a good tool to stick out from the rest of the crowd.
But it's also something that can help you get traction early on which is really the biggest problem
when you are starting your development business after you get your first initial call.
It's really starts become a snowball effect once you start getting referrals and you start getting more
business.
So at the very beginning I suggest you customize more.
I also suggest that you focus on customizing for smaller projects and then recognize that bigger projects
are more competition.
So it might not be worth spending the time at that higher tier to compete.
Now the other thing I want to point out is the 60:40 rule and that's just what we use to kind of decide
how much we customize and we just use it as a golden rule when in doubt do this if we have a good feeling
about a project we might customize mourn a bad feeling we might customize less but in general this is
what we shoot for.
We will shoot for 60 percent is either custom or tailored to the project.
And 40 percent is copy and paste.
Now help to help you understand what I mean by this.
Before when we talked about the sections in a proposal the components of a proposal you notice that
a lot of that stuff is not specific to the project or the client.
The proposal is getting delivered to.
So an about us section or how we work or even next step.
These are all templated things that you will include in all your proposals case studies as well typically
we shoot for 60 percent.
And the way that we do that is we try to make sure to balance not too much access information that has
nothing to do with the project.
Typically with a client their attention spans are very short and it's a mistake that you'll make if
you assume that you have a captive audience don't assume that the proposal you send to them they're
going to be automatically interested in it.
They're going to read every single page.
That's a false assumption.
You need to make sure that at least 60 percent is custom and tailor to them because that's going to
keep their attention span and keep them reading the pages 40 percent is OK to get away with.
And as you get more projects you get more experience with your messaging as you as you tinker and tailor
more with those sections about you and basic information about your firm.
Those will get better and better your success with proposals will get better.
But just in general shoot for 60 percent that's the best we've experienced with attention spans.
Try to put as much custom as you can.
Don't be that firm that sends 90 percent duplicate content.
As someone who has purchased software I can tell you that it's very obvious when you get a proposal
and almost all of it is nonspecific non tailored to you and it's something that's very very disconcerting.
Even though we looked at the OCT example previously there were actually only two pages out of the 12
that were specific to the project.
And in one of them it was an estimate and it was only one number.
The rest of it was just template information.
Your clients are not dumb and even if they are dumb they subconsciously will recognize the fact that
sections of it have nothing to do with their proposal.
They want to know that you're thinking about their proposal.
They want to know that you're thinking about their project what it needs.
And yet you are ready to address the problems that they have and the way you do that is by tailoring
the proposal to them and not just a generic pitch of your company.
Typically if you're in a conversation with them they've read your Web site they've probably heard something
of you.
They don't need 10 pages of information purely just pitching you as a generic provider.
OK guys go forth and customize the main takeaways from this lecture is just that you should try to customize
as much as you can but obviously be realistic about the efficiency of your time.
You can't customize everything.
So when in doubt try to customize at least 60 percent the way you do that you focus more on their project
and less on pitching you a lot of those templated pages are unnecessary and you really need to think
about whether or not that extra page that says more information about you or how you work whether or
not it's really absolutely necessary.
And the other thing is that just be aware of how big the project is that you're going after.
If it's a big project that means big reward but it also means big competition.
Also be aware that small projects typically have less competition.
You can win those much more easily if you just spend a little bit more time in them.
It's a little bit counterintuitive but it's something that I think will definitely help you down the
line.
All right guys see the next lecture.