Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So in this lecture we're going to talk about an adage that you hear all across the business world which
is the customer is always right.
You talk a little bit about does that apply to development businesses.
And is that something that you should incorporate in how you do business.
So in development businesses is the client always right.
Well let's answer it literally literally no.
Very frequently they are wrong.
And typically the most common reason why they're wrong is they're trying to make judgments on something
that they're experts on.
If they were experts in development then they wouldn't have a need to hire you.
But that surely does not stop them from trying to pass judgment or make large project decisions that
they are not equipped to make.
Now the true kind of heart of the question is do you treat them as if they right all of the time.
A lot of businesses out there in different sectors different expertise.
They like to focus as if every time there's a complaint the customer is always right.
And that's one way that they make sure that the customer always stays happy.
That's something that works for a lot of other different industries.
Now whether or not you want to treat your development business like that that's entirely up to you.
I've seen plenty of development businesses use that kind of motto when it comes to customers and client
disputes.
So if a client isn't happy with something they were fundaments the client thinks that they cut corners
somewhere.
They go out of their way to give them free hours and essentially free money to fix whatever the problem
is.
Now on the other end of the spectrum you definitely have businesses and business owners that are combative
when presented with a potential problem.
It's always not their fault it's always up to the client to lower their expectations.
Now obviously success lies somewhere in the middle of this spectrum.
My advice for you is to find some kind of balance.
Now keep in mind this is a highly technical job and your clients are almost never going to be as highly
technical as the people building their project even if they do have a programming background.
Even in that case they're not going to be so acquainted with the project that they're going to be able
to be in a position to make good project based decisions.
So in general when it comes to development businesses I say you do this on a case by case basis and
you do not have a strategy really across the board.
I think in our situation it's too hard to make a general rule about customers and how often they're
right.
Try to pick the individual details in each individual case and make a decision that way.
There are always going to be times where you made a mistake and unless you're a type of situation where
you don't think you're ever going to see that client again and you maybe you don't want to see them
ever again you're going to tried to remedy the situation regardless.
Now if you do have to admit fall and this is kind of a side note try not to be overly apologetic that's
something that really oh Roads Authority be rational.
Explain what went wrong and why the likelihood of this being wrong in the future is very very small
now.
There's other types of scenarios where the client themselves makes a colossal error.
Now it's either because they tried to make a judgment themselves or maybe they assumed they knew more
than they actually do.
These are really unavoidable and it's pretty much something that you're going to have happen guaranteed
throughout your business career.
Now I wouldn't fret because in the vast majority of dispute cases but if you've actually gone and detailed
out your process you made sure you had a contract you made sure that you listed out as much as you possibly
can about what you're covering in what timeframe for what.
It's very easy when something goes wrong and there's a misunderstanding to go back and actually look
at exactly what happened and where something went wrong.
Now of course there's always going to be situations where it's not nearly as cut and clear like that
it's not nearly just a definitional or a technical error or someone just misread something.
Sometimes both sides actually make assumptions unintentionally that they should not have made.
So try to do your best and figure out what exactly went wrong.
Did you simply build something wrong and you yourself forgot to check it.
Did you Bill for something that you didn't actually explain properly.
Is the timeline not sufficiently clear.
How is your client getting confused when things are going to be delivered.
If any of those things are the case that's something that you can easily figure out and that is something
that is your fault.
Now on the flip side obviously there are situations where clients are wrong and themselves.
Now you know is your client accusing you of not telling them something when you clearly did tell them
something and you have documentation to show it is your client surprised by a bill that they received
and the reason why they're surprised is because they simply didn't pay attention when you gave them
the estimate before these are all very likely scenarios that can pop up.
Now if you have properly documented everything and you left a paper trail all your conversations it
shouldn't be an issue figuring out who's at fault.
If you're in a type of situation where it's absolutely not your fault then you should deal with that
accordingly.
And it was a situation where it clearly is your fault.
Then you need to recognize that you need to own up to it.
Obviously don't go over the top with how you lather on apologies but be obviously rational about it
but admit that something is actually your fault and move to remedy it.
Now there's one thing that's really important that I want you to come away with from this lecture if
there is a breakdown in communication regardless of whoever's fault it is the fact that it was allowed
to happen is your fault as the service provider.
It is up to you to provide everything in excruciating detail to make sure that your client is on the
same page to make sure they understand exactly what's happening when it's happening and what to expect.
There is never an excuse for not facilitating communication.
That is your job.
That is how you keep happy clients.
That is how you save yourself from potential issues down the road.
So if your clients are not on board you should not be leaving the port and setting sail to use a metaphor.
So I'll say it again.
Breakdowns in communication.
It's your fault that you let it happen.
It almost always comes down to you did something or you cut a corner.
You decided to not send an update.
You decided to not keep your client with something or you decided to skip a step.
So is the customer always right.
No they're not always right.
It's up to you to make your own policy decisions.
Personally the best way of doing it is just on a case by case basis.
You can easily figure out whose fault it is.
And there's easy ways to handle situations that are your fault.
And there's easy ways to handle situations that are the client's fault.
Use your documentation use rationality and try to be as simple as possible when you explain what exactly
happened and how to fix it.
But always be aware of the fact this dispute does exist because you probably did something wrong in
your process so use it as a feedback opportunity to improve your process so that it doesn't happen in
the future.
All right guys.
Any questions.
Post in the group discussion.
Otherwise see in the next lecture.