You guys actually the chorus so quick lecture on a big mistake you probably might be making.
So in general this is something you want to avoid when talking with clients don't talk about problems
just tell them what is happening.
Now the biggest difference between those two is one you're just being literal saying what's happening.
And the other one you're kind of being ambiguous and you're framing the discussion in a way that says
whatever this is that's happening is a problem and it's something to be worried about now vendors don't
have problems they have setbacks.
That's something you need to kind of keep in your mind because clients are read those two things in
completely different ways.
A setback is just something that happens all the time.
Something that they should have been aware of before they started the project and a problem is something
they've never seen before and it's something that I should be worried about.
Everyone should be worried about.
It's a big deal.
There's a really big difference between this is broken and this part is sending the wrong information
saying this is broken.
It just saying that something's not wrong with it and I don't even know what it is.
Shows that you don't know what it is and it shows that it's potentially a problem and problem is a word
you don't ever want to use.
So when working with clients try to be as literal as possible.
Setbacks happen but when they do happen tell them what exactly is happening and how long it's going
to take to get out of this snag.
Nothing is ever unsolvable.
Whether or not that's actually true does it matter when you're talking to a client.
Nothing.
Nothing is ever unsolvable.
If you don't know what the problem is and you attempt to articulate it it might sound vague.
So just keep in mind stay away from being vague vague implies problem using generalized terms like broken
doesn't work.
Those things they convey that there's a bigger issue at hand if you're just literal and say this does
not do this and we're going to fix it.
That's not a problem.
So try to remove that language from your vocabulary.
It'll help you out quite a bit.
Guys any questions posed to the group discussion.
Otherwise see in the next lecture
at.