You guys will come back to the course.
So in this lecture I'm going to go over a strategy for getting more clients.
That really is tried and true.
It's something that works for big companies.
It's something that works for small companies at the very beginning you're going to have a lot more
time to experiment with different marketing strategies and this is something that's really helpful especially
when you're trying to get clients from scratch.
So what I call this one is this is bad.
Let me fix it.
I think colloquially around the office we call it.
This sucks let me fix it.
But you know for you to me we keep it PGE.
So what I mean by this once you get into development and you start actually looking at portfolios and
looking in other people's applications and sites you'll get a lot more sensitive to quality in web sites
you get more sensitive about how they do certain things you get sensitive to what is considered good
and what is considered bad.
Now once you kind of get that sensibility and it doesn't take very long and a lot of people who just
use a lot of applications these are online a lot.
They get this as well.
But once you do start to notice things that are wrong in other web sites you'll notice that commonly
a lot of Web sites have the same issues over and over and over again.
So what a marketing strategy is is that you can go to these Web sites point out something that sucks
and say you know this is bad for this reason and I can fix it for you.
So now you can do this on a technical level like an example would be going to someone's blog and pointing
out say a contact form that doesn't work.
Pointing out something that just doesn't look right.
Images overlapping point out mismatches and type graphy really kind of basic stuff.
What you can do is hey say hey this is bad.
I can fix it and you can give them an estimate.
Now the return on investment on that strategy is pretty big.
I mean it's you're sending them a customized e-mail to them saying I can fix this this is the price
that's going to be much much better than if you just randomly emailed anybody out there who is a web
or mobile owner.
Similarly you can do it like you can point out things that could be improved.
So what you can do is kind of keep in your mind some things that are very popular that are easy to do
or somewhat time intensive to do that you think that a wide variety of people will be interested in
having it on their Web site.
Here's another example.
A lot of people run blogs like to collect e-mails but they don't know how to install e-mail capture
forms.
This is a very small example but it gets the point across what you can do is you can go to places and
look to see in blog rings in popular blogs and see who does not have that.
And you can message them that you don't even necessarily have to customize the message for each individual
person because problems with Web sites and problems and mobile applications they persist pretty much
across the board.
This is also very helpful if you work in a specialized niche like if you work in real estate it's very
easy to go to someone's web site and say this whole section is bad or something over here isn't even
working or be much easier if I could just install this for you give you great example real estate Web
sites.
Tons and tons of them list out all their properties.
But then they don't list enough information about them or they'll put photos and the photos are completely
formatted incorrectly.
You can very easily install photo browsers for them and all you have to do is say hey I can install
it like this and it would cost 10 hours and 10 hours.
Cost $400 whatever it is.
So this one's a little bit more creative but it's something you can do pretty much all day long look
for Web sites see something that you know you can fix and then tell them that and when you do it give
them a price.
Even if they're not interested you can often get referrals that way.
Keep in touch with you.
But the point is you'll get kind of first entry with a lot of new clients.
So always keep in mind though getting clients is the hardest part.
And the best part of having clients is the returning work.
How often they'll give you work in the future.
So even if it's a small gig you say $400.
Well you know if they have Web sites or they have mobile applications there is a good chance that they're
going to have other things they want to fix or other things they want to upgrade.
When that time comes.
During the first person they talk to you.
OK you guys go out and try this out.
Be responsible don't insult their website but do point out why something doesn't work how it could be
better.
People almost always react positively to that.
Any opinions or any other techniques you'd love to share.
Post in the group section.
Otherwise I'll see the next lecture.