Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So in this lecture we're going to talk about.
Do you follow your instincts with what you think is good or do you follow what the client says is good.
It's a dilemma that you're going to run into.
Now there's going to come a time through your development business career.
You're drawn into a situation where a client wants something but you know and you're pretty sure her
that will end in a poor outcome.
It's something that you know will not end up looking good.
So as an anecdote to this I can tell you all of the story it's spread.
We had an application that was a mobile app.
It was a very large project and we are on multiple occasions had this dilemma.
And I remember very specifically one time having our client Harris redo the app icon four to five times
and eventually he just sent us an app icon that he liked and said was amazing.
It was probably the worst app icon I've ever seen.
I described it as it kind of looked like if you had an app icon but it was processed by a Nintendo 64
it was pixilated.
It had a really lame gradient across it that kind of reminds you of the early 2000s.
It just looked absolutely absurd.
I knew it didn't even match the design of the app and it would look horrible on your phone.
And that's not the only time that's ever happened.
It happens a lot of times.
I mean I've had multiple times clients read the thing that they know exactly what's hot and what they
show you are what they want.
Is just ridiculous.
Now in order to fix this dilemma and to figure out a way going forward you need to evaluate your priorities
primarily.
Are you doing this for a portfolio.
And if you are doing it for portfolio will adding this new design change or development change to the
project and then adding at project your portfolio is that going to ruin your portfolio.
Is it one of those cases where you're doing this for a small amount of money even no money but you're
just doing it to build out a portfolio or for some other reason you took on the contract.
Now if that's the case I would say that you need to try as hard as you can to convince your client that
what they're doing is wrong and you need to be very specific about why you believe that that can be
very difficult to explain.
A lot of times this is very subjective you're just going to say that color doesn't look good.
How do you objectively explain that the color doesn't look good.
It can be difficult but try your hardest and as long as you make sure that you give repeated efforts
to explain it it should be able to get the message that you're very adamant about this being a bad decision.
Past that if it is a portfolio project and not getting a ton of money from it you might want to consider
just walking away and trying to distance yourself from the project.
If you're in the middle of the project maybe it's something that you try to wrap up more quickly and
you don't try to continue wasting a lot of time and resources on it.
If you're at the very beginning stages of the project maybe you do really try to just walk away slowly
and try to kind of cut your losses.
Now if it's a big project or it's a repeat client or it's a project that's got a lot of money on the
line for you then I would suggest you try to suck it up as much as possible.
Obviously try to tell them why you think it's bad and try to explain that it is bad and tell them that
you do disagree but the end of the day try to keep the client happy at the same time.
You can definitely put as much effort as you can into minimizing the damage they do.
Maybe this new design thing they're putting in a new change.
It's only very minimal what you can do is you can try to offer them alternatives.
You can try to even suggest putting that section somewhere else.
You can also suggest other features that could potentially replace it or offer new design alternatives.
You can even go as far as to do some of that work for free for them because you know that if they do
it themselves even though you get paid for that additional work or that design it's actually going to
be a detriment to the project as a whole and that's what you don't want.
So guys this happens a lot I think as long as you're conscientious about the fact that it's going to
happen.
You can figure out a way through it if it's a very important project.
Then you need to suck it up but you need to try to at least divert your client towards trying something
else.
Try to give them alternatives try to get your designers or your friends to give them something as an
alternative that they could use instead.
But on the flip side if this is just a portfolio project or one you're not even crazy about this might
be the impetus for you to walk away if you work with clients that have very bad design and feature taste.
They're probably not going to be successful at their project and they're probably going to have this
problem multiple times along down the road if you end up with an ugly project.
It's very often the case that they blame it on you not realizing that a lot of it is their fault.
That's just a headache you want to avoid.
All right guys questions posed in a group discussion otherwise see in the next lecture.