Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So I've got another strategy for you that you could potentially use in your development business.
So this strategy is called the perpetual discount.
Now what I mean by that perpetual discounting is kind of a marketing term is something that I kind of
made up is probably not exactly what it's called.
But if you're familiar with you to me that's a great way to explain this to me constantly has displayed
really high prices for their courses but then they run massive discounts on that.
And that's typically how they sell most of their courses and what kind of happened at least in the marketplace
is that people have reacted to these non-stops sales by raising their price up and up and up just because
buying a $400 course for $10 is better than buying a $50 course for $10 gives you that optical illusion
that this is more valuable or I'm getting more of a discount.
So it's big.
It's a better deal.
I should really go and grab it now.
Now you can implement something similar to this in your actual application.
When we talked about before about you know it's really about scoring points with your potential client.
They need something that is going to draw them towards you having them think that they're getting a
discount is always a good thing.
So what you can do is you can for instance offer rates that are based off of the type of client you
could say this is what we charge for corporate accounts.
So we charge for startups so we charge for freelancers nonprofits something like that.
Then what you can often do is inflate those numbers and then when you pitch it to them obviously you
see if they accept it.
They usually don't.
And then you have some sort of a leverage point to lower the price to essentially sweeten your offer.
Now the question I think a lot of people ask is that in some way dishonest it really just kind of depends
how you think about it.
For us what we often do is will say you know our per hour cost is this and if there's a client that
we really want or something that we think is a really good portfolio item or something we'd actually
enjoy working on.
We will give them a discount or we discount relatively quite often.
But for us it's actually true because we do charging 60 dollars an hour typically.
And then when we offer a discount that is a true discount.
But what we noticed is it's always better to offer a higher anchor price because of the perceived value
and then it gives you more room to leverage to lower the price.
Now this is helpful for closing deals.
Not necessarily helpful for attracting interest to you.
It is something that you can use later on to get attention towards you for clients but the best part
about this is more about negotiating a contract.
A lot of times you will get stuck in a contract negotiation and after you've tried pretty much all your
techniques giving them a great portfolio giving them a really personalized proposal you know going above
and beyond answer all their questions all times are kind of at a loss for what you can do past this
point.
Budget is almost always the biggest factor in their decision.
Its just one of the things that they mention probably the least.
So if you advertise yourself at a much higher rate than what you're willing to work for that gives you
room to wiggle.
It's great if you get someone at a much higher rate.
That means you can spend more put more time and effort into making a better product.
But you can also lower the price as a way to close the contract.
So obviously don't go wild like you to me has where you have thousand dollar courses.
There's no point in saying I'm worth $100 but I'll give you ten.
For the most part if you have a contract negotiation being able to lower the price that can actually
get them over the hump.
And so offering what is called kind of a perpetual discount which is you know a false price and then
a much more realistic price.
And you know that you can always gravitate towards it.
That puts you in a much better position to close contracts and to bring in more business.
All right guys I'll see you in the next lecture.