You a max of the course in this lecture we're going to cover another strategy that can consistently
increase your project sizes.
And so it can dramatically increase the customer lifetime value of each client that you get.
Now obviously there's multiple ways of going about growing your business.
One is to have the same client base but work on having more valuable projects with them.
Another is to focus on creating an engine that creates more clients and obviously you know one other
strategy might be just focusing on retention so you don't need a lot of outreach.
But everyone you get you keep for a long period of time.
Those are all legitimate ways of growing your development business.
Now if you are interested in increasing the lifetime value of your clients or increasing the value of
each individual project and that's something you want to pursue a really good strategy is something
that works for us.
We call it constant estimation.
Now what do I mean by that.
Typically when you have a project you're only going to be doing estimation up at the very beginning
of the project right up front you give them you know the big estimate.
And if you listen to the other lecture about ballpark estimates maybe you give them two estimates.
After that a lot of people just think oh we're done with estimations.
Well if you're a successful freelancer in any other type of business you probably know that you relied
a lot on selling your graphic designer designers upswell all the time will always offer you to design
something else at a discounted rate.
Always bundling things together to save you money.
It's very very common.
Now the most effective way of upselling that we've found in our experience is the technique that we
call constant estimation.
Well at Sprint we actually work and what's an agile development methodology what that kind of means
is that we deliver chunks of work at a time.
Some people deliver the whole thing all at once.
Some people deliver bits and pieces and they all add up to the project total.
So for us every time we send out an email with a large update of what we've published and what's now
Dymo Bill what we typically will do is just for every single sprint.
And if you're not familiar with the sprint as that is what a chunk of work is we would actually include
extra estimations now when we're building out an application.
Constantly we noticed that there are other features that the client has foregone or there's other possible
things that could be done or there's a lot of times where extra layers of security or technology could
be added but maybe they're a little bit frivolous.
A lot of times when you have a client and they're trying to figure out what to put in their application
and what not to or their website they have to prioritize what's most important.
But the problem is is that when they prioritize they don't actually know how long each individual section
will take to get built.
And therefore they don't know the actual cost associated with it.
So they might be thinking that this feature is going to be huge and so therefore it's not worth it but
it might actually be the case that features are not particularly difficult.
So they should read prioritize.
So with constant estimation what we do is we constantly look at extra things they do and we shoot to
include estimations just as an afterthought.
At the end of every single sprint.
So the universe spreads will say you know this is what we've built.
This is what it does.
These are the things that are about to be done and hey by the way here are three extra things that we
think could help.
And how many hours they're going to take now.
We're not pushy about it.
Obviously you can build some sales techniques around this.
We just pump that out there to make them understand what are your options.
Right.
Because as a non-technical client they just have no idea what it's going to take to put in.
So if we give them the information they can do a much better job at planning their product roadmap.
But also in a lot of cases they'll start adding in more and more features as they now know this.
This feature is actually quite small.
Or they can find out this features you know maybe not even think about it it'll be next month.
So when you have clients get in the routine of building constant estimation CAUSLEY estimate additional
things try not to be annoying about it.
Obviously you try to listen to your client in that only pick things that they have mentioned that they
are curious about or things that you've seen be used in similar applications I've ever asked you could
just say you know these are things that we've seen that other people use.
And it really doesn't take us very long to estimate it out.
So we just kind of included it from a product management standpoint that's very much a good thing.
That's sort of a good product manager would do.
They'd constantly be aware of what else could be included in the product and how long and how expensive
it be and it would be up to them to make everybody else aware of it.
So if you get into that habit you can consistently grow your projects and you can consistently make
your clients more valuable.
OK guys if you have any questions about constant estimation Postum scutcheon any other questions you
just message me the x factor.