Hey guys I'm back to the core.
So in this lecture we're going to talk about running without contracts.
What happens in those scenarios where you didn't sign a contract but you're still making contract work
for one of your clients.
Now this is the type of scenario that will eventually happen.
A lot of you out there are going to try out your development business as an experiment and you might
not want to put a lot of time upfront into making contracts.
Now that's not a huge excuse if you're taking this course because we have contracts at the very end
of the course in the resources section that you can literally just plug and play your information.
And we don't have a lecture that explains how you get them signed electronically.
Really easy within 10 minutes.
But for a variety of reasons it might be tempting not to sign a contract maybe the work that you're
doing is incredibly small and it's just not worth it.
Maybe it's someone that you've worked with in the past and so you feel like you trust them or maybe
it's like a friend and family type situation where you feel like a contract might be kind of a rude
thing to do.
And it signals that you don't trust them.
It could also be the case that you are trying to close a client and you're worried that sending them
a contract might actually scare them away because it takes an extra step and a lot a little bit more
time.
But it also makes them have to come to terms exactly what they're doing and paying for now running with
contracts.
It's never ideal.
I strongly suggest you don't do it.
I suggest you focus more time figuring out ways to make contracts easy and get them signed quickly.
That's a better time investment than trying to figure out how you can do damage control after you've
done an entire project that has no contract.
OK.
But if you do insist on going on this route.
I have three things that you should keep in mind that will help you quite a bit.
So number one don't ever do this with someone that you've never worked with before and not never was
someone who hasn't paid you before.
That's the key there.
A lot of times people think oh I've worked with this person before but in reality they've worked with
them collaborated but they've never changed money that's important.
An important distinction you can figure out pretty quickly how trustworthy someone is how credit worthy
they are by having a cash relationship with them.
Once you've established that you can pay each other and you see eye to eye on projects.
You know the chance of you having a miscommunication is significantly slimmer than if you're working
with someone that you've never traded money before with people's behavior around money is very very
different than the way that they behave around projects that don't involve money.
Number two keep a paper trail as much as possible.
And what I mean by this is if you're going to do this try to force all of your communication into something
that has a record try to put it all in the email when you do do e-mail try to be as extensive as possible.
Try to take screen shots of updates take screenshots of changes to the application so you can show on
day one this look like there's some day to look like this.
Put annotations.
Try to keep as much paper as you can because later down the line if something does happen this is the
only thing that's going to stop you from being in a situation with the other person says.
None of this ever happened.
Now number three when you are communicating with them make sure at every opportunity you have to include
costs and features always list out everything you're doing.
You make sure this is in the written record and you make sure there's a record of your client seeing.
You say it's going to cost this and do this and then agreeing to it.
Now it doesn't necessarily have to be explicit.
They can see the cost and see what you said you're going to do for them.
And you know just by virtue of the fact they didn't say no and they continued on with the project that
is an implicit agreement at the end of the day if you need to go back written records are going to save
you.
They're a little bit sloppy and they're a little bit tedious but hey there are a lot better than nothing
right.
And again you're trying to save yourself some time by not writing a contract which would have saved
you all of this trouble.
So in general if a problem actually arises and you get caught running without the ball so to speak running
without a contract I wouldn't worry entirely as long as you follow those three things I just covered
with you if you do have an extensive written record of conversations and transcripts and places where
you list out exactly what you're doing and they agreed to it then you're in a decent position.
Obviously you're in a weaker position because you don't have a contract where a signature is pretty
explicit that they agree to it.
But for the most part you actually do have a solid foundation in virtually every jurisdiction at least
in the United States any type of verbal agreement in writing is virtually the same thing as a contract
and any judge or court is going to look at it the same way.
The only problem with them is just that they're so sloppily put together they're very hard to prove
what exactly someone meant by this or is a contract is completely unambiguous.
So I wouldn't completely fret if something happens at the end of the day written contracts are still
the law.
And the fact that you have documentation showing that they agreed to something that's pretty much all
you need but it's not advisable and it's really not ideal but there are certain scenarios we're running
another without a contract might be an OK thing to do.
Now keep in mind any long term project should always have a contract no matter what.
At the absolute minimum just to have a contract saying that you're being hired to do some work for them
and this is roughly what you're going to do at least you can do that to show that you're in a contracted
relationship and then anything after that is just work that it could be considered a Dinda or additional
work at that point.
There's really it's impossible to deny that you are not in a contract relationship with this person.
They have not willingly agreed to bring you on in some kind of a paid position.
Now remember if you're using one of the online platforms like L.A. or up work they have their own contract
written into it and they use their own escrow services and those scenarios don't worry about it.
OK guys if you feel like running without a contract you don't have to worry too much.
Just keep in mind some very basic things.
Focus on having a written record focus on only doing this with people that you've traded money with
and focus on in your written record being explicit as possible listing things out and getting a verbal
agreement.
You're not in a huge amount of trouble.
You're just up for something.
It's more of a headache down the road.
It's not really the end of the world.
It just might be more time consuming than it would have been otherwise.
All right guys.
Any questions posed in the group discussion although I see in the next lecture.