Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So in this lecture I'm going to talk about what are the most powerful strategies out there for finding
clients.
Now this strategy is called Give something away for free.
Now you've probably heard that in other verticals or other businesses.
A lot of times people give or create things.
Those things have value.
They give them away for free.
Now this is especially potent in development businesses for a couple reasons.
One is that when you create something for free and you give it away.
Not only does it establish you won as someone who is competent it shows.
Look at this thing I created it shows off to that person that you can master that technology or you
have such a good understanding of how that tech works that you can create it on your own and you're
so confident you can give it away for free.
The second thing is what it does is that it actually puts you in the door with tons and tons of people.
So not only does it raise your actual profile people might have heard of you if you give away something
that's really popular but it gets you automatic entry into conversations with people all over the world.
Now let me roll it back a little bit to help you understand what exactly I mean when it applies to a
development business.
Now typically what you would do is you would pick some type of tool that you think would be really really
helpful.
Or you go out and do some research on something that also you think would be really helpful.
You also do really simple things like create guides to links to popular tools or ways to fix problems
that you've run into.
Whatever it is something that your potential client group has problems with.
Now if you're trying to gain attention of say like the development community maybe you want to build
something around hard problems that developers have you create a free tool that solves that problem.
If you want to target a specific community let's go back to that real estate example.
Maybe you build a tool that is really makes it really easy for people to share photos of their spaces
or maybe you make a tool that automatically displays available houses on the market on a map something
like that.
Now the thing doesn't have to be incredibly complicated it just has to be something that you can do
simply that other people could not do very easily.
And the reason why you can do it simply is because you have development expertise and you have development
capacity.
So really what you want to do is you want to think about what group are you trying to sell to.
And then think about any type of problem they have that could easily be solved by say like a web tool.
Now the way that you're going to be successful with this is by how well you can understand your potential
customer and then how well you can identify a small problem they have that you could solve.
Now it's a good idea to go after a problem that everyone in your customer base potentially could have
and not just a standard solution for one person.
OK.
So to give you an example here at Sprint.
One of our biggest client bases is actually graphic designers and specifically graphic design studios.
Now how are their client.
So we've got a lot of our business by going after freelancers and graphic design firms and saying hey
you're losing a lot of money.
Why don't we partner together you design and we develop so we give you all of our design jobs.
You give us all of your development jobs and that's worked extra extraordinarily well.
We don't have to deal with finding new clients.
All we have to do is deal with keeping up the bargain of what are we just promised to the other firm.
So what we ended up doing was we had known that graphic designers do not have a ton of places or free
tools to show off their portfolio.
We also knew that while there are some tools out there like core a flaw or dribble typically they cost
money or Typically they are just really ugly and hard to customize.
And we also knew that graphic design firms really didn't like using those platforms for portfolios.
The reason they don't like that is because when you're a graphic design firm typically when you want
to show off a design you want to put more information about it.
Typically you want to do things like case studies you'd like to include testimonials quotes you probably
have a more holistic approach to it.
It's not just showing off your final product and a lot of freelancers like this too.
So what we did is we built a free portfolio tool that allowed you to present graphic design in a case
study type of manner.
And this is something that we cover.
If you've ever taken any of my other courses we actually cover this quite extensively.
We called the marketing access portal and there is something that we literally just launched as a part
of our development.
And then within our the app that we gave away completely free we just had lots of ways that you could
easily contact us.
Now that's a little bit of an exaggeration in terms of how far we went with it to get a lot of business
and to build hype but that's kind of the basic idea we identified that a good client base for US were
graphic design freelancers and graphic design firms right.
We knew that they had a problem or we knew that they had a solution out there that just wasn't perfect
and that since we had a lot of development capacity we could build something better for them.
So we did that.
And honestly you know with the portfolio we made isn't necessarily even better than anything out there.
That wasn't the point.
The point was just to get a lot of attention because people love free things.
So you can use that as a strategy in your development business.
Think of who you're selling to.
Think of a problem they have and see if you can solve that problem really easily because at the end
of the day that's a really good way of advertising yourself.
And the reason why it is so particularly effective is because you're giving them something for free.
So you're building trust with them.
They like the fact that they got something for free and also it's very easy to publicize free goods
when you're selling something that's free.
The kind of negative reaction from anyone you show that to is always going to be significantly less
than if you're charging money for it.
I came up to you and said here's a tool it costs $100 versus if I said here's a tool.
It's completely free.
If it's completely free you might forego the fact that you don't know me.
You have no rapport with me and you don't know what the tool does.
So it makes it a lot easier to spread.
But it's kind of like a little bit of a Trojan horse because it actually is advertising.
It is getting your name out there showing what you're capable of.
And if you're smart you put your information all over it.
So it's a great way to reel back in customers.
So that was a big growth hack for us that we did that our second year and building the marketing access
portal made a huge jump in how many partnerships we made.
Okay guys try it out yourself if you need help thinking of ideas.
Not an expert in every single field but just posts in the group discussion we can always try to help
you out.
Otherwise see next lecture.