After entering your application meta data,
the JHipster generator will prompt you as to whether or not
you want to use the JHipster registry.
You might be wondering just what this is.
The JHipster registry is a separate application from the
scaffolding that we're generating.
The application implements the microservices pattern named service registry.
Now you might be wondering,
why would I need a service registry for a monolithic application.
The JHipster registry functions as a Spring Cloud Config server,
so you can centralize runtime configurations using it.
The registry also functions as an administration server,
so you can gain the benefits of viewing metrics,
monitoring the application, and performing management tasks.
If you don't have existing tools to support these features,
you may want to consider the JHipster registry as an option.
You can find more about the registry application at jhipster.
github.
io/jhipster-registry.
I won't be selecting support for the JHipster registry in this course,
so let's respond with that decision now.
I've again opened Windows PowerShell with the
current step of project generation.
So we keep focus on the scaffolding regenerating,
I'm going to select No for JHipster registry. Now that that decision is made, let's continue to security.