JHipster gives you a lot of flexibility for selecting the database
that your application is going to work with.
As you can see,
the first selection you need to make is the type of database you want to use.
There are three options presented.
The first is to use a SQL database.
The second and third are NoSQL databases called MongoDB and Cassandra.
For this demo, I'm going to stick with SQL as it's the most common option.
Now that I've selected SQL for the database type,
I'm presented with different SQL database products.
They include MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle, and SQL Server.
Also note,
the question highlights this as a selection for the production database.
Well what does that mean?
Production refers to a database used in any environment
other than a local one for development.
We'll select the development database next.
First, I'm going to select SQL Server, and sure enough,
the next decision is for the development database product used.
Note that the first two options are for H2,
which is commonly used when the production database
can't be run on a local workstation.
With the ease and availability in installation for SQL Server,
you may want to select it for consistency.
However, for this course, I'm going to select H2 with disk persistence,
to reduce the number of prerequisites.
Please note,
I chose disk-based persistence as I've had trouble in the past
querying in-memory persistence at runtime.
So let's select the option.
The next decision you'll be prompted with is for second level cash.
JHipster generates your project using JPA, with Hibernate as the provider.
By default, Hibernate caches objects within its current session.
However, second level cache will cache object across sessions.
Second level cache can improve the overall performance
of your application's data access,
but it does come with the requirement of a cache provider,
as well as some additional complexity.
As noted by the options, each cache is used for a single node,
while Hazelcast and Infinispan are used for distributed
cache in a clustered environment.
While this is often recommended for performance improvements,
I'd again like to keep this demo simple,
so I'll be choosing No for this option.
You should evaluate for yourself if you require this
type of performance improvement.
Let's look at what JHipster will generate for these options that were selected.
There are three key assets that JHipster generates for database support.
First, JHipster will generate the full configuration for your data source.
Configurations will be available for different Spring profiles,
including a development and production profile.
Next, JHipster generates Liquibase configuration.
Liquibase is a tool that supports management of the database schema.
JHipster provides you with an initial schema that includes
database tables for security support.
Finally, JHipster generates the JPA entities for you.
To start,
these entities map to the database tables created
through Liquibase for security.
JHipster's database support is another feature that makes it
stand tall above other scaffolding tools.
Oftentimes,
one of the most challenging tasks we face as developers is to work
with an application that uses a local data store.
JHipster is standardizing schema management right up front for you,
which should help with the time it takes to develop locally,
and the time it takes to maintain and implement schema changes.
That covers JHipster's database support. The next decision is around the build tool to be used.