JHipster supports two build tools for the back end.
You can choose from either Maven or Gradle.
As I mentioned earlier in the course, we're going to use Gradle.
I prefer to use it because it uses code over XML configuration.
Let's select Gradle now.
With Gradle selected,
I'll briefly cover what JHipster is providing for your builds.
The build tasks that JHipster generates are broken down to two categories.
First, you have your common build tasks.
These tasks include compiling the Java code,
generating the WAR file, managing dependencies,
and running tasks.
There are also several support tasks that get included.
These type of tasks are available for supporting the running of
Liquibase for database schema management,
Webpack for web asset builds, Sonar for technical debt reports,
and Docker for container-based runtime.
Finally, Gradle scripts allow for support to run and configure tasks,
based on the Spring profile that you're running with.
This includes a development and production profile.
Now that you know what's supported for Gradle, let's continue to the next decision.