In the next step of the generation process,
JHipster allows you to make a decision on other technologies
that you'd like to include in the scaffolding.
This is sort of a catch all bucket for common dependencies.
We aren't going to select these options so that we can
keep focused on the main scaffolding,
but you may want to explore these options in case they
are of use to you for your application.
First, we have social login.
This gives you the ability to authenticate users from Google,
Facebook, or Twitter, using Spring Social.
Elasticsearch gives you support for a search engine
via Spring Data Elasticsearch.
Hazelcast supports clustering your HTTP session for storing Spring
Security authentication and authorization information.
WebSocket gives you support for WebSockets through
the Spring WebSocket's library.
Finally, Apache Kafka provides you with a published subscribe message broker.
I'm going to just hit Enter to continue to the next selection. Next, I'll cover the decision for a client-side framework.