Hi everyone, my name is Michael Hoffman,
and welcome to my course,
Scaffolding Spring Boot and Angular Web Apps with JHipster.
Along with being an author here at Pluralsight,
I'm also a principle consultant at Solstice,
based out of beautiful Chicago, Illinois.
Building a new web application using modern tooling
has always presented a challenge.
You need to address a lot of development concerns,
such as what frameworks to use, the configuration of the application,
and scripts for builds and deployments.
Yeah,
you need to balance addressing these concerns with the
priority of developing new features.
In this course,
we're going to walk through a web application
scaffolding generator by the name of JHipster.
You'll see why it's one of the best options for
starting your next new web application,
as it addresses development concerns early,
and allows for the development of new features right out of the gate.
Some of the major topics that we're going to cover include
installation of the JHipster generator,
creation of a new project through JHipster,
customization of the project's security,
implementation of the client and server code for a new feature,
and finally, the deployment of the project using a production configuration.
By the end of this course,
you'll know enough to successfully leverage JHipster for
generating your next web application.
Before you begin the course, you should have some familiarity with Java,
JavaScript, the Spring boot framework, and the Angular framework.
I hope you join me on this journey to learn JHipster,
with the Scaffolding Spring Boot and Angular Web Apps with JHipster course at Pluralsight.