Hi, I'm Michael Hoffman.
In this module, I'll be covering JHipster support for production deployment.
I'll demonstrate the configuration and execution of the application that
we generated into a production server environment.
JHipster defines two types of application runtimes.
Up until now,
I've used Gradle and YARN to run the JHipster
generated application in development mode.
Now, let's shift to running the application in a production runtime.
This means the application will be using a different set
of configurations from development,
such as using Microsoft SQL Server in place of H2 for the database.
The production runtime for a JHipster application comes
with a whole new set of concerns.
It should come as no surprise as no surprise that JHipster
provides you with strong support for addressing them.
The first concern is production configuration.
In the patient portal application I selected to use
an H2 database in development, and a Microsoft SQL Server database in production.
This has impacts on how the application interacts with the database.
To address this type of concern,
JHipster defines two Spring profiles- one for development,
and one for production.
As you saw on the server code demonstration,
the application code explicitly configures H2 for the
Spring development profile only.
I'll be covering more details about project configuration and profiles shortly.
The next concern is continuous integration and
continuous delivery of the application.
After development is complete,
there may be one or more tasks that need to be performed for
the deployment artifact to be published.
JHipster supports sub generators for configuring
these tasks to work with CI systems, including Jenkins,
Travis, GitLab, and Circle.
This concern is outside of the scope of the course,
however, please visit the JHipster website for more information on the topic.
Once the application is configured, and CI/CD tasks are complete,
the next concern is the creation of either an executable or deployable artifact.
JHipster provides you with support for either of these
options through a defined Gradle build.
I'll be demonstrating this after a covered production configuration.
Once the artifact is generated, it needs to be deployed.
As you likely know, there are many options for choosing deployment.
JHipster provides you with sub generators to support several of these options,
including deployment to Docker, Pivotal Cloud Foundry,
Kubernetes, AWS, and Heroku.
In this course, I'm just going to run an executable WAR,
as it's the quickest and easiest example.
Finally, once the application is deployed,
it's important to have ways to monitor the application,
such as metrics and auditing.
JHipster provides you with the support by generating the
application with dependencies and metrics libraries.
Monitoring is outside the scope of this course,
so I don't plan to cover it any further.
With these concerns of mine,
let's look at what you will need to follow along with
the demonstration of deployment.
To run the SQL Server production database, I'll be using Docker.
We can find the installation on the Docker website at docker.
com.
I'll be using Docker for Windows to keep consistency
with the rest of the course material.
I won't be showing you how to install it,
but if you run into setup issues,
I would recommend to check out one of the existing
Pluralsight courses for support.
Now,
let's look at how we can configure the patient portal application for deployment.