Hi I'm Michael Hoffman.
In this module I'll be demonstrating the implementation of
server-side code to complete the new feature that we
started in the previous module.
I'm going to complete the coding for the new feature, but let's quickly recap.
The business case is to allow patients to interact
with their physicians in a practice.
It's eventually going to be a full functioning portal,
but to start with we just want a feature that allows
patients to manage their appointments.
From a log-in perspective,
I already have made changes to modify the existing
user role to be a patient role.
On the server side, I'll be showing you how JHipster handles security concerns,
including the log-in.
While I initially stubbed out the API,
I'm going to replace it with full functionality.
The first step will be to add support for persisting new appointments.
I'll be implementing the REST controller,
service, repository, and database script for appointments.
With appointment persistence in place,
it will be fairly easy to then replace the API for returning all appointments. Let's start by adding the new appointment schema to our Liquibase scripts.