Hello, I'm Michael Hoffman, and welcome to the course.
In this first module,
I'm going to explain to you why it's important to start
developing Java web applications with scaffolding.
You'll also learn why JHipster may be the best
option of generating the scaffolding.
To begin, think about the last time that you created a new Java web application.
Commonly, projects are either created using a manual, or an automated approach.
When you created your last project, did you download the dependencies,
write your own build scripts, automation scripts,
configuration scripts, and security, or,
did you generate a project from a tool, or command line interface?
Did the generated project give you everything that
you needed to be production ready, or did you still have to perform manual steps?
Let's look at these approaches in some more detail.
I know that when I've tried to create a project entirely from manual steps,
I've often faced a lot of challenges.
One of the biggest challenges that I've faced is the decision-making process.
During project creation, there's a lot of decisions that need to be made.
I need to ask questions such as what Spring profiles am I going to use,
are developers going to want an imbedded local database,
how am I going to implement security?
Even after I make these decisions,
it may take me one or more attempts just to get the implementation right.
As a result,
it takes me a lot of time just to get the foundation of an application in place.
Likely, I'm going to run into time constraints,
so there's also a good chance I'll be cutting corners and leaving
out a key part of the application plumbing.
Instead of using a manual approach,
what if I used tooling to generate the project foundation for me?
When you use tooling,
such as generating a project from a command line or a website,
you're starting with scaffolding.
Scaffolding is any type of code structure that supports
the process of building an application.
The approach to scaffolding is two-fold.
With scaffolding, you make decisions right at project creation time.
The important difference from manual project creation is that
scaffolding helps you not only make the obvious decisions,
but also those less obvious ones.
These less obvious decisions often aren't made until later
in the project development life cycle, where they become more expensive,
and much more difficult to implement.
Scaffolding can also enforce the use of best practices.
It's likely that the tool used to generate scaffolding is being
updated to support the latest and greatest approach.
This can be a significant difference for manual project creation,
where you often follow practices that you're familiar with.
Even if those practices may no longer be relevant.
By taking this approach, what benefits should you get from scaffolding?
I'm going to cover four main benefits that I have observed from
using scaffolding over manual project creation.
The first, and most important,
is improved quality throughout the project lifecycle.
Because you're making standardized decisions early,
you'll reduce the chances of quality gaps later in the project,
such as the lack of a testing framework,
or the lack of deployment automation.
Because you're choosing best practices that are modern,
you should also gain an increase in the stability of the application.
Along with improved quality,
you should see a reduction in the time that it takes to complete a project.
If for example,
you didn't consider deployment automation until late in development,
you might be forced to make a lot of code changes just to support it.
And you can be sure that you'll be spending a lot of time
discussing options with team members,
who will likely be more stressed mid-project lifecycle,
than they would have been at the start.
Along with the quality of the project's foundation,
scaffolding should also improve the quality of the overall solution.
Why?
Because you and your project team could focus on the important tasks,
like making sure that the end user could log in and buy stuff,
rather than those less important tasks,
like deciding between Maven and Gradle as a build tool.
All of this leads to a reduction in the risk of developing a project.
Most importantly, you reduce those scary unknown risks,
like your ability to actually test the application,
or deploy it into production.
Given these benefits,
let's look at a common example for scaffolding Spring applications.
As a Java web developer, I leverage the Spring Boot framework heavily.
To generate scaffolding for a Spring Boot application,
I frequently use the tool called Spring Initializer,
which is available from the website, start.
spring.
io.
Let's look at what it creates for you.
I'm showing you the Spring Initializer website.
I have the full version opened,
and you can see all of the selections in this full version that are
available for you when you're generating a project.
Let's start by creating a simple Java web project.
I want it to have web, database, and security features,
and I want to use Gradle.
I've changed my selection to use Gradle,
I'm going to leave the other default selections for
Java language and Spring Boot version,
I'm also going to leave the defaults for the project metadata.
Let's start adding dependencies.
As I said I need a web feature, so let's search for Web.
Okay now I have that as a dependency, I'm also looking for security,
that was my second feature.
Now I need to look for a database.
So I'll search for database,
and I have five selections and really only one of them are of interest to me.
I'm going to use H2 for my local development, so I'll select that.
So now I have three dependencies, but I want more.
So let's scroll down and see what actually is available.
On the left, I have Security selected in the Core category.
On the right side, I have Web.
I think that's enough for me, so I'll continue to scroll down.
I see SQL at the bottom,
and that's of interest to me because I need database support.
The first option is JPA, I'd like to have JPA support so I'm going to check it,
I'm going to look down a little farther and I also want PostgreSQL support,
so I'm going to select PostgreSQL.
So, again, I should have everything I need for database,
I'll continue to scroll down just because I want to see
what other options are available.
There's a lot of stuff here.
There's a lot over on cloud,
well I'm not really using cloud so that's not of interest to me.
I get down here and I see I/O,
well I don't really have I/O right now so I'll continue.
Then I get to the bottom and I get Ops.
Let's go ahead and select Actuator.
So, now I've selected some dependencies, I'm going to generate the project.
And I have a demo project that's now been zipped up,
and I can take a look at it in an IDE.
Let's look and see what Spring generated.
I'm displaying the demo project that got generated
from the Spring Initializer website.
As a basic starting project, this can work for me,
but from an experienced point of view, I'm starting to see some gaps.
Let's take the resources folder for example.
I selected the web feature from the Spring Initializer website.
As a result, all I got was a templates folder and static folder.
I have to start from scratch creating my UI.
Also, if I look at my java folder, the only class in here is my DemoApplication,
which is the Spring Boot runner, I have no configurations in here at all.
But, I know I selected Spring security, and some database dependencies.
I expected something.
Next, let's look at the build script.
This build script is very basic.
All it's showing me are the dependencies that I selected from the website.
I have no type of integration with automated tools,
or let's say Docker for example as a container.
Again, it's very basic.
So,
why are there so many gaps to fill with this project
before I can be production ready?
While Spring Initializer supports the creation of a working prototype,
it also highlights an important issue.
Scaffolding tools may leave you with a gap between
working prototype and production-ready.
For example, while I selected a web dependency,
no client-side code was generated.
I'll need to manually integrate a client framework, such as Angular or React.
The reason this is important is that I'm back to manual project creation.
I won't see the benefits that I claimed you should
be expecting from scaffolding.
Now wouldn't it be great if there was a scaffolding tool that
could fill this production readiness gap, and provide you the benefits that you deserve?