The next decision that JHipster presents you with is to select
one or more options for test frameworks.
By default, JHipster will provide you with support for JUnit,
to code and execute unit tests for Java,
and Karma to code and run your JavaScript unit tests.
The selections shown are in addition to these default frameworks.
Gatling provides support for load and performance testing of web applications.
Cucumber provides support for automated testing of web
applications using a behavior driven approach.
Protractor provides support for end to end testing of Angular applications.
It acts as more as an integration test framework when compared to Karma.
Given its availability from Angular, and it's feature set,
this is a framework that I've found myself selecting for scaffolding,
therefore, I'm going to select it now.
Selecting Protractor as a test framework will result in both
the generation of protractor configuration,
and the generation of end to end tests for several of the features.
Along with these end to end tests,
JHipster will also generate JUnit and Karma unit tests for the default features. Let's look at the final step around the JHipster marketplace.