Once we made the last decision,
JHipster ran the full generation of the scaffolding for our project.
What I'm showing here is the end result.
There are four key lines to focus on.
First,
you should see a message that the server application generated successfully.
Next,
you'll see a message that shows you the command to
run the Spring Boot application.
That command is gradlew.
The next line tells you that the client application generated successfully.
And the final line tells you how to start your Webpack development server.
As we go through future modules in this course,
we'll be using these commands, but for now,
you just need to know that they are available.
Since I skipped showing you the output of the generation,
let's go over what actually happened.
There are three parts to the process of JHipster project generation.
First, JHipster creates all the necessary project files.
This includes assets such as the Gradle build scripts
client build script's Java source code, typescript source code,
and configuration files.
Next, JHipster will run Yarn install to resolve client-side dependencies.
Note that as part of the Gradle build,
a similar task will be run to resolve server-side dependencies.
The final step for JHipster is to compile the client-side and server-side code.
As we saw, once this step is complete,
you should see a success message for both the
client-side and the server-side build. That concludes the creation of the scaffolding for the project.