For the remainder of this course,
we will focus on the JHipster scaffolding platform.
JHipster takes an opinionated approach to making most of the
decisions required for modern applications.
These opinions are based on accepted industry best practices.
As a result,
you can start with a production-ready application that include kick
starters or features such as database schema management,
application configuration, and security.
In case you're familiar with it, JHipster is built using Yeoman.
JHipster is highly customizable.
As you'll see shortly, you can choose key features during project generation,
such as creating a monolithic application,
or a micro service.
If you don't need certain features,
you can even develop your own extension in the
templates used for project generation.
Finally, JHipster is a free open source project,
with an active community supporting it.
Let's take a more in-depth look at the platform.
As part of its core dependencies,
JHipster leverages the Angular framework on the client side,
and the Spring Boot framework on the server side when
generating monolithic applications.
These two frameworks are leaders,
and have reached a level of maturity that made them
first class citizens for JHipster.
In the field,
the majority of applications let my clients
leverage these frameworks exclusively.
With these core dependencies in mind,
let's look at some decisions that JHipster makes for you.
This course focuses on using JHipster for developing a monolithic application.
Please note, JHipster also supports creating scaffolding for micro services.
Here are some key decisions that the platform makes for monoliths.
Two of the most painful tasks I've faced with the
Spring Boot and Angular paradigm,
are getting all of the right dependencies in place,
and then figuring out how the project should be structured.
JHipster decides this all for you using out of the box code structure
and scripts that should suffice for most applications.
One of the biggest gaps I've seen with project development is
handling environment-specific concerns.
Why do these gaps exist?
As I explained earlier, we often make just in time decisions,
like deciding on our deployment strategy a few days before a production release.
JHipster starts you off with a foundational
development workflow that includes scripts,
configurations,
and Spring profiles to support the different environments for your application.
In this context, JHipster gives you multiple runtime options.
Want to do Hot Code Replace during local development?
It's supported out of the box.
Want to run in a Docker container?
Again, it's supported.
JHipster gives us support and gets us thinking about development,
build, and deployment strategies right up front. Next, let's focus on what you will learn from this course.