JHipster has generated a full Angular 4 client application for you.
There are three main folders at the root directory.
The app folder contains the Angular application module,
and corresponding code base.
The content folder contains static content like style sheets and images.
The swagger-ui folder contains the UI code for the Swagger API viewer.
Also, at the root directory is the main index page.
I'll be making a majority of the changes for the feature
using the contents of the app folder.
So let's quickly cover its contents.
At the root of the app directory is the definition of our application module.
We will make a small change to the application module
to declare our new patient module.
The first two folders under the app directory are for the
user account management and admin UI.
You saw most of this in the previous module,
including the user editor page, metrics,
registration, and password reset.
I don't plan to cover these modules in any more detail for this course.
The next folder is the blocks directory.
This includes common code for configurations such as pagination,
interceptors for authentication expiration,
errors, and notifications.
Again, I won't be covering these, but you should be aware of them.
The entities folder contains modules that you can generate
using a JHipster sub generator command.
The home folder contains the home page of the application
that you saw when the browser loaded.
The next folder is the layouts directory.
This contains the layout sections of the page,
including the navigation bar and footer.
We will be changing the navigation bar as we want to include our
new patient menu and appointment request form.
The last folder is the shared directory.
It contains common services around users,
requests, notifications, and pagination.
We will be making use of some of the services in this directory,
especially for authorization. With that out of the way, let's start to make changes to the navigation bar.