The goal of this course is to give you enough working
knowledge of the JHipster platform to use it for starting
your next Java web application.
First, you will learn how easy it is to install JHipster as a command line tool.
Next, you will use the command line tool to understand how to generate a project,
including the different options available to you.
After the project has been generated,
you will see a demonstration of how to develop a client-side feature.
You will learn what JHipster creates for you,
and where to add components in the code.
With the client-side code in place,
you'll get a demonstration of wiring up the server-side code for the feature.
Again, you will continue to learn what JHipster generates,
and where to add backend components.
Following the code demo,
you will get to walk through deployment of the application.
You will see the options available to you for runtime,
and learn how to customize the deployment strategy for your needs.
Along with the goals of this course,
it's important to understand what this course is not intended to be.
As JHipster generates a project with a multitude of dependencies,
it's very possible that you may not have worked with,
or even heard of one or more of these dependencies.
Unfortunately, it would be impossible to cover every technology in this course.
To help you with potential gaps in learning,
I've provided the link to a GitHub project.
This project provides resources for the various
frameworks and tools that JHipster depends on.
You can find the project at github.
com/michaelhoffmantech.
You can also visit the JHipster website for links to these dependencies.
That website is jhipster.
github.
io.
Now that you know what you can learn, let's make sure this is the right course for you.