To maintain focus on what JHipster is providing to you,
I'll be walking you through dropping in the new
patient module from a GitHub repository.
You can download the project from the repository that's listed.
The URL is github.
com/michaelhoffmantech/patient-portal-resources.
You'll be copying the folder client/patient into the project.
The source code is also included as part of the Pluralsight course material.
Let's copy those files now.
I've opened back up Eclipse,
I'm not going to show you how to actually get the project from Git
but I've already gone ahead and I've pulled down the project and
I've loaded it up in the workspace.
So again I have a project named patient-portal-resources,
and under the client folder I'm going to select patient,
and I'll right-click and select Copy.
I'm going to scroll up to the project,
and here under the folder source/main/webapp/app,
I'll go ahead and I'll paste in the patient module.
Okay so now you should have the patient module loaded into the application,
let's walk through the files that are found in this folder.
I'm displaying the code structure for the patient module.
While I don't plan to dive into the entire code structure,
I do plan to cover the segments where JHipster is providing a feature for you.
Here's a quick description for each of these files.
At the root of the patient directory is the patient.
module definition.
This texture class has a simple module decoration that
just imports the appointment module.
In the appointments directory we have the appointments.
module file.
This typescript class has a more detailed module decoration.
It imports dependencies for the appointments page,
including routes, components, and services.
The next file in this directory is the appointments.
componet class.
This defines the template for the appointments view
and corresponding style sheet.
It also loads all the appointments for the patient.
The appointments.
component HTML then defines the template for the view of appointments.
The appointments cascading style sheet file defines
the styling for this template.
Next is the appointments.
model, which defines the attributes of an appointment.
We have the route file that defines the route for the main view page,
and a popup modle dialog for creating new appointments.
The appointments.
service file contains the service definitions for getting and
posting appointments to the backend API.
The appointments-dialog component class primarily
defines the call to the appointment.
service for creating a new appointment.
The appointments-dialog HTML then defines the template for a new appointment.
There is an appointments-popup.
service for opening the modle, and finally,
there's an index page that contains the exports of services,
components, and routes.
Let's look at some of this code in detail.
Let's start by looking at a snippet of the code from the file appointments.
module.
ts.
Note that I'm importing the PatientPortalSharedModule.
This shared module was generated for you by JHipster.
It provides you with access to several shared items.
This includes an alert component for outputting
informative and error messages to the display,
authentication and authorization services and directives to
support working with the principle user and securing the
client-side of the application, constants for client code,
and finally, helpers for server requests and responses.
I've made use of some of these assets in the appointments module,
and I'll share it as we go along.
Next, I've shown you a snippet of the code from the file appointments.
component.
ts.
You'll notice in the constructor that there are three parameters passed.
I'll be showing you the appointment service shortly,
which is the first parameter.
The second parameter is the JhiAlertService.
What's interesting about this input is that JhiAlertService is an
interface that's brought in as a third-party dependency.
The third party dependency here is actually JHipster.
This is one of the first examples of where we have
application code coupled to JHipster.
The NG JHipster library is brought in as part of the project generation.
The alert service provides you with the ability to track one or more alerts,
which can then be displayed on the page.
It provides support for different types of alerts,
including success messages, warning messages,
error messages, and informative messages.
Given that,
I plan to include it as part of the page to display success and error messages.
The last parameter is the JhiEventManager.
Similar to the alert service,
this is provided as a dependency from JHipster as part of project generation.
It wraps RxJS observables for the purpose of providing a
published subscribe feature for events.
I plan to use it to update the list of appointments after
a new appointment has been created.
Along with the constructor,
I want to focus on three of the behaviors in the appointments.
component class.
The first behavior is loadAll.
This symbol uses the appointmentService the query the
list of all available appointments.
Note that Responsewrapper is another shared class that
was generated for you by JHipster.
It encapsulates the header, JSON body,
and status of a response from a backend server call.
Also note that as part of the error condition,
the onError behavior will be called.
The onError function simply uses the alert service to display an error message,
which in our case is the ResponseWrapper's JSON body.
The last behavior is to register a change in appointments.
Here I used the eventManager from JHipster's wrapper to
subscribe to appointment list modifications.
This will result in the loadAll behavior being executed.
Next, we have the appointments.
component.
html file.
This is the template associated with our appointments component.
Let's look at three parts of this file.
Near the top is the button to create a new appointment.
This opens a popup using a route to patient-appointments-new.
We're going to see that shortly.
Below the button in the alert selector.
This selector is used by the alert component that JHipster
generated in the folder shared/alert.
This approach is important,
as I've seen many applications that have inconsistent message
display return to the user across an application.
JHipster is providing you with a standardized reusable way
to display information across your app.
The final section is the output for the list of appointments.
Note that trackBy is used for the iteration of appointments.
This just calls the trackId function on the component to
return the appointment ID for iteration.
That covers the appointments component.
I'm not planning to show you the CSS file for the component,
nor am I going to show you the model.
Next, I'm displaying one of the routes from the fileappointments.
route.
ts.
There are two key values in this route, and both are related to security.
In the previous module, we made a change related to route guards.
Route guards define whether or not the user has the
necessary access to activate the route.
We changed the role name in the data that we passed.
In this route, we again are using the authorities value of ROLE_PATIENT.
Next,
note that I have defined the UserRouteAccessService as the value in canActivate.
This means that when the route attempts to activate,
it will call this JHipster generated service,
check the user's authorities for ROLE_PATIENT,
and return true or false based on the value being present.
I've displayed several of the behaviors on the appointment service class,
which is found in the file appointments.
service.
ts.
The create function will post data for our new appointment to our backend API,
which has the resource URL of api/appointments.
We're going to implement this backend functionality later in the course.
The next function is the query function.
Once again, we see the JHipster generated ResponseWrapper,
which includes headers, the body in JSON format,
and a status number.
This function also uses the imported createRequestOption.
This will add additional search parameter data for backend server calls,
including the page number, size, and sort action.
The last function is convertResponse,
which just takes a response object passed and wraps it in
the ResponseWrapper generated by JHipster.
There are four remaining files, which I'll cover at a high level,
since they don't introduce any JHipster features that you haven't already seen.
The appointments-dialog.
component.
ts file contains two classes.
The AppointmentsDialogComponent provides functions to support saving a new
appointment using the appointment service that we just covered.
The AppointmentsPopupComponent provides support for calling the
appointments popup service to manage the modle.
This component uses the template file appointments dialog.
component.
html.
This template leverages the JHipster alert directive,
and displays the form for entering a new appointment.
The final class if found in the file appointments-popup.
service.
ts.
This class is just responsible for the management of the modle,
including opening and closing it.
The final file is index.
ts.
This file just simply exports resources from our module.
With this module in place,
there's one additional update that we need to make to the
client code for our patient module to work.
I've opened back up Eclipse, I have the file app.
module.
ts loaded up in the editor.
You can find this file in the folder source/main/webapp/app.
We need to import our new module.
I'm going to start by adding an import declaration.
Great, now we've imported the module PatientPortalPatientModule.
The second step is to add the module as an import in the NG module declaration.
Scroll down a bit, and I'm going to drop our new module in.
So now the app is aware of our new patient module. Let's take the next step and stub out our server code.