Welcome everyone to the section on tax classification.
Our goals for this section are to first understand the machine learning basics and understand classification
metrics.
Since we're going to need to understand how we can actually evaluate our tax classification models.
After that we'll learn how to do things like text feature extraction and we'll familiarize ourselves
with psychic learn in Python to perform tax classification on real datasets.
Keep in mind we're gonna start off with quite a few quote unquote theory lectures and that means we're
not going to be coding anything until we have a solid understanding of machine learning classification
a text feature extraction concepts.
So you'll see quite a few lectures first that are only slides before we actually jump into the python
code.
With that being said let's get started.