Welcome back everyone to three of texture narration of Python keris in part 3.
We're going to learn how to generate new text based off of the seat input.
Let's get started.
All right so we have a Sade's trained model and we've also saved our tokenizer.
What's next is to actually generate new text.
So we're going to do is we're going to create a function that generates new text for US based off of
a given model tokenizer sequence length a seed text and then the number words to be generated by the
model.
So I will say DLF generates underscore text and then it's going to take in a model.
It's going to take in a tokenizer it's going to take in a sequence length some see text basically some
text to start off on and then the number of words that we want to generate after this
we're going to begin by preventing a placeholder for the final output text.
And at the very end essentially up protect the list.
So I'm going to at the very end join everything that list of space.
So say output text.
OK.
Now comes the part of actually taking that model and generating new text from it.
So the first we want to do is say input text and we're going to start off with some sweet text.
So we actually need to feed it some sort of line of 25 tokens that we want to start off with and then
it's going to generate one word after that then we're going to do is chop off the very first word of
the seed taken our new word put it at the end and then we have our new sweet text or a new pretext for
that and we're going to keep doing that however many times the user wants to generate words so I'll
say for I in range number of generated words will take the input text string and encode it to a sequence.
So I'll say in coded text is equal to the tokenizer and call text 2 sequences off of this tokenizer
object so text the sequences and then we're going to pass in our input text and we're going to grab
the first item here because it basically returns a tuple or a list so we're going to run the very first
item.
And want to encourage you to do is play around with print statements here so you can print out what
impot text looks like.
Print out what this tokenizer text sequences is etc. but we've seen this before previously.
And one of the lecturers.
And then we need to do is do some pad in coding so we're going to pad sequences to our trained very
So say pad sequences pad sequences here and in order to do that we actually need to import it.
So let's go ahead and do some imports.
We'll say from Krista pre-processing from is that pre-processing we're going to import is sequencing
and pet sequences so from care stop make sure he cares right.
From Krista pre-processing that sequence import pad sequences.
So we're going to now call Pead sequences here.
We're going to pasand the encoded text as a list of just one.
And then the max length here should be whatever the sequence length was that was passed then.
This essentially makes mixer's that if you pass in a super long text it's it's really trained on 25
tokens.
We're going to pad it to make sure it's only 25 tokens.
Or if you see text happens to be too short then we're going to pad it to fill up the 25 spaces again
in order to get best results.
I do recommend just passing a CTX that is actually the same expected length that your model has but
I want to make this function a little more robust so give him pad them out and then for truncating we
can either do a kind of pre or post beginning of string or after the string so will go ahead and do
it at the beginning of the string.
Since we're more dependent on the end of the string for a prediction purposes then we'll say predicted
word index position.
So is going to predict class probabilities for each word.
So same model predicts classes of the padded encoded string.
We'll see verbose is equal to zero so I don't see any output that will grab the very first index and
return there which means the predicted word is just going to be off that tokenizer
so tokenizer call index word and then grab that predicted word index and then we're going to update
our input text.
So say the input text is now going to have a blank space plus the predicted word and let's make sure
we say a word here for a predicted word
and then we'll take our output text and we'll append the predicate that word.
And that's it.
OK.
So let's kind of go line by line here because there is a lot going on through a lot of function calls.
So what does generate text function doing.
It's taking in the model we just trained the tokenizer which has knowledge about the vocabulary in what
ID number goes with what word the sequence link.
Some see text you want to start off with.
And this is robust enough to have shorter sweet text or longer see text and the sequence length.
But for best purposes or best results you should try to make these essentially equal to each other you
should make the text the same length as what was trained on.
Otherwise you have to pad it and then the number of words we want to generate.
So we have our output text which is the final output.
We have our initial seed sequence that initial seeding text and then let's say I want to generate 10
words.
So for i in range number of words so I'm going to do this 10 times I want to generate 10 words.
I'm going to first take the input text string and encode it to be a sequence.
Essentially what we did earlier we transform those raw text data into sequences of numbers.
Then if my CTX happens to be too short or too long I may need to pad it.
I mean need to cut it off or I may need to add to it.
So what I'm going to do is call pad and coding to make sure that it matches are trained rate for best
results.
Hopefully the CTX happens to be the same as a sequence like.
But this makes it more robust.
After that I'm going to predict the class probabilities for each word.
So modeled classes is essentially going to throw out the entire vocabulary.
Assign a probability to the most likely next word.
So they'll maybe you'll say something like 6 percent probability that the next word is Ishmail 7 percent
probability the next word is call et cetera.
So we can do that across the entire vocabulary.
So you can imagine most words are have a very small probability.
Next we're going to have the actual predicted word.
So the way that classes works when we index it with 0 it's going to return the index of that particular
word.
Essentially it's ID which if we can call tokenizer the index word from before we just pass in that index
and it matches with the actual word then we're going to take in the input text and I'm going to add
a space and then add on that perfect word.
So if my input text in the very beginning was 25 words after running this here for the first loop were
the first pass on this for a loop.
It's now going to be 26 words which means I'm then going to pet it and that's why I'm going to truncate
with PRI here.
So it chops off the very first word.
So essentially creating sequences as it goes along.
But more and more of the sequence is going to be in my predicted words.
And if you make numb generated words long enough eventually you'll just be predicting on your own predicted
words.
So true generation without even any seed.
Well there is always a seed.
But after you do this enough times if your number of generated words is longer than your CTX number
of words then you'll be predicting off your predicted words.
Now we still want actually a pen that predicted word so we'll say the up text and we'll append the predicted
word.
So this input text is for prediction purposes this output text is all I'm actually going to show some.
Only going to show these predicted words of the up.
OK.
So we can go ahead and run that.
So that function is ready to go for us now.
And now it's time to generate a seed sequence.
I'm first going to generate using the probably really poor network that we showed here and then are
going to load in the much larger more robust network.
So what I will do is just from my text sequences I only grab the very first one.
Call me Ishmael some years ago et cetera.
And then you can either grab the sequence of your choosing or you can grab a random sequence.
So what I could also do is say import random random seed Possum's a number like 101 and then you could
randomly pick out.
So we can say random loops random dot Ranz integer from 0 to the length of text sequences and then just
grab some random seed text by calling text sequences off of your random pick.
So the random see Texan looks something like this is just a random sentence in our tech sequences.
It's again up to you if you want to choose your own text sequence like the famous first lines or just
randomly choose some see text.
So once you've done that we'll go ahead and join this.
So it's actually a sentence we'll say see text is equal to and we'll say join random CTX.
So now our CTX just looks like a sentence like this.
And throwing the clothes to one side.
He really did this in not only a civil but it really kind and true.
But the way I stood looking and so on.
So I would recommend that because of the unique writing style of Moby Dick.
It's an older book has a more unique writing style that you actually use the text from Moby Dick as
your sweet text.
But if you really wanted to you could technically just write your own sentence here.
Like I went to the ship and then keep going until you hit 25 words.
Again I would really recommend that because unless you're good at mimicking the style of Moby Dick writing
in it it's up to you.
But you see texts eventually at the end should be some string that looks like this.
That is hopefully 25 tokens long or whatever your sequence length happens to be.
Once you have that ready to go we're simply going to call generate text we Pastner model passenger tokenizer
passenger sequence link all things that we defined earlier passen our text and it happens to be equal
to see text just to make sure it happens to be the case soci testicle to see text and then the number
of generated words will go ahead and generate 25 words off of this.
Keep in mind this is a really poor model that we just train really train that on two epochs that horrible
accuracy.
So I would expect to get pretty bad results here.
So let's go ahead and run this.
It looks like I made a slight typo.
I said text singular two sequences it should be text two sequences that will come back up here and fix
that in our original file.
So I kept mentioning kind of really easy to make a typo here.
So it should be if we take a look at tab here it should be text with an s.
So I'll say teks two sequences so run that again.
Let's run these cells.
So we have our CTX now generate Texican.
It looks like there's one more typo that underscore actually shouldn't be there.
So come back up here and fix that as well.
Now you should be able to generate some text.
And there we go.
So if you ran this for two epochs you should see really similar results.
It should is essentially just predict the most common word to be every single word.
So since that performed poorly Let's now load in a model that I trained on the entirety of Moby Dick
for about 300 epochs.
It was still only getting around 60 percent accuracy after 300 epochs but the results are a lot better
than what's shown here.
Let's go ahead and load it in.
We'll say from carious that models import load model and we'll say now are models equal to load model
and the file is called IPAC and there's two of them here.
The really large one is called IPAC big.
So go ahead and import IPAC big five and then the next thing we need to do is load up the tokenizer
that matches this larger file because this was tokenize thing the entirety of the Moby Dick text so
say load and then I'm going to open and this one is the big with no.
5 is the actual tokenizer and I'm going to read it in binary.
So run that and then let's go ahead and copy and paste.
Generate text.
And when you run this you should get back much more reasonable results.
So now that is generating text that says at that stub my frame Roman eyes of his own power for the whales
green wrenched et.
So whether or not this is a good prediction is kind of up to you.
OK.
I encourage you to play around with training your own models maybe on larger sequences or smaller sequences
for more.
E POCs as well as just playing around the different CTX maybe you write your own sweet text.
Okay thanks.
And we'll see you at the next lecture.