Welcome back everyone.
Or you can continue right where we left off last time by showing you how to use T.F. idea with sikat
learn.
Let's head back to the notebook in the previous lecture.
We went ahead and performed count vectorization as we discussed during the theory lecture.
We can actually use T.F. idea or term frequency inversed document frequency in order to actually give
words that are more important more weight one way to do this is by simply passing in our count vectorization
into ATF IDF transformer.
We can say from S-K learn that feature extraction thought text import T.F. IDF transformer.
We'll talk about TAF IDF vectorize or object and just a second.
First let's create an instance of the T.F. idea of transformer will say T.F. IDF transformer is equal
to and here we'll call an instance of it and then we can simply take X train underscore T.F. IDF and
set equal to the T.F. IDF transformer and then call transform on X train counts the result of the count
vectorization.
Now don't worry if you see a future warning show up that excess do of sikat learn and they will update
and fix that in a future release.
So you don't need to worry.
It still works even if you get this warning.
Next we're going to do is just quickly check the shape of this object.
The extraneous idea.
And here we can check the shape.
It's still the same shape but it's no longer just counts.
Instead we've taken in the term frequency and multiplied it by its inverse document frequency.
Now because it's so common to perform a count vectorization followed by T.F. IDF transformation that
sikat learn provides a T.F. IDF vectorization and that actually combines the two previous steps of Count
vectorization A.F. IDF transformation into one single step.
So we can do in the future is just say from S-K learn the feature extraction text import T.F. IDF victimiser
and then you can create an instance of this vector laser.
I was going to call vectorize or T If IDF victimiser and then we can say X train t If IDF is equal to
and we call her vectorize her and then we can call that transform directly on X train.
Remember this is our original x training data set and this essentially combines the process of both
count vectorization and T.F. idea of transformation.
So for convenience there's this T.F. idea of vectorize.
So we can run that and we would get back the same result.
Notice again I get a warning here at the Pentagon what version you are using.
You may or may not get a warning.
It's OK if it's just the warning.
Next we're going to do is we're going to train a classifier So we will say from S-K learn SVM import
and we'll be importing a linear support vector classifier will create an instance by saying CNF is equal
to linear s v c and then we will say our classifier and we're going to fit it to the vectorized training
data.
So I'll say X underscore train t f f and then we passen the corresponding y.
Training labels you run this and I'll report back the model that was used.
Now remember only our training set has been vectorize into a full vocabulary in order to perform an
analysis on our test set.
We would actually have to then repeat all the same procedures.
Now that can actually get a bit tiresome especially if you have a very long process.
What sikat learn provides is a pipeline class that essentially behaves like a compound classifier.
It can perform both the vectorization and the classification.
So instead of having to do this sort of thing transform and count vectorization on your test data in
order to predict what we can do is actually combine everything we just saw into one single pipelined
step so the way we do this is we say from as Kaylor that pipeline import and we import this pipeline
object and then we say text or whatever variable you want.
We're going to call this my text classifier and you create an instance of the pipeline object and the
pipeline object is going to take a tuple or a list of tuples excuse me.
So you're going to pass in a list of tuples each tuple.
What it's going to have is going to have a string name that either side or what to call this step in
the pipeline.
So I'm going to say T.F. IDF is my first step of the pipeline.
And then you actually call what you want to occur.
So I can pass in my vectorize or object there as the first item in my tuple.
Then I can passen in other tuple pair so I can say actually perform classification using a linear as
we see those means of open and close parentheses here and there.
We can actually create our pipeline.
So this pipeline object behaves just like a normal classifier of sikat learn our normal machine learning
model.
However what's convenient about this pipeline object is that it actually can perform all these steps
for you in a single call then that means you can directly provide the original extraneous data and have
it be both vectorized and run the classifier on it in a single step.
So this is what you see often use especially in natural language processing where you can have a really
long pipeline of things like text feature extraction or moving stop words tokenization limits ization
et cetera.
So the pipeline is a really convenient way to do this.
Right now we have a very kind of short pipeline.
It's just performing vectorization and the support or the support vector classifier you can imagine
that we can provide a lot more steps inside this list of tuples.
So the way to use the pipeline is exactly the same way you would using normal model you simply call
your pipeline object and then say that fit.
But now I can pass in my raw treating data X train and y train.
And this is a lot more convenient than what we did before.
Previously I had to call the vectorize or create an instance of the vectorize or do a fit transform
on my original x train dataset then import the classifier create an instance of the classifier and then
fit on the transformed or vectorize version of the ex-Marines dataset pipeline.
Does all of this for us.
It creates the pipeline and then you get to decide what steps to take.
Do some vectorization first then perform the classification next step so that I can simply say that
fit on the original x train.
Why train data.
So I run that fit here and again or if you get this warning you should eventually see something that
says pipeline and then report back the steps it took.
And then we can test the classifier and display results.
So I can say my predictions is equal to and here I'm just going to call my pipeline object and then
call predict just like I would with any other machine learning model and passing in the raw test data.
So X test remember if we actually take a look at this.
So for instance go below and take a look at what X test looks like.
Remember these are the raw text messages.
And what I'm doing is I'm going to pass in the raw text messages straight into this predictive function.
So now I have these predictions and then I can say from S-K learn that metrics import and I can import
a confusion matrix and a classification report and then see how well I performed.
So I can say Prince the confusion matrix of why test versus my predictions
and here I can see my confusion matrix Lotus's or performing much much better than our first attempt
on this dataset.
And then I can actually print out the classification report as well.
So I can say why test predictions run that.
And here I could see the classification report.
So again notice what's happening here.
I'm calling this all off of this text classifier which was this pipeline object for convenience and
now we're able to see that we get a much better performing classifier when actually vectorize and taken
the message to go ahead and compare these results for the confusion matrix and classification port to
our previous results.
We can also do is check out accuracy.
So I can say from S-K learn import metrics and then I can call metrics accuracy score and then pasan.
My lips are lower case why my tests and predictions and I can see I am achieving almost 90 percent accuracy.
So if you ever want to predict on a new message you just use the same predict method here though he
is on the X test data set.
Let's quickly show you how you can do that.
So I'm going to grab my classifier object text underscore C L F and let's have a predicate on a new
message that I make up whether or not it's spam.
So I'm going to say hi and pass this as a list.
Just a single message.
Hi how are you doing today.
I'm going to run that and it's predicting that it's him that is a legitimate message which makes sense.
This does look like a legitimate message string.
Notice I'm passing it inside of a list.
Let's try predicting on something that is more Spammy.
So you can say congratulations
you've been selected as a winner.
Text 1 2 4 4 or whatever some sort of number.
Congratulations.
Free entry to contest.
Let's see.
Let's see if that's spammy enough.
We run that and it looks like it does predict that is a spam text message.
Keep mine depending on what string you pass.
It may or may not predict that it's spam and spam is kind of harder to make a spam message.
It looks bad enough.
But if you pass in an oral message it should hopefully predict ham.
OK.
So we just learn how to actually build out a pipeline train a classifier display the results and predict
on our X test dataset as well as predicting on single new messages coming up next.
We're going to go through an entire code along Tech's classification project.
We'll see if there.