Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to go over the solutions for the natural language processing basics assessment.
Let's get started.
OK here we are at the assessment notebook the first we're going to do is run this top cell to perform
our standard imports.
And then we're going to create a document object through the Owl Creek thought tax file so we can say
with open and then we're going to search for it inside the text files folder.
You should see and be able to autocomplete or tab out.
Owl Creek that takes t open as f and we'll say is equal to a.p and then we'll read in the file as a
string and then we can run this cell confirmed that we worked.
Next we ask ourselves how many tokens are contained in the file.
For that we just need actually check the length of the document and we can get four thousand eight hundred
thirty three.
Next question is how many sentences are contained in the file.
So recall that we can build out a list of sentences by saying something like talk sentences is equal
to scent for sense and talk sense.
And then once you run that we can just check the length of sentences.
So you see there's two hundred and eleven sentences inside this document.
Next we want it to print the second sentence in the document.
So only to do is using doc sentences index at 1 since 0 will be the first one will be the seconds and
then we can grab its text and simply print it out.
Should get something like this.
A man stood up upon a real world bridge etc..
Next for each token in the sentence above its text POS had dependency tags and Lema tag lots of different
ways you can do this.
I am actually going to jump ahead to the challenge solution so you could just print out everything as
a tuple or you can format it nicely so it looks something like this.
So let's go ahead and show the challenge solution because it's very similar to the normal solution.
We're just going to say for token in and then here we're going to say Doc sentences and we're going
to say docs and this is one we're just interested in the second sentence.
We'll go ahead and print out using string formatting here.
We'll print out the token text and then we'll print out the token part of speech
the token was make sure it's lower cased token syntactic dependency and then the token lemma.
Now if you just print it like this you'll get something that looks like the answer above.
So we want to format it a little bit so it looks a little nicer by giving some minimum whitespace here.
So let's go ahead and add those extra braces and you can play around his values have to be exactly the
same values I chose here.
But the essentialist give us some spacing some minimum amount of characters that take up so we run that
and now it gets a nice table along with the space.
OK next we wanted to write a metric called Swimming that finds both occurrences of the phrase swimming
vigorously in the text.
So we're going to run and import this matter object and let's create our pattern.
Here's a couple of ways you can do this but probably the easiest way is to first search for the lower
case term swimming and then we're going to look for a space.
So say is space we'll say true and then we're also going to say as an option pass an asterix we're looking
for zero or more times that and then will also say lower and then we're looking for the word that makes
you spell that right vigorously.
The I.
G O R O U S L Y.
And then let's go ahead and say take our matter and add a metric called swimming.
There won't be any callbacks for now and we'll just pass in the pattern to match on.
So if we run that we can say found matches is equal to measure and then we can pass in the entire document
and then we can print out where we actually found the matches.
We can see here it matches the output here.
Next we want to print the text surrounding each of these so we can Orosi the start and end positions.
So we can do is we can create a little function by simply saying the ZF will say surrounding text should
have it be called surrounding and it takes in a document a start and an end.
And what we're going to do is print out the documents and we'll say Star minus let's say 10 words and
end plus five words.
We'll go ahead say minus five words way we don't get a huge sentence.
So I'm going to run that.
And what we're going to do is then we're going to say surrounding for these values right here.
So get a pass on the document that we created and then the start and stop.
And here we can say evade the bullets and swimming vigorously reach the bank.
So that's the first one.
And then the second one is just going to be this period.
So again we say surrounding the dock and then we can see a shoulder he was not swimming vigorously with
the current.
It's up to you how much before start and you want to go.
So it was pretty it took around the each found match for extra credit.
Print the entire sentence that contains each found match.
So it's a little harder.
Let me show you how you can do it.
You can say for sentence in Doc sentences
found match and then we're going to index 0 and off of that will index 1.
So again notice here what's happening when we say found matches.
Let's make sure that's found matches so often found matches we're right now looking at the first one
0 and then we're looking at the start of it 1 2 7 4.
So that's what this is doing right here.
So first sentence in DOCSIS is if the very first start is less than the sentence.
And then we're going to print that sentence.
Let's make sure we say sentence here.
We're going to print that sentence and then break.
So we're going to do is for every single sentence inside a document sentence we're essentially going
to check if found matches 0 1 is less than the end of that sentence.
So when you run this you should get back that entire sentence by diving I could evade the bullets and
swimming vigorously reach the bank take to the woods and get away home.
And then we can just do the same thing for the second match which is essentially just replacing from
zero here to one.
And if you're in that you should see the hunted man saw all this over his shoulder.
He was now swimming vigorously with the current.
All right.
That's it.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you at the next section of the course.