Welcome back everyone to this lecture on classification metrics.
We just learn that after a machine learning process is complete we use performance metrics to evaluate
how well our model did.
Remember in that train test split step we ended up running our train model on some test data and then
evaluating its performance.
In this lecture we're actually going to discuss in more detail how we actually evaluate the performance
of a model.
And that comes in discussion with classification metrics.
The key classification metrics we need to understand our accuracy recall precision and EF 1 score which
is essentially a combination of recall and precision.
But first we should really understand the reasoning behind these metrics and how they actually work
in the real world.
So we're going to follow along a little bit in a process with some more realistic example such as classifying
a spam versus ham message so typically in any classification task your model can only achieve two results.
Either your model was correct in its prediction or your model was incorrect in its prediction.
Unfortunately incorrect versus correct.
That expands to situations where you have multiple classes.
It doesn't matter if you're trying to predict categories with eight different types of classes or eight
different types of categories.
Your model fundamentally only has two outputs either a correct output or incorrect output.
When it comes classification now for the purposes of explaining the metrics we're going to imagine a
binary classification situation where we only have two available classes spam versus him in our example.
We're going to be attempting to predict if a text message is spam or ham ham being another word for
a legitimate message.
Since this is a supervised learning process we were going to first fit or train a model on training
data.
Then we will test the model on testing data.
Once we have the models predictions from the XT test data we compare it to the true y values that is
the correct labels because remember in a supervised learning process we're dealing with historical information
that we already have the labels for.
Keep in mind there are a few steps to convert the raw text message information into a format that the
machine learning model can understand.
So whenever we're dealing with raw text we're gonna have to do a little bit of work in vectorization
in order to translate the raw text into numerical information the machine learning model can understand.
So whether it's a text message from a cell phone whether it's an email whether it's a movie review that's
been written down there will be some steps that we're going to cover later on in actually converting
that raw text information into numerical information rather discuss these methods in much more detail
later on.
So just to give you a brief overview of kind of the process of vectorization going to wave our hands
a little bit here.
But essentially what we're doing is we're taking some sort of rock text message from the testing dataset
that is the X test that we saw in the previous lecture we passes through some vectorize.
And then we have a vectorized version of that.
So to give you just a brief idea of what that actually is or that would look like Essentially we would
have some raw text information.
So here's a text message from a cell phone saying hey how are you doing.
I've been doing well et cetera.
Theoretically after we pass it through the vector laser it should be formatted in some sort of vectorize
format that has a numerical matrix that the machine learning model can then understand.
You can imagine that we can do things such as count the number of times certain words show up and that
would be numerical information and we would format it in a way that the machine learning model can understand
or to learn about this entire process.
In a lot more detail things like term frequency inverse document frequency bag of words.
Those are all different processes that we can employ in order to vectorize text information the way
to learn about that in the feature or text feature extraction lecture right now who can kind of imagine
behind the scenes or some sort of vectorization process taking place.
So we set up this vectorization in a pipeline.
And again there's many ways of transforming that raw text into murky information.
For right now since we want to focus on understanding classification metrics we're just going to assume
that there were some underlying vectorization process that took place OK so it's actually jump right
into the middle of that machine learning process pipeline that we saw in the previous lecture and assume
that we have a trained model and the model is trained on the training data.
So we took in our next train and our white train and then we train the model.
Now it comes time to actually evaluate the models performance.
So what we need to do is taken our test dataset and then pass it into the train model.
So for example I go ahead and grab a test message from X test and if you're wondering what X test means
go ahead and watch the previous lecture we explain that there.
So we have this text message from a cell phone and it's from the X test dataset and we pass it into
the train model that I remember because a test message and this is supervised learning with historical
labeled information.
We actually already know whether or not this is a ham or spam.
So keep in mind we always already know the correct label for this particular test data point that's
going to allow sexually compare the output or the train model whether it's correct or incorrect.
So we pass it through a train model and let's say in this particular instance the train model said I
think this text message is ham or it's a legitimate test message.
Then all we do is we simply compare the correct label that we already know to be true against the prediction
that the train model output.
So here we say it was hand equal to him.
And in this case it's correct.
So here we get a correct prediction.
Keep in mind that for other data points the train model could be incorrect.
It might say Oh I think this text message is spam.
And in that case it would be incorrect for action.
So what we're going to do is we just repeat this process for all the text messages inside of our test
data.
At the end we're going to have a count of correct matches and accounts of incorrect matches.
Here's the absolute key realization probably the most fundamental part of this particular lecture in
real world situations.
Not all incorrect or correct matches hold equal value which is why we actually have those various classification
metrics.
It's not enough to understand that you got a particular count of correct versus incorrect its various
ratios that we need to take into account.
So in the real world a single metric won't tell the complete story.
So to understand all of this we're going to bring back those four metrics we mentioned at the beginning
and see how they're actually calculated and we could actually organize or predicted values compared
to the real values in what's known as a confusion matrix.
And the next lecture were to have a whole discussion of the confusion matrix the freight Now let's look
at accuracy accuracy in classification problems is the number of correct predictions made by the model
divided by the total number of predictions.
So again what we do is we count up our Telia how many times the model was correct and then we divide
it by the total number of predictions the model made.
For example if the test dataset was 100 messages in our model correctly predicted 80 of those messages
from the test dataset then we would have 80 out of a total of 100 predictions that were done correctly.
And that means we were 0.8 or 80 percent accurate.
Accuracy is really useful when target classes are well balanced.
So in that example it would mean that we have roughly the same amount of spam messages in our test data
as we have ham or legitimate messages.
Now here's a problem.
Accuracy is not a good choice with unbalanced classes.
Let's imagine a situation where we had ninety nine legitimate ham messages in a one spam text message.
If our model was a simple line of code that's always predicted him.
That means we would get ninety nine percent accuracy even though it was incorrect on every single instance
of spam.
We got unlucky because we had an unbalanced class situation and our test data set.
So in this situation we're going to want to understand.
Recall and precision that's going to give us a better understanding of how it performs.
On the other smaller class so let's quickly go over some formal definitions of precision.
Recall an EF 1 score if one score is simply a combination of precision recall.
We're going to go over their formal definitions and I think usually they make a lot more sense when
you see them in combination with the confusion matrix.
So keep in mind in the next lecture you'll see a confusion matrix which should clear up precision.
Recall an EF 1 score with further detail.
Let's start with free call.
Recall is the ability of the machine learning model to find all the relevant cases within a data set
and the actual mathematical formula for definition of recall is going to be the number of true positives
divided by the number of true positives plus the number of false negatives.
And when we see this in combination with the confusion matrix they'll make a lot more sense.
So keep in mind the next lecture we're actually going to see the formulas and how they're calculated.
So don't worry too much about these formal definitions.
Precision is the ability of a classification model to identify only the relevant data points.
Precision is defined as a number of true positives divided by the number of true positives plus the
number of false positives in the next picture we'll talk more about true positives false positives true
negatives and false negatives.
So keep in mind often you have a tradeoff between recall a precision wall recall expresses the ability
to find all relevant instances in the data set precision expresses the proportion of the data points.
Our model says was relevant that actually were relevant.
And in cases where we want to find an optimal blend of precision and recall we can combine the two metrics
using what is called the EF 1 score the one score is the harmonic mean of precision and recall taking
both metrics into account in the following equation.
We say if one score is equal to two times and in the numerator we have precision times recall and then
in denominator we have position of plus recall this is known as taking the harmonic mean in order to
say normal mean.
And the reason we use the harmonic mean instead of a simple average is because it punishes extreme values.
Let's imagine we had a classifier for a precision of one point zero but a horrible recall of 0.0.
If we were to perform the normal mean we'd end up getting in a score of 0.5.
So that's just a simple average.
If we take the harmonic mean we can be a little smarter about it and really punish this model for having
a horrible recall because we're going to say precision times recall then that's going to say one time
zero is zero.
So that means the score automatically becomes very small or zero.
If one of these values either precision or recall happens to be very poor.
So again it's a better display of the optimal blend than just the simple average because it's punishing
extreme values.
So persistent recall as I keep mentioning typically make more sense in the context of the confusion
matrix.
So in this next lecture coming up we're going explore his confusion matrix and again talk again in more
detail about the different classification metrics we'll be using throughout this section of the course.
We'll see at the next lecture.