Welcome back everyone the course curriculum lecture before you begin the course.
Let's build an understanding of our overall learning path.
This lecture is just going to be a brief overview of the main topics and the structure of the curriculum
of course that way you can understand the way the Course is laid out and maybe you can jump to a particular
section that interests you or understand the pathway from start to finish.
So the overall course sections are pie on text basics in LP Python basics part of speech tagging Tex
classification semantics and sentiment analysis topic modeling and then some chat bots and advance material
that fall under the deep learning category.
We're going to start off with Python text basics where we're just going to learn the very basics of
Python's built in text capabilities.
Those are things like learning how to open text files how to work with PDA files and the basics of regular
expressions.
Then we'll move on to the Python basics.
This is when we actually start using specialized natural language processing libraries such as spacey
and LDK.
These are the two most popular libraries for Python.
And we'll have a deeper discussion on the differences between them and why you may want to use another
like spacing in certain situations or in LDK in other situations.
So that's what I really begin to work with natural language processing libraries.
There we're going to move on.
And within that section we'll discuss things like Spacey pipeline's tokenization stemming limitations
Stoppard's and vocabulary and phrase matching the next section is essentially going to be a continuation
of learning how to work those libraries by talking about things like parts of speech tagging named entity
recognition sentence segmentation or spacey and we'll also see how to visualize speech and named recognition.
Now we'll switch gears and talk about teks classification.
This is where we dive deeper into machine learning learning about how to use sikat learn for machine
learning.
Just an overall process and then we'll talk about text feature extraction conducting operations like
Count vectorization and then T.F. idea vectorization term frequency inversed document frequency and
then we'll have a text classification project for you.
After that we'll talk about semantics and sentiment analysis semantics and things like word vectors
such as the words Avik algorithm and then sentiment analysis understanding whether a piece of text is
positive or negative sentiment.
Then we move on to topic modeling.
This is again on the machine learning side of things.
But we'll be switching gears to unsupervised learning.
We'll talk about things like later like allocation and non-negative matrix factorization and this at
the end will have a topic modeling project with LDA and MF towards the end.
We're going to have a general deep learning section where we talk about things like chat bots and advanced
material.
So here we're going to focus on more complex and more advanced topics like actually generating text
using recurrent neural networks and long short term memory units and then will also talk about using
deep learning to create your own chaplets OK.
Let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.