Welcome back.
Let's get started by learning and exploring word vectors that come already prepackaged for us with Spacey
and python.
Please remember to watch the previous lecture in order to download the larger Spacey English language
models that actually contain the word vectors.
The smaller models do not contain the word vectors.
OK let's jump to the Jupiter notebook.
OK.
Let's begin by importing Spacey.
And then we're going to load the large English or medium English download that we discussed in the previous
lecture.
So go ahead and say Spacey don't load and then even underscore core underscore web underscore and depending
on how you proceeded in the previous lecture for dialing the libraries I would do M.D. or LG or underscore
LG I went ahead and downloaded the large library so I'll go ahead and do that.
Keep in mind the medium core English library and the large English core library We're both trained using
the same familiar word to that family of algorithms.
So they should be pretty similar.
Once this is loaded up and keep in mind if you're loading up the large one it may take a while but once
that's loaded up all you need to do is say LP and then pass in a unicode string.
So for example we can say lion.
And then once you do that you should be able to access an attribute for vector off of that.
And so now here we have the actual vector components for the string lion.
You'll notice that there's a ton of dimensions here.
So that means we have a lot of information contained in this vector version of the word.
Now what's interesting is that Doc and span objects themselves also have vectors and these vectors are
then derived from the averages of the individual token vectors and that essentially allows you to not
just preferred or perform a word to vector but actually document to check where the document itself
is an average of all the words.
So just to show you this you could say something like the quick brown fox jumped and if you run that
and then ask for the vector notice here what happens.
We get back a vector and we can check up the shape of this vector since it's essentially an umpire.
And there's three hundred different dimensions to this vector that the formatting was slightly different
than a single word.
So it can say an LP you hear.
Now let's just say Fox lost for the vector and ask for the shape here.
But the dimensions are the same.
So we have three hundred by three hundred.
So what that basically means is there's three dimensions to the vector for this essentially a document
here and through dimensions for the single word this document is just the average of all the singular
vectors for all the words there.
So now let's try identifying similar vectors.
The best way to expose vector relationships is through the dots similarity method of the actual document
tokens.
So I'm going to create some tokens by simply saying an LP and then we're gonna pass in some similar
words but not the exact same words we'll say lion cat and pet.
So just naturally we can tell there's probably some sort of relationship between things like cat and
pet.
Cats are often pets and we also know that lions and cats are similar just because a lion is kind of
a form of a cat.
They're essentially from the same family of animals.
So then we're going to do is say for token one in tokens and we'll have a nested for loop then for talking
to in tokens essentially comparing each word to every other word.
We'll say print out the token one text then the token to text and then grab the first token and check
its similarity with the second token to a token too.
And then as here you just grab similarly directly off the token not off the text.
So what's interesting here is on the outputs you'll notice that line line cat cat and pet pet have 100
percent similarity between each other.
So the similarity values are going to be between 0 and 1.
So it makes sense that a word is totally similar to itself but what's really interesting here is that
the word vectors contain enough information to realize that line and cat do have some similarity.
They're at zero point five too.
So that means they're above zero point five similarity.
And what's really interesting is that cat and pet tend to have a very high similarity because most cats
are gonna be pets and pets are essentially at least Tyrion I'd say it's either cats dogs or birds.
So it makes sense that they have a very high similarity and it makes even more sense that line and pet
have a similarity less than zero point five.
It's probably not the best idea to have a line as a pet although some people do have that.
So we can already see that we have established relationships just from the word of actors themselves
essentially all this is doing is checking the cosine similarity between token one and token to something
you should keep in mind is that words that have opposite meaning but that often appear in the same context
may actually have similar vectors as well so let's put in three other words here we'll say like love
and then hate so you can imagine that love and hate are very different words of very different meanings
however they're used often in the same typical context.
You either love a movie or you hate the movie Love a book or hate a book.
So they're very similar words in that aspect in that they are often used in similar contexts.
So words like that can often have very similar vectors.
So we're going to run this tokens again and rerun this cell and so we can see again like and like love
and love and hate and hate are very similar but you'll notice that like and love and like and hate almost
have the exact same similarity relationship as well as love and hate here are also quite similar.
So keep in mind that if the words are used in similar contexts they may also be similar even if in normal
English they have the opposite meaning.
Now it's sometimes helpful to aggregate three hundred dimensions into a Euclidean L2 norm.
And so basically what that means is we're going compute this as the square root of the sum of squared
vectors and this is actually accessible as an attribute of the token called vector underscore norm.
And there's a couple other helpful attributes including has vector and is Ovi or is out of vocabulary.
So if we want to take a look at our current vocabulary we can just say MLP dot vocab dot vectors.
And so this is the list of all the vectors in the vocabulary.
So we could just check the length of this and here we see six hundred eighty four thousand eight hundred
thirty one.
So that means there is essentially around six hundred eighty five thousand unique words in the vocabulary
that we have vectors for.
So if we were to check the shape of this.
So learning to check the length just the shape of how this is held you'll let us it's this many words
by three hundred dimensions for each particular word vector.
So out of those around six or eight five thousand words we're gonna be able to understand if we have
a new word that is outside of the vocabulary.
So that could be someone's proper name.
Maybe there's an unusual name so that one's not going to have a vector.
We'll go ahead and check that out.
We're going to say tokens is equal to an LP.
Now let's provide a string with dog cat and then I'm going to kind of make something up so normal.
There you go.
And we'll say for token in tokens prints.
We'll print out the token text.
We'll print out has vector essentially answering true or false thus this sexual word have a vector associated
with it and then we'll say token dot vector underscore.
Norm and they will say token thought is underscore O O V which stands for out of vocabulary.
So when we run this as we may expect the dog and cat tokens do have vectors true and true and they have
these normalized representations.
Essentially the sum of the squares of all three hundred dimensions.
Now how interpretable that is is sometimes a little hard reducing three dimensions just one scalar value.
So it may not be very interpretable but keep in mind it is kind of there for convenience.
And then this last attribute is out of vocabulary is false for the first two because dog and cat are
in the vocabulary of these six hundred eighty four thousand ish words.
However this kind of made up word is false.
It doesn't have a vector so that means it returns back a norm of zero point zero and is it out of the
vocabulary.
It's true.
So keep in mind common names may actually be vector.
So if we just put John in there that actually does have a vector associated with it and even uncommon
names.
So if I were to put in my middle name that actually is in the vocabulary which is kind of interesting.
But if we kind of misspell this as something stranger that's gonna be false.
Okay so let's say you can check and understand that Spacey doesn't actually have a problem with words
in an MLP documents that it doesn't have a vector for they'll just go ahead and assign them a vector
norm of zero point zero and then inform you that it is outside of its vocabulary and it doesn't have
a vector.
So the last thing you really want to explore here is vector arithmetic.
So believe or not we can actually calculate a new vector by adding and subtracting related vectors from
these words and a really famous example is king minus man plus woman is equal to Queen and we talked
about this previously.
So let's go ahead and try it out ourselves.
So in order to do this we need to be able to calculate the cosine similarity ourselves.
So we're going to say from side pi import spatial and then we're going to essentially write the formula
for cosine similarity and we're going to write it as a lambda expression just for convenience.
So say lambda and we'll say that one Vec two and we'll say 1 minus.
And this is why we're importing side PI will say spatial thought distance thought cosine so essentially
cosine function there and we'll say Vec 1 vector.
So this essentially just returns back cosine so one minus that cosine similarity.
So how this little land the expression for cosine similarity and then we're going to do is we'll create
three variables one for King.
So out of our vocab we'll go ahead and grab King and then ask for its vector and we'll do the same for
man so MLP the vocab man ask for that vector and then we'll say the same for women.
So MLP that vocab woman and then grab that vector.
So the idea that we're going to do here is we're going to ask for the king vector minus the man vector
plus the woman vector and we hope that somewhere along the most similar vectors to this like brand new
vector we hope that this new vector is somehow similar to Queen or possibly princess or Highness or
something like that.
Essentially we're assuming that somewhere in those three hundred dimensions there is some sort of understanding
of maybe formality or royalty with the words King and there's some sort of understanding of the words
gender so we understand that kings are men and if we were to subtract the gender dimension from King
and then add woman to it maybe we get something that has royalty as well as those aspects of something
female like Queen Princess or Highness.
So that's our hope.
Again this isn't kind of a perfect science so we'll try it out who will say our new vector is equal
to and here we're just gonna say King minus man plus woman.
So I can just add and subtract these vectors so there's our new vector and then we're going to say computed
similarities is equal to an empty list and we'll do a little for loop here we'll say for word in an
LP dot vocab so notice I'm going through the entire vocabulary and I'm going to search for words that
have very similar values.
This new vector essentially checking for the cosine similarity for between this new vector and all the
words in my current vocabulary.
So essentially for all words in my vocab so all six hundred and or a hundred and eighty four six or
eighty four thousand ish words what we're going to do is say four word in that vocab.
I'll say if that word actually has a vector associated with it I'll say if that word is lowercase and
then I'll do one more thing if that word is Alpha which essentially means it's not like a number or
something.
Then what I'm going to do is I'm going to calculate its similarity and I will say cosine essentially
calling my lambda function on between my new vector that I just calculated using my custom formula of
King minus me and policewoman and then that current words vector and then I will say computed similarities
and I am going to append and what I'm going to a pen whips is a tuple so I'll put another set of parentheses
there and I'm going to pass in the word itself as well as the similarity value OK so let's make sure
I don't have a typo there whoops.
It should be has vector.
There we go.
Run that.
So keep in mind this may take a little bit of time since we are running it across around six or a four
thousand words but once that's done running well we're going to do is we're going to sort this list
of tuples.
So I'm going to say my computed similarities so computed similarities is going to be equal to sort in
computed similarities.
And then what I'm going to do is specify there's actually a special form of sorting if you have a list
of tuples or we can sort by the very first item it's the way we do this.
We simply say lambda is
lambda item and then we'll say minus item one.
So what that means is essentially going to come in descending order.
That's what this minus is for.
So descending order of the item at index 1 which is this similarity essentially is kind of a fancy way
of sorting by these tuples based on their similarity value in descending order.
If you didn't have this minus here it would do him in ascending order and then you would get the least
similar words.
So we're gonna go ahead and sort that so run that sorting that one shouldn't take too long.
And then let's go ahead and print out the top 10 most similar words so we're going to say print and
we can do this with list comprehension or before loop.
What are you more comfortable with.
We'll say remember we have a tuple here of a word and similarity so gram the first item in the tuple
which is the word and then ask for its text and we'll do that for tuple in computed similarities.
And we're just going to go through the top 10.
So colon 10.
So let's run that and there we go.
So we have king queen Prince Kings princess royal throne Queen's monarch and King them.
So in this case what's interesting is that the word King is still the most similar.
When you do this new vector of King minus man plus woman.
So trying to remove the man gender and then adding the woman gender still doesn't remove enough information
about King to make a new vector the most similar however knows what happens the second most similar
is queen.
OK.
I hope you thought this was super cool basically.
Now we understand that there's a wealth of information in these word vectors and you can add or subtract
word vectors and you can even expand this to documents so you could later on add and subtract documents
to find more similar documents after your experimentations.
So if you want go ahead and play around with this go ahead and choose a couple of new vocab words create
your new vector and then compute the most similar vectors.
All right.
Coming up next we're going to discuss sentiment analysis.
I'll see you there.