Welcome back to part two of working with textfiles with Python.
We're going to do now is go over how to read and write to basic text files with just the built in capabilities
of the standard python library.
Let's go ahead and get started.
OK.
Let's begin by actually creating a text file.
The method I'm going to use is specific to Jupiter notebooks and it's a magic command.
You do percent 9 percent.
Scientists are known as magic commands that work of Jupiter notebook.
And then you type out right file space and the name of your file will say TSTO for test Dot T x t for
textfile and then immediately below this line you can begin writing your textfile text.
So I can say hello this is a quick test file period and we'll say this is the second line of the file.
Keep in mind if you're not using Jupiter notebook just use a standard text editor like subline text
editor or Adam text editor to save a text file.
Again this specific line and what's written here in the cell only works for the Jupiter notebook's system.
So please if you're not using Jupiter notebooks just open up a basic text editor and say this is a text
file.
Go ahead and run this.
You should see the output writing test that takes t.
Keep in mind you can have any comment above this line.
It just look exactly as written here.
Now that I have this test that textfile I should be able to open it.
The first thing you should do whatever you're opening a text file regardless of what library using is
make sure you understand the files location.
To open up a file you first create the variable and then you say it equals two.
And Python has a built in keyword called Open and then in parentheses you passen the path to the file.
If you happen to provide a file that isn't there.
For example let's go ahead and make up a file name like whoops start to.
If you run this you'll get a file not found error and say Error Number 2.
No such file or directory will start to hear XTi if you ever get this error number two.
That means you're either providing the wrong file path or you misspelled the actual file name.
So keep in mind to avoid this error you should have a good awareness of where this notebook is currently
located as well as where your text file is currently located.
To figure out where your notebook is currently located you can simply type PWT into a cell.
Run it and it will tell you where you're currently located.
So right now I'm located at.
Users Marcio.
Thus top and O.P. course that means I should probably have my text files there if I want to open them
with this open command.
So now let's actually grab the test text file that we wrote.
Keep in mind it's easy to make typos here.
This is t e s t that t s t.
So we're going to do is say my file is equal to open and always be careful not to commit a typo here.
Or type T E S T T x t and when you run this you now have your file open and if you actually look at
my file object it should just tell you something like this is a wrapper ready to go for this text file
and by default it reads it with a mode r.
Which means reading and we'll talk about modes in more detail later on in this lecture.
But keep in mind if you ever get error number two it means you're either passing in the wrong file path
or you misspelled the actual file name.
In general the easiest way to go about this is to make sure your text files are in the same location
as your notebook is and you can always figure out the location of your notebook with PWT if you want
open files that are in another location on your computer.
You can just passen the entire file path.
Let me show you an example of that by copying and pasting from this lecture's notebook.
All right.
I copied and pasted this little mark down cell from the notebook and what it does is it just gives you
an example of passing in the entire file path.
If you're on a Windows computer typically you need to use a double backslash so that Python doesn't
treat the second backslash as an escape character and you'll notice that that format was followed here.
When I actually typed PWT so Peto these tense for print working directory.
And again if you want to open a text file that's located in a different folder than your notebook you
just need to provide the entire file path.
So for example if you are on Windows it would look something like this.
C-Drive colon.
Double backslash users.
Your username etc all the way until you find your textfile file.
Always keep in mind that sometimes text files don't actually explicitly call this DXi extension.
Maybe just my file.
If you're on a Mac OS or Linux you're going to use forward slashes.
It looks awful like this user's your username folder etc..
Again just to make it very clear if you're ever getting this error number two likelihood is you did
a typo or you're providing the wrong file path.
So please always debug that on your own first before posting to the Kewney forums.
Ok so now that we've opened up the file we have it saved as this.
My file and it's just text IO wrapper object.
Well we can do is we can read the file and the way you do that is simply by saying my file read open
and close print sees run that and read the file and noticed what happened here.
It says Hello.
This is a quick text file and then we get this backslash n that backslash n is an indicator for a new
line.
So if we look at the original text file it said hello.
This is a quick test file.
This is the second line of the test file.
That new line is indicated with this backslash and now what's interesting is if I were to try to read
this file again it suddenly shows up blank.
So this is often a point of confusion for beginners with Python or reading in textfiles of Python is
that you can't just call read multiple times on a file.
Essentially what's going on is you have a cursor at the very beginning of a text file and after you
call the read the cursor goes throughout the entire text file and then returns the entire file as a
string.
As we can see here and then the cursor is sitting at the end of the file which means when you call read
again it's just going to read from the cursor all the way to the end of the file which in this case
it's already called read.
There's nothing there.
Just an empty string.
In order to fix this we need to do is call my file thought seek and then you can change the cursor to
index position 0 which essentially resets the cursor.
I'll report back OK the cursor now is at index 0.
I mean the cursor is now at the beginning of the text file and I can call read again so my file read.
And here I see the entire stream again.
So that read is really useful for smaller files where you just want to grab everything and then save
as a string.
So let's go ahead and seek zero again so I can say maybe content is equal to my file.
Read.
Run that and now.
Content is going to be this save string of the file and since it has its backslash and if ever what
actually want to print the content.
Ill take that into account and then Ill display it as necessary so I'll take into account the escape
characters and print out the new line and keep in mind now content is actually the literal string.
I no longer need to worry about this seek reading capability off the file OK so that's how you can read
in the file as a string.
The last thing you should know is you should always close the file once you're done working with it.
So you can close the file simply by saying my file close shift enter and all that file object has been
closed.
The reason you want to make sure to do that is just in case you try opening that text file for another
program.
If you still have it open in Python it may cause issues of your operating system.
If you've ever tried to pull out a USP drive and it said hey some files are still under use.
That's the sort of thing that happens if you don't close a file.
They'll basically say hey Python is using this text file.
I can't open it right now so always make sure to close your files.
Now we just saw how the dot read method off a file object returns the entire text file as one large
string.
Often it would be nice if we could iterate through each line in the text file.
Notice that each line is essentially segmented by this backslash N..
Luckily Python actually has a read line method in addition to the read method which will actually read
in each line as a separate item in a python list.
Let's go ahead and show you what that looks like.
I'm going to open up the file again so will say my file is equal to open in as a string.
I'm going to say TSTO that DXi.
In general you should be able to tab out this.
That's another good indication that you're in the right place.
So I just opened the text file and instead of saying read I'm actually going to hit tab here and notice
that I have this read lines.
That's another really useful method and what this does is if you run this it's going to read in each
line as a separate item in the list and it's going to use this backslash and as the last item for.
Basically the last set of characters for each item in this list.
So now what I could do is let me go back seeker 0.
And then I could say my lines is equal to my Fylde read lines run that and now I have this my lines
object which is a list of every string are essentially every line as a string and then it could iterate
through it.
So I can say for line in my lines and then I can do stuff with it maybe like print out the first character
of each line which would be line 0 so run that and I see the first character in each of these lines
and you can begin doing additional things.
Maybe you want to split that actual string into separate words and then grab the first item there and
that's going to return back essentially the first set of characters before a space for each line.
And you can begin to experiment but that's why read lines is also a very useful method and it's often
more common to see red lines than just read.
But it really depends on the situation.
You should be familiar with both.
So read is to grab everything as one giant string read lines is the grab every line as a separate string
for a list.
OK.
So we just saw how we can read from a file.
Now let's talk about writing to a file by default that open a function that we just used up here.
It only allows us to read the file.
And that's really for safety because by default you probably don't want to just have any user have write
access to your text files.
Otherwise we'll be able to overwrite anything.
But let's show you how to actually write to a file and then we'll talk about appending to a file.
Let's go ahead and show this.
So I'm going to say my file is equal to open and I'm going to open that test that takes the file again.
Except as a second parameter if you do shift type here you should notice that you passed in the file
name and you have passed in this mode parameter where the default mode is R which is reading.
And if you hit plus here you should be able to expand on this a scroll down.
We'll have a little character table for character versus meaning.
So R is open for reading.
W is open for writing and then if you add this little Plus it opens a disk for updating.
Reading and writing.
So a really common way to see this is by seeing w plus and there are a lot more discussion here of all
the various methods but we're just going to focus on the simple ones.
So we're just going to say w plus and passing w plus allows us to both read and write to the file.
Now what's interesting here is that w Plus should be used with caution.
If you open a file with W or W plus it performs a truncation on the original that means anything in
the original file is actually overwritten and deleted over.
So I want to show this by running and I'm going to say my file.
And let's quickly read what is in the file right now.
You'll notice that immediately my file after calling that read has been an empty string because by opening
it with W Plus you're not overwriting the original test that TXI the file.
So that's why you should use WMW Plus with caution.
You should only use it when you intend to completely overwrite the original contents of the file.
So notice now if I say my file I can call the right method and say my brand new text.
So now I wrote some tax returns back the number of characters that were written.
And if you say my file seek zero
and run that and then say my file if we just call read here notice now it says my brand new text we
no longer have the original text lines appear which was Helo's a quick test file.
This is the second line of the file and that's because opening of W and W Plus will completely overwrite
the original file.
Now in a lot of use cases that's actually what you want to do if you're trying to create a updating
log or just create a new file every time someone runs a program.
You may very well want to completely overwrite any old information but in case you don't.
There's also an append method which you're going to show you next.
So keep in mind if you want to write to a file you should open it with W or W plus so w Plus allows
you to both read and write to the file and then let's go ahead and close this file.
And that file is closed.
So you should always do that when you're done with a file.
We just showed you how to read from a file and how to write to a file.
Let's not show you how to append to a file.
So the appending to a file will actually keep the old information and then allow you to add in new lines.
So try that out.
We're going to say my file is equal to open and I'm going to open that text file again.
Except this time I'm going to say a plus which now allows me to open it by being able to append to the
file instead of completely overwriting it.
So if the file doesn't exist a new one is going to be created.
So keep in mind that if you accidentally pasan a file here that completely doesn't exist such as whip's
that text is sort of producing an error if you're opening it with a plus it's actually going to then
create a new file called wups that text.
So keep that in mind.
We're going to say my file right and we're going to say is my first line in a plus opening and I'll
go ahead and close the file
and out.
Let's open the file again.
So I'll say new file is equal to open and I'm just going to open it now and read permissions.
So upset Tex here.
Now if I say new file read I see my first line in a plus opening.
So what actually happened here since I open with a plus I open the file that didn't exist.
So then it said OK I'll go ahead and make one for you.
Keep in mind that's not the case.
When you're opening with the mode are ill say hey there's an error here that follows it exist but since
you open it's A-plus it says No problem I'll create that file for you.
Then we write to that file.
Close it.
If I'm opening just read permission there I can see my first line and A-plus opening.
Keep in mind that the file here was mode and read permission which means if I say new file rights I'll
say try to write something with only read permissions I suddenly get an error that says hey that's not
ridable and that's because we only open this file this new file object with mode R which is the default
mode.
So if you're ever getting this error it's because you didn't open it with the correct permission or
the correct mode.
So let's close this file again.
New file close and I'm going to open up again this.
Whoops that TXI file again that's the one we just created.
We'll say my file is equal to open.
Whoops that DXi going to say mode is equal to a plus so allows me to append to it and then I will say
my file and then I'm going to say
writes
and then say this is an added line because I used a plus mode
and now if I seek all the way to the beginning of the file and then say my file read I see this as an
added line because I used a plus mode.
Notice how it's writing everything onto the first line.
If you actually want to add in a real knee line where you would have to do is take your file and then
say writes and then the very first character would actually have to be a line break.
You have to say backslash.
And for a new line and then say this is a real new line.
On the next line and then run that and again I will seek all the way to the beginning of the file.
Read the file again.
And now I see my first line and A-plus opening.
This is an added line etc. and then I see backslash.
And this is a real in the line on the next line.
So if I were to seatbacks 0 and then print out the results of my file that read I see this my first
line A-plus opening.
This is an added line.
This is a real newline.
Now before we end this lecture the last thing I want to show you is how you can actually use a context
manager to automatically close the file for you.
So previously we always had to say my file close because it's kind of annoying and it's also a little
unsafe because you may forget to write that close line.
There is an alias in-context manager which allows you to use the with keyword to say with open test
that TSC or whatever file you're working with.
So let's go ahead and use that spiles since we know we have a lot for it because a whipsaw text is going
to read it in with great permission and all say as my new file colon and then we can do whatever we
want here.
So I can say something like You know my variable is equal to my new file dot read lines.
So what's actually happening here.
This is just known as a context manager.
It's going to say with you open this file as this variable name and you can do whatever you want in
this block of code and it will automatically close the file once this block of code is done running
for you.
So you run that and then if you call my variable it's this list now based off those lines.
So often we're going to see us performing with open command instead of having to manually open and close
files or solves this with operator is a context manager that automatically closes the file for you.
And that's really what you see most professionals using but it is important to understand the basics
because that's essentially what's going on under the hood when you call this with context manager.
All right.
Coming up next we're going to learn how to work with PDA files.
We'll see if they're.