Welcome back everyone.
This lecture on the confusion matrix.
We mentioned the way to view various metrics of classification is called the confusion matrix.
Let's explore the basics of the confusion matrix to help us understand precision and recall better in
the classification problem during testing phase.
You're going to have two main categories.
The true condition and the predictive condition for example the true condition of a text message could
be that it is spam.
The predicted condition is what you're machine learning model predicted such as predicting that that
test message was spam.
Keep in mind it could have also pricked it that it incorrectly as him.
This means if you have two possible classes you should have four separate groups at the end of testing.
You have correctly classified the class 1.
So that means you had a message that was him and you positively identified it as him.
There's also correctly classified the class too.
So something was truly spam and then you correctly identified it as spam.
Then there's the other two options incorrectly classifying something to class 1 or incorrectly classifying
something into class to a false ham or false spam.
So if we were to map these out in a little grid we'd have something that looks like this.
And this is the confusion matrix and is the confusion matrix.
If you look it up on Wikipedia which is actually a really helpful article on this it would map out something
that looks like this.
So if we were to actually look at it a little more simplified for our particular example going back
to those text messages.
Again we have the real condition and the predicted condition so we can see over on the left hand side
if we're going to have two real conditions.
The real condition is either him or real condition spam.
And then along the columns we have our predicted condition predicting him or predicting spam.
You'll notice that if the real condition is him and we predicted him then we have a true positive.
We correctly predicted that this was positively him along the predicted condition as well.
We have a false negative.
That means that the real condition was him but our machine learning model incorrectly predicted it to
be spam.
That's a false negative here.
Relabeling him as positive and spam as negative.
We also see that we have real conditions spam and then predicted him.
That's known as a false positive falsely identifying something to the positive class which in this case
is him.
We also finally true negative correctly.
And the feeling something to the negative class predicting spam free spam text message.
Now if we come back to that other confusion matrix that we saw earlier we can expand on this to have
quite a wide variety of different metrics we can calculate things like true positive rate false positive
rate positive likelihood ratio false emission rate etc..
But really we're just concerned for a few of these.
We're concerned with recall accuracy and precision.
And here I can see a bunch of formulas for actually calculating those now the main point to remember
is the confusion matrix and the various calculated metrics is that they are all fundamentally ways of
comparing the predicted values versus the true values and what constitutes good metrics will really
depend on the specific situation.
In some situations 99 percent accuracy is fantastic.
In other situations.
Ninety nine percent accuracy may actually not be good enough for whatever you're are trying to predict
because maybe it comes at the cost of a really poor precision and poor recall.
So we can't just say that there's certain good values for particular metrics.
Obviously if you get 100 percent across precision accuracy and recall if you get across a hundred percent
on all three of those then you have a really good model.
But in the real world you're probably not going to get 100 percent of all those.
So let's go ahead and use confusion matrix to evaluate our model.
Let's imagine now we're testing for a disease.
So in this example we're going to test for the presence of a disease and we have the actual patients
come in.
Remember this is supervised learning.
So before we actually run them through the testing program we actually already know the true conditions
of these patients whether or not they had disease or don't have these.
So you can imagine that we're testing a new diagnostic tool.
So in this case for example test for presence of disease we'll say no is equal to a negative test or
false.
Often you just say that zero or yes is a positive test which is true.
And again you say that's one.
So in this particular example the total number of patients we have for this new diagnostic test is 165.
So we say end is equal to 165 and then we have the results as follows of the condition that people did
not have the condition.
Maybe we're testing for something like a cancer in this particular example.
There's 50 people that didn't have cancer that we correctly predicted they don't have cancer.
So we say predicted no actual no 50 then we can also see that we actually predicted 10 people to have
disease.
And these people actually did not have disease.
So those 10 were incorrect that we also see that we have actually yes and predicted no as 5 and then
actually yes or predicted Yes as 100
so some basic terminology here are true positives true negatives false positives and false negatives.
So you can see here on the great how that actually lines up and keep in mind you can kind of flip this
the order no versus Yes on either the columns or the rows in order to flip the quadrants of negatives
versus positives in the original confusion matrix we showed it in this lecture that was actually flipped.
So keep in mind you may see the confusion matrix both ways.
But other than that the information presented is still the same.
It's just the quadrants are slightly rotated.
So if we're trying to answer a question like What is the accuracy of this test.
We ask ourselves how often is it correct and for accuracy it's just equal to true positives.
Plus true negatives divided by the total essentially asking the question How many did I classify correctly
over all my examples.
And in this case we get 150 divided by the total number which was 165 and that means that our test was
91 percent accurate.
Now is 91 percent accurate.
Good enough.
That really depends on the situation.
If you're dealing with something that's as high stakes as something like cancer 91 percent accuracy
may not be good enough.
And you also have to take into the context of precision and recall notice that a really important statistic
here is the false negative the false negative means that you knew this person when you're going through
the test actually had the disease.
But the machine learning model predicted them as not having the disease.
That's an extremely dangerous situation to be in when the stakes are very high like a cancer diagnostic
because that means someone that actually has a disease you're telling them they do not have it.
So you have to keep in context the entire idea of what you're machine learning model is trying to achieve.
So there's always going to be a bit of a tradeoff between false negatives and false positives and ideally
for something like this where we're dealing with a really high stakes situation and we want to make
sure we minimize the false negatives.
It doesn't matter too much in kind of a diagnostic sense.
If we have a larger amount of false positives in order to lower our false negatives because we would
rather set up a situation where we tell a patient that they have a disease when they actually don't
have it and then conclude that they are in line now for further diagnostic tests.
Again it depends on the context of what the next steps are.
What we'd really like to avoid in this situation when it comes to disease is telling someone they're
clear of the disease when they actually have it.
So again there's no right or wrong answer as far as what your false positive rate or false negative
rate should be.
It really depends on the context of the situation and how important each of these are in the overall
study.
Now there's other things you can calculate such as the misclassification Ree or Airey.
That's another one that's essentially the reverse of accuracy.
It's just asking overall how often am I wrong.
So that's false positives plus false negatives divided by a total or 100 minus accuracy.
So in this case where 9 percent error rate in other common thing to keep in mind is that in statistics
false positives and false negatives are often referred to as type 1 errors and type 2 errors.
And here you can see kind of a funny example in order to keep in mind the differences between the two.
A false positive.
Here we're telling the man that they're pregnant.
Clearly this person cannot be pregnant or the false negative in which case this woman is clearly pregnant.
What we're telling them they're not pregnant.
So keep mine in statistics.
You may see type 1 error and type 2 error instead of the terms false positives and false negatives.
If you're still confused the confusion matrix don't worry too much about it.
I would encourage you to check out the Wikipedia page for it.
It has a really good diagram that we saw during this lecture with all the formulas for all the metrics
throughout the training.
What we're going to be doing is just printing out metrics for example just print the accuracy or print
out a confusion matrix or print out what's known as a classification report which reports back precision
recall an F1 score.
Again it takes time to really get an understanding of these metrics.
And more importantly an intuition behind them.
Check out the resource links for this lecture in order to help your understanding of things like precision
recall and accuracy.
All right.
Coming up next we're going to discuss a primer into using Python's sikat learn machine learning library
will see at the next lecture.