Hello everyone and welcome to the course installation and set up lecture in this lecture room.
The three main things.
The first one is to show you how to download and install Anaconda.
The second one is how to create a virtual environment using an environment file that we give you.
And the third one is opening up that Jupiter notebook system as a quick note.
If you're an advanced user and you're already familiar with some other development environment or I.T.
please feel free to use it.
There's no restriction on what ease you need to use all the Python code that we show in this course
will work on any ID that can run regular Python.
We do however recommend using our suggested environment including a Jupiter notebook and tools to avoid
issues along the way as well as being able to directly interact with the code.
Juber No because a great system.
And if you haven't tried it out first I would encourage you to try it.
But again please feel free to use any development environment you prefer.
Also keep in mind this lecture has resource links.
Make sure to download that.
Why a mail file before starting this lecture.
OK we're going to start off by showing you how to download and install Anaconda.
Anaconda is a distribution of Python that includes a bunch of scientific libraries that is really useful
especially for natural language processing.
Go ahead and either google search Anaconda download or go to the link here.
I'm going to head over to my browser and go to that link now.
OK here I am.
Anaconda dot com slash download.
Keep in mind this web site does change its appearance from time to time so if it looks slightly different
for you don't worry that's totally OK.
Somewhere along this page you should see three download options one for Windows one for Mac OS and one
for Linux.
So right now I'm filming this on a Windows computer so you simply click on your operating system.
You'll scroll down and it should give you two options one for Python 3 and one for Python to.
Go ahead and download the graphical installer and the pending on what kind of Windows machine you have.
You may need to download 32 bit instead of 64 bit.
But if you're on a more or less modern machine it's more likely that you have a 64 bit.
So go ahead and download that installer.
If you're on Mac OS simply click Macalester and then download that installer.
And if you're on Linux you're going to also have installer that you can download.
Keep in mind once you've downloaded that file if you scroll down there is a link telling you how to
install in a condo.
I would highly recommend you check out that link.
It changes the pending operating system you choose.
Basically if you click on that link it'll take you to the documentation on how to install and there
are specific step by step instructions for installing on Windows installing on Mac OS and installing
on Linux.
So essentially if you have any questions during the installation process there's written instructions
detailing step by step how to install in a condo in Windows on your computer.
Ok so I'm going to go ahead and download this file and then keep in mind locate where ever you actually
have the graphical installer on your computer.
Let's jump to me double clicking on that graphical installer Once you've installed that or once you've
downloaded an installer it's time to actually install Anaconda.
So a click open here this executable file that downloaded for me and then you'll have the Anaconda set
up guy.
You'll go ahead and click next agree to the license agreement.
I would recommend just installing it for just me.
Then hit next.
Go ahead and select the default hit next.
Then eventually you'll have the advanced installation options.
There's two advanced options here.
You'll notice that one of them says at Anaconda to my path environment variable.
If you've already installed Python previously maybe you've already installed Python from Python or than
actually highly recommend clicking and adding anaconda to my path environment variable.
I know it says here that it's not recommended.
But if you have previous versions of Python what ends up happening is when you download or install certain
files your computer gets confused.
As far as what's Python version it should use your previously installed Python or your anaconda one.
So if you've already installed python in the past from Python the org then I highly recommend adding
anaconda to your path environment variable.
If this is your first installation of Annacone then python ever then it's actually not really necessary
to do that.
OK so once you're all done with that go ahead and click install.
Alright once you then installing.
We now need to download the libraries you use for this course.
The Anaconda's installation has also installed the Anaconda prompt command line tool.
We're going to be using the command line for the next few steps.
Keep in mind if you're on Mac OS or Linux you can also use your terminal as the command line or if you're
on Windows you should also be able to use your command prompt.
All right.
So for this next step we're going to do is we're going to both create and activate the virtual environment
we provided for you.
This virtual environment is essentially a simple text file of a bunch of libraries that download along
with a specific version of the libraries.
That way you're going to be using the same libraries we use when creating this course.
So you shouldn't have any issues with typos or small syntax changes and this environment does this all
for you automatically check out the resource links for this particular lecture and download the Y.M.
file.
Upon clicking that resource link you should see something that looks like this.
It's essentially a Google rivaling with an p underscore course underscore envied that why M-L is a simple
I.M. file.
It's not going to preview you simply just need to click here on this download button.
Ok so once you've downloaded that you must keep track of the location of the dot why a mail file you're
going to need to know its location in order to use it.
Let's now go to the command line search for Anaconda prompt on your computer and then get started with
creating an activity in the environment.
Jump over to my command line now.
OK here I am and I'm going to search for Anaconda prompt on my computer and you should see the Anaconda
prompt.
Show up again if you're on Mac OS or Linux and you don't find the Anaconda prompt through a spotlight
search.
We can do is also use Terminal.
If you're on Windows and you still don't see Anaconda prompt We should also be able to Taipan is CMT
and just use the normal command prompt for our use case though.
I'm going to use the annica the Anaconda prompt.
So let's click on that and open it.
OK so I opened up my anaconda prompt and right now I'm located under-sea users and then my username.
Keep in mind that I must know the location of my thought why M-L file that I just downloaded from the
link.
So right behind that here we can see that underneath my downloads folder I have the LP underscore course
underscore NVI that y m l.
So I need a change directory and make sure I'm in the same directory as wherever this why all file.
So you have two options.
You can either change directory at the command line or simply move that y M-L file to wherever you're
located in the command prompt.
So I can either move that folder to under user of my username or I can see using the words or letters
CD and then type out the file path that my mail file is and you should be able to have autocomplete
so only to change directory or CD into Downloads.
And then if I'm on Windows I can type Diyar and I should be able to confirm that my M-L file is there.
If you are on Mac OS or Linux the command for listening everything is simply L S for list.
All right now it's time to take that.
Y m l file and then restore the environment from the dot.
Why M-L file the command for doing this is simply Konda eat NVI space.
Create space single dash F and then the name of the file which is an LP underscore course.
Underscore E and V thought y and L.
Now before I hit enter I want to show you two really common errors.
The first error is to accidentally have a typo.
So for example let's say I forgot one of these underscores and I tried running this.
If you have a typo somewhere you're going to get this error.
Can't process without a name.
If you have the error please triple check that you do not have a typo.
If you've confirmed that you don't have a typo then you may be in the wrong directory.
So for example if I actually go back up the directory notice now I'm in the wrong directory.
I'm no longer in downloads so if I were to try to run the command Konda ENVI create dashed F and even
with the correct filename if I hit Enter I'm going to get the same error.
This is a really common error and there's only two possibilities.
Either you spelled the file name wrong or you are in the incorrect location and you're not in the same
location as that.
Y.M. file please.
Triple check that in case you get this can't process without a name error.
Again it's an easy fix.
You simply need to be in the correct directory so will say CD to download.
All right now that we've confirmed or in the same directory as it that why M-L file simply type out
the command Konda space E and V space create space dasht F and then the name of the y m l file.
If you're in the correct directory you should either be able to tab autocomplete.
This last part if you're not able to tab autocomplete that then it's a good indication they are in the
wrong directory.
OK so I'm in the right directory.
I haven't committed any typos so I'm going to hit enter and then you should see something pop up that
it's solving the environment and getting the packages ready for you.
So once you do that it's going to eventually hit you with the list of packages to be installed.
It's going to be a pretty long list and that's going to ask you for a yes or no and you're going to
type out why.
Yes.
All right.
After you've installed everything you should see the actual commands to activate the environment.
So you'll see something like activates it use this and then to deactivate the environment.
Use that.
So here are the commands conduct of a and b course Conda deactivate the commands may be slightly different
depending on operating system we are using.
If you are a Mac OS or Linux you may have the same source activate anyways.
The command will tell you what to type out.
So any time you want to run the environment you're going to have to activate it.
So we're simply going to say Konda activates an old P underscore course.
Enter any notice here on the left.
Now it's telling you you are operating in the virtual environment and again you have to activate this
before typing out the following.
Jupiter space notebook and what this is going to do is going to start to put a notebook in whatever
directory at the command line.
And then from here you can work with our files that we've given you.
So I'm going to enter
and once you hit enter you should see a pop up with a token and your browser should actually automatically
open to the Jupiter notebook page.
So let's go ahead and go to that now.
OK so here I am at Jupiter notebook.
You notice I have that y M-L file because I ran this in the same folder under Downloads and then I see
other downloads.
So all you need to do is simply click new notebook and then you have a new notebook ready to go.
So this is the environment we're going to be using.
It's essentially just Python written in cells so you can say something like prints hello do shift enter
together and then you get to see the actual output directly below.
So I do encourage you to do is download the zip file that contains all the coarse notebooks and then
simply unzip it to wherever you're going to be running Juber notebook.
In this case I have have it in the actual downloads folder.
All right.
If you have any questions please search the Q&amp;A forums in case someone has posted a similar question.
And check out the ific Q lecture.
If you still can't find an answer post the question answer forums your question with as much detail
and screenshots as possible and I will be happy to get you up and running.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.