Welcome back everyone.
And this lecture we're going to discuss work and of PDA files often you may need to read in text data
from a PDA file instead of a normal text file.
We can use the pie PTF to library to read in text data from a PDA file.
There's one key thing to keep in mind though not all PTF have text that can be easily extracted some
PDA types are created through scanning and instead of being exported from a text editor like Word these
sort of scanned PDA apps are really more like image files.
And that makes it much much harder to actually extract the text if you have a scan PDA PDAF that usually
requires specialized software and you can try googling different Python libraries for reading in those
type of images.
But a lot of times it's really hit and miss and much more the pen on the particular PDA file than the
library itself.
The pie PDAF to library that will be working with.
And this lecture won't be able to extract text from a scanned PTF image.
Now the pipes have of 2 library is made to extract text from files directly created from some sort of
word processor.
But even that you should keep in mind that not all word processors created PDX will have extractable
text.
So even if you actually exported from a direct word processor the library may still have difficulty
extracting that text now to begin.
Make sure you are using our environment file.
Or that you've installed py PTF to since it's not a library that comes.
Based Python to install pipes you have to simply open up your command line and directly type typin install
py PDAF to and notice the capitalization there.
Let's go ahead and get started.
By opening up a notebook and showing you how to work with some PDA files what I'm going to do is inside
of the Python Tex basic's folder.
If you click on it you'll notice that there is some PTF here that we have for you.
Make sure you go ahead and create your notebook in the same location as these pedia files or know the
entire file path for these pedia.
I'm going to go ahead and create a you note book.
That way I can simply call the PDA.
When I'm opening them and reading them so now that we have this new notebook created Let's go ahead
and start off by running.
Import py PDA to.
And if you get an error here that means you need a Pipp install it or activate the environment.
And now it's time to actually read a PDA.
In reading a PDA it works a lot like reading a normal text file.
We're just going to say my file is equal to open and let's go ahead and open up the U.S. declaration
pedia.
And the other thing we need to do here is there's going to be another mode and the mode that we're going
to use is mode equal to r b and Arbi means reading binary method and we need that because it's no longer
the normal text file.
It's a PDA file.
So we're going to run that.
And then once you read in the file using normal Python we're going to convert it into a PDA file reader
object so go ahead and make a variable called pedia reader and set that equal to pi PTF to dot and then
we're going to call this hit tab.
You should see a couple of options.
The one we're looking for is pedia file reader and the past in the file you read in and now off this
pedia reader where you can do is a few action is called pedia fritter hit dot and then hit tab.
There's a lot of attributes and a lot of methods.
I'll show you some of the main ones here.
There's number of pages and if you run that report's back the number of pages inside the actual PDAF
document and then you can't extract text and you can do it page by page.
So for example I can say Page 1 is equal to then call pedia reader and call the get page method and
then pasand the page you want there indexed at zero.
So if you want the first page you just passen zero.
So Page 1 index 0 and if you actually want the text you can do is say Page 1 DOPs and you can call the
extract text method.
Open and close print sees and that will extract all the text.
It was able to read on that PDA.
So here you can see the Declaration of Independence.
And now we have it as a string.
And so we have these new lines in order to indicate there's a new line.
So if we actually wanted to print this out it would print this out along those lines and I can see the
Declaration of Independence here.
And just like a normal file after you're done working with it get in the pages you want extract the
text.
Maybe you want to save some text and say my text is equal to extract text.
Once you're done doing whatever operations you're concerned with it's always a good idea to close the
file.
So just say my file doc close OK.
So we learn how to read any page in it from a PDA file and then we learned how to extract text from
that page.
Often you may want to add another page to a PDA.
Now unfortunately we cannot directly write Python string text onto a PDA because of the differences
between a single string type of Python versus the variety of fonts and placements and other parameters
that a PDA could have.
What we can do is copy pages and append the pages to the end so you can copy a page from another PTF
or the same PTF and then append that to the end of the current PDA if you're working with.
Well you can't do is take a python string and suddenly insert it somewhere into the PTF because of so
many different parameters that a normal PDA file could have.
Let's see how we could add a page to a PDA if I'm just going to create a variable f and set that equal
to open.
Let's open up the U.S. declaration that pedia.
Again remember since it's not going to be read in a PDA.
I mean you say the mode is read binary.
I'll create a PDA for object again and say hi PDAF to and then call PTF file reader and then pass an
F which was the variable we gave the file and then I'm going to grab the first page and say PTF reader
get page 0 and then I'm going to create a writer object.
I will say PTF writer is equal to and directly off the pipes to a library I'm going to call.
PTF file writer open and princes and this writer object is going to need to add pages so I can say PTF
underscore writer thought add a page and then I can go ahead and add that first page that we copied
off the US Declaration that PTF.
And so now I have this new documents this new pedia file that it just added a page to what I can do
is the following.
I can say something like PTF output is equal to open and I went into Passons some new document so it
can say my brand new doc PTF.
So this is a PDA file that doesn't currently exist.
If you check out the python text basics notice I don't have that actual PDA.
I have some new doc PDA but I don't specifically have my brand new that PDA.
But remember if we open things with the right permission it will automatically create files for us.
So not only just going to use w here.
I'm also going to use B to say write binary and now I have my PTF output and if you take a look at Python
text basics you should see now kind of this.
Empty my brand new that PDA so that PDA is waiting to be written to.
So we're going to say PTF writer and I'm going to write to the output file you just created.
So again what am I doing here.
I'm reading in a file using pedia file reader and grabbing a page from that file.
The first page.
Then I'm creating a PTF file writer and then I'm onto the writer object adding that first page I extracted
from my original document that I'm opening a brand new file with the right binary permission and then
I'm going to write PTF output there.
Run that and then I'm going to say PTF output.
I want to close that file and I'm also going to close the original file and so now if I take a look
at my brand new PDA.
If I are to read that in it should have one single page in it.
So let's go ahead and read in The File.
We're going to say make a couple of new cells here.
Say brand new is equal to open and I'm going to open my brand new PDA.
I'm just going to open and read binary mode.
Create a PTF reader object from pite PDAF to pedia file reader and I'm actually going to read in that
brand you file and then let's check out the number of pages it has.
It should have just one page.
So if we say some pages we see that one page and then we can continue on and extract that page that
will be the exact same text we saw here for the first page of the US Declaration.
So now we know how to read text data from a PDA file.
And we also know how to add to a PDA file.
So now let's show one more example.
This is a simple example of grabbing all the text from a particular PDA File.
We're going to say the following f is equal to open let's go ahead and open that U.S. declaration pedia
that we've been working with.
I'll open it if read binary permission and let's imagine I wanted to list all the text here what I could
do is the following.
I could create an empty list of just one item zero.
So it's essentially just a placeholder.
So I have this PTF text list that just has a placeholder 0 and then I'm going to create a reader object
so PTF file reader passen after I just read in from the U.S. declaration and then I can do the following.
I'll say for p in range PTF reader number of pages.
So essentially it's going to say for every page in this range we can go ahead and say page is equal
to PTF reader get page P because P is essentially just a number here.
0 1 2 3 all the way until we hit the number of pages.
So I want to get that specific page save it to this page variable and then I'm going to grab that page.
I'm going to extract the text from that page and then I'm going to append it to this list which is right
now just the placeholder empty list right there.
So I'll say PTF text append run that and then we can close the file.
And in fact we can just have this be an empty list.
Doesn't even need a zero there.
Run that.
And if we check out our PTF text list now we have a list of everything here.
And those are all the tests in that particular file.
So for every page.
So we check out the lengthier it's a length of 5.
So I could say for page in PTF text print the page and then I can say print a couple of new lines
run that and you'll see kind of this giant document of the Declaration of Independence and then a bunch
of spaces for each new page.
All right.
So that's the very basics of CMPD files.
We don't really need to know much more than that for this course.
Coming up next we're going to talk about regular expressions.
We'll see at the next lecture.