Welcome back to part two of late in Thursley allocation with Python.
Let's continue where we left off in the previous lecture.
All right here we are at the notebook where we left off last time we defined three steps last time we
wanted to be able to grow the vocabulary of words grab the topics and then grab the highest probability
words per topic.
Let's begin by showing you how to grab the vocabulary of words I'm doing.
Enter to put themselves below the cell and what I want to show you is that the count vectorize or object
we created for the document matrix.
You can actually do a get underscore a feature underscore names method and if you check the length of
what's returned here it's fifty four thousand seven hundred and seventy seven.
And if we take a look at our previous sparse matrix that's actually the other dimension.
In fact this is documents by words or a document matrix so get feature names is actually just holding
everything or pulling an instance of every single word.
In fact if you check the type of CV docket feature names it's just a list of all the words that were
in all your documents so we can randomly grab some words off of this so I can say Get feature names
and then Passons some sort of index position off of this list so I can grab word number index location
50000 and that happens to be the word transcribe.
Or I can get the word at location 41000 and there happens to be reproductive.
So just to make this clear I could print out a bunch of random words from my list of words so I could
say import random and then say random word ID is equal to random random integer and then say grab a
random integer from 0 up to 54000 777 and make sure we still ran the word ID correctly and then call
see the get feature names and then pasan that random word ID.
So as you keep running the cell you should see some different random words show up.
So these are all words that are in our actual documents.
So now we know I can simply call Seabee that get feature names and then pass in some ID number like
10 and I will get some sort of string word that happened to be in the document.
So now I understand how to grab the vocabulary of the words.
Now it's time to actually grab the topics.
So the way we do this is we actually now grab this information directly off the trained LDA so I can
say LDA or whatever happened to call your model and call component's underscore.
Then you can check the length here of these components and you notice there's 7 components and LDA components
underscore.
If we check the type of this it actually is just a name PI array containing probabilities for each word
so that I can say grabbed the first item.
Actually you can even describe the shape of the array.
You'll notice it's seven topics by fifty four thousand seven hundred and seventy seven words and we
take a look at the actual components.
You just notice it's this giant array.
So what we're going to be able to do is combine this information with our ability to grab vocabulary
in order to show you the highest probability words per topic.
So we're going to do here is we're going to start off by just grabbing a single topic off of these components.
So going to create some new cells and let's grab one of these topics we'll say single topic is equal
to LDA components underscore and going to index at zero.
So it's the very first topic and we still again don't know what this topic actually represents.
So I'm going to take single topic and I'm going to ask for ARG sort and Arg sort does it returns the
index positions that would sort the story.
So let me show you with a very simple example first.
So this is the output of our sort.
But I'm going to create a very simple array just to make sure you understand this sort process.
So I'm going say a r r so the variable name and P array and I get a pass in 10 and then 200 and let's
say 1 and if I take a look at my array I have 10 201.
If I take a look at array and then call sore on it it returns to 0 1.
So what that actually means is this is the index positions that would sort the array from the lowest
value to the highest value because the index to that was 1 index 0 that was 10.
And then our largest value was the index 1.
So it was two hundred.
So what we're doing is we're going to take these single topics and then figure out what index positions
we should be looking at for high probability words for this particular single topic.
So it's all our is doing is essentially showing us the locations of these larger values.
So that's where we're using our sort here.
So I can then use these in expedition's.
So it's actually going to be directly correlated with the index positions of this CV docket feature
names since LTA that we're actually trained on the result of this compact razor.
OK.
So what we're going to do then is now I understand that I can call single topic the arc sort of index
positions for the high probability words for that particular topic.
What I'm going to do then is the following I will say single topic and then I'm going to call our sort
and let's go ahead and grab the top 10 words for this topic.
So off of our sort I'm going to say negative 10 colon.
So this line is a little tricky to understand at first but it's actually not so bad.
All we're doing here is remember that our source returns back index positions sorted from least to greatest.
And what we're looking for are the top 10 values.
In other words the 10 greatest values.
So that means I want the last 10 values of our sort.
And so what this does right here is after you call Ark's sort it says starting next mission negative
10.
Colin go all the way to the end.
All this is doing is saying grab the last 10 values of the result of our sort which returns the index
positions of the 10 highest probability words for this particular single topic.
So what we're going to do is say top 10 words is equal to single topic arc.
Negative 10 all the way to the end and then those are the positions of my top 10 words and I'll say
for index in top 10 words Prince CV get feature names and then I'm going to call that index.
So when you're done this may take a little time but hopefully you should see words that tend to have
some sort of generalized topic feeling.
So this first single topic the 10 highest probability words show up in that particular topic are new
percent's government company million care people health said and says.
So here we can maybe tell that these look maybe like business articles government articles or health
care issue articles.
So what it can also do is start asking for more words like the top 20 words here.
So let's go ahead and call this top 20.
We'll run this and we'll make sure we call top 20 here.
There we go.
And now I get to see the top 20 words for this particular single topic and now it definitely starts
to clear up that maybe has to do more with health insurance and politics so I can see President state
tax insurance federal government per cent and more.
But what's really incredible here is that LDA is now showing us some sort of underlying latent topic.
It's trying to show us that these particular words have high probabilities of showing up in this particular
single topic.
Let's go ahead and now set up a little loop that prints out the top 15 words for each of the seven topics.
So we're going to do here is the following we'll say for in the next column a topic a little bit a tuple
and packing because we're going to call enumerates off L.D. components.
I'm going to use some string formatting here to say the top 15 words for Topic number and then I'm going
to insert here.
Index essentially is just the count.
In fact was going to call it.
I sort of get confused here.
And then what I'm going to do is say Prince and I'm going to create a list of C-v get feature names
index for index and topic Arc's sorts and then grab the last 15 words after you done are sort and then
we'll go ahead and print we'll print some new lines here.
All right so what is is doing is essentially saying for each topic and LDA components are LDA components
was an array.
We come back up here of seven so seven topics by fifty four thousand seven hundred and seventy seven
words and has a value associated to each of these words.
The greater the value the higher probability has a value to that particular topic.
So what we're doing is for each of those topics we're just grabbing the top 15 words and then we're
using miscomprehension to basically grab those index actions off our Get feature names words.
So if you run this loop you should end up seeing the falling top 15 words for topic zero companies money
year federal etc. So it looks as if healthcare in the United States top 15 words for topic number one
military how security Russia government Trump $250 for topping number two World Family Home day time
water city.
So maybe some infrastructure stuff here we can see medical disease patients health.
So maybe just general health.
Topic number for the election.
Obama Clinton so looks like stuff do with the election.
Number five music maybe lifestyle articles etc..
And here we can see data science university students school science education topics.
So here we only printed out seven topics zero through six.
It's up to you to decide how many topics start beforehand.
If some of these topics maybe aren't clear enough or maybe some of these topics seem too similar maybe
you go for less topics or if you want to get some clarity and subdivide these into further topics you
would just ask for more topics right off the top.
So the last thing left to do is to attach these topic numbers to the original articles.
And that's actually pretty straightforward.
All we need to do is recall that we have our original document turned matrix as well as our original
NPR data frame but we would like to do is essentially create a new column here that has a topic number
and to do that all we really need to do is create a list of the actual topics off this document matrix
and what we can do is call LDA dot transform on our original DTM so say topic results and go ahead and
run that.
Again this may take a little bit of time.
Technically we've already done this but we call the fit transform instead of just a dot transform.
And now if I take a look at topic results what this is is an array.
And if you check the shape it's in array where we have the original eleven thousand nine hundred ninety
two articles presented.
And now we have by 7.
So what this is if I take a look at the very first instance of topic results.
These are essentially probabilities of belonging to a particular topic.
Remember we previously saw probabilities of words belonging to a particular topic.
Now we're seeing the probability of a document belonging to a particular topic where this topic is topic
number 0 indexed 0.
This is the probability of topic number one index 1.
Notice here how these are essentially just values in percentage form.
So somewhere between 0 and 1 and if it's a little hard for you to read that you can call that round
off of this and you can see the actual percentages.
So it looks like the very first article at index 0.
It has a high its highest probability is around 68 percent belonging to topic number 1.
So let's see if that makes sense.
What was topic number one topic number one tended to include words like military House security Russia
government President Trump police etc..
So let's take a look back at the original documents.
Remember we can print out any article we want so let's go ahead and print out the first article and
it looks like it does have to do with that.
So Washington of 2016 even pulsing the bipartisan politics cannot etc. so it does look like it has to
do with politics.
It has to do if Russia it has to do security Moscow etc. so that seems like a pretty fair topic.
Now keep in mind because of recent news and the way NPR works and some of these articles particularly
the way we scrape these articles a lot of them actually do of politics.
So you may see feel that some of these topics overlap which OK we're going to do now is show you how
to easily connect this with our original data frame.
So what we're going to do is I'm actually not interested in these probabilities.
I'm just interested in the index position of the highest probability.
And I can grab that by calling RMX and RMX returns back the index position of the highest probability.
So again RMX says index 1.
That's where you had your highest probability.
So going to do is say NPR topic is equal to topic results and then I'm going to call RMX across.
Access is equal to one.
And then I can see the assigned topics.
So note that these first four looks like their topic one then from photography Illustration A video
looks like topic to topic 3 2 3 2 5 5 and so on.
And then if you ever want to figure out well what is topic 5 represent says who's the YouTube star of
2016.
We go ahead and see will or the high probability words for topic 5.
We simply scroll up see topic 5 has to do with music people life etc..
So looks like it makes sense that this story about YouTube stars 2016 and Adele singing has to do with
top five.
All right I hope you found this as fascinating as I did.
If you have any questions feel free to ask in the Q and A forums and I would highly encourage you to
check out our original site and Thursley allocation notebook so you can play around with those values
as well.
OK.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.