Welcome to this lecture on tokenization tokenization is the process of breaking up the original raw
text into component pieces or otherwise known as tokens.
This was the very first step that occurred when we created our document objects using the pipeline was
spacey.
You can imagine that we have some original text and the very first step is to split on whitespace.
So from where moving to L.A. We split on the white space then Spacey is smart enough to understand that
it's going to separate prefix that is characters at the beginning.
It's also going to two separate exceptions.
Those are concatenations and it's also going to be able to separate a suffix.
So those are characters towards the end.
And then we can also realize that we have exceptions such as an exclamation point and then we're done.
So there's lots of steps involved but luckily Spacey is taking care of all of that for us.
We have prefix suffix infix and exceptions.
So again notice that the tokens are just pieces of the original text.
We don't see any conversion to words stems or lemmas the base forms of words.
And we haven't seen anything yet about organizations places money etc. that's going to be named and
the recognition we we're going to talk about later on for now you should understand that tokens are
the basic building blocks of a dark object everything to help us understand the meaning of the text
is derived from tokens and the relationship to one another.
As I mentioned we had the prefix those were the characters at the beginning.
We had the suffix characters at the end.
We have infix which are the characters in between the prefix and the suffix and then we have the exception
which is a special case rule to split a string into several tokens or prevent a token from being split
when punctuation rules are applied.
So we can see a few examples here such as.
A prefix is a dollar sign prefixing an amount of money.
A suffix can be something like K.M. suffix seeing at the end the kilometers travelled in unfix is just
something between like a dash or a forward slash and the exceptions can be basically things are a special
case rules to make sure when you're doing the split as the token you understand that it's actually part
of a joint punctuation like you dot dot.
Now tokens have a variety of useful attributes and methods.
We're going to explore tokens of Spacey in further detail.
But jumping over to Jupiter notebook.
Let's get started.
The first two are going to do in our note book is import Spacey and then load up our Spacey library
will say Spacey load and then call it an underscore co core underscore Wehbe underscore S-M that load's
or spacey library.
Next let's go and create a string that includes opening and closing quotation marks.
So say my string is equal to will have single strings on the outside and we're going to say where moving
to a exclamation point and then we're actually going to have this in its own set of quotes.
So those are the quotes I'm using on the very outside.
I have this single set of quotes and then the reason I'm using a backslash here is the so that the single
quote in between we and our ear isn't actually going to break up the string and then we have these double
quotes which are going to be intact so if I took a look at my string I see we're moving to L.A. But
if I actually print this out I will see we're moving to L.A..
So again just including some information in there such as the double quotes and then using this backslash
as an escape character for the single quote in order to not stop the string too early.
Let's go ahead and say Doc is equal to an LP and will pass in my string and then for a token and doc.
Let's go ahead and print the text of the token and we can see here we were able to grab the double quotes.
We're able to separate we an apostrophe are we moving to.
We understood the LS should be kept together and then we have an exclamation mark.
So Spacey is going to isolate punctuation that does not form an integral part of a word.
Things like quotation marks commas and punctuation at the end of the sentence will be assigned their
own token.
However punctuation that exists as part of the email address website or numerical value will be kept
as part of that token.
Let me show you an example.
Let's create another string and pass it into a dock.
We're going to create a unicode string that says something like We're here to help send snail mail email
support at our site dot com or visit us at each.
And it's going to make up a Web site here that E.W. our site dot com exclamation mark.
So we run that and run if we can see this is actually a really complex string to analyze.
We have a lot of punctuation here such as these exclamation points.
This dash or hyphens separating snail mail.
We have dots here which isn't really of a sentence.
Instead it's part of this email address and then we also have these dots right here which are part of
a Web site.
Spacey is smart enough to understand that.
So if we see 40 in doc to print see here we can see that the Web site and email are intact.
Space is smart enough to understand that this particular period isn't going to end the sentence.
What is interesting though is that the hyphen in between snail and mail is actually assigned its own
token and spacially has its own internal rules for deciding what kind of token gets assigned where.
Let's create another document.
Well say Doc three is equal to an LP and here we're going to pass in a five kilometer NYC cab ride cab
ride it costs $10 and 30 cents.
Run that and then we'll save 40 in Doc 3.
Go ahead and print t.
And he Rissi a five K.M. being separated from five NYC cab ride costs.
Dollar Sign and again it's smart enough to keep ten thirty.
Together.
So here that distance unit and the dollar sign are assigned their own tokens.
Yet the dollar amount itself here and $10 30 cents is preserved.
Punctuation that exists as part of a known creation will also be kept as part of the token.
So for example will create no document and LP and will say something like let's visit St. Louis in the
US next year.
We run that.
Well check out the tokens that spacey figured out.
And I'll say let's visit.
Notice it keeps St together Louis and it keeps us together again.
Everything is happening under the hood for your convenience.
You don't actually have to tell Spacey what rules to expect.
It's smart enough to understand that on its own.
Now if we ever want to count the number of tokens all we need to do is check the length of a document
object.
So if I want to know how many tokens doc 4 has.
I just checked the length and it reports back that it has 11.
Now we can actually also count vocab entry vocab objects contain a fool library of items so off of a
document object you can call the vocab.
And it's this large vocabulary object and this number is going to change based on the language library
loaded at the start.
So if I check the length of Doc for that vocab notice right now it's fifty seven thousand eight hundred
fifty two.
That means that when we loaded up this English core web as M for small that has a vocabulary of fifty
seven thousand eight hundred fifty two different types of tokens and there is an LG or a much larger
language library that you can use for more complex tasks.
But for most of our use cases this language library is going to service fine.
Now tokens can also be retrieved by index position and slice and we've actually shown this before.
But let's reiterate.
It will say duck 5 is equal to an LP pass and a unicode string that says it is better to give than receive
and if I have docked 5 here it can simply index.
And here I can grab one single token or I can grab a slice of tokens maybe 5 say give me everything
from position 2 to 5 and I can see better to give and we kind of have our own little span there.
Keep in mind tokens cannot be reassigned although document objects can be considered lists of tokens.
They do not support item re-assignment.
So once you created that document it's going to be fixed.
You can't do something like re-assign something like that it's going to say object does not support
assignment.
So this document object you're not allowed to do this sort of reassignment which makes sense there's
a lot of information here that spacey figured out from these tokens.
It shouldn't make sense to be able to simply replace it for a simple python string.
Now Spacey can actually go a step beyond simple tokens it can actually understand named entities named
entities.
Add another layer of context.
The language model that you load in at the very top recognizes that certain words or organization names
while others are locations and still other combinations relate to things like money or dates named entities
are accessible through the E and T S property of a document object.
I want to create a new document to show this will say Doc let's say eight is equal to an LP and we'll
say the following string Apple to build a Hong Kong factory for 6 million dollars want to just say six
million dollars.
So we run this right now and we already know that we have token information.
We can say for tokin and Doc date print out the token text and in fact I can print it all out along
the same line by saying and is equal to some sort of separator.
So I can do that to print out.
Let's add a little space there.
So here I can see all the various tokens.
Apple to build a Hong Kong factory for the dollar sign than six and then million.
But here's what's really cool.
I can go ahead and say for entity in dock 8 but instead of now going through dock I'm going to say dock
eight dot and Ts and we're not going to do is say print the entity.
So off of this string space is smart enough to figure out that there's something special about Apple.
Hong Kong and six million dollars and is able to figure this out without you telling it more information.
It recognized that Apple Hong Kong and six million dollars are named entities kind of similar to proper
nouns in a sense.
Basically there's more context to these particular words.
And in fact it's smart enough to know the falling off of each of these entities.
We can actually print out a label so you can say label underscore and then we're going to print a new
line here.
And you'll notice that it has these labels.
They'll say Apple is R.G. or organization or $6000 is money and you can check out the named entities
list that we have inside of our notebook we have a little link here that will show you a table of what
names and cities look like and what these actual codes stand for and then check out the link in our
notebook for link the documentation.
Now you can ask for more explanation on these labels directly by simply saying the following.
Print the string representation of a Speccy.
It has this really useful explain function and you can actually ask it to explain that label.
So I know a little bit nested here but all I'm saying is explain that label pasand into a string and
then print it out.
Whoops.
This should be.
And to see.
OK.
So again I'm just going through each entity printing out the entity print printing out the label and
then printing out the builtin explanation for that label.
So orgy's stands for companies agencies institutions.
GP is for countries cities and states 6 million are recognized as money which is monetary values including
unit.
So all of this is what space is doing for you.
Lots of awesome work though we don't really have to be aware of.
And the last thing I want to mention here is that Doc E.A. s or entities similar to that we have now
and Chunk's which are another object property nown chunks.
Our base noun phrases essentially flat phrases that have a noun as their head.
So you can think of noun chunks as noun plus the words describing a particular noun.
Let me show you what I mean by that.
We're going to say Doc nine is equal to an LP and we'll create a sentence here called Autonomy's cars
shift insurance liability toward manufacturers.
OK.
So kind of a complex sentence here and we have various chunks the chunks are going to be autonomous
cars because we have a known cars and this word describing that.
Now we also have insurance liability as another chunk and then manufactures itself is a now chunk is
just a noun.
But it doesn't really have the Scripter here.
So again I can say for chunk in and I'll say Doc nine and I can call noun chunks off of this and then
actually print out each chunk autonomous cars insurance liability and manufacturers.
And I would encourage you to again check out the link that we provide in the notebook for a list of
all the different types of noun chunks that are available.
Coming up next for part two we're going to talk about visualizing with builtin visualizes that's basically
also provides.
We'll see you at the next lecture.