We'll come back in this lecture and continue where we left off and go over a couple of more regular
expression techniques.
Let's head over back to the notebook.
Here we are in the same notebook we left off last time previously we actually showed you how to reduce
this pattern using regular expressions into this pattern with quantifiers.
One other thing I want to mention are the ability to actually grab separate groups.
Currently this entire phrase for the pattern is one solid group that you can compile separate groups
using parentheses.
So I can use parentheses to separate these groups
in between the dashes.
So I'm adding Prince C's and now when I search for this pattern inside of the original text which was
my telephone number and if I actually say my Match.com group that grouped together everything but I
can actually call individual groups starting at index position 1 and that's going to grab the first
set that was inside the princes.
So if I say Group 1 it just grabs 8 8 8 you can see here if I were to include the dash inside the princes
and we run this group one would have been a dash.
So this way you can actually use the same character identifiers and quantifiers as before except now
you can easily group things because maybe you only wanted the area code so that you could just say Group
One.
Or if you wanted the last digits Well that would be in group 3 and those would be the last four digits.
So that's the ability to use groups and if you want to group everything you just don't provide a number
of groups.
All the groups together some additional regular expression syntax that won't show you is the pipe operator
you can use the pipe operator to have an OR statement.
For example I can say Ariz search and the pattern I can search for is man pipe operator woman and I
can say text is this man was here and we end up getting a match on man.
Or I could say this woman was here and we end up getting a match on a woman so you can see here it'll
work for either man or woman with the pipe operator.
You can also use a wildcard character you can use a wildcard as a placement that will match any character
placed there.
For example I can say r e thought find all and I'll put a dot there for my wildcard and then say 80
and then I'll create some Dr. Seuss sentence The Cat In The Hat set.
And if you run this you can see it found cat and set basically a wild card.
And then 80.
So C.A.T. h a t an s t keep in mind the weight is currently working.
You're only matching on one letter.
So if you were to actually say splatt at the end of this and run this you would only get out 80.
You could then continue on messing around with quantifiers or identifiers or even more wild cards.
So you can place multiple wildcards here and illand the grabbing the space and then the letter.
Or in this case a grab two letters before a and so on.
So again a dot a wildcard character a combine it using the sort of grouping quantifiers or character
identifiers next maybe you're just interested in things that start or end with a particular type of
character.
Well you can use the carrot which is above your six on your keyboard in order to say starts with a dollar
sign signal's ends with.
So for example I can say are either fine.
All I will say backslash D for each digit and then a dollar sign and a dollar sign against signals ends
with.
So I can say this ends with a.
Number two and return back and it's going to fine where it ends of the number.
And there we see two.
I could then also say carrot here instead of a dollar sign.
And that and the Cate's starts with.
So I could say one is the loneliest number.
Run that then I get back one since it's starting with a digit.
Now I should note that this is for the entire string not just for individual words.
To exclude characters you can use the carrot symbol in conjunction with a set of brackets.
Let me show what I mean by that.
Let's create a much longer phrase and say there are three numbers 34 inside five this sentence.
Now let's imagine I wanted to get rid of all the numbers inside this sentence.
What I can do is I can say r e.
Find all.
And then I can pasan a pattern.
So I'll say are I then quotes and then I'm going to say closed square brackets carot for backslash D.
So my backslash d the carrot.
And when the carrot is actually inside these square brackets that's going to indicate exclusion.
So I'm basically saying exclude any digits.
So it's pass in our phrase and you'll see there are.
And then we just get spaces and then numbers inside this sentence.
So it's actually no longer actually grabbing any of these numbers we're excluding it with the use of
the square braces or brackets.
And then this carrot symbol then if you actually want to get the boards all back together you can add
a plus sign here and that's going to return back.
Basically anything that isn't a digit so we can actually use this to remove punctuation from a sentence
which is a common thing you have to do when working a natural language processing.
Let's create another test phrase and say this is a string but it has punctuation how to remove it.
Question mark.
So there's a bunch of punctuation here.
Again all you have to do is say R-E find all and then start indicating what we want to remove.
So inside the square braces I'll have my care and it's a exclamation point.
Period.
Question mark and that's say plus.
And then in my test phrase run that.
And then I get see this nice list.
This is a string but it has punctuation how to remove it.
So you notice right now is a list of everything that isn't punctuation.
So I'm using exclusion here.
And if I wanted to I could say my list is equal to this and then I have my list here and I can use the
join method off of a string in order to join this list together.
So I could say join.
Let's actually just say right here join a space six say space and that's going to join every item in
this list with a space in between.
So now I see this is a string that has punctuation how to remove it which now has successfully removed
any punctuation from this test phrase.
Main thing to note here is you have the square braces and the carrot.
And then this plus sign and then anything inside these brackets after this.
We're looking for exclusion.
Now the last regular expression parameter I want to talk about is something we actually just saw which
is the plus sign along with using brackets for grouping.
So this plus sign along with brackets allows you to use grouping Mishu what I mean by that by saying
text and the text string are going to work with is only find the we're going to say hyphenated words
here.
So hyphen words where are the longish dash words.
So let's imagine a situation where we want to find any sort of words to have this hyphen in it.
What we can do here is say Ari fine all so we're saying find some set of letters a dash and then some
other set of letters and the way we're going to word this here.
S.a.a be able to grab that period as well.
So the way we do this is we say in square brackets backslash w which if you refer back to your expressions
notebook and starts crawling up so you can find the table.
Here we have the identifier backslash lowercase W..
That stands for alphanumerics.
So both letters and numbers will be picked up here.
So this will grab inside square braces with a plus sign.
This basically indicates grab any number of alphanumerics.
So some group of alphanumerics.
So alphanumerics is indicated by backslash w the square braces with the plus sign indicates any number
then what we want is a dash and then backslash w and then plus for Again any number of alphanumerics
and then we're going to search that text.
We run that and it went ahead and find those words for us and actually then pick up this period because
we didn't ask for punctuation we just asked for alphanumerics in a period doesn't count as that.
So that allows you to actually grab anything of the sort of pattern.
So you get the idea here is this again a group of alphanumerics a dash and then another out group of
alphanumerics.
Notice that we don't have to specify how long we expected either side of number of characters on the
dash to be OK.
So I know that's pretty complicated stuff but remember you should always be able to break out a regular
expression using the tables that we provide here into it's basic steps.
It should also be able to use the example matches and example Petar codes with identifiers and quantifiers
to actually build up what you want.
And the main one that we're looking for here was this plus one which means just occurs one or more times.
OK.
So coming up next is going to be your assessment to test your new skills.
We'll see you at the next lecture.