Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and learn how to use sikat learn through this code long lecture and open up Jupiter notebook
now.
All right.
So of to begin we're going to import some pie as NPE and we're also going to be importing a library
called pandas and pand is going to allow us to actually read in CXXVI files which are comma separated
values files and other file types like text files or tab separated files and so on.
So we're going to be using panels a little bit and we'll be showing you a quick look about a few various
Pandurs methods that are really useful in conjuncture sikat learn so Pancho's can actually read in files
into what's known as a data frame object and it does this through the command.
PD read underscore see s the.
And then we pass in the file path to the file.
So we're going to be opening the up underneath text files.
There is an Esam as spam collection that TSB file and it's a TSB meaning it's tabs separated.
So we're going to pass in one more parameter here which is going to be backslash T.
And that indicates a tab just telling Panne those in Python that this particular file isn't separated
by commas for each column but separated by tabs and then we're going to assign this to a variable called
the F and then off of this variable.
If you hit that and then hit tab once it's been defined.
So if you run that cell that actually defined if you hit tab you'll notice there's quite a few attributes
and methods.
We actually don't need to worry about too many of these but the one we're going to see right now is
called head.
And this is going to show us the first five rows.
So these are actual data set and we've seen this before.
We have a label indicating if a text message is ham or spam and then we have the actual text of the
message and then we have the length of the message and then we have the punctuation.
So how many actual punkish pieces of punctuation.
Does this message contain.
We still don't know how to extract features from the text.
So instead we're just going to be using these direct numerical features and then later on we'll realize
and learn how to actually convert this text message that the most important feature here into numerical
information using text feature extraction.
But for this lecture we're going to be focusing on things that are already numbers in this dataset in
order to use them to actually perform a text classification machine learning model.
Now machinery models usually require complete data.
So one easy way to check if your data is missing anything is by taking this data from object and then
calling is null.
And if you just run is no by itself it returns back in other data frame of booleans in the killing true
or false is a null or missing value.
So what you can do is offer this simply take the sum and it's going to treat these falses as zeros.
And if there's anything missing they'll say it's true that it is null and ill treat that as a 1.
So if you say is no and then hold that sum.
Then if you ever see a one here then you know there's a missing value in this case everything is zero.
So actually no we're not missing any data.
Now we can also check information about this data frame like how many rows it has by simply checking
the length of state of frame and it returns back that currently we have five thousand five hundred and
seventy two rows.
So we have five thousand five hundred seventy two text messages.
Each of them labeled as well as understanding their length and they're basically how much punctuation
this particular message has.
Now we're going to do is take a quick look at the ham and spam label columns and the way you can access
columns off a data frame is by calling data frame and then in square braces passing in the name of the
column the name of the column is right here symbol to see the label message length or PNC.
So those are a column names.
Let's go ahead and check in the label by passing it in as a string so here I just grab the label column
and if I say that unique as a method it's going to return back the actually unique values.
So here you have two unique values.
Ham and spam.
And then I can call off the same column
the value underscore counts and it will actually count how many of each unique values we have.
So it looks like we are four thousand eight hundred twenty five him text messages and 747 spam text
messages.
Now what we're going to attempt to do is try to build a very simple machine learning model that attempts
to predict whether a message is ham or spam based solely on these two numerical features the length
of the message and the punctuation of the message.
And we can actually visualize this.
In fact if you check out the notebook that goes along this lecture if you scroll down we show some code
that allows us to visualize ham versus spam and the actual punctuation or the length of the message.
We can produce histograms for it.
So don't worry too much about what this actual code does because this isn't really a visualization course
if you are interested in what this code is doing.
You can check among other courses on that.
But really here we're just interested in this visualization.
So I'm going to just copy and paste the code that's here.
And then explain what it's actually doing.
So this is producing two histograms one for the hand messages and then one for the spam messages.
So right now what this is doing is it's looking at the length column and it's actually showing on a
logarithmic scale.
And notice here that the actual distribution of ham text message length versus spam text message length
is quite different.
Spam text messages look to be longer in length than ham text messages and intuitively that actually
makes sense.
A lot of ham text messages are legitimate text messages are going to be short they're just going to
say things like ok or on my way or see you there while spam text messages typically are going to be
quite longer because there's a lot more information to convey because there's more spam so we can check
it out here by actually seeing something like this free entry and a two weekly competition et cetera.
Most likely if it's a spam text message going to be quite a bit longer.
So this one is 155 versus these other hand ones tend to be a little shorter.
That's not to say that ham or legitimate text messages can't be long as well but the distribution of
each of these is quite different.
So that probably in the Cate's that's a good numerical feature to provide to our machine learning model.
It's still simplistic and we're really just focusing on how to use the sikat learn syntax.
So don't worry too much about this being the most robust machine learning model ever.
Now also we're going to do is we're going to take a look at the punctuation column and see if it has
maybe a similar behavior.
So again just coming from our notebook.
We're going to scroll down here and then copy the code.
It's essentially the same thing but now looking at the punctuation column on a logarithmic scale and
you see here these are two histograms for ham versus spam.
Punctuation wise and here that doesn't tend to be any distinct behavior.
It looks like spam tends to have a little bit more relative to other hand messages.
It it's a little more punctuation but tear the behavior is not as clear or the stink as it is here.
So in general we can say that it looks like spam tends to have a higher range of values.
It looks like spam messages tend to be longer and there's less of a range of overall values.
They all tend to be pretty long versus him has quite a large range of length.
So we're going to be attempting to use again these two numerical features along the label.
Again we're really just focusing on sikat learn later on we'll actually learn how to use this text message
data.
So what we're going to do here is learn how to actually conduct a machine learning model of sikat learn.
So the first thing to do is to split the data into a training set and a test.
And the way we do this is we simply say from S-K learn the model selection and he should be able to
tab a complete that we're going to import train test split and we've seen this before.
And then we're going to call train test split and we're going to pasan x and y.
But first we need to define X and Y actually are.
So what we're going to do is we're going to say that X is our featured data.
And why is our label so for feature data.
We're going to say x is equal to the F and I'm going to use two sets of brackets here.
I'm passing in a list of column names and will be passing in the length column and the punctuation column
again.
Note the use of double brackets I'm passing in a list of columns which is why I have two sets of brackets
and then we're going to pass in our label which in this case that column is just called label.
So have X feature data and white label data.
Then what we want to do is pass that into train test split.
And what I encourage you to do is if you do shift tab in Jupiter you can see the docstring for train
test split and if you scroll down inside of this eventually see this nice example you can scroll down
and essentially copy and paste this tuple that says X train x test Y train and white test because using
tuple and packing we can see what is actually returned here.
Train to split as we mentioned previously in the other lectures is going to return your training set
and your X test set your wily Wil's for the training set and your y labels for the test set and then
it's up to you to decide what the test size should be.
So we're going to say that 30 percent of our data is going to the test data set.
And then the other thing you may want to do is say a random state because this train split happens randomly.
So it's going to grab random rows that way in case your data sorted that won't affect the actual train
test split.
So if for if you want to be able to repeat this sort of randomness and the train test split you can
provide a random states and then choose an arbitrary integer value to in the actual value itself is
kind of meaningless.
What matters is that you use the same value if you want to repeat this train to split.
So we're going to pass 42 and if you pass and 42 that means you'll get the same train to split that
do.
If you pass in a different random state that's fine you just won't get the same split that I do.
So I encourage you to fall exactly and type in 42.
Again that's just the random state for the split.
So we're going to run that and now we can check out the shape of this data by simply saying X train
sheep
notice here X train is three thousand nine hundred rows and two columns.
So the two columns there are length and punctuation X test.
Check out the shape of that is 1672 rows with two columns so extreme that's going to be our training
data for the features the length of punctuation X test that's going to be the test features.
And remember it's still like the punctuation but it's only 30 percent of the data and we can see why
test.
And if you check out the shape of that that's essentially the labels right now.
So no.
1 6 7 2 because it's the labels that correspond with X tests so ham ham spam and the index position
is kept in memory.
So that's just the index that corresponds with X test.
So if we delete that thought shape and look at X test notice that we have these index positions and
that's going to allow us to match up the Y test to the X test.
And that how this is not in order because we randomly selected them using train test split.
OK so we have our X test our test our X train and are y train.
Now it's time to actually create and train a machine learning model.
So I'm going to show you how to train multiple models and you hopefully realize that the exact process
is really similar regardless of what model you choose.
So the general syntax is the following.
You say from escolar dots and then the family of models and if you hit tab here you'll notice that there's
a lot of options.
Now all of these are families.
The first we're going to show you is a logistic regression model.
So we say he learned that linear model import and we're going to say logistic regression.
So that's step number one in putting the model.
Then it's time to create an instance of the model.
We will say well our model is equal to.
And then you create an instance of a logistic regression and if he does shift tab here you'll notice
that you have a ton of different parameters that you can choose.
Often the default values are actually quite good.
If you want to learn more about how to actually edit these parameters what things like seemin or what
solver's to use.
You can check out the reading an introduction to the learning this the book we previously mentioned
which goes into a lot more detail of the mathematics behind a lot of these parameters but these are
the sort of parameters you'd be editing after you test your model against the test data.
So just for example we could edit this particular solver.
So if you scroll down here there's a lot of explanations over what these actually do these different
parameters.
So if you wanted to edit the solver you were to scroll down here until you see solver's.
And this shows you the different algorithms it uses as well as what options you have.
So you have this Newton option.
Elby Yes et cetera.
And that actually even gives me advice so for small data sets lib Liniers is a good choice for multiclass
problems.
These can handle multinomial loss etc..
So just to show you an example of how you would actually do this you could just for instance choose
a different solver like Elby G-S and then say for this particular logistic regression I want solver
to be LBG of us.
Once you've completed that step it's time to actually fit the model to the training data.
So you just take your model called that fit and then pass your X training data and the labels that corresponds
to that data set.
Notice that I'm not setting this equal to a variable.
I'm simply just calling that fit.
I don't need to actually set the sequel to any variable.
I'm calling that fit on the training data and then it will report back the actual model that was used
along all the parameters that was used.
And now the model is ready to predict.
So coming up in the next lecture we're going to show you how to actually test the accuracy of the model
against the test data set.
We'll see if.