Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to again take a look at the previous movie reviews dataset that we've already
explored using text classification techniques.
Let's now apply sentiment analysis and see how that compares at discovering the labels.
Let's open up a notebook and get started OK.
Let's begin by importing numb pies and PPI and importing pandas as PD and then we're going to do is
read in the as we file and underneath the text files folder depending on where you have it save on your
computer.
There is the movie's review that TSC file raising movie reviews that TSB not movie reviews too.
And then since this is tab separated we need to indicate that by saying SGP and then separator is backslash
T.
So we've already seen this dataset again we can check it out with head and we see we have labels and
as well as the reviews and we can also do a quick check to make sure there are no blank records so we
can do here is say the F drop N A and then say in place is equal to true.
So that's going to drop anything that is missing and then we can also remove single strings by creating
a list called blanks and then iterating through the data frame for every index label and review in D
F it or tuples we'll do what we did last time we'll check if the actual type of the review is equal
to a string then we'll say if that review is a space go ahead and grab its index position by saying
blanks and append that index position then we can check out blanks and see if we have any blanks.
So looks like we do have quite a few blanks so we're gonna do is we'll go ahead and drop those simply
by saying the F drop and then pass in those blanks index positions and then say in-place antithetical
to true.
Okay.
So we can now check out our label counts simply by saying the F label value counts and we should have
after that process nine hundred and sixty nine of each label.
So let's go ahead now and import sentiment analysis and create the essay the object will say from an
L T.K. that sentiment dot Vader.
Notice now I don't need to download that Vader.
You only have to do that once in the previous lecture.
Then we're going to import sentiment intensity analyzer and create the essay the object from sentiment
intensity analyzer.
I'm just using tapped autocomplete here and then we'll go ahead and use sd to append a compound score
as a column so just as before we say D F scores we'll go ahead and grab our review column and then we'll
apply a lambda expression simply by saying lambda taken that review and then call essay The polarity
scores on that particular review.
So this is the line that's gonna take the longest to run because it's performing that polarity score
analysis on every single review.
But once we have the scores we can simply grab a compound off of that basically the value for compound
by saying grab that score is dictionary and then apply lambda and then for that dictionary simply grab
back the compound value.
So we run that and then if we check up the head of our data frame at this point we have our scores dictionary
we have the compound value let's go ahead and convert this compound value into a label either negative
or positive by simply saying the following grabbed the compound value.
It's actually saying this is our comp score or predicted label.
However we want to label it but will say compound apply and we'll say lambda and then we'll say score.
Passed in return positive.
If the score is greater than or equal to zero else return negative.
And the reason we choose P Os and energy is because that matches the labels here.
Which is then going to allow us to actually use cycle learn to calculate things like accuracy precision
and recall.
So we run this whip.
Let's make sure we have valid syntax so pause if there we go.
There we go.
Okay so fix that little type of there.
And if you check out the head of the your frame at this point you should build see a comp score with
the predicted value and the label.
So right off the bat it looks like it's matching the first couple first five the compound score is working.
Let's go ahead and compare it across the entire data frame so we will say from a scalar that metrics
import will improve accuracy score classification report and then the confusion matrix.
So run those and let's just check our accuracy remember our accuracy score.
If we were randomly guessing if a movie review was positive or negative would be around 50 percent.
So hopefully we're performing better than 50 percent otherwise then we're no we're not performing that
in the random guessing.
So we're going to compare our label column to our calculated compound Score Column so it looks like
overall accuracy is around 64 percent.
That's definitely not as good as our ATF IDF analysis with our train model from earlier.
But keep in mind we're not really doing any sort of training step.
We're essentially just importing this Vader sentiment analyzer and hoping that it works well enough
on existing text data and you should also note that if you read some of these reviews there's a lot
of sarcasm in the reviews which is again really hard to detect.
So let's finish us off by also checking out our classification report on DFA label and the F Com Score.
I'm simply just going to copy and paste these in
so again.
Looks like we're getting not so great precision and definitely not great recall on negative and we can
see the F1 scores for both.
Again negative reviews.
Those tend to be often sarcastic and that's really hard to detect for any machine learning algorithm.
And then let's also point out our confusion matrix in case that interest us and we can see here the
supporting instances and the non supporting instances so it looks like Vader couldn't really judge the
movie reviews very accurately and this demonstrates one of the biggest challenges incent him analysis
really understanding human semantics.
Many of the reviews had positive things to say about a movie reserving final judgment to just the very
last sentence.
So even a negative review can highlight positive things.
Maybe saying oh the actors were really good in this movie but the script was horrible leading to a bad
movie.
That sort of dichotomy within a single review can be really hard for something like Vader to the text.
And sometimes it takes something more robust like TFA IDF in order to create your own sort of classification
models specifically for a positive versus negative sentiment analysis.
So keep that in mind whenever you're exploring sentiment analysis of your own datasets.
Coming up next we're going to test your full understanding on not just sentiment analysis but semantic
word vectors as well with a project in the next lecture.
We'll have an overview of that assessment.
Let's get started.
I'll see at the next lecture.