Welcome back in the previous lecture I mentioned that we can actually visualize tokenization with the
built in display see that comes with Spacey.
Let's go ahead and show you how it works by jumping back to the notebook or we left off last time.
OK.
Here we are at the notebook where we left off last time.
Well we're going to do is say from Spacey import and we're going to say this.
Blazey it's just a funny pun on display.
So the Spacey is the actual built in visualizer.
It's really cool.
And what's awesome is you can run it both inside the notebook if you're using Jupiter notebook or you
can create a little server if you're running stuff outside of Jupiter using just the normal Python script.
First let's create a document that we want to visualize will say a.p and then say Apple is going to
build a UK factory for and let's do six million.
Now that we have that document the next we're going to call is displacer remember its display of facey
there and then we're going to say render and then we pass in the documents.
There's also different style parameters you can do.
So I'll put in some defaults here and then we'll kind of look for the documentation to see what else
we can provide.
The one parameter we are going to make sure we say right now is because I'm using an open notebook also
Jupiter is the true.
And then there's an options dictionary comparison and I'll say distance is 110.
So if you run that you should see inside of your notebook this display.
So notice here we're able to see Apple is a proper noun is is a verb.
And you can see also the syntactic display over here of the arrows.
So again lots information that we're now able to show this optional distance argument is the distance
between the tokens.
So you can make this a little smaller.
Let's go ahead to make it 50 and run that again and I can see everything is a lot closer together.
So depending on how long your actual document is you may want to experiment with the size to make the
distance larger or smaller.
Now you can also visualize the entity recognizer.
So let me show you how to do that.
Let's create another document will say and LP Pasadena could string saying something like over the last
quarter.
Apple sold nearly 20000 iPods for the profits of I don't know let's go ahead and they say $6 million
again.
There we go.
So we have that string noticed that we have Flip's Let's make shall we say Apple correctly.
Laura SPEEs So we have apples we have iPods we have 20000.
And then we have six million.
Let's go ahead and run that through display see the render pass in that document.
But now for the style We're going to say E and T.
So again the original style was the eppi for syntactic dependency.
Here we're saying E.A. for entity and since we're using Jupiter we'll say Jupiter is true.
So run that and this is a different type of display.
What it's going to do is it's going to attempt to find every entity that it can.
Inside this document and it's going to highlight it.
So over the last quarter and then so here we see the highlight and we also see the type of events titas.
So the last quarter is that date Apple is an organization nearly 20000 that's some sort of cardinal
entity i-Pods.
It's smart enough to understand that that's a product and then a for profit of six million it understands
its money.
So Spacey is smart enough to do this all on its own which is really amazing.
Finally if you are creating visualizations outside of Jupiter maybe you're just running this in some
postscript.
Let's show you an example of how you can work with that.
You simply say a.p and we'll say this is a sentence
you say display C and instead of saying render inside the notebook you can say serve and then pass in
the document and then pass in whatever style you want.
I'm going to pass on style as syntactic dependency.
So if you read that you may get something that says hey your firewall is blocking it.
Go ahead and allow access and then you'll notice it's serving on port 5000.
So we're going to have to do is inside your browser you're going to go to 6:59 dot 0 0 1 Colan 5000.
Essentially your local IP address at port five thousand if you're on that night should see here the
actual visualization and this will work.
Even if you're running a shop by a script so it would just run this code inside it that postscript and
will report back that it's running.
Essentially this little mini server with this visualization.
And before we finished off this lecture I want to also talk about this options dictionary that we mentioned
above here.
So this option's dictionary it's basically a bunch of styling calls you can make.
You can check out the link we have in the notebook for the documentation link on visualizing the dependencies
so you can visualize the Pennsy parse or visualize and see the recognition and so on.
There's a lot of options you can do here and you can do things like coloring.
You can do background colors.
You can do zoom in zoom out all that stuff.
So essentially you have this options dictionary and you can provide the colors you want the different
fonts you want the background color you want and so on.
And here's a table of all the options you can provide for a list of even more options.
You can check out this place the API documentation simply by clicking on this link.
You can check out all these different options.
OK.
I hope you have fun.
And I would encourage you to passen your own sentences or own strings and play around and see how you
can visualize it.
We'll see you at the next lecture where we talk about stemming.