Welcome back everyone to this lecture on Ellis T.M. and G are you so a common issue that recurrent neural
networks face is that after a while especially if you're training the network on a really large sequence
then the recurring neural network is going to begin to forget those very first inputs the later and
later training batches of later inputs things that come towards the end of the text document that's
going to start kind of overwriting the weights of the very beginning inputs of the beginning of the
text.
So we want to make sure is that we're not beginning to forget those first inputs as information is lost
that each step going through their current neural network.
So what we really need is we need some sort of long term memory for our networks.
We've balanced both the short term memory of the networks the data that it was recently trained on versus
the long term memory of the networks all the data and the very first data that was being trained on.
So the Ellis team or long short term memory cell was created to help address these recurrent neural
network issues.
And while long short term memory cells aren't exactly state of the art they're still quite new considering
that they've really only been around in Paris for just the past few years.
So we're gonna do is go through how an Elysium cell works.
Keep in mind there's actually a lot of mathematics here.
There's really just a mathematical theory lecture where we're actually dealing with Caris it's gonna
be a simple import call.
So check out the resource link for a fool.
Really great breakdown in fact that's a super common link when discussing Ellis Thames and then we'll
also discuss the related G are you sell.
But for our use case I really want you to focus on Ellis Tam because that's what's most commonly used
for tech generation.
So let's get started learning how this Ellis Tam cell actually works but quickly recall that a typical
recurrent neuron basically has this sort of structure where we have some input at T minus one.
Then we have the output a T minus one and that output is also fed back in along the input at T so as
a quick note these outputs are often called Hidden so we can have instead of saying output at T minus
one.
We can say h of T minus one and then that also gets fitted with the input at t that gets passed through
some sort of activation function like the hyperbolic tangent.
Then that gives the output h of T etc. So when you see h of t just kind of think of that as the typical
output of a recurrent neuron cell.
All right so here we can see the entire model of a long short term memory cell and I know it can look
really complicated if you see it in this format but it's actually not so bad when you break it down
in parts.
So let's go ahead and first take a look at what's being input and what's being output it here.
We still have those original inputs from a normal recurrent neuron.
Those h of T minus one and exit T.
But note here we have this third input and we'll call that the cell state.
So right now we're receiving the cell state at T minus one and then the outputs we again output h of
T and then we also have the cell states.
That's the current cell state C of T.
So what we're going to end up doing is we're gonna take in h of T minus one and exit T as well as the
previous cell state C of T minus one and we'll output h of T as well as the current cell state C of
T.
So we're gonna do this step by step so the very first step is called the forgets Gates layer and this
is going to be the first step or we decide what information are we going to forget or throw away from
the cell state.
So what we end up doing here is you pass an h of T minus one and x of T and we pass that in after performing
a linear transformation with some weights and biased terms into a sigmoid function.
And remember because this is essentially a sigmoid layer it's always going to output a number between
0 and 1 and a 1 is going to represent to keep it and a 0 is going to represent to forget about it or
get rid of it.
So if we think back to maybe a language model where we're trying to predict the very next word based
on previous ones a cell state might include the gender of the present subject so that you in picking
the correct pronoun so when you end up seeing a new subject you want to forget about the gender of the
old subject.
So that may be a use for a forget gate layer when working with a natural language as a sequence.
Now the very next step is to decide what new information are you going to store in the cell state.
So we order the what we're going to forget.
Now we need to decide what are we actually going to store in the cell state.
Remember that's C of T.
So the first part is a sigmoid layer.
And the second part is a hyperbolic tangent layer.
So let's go ahead and tackle that first part that sigmoid layer.
So let's sigmoid layer is called the input gate layer.
So we'll say that's equal to I F T for input gate layer.
And again we take an h of T minus 1 and x of t do a linear transformation on it.
With they'll be a vi plus b a vi we pass that into a sigmoid function and again now we have a bunch
of values between zero and ones.
Then the second part of this is the hyperbolic tangent layer and that's again going to take h of T minus
one and exit t do that linear transformation and then pass it through a hyperbolic tangent so that ends
up creating a vector of what we call new candidate values.
So that's that C of T with a little tilt above it.
So these are candidate values that could be added to the state in the next step.
We're going to combine these two to create an update to the cell state.
So if we think back to an example of a language model we essentially want to add the gender of the new
subject to the cell state and replace the old one that we've already decided we're forgetting so now
it's time to update the old cell state.
Remember the old cell state is C of T minus one and we eventually want to update that to the new cell
state C of T so we can pass that on to the T plus one state of the cell.
So in the previous steps we already decided what we're going to forget and we also already decided what
we're going to store.
So now what we need to do is just perform or execute these actions.
So what we end up doing is we multiply the old state C of T minus one by F of T so we end up forgetting
the things that we essentially decided we're going to forget.
Based off that first sigmoid layer then we're going to add I have t the input gate layer times those
candidate values C of t with tilled on top.
So these are the new candidate values and now they're being scaled by how much we decided to up they
each state value.
So if we think back to a case of a language model this is where we would actually drop the information
about that old subject's gender and add in new information based off what we decided in the previous
steps.
Now our final decision is going to be what do we output for h of T.
So this output is gonna be based off your cell state.
That is just a filter diversion.
So it's actually pretty straightforward now.
We just using h of T minus 1 and x of t we pass that after a linear transformation into the sigmoid
layer and that's going to decide what parts of the cell state we're going to be outputting.
Then we put the cell state through a hyperbolic tangent so that's gonna push the values to be between
negative 1 and the 1 and we're going to then multiply it by the output of that sigmoid gate so that
we only output the parts we decided to.
So that's what's occurring here in this red line.
Again we're taking h of T minus one and exit t doing a linear transformation on it passing it through
the sigmoid and then once we have that output so we're going to say that's o of T output of T We're
then going to multiply by the hyperbolic tangent of the C of T or that current cell state and that gives
us h of T.
So that's how an Ellis team cell works.
Now there's different variants on an Alice T.M. cell.
So there's a variance called the peephole variance.
So this is actually quite popular.
And the reason for that is because it adds peepholes to all the gates.
So basically it allows these FTI of T and o of t to be able to see the previous cell state or C of T
minus one.
So you can see here now instead of being a function of just h of T minus one an X of T we're also passing
in C of T minus one and then for the output we're also passing in a sea of T directly.
So that's called an Ellis team with peoples another variation of the Ellis T.M. cell is called the gated
recurrent unit or G are you.
And this was actually introduced quite recently around 2014 and what it ends up doing is it actually
simplifies things a bit by combining the forget and input gates into a single what they call update
gates.
And it also merges the cell state and hidden state and it makes a few other changes.
So this resulting model is actually simpler than standard Ellis models and because of that it's been
growing increasingly popular over the last few years that it's been around.
So there's actually lots of other slight variations off of this and they're being introduced all the
time there was another one called depth gated recurrent neural networks and that was introduced in 2015.
And I mean who knows maybe in a few years we'll see another variation that further improves on this
model.
But the main idea is to understand how Ellis teams work and that allows you to quickly learn how these
variations work off of it.
All right.
Now that we understand Ellis teams and G use we can now use them with Caris.
Now fortunately Caris has a super nice API that makes Ellis Tam and RNA and really easy to work with.
And typically from the research I've done protects generation Ellis teams work best.
So that's what we're going to be using.
Coming up next we're gonna take a several part process in order to learn how to format our data.
That is our text data for recurrent neural networks.
And again Caris has a lot of convenient built in tools for this and then we'll see how to use Ellis
TAM for tech's generation.
This is a really awesome project so I hope you're super excited for it.
I'll see you at the next lecture.