Welcome back everyone in this lecture we're going to go over the solutions for the python text basics
assessment.
Let's get started.
OK.
Here we are at the python text basics assessment notebook and if you come down the first question was
print an F string that displays and piece stands for natural language processing.
So this one is pretty easy.
We just need to say print and then put an F in front of a string and then we can insert the variables.
So we're going to insert that abbreviation and then say stands for and then we'll answer for underscore
text.
If we run that you should get the result and all P stands for natural language processing just using
an F in front of a string and then inside the curly braces passing in whatever variable name you want
to insert next we want to create a file.
So we just had to run the cell that does it automatically for us.
Then we wanted to open the file and use that read to save the contents of the file to a string.
So there's different ways we can do this.
We're going to use the with operator.
We'll say it with open and then we'll open contact stop t x T.
And we'll say as.
And you can really call this if you want can say as F will say Fields is equal to and then we'll say
F that read.
So if you run that let's go ahead to make two cells here.
If you're able to run this then when you call fields outside of that you should see fields is now this
large string.
First name last name title.
Extension.
Email.
Next we're going to work with files.
So the first thing is to actually import PI PDAF to that we want to open the file.
Remember we need to open it with our B.
So say F is equal to open
business proposal and you can actually use tab to autocomplete this and then say mode is RB then we're
going to use pi PTF to read the text of the file.
So create this idea for object and say pi PTF to and then call PTF file reader.
So save file reader and then pass an F there and then get the page from text too.
So Page two text is equal to pedia reader.
And then we're going to get page and the challenge to do this in one step so you can actually change
the methods off each other and to get page number two.
We're going to index at once indexing starts at zero and then we're going to call extract loops extract
text and you can do this in one step or two steps so I'm just chaining off the methods and then we want
to close the file.
So I'll say F but close and then we'll print the contents.
Print page 2 text and if you run this you should see these authors along with some emails next to open
the file contacts t XTi and append mode and add the text of page to from above to the contacts start
to XTi.
So a simple solution for this could just be with open contact stop XTi.
And then we're going to open it in mode.
A plus and we'll say as well go ahead and write that page to text and then we're going to seek back
to zero.
Just so I can print this out to confirm that if I read it I see the actual extension.
So technically you don't need to seek or read this is just so I can confirm that I get to see this output.
So if I run this notice now how I see the output of the original context that textfile.
And now I also see the appendant information here from that pedia file.
Now there was a challenge to this question which was to see if you can remove the word authors.
So right now we actually don't have the authors who just have their e-mail here.
So it might be nice to be able to remove authors and then just have email as a last one because it's
kind of almost building out a CSP file.
So the way we can do that is if we come back up here we can rerun contacts that cxi to essentially get
a fresh version of this file and then when it come down here and then we want to remove authors because
it showed up here in page to that text.
So the way we can do that is we can say with open contacts DXi and then a plus open it as whatever file
name you want and then I'm going to write page to text but I'm going to use string indexing taxes start
grabbing at the eighth exposition onwards which is essentially everything after authors from this text
right here.
So just these three lines instead of this right here.
So that or move authors from being appended a scene they're going to write that.
And then let's try this again.
I'll seek a zero and then print out after read.
And when you run that now I don't see the authors there.
So that's a little challenge basically figuring out how to actually take that slice and remove author's
OK.
The last question was using the page to text variable create above extract any email addresses that
were contained in the file business proposal that pedia.
Now there's actually a lot of different ways you can build out a regular expression.
And as long as you get these three email addresses you should be good in whatever method you used.
But let's go ahead and break this down.
What are we actually looking for.
We're looking for a set of alphanumerics then an alpha symbol.
Another set of alphanumerics ADOT and then a set of three letters essentially dot net or dot com et
cetera.
So how can we actually build this out.
Well first start up with our.
And then I'll start building up my string.
So I'm looking for a set.
So we'll say in the square Brace's of a plus sign backslash W..
And then I'm looking for an at symbol and then another set of letters.
We don't know how long they're going to be which is why we're using the braces and the plus sign.
And then we're going to say a dot and then a backslash w and then a set of curly braces for three because
I'm looking for three on this last one.
Such as dot net dot com etc..
So when you run this you should then be able to get out this output of these three emails of mine.
There are several ways you could have done this.
The expressions are actually quite versatile and they're actually even quite flexible.
So for instance could have edited this to be some other sort of regex pattern that also would've worked
for us.
So if you figure out this exact pattern but still got the right results that's totally OK.
Okay.
So I hope you found that useful.
And now we're finished with Paice on text basics so we can begin moving on with natural language processing
basics and learning about the Speccy Library.
We'll see at the next section of the course.