Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to go over the solutions for the sentiment analysis Assessment Project.
Let's get started.
All right let's begin with Task 1 performing vector arithmetic on our own words.
We're gonna begin by importing spacey and then loading up the spacey language model.
So Spacey the load and then we're going to load in English core and you can either load in the large
or medium.
So I'm going to load in the large again if you download these smaller medium.
Go ahead and load that one up then we're gonna choose the words we wish to compare and obtain the vectors
and the way we do that is you simply call an LP the vocab and then almost like a dictionary call it
you're gonna ask for the word.
So let's go ahead and again your words may have been chosen differently but I'm gonna choose Wolf or
Wolf and then ask for the vector here and we'll say this is word one and then I'm going to copy paste
this command two more times rename this word two and word three and then let's ask for I'm going to
choose dog and cat.
So say dog and cat.
So my idea here is I'm going to see if I can take Wolf subtract dog from it and then add a cat and see
if the dimensions hold some sort of understanding that Wolf is essentially kind of an underestimated
version of a dog.
So hopefully if I subtract dog and then add a cat I can get some sort of underestimated version of cat
with my vector arithmetic.
We don't know for certain if that's going to work but we can definitely try it out.
So next we need to import from spatial that is from Spy import spatial and define a code similarity
function.
So we'll say from Spy import spatial spatial and here I'm just gonna do this as a lambda expression.
We'll say cosine Sim is equal to Lambda that takes in an X and Y.
Again this can also just be a normal function does it have to be lambda and we'll say 1 minus we'll
call spatial dot and then distance and then say dot cosine X come alive all right.
So there's a cosine similarity function.
Next we want to write an expression that actually calculates the new vector.
So we'll say if I can just copy what is written here you vector is equal to word one minus word two
plus word three doesn't have to be this exact or arithmetic you could do all addition or all subtraction.
Up to you.
But let's make sure we've defined word one up here by running that vector running this again.
Okay.
So now we have our new vector.
So if we take a look at this new vector it should just be some vector of three hundred dimensions so
you can check out a shape.
Now we have something here that mentions this new vector itself isn't a word vector.
It's some sort of earth metric based off these words.
So in order to find an actual vector that belongs to a word we want to find out what are the top 10
closest vectors in the vocabulary to this particular new vector.
So we're going to hear is saying computed sims or computed similarities.
And we'll go for every word in MLP vocab
will say if that particular word has a vector has not had so if that word has a vector.
And then if that word is lowercase and if that word is Alphabetic.
So it's not just the number we'll say is alpha then we will say its similarity is equal to the cosine
similarity function that we define and then we're simply going to pass in the new vector we calculated
against that particular word vector because we're going for every word inside our vocabulary is really
similar to what we did during the lectures.
And then we're going to grab our computed similarities or computed Sims list and append not just the
similarity but also the word associated with it.
So I'm going to say as a tuple nurse I have another set of princes here.
We'll say a word and then it's particular similar.
So word and same.
So you go ahead and run that and it's going to take a while to run because we're running through the
entire vocabulary and I have a really large vocabulary here because remember we're loading up the largest
basically possible language library.
So it's going to go through around I think it's around 600 to 800 thousand words there that we're running
through here.
Then once this is done in order to actually grab the most similar word vectors what we're going to do
here is say computed Sims is equal to the sorted computed Sims but we're going to sort by the similarity
value systems tuples here so we can do this by simply saying key lambda item and in order to get descending
order for similarity we'll say minus.
Item 1 so this item is essentially the tuple here and then we're sorting by index 1 the similarity and
we're doing descending indexing or descending slaughtering.
So we have the minus sign there.
Go ahead and run that and then let's check out our computed Sims particularly let's just check out the
first 10 here and we actually just want the text not the tuples themselves.
So we're gonna do a little bit of extra list comprehension here.
So we'll say prints and we're going to grab the word or essentially the token text for word in and then
we're just gonna print that out.
Okay.
So it looks like we still love wolf and wolves as really similar but know that because we added cap
we start getting more underestimated cat like things like a panther or lynx or a tiger.
We also get underestimated animals in general like owls but lions foxes and then again we get cat.
So adding cap and otter.
So it's really interesting that we first off we all got animals which makes a lot of sense given that
I'm passing in words wolf dog and cat but also just adding in that cat vector and subtracting the dog
component allows me to get things like Panther and Tiger.
So pretty interesting there.
I hope you had fun with your own arithmetic the next challenge was to write a function that takes in
three strings and performs this sort of similar arithmetic and essentially all you need to do is copy
and paste the code that we provided.
Well that we already work through here.
So the way we can do that is we can simply create our new vector so we can say something like new vector
is equal to and then we will just copy and paste what you wrote up here.
So a new vector is equal to word one minus word two plus word three.
There we go.
And then we'd have to calculate the word vectors of ABC and they're going to pass in as three strings.
So we just calculate them like this.
Copy and paste these guys.
So this essentially just so you can play around with this in an easier fashion in the future and then
instead of providing wolf dog crap you simply say
B and then C and notice I'm not providing them as strings I'm just providing them as the strings that
are or the variables that are being passed then so have what one or two or three are new calculated
vector and then we just copy and paste these last couple of cells here and you'll get the same result
and then make sure this is in or indented correctly and then we want to get our computed Sims right
here and then we're going to return this list or you can print it out whatever you want to do if this
particular function.
So can say return right here.
So if we run that and then run the vector math on King man and woman again this takes a little bit time
since this for loop takes a little bit of time but eventually you should see a list pop out of the 10
words so I'll let that run for a little bit while we start talking about task to task to was to perform
Vader sentiment analysis on our own review and this is actually pretty straightforward.
So here we go.
We see the results here.
King Queen Prince King's princess.
And so on.
But this one's pretty easy.
We just need to say from and I'll take that sentiment sentiment that Vader remember you need to download
Vader.
But we did that during lectures we'll take sentiment intensity analyzer and then say ASI D is equal
to sentiment intensity analyzer.
Create an instance of it.
Go ahead and write your own review as one continuous string.
So say this movie was absolutely awful the worst movie I have ever seen OK so pretty bad movie.
Then we're gonna do is we're going to obtain the S.A.T. scores for our review and then here we have
it.
So we have quite negative a little bit neutral but no positives of the compound score was just atrocious.
Now a challenge was to write a function that takes in a review and returns a score of either positive
negative and neutral.
Again pretty straightforward here.
All we need to do is calculate the scores as a dictionary by calling S.A.T. polarity scores on the string
that's passed in.
And then we simply say if the scores compound key member of the compound score if that's equal to zero
which is pretty unlikely but you never know you may have a truly neutral string you'll just say neutral
and then we'll say Elif the scores compound is greater than zero will return positive and then else
we'll return negative.
So here we have a function that will basically read in any review.
So go ahead and run this again and return back negative for our negative string review up here.
And keep in mind you can also set these values beyond zero.
Maybe you can have a threshold for neutral.
So you could say something like If this score compound is in between values negative zero point two
and positive zero point two.
Maybe that's your neutral range.
So you're only looking for really extreme negative or really extreme positive reviews.
So you can do that as well since typically your compound score will often be exactly zero.
It may be a better idea to provide a range of neutral score values.
OK.
So that's it.
Hope you enjoyed the assessment and I hope it felt more like a review of everything we covered in this
section.
I would encourage you to play around at these functions that you just created by performing more arithmetic
or testing out your own reviews.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next lecture.