Welcome back everyone to this lecture on stop it's words like and the appear so frequently in text that
they really don't require tagging as thoroughly as unique nouns verbs and modifiers.
We call these words stop words and they can be filtered from the text to be processed.
Spacey holds a built in list of some around hundred and five English Stop words so against upwards just
the really common words that don't really give you any additional information.
And sometimes they can actually hurt your natural language processing.
So a really common use case when you're working with the pipeline in natural language processing is
to remove stop words.
So we're going to show you how to remove Stoppard's with Spacey and we'll also show you how to add in
your own special stoppers in case maybe you're dealing with a unique dataset where you have an acronym
that gets used too much and you want to add that as a stop word.
So let's go ahead and show you how to do all that with Spacey.
OK here I am at the notebook.
I've imported Spacey and I have loaded up the English core web small language and what we can do here
is directly off this and opii object.
I can print out a.p dots defaults dot and then you can passen stop underscore words.
And if you run that it's going to give you this set.
So notice it's not a dictionary it's actually a set of all the Stoppard's that are built into spaces.
So again these are really common stop words and really common English words that typically don't give
you too much more information.
So the length of the actual object if you look at the length of and all the defaults stop words is 300
in five words and you can easily check if a word is a stop word by simply calling an LP vocab.
So I can say a.p the vocab and then I can pasan any word I'm interested in.
So for example let's use a really common word like is is going to return back this lexia object which
carries a lot of information.
And you can simply call is stop attribute and it's going to say true is is a stop word Let's go ahead
Adam more unique word like mystery.
Run that.
And that's false.
This is a unique enough word.
It's not that common.
So it is not a Stop word.
Now there may be times when you wish to add a stop word to the default set.
We just saw here above.
Perhaps you're working with text data like text messages and you see a lot of people using BT W for.
By the way.
So maybe you want that to be considered a stop word for your particular dataset.
So we can do this is all you need to do is call an LP defaults stop words and then you say ADD and you
add in the stop where they are interested in such as PTW then the next step is to manually grab again
an LP vocab passen be T.W. and say is underscore stop and set it equal to true.
You can go ahead and run that.
And if you actually check the length of an LP defaults.
Stop words you'll notice it's now 3 0 6.
So we went ahead and added beat W to our vocabulary of stop words and if you actually now check and
LP vocab for W and you ask is it actually a stop or it's going to return back.
True it is a Stop word or remember PTW was not in our original list here or original set of stop words.
If you want to remove a stop word so maybe you see a stop word here that you actually want to take into
account maybe via or someone or third These are actually important words to you and you wanted to remove
them from the set.
You apply a similar process we do hear you say LP defaults stop words and then you call remove any passing
whatever word you want to remove.
So maybe you want to remove beyond because that's technically a stop word in this original appear.
So I want to remove beyond and then what you end up doing is you call vocab
beyond.
And you say is stop and you said equal to false.
Essentially doing the reverse of what we just did for adding a stop word and now when you call in LP
vocab and ask for beyond and you ask is it a stop word.
It's going to return back false and that's really it.
Now you should be able to access bases defaults of Stoppard's and add or remove stop words as needed.
Coming up next we're going to talk about vocabulary and matching with Spacey.
We'll see at the next lecture.