Welcome back everyone.
And this lecture we're going to go through the solutions for the topic modeling Assessment Project.
Let's head over to the notebook and get started.
All right.
Here I am at the topic modeling Assessment Project notebook.
The first they're going to do is import pandas as PD and then read in that data set for Quora.
So PD that read and it's a CSP file and it's called Korac questions you should be able to tap autocomplete
this.
If not you'll need to provide the entire file path and then we can check the head of the state of frame
and you notice it's just a series of questions.
So if you ever wanted to grab one of these singular questions where you could do is simply from the
question column grab any index.
So what is step by step guide to invest in share market.
India is the first question.
So for pre-processing it's pretty straightforward.
We simply say from S-K learn the feature extraction thought text import T.F. IDF vectorize or then we'll
create it.
Let's create an instance of our vectorize or T.F. IDF and we'll say T.F. idea of vectorize or and you
can play around with the max document frequency values will say we're looking for terms that show up
at our max docking at frequencies 95 percent.
So kind of drop the 5 percent most frequent terms since those probably aren't conducive to any particular
topic.
SR so common and then also essentially remove any words unique to any documents by saying that the words
show up at least in two documents and also pasand upwards English English.
There we go.
And then we'll create our document matrix.
Again it's not really a dominant term matrix we're also performing T.F. IDF on it but it's just to keep
things in line.
What we did before Deif IDF and then we fit transform on the article or on the question column here
so run that and at the end you should see a matrix with 400 and 4000 ish questions and then around 40000
words.
Now it's time for non-negative matrix factorization.
If you want you can also perform LDA but LDH takes quite a bit of time.
So we're going to stick with an MF sual say from Skillern about the composition import and F. We'll
create an instance of a MF model by calling an MF saying number of components.
And here we specifically asked for 20 topics and if you want make sure the topics are lined up the same
way I have them here.
Go ahead and put in random state is equal to 42.
Again the number 42 is completely arbitrary.
It's just to make sure that your random values are the same as mine.
Setting a random seed and then it's time to actually fit the model so we will fit the model to our documentary
matrix and then we're going to print out our top 15 most common words for each of the topics.
So I'll go ahead and get started on this while that's fitting.
I will say for index topic in enumerate and IMF model and IMF underscore model components underscore
we're going to do is we'll just print out that top 15 words a line using some string literals will say
the top 15 words for topic number and then we'll pass an index and that's the current topic number we're
on.
And then we'll use less comprehension just like we did before.
We simply grab that TAF IDF T.F. IDF object and then we're going to say get under score feature underscore
names and then grab it at index eye for eye in topic loops in topic and recall we are sort.
And then if we want the last 15 we say from negative 15 all the way to the end and then we're going
to print out a new line.
All right.
So as I previously mentioned this is a much bigger file than before.
So an IMF model is still going to take a while LDA will take even longer.
Someone quickly hop forward in time until this is done training.
OK so that's done training for me now.
It took several minutes and I have a pretty fast computer so it may take you longer depending on your
hardware.
If you have a really slow or small hardware computer there's a possibility of getting a memory error
here.
And if that's the case there's really nothing you can do except either take a subset of that data set
or get better hardware.
So let me run this next topic and we can see here the top 15 words.
So here are the various topics we found.
Number two.
Number three and so on.
So the last thing to do is actually connect these topic numbers to the questions themselves.
So remember our original data frame looks like this.
And we want it to look something like that.
And then we can do this.
It's pretty straightforward.
We simply say something like Topic results is equal to an MF model and we're going to transform our
original DTM and then we're going to say topic results and Graham the max coefficient value along access
equal to 1 and then we'll say Corra topic is equal to topic results.
RMX is equal to 1.
Actually we could just say that this is something else whip's kind of wrote this line twice there.
So core topic topic results are maximal to 1.
So if you run that and then check the head of the data frame that should have matched up the topic based
on the index this for the questions.
And we can see here if you use the same random state as I did the first three topics would be 5 16 and
17.
Again that's only if you happen to use the same or in them they did.
OK.
So that's it for this project.
Hopefully you can see now it's pretty straightforward to perform topic modeling and psychic learns has
a lot of convenient functions for you to use.
And really all of this is essentially it looks like just around 15 cells.
So just a few lines of code in order to perform topic modeling on a really large dataset.
Thanks.
And that concludes the topic modeling section will see at the next section of the course.