Hello and welcome to this module of Collecting Data on
AWS: Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose.
My name is Fernando Medina Corey,
and in this module we'll look in Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose in depth
and learn how we can leverage it for our data collection needs. To
start, we'll be looking at some basic concepts surrounding Kinesis
Firehose. We'll look at records, buffers,
destination, and data retention.
Then we'll look at Firehose's limits, what it can do and what it can't do.
After that,
we'll look at how we can use data transformations with Kinesis Firehose,
visualize some of those transformations, and look at how we could use Lambda to
transformation data and a few examples of using Lambda.
From there,
we'll look at Kinesis Firehose producers that send data into
Kinesis Firehose, and Firehose destinations,
or where the data will end up when Firehose is done with it.
After that,
we'll look at a demo, creating a Firehose delivery stream inside of the
AWS console. And we look at a few examples of when to use Firehose versus
Data Streams, to make sure that we understand which Kinesis service is
appropriate for which situation. So let's get started in the next video.