So before we learn more about collecting data on AWS,
let's see why we'd want to learn about AWS data services.
Let's look both for the benefits for ourselves and our careers and the
benefits that they might have for our organizations. To get started for
us, we might be interested to know that AWS data services are among the
top highest paid skills included in a Dice 2020 salary survey that they
were sending out to see what the top technology skills were and how they
were compensated.
Among the top 20, five of the 20 skills were
related to AWS and AWS data services.
In addition,
one of the top compensated roles of data engineer saw a
9.3% salary growth from 2019 to 2020.
So it looks like this trend of high pay for these skills isn't going
anywhere. Now you also might want to learn more about AWS data services
if you're preparing for AWS certificates, like the Data Analytics
certification or the Databases certification.
Knowing about AWS data collection technologies is pretty useful
when you're preparing for many of the different AWS
certifications. Now, for your organization's,
why would we think about using AWS data services? Well,
one of the first key reasons is that AWS is still the public cloud
leader and has many services and capabilities that are still far beyond
what the other cloud providers currently offer.
Now, of course,
there's specifications depending on which cloud provider has a particular
service that you might really benefit from, but overall,
AWS still leads that area.
In addition, when you're using AWS data services,
you'll be able to integrate those with a full platform of other
integrations and services inside of AWS while still taking advantage
of many open source tools and technologies.
You wouldn't necessarily get this from single tools or
other providers with smaller footprints.
So now that you have a better personal understanding and organizational
understanding of why we might want to learn about AWS data services, let's dive into looking more about the Amazon Kinesis family.