Let's look at some of the producers we can use to send
data into Kinesis Data Firehose.
There's some overlap between the Kinesis Data Streams
and Kinesis Data Firehose producers,
and I'm not going to waste your time by going over all the same ones over again,
but let's briefly recap what those are.
First, there's the Kinesis Agent, the AWS SDKs,
and Kinesis Data Streams themselves.
Now, with the Kinesis Agent,
we already learned about how we can use that to put it on an EC2 instance,
for example,
to send log data and pre‑process that before it gets
over to a Kinesis Data Stream or, in this case,
Kinesis Firehose.
The AWS SDKs give us a lot of customization about how we send data in,
directly by putting information to the Kinesis Firehose
with a PutRecord or PutRecords operation.
And,
we learned about Kinesis Data Streams themselves in previous
videos and how they can be used to collect information and
then send it over to a consumer.
Now, in this case,
we can use Kinesis Data Streams themselves to feed
data into Kinesis Data Firehose.
But now, let's also look at some producers that are specific to Kinesis Firehose.
First, there's the CloudWatch Logs subscriptions option.
Now, this allows you to send data that's going into CloudWatch Logs,
for example,
metrics coming from an EC2 instance that's being sent to CloudWatch Logs,
or custom metrics, or records and logs that are being sent there,
and then take that data and process it with Kinesis Data
Firehose and move it to a destination.
There's also the option to use CloudWatch Logs Events rules in
a similar way that you could use the CloudWatch Logs
subscriptions to send data directly into Kinesis Firehose and
then process that in the same way.
Additionally, there is the option to use AWS IoT,
or the Internet of Things, platform rules,
to send data from IoT devices coming into AWS' IoT suite and IoT
home of products to go then to Kinesis Firehose for processing
and to send to a destination like S3,
or other destinations to be stored for long‑term availability.
Now, if you want to learn more about AWS IoT,
you could check out one of the courses that I have here on
Pluralsight that goes over AWS IoT in more detail.
But for right now,
let's look at each of these cases and see how they work in practice.
Let's start with CloudWatch Logs subscriptions.
With CloudWatch Log subscriptions, we have our Kinesis Firehose,
and then we also have CloudWatch Logs.
Then, we create a subscription between CloudWatch Logs and Kinesis Firehose.
And then, when we have an EC2 instance that sends data into CloudWatch Logs,
it'll be recorded there.
We might also have other services like AWS Lambda sending
information over to CloudWatch Logs.
After that,
this data will go through the subscription over to Kinesis Firehose where
it can then be taken and sent over to a destination.
Now again, this destination could be a variety of different,
specifically configured destinations that we'll cover in just a bit.
We could also use AWS IoT rules using the AWS IoT
Rules Engine to send this data over.
We do something pretty similar where we create a rule that
associates the Rules Engine and the Firehose.
And then we have a bunch of different IoT devices that might be
sending data into our IoT home inside of AWS,
and then this data is then picked up by the Rules Engine
and sent over to Kinesis Firehose.
From there, we do the exact same thing and send the data over to our destination.
Keep both these newer producers of data in mind when
you're working with Amazon Kinesis,
as well as the existing producers that we covered in
the Kinesis Data Stream section,
as they can both be used with Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose. Next up, we'll look at Kinesis Data Firehose destinations.