Now let's look at how we can send data to Amazon
Redshift using Kinesis Firehose.
First, let's set up a similar example to our earlier videos.
In this case,
we'll have data in a Kinesis Firehose, and we'll have an intermediate S3
bucket where we send data into before it goes to Redshift.
Now, finally, we'll have our Redshift cluster set up and ready to adjust data.
The first thing that'll happen is the data will fill up either a buffer size,
or the buffer interval in Kinesis Firehose will run out.
Then that data will be sent over to the intermediate bucket.
Now,
this data will stay in this S3 bucket until a Redshift COPY
command is run from inside Redshift to take this intermediate S3
bucket data and put it into Redshift.
Now,
if any data isn't successfully copied into Redshift and we have some
sort of error when we're trying to send it in,
then that data would still be stored inside of S3, and we'd be able to
review any errors that we had when sending it in.
Now, in another example with Redshift,
we might start with some data inside of Kinesis Firehose,
and we might want to transform this data before we send it along.
We would use AWS Lambda again to take this data into
Lambda functions and process it.
And when we do this,
we would also once again have either successfully processed data
or records we want to drop because they're irrelevant and we
don't want to send them into Redshift.
And this would happen in our processing.
Or,
we might also have failures come up when we're trying to
process the data but aren't able to.
Now, with this,
we would then send our successful records and any
failures over to two different places,
and we would drop the dropped records and not include them anywhere.
Now the successful records would go into the intermediate
bucket before being copied into Redshift.
And those failed records, where we weren't able to transform them,
would just stay inside of the S3 bucket, and then we would
look at them later to see why they failed.
Now, for another example, we might add a little bit more complexity here,
where we'd have an intermediate S3 bucket and a backup bucket for our data.
We'd have the data come into Kinesis Firehose,
and we'd take a copy of it and put it inside of the backup
S3 bucket without changing anything.
Then,
we could still go through the entire process of
transforming our data inside of AWS Lambda,
where we'd use the Lambda function to process everything in
there and either get successfully processed,
dropped records,
or failed records over from Kinesis Firehose into the
intermediate bucket and, finally, over to the Redshift cluster.
So, now you know a few of the different ways we can use Kinesis Firehose,
AWS Lambda, and how we'll use S3 to get data from Kinesis Firehose into Amazon Redshift.