In this example,
we'll be looking at how to get data from Kinesis Firehose into Splunk,
a third‑party tool that allows you to visualize and analyze your data.
Now, we'll start in a very similar scenario to previous examples
with a Kinesis Firehose that's ingesting some data.
Once we fill up our buffer size or the buffer interval runs out,
we'll try and send our data over into Splunk.
Now,
in any cases when we have data that's unable to be sent into Splunk,
we'll then send that data over to S3 so we can look at it and determine
why it wasn't able to send into Splunk, and what the failures were when
we tried to do that. With Splunk,
we can do many of the same things that we did with earlier destinations.
When data goes into Kinesis Firehose,
we can send it over to AWS Lambda, and from here we can then have this
data be processed in the same ways we were doing earlier,
where it gets processed and then comes back as either a successfully
processed record, a dropped record or a failed transformation.
From there, we take the dropped records out,
send our records that are successfully transformed into Splunk, and send
our failed transformation records into an S3 bucket so we can look at them
in more detail. Now we could also do the same thing we were doing in
earlier sections, where we take a copy of the data and store it in an S3
bucket without making any changes.
At this point,
we could either send the data directly to Splunk and see if
there's any failures, and store those failures in S3, or we could
take the exact same approach we were doing just a second ago by
sending the data over to Lambda,
having it be processed and returned to us, and then having that
data either go from Kinesis Firehose directly into Splunk if it
was a successfully processed item, or over to an S3 bucket if it
was a failed transformation.
So now that you know how to use Kinesis Firehose in
combination with multiple destinations, let's take a look at a hands‑on demo using Kinesis Firehose in the AWS console.