Now let's take a closer look at another member of the Amazon Kinesis family,
Amazon Kinesis Video Streams.
So what's the purpose of Kinesis Video Streams?
Well, it's a tool designed to help simplify the process of streaming video data.
It can start by helping you stream video from a variety of sources and devices.
Then,
it can help you process the data with a variety of tools to make it
easier to analyze and interact with video data using things like machine
learning or other tools to do object detection.
Finally, it can help you store data from your video streams.
This has a wide range of applications,
but maybe especially relevant for IoT devices with video capabilities.
When it comes to using Amazon Kinesis Video Streams,
there's really two key toolsets to be aware of.
The Producer libraries for Video Streams allow you to easily
set up devices to send video data to AWS.
They help provide a set of libraries to configure with your video software,
and you can do this when working with Java,
Android, or C++.
Now, the Consumer libraries are their counterpart,
where you can use them to parse information coming in from the video streams.
They can help send video data into machine learning
algorithms for image detection or help you parse video data for storage and something like Amazon S3.