Let's look at a demo involving Amazon Kinesis.
Now a quick warning.
This is not included inside of the AWS Free tier,
so some of these services that you're using will leverage
things that AWS will actually charge you for.
So if you decide to go through with it in your own
AWS account that you're paying for,
just be sure that you delete the services after you're done with this demo
to make sure you don't keep getting charged for them.
First,
we'll be looking at creating a Firehose delivery
stream inside of the AWS console.
We'll create a Kinesis data stream source for that Firehose delivery stream,
and then we'll use a script to send data into the data stream so that it
will then go to the Firehose delivery stream after that.
Now we're of course,
going to have to create the Firehose delivery stream
inside of the AWS console and configure with the Kinesis
data stream that we also created,
but we'll also create a Lambda function that we
configure with Firehose to process the data.
We'll use that to transform data from JSON format to CSV.
In this example,
we'll be imagining that the Globomantics finance team needs the
data in CSV format because that's something they're a bit more
comfortable with than the JSON format,
in order to put it into something like Excel and let them
process the data and run their own analysis on it.
So we'll need to take this data and output it to S3,
where we're going to assume that there's an application waiting
to provide it to those finance professionals.
So let's go ahead and get started by jumping into the AWS console now.
Over here in the AWS console we'll go to the Services
drop‑down and then look for Kinesis.
We'll click on the Kinesis button here, and in this new window,
we can either click Create data stream with the Kinesis Data Streams selected,
or we can go over the left side here and click into the Data streams section.
From here,
we're still going to need to create our first data stream if we haven't already.
Now, in this case,
I'm going to make sure to name my stream the exact same
thing that's in my code for this demo.
Let's take a look at this now.
Inside the code for this section,
you'll see that we haven't in index.py file and a streamer.py file.
Now inside of this streamer.py file we'll be using this to
send data into a stream that we create, a Kinesis data stream,
not a Firehose delivery stream.
So we'll need to make sure that the stream name in this file, in
this case it's currently listed as sales, is the same as the stream
name we give to our Kinesis data stream.
We'll also need to make sure that it's in the same AWS region.
In this case,
you can see it's in us‑east‑1, so we'll need to make sure this is
the same region that we're in in the AWS console.
So let's go back to the AWS console now and create our stream.
We'll call it sales, and then because we we're in the northern Virginia region,
this means that work in the correct region in this case,
in us‑east‑1.
But just make sure those two things line up for you as well.
From here,
we can scroll down a little bit and determine how
many shards we want in this stream.
In this case, I want the cheapest stream possible,
so I'm going to type in 1 here.
Now, this will still be outside of the AWS Free tier,
so make sure you delete this stream once you're done
to avoid getting a bill for it.
Now let's scroll down and make sure that we have 1 selected here when
we're creating our stream because we could accidentally select a lot more
than 1 and end up getting charged a lot more.
But with that selected, we can click Create data stream.
Now, this might take a minute, but once it's created,
we'll be able to use it in configuration with a delivery stream as well.
So now that it's been created,
we can go over to the delivery stream section to configure this Kinesis
data stream as an input source for a new data firehose.
So once were in the Data Firehose section,
we can scroll down and click Create delivery stream.
From here we'll need to give our delivery stream a name.
This is less important than what we named our Kinesis data stream.
Let's call our delivery stream salestoS3,
since we'll be sending the Kinesis data stream called sales over into Amazon S3.
Now let's scroll down and choose a source that we're going to be using.
In this case, we're not going to be using a direct put,
so we'll need to select the Kinesis data stream that we just created.
And under this we'll need to select that particular stream.
So we'll click sales here, and then we'll scroll down a little bit further.
Now that we've got all that configured,
we can click Next for the next section to determine how
we might want to process records.
In this case,
we do want to process the records because they'll be coming
in as JSON from our Kinesis data stream and the things that
are sending data into that, and we'll want to transform them into a CSV.
So let's click Enabled here, and instead of choosing a Lambda function,
let's create a new one.
Now,
you can use any of the blueprints here because we're actually going
to be modifying the function that we're using.
So let's start with the General Kinesis Data Firehose Processing function.
Let's just give this a name of sales‑proc for sales processing.
Now, I'm going to scroll down and we'll be able to create this function.
Currently,
we can't modify much that's inside of it because we're in the
process of building it out from a template.
But once it's created, we can go back in and edit it.
So now that the function is created,
we can scroll down in this configuration section,
and we'll change a few things about our function.
Actually, instead of JavaScript and Node.js code,
I want to run a Python function,
so I'm to select the most recent version of Python,
which at the time here is Python 3.8.
Now going to change this index.js file from index.js to index.py.
Now the last thing I'm going to need to change is the
code that's currently in index.py.
So let's go over to my VS Code editor where I've
copied the files for this module.
Inside of here, instead of the streamer code,
we're going to want to go up to the index.py file to
copy the code for the Lambda handler.
Let's copy the entire chunk of code here and then go back to the AWS
console to paste it into the index.py file and then hit Save.
Inside of this code,
it's going to process all the records coming in from the Kinesis data stream,
and then it's going to take those records and change them from JSON
format by loading the JSON in with the JSON library from Python and
then output them as a CSV by adding the comma separation between the
values that was in the JSON.
From there,
it's going to send them out as the output record format here back out to
Kinesis Firehose to let it know how to deliver it into Amazon S3.
So with this all saved,
we should be able to use this function inside of our Kinesis Firehose.
So let's go back here for now, and let's click Close,
and now we should be able to choose our Lambda function
from a list of functions in our account.
Now I have a bunch here right now, but we can search for the one we just made,
which in this case was sales‑proc.
So let's select that one here and make sure we have the latest
version of our function selected from this drop‑down.
If we had any other versions, they might appear here,
but we're going to stick with that most recently updated one.
So now I'm going to scroll down even further.
And you'll notice that there's this alert that's warning
us about our timeout for a function.
What this is saying is essentially that we might be
sending a lot of data into Lambda,
and it might need more than 3 seconds to process that data,
which is currently with the timeout is set for this Lambda function.
So to change this, we'll want to go back to our Lambda function,
go over to the settings for this even further below the code,
and when we see the basic settings, we'll be able to edit those.
And here we'll need to change the timeout,
let's say from 3 seconds up to 3 full minutes.
Now, after that, I can scroll down and hit Save,
and this Lambda function should be able to spend more
time processing the data if it needs it.
From here, we can go back to the Kinesis Firehose section,
scroll down even further, and then click the Next button.
From here we'll need to pick the destination that we want.
Now these are all the destination options that we
talked about in the previous videos.
In this case, I'm going to leave Amazon S3 selected,
as it's where we want this data to go for our Globomantics finance team users.
So let's scroll down even further and set up a bucket for them.
Now in this case I want to use a new bucket so I'll click Create new.
So I'm going to name my bucket sales‑bucket‑globomantics‑12.
Now, in your case,
you're going to want to name this something completely different.
It can be your name, your favorite animal, and some gibberish alongside of that.
It doesn't really matter, as long as it conforms to S3 bucket naming conventions.
Really, just use some dashes, letters, and numbers,
and as long as you keep the dashes after the first character,
you should be pretty good to go.
So once you're done naming this bucket, you can click Create S3 bucket.
Now that the bucket is created and we've configured our Lambda function,
we should be able to scroll down to the very bottom and just
click Next in order to get things rolling.
From here, we have the last few settings that we need to set,
the buffer size, which we've talked about a lot before.
In this case,
I'm going to bring it down to 1 so that we can make sure that it's
going to send data over as quickly as possible.
And I'm also going to set the buffer interval down to the minimum of 60 seconds.
This means that at a minimum, we'll see the data in 60 seconds or less.
So now that we have these last configuration options set,
we'll scroll down to the bottom again and need to set up on IAM role.
You might have to click this depending on if you already have an
IAM role created to use for Kinesis Firehose.
I'm going to click Create new or choose,
and this will direct me over to Identity and Access Management.
It should create a role for me or allow me to pick one from this drop‑down here.
In this case, it's already prepopulated the role,
so I'm going to click Allow. Now once I do this,
we should be able to use this Firehose delivery role in
combination with my Kinesis Firehose, so I'm going to click Next
again, and we'll review the last bit of configuration and
finally click Create delivery stream.
So now that our delivery stream is being created,
we should be able to see the data inside of S3 as soon as it gets sent over to
the Kinesis data stream, gets ingested by the Kinesis Firehose, processed by the Lambda function, and then eventually sent to S3.