The first thing we need to do before anything there can
happen is go back to our VS Code editor here.
Now, in this case, we're going to be running the streamer.py function,
which is going to send data into the Kinesis Stream we created using a
very similar format to a previous demo we looked at.
In order to do this, I'm going to use python3.
In this case,
I'll start with python3 ‑m venv and venv again to create a virtual
environment to store our Python dependencies in.
Now,
this will help us avoid polluting our global installation of
Python and its dependencies by creating this virtual
environment to do everything inside of.
On a Windows machine,
you might have a different command you need in order to
turn this virtual environment on, but on Mac or Linux,
you should be able to run the source command and then run venv/bin/activate.
Now,
typing that in and pressing Enter should put the parentheses
in venv in front of your terminal here,
and that means that you've successfully activated it.
On a Windows machine,
just reference the cheat sheet of commands that I have for this module.
That explains the different options that you have for activating venv,
either in the command prompt or in PowerShell.
Now that I've turned this on,
I can use pip install to create dependencies in this virtual environment.
In this case,
I want to install boto3 because that's one thing we'll be
using inside of this streamer.py file.
You can see that if you scroll to the top and see the import of boto3 on line 1.
Now, with this all imported, let's clear the screen,
and then let's start running this script by doing
python and then typing in streamer.py.
Now that I hit Enter,
it should start streaming data into our Kinesis Data Stream.
Now, if we're wondering if this is working or not,
it might take up to 60 seconds for the data to go through the
Kinesis Data Stream over to our Kinesis Firehose and get
buffered inside of the Kinesis Firehose,
either with the buffer size of the buffer interval,
and then sent over to S3 after it's been processed by Lambda.
So let's try and take a look at this now.
Fortunately, in the Firehose section,
it makes it pretty easy for us to look at all the different resources.
I could look at the Lambda function that's actually processing the data.
I could also go to the source itself to see what's
happening in our upstream Kinesis Data Stream.
And I can go to the destination to see whether or not
the data has already arrived there.
So, let's look at the Lambda function first,
just to see if in the Monitoring section we have anything going on.
And it looks like we haven't had anything start quite yet,
so give it a moment,
and we'll see how long it takes in order to send the data over.
After refreshing the page and waiting for about 60 seconds to a few minutes,
we should start to see some data coming into our Lambda view here.
Now,
this means that our Lambda function is successfully processing
some things inside of our files that are going through the Kinesis
Data Stream over to Kinesis Firehose.
So we should be able to close this out and then go to the S3
bucket that's respective to our Kinesis Firehose.
Inside of here,
we should be able to open up the folders that start with the year,
month, and then day of whatever day we're processing things on.
Then we'll have the hour in UTC time, and finally,
a bunch of different files that have been processed by Lambda.
Now, I've been waiting for a few minutes to make sure that some appear here,
so we can go ahead and download the latest one.
So now that I have this sales data downloaded,
let's open it up in our browser to see what it looks like.
It looks like it's correctly output into CSV format here,
and if we wanted to,
we could give this directly to our data analysts to start letting them
review how many shirts have been sold in this period,
and give them the ability to interact with it in their native CSV format,
and the tools that they like using,
like Excel and other spreadsheet tools like that.
So, congratulations, you've just managed to put together a Kinesis Data Stream,
Kinesis Firehose,
and AWS lambda‑based application to stream data into Kinesis Data Streams,
process it with Data Firehose in the AWS Lambda, and then deliver it to Amazon S3.