Let's take a closer look at Amazon Direct Connect.
First,
let's look at what Amazon Direct Connect is, it's a
dedicated network connection between your own on‑premises
infrastructure and the AWS Cloud.
You'll be able to use it to get virtual interfaces to AWS services
and it'll help you to bypass some of the ISPs in your network path to
AWS giving you a more direct route to AWS services and your own
infrastructure inside of the cloud.
Now this requires that we have a partner in order to use to connect more
directly with AWS. Some of these partners include CenturyLink,
A,T&T, Cologix, and many others depending on the region that
you're trying to connect to inside of AWS. These partners will be
dependent on the region. For example,
there are different partners in US‑East1, Northern Virginia
than there are inside of AWS's Oregon regions. Now there
might be a little bit of overlap, but when you're using Direct Connect,
you're going to need to specify which ones you want to work with in
order to get your data from your local on‑premises environment into
the cloud. So what are some of the configuration options that we have
when working with Direct Connect?
Well, we have multiple different speed configurations that we can use.
We can have anywhere from a 50 MB connection to a 10 GB connection
that goes directly from our on‑premises environment through a
co‑location provider directly to the AWS Cloud.
And then when we're getting that connection,
we can then access VPCs in the same region as our on‑premises environment.
Now,
if we needed to access other regions inside of VPCs, we need to
make that possible with VPC peering between regions. But if we
don't need to access services in a VPC,
we can access any region's public AWS API endpoints while
we're using this direct connect connection.
So why would we want to use direct connect and what are some of the
potential benefits that we get when working with it?
Well,
it's going to allow us to potentially reduce our
network costs from that ISP. Now,
this is something that you'd have to take into account if you have high
bandwidth costs or you have ISPs that charge you significantly more when
you're working with them to get data into AWS over the public internet. When
you're working with the Direct Connect, it might be possible that the speed
and benefits you get from it, along with the reductions and cost,
might be able to balance some of the spending that you have for it.
Now a big part of this is that Direct Connect will build data at a lower
rate than the traditional data transfer rates of AWS.
So when you're doing all the math on calculating this,
you'll have to think about how much data you're transferring at
AWS's standard data transfer rates versus how much you'd be
transferring at the reduced Direct Connect rates.
In addition to these potential cost benefits,
you also might get some more network consistency. Because you're avoiding the
public internet infrastructure and all of the additional hops that go through
different servers and routers on their way to AWS,
you might get some benefits from avoiding those.
This direct connect option allows you to use Ethernet cables and
hardware in order to plug in directly to co‑location providers
that have more direct access to AWS.
Skipping some of those hops and being able to take this sort of approach can provide better network consistency.