Before we're able to use the Database Migration Service to
move our data from our databases into AWS,
we need to understand the concept of sources and targets.
Now these concepts are relatively straightforward.
A database source is where you're getting the data
from and where it is right now.
This could be an on‑premises environment or another cloud or even another
database inside of AWS that you're migrating between.
There's also the concept of a target.
Targets are where you want to move your data to.
Now there are a lot of different sources and targets that we
might want to use when working with DMS.
Let's take a look at a few of them here.
One of the first options is a source like Oracle,
which can actually be both a source and a target.
If you want to move data from something elsewhere inside of an Oracle database,
you could also move it into AWS inside of an Oracle database.
And there's a few examples of this,
like Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, and PostgreSQL. These
can all be either a source or a target.
Now let's take a look at some other options that might be different in that
respect in that they can only be a source or a target.
First, there's the option of MariaDB,
and it's another popular open source database.
But there are other options, like Db2 LUW, SAP, and MongoDB,
which are other frequently used databases.
Now if we wanted to move some of those into AWS,
we need to end up picking some sort of target inside
of AWS that isn't one of those.
Now there's also the option to use Amazon Aurora as a source and
migrated over into one of these targets inside of AWS.
Now if you're using Amazon Aurora, technically,
it's already inside of AWS, but you can migrate it between other options there.
Now what are some of the options that can only be targets?
Well, you might want to move things over to Amazon Redshift,
especially if you're using some sort of data warehousing applications that you
want to be able to run queries on large amounts of data and get some analytics
back. Now you might also use things like SAP ASE or,
if you want to store more data in an object‑style format,
something like Amazon S3 can be really useful.
You can use it with other tools like AWS Glue or Amazon Athena.
Or you can just keep your data around in pretty cheap storage for a long time.
Other options for more structured access to your data would
be something like Amazon's DynamoDB tool,
which is a NoSQL offering that gives you really low latency to access your data.
Now if you want a full understanding of what the different sources and
targets are and which ones of them are supported,
I've left the link below that you can check out any time to see what the
newest and best supported sources and targets are for DMS. Now one
important distinction to make with these sources and targets is that
there are two kinds of migration types,
and this might come up in AWS exams or just when you're talking with
other people about database migration and AWS. The first is a
homogeneous database migration where you're moving from something like
a MySQL database into AWS, but it's still a MySQL database. So,
essentially, you're moving the same kind of database from one location
to another location.
Now there's another kind of migration that you might
use called a heterogeneous migration.
Now this might be something like moving a SQL database into a NoSQL tool
like DynamoDB, or it could be moving one SQL database from one SQL database
tool like MySQL to another SQL database tool.
So now that you know a bit more about sources and targets,
as well as the different types of migrations we can have
between those sources and targets,
meaning homogeneous or heterogeneous migrations, let's look at how the replication actually happens in the next video.