So now that we know some of the basics of Snowball Edge,
let's try and visualize it.
First,
let's think about a manufacturing process where we have a bunch of
different machines that are all sending data,
and we want to collect this data and be able to analyze it.
Now, if we wanted to send this data over to AWS,
we might send it through a router on our local environment.
But,
what happens if we have either a spotty Wi‑Fi connection or we
have some other reason why it's difficult to send this much data
through our limited bandwidth to AWS?
Well, in that case,
we might get a Snowball Edge device delivered to our local environment.
And then,
we could send all this data into that local Snowball Edge device that
lives in the same warehouse as our manufacturing process,
for example.
And,
we could use the device to process this information before we send it to AWS.
For example, if we have a lot of redundant information,
we might take an aggregation of all of our machines, and
instead of sending in three times the data,
we could take all of the outputted data from our machines and
then squish it together before we send it over to AWS once our
Wi‑Fi is either reestablished, if we had a spotty connection, or
we're done aggregating it,
just to save ourself space after we send it into the cloud.
So now that we have a better idea of how Snowball Edge works,
let's take a closer look at when we'd use Snowball Edge versus something like Direct Connect.