We've done a lot in this module.
We learned a bit about Amazon Direct Connect and how we
can use it to get direct access to AWS, not using the public internet.
We also learned how we can use Snowball Edge and Snowmobile
to either send data into AWS or to process data at the Edge
inside of our own locations.
And, we learned how we might want to use these different services in
different scenarios and when they're most appropriate.
Now, in the next module,
we'll be taking a look at the AWS Database Migration Service,
which is another great option if we have data inside of a database
of some kind and we want to move it into AWS. So I hope to see you there.