Hello and welcome back. Today we're going
to solve the homework exercise for the
law of large numbers. Let's get straight
into it so this is our exercise. Let's
just quickly
refresh what it was about. Test the
law of large numbers for N random
normally distributed numbers with mean
of the zero as a division of one
and that means create an R script that
will count how many of these numbers
fall between minus 1 and 1 and divide
by the total quantity of N. You know
that the expected value of many of your
measurement is 68.2 percent, check
that the mean of the actually measured
value is converging to the expected
value as you rerun your script while
increasing N. So that was exercise and
let's get straight into it, stick into
the code.
Ok, so here I've got R studio and I've
got a blank new script and we're going
to create this solution together first
thing we need is R norm function as
you remember we used Rnorm with the
value of one right.  So we ran Rnorm
like that and it would generate us a new
random variable from a normally
distributed sample every single time
right. So now what we want is we want a
hundred of those variables so to do that
we need to replace the one with a
hundred and what we'll get is a vector or a
hundred of those numbers. So you can see
all them here, so first on second and
third fourth fifth and then sixth and one and
that's what this actually six represents
here, 6,7,8,9,10 and 11 and so on. So
here we have our 100 normally
distributed variables, great! So now we need
to create a cycle through or a loop
through all of these numbers for in
order to do that we need a for loop
right? So let's create a for loop and as
you remember we need a for then we go
we say I, in  and what did we say we used
to say 1 to 10 or something like that
right? So then we've got to the curly
brackets right. So we used to create
loops like that and what was this?
Well we knew that this was a vector of
ten numbers, so in this case we were
cycling this index through these 10
numbers. What we want to do now is we want
to replace that vector with the
vector that we actually want to cycle
through with the R norm vector, so we
want I to go through all of these
numbers that we've created here and bear
in mind that every time we re-run this
script it will be a different hundred
numbers, so when I to go through all of
these numbers and then we'll do
something we find that, so hopefully that
makes sense so far.
Let's start typing up in the body of
this for loop so here we're going to say
if right we want to check does I fall
between minus 1 and 1 so we're going to
type this up and I'll explain it, so I is
greater than minus 1 and I is less than
one right and then we'll have the body
of our if statement. Now the very
interesting thing here is that
especially for those of you who come
from a programming background who
programmed even at least once in any
other programming language what you'll
notice is that here we're actually using
the I letter itself or rather you've been
using the I letters and index. So in
another programming language you would
hypothetically write something like this
A, I is greater than one and A, I is a
less than greater than minus 1 is less
than one and that's if you're cycling is
you using I as an index to go through an
area and let's say a was this like all
this of course is completely incorrect
but hypothetically if this was your array
you would be running through it but what
we're doing here is very different.
We even though we're creating a loop I
is not our index. Even though it has it's
the letter I what what it's doing this
variable I is it's actually taking the
values of these normal variables and one
normally distributed random variable
that we generating. I is taking them one by
one so in the first iteration I will be
equal to this.
I won't be equal to 1. It won't be equal
to 2 3 4 5 it's not an index. It will be
actually taking the actual value so I
will be equal to 0.75 in the first iteration,
in the second iteration I will be
equal to minus 1.26. It won't be equal to 1.877
and so on. So every single
iteration I will be assuming one of
these values that we have generate. So
the next consecutive value and so that's
why we're actually operating with y. We want
to check if the value itself is greater
than minus one or less than one. If it makes
things easier for you you might want
while you're learning this and getting
used to the second because it took me
personally took me quite a while to get
used to this like first I wrap my
head around this was going on was I not
an index but then to get used to it. So
you might want to change the letter I to
say X or something that so that way you
won't be tempted to think of I as an
index but we'll just keep it as I for
now just for consistency consistency
purposes and what do we want to do now?
Now we found out
yes if this condition is true I is
indeed between minus 1 and 1.
What do we want to do inside this if
statement? What do we want to tell R to
do well? We're what are we doing we're
counting the number of these, the
quantity help these numbers that full
between minus 1 and 1 right? Went to know
how many of them are there so this one
would fall in there this one wouldn't
this one wouldn't. This one wouldn't fall in
there.
This order for this so we want to count
them. How do we count them? Well we already
done an exercise like this before, we
need a counter variable so we need a
counter variable that starts with zero
before we even launched this loop but
then every time we find one of these
variables that we are interested in we
got increase the counter variable by 1
right. So we're going to say counter is
whatever counter was before in the
previous iteration plus 1, so in the
first iteration as soon as we find
they're not in iteration as soon as we
find one of these variables counter will
be increased from 0, it will be 0 plus 1,
will become 1 then the next iteration or
the next time we find another one of
these variables, so here counter will be
immediately increased from 0 to 1. Here
counter nothing will happen. This this
part of the for loop or the condition
won't be true. So the body of the if
statement will be executed. So the
counter won't
change on this iteration, on this
iteration. The counter won't change again
but on this iteration the condition will
be correct, will be true so the body
will be executed and the counter will
change from counter was one and now it
will become 1 plus 1 will become 2 and
it will be stored here in the memory and
then we'll move the studio
R will move
on to the next variable and this time
the condition is true against. So counter will
become 2 plus 1 equals 3, will be
stored in memory and then R will move
on to the next iteration. This time
conditions not true so counter will
increase and so on. So every time with on
it find a variable the counter will
increase by 1, so every time we find a
number that we are interested in every
every time this condition is met
ok so that's the main part of our loop.
So what do we want
next? We want to print out counter right.
We want to find out on many of them were
there. So this is like the start we've
created the bulk of our program now
already so how about we just run it and
see how it works.
Ok so let's select all that and come and
run right so here we have 68. Let's run
it again 68, 70, 63, 71, 65 so it's telling us
how many of the numbers that we've
generated out of the hundred numbers
actually fall between minus 1 and 1
right. So we can keep running that then
we every time we're going to see and a
new set of random normally distributed
variables and this number will change.
Ok so what does the exercise ask us for?
Well the exercise asks us to compare
that percentage the percentage of these
numbers to 60 wasn't 68.2 percent right. So
let's just put a comment here so we
remember compare to 68.2 percent right?
So here we've got a number, we want a
percentage so in order to get a percentage we need to
divide by a hundred right. So that will be the
ratio right, so in that case we'll be
comparing to 68.2 points or we'll just leave
that or 0.682 right. So we need to
compare set so let's run it again and
now we have a ratio
alright so as you can see it's kind of
there we go there's a 66, 0.68 but
because the sample is quite small
sometimes you'll be off to the left,
sometimes you'll be off to the right
from what you're expecting and that's
exactly what the law of large numbers
tell the samples quite small and so
there's a higher likelihood that this
number will be different but as we
increase the sample size
this should change. So how about now we
instead of a hundred, we put in a thousand so
it's changed both of these and
important to remember to change both of
them because there's a total of a
thousand number so we divide by thousand right. So now
let's rerun that, so as you can see now
we are getting closer again to the 6.0682
there we go
and finally what we want is we want a
variable to control this script right. So
that we don't have to change it twice
every time we want a variable N at the
top to control this whole script.
So in order to do that we need just a
variable N and then we'll give it a
value so let's start with a thousand and
then we'll replace N here, replace N
here right. So now we don't have to
change it every time twice, we only have
to change it up at the top and it's
easier like that so people somebody was
using a script will know that this is
the input you can even say here
hashtag input and you can see how
comments can be useful for people who
are running your script who are not you
and we didn't create the script but who
are running your script. So they don't
have to worry about all of this right,
they just have to worry about this bit.
Ok so there's our script for thousand
variables or numbers now let's change it
to 10,000 and see that if that improves
the how close we get to the expected
value. As you can see now is 0.68 pretty
much all the time right?
If there's no more 0.71, no more 0.7 or
a 64 and so-and-so and now if I add a
couple more zeros. So what does that give
us? A hundred thousand, no it's a
million already so we're generating a
million random normally distributed
variables right so you can see the
computer was thinking there for a second
and you can see now we are very close right.
It's always 0.68, 68 to
something 683 so we're getting closer
and closer so if I add another zero the
computer will think for a bit longer.
My poor little handbook. Ok so you can
see it's taking some time because it
needs time to generate these numbers but
more importantly needs time to run
through all of them and there we go so
6.82. So as you can see we're getting
closer and closer, the more we have in
our sample the closer we get
that's exactly what the law of large
numbers tells. So there we go we have
confirmed that the law of large numbers
hold in this exercise we have actually
tested it and demonstrated that it works.
Hope you found this exercise useful hope
you enjoyed creating this code
together with me and I look forward to
seeing you throughout this course, until
next time, happy coding.