Hello and welcome into the section on
advanced visualization.
I've got another very exciting data set
prepared for us today and it's called
the movie ratings data set.
We're going to be visualizing ratings of
movies, Hollywood movies mostly between
2007 and 2011 and we're going to create
lots of different great and outstanding
and fascinating charts and plots and
graphs and that way we'll learn a lot
and have fun at the same time.
Alright let's check out this challenge.
So you have been approached as an analytics
consultant by a movie reviews website.
They are writing up an article analyzing
movie ratings by critics and audience as
well as movie budgets for the years
2007-2011. This is
the first time they're doing this
analysis and they don't know exactly
what they need.
Don't you love those situations when
somebody comes up to you and says I have
some data, analyze it, I don't know
exactly what I need.
Yeah this is one of them. They have asked
you to look into the data and provide
them with five graphs that tell a story
about the data. However, there is one
chart the CEO specifically requested. A
diagram showing how the correlation
between audience and critic ratings has
evolved throughout the years by genre.
This is in addition to the other five
see the next page for the CEO's vision.
So it sounds like a pretty complicated
chart so the CEO decided to explain it
with a picture. Here's the picture, audience
rating, critic rating, like you know
how CEO's are sometimes quickly scribbles
something on a paper give it to you and
then you go and have to figure it out on
your own what exactly that they want,
where where are the years here? What are the
genres? What is that question mark? Well this
is a one of those very ambiguous type of
projects but it doesn't matter because
we will still prow through it and we
will learn a lot along the way.
Ok so that was a challenge, let's move on
to where to get the data. So in order to
get the data set we need to go to
superdatascience.com/rcourse and if
you scroll down, here we've got section 6
advanced visualization. So section 6
challenge was that presentation with
awesome picture from the CEO and we've
got movie ratings here so that's the csv
file that we'll need and I actually want
to show you inside the file, so this is
what it looks like once you open it and
here we've got one, two, three, four, five,
six columns. If you scroll down, there's
quite a lot of movies. I wonder how many
of them you have seen. So it just try see
if there's a couple that you've since I've
seen zombieland for example. So 562
movies in here and they have different
genres, comedy, action, thriller, drama,
horror even. So we had quite a few
different genres and also we've got the
rating so we've got the run to
modest rating and actually it might sound a
bit confusing but the higher the rating
it's actually good it doesn't mean they
get more rotten amount. That means,
just that's the name of the rating but
the higher the better and then so that's
the critics rating so basically critics
they review the movie and they give
their expert opinion on the movie and so
basically they're rated and then once
sufficient number of people have
actually seen from the general public
they also rate that movie and then so
you can can you compare them. So here the
movie was rated 40 by the critics but 71
out of a hundred by the audience so
sometimes they match, sometimes they
don't. That's one of the things that we're
going to explore. Another column we have
budget, so what was the budget of the
movie. It'lll be interesting to see, does
budget actually affect the ratings and
year of your release
so that's another variable that we'll be
using so comparing year-by-year. There we
go, that's our six columns and that's our
data set go ahead and download that and
we will connect to it in the next
tutorial and I look forward to seeing you
then.
Until next time, happy coding.