Hello and welcome back to the course on R
programming and in this tutorial we will
learn how to import data into R studio
and we'll look at two methods. One where
you will be able to choose the file
manually and another one where you'll
have to set your working directory. So
let's jump straight into it. The function
that we're going to be using is called
read dot CSV and let's have a look at
the help for that function. So if we zoom
in over here we can see that there's a
function, it's got quite a few parameters
but all we are interested right now is
actually the description. It says here
reads a file in table format and create
a data frame from it with cases
corresponding two lines and variables to
fields in the file. So there we go, that's
the important bit that we are going to
be reading this data into a data frame.
Alright, let's get started. So the first
method, we're going to select the file
manually and we're going to call the
read dot CSV file a function and in the
brackets we're going to type in instead
of typing in the file itself, we're going
to say file choose. So this function
inside will tell us, will create a prompt
for us to select the file manually and
whatever this returns, whatever this
function returns, which will be a data
frame we want to put into a an object
right? So let's create an object and this
object we will call it just stats
because we've kind of overused the word
data already in the past tutorials, so
let's work with stats for a while.  So if I run this line
now, what will happen is a pop-up appears
and from here I can navigate to my file
like I usually do and I can select it
and click open and there you go so the
stats have been imported you can see
them over there and if I run this
variable you will see that the steps
indeed here so I can make some space and
do that again stats there we go, so you
can see that the same file that we
looked at previously is now in R
studio.
Alright well that's great and now let's
look at method number two, because
sometimes in your work with R, you will
need this one actually more often you
will need method number two where you
you set the working
directory and read data from there.
So first one is a working directory, well
the working directory is where by
default your R studio goes to save files
open files or do like even save the R
files that you're creating and so on so
that's what a working directory is. How
did you find out what it is currently
set to? Well the easiest way is to type
and get WD and then brackets because the
function and if you run that it will
tell you what the current working
directory is, so for me it's currently my
desktop. So that's not exactly what I
want because I want to save my files
in a folder that I have on the desktop.
So how do I do that? Well you need to
type in the function which is setwd and
here you'll be able to supply the path
to where your working directory is. Now
the tricky bit is that said working
directory works differently in Windows
and Mac. So let me type in the command
that you will need to type in for
windows and then I will show you how
to do it on Mac as well, so depending on
which machine you're on you will use one
or the other. So let's start over here,
let's start with windows, so in windows if it's on
your desktop you would type in c colon
then you would type in double backslash
users double backslash, your name or the
login desktop double backslash, for me
it would have been for instance R
programming. If that's the folders name
right? For Mac it's different, for Mac you
would type in slash users so forward slash
single falls and don't forget the
quotation marks slash your name in my case,
it's Kirill Eremenko, that's the
username desktop and slash R programming.
So you can adjust all these based on
where exactly your folder is. It might not be
on your desktop or in Windows. It might
not be on your desktop but basically
that's the concept, you find the drive
and then you select where you want to go
and on Mac so you just start with users
and then your name and so on.
Alright, so
I'm going to run the mac one because I
am on a mac right now and if I run that
you will see that my work interaction
has been set without an error which is
always good news and now if I look at get
wd, you'll see that my new working
directory has been changed to exactly
what I want to that folder on my desktop.
So now I can import the file using the
second way so I'm going to overwrite our
variable that we have stats. In fact just
to make this absolutely clear or like
like the experiment is going to be
unjeopardized, I'm going to remove stats so
I'm going to type in RM stats. As you can
see the object has been removed and now
I will populate it with the value that
once. I'm going to type in read dot CSV
and now what I'm going to do is I'm
going to type in the name of the file in
quotation marks so demographic data dot
CSV and now if I run this line, you will
see that the object has been imported
without me having to select manually
and now if I select stats, you will
see that same file is here. So there you
go, that's two ways how to import data
into R studio and in the next tutorial
we will start exploring our data set. I
look forward to seeing you then,
until next time happy coding.