Hello and welcome back to the course in
R programming and in today's tutorial
we will solve the challenge for section
five.
So I've already copied the csv file onto
my computer and I've got the vectors
file open here in R. So let's go ahead
and run all this so that we got the
vectors in our environment prepared over
there and let's make some space on here.
So there are the vectors that's beautiful
now let's load the csv file. The comments
load data, now
first we'll get the working directory. Ok
that's not exactly what I need to load
my data because it's in a different
folder so I 'll just copy that and I will
set the working directory to desktop slash
R programming, if I run that get working
directory good now bear in mind that
this is for a mac this style is for mac
for windows it would be different it
would be something like let me try type
it up here so it'd be C colon, slash, slash
actually backslash backslash users
backslash backslash, Kirill desktop and so
on
right so you can complete that if you're
working windows. Alright now what we're
going to do is we're going to actually
load the data we're going to put into a
data frame called the data into an object
called data and we'll use the
CSV function and here we'll say
section 5 more data dot CSV, run that
you can see that the data frames
appeared and we can look at it already
now but once again it's very big we
don't want to scroll through all of this
will take time. So let's use the
functions that we now know to explore
data sets so head data gives the top six
rows and here we can see we've got
country name, country code, region, year and
fertility rate. So what's missing from
here?
Well what's missing is of course our
life expectancy for variable and that is
given to us in the vectors
ok so that's good to know, let's look at tail
alright.
Do you see anything suspicious here? Well
maybe a little bit, you can see that year
here was nineteen sixty across-the-board
here is 2013.
So that right away jumps out at you
you're paying attention to the data
that's a good thing that we noticed
something plus we also know that from
the challenges we've got two years in
the data set so looks like first to all
the rows for one year and then it's all
the rows the next year. So let's have a
look at the next function str structure
for data and here we've got, we've got
five columns and we've got 374
observations and we've got some factors
then we've got year which seems to be an
integer instead of a factor as you can
imagine in we're not going to be
performing any arithmetic calculations with
year but R is seeing it as an an
numeric variable instead of a factor
would have been better for the factor
for us but anyway doesn't make that much
of a difference. So let's look at summary
data. What do we see here? Well here we've
got country name and what you can see
right away and country code is that
instead of being there being one record
for each country is two records right
and that is in line with what we were
told that there's two years in the
data set and then if you look at here
we've got the minimum, the maximum and a
median. So once again this makes
absolutely no sense and that is because
year should be a factor variable should
get categorical variable rather than
numeric. So now I'm going to actually
show you a quick preview and this
previous only going to be available for
people that watched the solution for
this section so congratulations and it's
going to be end in sight into the next
section. So we've got a variable here data
this is going to be talking a little bit
about in the next session. So we've got a
variable here data and it's called year, if
I run that you can see that it's got
all these years in there so what I want
to do is I want to turn this variable
into a factor right. We saw that it's not
a factor it's just a numeric number.
Let's say a temp variable and here we'll
say factor,
surprise, surprise the function name is
very obvious data, year so if I run that
I've got a temp variable that is a
factor so you can see that it's got all
the same numbers but at the end it tells
you how many levels it has,
two levels and you can actually check
that a separate. You can say levels temp
so there you go so that's how to turn a
normal variable and numeric variable that you
don't want to be in numeric into a
factor variable and in fact you could
even override your existing column with
this new temp variable but we're not
going to do that that was just quick
sneak peek into the next section.
Alright so let's get back to chart what
are we doing now? What we're doing now is
we are going to split the data frame
because we have two years and one
data frame we want to split it into
two so let's go ahead and do that, filter
the data frame. Alright how do we
filter a data frame? Ok just because
put this tab and now it's following
around good. How do we filter the data
frame? We say data1960, going to be
a first data frame is going to be
data and here we want the filter right.
So I'll create the filter first and then
we'll play paste in that year equals to
1960 maybe remove that space.
Okay so if I run that you'll see we've
got first about true true true true
true and then we've got false, false ...
so basically we've create a filter vector
right which we talked about in this
section and if I copy here it will tell
me which rows I want to take and don't
forget the comma, comma nothing because I
want all the columns and I want only the
rows that will have true in this vector.
So if I run this you'll see that it's a
data frame that only has 1960 and right
so if you look on the right here in
the year column you'll see that only has
1960 all the way and hundred
eighty-seven rows. So exactly half of
the data frame so if I run this line
I've got the data 1960 now same thing
for data 2013, 13 they're just copy this
line and here we want equals 2013,
beautiful.
Okay, so we split the data frame into 2
now let's do a quick check because
always good to do checks for audit
purposes, check row count and also we get
to practice the end row function which
we learnt data 1960.
If you  run that you've got 180 sounds good
idea to put a comma here saying that there's
187 rows and row data 2013 run that
once again 187 rows and let's type it in and
we can say equal split which is good
right means everything is working as it
should be and also they should adapt to
374 which is a total number of rows and
they do alright. Now we want to create
the additional data frames because we
have those vectors and they should
actually be in data frames so that
we can work with them better
let's do that, add 1960's going to be the
name of our data frame for the 1960
vectors data frame and so here we're going
to use that trick. We're not going to
just type in country code right? We're
going to actually say country equals
country code because we want the name of
the new column to be country and then
we're going to say life that's a dot
expectancy equals life expectancy at
Birth 1960, alright and then add 2013
data frame and same thing. So let's just
copy that here will say 2013 right and
by the way this is life expectancy at
birth just an average in that population
for that year and we'll see how they
work together with fertility and the
final result, so there we go we've got
the two new data frames which is great
now let's check them will check
summaries this time. Will say summary,
add 1960 right. So there you go, you get
your countries so that should add up to
187 and here you've got your mean,
median, maximum and quartiles and you can
kind of understand the life expectancy
was never less than 28 which is very low
actually and never more than 73 for any
country in 1960 summary add 2013 so here
you can see that life expectancy
increased I went from 28 to 48 add the 20
years to the average life expectancy
across countries of the world and maximum
went up to 83 so maximum increase as
much but it increased
by around 10 years. Alright that's
good, now we're going to merge the pairs
of data frames.
Let's do that alright let's make some
space and how do we merge? Well we'll use
the merge function. First we're going
to create object merged 1960 and here we
want to merge data 1960 then add 1960
which makes sense right that the data
frame that we split out this one and
the one that we created over here from
the vectors and then we want how to merge
by dot X which column we're
going to use in the first data frame
going to use country dot code and which
one gonna use the second data frame by dot y if
you're going to use just code because
that's the name of the column in this
data frame.
Ok so now let's go ahead and actually
run this. What you'll see is actually one
run because I named these columns and
correctly this should be called as like
wondering what's going on.
So this should be code not country
codes for the re-run those and now if
we try running that there we go now it
works, ok so be careful with that hope
you picked up on that too well as typing
it and now we're going to do emerged
2013 let's do same thing but just 2013
alright. Alright run that
and there we go so both data
frames ok let's now check how we're going
to check them maybe let's check the
structure hashtag check the new
structures cause ultimately we've just
created new data frames by merging so
it's a good idea to check the structure
and see how they going. Alright so you're a
country code, country name, region, year,
fertility rate, life expectancy so we've
basically added that column that we were
after and we just need to make sure that
we added the right year to the right a
year and same thing merge 2013 okay
looks good so there we go the only thing
I wanted to say here is be careful when
merging so in our case we know that the
number of variable is the same in these
are number of rows of the same in these
then there's no duplicate on so none of
these columns is duplicated in their
respective data set if you're merging
and for instance there's a duplicate in
this column code then what that will do
is obviously it will duplicate the
matching rows for this data set. So be
very careful careful emerging outcomes
of experience has emerged more data sets
and kind of think of it as a v-look
up operation so if you were doing a
v-lookup and there was a duplicate in
this column or in this column obviously
they're the v-lookup in Excel. You know we
generate and not the exact results that
you want to be careful if your data does
have duplicate rows or even duplicate
values in the columns year. A merging on
so you need to take that into
account when you're pretty merges.
Alright so what are we doing now we're
going to get rid of this variable of
this column year because we don't really
need it it's it's obsolete because we
know the year and here's 1960 and here
2013 there is no different years and each
data set. lt'll be good chance for us
to practice the leading columns so
delete columns.
Let's go and do that merged 1960 dollar sign
year and that's going to be a null, run that.
Ok and run this one is going to be 2013
here run that beautiful so now we're
around this line and this line you'll
see that we don't have the year column
anymore because we don't really need it
we know what you're dealing with.
Alright visualization time, time, yey
library looking at the library ggplot2
don't forget you need to install the
package this actually package the
functions collaborate. You need to
install the package if you don't have it
but you should buy now visualize the
1960 data set.
Alright let's do this Q plot, Q plot to
the rescue.
How do we use q plot well let's step it up
data equals emerged 1960 obviously in
the data then you need X we were told
was supposed to be thrilled to fertility
rate
and why it's supposed to be life dot
expectancy, good! That's a start and then we
want to color going to be a region and
looks just from that for now, see what we
get.
Ok it looks good, it's over here. It's
tiny. It's but it's there and let's make
some space.
Alright next we want to do is increase
the size, size equals don't forget about
the I because we want to apply to
everything and add transparency right
away alpha equals I 0.6. So if I run that
awesome
the last thing we need is to add a title
main and I'll say life expectancy vs
fertility. Fertility is how many children
per woman or that per woman on average
in that country that year. So if I run that
we've got the title and now I'm just
going to copy that and I'm going to
change this to 2013 it's as easy as that
because the data sets are actually
identical in terms of the structure we
don't have to change anything else
inside so far on this is going to be
2013. Alright beautiful so now I'll show
you another trick over here there's two
arrows and actually let's let's make
some space because we don't need the
code anymore we just need this chart and
let's zoom into the chart and you'll see
that here there are two arrows and you
can go back in terms of visualization
and forward and now just bear in mind
that access did change but we can
compare the two years so we can see that
here
african countries the red ones were at
high fertility rates are lots of
children per woman and very low life
expectancy, where as the European
countries were at very low fertility so
between two and four children proven and
very low, still very high but you know
lower than African countries and very
high in terms of life expectancy and
what changed in the past all not done in
the past but in 53 years between the two
data sets. What which you can see
that the fertility rates dropped
substantially so here it was between six
and eight for African country
now or in 2013 was between four and six
and the life expectancy increased so
back here it was between just 30 and
up to 60-below 60 and now is between 50
and 70. In European countries these
green ones you can see how the number of
children between two and four and now
it's dropped between one and two
children. So less than two children on
average along European country but the
life expectancy has increased so as you
can see a huge dramatic changed all of
these countries are moving from here
into the left top left corner slowly
slowly slowly getting there and that's
where the world is going and that's
exactly the inside the beautiful inside
that the world bank was after and
congratulations on delivering that
successfully. I hope you enjoyed this
homework exercise and you were able to
practice a lot of things that we talked
about can't wait to see in the next section
and until next time, happy coding.