Hello and welcome to the world's best iOS development course.
My name is Angela and I've been working as an iOS developer for over seven years as a part of my job.
I work as the iOS lead at the at the app brewery
I also teach on our in-person programming bootcamp and today I will be your instructor on your development
journey as a student on this course you're going to get access to over fifty five hours of HD video
content which contains step by step instructions to teach you how to build over 25 fully fledged iOS
apps.
So if you are somebody who wants to get a job as an iOS developer then this is perfect for building
up your portfolio to show off at your next interview.
On the other hand if you're somebody who wants to build your own apps for your app business then in
addition to all of the programming lessons I've also included full modules on app design and app marketing
so that by the end of the course you'll know how to build design and publish your app onto the app store.
Now this course assumes absolutely no programming experience.
So if you're a complete beginner then I'll be there for you every step of the way.
As I take you through fundamental programming concepts all the way through to intermediate and more advanced
programming techniques.
Now if you're an experienced developer on the other hand there's plenty of advance swift programming
concepts as well as design patterns to sink your teeth into.
At the app brewery we have over a quarter million students worldwide.
So that means you're never going to be alone in your learning journey.
You're gonna get access to our private student community where you'll have to ask questions get advice
find co-founders and work through the course together.
Now as if all of that wasn't enough.
You also going to get the download my 12 rules to learn to code e-book and you're going to get access
to a design package that'll help you when we start building your own apps with over thirty nine thousand
five star ratings and reviews my iOS courses are the highest rated in Udemy history and this iOS 13
course is going to be even better at fifty five plus hours.
This is my longest course yet and then include some of the latest and greatest technologies that Apple
has released including a comprehensive module dedicated to swift UI.
Well then all of the ins and outs of this new technology and use it to build fully fledged complete
apps like this hacker news app.
You're also going to learn about ARKit and core ML which you'll use to build this Pokemon Go style
app.
And this magic newspaper app just like the ones you see in Harry Potter.
As a student on this course you're gonna be saving yourself a lot of time because all of the lessons
in the course have been completely updated.
For the latest versions of iOS, Swift and Xcode. You're also going to be saving yourself a lot of money.
This course has exactly the same curriculum as our in-person programming bootcamp.
So instead of spending thousands of dollars and taking time off work you get access to the same curriculum
that has taken years to develop to ensure that you don't just know what you're doing but also why you're
writing the code and what it does.
Now don't just take my word for it.
Check out some of my past students had to say about the course.
So what are you still waiting for.
Find out why.
Over thirty nine thousand students have rated this course five stars and see what they've been able
to build.
I look forward to having you on the course.