Hey, guys. It's Angela here and I've got a brilliant module coming up for you.
So in this module, we're gonna be building an app called FlashChat which is going to be a messaging
app. And in the process of building this app, we're going to learn about a lot of really awesome and advanced
features of iOS Swift,
as well as something called Firebase.
So this is what we're going to be making.
It's a chat application that has authentication built-in.
So you're able to register and log in users.
So let me go ahead and log in with this account over here.
And on this phone, I'm gonna log in with a different account.
So, now I've got two accounts running the same app and I'm able to write a message, for example, over here,
"Hello,
IPhone 8."
And hit send.
And you'll see it pop up over here from you.
So if I go over here and I type a message, say,
"Hello, IPhone 11," and click send, then that will populate over on this app.
So this is a pretty fully fledged messaging app with animations, with custom UI, with a whole bunch of
things built-in.
And even though it looks simple, we're gonna be learning so much stuff to be able to make this.
For example, we're gonna be learning about the iOS navigation controller, so how to go back and forth between
different screens.
We're gonna be learning to use Swift loops to create that animation that you saw in the beginning of
the app.
We're also gonna be learning about package managers and using something called CocoaPods and the Swift
Package Manager to be able to incorporate third-party libraries into our app.
And one of those third party libraries is something called Firebase which is a service provided by Google
that we're gonna be using for free
to be able to authenticate all users as well as store the message data on a cloud-based database.
In addition, we're going to be learning how to use iOS table views which is pretty much the bread and
butter of a lot of iOS development.
And we're also going to be creating custom UI, such as those cells that you saw earlier on using something
called a ZIP file.
So we've got a lot of stuff coming up for you.
And once you're ready, go ahead and head over to the next lesson. Clone the starting project and let's
get started.