All right, guys, in this module, we're going to recreate something magical, literally. For those of you guys, who
are Harry Potter fans,
you'll know that in the movie and also in the book series,
they have these interactive newspapers, an interactive images. So all the newspapers contain live images
that add extra detail and extra color to liven it up.
So inspired by this, I've created a tutorial where we're going to be using the latest features of ARKit 2
to turn our box down newspapers into magical newspapers that play the content that's relevant to
the image that gets detected, turning a boring old newspaper into something really, really interesting,
and it really livens up the experience of reading a newspaper.
So I hope you're going to enjoy this tutorial as much as I did making it.
And once you're ready, head over to the next lesson and we can get started.
[rap music playing]
.