So we're now ready to download and install Xcode 11.
So this is the application that we'll be using to write our code and build our iOS apps.
It's developed by Apple and it's free to download so you don't have to worry about paying for it or
paying for upgrades or any of that.
But before we start, there's a couple of things that you need to check to ensure that your download and
installation go smoothly.
First thing is to make sure that you have enough space on your hard drive.
So even though Xcode is only about 4.5 GB you need about 10 GB for the download and installation.
So first check to make sure that you have enough space and to do that.
It's pretty simple.
Just head over to the Apple icon at the top of your menu bar and go to About This Mac.
And when you're here you can click on the Storage tab to see how much free space you have to play with
and just make sure that that it's over 10 GB.
So the next thing that you need to check is to make sure that your macOS - your operating system - is updated
to the latest version.
So to make sure that you've got the right operating system. It's as simple as going to the Apple icon
and going to again About This Mac and you can see here which version you've got.
And ideally, you should be on macOS Catalina version 10.15 or above.
And depending on the age of your laptop you might be limited to a previous version of macOS, something
like High Sierra or even El Capitan.
In those cases, you won't be able to download and install the latest version of Xcode, which is
Xcode 11.
And in that case, I recommend you following one of my previous courses such as the iOS 11 or the iOS 12
course.
So, once you've done those two things, the last thing that you need to make sure is that: don't download
a beta version of Xcode.
It's actually not that easy to download it by accident, because as long as you're going through this
video and following along with what we're doing, you're going to be downloading the official release version
of Xcode and you won't have any problems.
The reason why we don't like our students to be working with betas is because beta software is meant for
testing so it can contain bugs and it might end up giving you more headaches than it's worth.
So, no betas. Stick with what we're going to do and you'll have a much, much better experience developing
for iOS.
All right.
So let's go ahead and do it together. So, head over to the App Store.
You can either use Spotlight by holding down command and spacebar to bring it up using the shortcut
or you can head over to the spotlight icon over here or if you want to be really fancy, you can even
get Siri to do it for you.
"Siri, open the App Store."
There we go.
So head over to the search bar here and just type in Xcode and then hit enter. And you can see it come
up over here.
And if you just click on this button here, you'll be able to install it onto your system.
Now, this can take a little while. And sometimes you'll see it just hanging and it refuses to do anything.
So have a look and see if some of those things I mentioned earlier might be the problem.
So, downloading Xcode can take anywhere between 30 minutes to 2 hours depending on your network connection.
You have to make sure that you have a good strong stable network connection so that it doesn't fail
in the middle of downloading.
Now while you're waiting it might be worth heading over to a bonus video that I've included which is
a talk that I often give to companies as well as students on how to make an app from beginning to end.
But once you're done with downloading Xcode, then feel free to head over to the next lesson where we're
going to get started by looking at Xcode and walking through all of the important parts.