Now the next question is, what exactly makes a good app icon?
What should you tell your designer to create?
The first thing that's most important is that never have text in your app icon.
Just never do it.
The reason for that is because text scales really badly. So it might look really nice when that icon
is huge and on Photoshop,
but if it's displayed on an Apple Watch or if it's displayed on an iPhone 4
trust me
you can't see what it says.
And if you can't read it then there's no point having it there at all.
So try to stay away from text i.e. words as much as you can. Instead keep it clean, keep it simple, keep it
iconic.
So something that makes it so unique so people can recognize it just by the font, just by the color
scheme.
For example, you know any of these five Apple icons if I just took away the word that showed you which
app they're from, you'll know that the icon is Pinterest and you'll know that's Pocket if you've used
Pocket and you'll know that's Vine.
So just like a logo, it's simple, it's iconic and it encapsulates the brand.
So try and aim for something like that.