So why exactly is app design even important?
Why are we dedicating this time to learning about it?
So currently in 2016, there's around 2 million apps on the iOS App Store and around 2.4 million on the
Android Google PlayStore.
That's a lot of apps.
When you release your own app into either platform, it's like a drop in the ocean. And
in order for your app to stand out and to be downloaded, we need to care about design.
But also if you think about it despite all of your hard work, all of your blood sweat and tears that
you've poured into this amazing app, it only takes three taps for a user to completely wipe it from their
device and that's usually due to user experience problems,
they get frustrated with using the app or that it doesn't create an emotional response from the user.
Because at the end of the day how much a user likes your app is not related to how feature rich it is
or how good the code is, although those are important.
But the most important thing that actually makes people fall in love with your app is the design.
How easy is it to use,
how beautiful is the interface.
These are emotional responses that are not related to the features in your app or the code.
And that's why we need to focus on the fundamentals of app design in order to make your app as beautiful,
as delightful as it can be so that users will fall in love with it and hopefully you'll get those 5
star reviews that's going to propel you to the top of the App Store.