So the first thing I want to talk about is email marketing. I think the marketing veterans and the
pros all know just how much of a gold nugget this is.
But I feel like a lot of people who are coming into marketing anew they don't realize the full power
of email. And a lot of people think that it's dated or it's old or nobody uses email anymore.
It's not true.
Email is still king.
So one of the most important things you need to know about launching your app is that both app stores,
iOS and Google Play, take note of your stats
on the first 24 hours, 7 days and 30 days of its lifetime on the App Store.
So when you first launch, those are your most crucial periods.
And both app stores look at your metrics.
So this could be the number of downloads, it could be how many reviews you're getting, how positive reviews
are, how much time people are spending within the app, how often they're opening it up etc. etc. So essentially
they all have algorithms for detecting trending apps. And if they see good metrics within those periods
I mentioned then you have a chance of getting featured on the App Stores.
And I think it was last estimated that a feature on the front page of the iOS App Store was worth something
like around 300 grand in marketing budget.
So it's well worth trying and well worth doing.
Now the question is, how do you get those favorable metrics
when you initially launch? Well in order to do that you need an email list.
And the idea is that you collect you know around 10,000 emails or more of people who have explicitly
stated that they're interested in downloading your app.
Now this is not about buying an email list off the internet and spamming people.
Firstly, the problem is that you'll get very low deliverability. So your emails won't even reach the inbox.
It'll probably get stopped by the spam filter.
But the other thing is that it will drag down your credibility rating to the email service.
So if you try to send legitimate emails in you know in the future, you will have problems getting through
the spam filter because you've mass-emailed a bunch of people who labeled you as unsolicited spam.
So it's really important to only email people who actually want to hear from you.
This is not just a politeness rule, but actually it will determine your success for years and years.
So be really careful about that.