Hey, guys. In this lesson, we're going to be learning how to use Cloud Firestore. Firebase's main product,
essentially, and we're going to be using it to store the messages that our users sent.
So, first of all, head over to the documentation page Firebase on google.com/docs/guides.
And here you're going to navigate to Cloud Firestore and we're gonna go to the Get started section.
So feel free to have a read around if you have a moment.
But, essentially, we're going to follow this guide step by step like what we did with the authentication
module.
So the first thing we have to do is to create a new database.
Let's head over to our console and select our Firebase app.
So mine was called Flash Chat iOS13. And now we land on our console page for this project.
So we're going to select the database tab over here on the left.
And notice how Firebase actually has two different databases.
One is the brand spanking new Cloud Firestore which has now been officially released, and the other
is the real time database which was their original product.
Now, there's actually a section on "Find out if Cloud Firestore is right for you."
So choosing between these two databases. But, basically, the overview of it is that realtime database
was their initial product. And it was just a way of being able to save JSONS in the Cloud.
But as more and more people started using Firebase, they wanted more features, and especially things like
querying and ordering, and the kind of things that you get from modern databases like MongoDB.
So Cloud Firestore is the solution,
and that is what we're going to be learning how to use in this module.
Now, in terms of the dynamics at Firebase, even though they are still supporting realtime database,
you can see that they're really trying to hide it by putting it all the way down here.
And I have a sneaking suspicion that because it's Google, you never know what they do with the older
products. And if there isn't enough demand, then I don't know how long they'll still maintain that
realtime database.
So let's learn the latest and greatest.
Go ahead and click on this button, create database under Cloud Filestore.
Now, we get to set the rules for how to access our Cloud Firestore.
We can either start in production mode which will not allow any third party, so any of the apps or any
users to read and write, which is going to make it very hard to test our app, or we can start in test
mode which allows anyone with a reference to our database to be able to read or write to it for 30 days.
And this is perfect
while we're getting up and running and testing our app. And we're going to be using the test mode until
we're ready to add some rules around who's allowed to read and write from our database which we'll do
at the very end.
So let's go ahead and select test mode, and then hit next.
And now we get to choose a Cloud Firestore location. Now, the location that you choose
doesn't really matter that much, unless you have a lot of users, because, obviously, the closer you are
in terms of your region to your end user, then the faster will be to retrieve things from the database.
But note that there's also differences in cost.
So, for example, certain areas will cost more than other areas.
I recommend going with just us-central,
and this is the default selection, and then go ahead and click Done. At this point, with our small amounts
of data,
you really won't notice a difference in speed.
Now, it's going to take a little while to create your Firestore.
But once this loading screen is done, it will take you to your brand-new database.
So now we're ready to start creating some documents in our database. Heading back to the docs,
we've already completed this step creating the Firestore database on Firebase.
And we've also already set up our development environment.
So when we install the Firebase Authentication Module, we also added the Firebase Firestore pod.
So if we take a look in our project and you take a look down here where you've got pods and pod file,
you can see we've already got Firebase/Auth and Firebase Firestore.
Now, notice how here, they've also added Firebase Core which is the core module that these Firestore modules
and authentication modules all depend on.
But since a few months ago, it no longer is required for you to explicitly add the pod into your pod
file.
So we're actually good to go.
And this optional part if we're using Swift extensions, we actually don't need either.
So the only thing you need is this Firebase firestore. And in order to check to make sure that that's
already been added,
if you go down here and you expand the Pods folder, you should be at to see a module called Firebase
Firestore.
If you see that, then you're good to go.
So the next step is to initialize our Cloud of Firestore.
So in our AppDelegate.swift,
we've already imported Firebase and we've already configured the Firebase app in order to use Firebase
Authentication.
But now we're also going to use the Firestore module to create a new database.
So let's copy this line of code and let's go into our AppDelegate.swift, and just below where we've
configured our Firebase app,
I'm going to paste that line right here. So this line of code creates our Firebase Firestore. And to
test to make sure that it actually is working and creating that Firestore,
we're simply going to go ahead and print the db.
So let's go ahead and run our app so that the AppDelegate gets triggered and when our app has finished
launching.
So when we see our welcome screen, then that means this block of code has been triggered. And, indeed, down
here,
I see my Firestore reference being printed.
So that means that this line of code is working and we're now ready to move on to the next step.
Now, if you don't see this, the first thing I recommend you check is that your pod --version
is 1.8.4 or above.
I've noticed that if I haven't updated my CocoaPods and I'm using a lower version, when I tried to install
Firebase Firestore, this line of code doesn't actually work and I don't get anything printed, or I end
up with a crash.
So check that your version is higher than this
and if it's not, then be sure to run sudo gem install CocoaPods, so that you install the latest version
of CocoaPods and it gets updated. But if like me, you're getting that reference printed, then it means
that we're ready to go ahead and put in some data. Heading over to the ChatViewController, we're going
gonna go ahead and create our first piece of data based on what the user has typed in. And the time point
where we actually send our data to our Firestore should be the moment that the user presses the send
button,
so inside this IBAction. The first thing that I'm going to do is I'm going to create a Constant that
stores the message body.
So this is going to be equal to whatever is inside our messageTextField at the moment when the user
presses the send button. Because if you think about it, once they've typed a message and they're done,
then they're going to press on this little button and it's in that moment in time where we grab hold
of the text inside this text field, and we set it as the message body ready to be sent to our Firestore.
So I'm gonna set the message body to messageTextField.text.
And next, I want to also create the sender part of my message. Because remember, if you take a look inside
our message model, we've got two properties: a sender and a body, which we need to fill.
So we've already got the body. But how do we get hold of the sender?
How can we get hold of the logged in users'
email address?
Well, if we take a look back at the documentation for Authentication and under iOS, if we take a look
at the Manage Users section, you can see that you get hold of the currently signed-in user by tapping
into the current user property.
And this happens to be a optional because if there's no user signed in, then current user is going to
be equal to nil.
And in Swift, things are only allowed to be equal to nil when they're an optional.
So heading back to our project, we're going to create a constant code messageSender and we gonna set
it to equal Auth.auth().currentUser. So Auth.auth().currentUser
and this is a user question mark.
So we don't just want the user though,
we can't do anything with that.
What we actually want is to drill even one level deeper and we're going to write .email.
So if we have a current user, then we're going to get a hold of their email and save it inside
our messageSender property.
Now notice how this is a optional string.
And this is also an optional string because the text field could be empty,
that might not be any text.
So it makes perfect sense to use an "if let" to actually bind both of these options to a constant as
long as they are not nil.
Now, we've said if the messageTextfield.text is not nil, then save it inside message body. If there
is a current user logged in, then save their email inside the messageSender.
And now if these two pieces of information are not nil, then we go into this block of code where we can
send these pieces of data to our Firebase Firestore. The first thing that I'm going to do here is I'm going
to create a reference to our database at the very top.
So I'm going to call this again db and I'm gonna set it to equal Firestore.firestore.
Now, once I've created that reference, then I can use it down here.
So how do we use it?
Well, if we take a look at the getting started section for our Cloud Firestore, you can see that you
can add pieces of data by tapping into a collection, and then using the addDocument method to send a
dictionary over.
So let's try this out. Let's tap into our database, and then tap into a collection.
Now, this collection expects a name as a string.
Now, in our case, we're probably going to call it messages. But just to make sure that we don't make any
typos in the future when we access this collection.
So when we're trying to retrieve from it, we're going to use our constants.
So we're going to use our collectionName here.
And notice how in this case, this constant collection name is inside a struct called FStore. But the
FStore struct is itself nested inside the K constant struct.
So in order to access this piece of information, we have to drill two levels deep.
So we'll write K.FStore.collectionName. And while you could put all of these constants simply
at the top level inside the K struct, it makes it easier this way that you can organize them into different
groups.
And when you call them in the code, it makes a little bit more sense. Say, the collectionName is associated
with the Firebase Firestore from the constants file. At least, I think this is more readable and slightly
better code. So now that we've tapped in to this collection which is code messages, let's go ahead and
call that method addDocument, and we're going to call the one which has a completion handler, so that
we'll hear if there are any errors.
Let's go ahead and hit enter to insert this bit of code. And the data that I want to send is, of course,
is going to be a dictionary.
And so it's going to have a key value pair.
And notice if I just back up a little bit that the key has to be of type String,
nut the values can be Any data type,
so it can be an object from a structure or a class.
And, essentially, it doesn't matter what it is.
Firebase doesn't actually care.
So let's go ahead and add our data. And the first piece of data is going to have a key using
the K.Ftstore.senderField, and then after a colon, we're going to add the value.
So in this case, the value is going to be that messageSender here.
So we'll call it messageSender, and then we're going to add a comma to add the next key which is going
to be K.FStore.bodyField, and this is going to be equal to the messageBody that we created
up here from what the user typed in the messageTextField.
Now that we've created our data dictionary, we're ready to create the completion handler.
So selecting this placeholder, go ahead and hit enter, and give the error a name of error.
And inside this completion block, we're going to check to see if let e = error.
So remember, this isn't optional, we might get no error at all. When this case, we're going to print out
the error.
I'm going to say, "There was an issue saving data to Firestore," and then we're going to just add that
"e" right at the end, so that it gets printed out
if it's not nil. But we're going to have an "else" statement as well.
So if there were no errors when this case, let's print "Successfully saved data." Let's go ahead and hit
save and run our app and test it out.
So I'm going to log in as 1@2.com. And here, I'm going to type a message.
Now, notice that if you have the keyboard enabled, it completely obscures that text field and the send
button.
We're going to sort this out in a little moment and we're going to make this text field go up to the
top and animate alongside the keyboard.
But for now, what I want you to do is to either go to Hardware Keyboard and Toggle Software Keyboard,
so you can make it go down essentially, or you can use the shortcut command K to do the same thing.
Basically, we want to be able to see what we're typing here.
So I'm going to write a test message and I'm going to click the send button to trigger our code here.
And notice how we've already got that callback completed and we've got successfully saved data printed,
so that means there were no errors,
and, hopefully, if we go into our Flash Chat iOS 13 database, and we hit refresh on this page, we should
be able to see our data being added in here under a collection code messages. And, indeed, there it is.
So we've got the body, which is text message, and we've got a sender, which is 1@2.com, and then
we've got this I.D. for this piece of data which is automatically created whenever we add a new document
to the Firebase Firestore. That's it.
There it is.
We've managed to save our very first piece of data to our Cloud-based database using Firebase Firestore.
In the next lesson,
I'm going to show you how we can retrieve data and read from our Firebase Firestore in order to populate
the cells of our Flash Chat app.
So for all of that and more, I'll see you there.