Now, in the last lesson, we saw how we were able to get hold of documents by calling this getDocuments
method which has a closure, which will get triggered once we've actually managed to get hold of all the
documents from a particular collection from the Firebase database.
But at the moment though, this getDocuments is very manual.
You have to call it every single time
if you want to get a hold of the latest documents that have been added to the collection. If we take a
look back at the Firebase Guides and we take a look at Cloud Firestore, you can see that under the Read
data section, there's something called "Listen for realtime updates."
And what this allows us to do is to add a SnapshotListener, so that whenever new documents are added
to a particular collection, we get our code to be triggered again.
So if you wanted to get data just once, then you would use the getDocument method.
But as we have a messaging app, it would be great if every time a new message gets added to our database,
then we simply just trigger this block all over again, so that we can add the messages to our messages array.
To do this, instead of calling get documents,
We're going to change it to addSnapshotListener.
So we're going to write addSnapshotListener. And the rest of the code,
we're going to keep exactly the same.
So, now if we run our app again and we log in, and I write a new message and hit send, then you'll see
that it reloads our table view and adds that new message into our table view.
But it does a little bit more than that. It actually doesn't clear out the previous items inside the
messages array.
So how can we fix this behavior?
And I want to pose this as a challenge to you.
Can you modify the code inside the loadMessages function, so that when a newMessage is added, there
are no duplicate messages being displayed inside the table view.
I'll give you a few seconds to pause the video before I show you the solution.
Ready?
Here's the solution.
We know that the addSnapshotListener is going to listen for changes in this collection. Whenever a new
item is added,
it's gonna trigger all of the code inside this closure.
So instead of having our messages array being emptied right at the top, we're going to empty it inside
our closure like this.
So this way, whenever a new item is added to our collection, we empty out our messages array, and add the
fresh messages into it from scratch.
And, of course, in order to tap into our messages property inside the closure, we have to insert the "self"
keyword and a dot in front.
Now, let's run our app and see what happens. Let's go ahead and add a new message which I'll just put
as "123456,"
tell the world my password, and hit send. And you can see that it now gets added in without having all
of the previous messages being added alongside.
And that's the solution to the challenge.
Adding a new message now no longer results in duplicates being added to our table view. But you'll notice
that the order is a bit weird, right?
Why did it go in in the middle instead of what we would expect which is at the very bottom?
Well, the reason is because if we take a look at our database, you can see we've got all of these messages
in here, and you can see that they're ordered in this collection by their IDs. But the IDs are generated
pretty much automatically by Firebase.
So we have really no control over this ID. But it's through the use of these IDs that our messages
are getting sorted in our database.
So, for example, signing with numbers.
So, 2 is less than 8.
And then we go to the alphabet, and "b" is before "n."
What we would like, though, is for this to be ordered in terms of the timestamp that it was sent.
So how can we do that?
I'll give you a moment to have a think about it, and I'll see you on the next lesson where we'll walk
through it together.