Now the second launch site I'm going to talk about is called Beta list. And I have to say Beta list has
gradually declined in popularity.
They came before Product Hunt and they were doing quite well initially but then they kind of changed them
monetisation model.
And personally I'm not a big fan of it.
So the idea is that if you are in beta i.e. if you are if you have yet to launch, you can submit your
project or your product to Beta list and they will distribute it among that email list containing
a whole bunch of angels or a whole bunch of VCs important people etc. and also you get displayed on
their website and gain a bit of visibility.
Now the problem I have with Beta list is that I think since a year ago or so, they started saying that
you know there's so many products that come in that you know vying for space on our website. That they've
had to start charging people to skip the queue.
To be fair it's not a lot. It's something like $200. But that daily traffic is lower than Product Hunt.
Usually even if you get featured the number of hits is you know within the thousands rather than the
tens of thousands.
So for an unknown outcome, I just don't think that parting with your money is always the wisest thing
to do.
But I want to tell you about it because it is one of the big product because it is one of the big launch
sites.
But check it out and make up your mind for yourself.