All right.
So you should have downloaded and unzipped or git cloned
the calendar project to your desktop, and we're going to go ahead and open it up inside Xcode.
So first things first, I just want to show you around the Main.storyboard that I've created here.
Now, you'll notice that the design looks a little bit different from the one that we ended up with at
the end of the Auto Layout module.
And that's because I added a few more modifications just to make it look a little bit more realistic
and more similar to the version of calculator that we've got on the Mac.
So a couple of changes that I made are, firstly, I've reduced the space between all of the items inside our StackView.
So when you click on any of these StackViews, you can see that the spacing is only one point between all
of these gaps.
I've also made the background view black so that these gaps show up as lines outlining each button for
us.
And I've also split up the bottom part by placing these two items in their own stack view, and then stacking
that along with the 0 into another vertical stack, so now it distributes equally.
And I've also changed the font to a thin font at 50 points and some of these other ones a little bit
bigger as well, a system 30, for example.
So now that we've taken a look at the design part, it's useful to take a look at what these parts are
all linked to.
So I've already created IBOutlets and IBActions.
So the only outlet that we've got, currently, is the one that's linked to the displayLabel which is this
one up here, and this displayLabel is going to be the one that's going to show up our results of our
calculations, as well as the numbers that the user types into the keypad.
Now, there's two IBActions.
One of these IBActions are linked to all of the calculation buttons and it's called calcButtonPressed.
And the other one is linked up to all of the number or the digit-related buttons,
and it's called numButtonPressed.
And we're going to be using these two methods in order to implement the functionality of our calculator,
but it's important that you realize which buttons are linked to which method.
So just familiarize yourself with that.
So once you're ready, we can crack on and start building our calculator.
So first things first, we want the user to be able to tap on any of these numbers and have it show up
up here in the displayLabel.
So as I mentioned before, the numButtonPressed is the action that's responsible to a tap on any of
these buttons.
So this is what should happen when a number is entered into the keypad.
And this is also where we're going to add our code.
So previously, in the Xylophone app, if you remember, we also had multiple buttons linked up to the same
IBAction, and in that case, what we did was we gave each of these buttons a different Tag value.
And by looking at what the Tag value of the sender was, we figured out which button was tapped on.
Now, that's a little bit manual, and it involves you having to edit the tags manually one by one which
is a bit of a pain.
So as I always say, programmers are lazy, so what can we do that makes it a little bit easier and less
manual?
So I want to know the identity of the button that was tapped.
And I know that that information is stored inside this object called sender.
Now, the sender has a whole bunch of different properties, such as what is the background color,
well, in this case, it's blue, or what is the size of the button, for example.
Now, you can also see that these different buttons already have a title, right?
They already have some text in them.
And if I could just figure out what the text was of the button that triggered the IBAction, then that will
be really helpful for me to implement my calculator functionality.
So if we tap into the sender object and we use the dot to find all of its properties, even if you just
start searching randomly for what you think could be the name of the property, Xcode is very helpful
in pulling up all of the related properties and methods.
So in my case, I kind of want to know what the title of that button is.
So I might say sender.title and you can see that it's giving me a whole bunch of suggestions.
Do I want the titleLabel? Do I want the title for UIControl.State?
And you can see which ones are variables, which ones are methods. Or do I want the titleColor, titleRect?
Now, you can see that there's two contenders in this case.
One is the tie to a label, and this as it describes down here, is a view that displays the value of the
current title property for a button.
So we could go through it this way.
But there's actually even better one if you scroll through this list.
There's this one called current title and the description for this one is the current title that's displayed
on the button.
Well, that's perfect, right?
That's exactly what we need in order to figure out which button was pressed.
Now, there's a lot of documentation that you can look up online and you'll find all the help in the world
on Stack Overflow and Google and blog posts
but there's nothing that is quite as quick and easy as just searching for what you want and just coming
up with a name that you think is likely, and then scrolling through that list for a good contender,
just as we did here. So in my case, I want to set the display label's text to the current title of the button,
so that means if the user taps 1, I want this to read 1.
Now, I can do that by tapping into my IBOutlet displayLabel, and then going into its text property and
setting that equal to sender.current title.
Now, there's just one problem.
If you hold down alt and click on current title, you can see that this is a String question mark,
so this is an optional string.
And if we read through the discussion, the last sentence says that the value may be nil.
Well, what if we had a button that didn't actually have a title?
Well, in that case, sender.currentTitle will be nil
and this line of code will crash your app.
Now, another neat thing that you can see now that you know all about computed properties is that you
can see that this currenTitle property is a get-only property,
so it's read-only.
So that means we can't, for example, say, sender.currentTitle equals something, something, that doesn't
work because as it suggests currentTitle is the currentTitle that's in the button, and it doesn't let
you to give it a new value by setting it.
And this is achieved through making currentTitle a computed property that only has a get defined and
no set.
So here's a little bit of a practical example of what we've been learning about in the last module.
Now, in our case, I don't really want this line to crash.
So what I want to do is I'm going to use a "if let" and I'm going to call it a numValue,
so the number value.
And I'm going to set that to equal the sender.currentTitle.
And if this sender.currentTitle happens to be not nil,
then inside the "if let" is where we're going to set the displayLabel.text to equal to that new
unwrapped numValue. And you can see now numValue is just a bog-standard regular string as
opposed to an optional string.
So we can test our app and see what we get.
All right, so here's our simulator on the left here,
and I'm going to tap on the 7 and you can see 7 shows up in here.
Now, this is just a bit of an issue with our app and I'm sure you can already see it.
Now, what if I wanted two digits?
Well, I can't at the moment. I can only put in one digit because I'm setting the displayLabel.text
to equal whatever button was pressed through these three lines of code.
So here's a challenge.
Can you figure out a way of appending the numbers that the user keeps on tapping on, so that inside the
displayLabel, we display the entire number that they wanted to put in?
So for example, if I wanted to type 150, I should be able to see 150 show up up here.
And to only set it back to nil or allow a new number to be entered
when I click on any of these other buttons.
So this is pretty much classic calculator functionality.
You don't need me to go through it any more than that.
So pause the video and see if you can complete that challenge.
All right.
So, basically, what we need to do is to append each of these numValues to each other and display it
in the displayLabel until the user taps on one of these calculate buttons.
So a typical case would be, say, for example, I'm trying to type in 150 plus 3,
right?
So when I type plus, then I can clear the 150, and I can start from scratch on the 3.
So in order to do that, I need to have some sort of property that keeps hold of whether if the user is
done typing the number.
So let's go up here, and just below IBOutlet,
let's create a new variable and let's call it isFinishedTypingNumber.
This is a little bit wordy but, hey, we've got Xcode autosuggesting everything, so we don't have to type
everything out,
so why not make it super clear.
So isFinishedTypingNumber is going to be a Boolean and it's going to start off in life as being true.
So when we first start up our app, then isFinishedTypingNumber is going to be true.
So, now we can go inside our numButtonPressed and we can check to see if isFinishedTypingNumber
is equal to true.
You can either use this full syntax where you have it checking with a double equals or you can simply
just delete that and everything between the "if" keyword and the open curly brace is evaluated.
And if it is true, then this block will be carried out,
otherwise, it will not.
So inside here if isFinishedTypingNumber is true, then that means we're just starting out,
and the number in the label is probably 0 or we're just starting out with a new number that we want
to type.
So in that case, we do want to set the displayLabel.text to equal the numValue, so the value
of the button that got pressed.
So when I first start out the app, the display label says 0 and isFinishedTypingNumber is going
to be initialized to true.
So in this case, when I press one of the buttons, then that is the value that is going to go into this
UILabel.
Now, once we've set a number into the label,
so the first number is showing up in there,
then we have to switch this isfinishedTypingNumber to false, because we are not done typing the number,
right? We've just typed in the first number, and until I press one of these buttons, the orange or the
gray buttons, I want my calculator to accumulate all the numbers, so that I can type a number that is
more than one digit.
For example, I want to be able to type 150.
So inside here, we can define our else case.
So namely, when this IBAction is triggered and we are not finished typing number, we've just started typing
a number,
then we should be able to accumulate the number by appending them to the previous number.
So in this case, then we can say displayLabel.text is equal to the current text in the displayLabel,
plus, or rather append what is currently the numValue.
So what this line of code will do is it will look at the currentTitle of the button that was pressed
and it will append that value to what is currently inside the displayLabel here.
So if I run this code now, you can see that when I type 1,
now at this point isFinishedTypingNumber is set to false.
So we're going to go inside this else bracket, and that means that the next button I press will get
added or appended to the previous value of the displayLabel,
and now I have 15. And if I keep going until 0, I can keep adding numbers and it will continue to append.
Now, ideally, when I press any of these buttons, for example, plus, I want to be able to start typing a new
number, instead of continuing to append numbers.
So in order for that to happen, we have to go into our calcButtonPressed because, remember, this
IBAction is linked to all of the calculation buttons.
And here I'm going to set that variable isFinishedTypingNumber to
true.
Because if I've typed a whole bunch of numbers, and then I press the add button, then I'm pretty much finished
typing number, right?
I want to type a new number to add to my last number.
So, now let's run our app with that minor update. Now, you can see I can type 150,
and then when I press any of these buttons, say, plus, then I can add in a new number, 150 plus 250.
Now, none of the equal signs or anything else works because we haven't implemented anything in there.
But you can see I've already managed to use our variable isFinishedTypingNumber and toggling it state
to be able to make my calculator accumulate numbers when I need it to, and to forget about the numbers
when I need it to as well.