So in the last lesson, we looked at how to perform create in CRUD using Realm,
and we were able to successfully add new categories that we created inside
our addButtonPressed IBAction and save it to our Realm persistent data store.
Now, in this lesson, we're going to tackle the next letter which is read inside CRUD and we're going to
look at how we can load up our categories from all Realm database, rather than from Core Data.
And so the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to delete this thing called context because we no
longer need it.
So the place where we read from our database is inside our loadCategories method.
So if we scroll down to find it, you can see that we've commented all out.
So instead of having this request which is a fetch request or try context.fetch, we can replace
all of this code with just a single line.
We can say let categoryies = realm.objects, and then we just specify the type which is all of the
category type objects. And this will pull out all of the items inside our realm that are of Category
objects.
And that means that we can delete all of these lines of Core Data code replaced with just this one line.
Now, at the moment, I'm creating it as a local variable.
But if we wanted to use it elsewhere, then we can use our variable categories.
Now, what you'll see is that I can't straight up just assign it to this variable called categories,
it's going to give me an error. And the error it says is that it can't assign a value of type results
to type array.
So what it's saying is that the data type of the objects that we get back is results which is a container
type that comes from Realm Swift.
So this is equivalent to list or array, but it's a different data type and it's not very easily converted.
But what we can do is we can change the data type of our Category's property to the results data type.
So we can say that categories is of data type Results, and Results is basically just an auto-updating
container type,
so container types are things like arrays, dictionary, results, lists, and it comes from Realm and it gets
returned from object queries.
So that means that whenever you try to query your Realm database, the results you get back is in the form of
a Results object.
So we can specify our categories, which is what we're going to get back when we query our database, as
data type of results, and it's going to contain a whole bunch of Category objects. And I'm going to first
unwrapped that and we'll go with that for now.
So now this line of code is perfectly valid because the data type that we get back here is Results containing
code bunch of categories as the element inside the results, and then categories is also the same data
type. So that matches and that's now allowing us to proceed. But we get this error down here where we say
self.categories.append newCategory.
Now, because this result data type, as we found out earlier on, is an auto-updating container.
We don't actually need to append things to it anymore.
It will simply auto-update and monitor for those changes.
So, now with just one line, we've managed to place four or five lines of Core Data code that does exactly
the same thing.
So let's give it a go and run our app and see if it works.
So there you go.
Those are our two items that we saved earlier on into our Realm Browser as you can see here.
And if I terminate the app and go back into it, you can see that it's still able to persist and load
up or read from our Realm database just based on those two lines of code.
Now, let's address the issue of force unwrapping this particular property.
It's not ideal because what if, say, we forgot to load up our categories,
and this was, in fact, nil when we force unwrap it and try to use it to populate our table view.
Well, then we're going to have an issue, and you're going to see it when I run our app. There we go. "Thread 1:
Fatal error: Unexpectedly found nil while unwrapping..." this particular optional.
So let's stop our app and let's make our code safer.
So instead of making it a forced unwrapped, I'm going to add a question mark to this data type and make
categories an optional.
So, now instead of saying categories. count, I'm going to say if categories is not nil, then return
categories?.count.
But if it is nil, then just return 1.
So this is a new bit of syntax. And this in Swift is called the Nil Coalescing Operator.
What it means is that this could be nil.
Because categoreis is an optional and we're only saying get the count of categories
if it is not nil, but if it is nil, then this is going to be nil, right?
But if that happens, then the nil coalescing operator will say then use this value instead.
So if categories is not nil, then we'll return the number of categories we have.
But if it is nil, then we're going to just return 1,
so our table view will have just one row. And down here if categories, the optional is not nil,
then we're going to get the item at the indexPath.row and we're going to grab the name property.
But if it is nil, then we're simply going to say the text is just going to be equal to "No Categories
Added yet."
And finally, I'm going to add a question mark here to say that the selected category of the destinationVC
will be set to the category
if it's not nil at the indexPath.row that we selected. And that gets passed into here as the
selectedCategory which is an optional category. And only when it is set,
i.e., it's not nil,
do we actually call load items.
So we're still okay over here.
So, now even though my loadCategories is still not commented in because it's not active and this categories
will be nil when we try to run our app, you'll see that our app no longer crashes and burns. And instead, it
actually has a slightly different but better user experience.
So, now you can see that the app has not crashed even though this categories property is now nil.
And that's because it has some default values. And the default value when categories is nil is to produce
a single table view cell and for that cell to have the text of "No Categories Added yet."
And that makes our app so much safer and a much better user experience.
Now, the Add button is still going to break
when we try to add new categories, and it's not going to show up.
And that's because we need this loadCategories method to be called so that we start auto-updating our
categories using the objects inside our realm.
So let's go back and uncomment this method call and run our app again, and you'll see that we still have
all of our items showing up and persisting.
So we've now managed to use our Realm database to add new items and save them to our Realm, and we've
also managed to use it to load up our Realm objects using a single line of code.
And now all we have to do is to fix the same things inside our TodoListViewController.
Now, all we have to do is to fix the same things inside our TodoListViewController. So we are passing
over the current category as a optional category and it's going to land over here as the selectedCategory
And when that happens or when that does get set, then we're going to call this method called loadItems,
and we no longer need our context,
so we're going to delete it, and we also no longer need Core Data.
So I'm going to instead import Realm Swift. And, of course, because we're using Realm, we have to create a
new instance of Realm, let Realm = try! Realm.
So, now when our selectedCategory does didSet from our CategoriesViewController coming over from
the segue, then we're going to call loadItems. Now, loadItems is an unresolved identifier because we
commented out before
in order for our app to be able to run without any errors so that we can fix it now.
So I'm going to uncomment this method. And inside here, I'm going to delete all of this and all of this,
and instead of all of those lines of complicated Core Data code, I'm, instead, just going to say itemArray
= selectedCategory.items.
Remember that relationship that we're going to use now?
So all of the items that belong to the current selectedCategory and we're going to sort it by KeyPath
and ascending, and the KeyPath is just as we've done before,
sorted by the title of each item and we're going to make it ascending: true.
So KeyPath is called "title," so that's the title of each of the items that come back into the itemArray,
and ascending is going to be true. And because itemArray at the moment is a array of item objects,
we need to change the declaration of the tub to be this results container containing item objects data
type.
So let's do the same as we did before
and delete that,
instead declare its data type as Results, the auto-updating container containing a whole bunch of item
objects.
I'm going to make it an optional.
So, now we can replace all of this code with just a single line like this. Now, it no longer really makes
sense for this to be called iitemArray because it's now no longer an array,
right?
It's actually a Results container containing a whole bunch of items.
So we probably should change the name of this variable.
Now, I can either go around finding all the places where I used itemArray, itemArray, itemArray.
In fact, the errors actually help to guide me all the places where I need to change its name. But a slightly
simpler way of doing this is you can simply hit command F to find all the places where itemArray exists
and you can replace it with a new name,
for example, something like todoitems. But this is still a little bit clunky, it actually gives you a
really, really nice way of being able to rename yourvariables and not have to worry about changing it
everywhere it's used.
Now, you might get some errors if you tried to do it just like this because, remember, we changed the data
type of this variable and in all the places where we used it, we used it in the context of an array of
items.
So if you get any strange behavior trying to rename, then you can actually revert this back to an array
of Item objects, and you can initialize it to an empty one,
and we can simply hold down command and click on item array.
And if you scroll down, there's this thing called Rename and it'll go into this accordion view where
it'll only show you the lines of code where you use this variable called itemArray, and you can select or deselect
the ones that you want to change.
So, for example, the comments are by default not included in your renaming because, as you can see, our
comments come from our old code, so we can leave those alone.
But all the ones highlighted in blue will get renamed as we type in here.
So I'm going to call that todoItems and I'm going to hit Rename and it's now updated it in all of
these locations.
So, now we can change this back to our previous results containing a whole bunch of items and it's an
optional
and we managed to rename all of those places which used to read itemArray.
So, now because todoItems is an optional, we're going to have to either unwrap it or do something about
it.
So we're going to do the same as we did before.
We're going to use optional chaining to say if todoItems is not nil, then return the count.
But if it is nil, then return 1. And down here,
we'll, first, going to use optional chaining
to say that if todoItems is not nil, then grab the item at indexPath.row.
And if all of this works and it's not nil, then, in that case, we're going to change all of our accessories
based on the item.title and the item.done properties.
But if it is nil or if it fails a "else," then we're going to say cell.textLabel?.text is going
to be equal to just a simple string, and it's going to be no items added,
and we're going to return the cell whichever state it is in depending on this optional binding check.
Now, all we have left is this error.
And for now I'm just going to comment it out because in order to persist this data using Realm, we actually
have to do it slightly differently than this.
And we'll tackle this in the next lesson. We will learn about update in CRUD using Realm.
So let's leave that for now.
But we do have to change our saveItem data.
So as a challenge, I want you to be able to fix these lines of code and change it to use Realm, instead
of using Core Data, as we are here.
Now, when you complete this challenge, I want you to ignore this function called saveItem.
In fact, just go ahead and delete it.
And I want you to do all of your saving just inside this closure.
So I want you to create a newItem from our data model item and I want you to save it here as well.
So pause the video and give it a go.
All right.
So how did that go?
Let's go ahead and uncomment these few lines and we're going to update it in order to use Realm. So, we
no longer have a context,
so let's delete that. We're just initializing a new object of the item class. And the title is going to
be the current text that's inside the textField. Done doesn't need to be specified anymore because it
is already here as a default.
Now, because our selected category is of data type optional Category, we have to somehow unwrap it or
use optional binding in order to make it work.
So if we say if let current category = self.selectedCategory, and if that's not nil, then
we're going to say let newItem = Item, and newItem.title is the textField.text, and instead of setting
the newItem's parentCategory property here,
instead, we're going to go the other direction.
We're going to tap into the items that belong to the current category
and we're going to append this newItem to that list. so we can say currentCategory.items, which is a
list of item objects, .append this newItem.
And that takes care of these two lines
and replaces them. Now, as we said, instead of calling self.saveItems to do our saving down here,
we're going to do all of it up here.
And so we need to be able to say
try realm.write,
And we'll going to write is all of this.
So create a newItem, give the newItem a title, and appended to the items in the currentCategory.
And this, of course,, has to happen after we've unwrapped our self.selectCategory, so it needs to
go in here.
And because this can throw, then we need to wrap it inside a do-catch block.
And because we're inside a closure, we'll use self.realm.write,
and we can delete this call to save items.
So did you manage to get that?
It's a little bit convoluted in terms of the logic, but you can clearly see that this is far less code.
And to me, it's way more human readable and the logic is easier to follow than using Core Data.
And the last thing we need to do here is that once we have written this new data to all Realm, we need
to call tableView.reload data, so that we call those data source methods again and update our table
view with the newItem because we've gotten rid of our save method.
So, now all that's left to do is to run our app and see if it works.
So as you can see, we've got all of the four categories that we added on earlier.
And if I go inside Shopping as a category, then you can have a look inside the Realm Browser as well.
You can see that Shopping does in fact contain a list of item objects, but it's currently completely
empty, i.e., there are no items associated with Shopping.
So let's go ahead and add one, let's say, "Buy Apples," hit Add Item, and you can see that, firstly, the item
model gets incremented with a single new object.
But also inside category, inside that link, you can see that when you click on this item, it takes you
to that particular item.
And it's now equal to 1.
So as we add more,
you can see that, firstly, they're getting fetched back in alphabetical order because of that sort that
we specified here,
and they're also showing up over here, and you can hover over it in order to see it at a glance.
So in the next lesson, we're going to look at the next letter in CRUD which is "U" and how you can update
your data inside Realm.
So for all of that and more, I'll see you on the next lesson.