Now this is a slide from the Founders Institute and this is something that served me personally really
well over the years
no matter what it is that I was doing because it's a very succinct way of structuring what it is that
you're doing so that anybody can understand.
Very often you get pitched by people who say "we are a data integration social analytics company helps you
connect with your prospective leads."
Now I'm not going to point out which company this is but just by having read this paragraph over and
over and over again giving this course, I still to this day do not know what it is exactly that they do.
So don't be like that. Instead structure at something like this.
So for example my company Spacex is developing reusable rockets to help space agencies reduce the costs
of rocket launches.
That makes sense to everybody.
The other thing that you have to remember about the elevator pitch is that if you've ever been to Sand
Hill Road in San Francisco,
so the street where basically all the biggest venture capitalist firms are, you'll notice that none of
the buildings are more than two stories high. So that elevator ride is maybe 30 seconds or 20 seconds
and you have to get your point across in that limited time span.
It's not Trump Tower.
You don't have time to fluff around what you're talking about.
Get to the point. And this is great
not just for pitching journalists, but for pitching investors or for telling people what you're doing
or pitching customers even or pitching B2B customers.
So think about how you can structure your own company or your own app in this way and start practicing
using it and you'll see some really great responses.