The next difference that we're going to talk about is title placement. On Android
the title is always left aligned, so it will extend towards the right.
But on iOS the title is always centered. So it's always small details like this that users pick up on
and can make them feel like this is an app that was really carefully thought out and made in such a
way that takes into consideration of their platform you know or it could feel like it was cobbled together.
And then there's also things which are only on Android which you don't actually have an equivalent on
iOS.
An example of this would be the drop down menu. On Android
what you can do is you can tap on one of these selectors and it will drop down a list of items for you
to choose from.
Now the equivalent in iOS is the sliding wheel. But it looks and feels and animates very very differently.
So this is something that actually doesn't exist on iOS. If you did implement it
it'll be quite confusing for a user that's used to iOS.
So again, a lot of food for thought.