Now that you know who you want to approach, the next question is how do you approach them?
For example, how would you find their contact details?
Well there's a website called VoilaNorbert.com and it has a really simple interface but it does
something really powerful.
It allows you to put in the first and last name of your potential journalist or person that you want
to contact and then put down the company that they work for, their domain.
So for example it would be something like MikeButche@Techcrunch.com.
And then once you hit Work for me Nobert, it will go through all the different variations that most
companies use in order structure their corporate email so that will be.
So they'll be initials or a full name or initial plus surname etc. and it pings all those email addresses
until it gets one with a successful response. And then it will tell you what is the email of that journalist
or that person you're trying to contact.
And usually when we tell this in class in person, there's two reactions that we get in the classroom.
One is people who are really shocked and really angry.
This is how people have been getting my email.
This is how all these strangers have managed to reach me. And the other response that you get are really
mischievous people going like "ha ha ha.
Now I know how I can enact my evil plans on the world."
But either way it's a really useful service and it's useful not just for pitching journalists but for
finding venture capitalists or angel investor details or doing B2B sales when you're looking for like
say the V.P. of sales at a particular company etc..
So really really powerful tool.
Try it out.