Now the next thing I want to stress if I haven't stressed it enough already is build a relationship with
journalists.
If you are cold-pitching out of the blue your chances of success are way lower than if you are pitching
somebody who you have a relationship with.
So this could include you know following them on Twitter, getting to know what the journalist is all
about.
What do they care about, what they feel passionately about and responding intelligently to some of the
things that they tweet about so that you start to establish a relationship.
You're not just some joe bloggs off the street who is mass emailing every single journalist.
No you're Joe who always read Steve's intelligent tweets and you reply with your own intelligent conversation
and you are a somebody. So as I mentioned before, every single tech journalist worth their salt has a
Twitter handle.
So follow your favorite journalist or follow the people who cover topics that are related to your niche.
And there's a whole lot of really interesting content that people share exclusively on their Twitter.
Their thoughts or their updates or their progress.
And yeah and just have a intelligent conversation.