Guys, welcome to yet another Swift Deep Dive.
And in this Deep Dive, we're going to talk about structures. Now, structures helps us create custom data
types.
So whereas previously we saw that there were loads of basic data types that comes prebuilt along with
Swift. For example, Strings, Ints, Floats, Doubles, Boolean, Arrays, and Dictionaries, you name it.
There's a whole lot of different prebuilt data types.
But what if we needed our own data type something that groups gather related properties and behaviors.
For example, our quiz questions.
Currently, we have a 2D Array which basically forces these two pieces of data, the answer and the question,
to be associated with each other.
But, actually, these are two properties of a question, right?
The text of the actual question, as well as the correct answer of a question,
those should really somehow be interlinked together. And in order to do that, we could use a structure.
So we create a structure by using the struct keyword, and then we give it a name.
Now, notice how the names of struct are a little bit different compared to methods or properties.
When you're creating a struct, the name that you give it has to be capitalized even at the beginning.
So that way, you can tell that it's actually a data type.
Similar to how our string Int or Float data types, all start with a capital letter.
Let's go ahead and create our own structure in playgrounds. So let's say that I was to create the structure
of a town.
Well, I would start by writing the struct keyword, and then I would give my structure a name.
So let's just call it Town. And then I'm going to open a set of curly braces inside of which I can define
the properties of my town.
So what other kind of properties a town might have?
Well, it might have a name, right?
So let's create a constant using the "let" keyword and give this constant a name of names, so the name of the
town. And then I'm going to give it a value, so let's call it "Angelaland."
Now, let's think. What are some other properties that a town might have?
Well, it probably has some citizens, right? But in this case, I'm going to create a variable and the variable is
gonna be called citizens and it's going to be equal to an array.
So these are all the people that live in Angelaland, and it will be myself and, let's say, Jack Bauer,
my ultimate hero.
And so now that we've got the citizens who live in the town, the name of the town, the last property I'll
add are the resources in this town.
So let's say that we had some "Grain," maybe 100 bags of grain, some "Ore." I think I've been playing a little
bit too much of a Settlers of Catan recently.
That's all I can think about.
Let's say we had 42 blocks of ore. I'm not sure what's the unit of count of ore. And then, let's say we
had some "Wool."
Notice how here I'm creating a dictionary,
So it's a variable called resources which is a collection of dictionary items.
So we've got our key and our value.
So a 100 bags of grain, 42 bags of ore, 75 bags of wool.
And these three properties are now all packaged together into my Town structure. Now that we've created
our struct,
it's time to actually initialize it. By initializing, I mean creating an actual object that we can use.
So to create an actual town from our town structure, all that we would need to do is create a new var
and this var will be called myTown.
Now, this myTown is going to be the actual town created from this structure. And to express that in code,
we would write var myTown = Town, and then a set of parentheses.
So now what I've done is I've created a new copy of this town structure and it's held within the variable
of myTown.
So that means I can actually use this object myTown and I could access the properties of myTown.
For example, I could print myTown. And to access the properties, I would use the dot notation.
So as soon as I write dot, you can see all the things I can tap into. And let's say that I wanted to print
"Who are the people who live in my town?"
I'm going to print myTown.citizens. And currently, it's just me and Jack Bauer.
Now, I can tap into some of the other properties as well.
So, for example, if I wanted to use my string interpolation to get hold of myTown.names or the name
property of my town.
And then, let's say, myTown has-- Let's do like a little report, shall we?
How many bags of grain have I got?
So then it would be myTown.resources.
And then we would use the square brackets to access the "Grain" key, and then we could say, well, it has
this many bags of grain.
So now if I run my code, you can see that these are the citizens and Angelaland has 100 bags
of grain.
That's a pretty good, pretty good town
if I might say so myself. Now, with the object that we've created, myTown, we don't have to limit ourselves
to just retrieving data or retrieving the values or properties of this object. But we can also add and
modify it.
So for example, if let's say that my town has a new citizen, let's say that Keanu Reeves decided to
move into this wonderful town.
Well, then I might say myTown.citizens to access the citizen property of myTown.
Well, then I can append so add something to my citizens array, and the name that I'm going to spend is,
of course, our new neighbor, Keanu Reeves. So there's three of us now in our town. And I can print, for example,
myTown.citizens.count. And when I do that, you can see that after I've added Keanu Reeves to
the citizens of myTown, we now have three people living there. Whereas previously, when I printed
myTown.citizens, we only had two people.
Now, so far, the structure of our town only defines the properties of a town.
So town should have names, each town should have citizen, and they should have resources. But we can also
define a behavior of our structure so we can make towns be able to do things like build barricades and
get everybody inside and we sort of eat all our 100 bags of grain. And to do that, we would simply just
create a function within our structure.
So let's say, we created a function called fortify. And now inside this fortify function, we could simply
just for ease of use, we'll just print "Defenses increased!" So now our town structure has properties and
it has something that it can do.
Now, when we have a function that's associated with a structure, well, then the name for it is actually
called a method.
So if you hear the words functions or methods, when people refer to it on StackOverflow on line, just
know that they're both referring to this same thing.
The thing that we create with a funky word and it defines some behavior inside the curly braces,
but if this behavior was defined inside the curly braces of a structure or a class, then we would call
it a method.
But if it was sort of standalone, free floating around somewhere, well, then we would call it a function.
At the end of the day,
it's just defining behavior, something that it can do.
But now I can trigger this method or this functionality that my town has by writing myTown,B
so this is the actual object that can do things and has properties, dot,
and I'm going to make it do something.
Now, notice here that this "M" stands for method.
And if I hit enter, then my town is going to fortify itself
when I run that line of code. And we can see that myTown has its defenses increased, so it's able to
perform an action or a behavior. When we create a struct in our code, we're essentially creating a blueprint
for an eventual object that will get created from our blueprint.
And in this blueprint, we get to plan ahead for how this eventual object will be.
For example, we create variables, and when our variables live inside a struct, that variable is associated
with our struct and it's known as a property of that struct.
Similarly, we've created functions inside our struct. And when functions are created inside a struct, they're
known as a method.
So you can consider these properties as a way of defining what this eventual object created from the
struct will be like.
So its attributes or its properties and the methods can be thought of as what the objects can do.
So in the context of an actual car object that gets created from a car struct or car blueprint,
well, those properties might be things like the color of the car or the number of seats it has, or the
number of doors it has, or whether if it's a hatchback or a sedan, something that describes what this
eventual object is going to be like. And the methods for the car,
well, those are things that the car object can do,
so things like drive or brake, or switch on the indicator lights. And it's through describing these properties
and methods of the objects that will get created when our app is running.
So these objects are invisible. We can't see them. We can't touch them. But we can plan for how they will
behave and how they will look
by creating these properties and methods. So when we were defining our town struct, we were writing the
blueprint for the eventual object that will get created. And we can take our blueprint and initialize
it which turns it into the actual object.
In this case, maybe an actual car.
But what do I mean by that? What is initializing mean and what does the code actually look like?
Just like we would create a function,
we create our initializer in a pretty similar way. We have are parentheses for the inputs that gets
passed over.
We have our curly braces for the implementation or the code for how to initialize our structure.
So how does the initializer get used?
Well, the initializer gets triggered when we create our object from our blueprint. But why do we have
initializers in the first place?
What's the purpose of the initializer?
Well, suppose you want to create the next civilization or Settlers of Catan video game,
well, in that case, you're going to need more than one town,
right?
Well, in addition, to Angela Land, you'll need Athens, Beijing, and New Delhi, and many, many more, but all
of these places are different.
They have a different name, different citizens, and different resources.
Wouldn't it be nice if we could use our struct to act as a blueprint for all of these towns, but still
be able to customize each town?
Well that's where the initialize it comes in.
Let's head back into playgrounds to see this in action. Let's delete everything we have here currently
and just be left with our structure.
Now, I'm also going to delete the values of these properties to keep my town very generic. So the name
is going to be a string data type.
The citizens are gonna be an array of strings and the resources are going to be a dictionary made up
of strings for keys and integers for values.
So now my town structure has blank properties for each of these attributes and I can now define a custom
property
every time I create a new town.
But before we do that, we need to create the initializer.
So I'm just gonna write "init." And when my swift code snippet symbol comes up, I'm just gonna hit enter.
And inside the place holder which says "parameters," I'm going to add some input parameters, so when
I initialize a new town from myTown structure,
I'll be able to use these inputs to fill in my properties.
The first one is going to be townName which is going to be of type String.
Next, it's going to be the people of the town which are going to be an array of strings.
And finally, I've got the stats for my town which is going to be a dictionary comprised of String keys
and Integer values.
So that's all three inputs that I need for my initializer.
And inside the initializer, what I'm gonna do is I'm going to set my town's name property to equal
whatever got passed in as the townName, and then I'm going to set my citizens property to equal whatever
got passed in as the people of the town.
And finally, my resources property is going to be populated with these stats that have been inputed for
this town.
So now if we're creating our town with an initializer, the  way that we would do that is, let's create
a variable code,
I don't know, another town, and let's set it to equal a town created with our Town blueprint.
And then, once we open a set of parentheses, you can see all of those input parameters show up, townName,
people, and stats.
So if we hit enter, we can use these placeholders and you can hit tab to go between them, and we need
to provide some values in each of these positions. And we can also see what type of data we need to provide.
So the first one for the town name has to be a String.
So let's call this "Nameless Island." And the people who live in this Nameless Island will just be one
guy and it's gonna be Tom Hanks.
And for the stats of this town that I'm creating, it's just gonna have a whole lot of coconuts.
And let's say, it's got 100 coconuts on this Nameless Island.
So now that I've created another town, I can do exactly as what I've done before, I can tap into my object,
the anotherTown. So remember the object is the thing that's actually created from the blueprint.
And I can, of course, print the properties, say, the citizens or the name, I can call or trigger the methods
or the behaviors that the town can do, namely fortify itself, but I can also, of course, tap into, let's
say, our citizens. And then just as we did before, we can append a new element which happens, in this case,
to be a beach ball who's going to join the citizens of Nameless Island, and he's gonna be called Wilson.
So now we have another town which is an object created from the Town blueprint with all of these properties
that we've specified when we created the town using the blueprint.
And we're able to use this object just as we did before to tap into its properties or to manipulate
or change some of those properties.
And we can, again, if we wanted to, now print our anotherTown, so our objects property.
Let's print and see who lives in this town.
So this time it prints, there's "Tom Hanks" and there's "Wilson" on Nameless Island.
Now, notice how I'm twisting these names so that they don't overlap with the names I've got as the properties
of my town. Because in reality, it would be much easier for me to just name this name,
name these citizens, and name these resources.
But now, when I initialize it, I have to set the name equal to name, and the citizens equal to the
citizens, and the resources equal to the resources.
Now, it kind of makes sense if you really think about it.
So I'm saying that the name property of myTown structure should be set to equal the name that got passed
in as the input parameter.
But this code is very confusing because this name matches exactly this name.
Now what else can I do?
Well, I can make it really explicit which one I'm talking about whether if it's the property or whether
if it's the input here by simply adding the word "self" in front. Now, you might have already come across
this keyword "self" and we haven't really gotten round to explaining it and this is the perfect time
to really explain it. Because the "self" keyword refers to the eventual object that will be created from
this structure blueprint.
Whereas right now, we're saying self.name referring to the property name of our structure town.
Well, eventually, when we try to initialize our town, that "self" is going to refer to the object that's initialized,
so, for example, the anotherTown. By adding that "self" keyword in front of all of these properties, I can
now easily differentiate them by saying, well, self.name, of course, refers to my town's name property,
self.citizens,
of course, refers to my town's citizens.
And you can view this "self" keyword as referring to the structure.
Now, that I've changed the parameter names of my initializer for my town structure, well, I also have to
change them here,
right?
So this is what this error is about.
It says that the labels should be the name citizen resources, but instead, we have townName, people, and
stats. So we can go ahead and click Fix for it to change it for us to the ones that we specified in the
initializer the and all the errors go away.
But from now on, also, when we create, say, let's create a ghostTown from our Town blueprint,
and when I hit enter, you'll see that these are now the parameter names
I have to provide. Let's create all ghostTown which is going to be called
"Ghosty McGhostface," and the citizens are none.
There's nobody living here because it's a ghost town.
And the resources are--just got like a lot of "Tumbleweed" of 1, just tumbling around in our ghost town.
So notice how right now I've got one object created from my Town blueprint which is called anotherTown.
And in there, we've got Tom Hanks with a bunch of coconuts, and we've got another town called ghostTown
which, again, we've created from exactly the same blueprint.
But this town is completely different,
it's got a different name,
it's got no citizens, and it's got just a single tumbleweed, "Tumbleweed."
So now when we tap into our objects, let's say that in another town, we've got a new citizen who's moved
in, so we'll append "Wilson" to that town.
Whereas in the ghostTown, well, nothing really happens.
But let's say that we just decided to fortify the town.
Notice how here I'm tapping into different objects that have essentially been created from the same
blueprint.
And when I hold down option, click on each of these objects, you can see that they both have the same
data type.
They're both created from the town structure. But they are really different from each other.
They have different names, different citizens, different resources,
and I can specify which one I want to manipulate, which one I want to change, whose properties I want
to tap into.
And now, we've got essentially a whole bunch of things that we can play with by using this blueprint
as a starting point.
So now that you've learned all about structures, it's time to test your knowledge in the structures assignment
on Repl.it.
So head over there before you continue in the project.
And once you're back, I'll see you on the next lesson.