All right.
So in the previous lesson, we managed get our calculators start accumulating numbers and were able to
use any of these buttons, say,
plus, minus, times, or divide
to start accumulating a different number.
So we're ready on our way to building our calculator.
Now, in this lesson, I just want to show you there's one thing that we could do to make our code a little
bit more secure and less prone to unexpected errors,
and that is by making this variable which we're using to track whether if the user is finish typing number
to a private variable. And in order to make it private, we just add the keyword private in front of the
keyword var and this variable is now private to its current scope.
So what that means is that if you look inside the parent block, so this variable is only accessible between
these two curly braces.
And if you try to access it from anywhere else,
so, say, for example, if I was to go and create a new file, let's create a new Swift File and let's just call
it Test because we're going to delete it very soon. And inside Test, I'm going to create a new class and
this class is going to be called Test and we're not going to inherit from a superclass. We'll delete
that. And inside test, I'm going to create a new object of our viewController
and this is going to be equal to viewController.
So in the init of this class, I'm going to tap into that brand-new viewController with the lowercase "v"
and I'm going to try and tap into its isFinish,
so you can see it doesn't exist, right?
It's not letting me get into that private var at all.
But let's see if I delete that Keywood "private," and make sure that you save this viewController file
while your cursor is inside the file.
And now, if I head over to my Test.swift, then I can say viewController.isFinishedTypingNumber,
and you can see it's now accessible.
And, again, if I just go ahead and add this private over here and hit save again,
then over here, you'll see that this will soon turn into black.
Then if I hit command B to force it to build, then you can see that it says, "'isFinishedTypingNumber'
is inaccessible due to 'private' protection level."
So what exactly is this whole private protection level anyways?
So Swift has something called Access Levels. And a good analogy for access levels is kind of like the
clearance level that people working in the government, for example, have.
I don't know about you, but I watch a lot of shows that involve the CIA or the FBI or, of course,
Jack Bauer.
And what you hear very often is something like, "You don't have clearance to view this file,"
right?
And there are certain things that our top secret and only a select number of people can have access
to it and see it.
So you know common things are: are there aliens?
Did we actually land on the moon? And all of these things.
But this is exactly what Swift Access Levels do.
Now, while most programming languages have different access levels, they are slightly different from language
to language.
Now, Swift 4.2 and above have five different access levels or five different tiers of clearance if you
will.
And the first here is private.
This is, as the name suggests, very, very limiting in scope and it means that when you create a property
or method inside a block of code, then that property or method is only accessible in between the curly
braces of that block of code.
Now, the next least restrictive is something called fileprivate, and as it suggests, it means that your
property or your method is only accessible inside the file that it was declared.
So this will be your ViewController.swift or your Test.swift, and you can access a property or
a method from a different file.
Now, the third one is what's called internal and this means that your property or methods are accessible
anywhere inside your current app module.
So this is also the default level of access that all properties and methods are given.
And it means that if you don't
add the key keyword "private" or "fileprivate" in front of your "var' or your "let," then
this is exactly what it will be, it will be internal access. And it kind of makes sense,
right? By default, Xcode lets all the files in the app access all of the other properties and methods
in the app.
Now, the next level is public.
And this means that access is granted to other modules.
Now, when we were working with CocoaPods, you saw that we had a pod module and we also had our app module.
And this is exactly what the public access level was created for.
It's when you're creating frameworks or APIs, or SDKs, or libraries, basically, a bunch of code which
you want other modules to be able to tap into and use.
Now, the final one and the least restrictive access level is called open, and this is basically like public
plus,
right?
This is everything that you get in the public access level, namely the properties and methods, and everything
can be accessed by other modules.
But also it allows your classes and functions to be subclassed and overridden.
So it basically means that anybody can do anything they want
when you label something as open. Now, for your standard app development, you will only use one to three.
That's the only ones that we concern ourselves with.
But for developers who are working on frameworks, library, SDK development, then they will be looking into
using four and five.
And this is because their module that they're working on their library or their framework is going to
need to be exposed to other developers.
And the only difference between these last two levels is that public doesn't allow the class or the
function to be subclassed or overridden while open,
basically, lets you do whatever it is that you want.
So if you take a look at, for example, the Clima project that we built previously, and you look inside
the Pods modules, so everything that has a blue icon is its own module.
And remember, we mentioned that the internal or rather the default level of access, everything gets, is
module white,
right?
So that means everything that you declare within Clima will have access to everything else that is
inside Clima.
Now, in this case, when we're using pods, we actually have two modules now, right?
Pods and Clima.
And inside the Pods, one of the ones that we've incorporated is Alamofire.
And if you look inside the Alamofire code, you can see that there's public all over the place.
Literally, all of the methods that are needed when somebody incorporates the Alamofire pod is going
to be marked with public to allow this module to tap into this file
and these methods.
So coming back to our code, the best practice when you're thinking about access levels is to by default
just give everything a private keyword whenever you write a var or let or func,
so any of your own properties and methods, just write a private in front of it as well.
Now, in a lot of cases, it can't be private because you need to use it somewhere else outside its current
scope.
But if you start off with private and you level up to file private or to internal, then that means that
you are starting out by being extremely restrictive and extremely safe,
and you'll only expose your properties and your methods a little bit more as and when necessary.
So what are the advantages of marking something private anyways?
Well, it means that you can't accidentally modify something that is not meant to be modified by a different
class or from a different place.
So inside Test that I created earlier on, let's say that I tried to change is typing number to
true,
so now if we didn't have this variable marked as private, then this other class Test could legitimately
modify this property isFinishedTypingNumber to true when it's initialized.
And this is definitely not what you want, right?
We don't want this tracker to be modified by anybody else because nobody has any business in messing around
with the state of this Boolean.
It should only be accessed by this current class and only when the typing is indeed done,
so, for example, when the calc button is pressed or when the calculator is initialized from scratch.
So this should be something that is completely private to this class.
And so we should, in fact, market with a private to prevent accidental modification by other classes.
Now, this can happen accidentally.
So, say, you forget that, you know, what was the purpose of isFinishedTypingNumber, or in another case,
if you're working and you're collaborating with other developers, they might have used this name for
something else in a different class, and they accidentally modify the one in the ViewController class.
All of this can happen accidentally.
So to prevent that and to make your code safer, try to use access levels by starting out with private
for all of you "vars" and "lets," and methods, and leveling it up only when it's necessary.
All right, so let's go ahead and delete that test file because we won't need it from here onwards.
And I've got a challenge for you just so that you can play around with the code, so that you can better
understand these ideas that we've talked about in this lesson on Swift access levels.
So this is a Mac command line tool that I've created and it's got simply two files.
One is called AFile and inside AFile, there is a class, and there is also another class in the same
file.
You can see where what I'm getting at.
Now, there's also another file which has a class called AnotherClassInAnotherFile.
And inside AFile, I've created a private var, fileprivate var, and a normal var which remember is going
to default to internal.
Now, just for comparison, I've also created aLocalVariable because, remember, when we're adding access
levels,
we're only able to add it to our class properties which are, in fact, Global variables.
They're not the same as local variables.
So I want you to go through these steps 1 through to 10 and try to complete all of the instructions.
Now, in order to do this, you're going to need to initialize some objects, you're going to need to call
some methods. But, essentially, through completing these 10 steps, I want you to be able to see for yourself
just what these access levels do.
And the ones that we're going to be exploring are the ones that you're actually going to use as a app developer.
So from private, fileprivate, internal, and local.
And once you've completed this exercise, you should have dissected the differences between all of these
and understand exactly how they work and what their scopes are.
So let's go through Step 1 together, just so I can show you how to do this.
So Step1 the instruction is "Try to print aLocalVariable Here."
So you can see I've already created aLocalVariable as a var inside methodA
inside a class.
So in order to print it here, all I have to do is say "print." Now, in my print statement, that's going to get sent
to the bottom of my debug console.
I want to know where it came from.
So in addition to simply printing my aLocalVariable, I also want to say aLocalVariable printed from
methodA in AClass.
So, now here's my print statement and I have to make it work.
Now, I have to make it actually run.
So if you remember from previous lessons when we dug into intermediate Swift, we can use the Mac command
line tool by calling commands
inside this main.swift.
So in order for this methodA to be carried out, I have to initialize a new object from the class AClass,
and then call the methodA on that object.
So I can do that by saying let aClass = AClass and we'll initialize a new object from that, and then
I'm going to tap into that lower case aClass object that I just created and I'm going to call the method
methodA on it.
So, now what should happen is once I run this command line tool, it should go in and try to create a new
object from this class, and then it will run all the code inside methodA which should, hopefully, print
on a local variable to the debug console.
So let's give it a go.
All right. Great.
So it says local variable printed from methodA in AClass program ended with exit code.
So that's the end of our execution
and that is exactly what we wanted to happen.
So step one succeeds.
So next to it will mark that it is possible to print aLocalVariable within methodA within AClass.
And now I'm going to go ahead and either delete or just commented out so that you take it out of the
functioning code because if we get loads of these print statements, as you can see we've got Steps 1
through 10,
it'll get very confusing in the debug console.
Now, this is completely up to you whichever way you find easier,
but I find through testing that shouldn't get a bit confused when there's like 10 print statements.
So just go ahead and comment this out
if that helps you.
Now, in the next lesson, there is a quiz where we will test to see whether you've actually managed to
make all of these work because some of these steps are indeed possible, and some of the other ones, because
of the restrictions in access levels, are not possible.
So the idea here is that before you start executing the code and running it to prove to yourself whether
if it's possible or not, I want you to go through this step by step and try to predict whether if they should
be possible or not.
Because as always,, I think the best way to learn programming, especially, is to predict what should happen,
and then run the code and see what actually happens.
And that difference between your prediction and the actual reality narrowing that gap and trying to
make it so that there is no difference between your prediction and reality is how you really level up
as a programmer.
So Step 1 of completing this challenge is go through these Steps 1 through 10 and see what they're
trying to ask you to do,
and then using your knowledge of Swift access levels, try to predict whether if they are possible or not
in the locations that they have been specified in.
And then the next step is to go through Steps 1 through 10 and try to carry out the instructions to print
whatever it is that you need to print at the location where you're asked to print it. And then you might
need to initialize objects or call methods in order to make it show up in the debug console.
So as we're in the advance Swift section, I'm not going to give away any more solutions, and it's time
for you to mess around with the code and really learn through doing.
So pause the video now and download this file from the Course Resources List and go ahead and try to complete it.
Once you are done,
head over to the next lesson and complete the quiz, so that you can check to see if you've got all the
answers right.
All right.
So have fun.
Go ahead and do that now.