Now, in the last lesson, we've managed to brighten up our categor's view controller by assigning some
random colors to the background of the cells.
And we're persisting this data, so that every single time we open up our app or we add a new category,
the color stays consistent for each of the categories.
So the next thing I want to do is I want to go to the items or the TodoListViewController and I
want to create a slightly different effect.
I want to create a gradient effect so that, maybe, at the top, we've got one color say, blue, right? And it's
light blue.
And then through a gradient, all the items get progressively darker and darker and darker, and it'll look
like a nice gradient transition.
So let's try and see if we can figure out how to do that.
Now, back in the Chameleon Framework Documentation, you can see that they have some methods that allow
you to color a shade lighter or darker, so that will probably help us to achieve our goals.
So let's go into our TodoListViewController and go to the place where it makes the most sense
to change the background color of the cell which is, of course, inside cellForRowAt indexPath again.
Now, the place where we change the cell properties here is inside this "if-let" and we change the
textLabel's text
and we're also going to change the cell's background color.
So we're going to set the background color depending on the current indexPath. If the indexPath is,
say, 0, like the first cell, then we're not going to darken the color by very much. But if the indexPath
is much higher, say, at, you know, the tenth row, then we're going to darken it a lot more.
So it makes sense if we can change that darkening percentage based on our item number in all of the
todoItems.
So, say, if we had 10 todoItems, then we want the first item to be darkened by 10 percent.
The fifth item to be darkened by 50 percent and the last item to be darkened by, maybe, say, 100 percent.
So that way we get a nice gradient transition from the top item all the way down to the bottom item.
And we can start doing that by setting the sales background color to--
Let's just pick one from Chameleon Framework, maybe something like Flat Sky Blue, right?
It looks pretty nice.
So we can say that cell's backgroundColor = flatSkyBlue. And in order to get this color out of
Chameleon Framework, we, of course, have to remember to import it.
So there's a FlatSkyBlue. And we're going to say darken
this color by a percentage. And the percentage is going to take a CGFloat,
so that's a floating point or decimal number.
And the way that this works is it takes a number between 0 and 1, where one is basically 100 percent
and 0 is zero percent, and everything in between is your percentage as a CGFloat orCore Graphics floating
point number.
So the percentage that we want to darken our background color depends on two things.
One is which item are we currently trying to color up.
And the second thing is how many items are they in our todoList.
So let's delete this placeholder and give ourselves a bit of space in order to write out the maths.
So the percentage that we're going to darken our cell is going to be the current indexPath.row.
Say, if we're currently on the fifth row, right? Let's just imagine one particular situation, rather than
trying to plan for all the scenarios. We're currently on row number, number five, right?
And there's a total of 10 items in todoItems. So, now we're on 5 out of 10.
So we want to darken our background color by, basically, 50 percent, so close to 0.5,
and we can get that number by dividing the indexPath.row by the total number of items, right?
So todoItems.count.
Now, indexPath.row is going to be an integer
and todoItems.count is also going to be an integer.
So integer divided by integer,
that's perfectly valid.
But we need to get it out as a CGFloat in order to satisfy the requirements of this particular parameter.
So we can cast it into a CGFloat
or you might think we can. This line of code will make sense to the largest number of people. But I'm
going to show you what happens when we do this
and you might already be able to predict if you are good with the logic, and you've been keeping up with
what I've been saying. But no matter,
this line makes sense to us, right?
Take the current indexPath.row which is five, divided by 10,
you get 0.5.
And 0.5 works as a floating point percentage to darken our FlatSkyBlue color.
Now, all of this code, remember, gets called for every single cell in the tableView.
So when we are on row number one out of 10 items, then this is going to be 0.1.
And so we're only going to darken our backgroundColor by 10 percent.
Now, the problem as Xcode is suggesting to us, is that this darkoen byPercentage method returns an optional
UIColor, but this needs a definite UIColor.
So what can we do?
Well, we can, of course, use our handy "if-let," and you can see that we are now building a optional binding
pyramid. And this pattern, unfortunately, is a bit too common in Swift.
So if let colour equal all of this,
so let's cut it and paste it.
Now, we can, of course, shorten this if we don't want all of that extra commenting.
You can see that we can actually make it all fit into one line. At this point, it's telling us that your
optionally chaining todoItems here using this question mark.
So this is saying get the count if todoItems is not nil.
Now, we know that todoItems can't be nil
inside this current if-let because it's only going to get called if todoItems an indexPath.row
is not nil.
So this is a place where it's actually safe to simply force unwrap, force unwrap todoItems.
So if like let colour equal this darker color, then what we should do is we should set the cell's
backgroundColor to this color.
And now, if we run our app, you'll see something slightly peculiar happened.
So let's go into our Home category and let's add some items, shall we?
Buy Food. Eat food.
Enjoy Food.
I'm getting a peek into my mindset here.
All right, so--
Oh, there's still the separators over here, right?
So let's get rid of the separators by putting it inside viewDidLoad, tableView.separateStyle
= .none.
So we'll run that change a little bit later on.
But the more pertinent problem is, why on earth do we have the same colors, even though we told our code
to darken this FlatSkyBlue color by a percentage depending on which row we're on.
So we're expecting a gradient here,
right?
That would be nice.
So here is a fundamental logical mathematical issue with type conversions.
So I'm going to print two things here.
I'm going to print, say, "version 1" and version 1 is going to be what we've got here.
indexPath.row / todoItems.count, and then the result of that division turned into
a CGFloat.
And the second version or "version 2" is going to be slightly different.
What if we first turn indexPath.row into a CGFloat by casting it, and then after we've turned
it into a float, do we divide it by todoItems.count,
And because we can only do division between similar types,
right,
as it says, "Binary operator / cannot be applied to different types,"
then we're also going to convert todoItems.count into a CGFloat as well.
So the important difference between version 1 and version 2, is that version 1
we're doing whole number divided by a whole number, and the result gets turned into a CGFloat,
version 2 is whole number gets turned into a CGFloat, whole number gets turned into a CGFloat,
then CGFloats are divided by CGFloats.
So let's go ahead and hit run and see what we get printed out for every single row in our table view.
So let's, again, go into Home where we've already got three items,
and let's take a look over here.
So version 1 for the first row, indexPath is 0, 0 divided by 3 is still going to be 0,
so both of them are 0.0.
Now, the differences come in the second row where the index top row is equal to 1. 1 divided by 3 is a
third or 0.3 recurring.
But that only gets shown in our second version, not our first version. Our first version is still 0.
Now why is that?
Well, when you divide a whole number by a whole number, the output here gets rounded into a whole number,
and then that rounded whole number gets turned into a floating point.
So you can try it yourself inside Swift Playgrounds, but this is, essentially, the reason why our code
does not work.
And this is a very, very simple reason why sometimes when you work with floats and doubles, and trying to
use variables that are integers, you might get unexpected problems.
So this is something that happens to a lot of people and we're simply going to replace that inside here
where it says byPercentage.
Okay. So, now I'm going to comment out my print statements because we no longer need them. And I'm going
to run our app
and we are going to hope for the best.
All right.
So let's go inside Home, and dun-dud-dun,
Isn't that cool?
And as we add more items--
I don't know. "Eat more food."
"I'm so hungry."
"Feed me."
You can see the gradient starts building up, and depending on which road we're on, it will darken it by
the percentage determined by which row it is in the total number of items.
So this is looking pretty neat, right?
Now, there's just one problem, and the problem is that this part gets so dark that we can't actually see
the text anymore.
Yeah, it looks pretty neat and it's pretty.
But as we always say, you should choose function over form,
right?
Unless we can have both.
So what do we need to happen in order for our app to work well?
Well, we will need the text for the darker backgrounds to be white instead of black, and the text for
the lighter backgrounds to be black instead of white,
so how can we do this?
Well, we can either Google for it and look through custom solutions or why don't we just see if Chameleon
Framework already has a method that does it.
If it doesn't, we'll build a custom solution. But if it does, let's not reinvent the wheel.
And if you scroll through that documentation, you'll come across this neat little thing called contrasting
text. And it means that you no longer have to worry about the text
standing out from the background color because it's going to take care of it for you.
So let's try and figure out where it allows us to do that.
So I'm just going to go for command F to find contrasting text. Contrasting Text. Contrasting colors.
Okay. So this contrasting color feature returns either a dark color or light color depending on what
the Chameleon algorithm believes is a better choice.
And we can use it by using UIColor(contrastingBlackOrWhiteColorOn:UIColor, isFlat,
true or false,
or we can just use the shorthand contrast color passing in the current background color and specifying
whether it should be flat or not flat.
So let's go ahead and implement that in our code.
So inside the same place where we did the optional binding, where we specify the background color, we're
going to change the cell's textLabel.textColor. And that textColor is going to be equal to
ContrastColorOf backgroundColor.
So we're going to pass in our backgroundColor that we generated up here and return a flat color or not
a flat color,
we're going to set equal
true.
And now let's run our app and see the magic happen.
Nice, right?
Looks pretty sweet.
Now, you can see that they're all white because the flat sky blue is a little bit dark of a color by
itself, and the white stands out quite nicely against it.
So this algorithm behind the scenes is trying to figure out whether it's white or black is the more
optimal choice.
So if we went for a slightly lighter color from the palette, instead of flat sky blue, say, something like, I don't know,
a flat white,
right?
Let's try that one, FlatWhite.
This is making me want coffee now.
Okay, so let's go ahead and hit run. And you can see that, automatically, the lighter colors at the top were
given black text colors, and the darker colors at the bottom were given white text colors.
So it's pretty neat, right? Now, it's all very well and good
specifying a color and getting it darkened by percentage.
Wouldn't it be nice if you could carry through the color of the category, so the user will select Home
and this will be a gradient of green colors similar to our Home color.
So what you'll need to do is to, somehow, change this to the color that we persisted using Realm.
So pause the video and try and see if you can complete this challenge.
All right.
So this one shouldn't be too hard because if you remember we passed in the current category using the
selectedCategory property, and this is a optional category that contains all the pieces of data in here,
so the name of the category, as well as the color of the category as a string.
So if we go in here and replace this FlatWhite using something like UIColor, using hexString,
and the string is going to come from our selectedCategory.colour property.
Now, we've got some problems here because if you click on the error, it says that selectedCategory is--
It says that--it tells us that selectedCategory,
the first little highlight, is an optional category and it's not unwrapped.
The other problem is that the output or the return of this initializer create a UIColor using
hexString is also a optional UIColor, and it's also not unwrapped.
So there's two ways of solving this.
You can either go down a pretty steep if-let pyramid,
if let color equals this,
then if let blah-blah-blah.
And then if let, the next one,
then if let, the next one, unwrapping each property as you go along.
But let's go back to first principles
where inside this if let
at the moment, and checking to see if todoItems at indexPath.row is or is not nil.
Now, if this is not nil, then that means that we manage to have items inside todoItems, then that means
todoItem exists. And todoItems comes from our selectedCategory which must mean that selectCategory
can't be nil either.
So sometimes having these warnings forces you, as a human developer, to think and see if this is safe
to be unwrapped.
Now we've unwrapped selectedCategory.
The next thing we need to tackle is, what if we can't actually get a color from this hextString?
What if I just entered some piece of, you know, mumbo-jumbo of a hexString, and you can't actually get a
hex color?
And this is a problem you always have when you allow strings because strings can be free form.
It doesn't have to conform to a particular format.
Then I could have put in any old string in here.
And of course, you can't just generate a color from any string.
That's not how it works.
It has to be a valid hexString.
Now, we don't have any validation for that.
But what we can say is if this is nil, then don't go forwards with the next method,
i.e., darkened by percentage.
So we're saying optionally chain this.
So if this is not nil, i.e., we got a valid hex code creating a valid UIColor and it's not nil, then go
forwards and try to darken it. Because if we try to darken a nil value, then this is where our app is going
to crash.
So we're using optional chaining to make sure that all of this is not nil before we continue with our
code block.
So let's run our app and see if we manage to carry forwards that color from the category to our
TodoListViewController.
All right.
So here's our Home category which is green and if we click on it-- Oh, look. Isn't that nice?
We've got a gradient of green items
and we've got text that's contrasting with the background color, and it looks pretty neat to me at least.
So did you manage to get that to work?
If so, then great.
If not, then you might need to watch some of the past videos
a few more times.
All right.
In the next lesson, we're going to tidy everything up and we're going to change our nav bar to make it
reflect the colors that we've got in our
TodoListViewController.
So all of that and more, we'll see you on the next lesson.