So this is pretty much something that applies to the Apple app store more than anything else.
And it's this key line "Only on the App Store".
Now if you have a look at the home screen on the featured page, at the top you'll see an app being featured
on a wide banner. And very frequently if you look at the bottom of the banner there is this line "Only
on the App Store".
And this is where the app is only available on the Apple platform.
The editors at the app stores actively look for apps that are doing really well but are as of yet not
available anywhere else. And this effect contributes to why all of those Android users out there are
getting their apps
you know maybe a year later or two years later.
And it's because when you are being considered for feature on the App Store, you'll get a call from the
App Store manager and one of the questions that they will ask you is "Are you exclusive to the Apple
App Store?"
And at this point you want to be able to say yes, hell yes, we are.
We love Apple so much.
Please feature us.
Maybe you want to play it a little bit cooler than that. But it is something that's really important to
them for whatever reason
I'm going to add to the conjecture.
This is why a lot of app developers especially game developers, even if they have the resources will
first develop and launch on the iOS App Store, and then work on the Android version.
So a lot of people have questions as to should I develop the iOS or Android? or which one should I
do first?
And this is one of the things that will determine your answer to that question.