One of the most common questions that we get from students is what is the easiest way to place those
mockups into real products like iPhones or having it in somebody's hands?
Well there's a website called www.placeit.net which makes it pretty simple for you to just drag
and drop your app mockup into a whole bunch of images so that you can show off you know the app being
in use by a real person.
Now I think they do charge for this service.
So an alternative if you are happy using Sketch is going on to a www.sketchappsources.com and you'll be able
to find quite a few mockups where you can simply just drag and drop your mockups into the iPhone frame
or any of the other frames.
All right. So enough watching me doing things. It's time for you to build up your mockup for your recipe
app.
Now you've already created the use of flow diagram,
you already know how the navigation is going to work.
You've then gone on to create a wireframe using pencil and paper.
Now the next step is turning that concept into beautiful photorealistic mockups using some of the tools
and methods that we discussed in this module.
So if you have access to a Mac then use some of those methods
I showed you just now in order to create your mockup using Sketch.
Now if you don't have access to Sketch I'm going to show you something else that you can use.
So if you have a Mac then go ahead and download the trial version of Sketch 3 and have a play around
with it.
Try using some of the methods that I showed you in this module and create your beautiful mockup using
Sketch.
Now if you don't have a Mac or access to Sketch, then you can use Canva as we showed you in the previous
lesson.
Alternatively I've listed some other websites and tools that you can have a look at in the text box
below.
But either way, you'll be able to turn those wireframes into beautiful high fidelity mockups.
So go ahead.