Now I've been talking about the Apple App Store and the Google Play store and there are a lot of things
that are common to both
for example keyword research or traffic versus difficulty.
But there are a few things that are different between the two of them
and this is just a table that summarizes some of those things.
So for example Apple app store
gives you more characters in the app name but Google only gives you 30 characters.
The other thing that's really important is your description.
Now in the Google Play store that is pretty much where most of your keywords will get taken out of
whereas on the Apple App Store it doesn't impact your keyword ranking so much although we are seeing
it becoming picked up. For the Apple App Store
as we mentioned before the majority of the keywords will come from the keywords field which is limited
to 100 characters whereas the Google Play store does not have a place where you can enter your keyword.
It has to be like a website.
They gather the information on the words that appear the most frequently in your app name and in your
description.
And the closer to the beginning of each of those fields the heavier the words are weighted.
Now the other thing that's really interesting is that words are counted as keywords in places that you
won't expect.
So for example when you name your in-app purchases, you'll think that "Oh you know I'm just going to come
up with a name that makes the most sense" but in fact those also count as keywords.
So make those names something that you want to rank for.
And finally through observing a lot of app performance on the Google Play and Apple app stores, you can
actually see that the things that people write in their reviews actually count towards your keywords.
Now obviously this is something that you can't control unless you decide to go and pay people for reviews.
But it's something just to be aware of and the reason why we know this is because somebody wrote on
the Pandora app, they wrote a review saying "I hate this app.
I prefer Spotify." And you start seeing the Pandora app appear when you search for Spotify which is really
interesting.
So this is just a couple of differentiation between ASO on the Apple App Store and the Google Play
store.
As always, study the platform that you're going to target and really understand how it works. For both
of these app stores listing your app on it is pretty straightforward.
The platform guides you through it's just filling in a whole bunch of fields but the intricacies lies
in knowing which fields get counted towards your keywords and how to make those keywords count towards
getting your ranking higher.