All right.
So the next thing I want to talk about is paid advertising.
Now if you watched the module on growth hacks to get downloads, you'll realize that there are a lot of
free options that you can explore and play around with before you have to start forking out cash.
Now your-- now your motivations for going down the paid advertising route should not be for vanity i.e.
you have no users, you need users fast, pay Facebook and Google a load of money in order to buy those
users.
No. Instead it has to be a calculated decision where you figure out how much on average can you monetize
per user and what is the maximum cost of user acquisition you can stomach in order to continue bringing
in profits.
So once you've answer those questions, once you're at a stage where you know how much per user makes you,
then you can start exploring paid advertising.