All right.
So you've watched me do a lot of hard work.
It's now your turn.
So going back to that recipe app that you've already fleshed out, so you've already got to use a flow
diagram, you've created the wireframes, you've created mockups for them and now it's time to create the
prototype.
So using one of the software that we mentioned either using Keynote or using Marvel, you can start creating
some fully functional apps.
And the nice thing about Marvel is that you can actually put it onto your phone.
There's a Marvel app that you can download for free from both the Android and iOS app stores.
And then if you log into your account you'll be able to use your prototypes on your phone and you can show
other people with it as well.
So I'm going to share the URL of the workout prototype that I've created in the text box below in
a link. So feel free to go and have a look at it and see if you can be inspired as to how you're going
to create your recipe app prototype.
So once again if you're particularly proud of your design we would love to give it a shout out.
So just share your links in the comment box below.
And as always, if you have any questions or anything that's unclear, feel free to leave us a comment.
So that's pretty much all from me.
I'll see you on the next lesson.