So as we said previously when we spoke about how to figure out if your app icon is optimal or if your
description is optimal,
the key to any sort of successful marketing is split testing. It's actual scientific experiments that
get you results.
So it's the same thing with your Facebook ads.
Don't just make a single ad copy. Make ten, make twenty.
Make sure that you have different descriptions for each of the ads.
Make sure you have different images or you can have different text for the button for the action button.
So for example, the get off a button probably will convert more people than the like page button.
And Facebook allows you to do split testing quite easily.
You basically just create a whole bunch of ads and it shows you which ones are getting more clicks, which
ones are people lingering over,
which ones are converting more people. And that is crucial data that they're going to use in order to
refine the ads and also get a higher conversion rate.
So remember when we spoke about using the cheaper CPM or cost per thousand people or cost per thousand
impression way of advertising?
Well this is where you optimize your ad so that you make those 1000 people really count and you grab
a high proportion of those people's attention.
So one of the things that we tend to do is that if we're launching an app that is in a particular niche
say using our coffee example, I will go and like every single other app that is within the same niche.
Because once you've like those pages, every single time they put on a sponsored ad you will see it. And
you can look at how some of these big spenders are structuring their ads. What are the app icons they're
using,
what are the images that they're using,
what are they writing in their description,
So for somebody like Clash of clans or mobile strike, you can bet that they've thrown millions and millions
plus a load of people's time into optimizing these ads.
These ads have been split test to death and you can benefit from their ad budget by trying to figure
out what it is about these ads that work.
Maybe it's because of the annotations,
maybe it's because of the human faces. Whatever it is try and benefit from your competitors ad budget
by figuring out how they're split testing has resulted in the ways that they are advertising.