All right. So another day, another new challenge.
So the next thing that we want you to do is to use that Flower Classifier in order to classify the image
that we got back from the imagePicker.
So we want to create a method called detect that takes a single CIImage that's going to be called
Flower Image and we're going to pass in the image that we got back from the imagePickerController and
to change the title of navigation bar to the name of the flower that we detected.
All right.
So this is the end result that you're aiming for after you complete this coding challenge.
So we still have our blank user interface.
And if I tap on camera and I take a picture of these flowers that around me and I hit Use Photo, you'll
be able to see the classification of that flower at the top of the navigation bar.
So we're not doing anything that's different or new from previous modules when we used CoreML, so try
and see if you can code up this functionality, and I'm going to guide you through the steps that you'll
need to take.