So that was a bit of theory behind how different colors can be combined to look pleasing to the eye
and achieve certain effects.
But as a busy app developer or entrepreneur, you might not have the time to sit there and combine different
hex codes so tweak it ever so slightly and perform experiments with some of these color theories.
So what can you do to be lazy?
Let me show you some of my favorite tools in terms of providing color palette for my design projects.
One of my favorite websites is colorhunt.com and you'll be able to find the links to all of these
tools that I talk about in the text box below.
Now we're not sponsored by anybody that I mention here.
It's just tools that I really like and can be used quite easily and can be really really helpful when
you're designing apps or websites.
So colorhunt.com is a place where professional designers go to curate their favorite color palettes
and you can search them by hot or popular or random. And depending on the mood of the color palette, you
can find one that fits your particular project.
Now if you're even lazier than this and can't be bothered to browse through thousands of thousands of
color palette, there's another solution for you called flatuicolors.com and this is a 15 color
palette that was formulated to work especially well on the iOS platform.
So you'll see a lot of apps on the iOS app stores that use these exact shades and exact tones from this
website.
For example if you ever looked at the first seven minute workout app, they pretty much just use all of
these colors in their color palette.
That tends to mesh really well on the iOS App Store.
Now similarly for Android designers out there,
you've got something called materialpalette.com which is a website that allows you to pick two different
colors from all of these rather androidy looking colors and it automatically generates for you
a 8-color palette complete with an accent tone. So it's really helpful and really useful for making your Android
designs.
And one final tool that I'm going to talk about that I really love is a free Chrome and Firefox browser
extension called ColorZilla. And it basically just acts as a little color dropper that sits in your browser.
So when you come across a website that has a particularly nice color palette and you want to find out
what is the hex code of the color that they're using so that you can use it in your later project,
you can use ColorZilla to spy and save that hex code for later use.
So by using a combination of some of these tools as well as the theory behind mixing and matching different
colors and the mood of different colors, you should be up to arrive at a color palette that is suitable
for your app project and makes your app look appealing as well as to evoke a certain idea or emotion within your
user.
And the next module we're going to talk about typographic and how to combine different fonts.