All right.
So what are we making
exactly?
Well, in the later seasons, Season 4 of Silicon Valley, there was an app that Jìan-Yáng created called
the Seafood app.
Now, if you are as big of a fan of Silicon Valley, as we are, then you will be completely up to date and
know exactly what I'm talking about,
so you can just go ahead and skip to the next lesson.
Now, if you're new to the show or if you don't know what I'm talking about, I'm going to show you a quick
clip that demonstrates what exactly the app does.
Okay, it's ready.
Please, God.
-What would you say if I told you there's an app on the market...
-Well, pass that part, just demo it.
Okay. Let's start with a hotdog.
-Oh, yes.
-It works!
-Do pizza.
-Yes, do pizza.
-Pizza.
-Not hotdog?
-Wait. What the [REMOVED]?
-Huh?
-That's... that's it.
It only does hotdogs?
-No.
And a not hotdog.
All right.
So you've seen the Silicon Valley version.
Let's look at the version that we'll be building.
So this is what our app will look like. And when you tap on the camera button in the navigation bar, you'll
be able to take a photo of something and click, use photo, and it will show you whether if that image
was classified as a hotdog or as not a hotdog.
So let's try out some test pictures.
So I've got a Google image of a hotdog here, and I'm going to click Use Photo, and there we go.
It's a hotdog.
Correct.
Now, I've also got a Google image of myself and I'm going to try it out, so I could really be shooting
myself in the foot if this classifies as a hot dog,
But let's click Use Photo, and not a hotdog.
I'm so happy.
All right cool.
So you've seen what the app does.
Let's go and create it.