Now the second easiest way and especially if you're not making an ioS app is using something called
Start bootstrap.
So they basically have free for commercial use bootstrap templates and you can browse all of these by
giving here and you can see various website layouts.
Now once you're happy with one of these templates so you can have a look at the live preview or the
demo page over here.
And this is basically what your website will look like. It's got little description, links, images, get
it on Google Play, get it on the Apple App Store, various icons etc.
So really nice website
and I'm going to show you just how easy it is to modify this so that you keep the designs but you just
change the content to your own.
So the first thing you want to do is going to head over to startbootstrap.com, find the template that
you want and then go ahead and click download.
So once the zip file has downloaded just go ahead and unzip it. And then you're going to need a code
editor.
Now if you have Sublime Text installed or if you have, my personal favorite, Atom installed then you can
go head to just open the files in those text editors.
If you don't have one, then my recommendation is to get the free Atom text editor. It's made by the same guys
at GitHub
and I've been using it for a while and it works beautifully.
So go ahead and do that.
But they do only have it for Mac. So if you're a PC guy then Sublime Text is probably the next best solution.
Right.
So once you've extracted that file then you'll have a folder called startbootstrap-new-age
and inhere here you're going to see a file called index.html.
So you right click on it to open it with Chrome.
So it's my default
but it might not be yours.
Then you'll see this website displayed locally.
But what we're going to do-
So what we're going to do is we're going to keep that page open and we're going to edit it. And in order
to do that we're going to use our text editor or Atom.
So I'm going to right click on index.html and open it inside
Atom.
So now this is the HTML file of my website essentially and I'm going to use this local version,
you can tell because the URL is not www but in fact it's a file directory that I've got locally.
So now we want to change our website to make it our own.
So the first thing I want to do is I want to change the Start bootstrap logo to say London App Brewery or
use your app name.
So you're going to do it.
So are you going to do is you're going to--
So what you gonna do is you're going to right click on this start bootstrap part and you're going to
click on inspect to look at the HTML code. Ad here it shows you what is the ID of that section
and it's called navbar-brand.
So we're going to head over to Atom now and we're going to go command + F in order to search for navbar
-brand. Hit enter.
There we go.
That's that corresponding part of code that we saw over here.
And we're going to change the part where it says start bootstrap to whatever it is that we want.
So London App Brewery.
There we go.
And then I'm going to hit command s to save and if I go over here and I hit refresh then you'll see that
change in the code reflected here.
Now let's go ahead and change this bit as well.
So remember we're going to select it, right click, inspect, see what that's called. And it's under an
h1 in the div header-content-inner.
So let's go ahead and find header-content-inner and there it is and there is that h1.
So to edit it you're going to select everything that is not a tag i.e. not something with angle brackets
and you're going to just change that text to Hello World.
This is this is how much imagination programmers have.
So we've changed the text that we wanted to say and then I'm going to hit command s again to save, go
here and refresh command + r to refresh.
Voila! You've got a new description.
Now what about the image?
Let's do the same thing. Right click on the image,
hit inspect and see what it's called.
So the image source is in an image folder and the image name is demo-sscreen-1.jpeg.
So we're going to go and change that image to something that we want displayed over there.
So in my downloads folder I've got one of my apps screenshots and it's just called screenshot.
Now I can find that inside Atom by just looking in my downloads folder and you can see that image screenshot
right here.
Now if you expand the folder called startbootstrap-new-age where all of the files that
I used to create your website are located, there is that folder called image that we saw earlier.
And the one that's currently being displayed is something called demo-screen-1.
So that's that image over here.
And what we're going to do is we're going to replace this image with our image.
So in order to do that the easiest thing is for me to first rename my screenshot to demo-screen
-1.
I'm going to hit save.
Now I'm going to delete this image.
So that was the old version.
Move to trash. And then I'm going to put my new demo-screen-1 in there and
I'm going to hit
command + s
to save.
And then we're going to go and refresh our website and you can see.
And there we go.
There's on you screenshot on our beautiful web site.
So basically you can go through this bootstrap template changing anything and everything that you want.
And essentially all you're doing is just right clicking on something that you want to change.
So this currently is a link that just redirects back to the home page.
Now we want it to go towards our download link.
So let's again inspect the element.
So it's called badge-link.
So then we go back to our index.html and we find badge-link and you can see those two badge
links.
One is the image for the Google Play badge and the other one is the App Store badge.
And at the moment the href or the URL is redirecting back to the top of the home page.
So instead, let's do something else. Let's paste in the iTunes link for the Pokemon go app and let's
hit save and let's go back over here and hit refresh and then we're going to click on this one which
we edited and as you can see it redirects to the link that we wanted to go to.
Okay. So once you're done with fiddling around with all of this, the next thing that we're going to do is
we're going to publish it.
Now you might have heard that hosting domain fees etc. are all a hassle and very difficult.
Well I'm going to show you a really really easy way of getting your website published in literally four
or five clicks.
So the first thing you going to do is you're going to set up a GitHub account if you don't already
have one.
Now once you've done that, what you're going to do is you're going to create a new repository. And in this
repository we're going to save all the files that are related to our website.
Now the important part is how you name this repository.
And the first part is putting in your username.
So here it's my username and then it's .github.io.
So this is going to be the URL of your website.
Now you can leave the description blank, leave it as public, and then hit create repository.
Now here is your repository. Now if you're familiar with Git and you're familiar with terminal then go
ahead and set it up however you like. But if you are a beginner then just follow along with me and we're
going to use a really simple way of doing this.
So the first thing you need to do is download something called GitHub desktop.
Now the download link for Mac is desktop.github.com and you can just go ahead and click that.
Now if you're using Windows you can get it for Windows as well.
Now once you've downloaded that just go ahead and extract and install it.
It should be pretty simple.
So next, once you've installed that you're going to have a welcome screen that helps you set up
your GitHub account.
So here you put in your GitHub account details.
So now we're going to add all of our website files that we edited earlier on into this repository.
And then you're going to choose that folder where you've got all the website files so it was called
startbootstrap-new-age.
So in order to commit it we're going to add a commit message which is going to be something like First
commit. And then we're going to get commit to master and then we're going to go and hit publish.
So once the publishing has completed then you can head over to your favorite browser then you're going
to type in that repository name that you created earlier on.
So it was your username,
so for mine it was angelabauer.github.io and if you hit enter then magically you'll see your
brand new website that you've created appear online and anybody can go there to angelabauer.github
.io and see your product page and everything will be exactly as you created it.
Now if you want to buy a custom domain and set it up with GitHub pages then it is also possible and
I'll link to a GitHub help page for that particular feature in the text below.
But essentially the point is there are so many beautiful bootstrap templates out there and you can edit
them very easily with a text editor and you can get them published and online within a few minutes.
So always go for the low hanging fruit and you don't need anybody to create a beautiful website for
you.
You can do that very easily nowadays.
So if you come along with me this far, I hope you enjoyed the course and I wish you all the best for your
own app launch.
If you are ready to publish and launch your app, do get in touch with us and we'll try our best to spread your
word far and wide and shout about it to everybody we know.
So thanks for watching and I hope I'll see you on one of our other courses soon.