Okay. So what do you do once you've created the landing page and you've demonstrated that people are interested
in it?
Do you go ahead and pour in you know 30 grand 40 grand to build the app?
Or do you, you know, go ahead and spend six months or a year of your time and build a full blown version straight
away?
Probably not.
So the next step after you've demonstrated interest in your product is actually building what's called
a minimum viable product.
And this comes from you know the lean startup kind of methodology where you really don't assume anything
about your users or about your buyers and let them guide you in your development cycles.
So I'm going to bring back this example of Great little Place which is an app that allows you to discover
essentially cool things to do in London.
And it's I think it's user submitted with a little bit of curation as well.
And the reason I want to talk about it is because we saw earlier on how they collected emails through
their landing page and gathered interest in this app but they didn't go straight away
jumping into building the app. Instead what they did was spent you know five 10 minutes maybe building
a Facebook page.
And what they did was they use this to validate the concept even further.
So by having a page called "I know this great little place in London..." they publish posts on discoveries
or places, let other people of the community join and publish their own little tidbits of local knowledge
and they can look at how many people are interested in this.
How many people are reacting to the post,
how many people are liking the page, following the page and really being able to build a community around
this concept, being able to demonstrate that it works that people are interested in discovering these
little bits of no local knowledge.
It's very easy sometimes as a founder to get really carried away with your idea and believe that the
whole world needs it and it's obviously going to be a huge hit before you've demonstrated any of this.
Instead, the sort of more careful way of demonstrating interest by looking at sign ups, gathering those
sign ups those emails for later use and building a MVP or minimal viable product just to test out if
the concept works
and if people would actually use in real life. And sometimes you can see that people guide your product
development. For example on the Facebook page you've got people saying "Do you have an Apple app or do
you have an Android app?"
And by looking at how many people make these kind of requests, you can see how much interest there is
because they actually you know gone off their own back to write this.
So they're clearly interested in something like that
if it were available. Now your MVP will differ depending on what kind of product you have.
So usually for a lot of these kind of services or data orientated kind of products, Facebook page
is actually a really really easy way of doing your
MVP. Now this is another company called the Jamie app which the concept is very simple. It allows you to
meet other professional in the sort of startup adjacent world.
They could be designers, product managers, certainly interesting people. And the company sets you up with
a 30 minute meeting every Friday morning and even though they're called the Jamie app, they actually
don't have an app.
Instead what they have is an MVP.
So the beginning of every week, the app will send you an email asking for your availability on Friday
at 10AM and you can say yes or no.
And if you say yes, they'll set you up with a random person to me and you say no
then they leave you alone for the week until next week.
It's basically an interesting person that they found for you and allows you to really settle on a date
and time that you're both available and then essentially meet up and meet this random person.
So instead of jumping down the route of building a really complex app or you know putting in a whole
bunch of features, this is actually the core of the product.
It's just about setting up random people to meet once a week. And doing this via just sending emails
means that there's no infrastructure, there's no investment. You don't have to build anything.
It's just a MVP.
And by doing this they've actually gathered you know tens of thousands of users and they've demonstrated
a real need in this kind of product.
So the next step of their product development cycle I presume is actually getting a bit of funding and
being able to demonstrate that traction using your MVP. Being able to show look at how many weekly users
we have and how many people we've set up already,
this is clearly a need that people have
you're far more likely to get the interest of VCs or angels and people who can help you build this into
a real fully fledged product.
So before you really jump the gun and you know build the product of your dreams, think about what it
is that other people want and try to build a core version, a stripped down version of your idea so that
it really is just one concept.
Very often when we do these large talks and when we do some of the larger courses you hear lot of people
saying you know "I have an idea that's basically like Facebook meets laptop meets Twitter and I want
to launch it in like a week and it's going to be a huge success."
Well that will take quite a lot of building time to make
right?
Why not test your idea first?
See if people actually want it. Build a you know really really stripped down version and then see how
it goes. See what other features people want instead of presuming them because no matter how hard you
try, you can't know what the--
You can't really know what the hive mind wants or what it is that you know will be a success.
So build an MVP.
Think about having a product where have all the features that you possibly want and take out one feature
at a time and keep asking people you know, would you still use this? Would you still use this? Would you
still buy this? Would you still buy this?
Until you get to the point where you have barely anything in this product and people are still willing
to use it or buy it. That is your core product, that is your core concept and build an MVP around that
and then test out and see how people respond to it.
Look at your growth, look at your traction, look at how many more sign ups you're getting every week,
look at how often people are engaging with your product whether it's on Facebook whether it's through
email. Doesn't really matter
just keep it really really simple.
Now this is a really good story.
There's a company called Gimlet that essentially makes these really great podcasts about startups about
the tech community etc. and have a whole bunch of really really good episodes.
One that I would highly recommend is a is a hour long interview with some of the previous employees
of Grooveshark which was this music streaming service.
And it's kind of a really sad story about how Grooveshark was run and how it eventually died. But the
sort of you know de-brief and analysis is really really interesting and I'll link it in the video below.
But another thing I'm going to link is on their episode where they built a minimum viable product which
is just a I think it was like a five minute video showing a prototype.
So it's not a real app, like you can't download it. It's just a bunch of images that's narrated with a voice.
And they showed this video to a bunch of listeners of their podcasts to see how many people would want
these features, which features they wanted, and they had this Google form at the end surveying essentially
what do you think is good,
what kind of features do you want
in this app, is an app even necessary?
That's always a question you should actually ask yourself before you build any app.
Should I be making an app?
Can it be a website? Can it be simpler?
But essentially they used the survey to gather feedback on their minimum viable product. And it's a really
good story or description on how the whole process works.
And I would highly recommend if you have a few minutes to spare
have a listen to that.