All right, let's talk a bit about typography.
Now whenever I mentioned typography, students always say "Oh my God. There's so many fonts.
How the hell do I pick and choose between them?
And does it really even matter at the end of the day.
I just choose one that I think is pretty. Isn't that good enough?"
Well typography is really important for a number of reasons.
I mean first they consider this.
You know if you write a love letter to your beloved and you know you write something like "you'll always
be mine."
Using one particular font will achieve something very different from using a different font.
So even if you're never going to design anything for print or for digital it's important to know how
to use and how to combine different fonts
so at least you won't come across as a creepy serial killer.