All right. So I hope you gave that ago.
And now I'm going to show you the solution.
All right.
So I'm going to pull up Terminal and I'm going to navigate to where our WhatFlower is located.
So it's this directory that contains the WhatFlower Xcode project, and I'm just going to drag it into my
Terminal.
So here I'm going to do part in it to create a new pod file,
as you can see up here, and then I'm going to say open Podfile using the application Xcode-beta.
So for you, it should actually be Xcode. If you're working with the beta,
then it will be like this.
So next I'm going to comment out the platform and the pods
I'm going to use are pod 'Alamofire' and, of course, we're going to specify the version which was
4.4.
And then the other part that we needed was SwiftyJSON.
All right, cool.
So that's what we need. You can hit Save, Close, and then we're going to go back to our Terminal and say pod
install.
All right.
And it's done.
So, now we've got our What Xcode project workspace created and that's what we're going to launch.
So this is the one that's going to contain our pods
if you remember.
All right, cool.
And let's just check to make sure that we can actually import Alamofire.
There it is.
And import SwiftyJSON.
There it is as well.
OK.
So they're both included.
I'm happy with that. That's done.
So if you're confused at all about CocoaPods, then have a look back at the modules where we explored
them in detail. On the next lesson,
I'm going to show you the structure for the API call from Wikipedia and we're going to start getting
some information back.
I'll see you there.