All right.
So, now that we've gotten our UIImagePickerController set up and ready to go,
and we've also incorporated our Inception v3 machine learning model,
we're ready to start getting some interpretations using that model.
So the first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to go just below where we set the image views image
property to the image that the user picked,
we're going to convert this UIImage into a CIImage which stands for Core Image image and that's a special
type of image that allow us to use the Vision framework and the CoreML framework in order to get
an interpretation from it. To do that, all we need to write is let ciimage,
so we'll just call it ciimage,
you can call it whichever you like,
equal Core Image image, open bracket, and the image that we're going to be using to process is that
userPickedImage that we got from earlier on.
So the code as it is is fine and it will work, but I'm going to add a little security feature in order
to make it a little bit safer.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to add a "guard" statement in front of the "let," and then I'm going
to write an "else" statement that will trip if this part fails, i.e., if it's unable to convert our UIImage
that the user picked into a CIImage.
Now, that shouldn't really happen, but if it does, we want to trigger a fatalError
and we also want to write a message saying something like, "Could not convert to CIImage," so that we
know exactly what's happening.
All right. So, now that we've converted our UIImage into a CIImage, we're going to create a method
that will process that CIImage and get an interpretation or classification out of it.
So I'm going to write this just above my cameraTapped IBAction.
I'm going to create a new method and the method is going to be called detect and it's going to take
only one parameter and the parameter is going to be called image and the data type will be a CIImage.
And what I'm going to do inside this method is I'm going to use the Inception v3 model.
So all you have to do is to create a new object, going to be called model, and we're going to use the
and VNCoreMLModel as a container for our mlmodel and our model is called Inceptionv3.
So in this part where you've got a placeholder for mlmodel, you're going to write the model that was
generated when we dragged and dropped in this Inceptionv3 mlmodel.
So you can see it's already autosuggesting, but you can also find out if you just click on this little
arrow here and you can see that our class that was generated is called Inceptionv3 and it's got a property
called model.
So, now we've got Inceptionv3 creating a new object and we're tapping into its model property. So, now
we have created a object called model using the VNCoreMLModel container and creating a new
object of Inceptionv3 and getting its model property loaded up.
So, basically, this model is now what we're going to be using to classify our image.
Now, you'll see that if you write this line, you're going to get an error, and it's saying that this line
of code can throw an error and we're not handling it at all.
So let's go ahead and handle that by typing
"try?" in front of this.
So when we add "try?" it's going to attempt to perform this operation that might throw an error. If this
operation succeeds, then the result is going to be wrapped as a optional.
But if it fails, i.e., if there was an error that was thrown, then the result of this line will be nil.
So to guard against those situations where this fails and we end up getting a model that is nil, we don't
want to do any more image processing with something that with a nil model.
So if our app does crash under those conditions, we want to know exactly why it did, so we want to send
an error message to our debug console.
So to do this, I'm going to wrap everything inside a "guard" statement.
So, now instead of "if let," I've got "guard let." And this means that if my model is nil, then I'm going to
trigger an "else" statement that is going to throw a fatalError, giving me the message that, maybe, "Loading
CoreML Model failed." That way I'll get it printed in my deep console and I'll know exactly which part
of my code failed.
So, it's basically a way of allowing your app to exit, giving you plenty of information about what caused
it to exit or to crash.
And in fact, if you think about it, in this case, we could probably also benefit from wrapping it inside
a "guard" statement because in the cases where we can actually convert our UIImage into a CIImage successfully,
then we could end up crashing our app without knowing what caused it.
So let's do the same.
So if you remember how to add the "guard" statement and how it worked, then pause the video and add it now.
So we want to throw a fatalError telling us in the debug console that we couldn't convert the UIImage
into a CIImage.
Now, if you don't remember how to do that,
I'm going to show it to you now.
So instead of simply "let," we're going to call it "guard let,"
and it's going to evaluate this statement. If it's true, then it's simply going to do nothing. But if it's false,
then we're going to trigger this "else" statement.
So instead of an is--
So instead of an "if else," it's a "guard else. And in here, we're going to throw a fatalError
that tells us that we could not convert UIImage into a CIImage.
So, now if our app crashes because this failed, we'll know exactly what happens because we have that message
in there.
So you might be wondering where this VNCoreMLModel comes from.
Well, it actually comes from the vision framework. It allows us to perform an image analysis requests
that uses our CoreMLModel to process images.
So the next thing that we're going to do is we're actually going to use this model that we're certain
exists because this part didn't trip and our app didn't exit.
So the next part will only happen if this was not nil.
So here, we're going to create a Vision CoreMLRequest.
So we're going to call it request and it's going to equal VNCoreMLRequest
and we're going to use the one that has a completion handler.
We're going to hit into the model that we're going to be using is, of course, this model that we created
earlier on.
And if you now just click on this  VNRequestCompletionHandler? placeholder and hit enter,
it'll insert the code automatically for you.
So, now as a part of our completion handler, we're going to get two things back.
One is the request.
So we're going to call it simply request.
The next thing is an error,
so we're going to call this error. And the code that we want to happen inside this completion block, i.e.,
when that request has completed is to process the results of that request.
So to do that, we're going to create an object called results,
so let results = request.
So that comes from the completion handler callback .results.
And as you can see at the moment, its data type is an array of any objects.
So we're going to make that little bit more specific
by, again, using the "as?" and instead of being an array of any data type, we're going to make
it an array of VNClassificationObservations.
And this is a class that holds classification observations after our models been processed.
So, again, we want to use a guard to make sure that if this fails, our code exits, and we know why it failed.
So go ahead and wrap this line inside a "guard" statement as we did before.
Pause the video and try it out.
All right.
So as we did before, all we need to do is add the "guard" in front of the "let."
I'm going to add an "else" statement that addresses what should happen when that fails.
So, again, we're going to trigger a fatalError and the message is going to say, maybe, "Model failed to
process
image."
But if it succeeds, then we should have this object called results which we should be up to print out
into the console in order to see what results we got back.
The last thing that we need to do is to actually perform this request.
So you might notice that this request has a model associated with it, but it doesn't actually know which
image to perform that classification request on.
So this is what we're going to address now.
We're going to create a handler that specifies the image we want to classify.
So I'm going to write let händler = VNImageRequestHandler and it's going to take a ciimage,
and the image that we're going to input in here is the one that was passed into this method as a parameter,
so the CIImage that we're going to pass in, and that image is going to come from, of course, over here.
So we're going to call that method in here a little bit later on.
So the image that the user picked gets converted into ciimage, then gets passed into this method
as a CIImage, and then gets put into this handler to specify that it's the one that we want to classify
using our machine learning model.
So I'm going to use the parameter name, of course, which is image, and there is my image handler,
and now all I need to do is just to write try using my handler to perform the request which is, of course,
this request that we created early on.
So this line of code will work as long as you don't get any errors here.
Now, as you can see, we've got the exclamation mark after the try
which means that we're forcing it to execute this line.
But instead, the safer way to do this would be to wrap this execution inside a "do catch" block.
So if you don't remember from previously,
all you need to do is write the keyword "do," and then enclose whatever you want to try
inside the do block. And then you have another keyword called "catch" which catches any errors that are thrown.
And if there are any errors, then we want to print them into the console. And that's all you need to do
in order to use a machine learning model to classify your image.
So the last thing we need to do before we can run our app and test it out is that we actually need to
call this beautiful method that we've just created. At the moment,
it's not called anywhere,
and we won't get any results back if we run it now.
And in fact, you can see that this warning here is sort of giving you a hint as to the fact that maybe
you have a bug in your code, because it's saying that this CIImage that you created was never used
anywhere. It says, here's a fix,
instead of giving it a name, just make it a Boolean test.
But that's actually not what we want,
it's onto the right problem,
we haven't used this anywhere in our code, but it suggested fix is not always the right one to go for.
Instead, what we want to do is we want to pass the ciimage into this method detect so that the image
can be used to be classified by our model.
So very simply, all we need to do is detect and the image that we want to detect is of type ciimage
and that, of course, is this image that we converted from our userPickedImage.
So, now if we run our app, see what happens.
All right.
So here, I've got the app and I'm going to tap on the camera button.
I'm just going to take a picture of my keyboard and I'm going to click use photo.
So this is the data that we got back.
And as you can see, it looks like a pretty big mess.
But if you dig into it in detail, you can see that we've got a whole bunch of these
VNClassificationObservationObjects.
And if we go from the top, you can see that the first one which was rated with 82 percent confidence
is computer keyboard or keypad
which is exactly what it is.
Now the next one with low percentage confidence is maybe a typewriter keyboard which is also I can see
where it's coming from.
And then you've got this one with temps and confidence which is a notebook or notebook computer.
So as you can see this Inceptionv3 model is incredibly accurate in predicting what that image shows.
Now, the only problem is that this is a tangle of data.
So we have to make some sense out of it.
So, in the next lesson, that's exactly what we're going to be doing.
We're going to be focusing on the task that we've set for ourselves in the beginning which is being
able to take an image of anything and classify it as whether if it's a hot dog or whether if it's not
a hot dog.
So we're going to do that in the next lesson.