I will come back.
My name is Edwin and of course you already met me but you met my other me from the past.
I'm from the future and I come by once in a while just to add a couple more lectures to the course.
I hope you don't mind me coming to the out more lectures.
I think that gives you a better value for your time and the money that you spend for this course.
So if you don't mind me being around.
Dand good if you mind me being around.
Send me a message and I'll handle any issues you got.
But anyway on this section here we are going to be creating a database we are going to be learning how
Ajax works with Jake werie.
But before we do that I also added some new lectures to introduce to introduce you to javascript to
do in jets with pure javascript.
I think you should know that foundation before you jump into Ageod's.
All right.
So I'm adding those two lectures here.
Well you know my other me from the past told me to do that.
So really cool.
But anyway for those of you that are here for some reason and don't know Ph be.
Ph be.
I don't want you to actually miss out on this.
You shouldn't ph be for this course but if you don't don't worry you can still follow a norm even though
you might now understand the BHB PSI or the Cheikh where we say.
But you can follow along with everything I type.
All right so all you have to have is a local environment.
So if you already know what I'm talking about and you know BHB you can skip this lecture.
All right.
If not go ahead and keep watching because I'm going to show you how to set it up.
So basically you will find something like Zap line which is a software package that will install a couple
of things for us.
It we install BHB at bacci in my school that we are going to need in the course you install it.
Then you turn it on with an application that he has inside once you install the cold the control manager
or something like Application Manager.
Make sure that you my squill database is running are you Apache is running right.
And does the same thing for another software package called wimp bright.
There are a couple of them.
These are the big ones.
Lamp.
That's another one that you can stuff windows.
And there's another one for Mac and Windows as well called.
All right.
So these are the software packages.
You install it.
Make sure that you go in the Control Panel make sure that those services are on your mind.
You know you have Patchi and all that.
And then once you have a radio you have to go and visit your your browser and type in localhost.
This is going to give you your server directory basically.
This is where you're going to be placing all those files to make them work.
For example the application that will build and coal is in a folder called Ajax Demel and this is where
it is.
All right localhost forward slash the folder name where your application is.
All right.
I'm also using an editor call it the cold brackets which is free for Windows Linux and Mac users.
Right.
So once you have the local environment ready.
All right.
For Windows users this is going to install the in a folder called zap.
Right.
And you Feigel in my Mac this is my Mac but it's very similar.
So if I go to my applications now all my files my application you're going to find you're going to find
a full decode zem for Windows users this will be you see Dr. for Mac users.
Obviously it would be an complications.
So when you click on this folder and you have another folder called HD docs This is where all those
folder that I just showed you in the browser will be located at.
This is where we will store our project.
As you can see right here that Demel they juts underscored Demel.
All right.
And what I am going to do later on in the lecture is I'm going to make a shortcut and put it on my desktop
from the docs so that way we can create a project right here right.
This was a fast overview.
For those of you that for some reason did not get my warning about not getting into the cores on lets
you know BHB.
All right but I didn't want you to miss out.
Thank you so much.
And on the next lectures I'm going to explain to you how javascript works with AJAX.
All right and then we'll continue with the rest of the course.
Thank you so much and I'll see you then.