Hi welcome back on the last lecture we talked a little bit about object's properties methods many states
and statuses on this lecture you will going to see how everything is how we can put everything together.
So now that we have created this object is being held on this variable here we can access the methods
which are already predefined and the properties of it.
Right.
Those are pretty already they are ready made for us.
We just got them using my right.
So the first one the first method that we are going to be using is the open method.
So we grab the object and that is how you put it together.
This is how you use an object method of an object would it not.
Remember what I told you in the last lecture.
Okay.
And then basically this in this function you want to call it you can call it a function if you like
but since it's an object we call it method.
So the first parameter of this method takes is the data type.
In this case we were sending a get later on and want to show you how to send a post request but we use
GET request to get information from the database.
All right.
This is mainly the good reason to do that.
And then we use post to update the lead.
You know which is more secure then the second parameter is where we want these data from.
We want it from the right.
So we are sending this there to this file.
Right.
And then we want to send it in a synchronously way.
All right basically what that means is you do you want your page to refresh yes or no.
And if you don't want it to refresh you make sure that you said this here to asynchronous Knisley a
synchronous requests an array which is not going to refresh anyway that word was kind of hard for me.
But anyway the next thing once we opened the connection.
All right we need to track the ready States just like I told you on the last lecture.
All right there are five of them I think I said four before but they are actually five because that
0 count for one right.
Zero is the number right of their request.
So we can kind of take them with the numbers.
We are actually looking for number four so we can say something like If Let me just write it down real
quick here.
So that way you can see how it's done so.
All right we grab the object and we say on ready state change.
So we are tracking it now.
I want you to execute this function.
All right.
So one wants is actually going through those stages to two those red states we can detect to see one
number it is.
So we can say if the range state equals to for
and we can also detect the object status.
So if it's equal to 200 We know he's OK right.
And then we can do something with information.
So we can get everything back in there are not a property called response.
Tests like this.
All right so we get them back in this attribute right from the object and then we can sort this wherever
we want if we want inserted with javascript we just say you know
let's create an element here let's say for example we had an element with an ID of container.
There you go.
All right.
So we grab an element within the container and we enter any l that's coming from here.
All right so basically we are signing the response to this container here using javascript.
Really cool stuff right.
And then we can come here and finish this next thing is to send this right.
And then here that's
it.
Now let's actually look for a way to activate javascript Ajax.
So I got some stuff that I can face here.
That way you don't have to see me writing it.
There we go.
So what I did is I have a button here with an enclave attached to it that is going to be calling a function
when we click it and then whatever response we get back from here he's going to insert it in this element
with an idea container which is right here.
So we're getting several information down here below.
All right.
So I'm going to actually pace all this.
So this ready from here I'm going to pace everything and I'm going to create a function here.
I just want to make sure that I'm not making any mistakes because I'm explaining how everything works
right.
But all right Burfoot.
All right.
So as you can see I've wrapped everything around in this in its function.
And then we are calling it right here.
All right.
Let's find out if it works let's make sure that we Sonthi and the javascript here and we can let's say
for example we are getting something from the database right.
And this is where we put our mice.
Q Well you know fetch all these data from this table.
But in this case we don't have that.
So we're just going to say yes it's working or something like that.
Save it.
That's opened his file on the browser and let's check it out real quick
hear this if it works then Imphal yes is working as you can see that was really fast.
All right.
And to send post requests is super simple.
All we got to do is two more things I believe here.
All right well we've got to use the object again.
Well first of all we need to change this from get to post right.
And then we can use the object again to set the request Hetter.
All right.
Is a header that's also sent to the server every time.
Next e-mail page is view the headers in the background there is already pre-define but we can change
it.
All right.
And basically here what we're going to be changing is the content type.
So we've got to change the content type to let the server know what kind of data is going to do and
going to copy them because I already have.
I don't want to write it down.
All right so we're going to change.
We've got a method that would change for us.
We passed it first parameter which is Content-Type and the second parameter is this application forwards
slash and you are in court right now that we are sending a post request
when I paste in my code you can see all the information here.
Well this is where all the posts would be.
So if I have a post request that I need to send I can put this and this would be the key of the post.
Super global.
And this would be the value the value in this case would be my name ampersand and say password here.
And that would be secret and something like that.
All right so now to access this information in the other side.
Super simple right we can go back.
Can I get my stuff back my.
Go
right now here we can say if a set post.
All right we can echo now
post I believe the key was name
and let's just write some text here.
And here would be maybe.
I think it was email or password your yelling password password.
All right.
So let's check this out real quick.
Because we are trying to echo this.
We are on the HP page of course is now going to be set.
We need to set it from here sent.
As you can see Edwyn and secret.
All right.
So the post requests we are getting from here.
Oh and by the way I'm from the future so if you see some files here on the left Cy don't worry about
it we haven't done those yet in the course.
All right.
So I just came to get some extra lecture here because I think you had to know about this stuff.
I think I've already told you that but just in case.
But anyway this is how we can communicate using javascript pure javascript and Ageod's and the server.
Right.
So hopefully this help you help you understand how everything works and you're happy.
That's what I care about.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.