Hi my dear students I hope you're having a great day.
I'm having an awesome day because I have the chance of teaching you this matyr that I know will help
you get further in your professional career.
Be grateful that you are learning this because a lot of people can't it out or people even have a computer
right now or a phone that they can watch this with as I said on this lecture.
We're building a database.
We're building a database table and we are sending some data inside that table.
Right.
I'm assuming you already know BHB my you a lie and if you don't have the best scores in the planet to
teach you just check out my Ph.D. course for beginners where I teach all the fundamentals of PH BE O.P.
Ma Su ally and I even teach you how to build a CIMS just like Wordpress Drupal or Joomla.
All right.
Just make sure that you check all those courses if you don't know them because if you don't know BHB
this won't make much sense.
All right so just to let you know.
So what we're going to be doing is let's go and create that database right now.
So let's go to our local host.
And you should know how to do this already because if you know my ask you l or my ask you a lie you
know that we have a server right we have a local server in our computer.
So let's use the software ph be my admin just to create a simple database right where you can post his
video and create a database and the table is going to create a database called Ajax right there.
And Danny said that that database is going to create a table called cars are going to create two columns
there and then click go here I'm going to create an ID and then are going to create a road called cars.
This is going to be an integer
primary and auto increment.
Right.
Cars is going to be Vark car and to 55 that's fine.
All right.
That is good.
Where are you Dick.
Perfect.
Right.
All right.
So now that we created a database in the table let's insert some data.
You are just going to insert a couple rows of data and you're going to create five more
so when you're going to create a card called Honda Civic here because I like the car is kind of nice
right.
Honda's are really good cars but I also like BMW.
Right.
So I'm just going to create another Honda here Honda sit and
I'm just going to make sure that you take these NORAD's checked checkbox on check them because if you
don't check them they will not show.
All right.
So Honda sedan Honda CRV and I think that's about it for Honda.
Let's go ahead and create some some more Actually let's create 10 of them at least.
We're going to need some data.
BMW and car I.
I actually have a BMW not to show off but it's not a really new car to this date but it's it's not that
old either.
Right.
But it's a really nice car.
I actually it was my dream car.
And finally I was able to get it with just knowing some of the knowledge on teaching you here.
All right so be it that 330 BMW and three BMW.
What is it.
Five
VW at sits B and W
What is the one that they have Emmets sits.
I might be making up some of this sense.
They have so many different models.
Right now we're going to create a Mercedes that's another nice car right.
Benz Right.
And then they have the three hundred in my city.
Right let's create another watchfully Oops that's too many rolls right.
Doesn't matter.
We're just going to keep going down a little bit.
That's it.
Mercedes which is Mercedes 320
you can go and grab a list somewhere on line.
That's fine.
All right we're almost done.
I promise.
And the next one would be maybe a nice Toyota.
That's a popular car right.
To your to Tacoma
your Corolla
or Camry.
All right that's fine.
OK.
I think that's enough just to show you show you some functionalities.
Let's do a couple more I like I like cars a lot.
And try.
All right.
So this could go on any of these.
And we've got 16 rolls right.
So I think we were good with this lecture here.
I think this is long enough.
Let's just check our.
All right.
So we got some some data here going on right.
Perfect.
So in the next lecture we're going to continue with building our documents and connecting with this
database.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you on the next one.
Take care.