I'm a wonderful students today I'm going to show you will.
You should already know but we will be making our connection with our database.
Right.
So let's go ahead and do that.
I'm going to open my coeditor one of them.
I use brackets and this is a free coeditor by the way.
Get off their phone.
B corps which I will be removing in a minute.
So I'm going to make a folder here called age that's all right.
Whoops.
I'm already doing something in my coeditor.
Sorry about that.
Let's just make something for the code that's on my desktop and I'm just going to make sure age is already
taken.
All right.
So that's Demel.
A judge underscored Demel.
It looks like I have another folder on my desktop.
All right.
So Ajax Demel perfect.
So here I'm going to connect.
I'm going to create a couple of files let's just create the first file and then we will do with the
rest.
All right.
So I'm just going to reichlich it right click anywhere here.
Again this coeditor is free and advertising them.
It has been pretty good for me.
All right.
It's a really good way to mail.
So let's create the first one is going to be called Search Dopp HP.
And the reason why we created this first is because I want to make sure that we have a connection where
our database are really super important right.
So I'm going to open some ph BTX here.
All right.
And let's create our connections here.
Like I said before you should already know how to do this.
If you don't.
And I said very clearly before lecture.
All right because this is a little advance if you don't know it.
All right.
So let's create a connection here where a local host parameter there make sure we are creating this
list doesn't let me majus does a little bit bigger here so you can see and just going up there.
All right.
Perfect.
OK
and our database name.
That's I believe.
All right.
So that's that's you.
Let's go ahead and test our connection actually make sure that it is working right.
So let's just say yes it is perfect.
All right so I hope you have an awesome day.
I'm having a really good day today again.
Able to be alive and breathing right.
I was just sick one or two weeks ago and I thought I was going to die basically.
But thank God that everything is fine.
All right.
So now we do need to actually places folder in our
zap location right.
Just make sure that you place there I think I have the docs folder in my somewhere and my desktop looks
like I don't but that's fine.
I'm just going to go to my Xantippe HD Ducs make sure that you place it in your local server.
There we go.
Now we have that working there.
Now I'm going to go back to my coeditor and this button here allows me to preview this in the browser.
So I'm just going to define loco's here actually.
HTP localhost and the folder that we made for this one is Ageod's underscored them all right.
He juts underscored them all that we are.
Let's see if this works.
All right let's check it out.
Perfect.
All right.
So what I like about this coin is that I can preview my documents when I take them here.
I can just preview right away on the browser.
All right.
Even though it's BHB.
All right so we create a connection.
It looks like he's working perfect on the last lecture.
We're going to be creating that mark up and following with a tutorial right.
Perfit thank you so much for allowing me to teach you the scores and this classes and I'll see you in
the next one right.
Take care.
Have an awesome day.