Hi welcome back my awesome student on this lecture here we're finally going to test to see if our data
is actually being sent if our request has been sent to the server.
Right.
So we need to get some type of response back just to make sure that everything is working fine right.
We roll the school here.
We don't even know if we have a mistake here somewhere.
Right.
So let's go ahead and go to our search got BHB.
All right.
And just because we are sending a post requests I'm just going to take this esteeming out of this since
we don't need it anymore.
Actually I'm going to leave it there and just going to comment this all because I want to give you these
files at the end of this.
Right.
So you can have something that you don't have to write everything from scratch.
I hope you're writing everything from scratch that way you can learn more to be honest with you.
All right so now we are getting a POST request being sent to this page right here.
Right.
So the post requests a few If I go back.
Well let me just go back to that in that we are sending a key with it right here called search and we
are sending the values of this variable right to this variable.
We have these values here from the user.
Right.
So let's go ahead and search for that key right here in this Superguy o'War Ray Ray.
And I was going to say search and now we need to assign it to something we actually don't need to but
I like to assign it to a very well I'm going to assign it to a very we'll call search.
What are the odds of that right.
And you know we're going to do.
I'm going to echo this and try to see if I can get some response back just to make sure that everything
is working fine.
Make sure you put a semicolon there right.
So I think we're good here.
Let's go ahead and check it out.
Let's go to our page and get a refresher here.
And I'm just going to say hello.
Look at that.
We were already getting a response back.
This is age outs right now working.
Hello my dear my dear student
All right.
You see that instant result from the server.
This is no refreshing at all in the speech.
Imagine the possibilities when once we start searching our database with this every day all the resorts
are going to be instantaneous here.
So
right perfect Hope you're really enjoying this class.
It's my goal to you know just for you to maybe send me a message later on tell me how awesome this course
is on what you're learning and maybe see more of you.
Mauldin courses.
All right.
So it's really a pleasure for me.
I love teaching my students and preparing them with knowledge affordable knowledge free knowledge.
You know the word to you.
You are my battery or hey you are you are my cup of coffee when you send me those reviews are those
messages.
Anyway thank you so much.
We're going to make this story very short.
And because I don't want to just drag you here with a 20 minute tutorial and on the next lecture here
we're going to start building our Querrey into our database and making sure that we can pull some data
out of it.
All right.
Again thank you so much.
Have an awesome day and I'll see you the next lecture.