Welcome back my ideas today it is a pleasure to have you here again.
Now on this lecture you were going to write some Ph.D. since our database application right here our
request has been sent to the server.
We're getting our response back to our little application right so we say hello and we get it right
here.
So this is working now we're done with it.
So let's go ahead and concentrate on our Ph.D..
Now we do need to be echoing anything out.
So let's just take that a quarter there and let's start writing on Querrey How about that.
Right.
Finally some PH Because I love BHB.
Let's go ahead and check first if this which is this here is empty or not.
Because we don't want to you know empty information to be sent to our server.
So we're just going to say just a simple statement here we're just going to say if it's not actually
empty was going to use this function empty.
If it's not empty
right if it's not empty then we want to do something with it right.
So let's just say we're going to make a query when to select
all from where.
From our users table actually is not use it's cars where cars like and that's the special key where
they used to find similar things right.
Or something started with certain words and search and that percentage right here.
You know I don't know what I'm doing.
Just make sure you watch my BHB course is going to teach you everything that you need to know about
my you know writing stuff like this.
Right.
Of statements.
All right.
So we're going to start searching our database for anything else when we type here the first word is
going to find something in our database right.
So if he's not empty we do that.
So the next thing for us to do is actually send that query in.
So I'm just going to say something like Ajax search query that sounds more semantic right search query
and let's just send it with my lie and go Kohary
send it in with a connection and let's send it in with that with this with equerry query.
All right.
Perfect.
Make sure the search actually spelled it wrong.
I'd also like to check on my connection.
All right.
I like to check them every day.
I don't like to be writing called that.
Maybe later on is going to give me a problem if I don't check it before right.
So let's make sure that that query is actually successful.
So if it's not quite what I want you to do BHB is go and die.
Actually now really just killed every script below there.
So in a way die.
That's a really good name for it right.
My ask you lie error and give me an error.
Also send in the connections so that way you know to give me an error right.
Especially for this connection here.
All right so if our query is not successful is going to give us an arrow.
All right there we go.
No arrows means good.
So if I make any mistake here on our Querrey and I come here and I type in the day and we get this big
error here.
Perfect.
So our core is actually working.
And I think we are good here.
Let's just make sure.
All right.
So in the next part here I'm going to leave this lecture.
I like to make a short and sweet so that you can have some coffee time or maybe some wine time and and
relax.
All right.
So on the next one we're going to continue building this Querrey here and that will build a nice function
that's going to pull everything from the database.
Right.
So thank you again for giving me this opportunity it's really really a pleasure.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.