Welcome back my students.
So we are here in the mail and we create an idea and the last lecture there so we get to actually target
is formed by doing that by actually with his ID.
So let's go ahead to our Jake werie right here and let's make sure that we are right after this function
ends right here and between this is going to be the document right here right.
Dokument This is the commands ready function.
Just make sure that we put some type of common here here's what we know.
All right.
And all right.
So the first thing is we need to target our button right.
So let's target it like this ad form at with an idea of course at car form and then we're going to use
a function called submit.
All right so basically we got to actually take this when we submit the form.
Right.
And of course we can put a callback function here right.
And we don't actually create this function.
And let's just put this variable there because we're going to be using it here to see just to prevent
the form from submitted submitting pre-event.
And you can see that does this editor.
I was already writing bracket's is already writing that that function prevent default.
All right so now now if I want to go back here and I try to submit that data from this form it doesn't
go anywhere.
Now if you have that you see right now I'm going to comment this.
I'll save it come back here and I click and you can see that he's already sending information that doesn't
wouldn't want to do that we want to pick up the information before he sends it.
So that's why we use in this function right there to prevent that.
Come back here and now we clean this up a little bit to refresh and click it and nothing happens.
All right so it prevents the default functionality of it.
Now we need to do something called serialise right.
We need to take all that data and I'm going to call this phone data.
We're going to take all the data from the form like this.
This serialise So we're going to serialize the form and you can see the function right here in my brackets.
All right.
So now we got all the data from that form right there on this variable.
Beautiful.
Now we also going to need your mail so that we can send our information somewhere our data and we get
to pick this up from where from this ETR.
There you go.
Look at that right there from the action remember.
So we're going to see action.
There we go.
All right.
So we can even alert this hour if you want to see it.
We can Adlard your L here.
And let's just click here and you can see that it actually doesn't have anything that is actually put
or you are out there in that form.
Let's go to the in the form and make sure they submit it to add on the score cards that BHP.
All right.
So now we refresh here click on it and now you can see that it's picking up that actually there.
We can also if you want to see it.
Also check the full state of
save refresh.
Click on it and you can see that it is actually taken in the car on the score name.
All right.
So he's taking the pulls data as well.
So let's go up a little bit here make sure that everything is so that we can put a little comment here
real quick and this code adds cars to database table cars something like that.
All right.
So in the next lecture we'll continue adding doing some more processing here so that where we can send
this information to our database and execute it.
So thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.