All right welcome back my students so in the last lecture we were getting some type of bug here.
Well this is not actually a bug.
This is actually the form Sending get requests.
Right.
Basically sending you are l parameters and we don't want it to do that.
What we want to do is send post requests which are actually more secured post data.
So we need to go back to our form.
Right we don't have that much time on The Last Lecture out of anyone that lecture to be 20 minutes.
So that's why I caught it off like that.
Sorry about that if you didn't like it.
But I think short lectures actually better.
So let's go to index the e-mail and let's make sure that our form data right here.
This form has a method of post right and that's it.
That's all we need there.
Let's go to our cars here.
What we doing here is we're saying if set basic Luisa's this function from BHP saying if this PPO's
data is set then we'll you know execute this.
And basically remember that this current name field is coming from the form.
Right.
Right here this name actually has its value and that's why we get in there that's it.
POST data that we are receiving these are going to turn into variables and it's going to be in the mental
of polls.
All right so once we save that we come back here we take these you're out parameter come back here and
add the car.
And as you can see it says data received.
So that's beautiful.
So we are we are actually executing data.
All right.
Beautiful.
Now we need to actually spell that a little bit better.
Data received.
All right.
So that's where this is going.
If we want to we can actually create ph P can convert this page in the the mailing to ended up fee and
receive the data right up here.
All right we don't have to send the data somewhere else if we don't want right that's up to us.
All right.
So
now now that we got that squared down to the point where everything is working good we're actually sending
these data and we are echoing that data right here.
We could return these data.
All right.
And then do something else with it.
But what we're going to be doing is inserting stuff in the database.
Right.
So let's go ahead and write a query down and we're going to say insert
into and this is how we put stuff in our database into cars which is a table right and we'll put the
parentheses this is going to we are writing actually you a statement and you should know that values
and we gonna to be actually writing values for the I believe the column name in ph P is actually
a color name is cars right.
And what we're getting here is this post we're going to convert into a very old variable.
So that way we can use it inside there.
So you're going to call his car name right.
And we just put it right here in between coult single quotes because we've got double codes outside.
We'll put a semicolon there and what we need here is my SU ally.
Actually I don't.
This needs to be Querrey car name.
We are scientists or variable mice here like Querrey All right we'll pass into a connection which is
included already in the on the top of this page and we pass and query.
All right.
And once that's done we should be actually seeing some stuff going on but before we do that let's make
sure that this
this is going through.
If it's not then we need to display an error right.
So you're going to put a quick die here and you're going to say where he failed.
If we if we fail then we'll welcome cutting a heire function here and make sure like we did in the one
and make sure that we get we know exactly what's going on.
Right.
So let's check it out real quick.
Let's come back here and we can go back.
Once we do this we can redirect and I'll show you how to redirect back to we come here we redirect to
add to and it's actually in the mail.
All right.
But we also need to put a location here Paulin and space.
Make sure you do that location with a cup of oil.
That's best practice then location call in space.
And they say the amount.
All right.
Make sure that you are actually Kochie.
Debbie
for some people you might not get this working unless you have let's go to our connection here and put
up the start.
This is just a turn on output buffering so we can do redirection.
All right.
And we don't get no errors so and save Let's type in something here is like a nice car and add bright.
You didn't see it but we got redirected back to this page here.
So let's go to our
database and our table cars.
We see that we don't have anything here.
Let's refresh this.
And now you can see that he says nice car.
All right.
And this is all using AJAX.
Beautiful right.
Beautiful beautiful beautiful.
So we can say another car like this just something else.
Where can we put it here.
Bad car.
All right.
Enter
this go and check it out right.
Fresh.
And now we can see who says bad car.
All right.
So in the next lecture will actually make it make this a little better.
All right we'll create an update we'll create delete and we actually want to even see our database information
down here so we'll create something to see that.
So it's going to be pretty awesome application you're going to like it.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.
Keep having fun in though and I'll show you some more stuff.
Take care.