Welcome back my students for those of you that have been where they have been waiting for me to do this
course.
Thank you so much from the bottom of my heart.
You are awesome.
Really.
My students are really nice students anyway.
So they were going to be updating this up location.
And while we are going to be updating just a couple of things first of all first of all we are going
to be updating day displaying here of information from the database.
So for those of you that are adding stuff to your database and it's not explained for some reason is
because we are only sending one request to the server.
We're just telling the server right now listen I'm going to send you these values and update the database
one time of day this request.
Just send me back the response.
One time.
Basically that's what we're saying to the server.
I'm going to show you what I mean right now.
So we've got this cold right here.
Yours yours might look a little different than mine and that's just because I move things around a lot
so.
But anyway go to this cold right here display where we are sending the information to display on the
score cards at BHB.
Right.
So get these age outs here.
All right and we are sending our request to the server and the server is bringing back the response
and we are displaying it in this section right here.
But we are sending only one.
All right this is only being executing one.
So we're saying listen sir I want you to select everything from cars and you know and I want you to
display it right.
So that's one request.
What we need to do is we need to set a functionality where we keep actually refreshing this updating
these requests sending requests every couple of seconds or every couple of minutes whatever we want.
So let's go back to index and let's do that.
So for that what we're going to be doing is we're going to be wrapping this cold here inside a function
like this.
And you can wrap all your cold inside functions if you like but we're going to wrap this inside a function
we're going to call this update cars.
All right.
And we're going to go down here like this.
Make sure that this function this one here
wrapped.
All right.
This code is wrapped in this function.
So we got this wrapped in a function is not going to work of course because you know we need to call
the function to work.
So if you save it and you go back here you won't be able to see anything.
All right we need to call it we need to use a function.
So what I'm going to do what I'm going to do is I'm going to use another function called set interval
in BHB which allows me to actually called a piece of code in my application every couple you know time
every couple of seconds every couple of minutes whatever I want.
So I'm going to show you how to use that.
You're going to be set interval.
And I think bracket's is helping me out right here.
Set interval right there.
So set with a capital I interval.
Right.
And is a function like this.
So we close it with a semi-colon right.
Any inside the function we're going to get that flushing is going to take a couple of parameters.
First it's going to take a function or an anonymous function like this and two curly brackets and we
bring it down like that.
All right so now what is going to be executed here.
Well we're going to be calling this function and we close with a semi-colon like this.
And the second parameter.
This is going to take well when we need to do is set the time that we want to call this function.
So right now we want 1000 1000 means one second.
So this function is going to be executing every couple of milliseconds.
So if you want more of course you keep bracing this Ciro's right.
Right now that is less than a second and that's too fast and it's going to slow down your application
so let's do one second thing one second is good.
Well even 500 is good.
All right ballista one second so you can see how it works.
All right.
So you can always make a comment here and so that will you know what's going on.
I'm not going to do that because I don't want to waste a lot of time and want to do a couple of more
things in this lecture.
So let's save it.
Maybe I'll do it in the next lectures.
Let's refresh it.
Right now you can see all the values here.
Again so now when we insert something here so let's say I want to insert a car we are going to be let's
say.
Wow I just went blank for a minute there.
I don't know what car.
OK Toyota.
Let's see.
Right click ADD and you can see that inserted Toyota there.
We've got to do a couple more things to this application like maybe MTA in this field one when I get
sent maybe requiring the tests just in case is blank you know things like that.
So let me do that again.
Let me see if I can minimize it so you can see it working better.
Let's do I don't know.
Ferrari
you can see it right here again.
And if that's.
Let me put this to three seconds so that you can see it when he really does it let's refresh that you
are takes once three seconds.
You see that.
So now let's say it's simple add.
Now I was going to take three seconds and you saw me there.
All right.
So that's how that works.
Beautiful.
So in the next lectures we are going to be improving this application a little more.
I hope you like it and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care and thanks for everything.