All right welcome back my students.
So hopefully you guys follow my advice on the last lecture you in which I told you that you needed to
change your column your BHB cold where we change the column title name.
All right.
If you did not let me just walk you right through it right because right now you can add cars or you
can search if you try to search you get this arrows here or if you try to add you can add because you
need to do that cold as well with a new
column name.
All right so in the search that BHB you can go ahead and say select from cars where title would go.
That's going to work now you save it.
And then as well as in the ad cars out BHB.
All right.
So you can go heading into
actually right there title and you could just leave that one now that way and it should work.
You can change everything if you like but I'm gonna leave it that way it is Honda defined in its cards.
On line 9:29 has checked out a quick line 29 which are doing quite We OK fetching and should be title
here.
All right let's go and check it out real quick.
I'm doing this with you so that way we get we are on the same page.
All right.
So now let's add another car here if I can come up with another one.
Maserati I think that's the name.
Actually that's true.
I don't even remember how to spell that name for that car just example car at and you can see that simple
car works right.
So we're good to go with that.
What else do we need here.
OK.
All right.
Hopefully you were able to do that.
And I just wanted to walk you right away just in case you had any issues.
All right.
So now that we can display we can search our database for cars right.
We can add cars now we need to find a way to delete right.
That would be nice.
They delete all that stuff.
All right so in the next lectures hopefully we ask some of those lectures after this one if by having
these please be patient.
I will Adams when I have some time.
I remember this a bonus lectures for the course.
So thank you for watching this and I'll see you in the next one.
Thank you.