Welcome back my new student This is Edwin from the future.
I'm already done with the Course but I came here just to make sure that you're called on the next lecture
is working 100 percent on the next lecture.
I'm going to make a little table right here in this function in this page display underscore cars that
ph be in right here on these h.
I'm going to be typing in javascript like this.
Right.
This will not work for Firefox.
So make sure that you actually spell it correctly with a s javascript.
Right.
So anyway thank you so much for being my Corson's always a pleasure to help if you need any help I'm
here to help you.
So see you in the next lecture and say hi to Edlund from the past for me.
Take care.
Bye bye.