All right welcome back my students.
So it's time for us to start actually spending a little bit more than hello to our application right
to our boss right here.
Let's go and do that right now.
All right.
Let's take that off and let's comment this whole thing right here.
So right now the way this is if I send this like this I think we should get something from it.
Let us refresh and click on it as you can see.
We get all the records back with IDS and everything.
All right.
But we want to show a little bit more than that right.
Well a little bit something different right.
We don't want to show everything we want to show something specific to that record so let's do that
test right now.
First of all we want to test to see if the I.D. that's being said the post requests is equal to the
ID right.
So we're going to say post if we're getting post value or key
right here.
Right.
Then we execute everything else and we are going to be selecting from cars where we see OK where ID
equals the idea that we're getting from here.
You can use this whole thing or you can make it a variable is up to you so I can go ahead and do that.
Of course you might want to clean that up with a function.
Let me show you how to do that.
So whatever you get from here I think you should clean it up.
All right my ask you a real scape string will scape everything coming in.
From here even though
this is very secure.
Right because he's a post requests.
Nobody's looking is sending is not typing anything that's import or anything like that right now because
we just sending that in.
But in the future when somebody is typing something in a tetes make sure that you clean it up like this.
All right.
We'll just the first parameter with this would be the connection.
And the second would be what I was cleaning and then you can assign an ID to it.
I mean a variable Now this is clean.
And we can replace that with like this ID.
All right so now let's check that out real quick to see if it works.
We're running a lot of calls and we haven't tested it.
Click on it and now he's bring that specific code for click onto yota when it comes perfit things being
cleaned.
That's beautiful isn't it.
All right.
But now that we've been in that specific record let's actually make this look a little better.
Right.
Well we don't one TVs we don't have a table or anything like that.
I don't think I need we don't need this anymore we don't need this and we don't even need the TVs anymore.
Let's just do input them and see how it looks.
Import would a class of actually already have a class.
I don't know maybe one control would make this look better for in-control
this out here.
Let's see.
This just making both input like this.
We're going to need a couple of inputs here.
The first input that we need is a ttes sole input type ttes that Sec.
That's the first one that we need the second one that we need it would be.
But in
so that would be a
button here and the buttons have different classes.
So let's say for this button would be that of the bond so let's say between success which would make
it a green one.
This is bull strapper right guys and ladies and this one would be for deletion for the leading so Bun
B D danger would make a red.
Let's take the form out there let's see how this looks real quick.
All right.
Not much to it yet.
Let's put something value or something there.
So as a matter of fact we can make these bones there instead of inputs but it's up to you.
I mean whatever works you know let's just say the value would be for this one would be update
actually.
That would be updated like this.
And the value with this one here would be
to see how that looks now.
Looking a lot better right.
All right so we made really good progress in this one here.
All right.
So thank you so much for watching in the next lecture.
We'll continue working with this functionality here and I'll see you then.
Take care.
Have fun.