All right welcome back my dear student.
So we need to write some functionalities here so that way when we click on here we send Ageod's requests.
All right.
And get something back from the server right.
Make everything work.
So we need to target is born here and when we when we talk when we click on it we want to send the data.
We want to send is value we want to send the ID and everything through agents.
So let's target our buy in there and make sure that we add some type of functionality when we click
it.
So let's say let's first give up on an ID.
So this one here of the
has a car Id here.
Let's just say update right here.
And let's while we at it let's just change this one to the list.
There we go.
So what are we going to do.
Let's actually is class and we're going to say when we click on it I'm going to use on function
run dysfunction
make sure you put your pull my ear.
All right let's test it out real quick just to make sure that it works.
What an industry in there real quick.
All right refresh
and click on it.
It's not working.
All right.
Let's check it out.
And that's just because it is inside the other functionality there and that needs to be separate.
So I'm going to put this right here.
There we go.
Bigot.
And now it works.
And he takes over stuff there.
All right.
Perfect.
All right so I'm just going to actually write some variables here.
Update delete stuff I don't want to use that.
That's just say delete this all right.
They did delete this.
I know this is weird but let's do that.
All right.
And as a matter of fact I'm going to just put something here.
Update science on something right away way to and we're going to use this just to detect the pulse requests.
That's all right.
So let's use post that falls right here.
And the first of course parameter would be the process that BHB then the data that's going in and taking
in the title we're getting right here.
So let's write that right there.
Title.
And we're also taking in the idea as well that this should be first lady.
What else.
And maybe this update by now.
I think we should take that.
UPDATE this.
There we go.
And then the function
right looking pretty good.
Let's look at the data coming back.
Let's go to process values.
We are here ready.
You should put a comment on this one here.
Just saying.
Just playing
choose me.
And you can bring them down here
and here you would write something like updating or something like that.
Perfect.
So now we can write functions if set and then post
update does that said then we will do something right.
So what can we do.
Well we can just Eckl it works
and it's called here.
All right beautiful.
Save it.
I click on it and it works and then we have pulling out all that information.
All right.
Actually pulling out all the data.
We don't want to see all that data right.
But anyway thank you so much for watching.
This is working if it's not working for you.
Make sure you watch the video again.
Any little cool My here or the cold or single call that you're missing can make your whole thing fail.
So you know check your inspect Elliman.
All right.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.