All right welcome back my students so if you went ahead and try this cold and the last section of a
cold you've probably got to work.
Let's find out real quick let's just click Update.
Oh we got this.
We got to work on that.
And now you see that the record is being updated from the database.
Isn't that beautiful right.
So it works really good.
We're getting that.
Let's see if we can at least get something back a little nicer on alert alerting everything.
Let's just say something like
your data of data and successfully.
All right.
You can also insert
Let's see.
Let's actually refresh this
right.
We can actually write more advanced Querrey see if we wanted to if nothing was changed.
We can also alert that now.
But that would probably be really events parts of this placation.
If I decide to make more lectures.
My main goal here is to show you the crowd create read and delete this actually create something a little
better than an alert.
Right.
Let's go to bootstrap real quick.
All right.
And bootstrap P As a matter of fact I already know how to do this.
I don't have to have bootstraps So you just do it real quick.
What I want to do is insert something in a div somewhere.
So let's go to end its real quick and let's find out where can we insert this type of notification that
it was already updated.
Instead of being alert.
Right.
What about here.
Right up off here.
Can we do that.
Yeah we can actually look for that code in the process that BHB because that's dynamic code.
All right.
So we are displaying or inputs right here we've got these tetch input right.
If we could if we wanted to display it we can use BHB to do that but I think that's too much colder
ready.
Let's go to end that's and ry above here we can say we can read a little paragraph with an ID
and also it a class of
e.g. success.
There we go.
Right.
So we're going to target this and put some information there.
All right.
US is that BHP all the way to the bottom here.
Just answer some stuff right.
Use this idea and let's just answer some HDMI in there.
All right.
And whether we want insert We could write some tests.
Well I think tets would work fine for us.
Let's just say.
Of data successfully Let's see how this works.
All right.
Perfect.
Ray as you can see says Recker of data successfully.
All right.
And you can also get another container in Bootstrap where you can take this off if you like it will
go off every time there.
But
that's just to give you an idea how this is done that you can get really advance on this if you like.
But anyway I'll leave it like this and maybe later on we'll create something a little more fancy.
I just wanted to show you this could be done with the data coming back from the database.
All right.
With the response coming back from the database it was a pleasure as always.
I'll see you in the next lecture.