All right welcome back my students.
So I decided to come back because I wanted to work on this notification that we were getting here.
All right I want to close it.
We get this little bug here.
And I also wanted to work on THE LEAD functionality right now which is alerting saying something like
delete whatever.
And we still have this problem here.
Now we can hide it every time we took one of those.
But I think it would be nice if we had this close automatically with the bots.
So all we have to do for that is go to and that's take it out from there or put it right here.
Actually we go to Prosser's up the HP and we can include it right here on top this for sure where we'll
work as we go.
Now we save.
And when we come back if we have some this we still get this but when we close it does disappear so
that's taken care of.
Right now let's work with the delete to what can we do with the functionality Well what I had in mind
was a confirmed bond saying something like Are you sure you want to delete this item.
Something like that anyway.
We are not sure we can solve it and then everything will be cancell.
If we are sure we can continue deleting it because sometimes we might just click on that and there not
be sure that we want to delete that data.
So right here what I want to do is when we click on this button there I want to add to q an if statement.
Now I want to say if because this function will return true if something was if it went through or not
right if it's cancel is false the fees.
OK then is true.
So confirm from javascript.
Are you sure you want to delete this.
So we wrap it around here
here and just put a semi-colon there for some reason that's not that did not have it there.
All right.
Let's save it and let's find out if it works.
So click to what I would try to delete it and says Are you sure you want to delete it.
No cancel.
Nothing was deleted.
Beautiful right in simple this actually click it again.
And you know what I want to delete it delete it.
But I want to take it out of there right here.
We don't need that anymore.
All right that was fun let's test it again.
Let's add something to the database and w.
Let's try to delete this item right now.
Delete.
Are you sure you want to lead counsel.
I don't want to delete it.
I'm going to try this guy right here.
Are you sure you want to delete this.
Yes I am.
Item deleted.
Beautiful.
All right.
Very simple I think you learn something new here.
Thank you again for your support and for taking the time to watch my courses.
You're awesome.
See you in the next lectures or so in the next course is.