Congrats unleashes my friend you have made it to the end.
Great job.
Really great job.
Really proud of you.
Now before you go I want you to practice do different things every single day.
Try to be creative.
We're building different applications now and then you have the knowledge of our agents words.
All you have to do is try to make differing applications and that's all just be creative.
Right now if you phone scores are valuable if you find some type of value in the scores.
Leave a rating in a review right.
It helps a lot.
Share it with your friends and coworkers you might find that some of them out there might need discourse
and when you do somebody a favor I found out that most of the time you get the favor back.
Multiply that into your life like 10 times over.
So if you want good karma you want good positive things in your life.
Share what you have with your friends coworkers and family and in this case this course now if you want
to learn more about BHB take my all the course.
This is going to take you from the beginning of BHP to an intermediate level.
You've got to be able to play around with databases.
We also have object oriented programming and we build a CMF system like Wordpress is a really powerful
course.
Now you can also check out my older courses at you to meet that com forward slash you forward slash
and when one sits sits right.
I've got a lot of more courses out there.
I got a bootstrap course that can help you build Responsive Web sites real fast and easy BHB.
You're already seeing that avid javascript cores are really good javascript course and I also have a
H.T. of male and CSSA scores.
So if you need to polish some of the skills or maybe learn a new skill take one of my all the courses
and the address again is uty me come forward slash you forward slash.
Edwin 1:06 it's.
Thank you so much.
Great job you're awesome.
You are the best because you are my student.
All right.
Take care.
And I see you my other courses.