Alright, so for challenge number two,
I want you to work with a singly-linked list
that handles integers, so it stores integer objects.
So what I've done is, I quickly updated
the employee link list class that we implemented
so that it stores integers instead of employees.
I was gonna make you do it, but then I thought,
oh that's just trivial work, so I'll do that for you.
So there's a starter project in the resources section
that contains all the code that you'll need,
and what I want you to do is, I want you
to implement a method in the IntergerLinkedList class
that inserts a value in sorted order.
If you look at the class, I think
I called the method insertSorted,
and instead of calling the add to front method,
we'll keep calling insertSorted
and so the values are always inserted in sorted order.
And what I mean by sorted order is
that the lower values should appear first in the list,
so they should be closer to the head.
And so if we were to insert value four,
and then two, and then one, and then five,
the list would look like the following.
You'd have the node for one, and then the node for two,
and then four, and then five,
and five would be the last node in the list,
and its next field would point to null.
And so IntegerLinkedList is a singly-linked list,
and I want it to remain a singly-linked list,
this would be an easier challenge
if it was a doubly-linked list.
So, as I said, the project contains all the code you'll need
and the main method has the code that should work
when you're finished, so when you've finished implementing
the insertSorted method, you can then run the main method,
and the list that prints should have the nodes
in sorted order.
So, good luck with that,
and I'll see you in the solution video.