(bright music)
(keyboard clicking)
In this video, we're going to look at Quick Sort.
And Quick Sort is another divide and conquer algorithm,
just like merge sort.
And just like merge sort, we can write it recursively,
and we often do.
So how does Quick Sort work?
Well, Quick Sort
chooses a pivot element
and then it divides the array into two halves
and this division is a logical division.
So it chooses a pivot element.
It divides the array into two halves.
On the left half, it puts elements that are less
than the pivot element.
And in the right half, for the right subarray,
it puts elements that are greater than the pivot element.
And so the pivot element will be in the middle,
between the two arrays.
Everything less than the pivot element will be to the left
and everything greater to the pivot element
will be to the right.
And this is called the partitioning step.
So think about this for a minute,
if all the elements less than the pivot
are placed at its left
and all the elements greater than the pivot
are placed to its right,
that means that after we've finished the partitioning step,
the pivot is in its correct sorted position in the array.
But, and this is important to note,
the left and right subarrays aren't necessarily sorted.
We know all the elements in the left subarray
are smaller than the pivot
and we know that all the elements in the right subarray
are larger than the pivot,
but those left and right subarrays aren't sorted.
And so once we've done this partitioning,
we then do the same thing for the left array
and the same thing for the right array.
In the left array, we're gonna choose a pivot.
We're gonna put all the items in the left array
that are smaller than the pivot to the left.
All the elements in the left subarray
that are larger than the pivot to the right.
And then we're gonna do the same thing
with the right subarray.
And then we're gonna repeat the process.
So essentially, it's divide and conquer
because at each stage,
we're sort of doing what we did with merge sort.
We're partitioning the array into two
around this pivot element.
And just as with merge sort,
we'll end up partitioning the array into a series
of one element arrays.
Now because eventually, every element will be chosen
as the pivot,
eventually every element will be
in its correct sorted position.
Now unlike merge sort, this is all done in place,
so we don't have to create any temporary arrays.
So one advantage of Quick Sort
is you don't need a lot of memory to do this sort.
If you were sorting a really large array,
you would be doing the sorting in place with Quick Sort,
but with merge sort, you'd have to create
a bunch of temporary arrays.
So let's take a look at this.
Let's go through it with our usual array.
In the implementation I'm going to show you,
we're always going to choose the first element
in the array, or the subarray, as the pivot.
So we're going to set the pivot to 20.
We're going to set the start index to zero
and the end index to seven.
And we're gonna make i equal start
and j equal end.
So we start with minus, minus j.
J was, if we go back, j is gonna equal seven,
because it equal n.
So minus, minus j is gonna equal six.
And we're gonna go from right to left,
looking for the first element
that's less than the pivot element.
Minus 22 is less than the pivot element.
The pivot element is 20, and so we assign
minus 22 to position zero.
Now don't worry that we've overwritten 20
because remember, we'll have saved 20 in a pivot field.
Now at this point, we switch to i.
And we add one to i.
Now if we go back a couple of slides,
i started at zero.
So when we add one to i,
we're going to be i equal to one.
And this time, we're going to go from left to right
and we're gonna look for the first element
that's greater than the pivot.
35 is greater than the pivot
and so we're going to assign it to position j.
And currently, j is six.
And so this is going to happen.
Now notice that we've not lost any data
because we already moved what was at position six
down to position zero.
And so by alternating between going from right to left
and left to right,
we can be sure that we won't lose any data.
We're not going to overwrite any positions
that haven't already handled.
So essentially, j moves from right to left,
looking for values that are smaller than the pivot.
And i moves from left to right,
looking for values that are larger than the pivot.
And by doing these alternate assignments,
we're never going to overwrite a position
that we haven't already handled.
So at this point, j is equal to six,
and i is equal to one.
And we're now going to check whether the values
of i and j have crossed each other.
If i is less than j, they haven't crossed each other
and so, once again, we switch back to j.
And we look for the first element
that's less than the pivot.
So we're gonna subtract one from j.
And one is less than the pivot value
which is 20.
And so we're going to assign to position i.
And remember, i is one.
So we assign it to position i.
And notice, again, that we haven't lost any data
because we've already moved 35 from position one.
So now we switch back to i
and we're going to look for the first element
that's greater than the pivot.
And this is going to take us all the way to 55
because minus 15 is less than the pivot
and seven is less than the pivot.
And so we eventually hit 55
and that's greater than the pivot.
So at this point, we're going to assign 55
to position j.
J is five,
so we assign 55 to position five.
And once again, because were doing this alternating
between i and j, between going from right to left
and left to right, we haven't lost any data
because we already moved the value of one
from position five.
So now, we check to see whether i
and j have crossed each other.
At this point, i is four and j is five.
So they have not crossed each other.
And so we switch back to j
and we look for the first element that's
less than the pivot.
Now we're gonna find that at position three,
but at this point, j has crossed i.
Because i is equal to four,
so j has kind of jumped over i
and is less than i and so we stop.
We don't do anything.
Now if you'll notice at this point,
the value of i will be the sorted position
of the pivot value.
So right now, i is four.
And so we're gonna assign 20 to four.
And notice that everything to the left of 20
is smaller than 20
and everything to the right of 20 is larger than 20.
And not only that, 20 is in its correct sorted position
in the entire array.
If we were to sort this array,
20 would end up at position four.
So we've completed our first partition
and now we're going to repeat this process
for the left partition.
So for indices zero to three,
and the right partition, indices five and six.
And we're going to do this until the entire array is sorted
because by doing it for the left and right,
and of course, once we finish those,
we're gonna partition their left and right.
And so eventually, every single element
gets to be the pivot element.
will end up at its correct sorted position.
So as I said, Quick Sort is an in-place algorithm.
It takes place within the array
and that's an advantage over merge sort.
Just like merge sort, it's O(nlogn) and that's to the base 2
because we're repeatedly partitioning
the array into two halves.
Now one thing about Quick Sort is,
in the worst case, it's actually a quadratic algorithm.
But in the average case,
it performs with a time complexity of O(nlogn)
and most of the time, it performs better than merge sort.
Now Quick Sort is an unstable algorithm.
And I think you can probably guess why
because when we're alternating between i and j,
we're swapping, potentially, things from the
left to things to the right
and things to the right over to the left
so we can have elements jumping over each other,
there's no guarantee that the relative positioning
of duplicate items will be preserved.
Now it's important to note that the choice of pivot
can have an effect on the time complexity,
depending on the data that's being sorted.
All right, so that's it for how Quick Sort works.
Let's move onto the implementation.
I'll see you in the next video.