(upbeat electronic music)
(keys clicking)
Alright, so, let's get cracking
on this solution.
Here's the code that populates the link list,
and we have a couple of duplicates,
Jane Jones has been added twice
and John Doe has been added twice.
So, if we run right now.
We'll see that we have Jane Jones twice
and John Doe twice.
And so, we want to remove those two instances.
And so, the approach that I'm going to take
because I said that we had to use a hash map
is I'm going to traverse the list,
and for each employee I'm going to
check to see whether it's in a hash map
that consists of key value pairs.
The key is the ID, and the value is the employee,
and so I'm gonna check whether the employee
is in the hash map, and I'm going to do that
by checking whether it contains the key.
Because, remember in the last video,
I said that we can assume that if two employees
have the same key, they're the same employee.
There's no need to actually compare
the instances against each other
and look at all three fields for equality.
And so, all I have to do is check whether the key
is in the hash map, and if it is,
then I can assume that the employee
has been added already, and that means it's a duplicate.
And so, I'm gonna want to remove it.
And so, let's start writing the code for that.
And so, the first thing I'll do
is create the hash maps.
So, I'll say HashMap, and I want a hash map of integers
and employees.
And I'll just call it employeeTable equals new HashMap.
And then I'm going to need to traverse the list.
And I'm gonna use a list iterator to do that.
So, I'm gonna create that now.
So, I'll say ListIterator Employee Iterator
equals employees.listIterator,
and then finally, I need another list.
And the reason I need another list is
as I'm using the list iterator to traverse the list,
I can't remove a duplicate when I find one
because the runtime will throw an exception.
Because, as I'm using the iterator
to traverse the list.
The list cannot change otherwise
the iterator will throw an exception and say,
hey I'm iterating over this list
and now you've gone ahead and changed it.
Thanks you just screwed me up
so I'm gonna throw an exception.
And so, if I hit a duplicate instead
of removing it right there and then,
I'm just gonna add it to a list,
and then once I've finished traversing the list,
the link list, I'll traverse the list of
employees I wanna remove and actually remove
them from the list.
And so, I'm gonna say List Employee and I'll just bring
in the Java dot util import here.
And I'm gonna call this Remove equals new ArrayList.
And so, now that I have all my fields I need,
I'll say while iterator.hasNext.
I'm gonna get the employee from the iterator equals.
And then I'm gonna check to see whether
the ID for this employee is already in the hash table.
So, I'm gonna say if employeeTable.containsKey
employee.getId.
If that's the case then I know
this employee is a duplicate.
Because, I've already seen an employee with this key,
and I've added it to the hash table.
As we were iterating over the list,
an earlier entry in the list has this ID.
And at that point I added it to the table.
So, this is the second time I'm seeing this ID
because it's already in the table.
And so, what I wanna do here is add this employee
to my remove collection.
So, I'm gonna say remove.add employee.
Otherwise I wanna add this employee to the hash map.
So, else I'm going to say employeeTable.put
and I need the key.
So, that will be employee.getId and then the instance
that I wanna associate with that key in the table.
And so, that's it for figuring out
whether an employee's a duplicate or not.
And the final step of course is to actually
remove the duplicates from the list.
So, the final thing I'm gonna do
is iterate over my remove collection
and actually remove them from the list.
So, I'm gonna say for Employee,
I'll just move this up a bit.
Employee in my remove collection
I'm going to say employees.remove Employee.
And this is the code that's actually
removing them from the list.
Now, I can't do that here because if I do,
the iterator will throw an exception.
And then for our final step,
let's just print out our list again
after we removed the employee.
So, I'll say System.out.printline.
And I'm gonna just print out this
so that we can distinguish this list
when we printed out up here from that.
And then I'm just gonna copy this.
And move it down here.
Okay, so that should do it.
So, let's run.
Alright let me lift this up.
So, before I delete duplicates
we've got one, two, three, four, five, six, seven items
and two of them are duplicates.
And afterwards, we have five items
and we can see that Mike, Mary, John, Bill, and Jane
are on the list.
And these two guys are gone.
And so, we've removed duplicates from the list.
Let me just pull this down.
So, I'm gonna show you what happens
if we actually try to remove the items here
rather than adding them to a collection.
So, I'll say employees.remove employee.
And if we run now,
you're gonna see that we get a
concurrent modification exception.
And we're getting that because
when we're iterating over the list using an iterator,
we're not allowed to change the underlying list
until we're finished with the iterator.
And so, I'll just put that back
the way it is.
Just wanted to explain why I'm doing this step.
Now, your solution doesn't have to match mine.
You might be traversing the list
using a different method and so you can just go ahead
and remove the employees on the spot.
You might have a little optimization here
that instead of adding the employees to the list,
you may be tracking their position in the list.
Remember we talked about that,
that if you provide the index that you wanna delete
so, remove, down here remove and give an index
rather than an object.
It would be a little bit faster.
You'd still have to traverse the list
to that position but then you wouldn't have
to do any comparisons because you provided the index.
So, just a very small improvement there.
You may have found a completely different way to do it.
As long as you're using a hash map,
and as long as when you print out your list
after the deletions, it looks good
and the duplicates have been removed,
your solution is good.
Now, we used a hash map here.
We don't really have to.
We could use something called a hash set,
but we haven't looked at sets yet.
Here because we really just care about the ID's
we could write a different solution
using a hash set.
We don't really need key value pairs
but this is a hash table section,
so I wanted you to use a hash map
and as I said we haven't covered sets yet.
So, that's it for hash tables.
I'll see you in the next section.