(upbeat music)
All right,
so let's get going on talking about stacks.
Now, as I mentioned in the introduction,
the stack is a conceptual or abstract data type.
So what it does is it dictates the operations
we can perform on a set of data,
but it doesn't tell us how the data should be stored.
A stack says I don't care how the data is organised
but these are the operations you're allowed to do on a data.
And so basically, a stack can be backed
by any data structure.
Now, it doesn't make sense for it
to be backed by some data structures,
but you could back a stack
with any data structure you wanted.
So let's talk about the operations we can do on a stack.
Well, one feature of stacks is that the last object,
the last item element that you add to a stack,
is always the first item that you can remove from the stack,
and so that's known as LIFO, last in, first out.
So that means there is no random-access.
We can't do what we can do with an array and just say,
hey, give me the element at position five,
because you're only ever allowed to remove the last item
that you added to the stack,
and because of that, as we'll see in the upcoming slides,
the stack has the concept of a top,
so we talk about the top of the stack.
The item at the top of the stack is the only item
that we are allowed to access.
It's the only one that we are allowed to
look at and it's the only one that we are allow to remove,
and so imagine a deck of cards or a stack of papers.
So if you have a stack of paper,
if you want to get to the paper
that's 10 pages down on the stack,
you have to remove the nine pages
that are on top of it first or if you have a deck of cards
and you want to get down to the 10th card in the deck,
you have to remove the first nine cards before
that 10th card is going to be
at the top of the stack of cards.
So it's last in, first out.
If we add a paper to the stack,
the next time we need a paper we're gonna be taking
the paper that we last added.
Now, we've seen one use for a stack,
and that's the call stack.
When we looked at recursion,
I talked about pushing method calls onto the call stack
and removing them from the call stack and in that case,
the last method that we called was always the first one
that got taken off the call stack.
I mean, if method foo called method bar,
it wouldn't make sense for method foo
to return before method bar does,
because foo has to wait until bar finishes executing.
So a stack is the perfect data structure
to use for the call stack.
Now, we can perform three operations on a stack.
We can add an item to the top of the stack.
That's known as a push operation.
We can remove the top item on the stack,
and that's known as the pop operation,
and we are allowed to peek
at what's at the top of the stack.
Now, when we do a peek,
we can get the first item on the stack
but we don't actually remove it,
and so a pop removes the item from the top of the stack,
but a peek just allows us to access the item
but we leave it on the stack.
Now, I said that a stack can be backed
by any data structure.
It can be backed by an array,
but if you think about it,
a linked list is the perfect data structure for a stack,
because in a linked list,
we always want to be working with the item
at the front of the list if it's a singly linked list,
and so we add items to the front of the list
and we remove items from the front of the list
and by doing that, it means
that the last item we added will always be the first item
that we remove, and so a linked list
is a perfect data structure to back the stack,
and in that case, a push would be an add to front method,
a pop would be a remove from front method,
and a peek would just give us the head item
without removing it from the list.
So it's pretty common to have a stack
that's backed by a linked list,
but as I said, you could also back
a stack with an array.
So let's take a look at the stack, so here's an empty stack.
There is nothing on it.
So the top would be null
if we were dealing with a linked list,
and then let's say we push Jane.
Well, Jane will now go into the stack
and she is the top item on the stack,
so we have a top pointer
or a top variable that's pointing to Jane,
and then we're gonna push John,
so John is now at the top of the stack,
and then we're gonna push Mary,
so Mary's now at the top of the stack.
Now, if we did a pop at this point,
Mary would be the popped value because Mary's
at the top of the stack,
she was the last item to be added to the stack,
and so if we do a pop, the popped value will be Mary
and the new top of the stack will be John.
Now, if we do a peek, the peeked value will be John,
but you'll notice that John is still on the stack,
so here's the state of our stack before doing the peek
and after the peek, John is still on the stack
but we've been able to access him.
We've stored him off in some variable,
so we can look at what the top item of the stack is.
So those are the three operations that we can do on a stack,
push, pop, and peek, and because of that,
a stack has LIFO behaviour,
the last item pushed onto the stack will always be the item
that's popped from the stack.
So let's talk about time complexity.
Well, this is going to depend
on how you're backing the stack,
what data structure are you using to implement the stack.
Now, if we are using a linked list,
the push, pop, and peek operations are
going to be constant time,
because when we looked at linked lists,
we discussed that because we're always operating in the case
of a singly linked list,
which is all you need for a stack,
for the case of a singly linked list,
to add an item to the front of the list is constant time.
To remove an item from the front
of the list is constant time,
and if we wanted to get the head of the list,
which would be a peek, that's constant time.
Now, if we were to use an array,
than push could be linear time
because if the array is full,
we'd have to resize the array,
and we'd have to copy all the existing elements
on the stack over to the new array.
So I say said, the time complexity
of the operations is going to depend
on how you're implementing the stack,
what data structure are you using to back the stack.
Now, if you know the maximum number of items
that will ever be on the stack,
then an array could be a good choice
because you could declare an array
that's large enough to hold the maximum number
of items and the array would never have to be resized.
If memory is tight, an array might be a good choice
because with an array, you don't have the overhead
of having to have a next field.
But if memory isn't tight
and if you don't know what the maximum number
of items is going to be,
then linked list is ideal,
and even if you, if memory is tight,
a linked list would be ideal if you're not,
if you don't expect to be adding a whole tonne of items.
I mean, a linked list really does lend itself well
to the behavioural restrictions that a stack has.
So now that we understand what a stack is
and we understand the operations we can do on a stack,
let's implement a simple stack.
I'll see you in the next video.