(upbeat music)
(keyboard keys clicking)
Alright, so we know a little bit
about Big O notation now.
And now we're going to very briefly look at arrays,
because when we get to sort out algorithms,
we're going to be sorting arrays.
So we need to at least review arrays.
Now this is not a beginner programming course.
So I'm going to assume that you know what an array is,
and you've probably worked with an array
but to make sure we're all on the same page,
let's just quickly create an array
and remind ourselves of
how we can access elements in an array.
So I'm in the IDE here.
This is just a test project,
I'm going to create a new project
and I'm going to go through doing that with you.
I'll do that the first couple of times
and then I'll then I'll assume
you know how to create a project
and all great projects off screen
before we get going in a video,
but for now, we'll go to File, New Project.
You want to make sure Java is selected
on the left hand side.
And here you can set the project SDK.
Now right now I have mine set to Java 9, 1.9.
As I'm recording this video,
Java 9 is still in early access.
So I'm actually gonna change mine to Java 8.
But if you want to use Java 9, that's fine.
For this course it doesn't really matter.
I would recommend at least Java 8
because later in the course,
we will be writing some code that uses language features
that were only made available in Java 8.
So make sure you're using Java 8 or Java 9.
I'm gonna switch mine to Java 8,
I'll take the latest version 102.
You don't need to check anything on the right hand side.
We're going to click Next.
I'm going to check the Create project from template
because this will have the IDE,
generate a main method for us.
Then click Next, I'm gonna call my project Arrays.
And I was fooling around with this before.
So the package is already set.
My package is set to academy.learnprogramming.arrays,
you can set yours to whatever you want.
And then click Finish.
Now because I have a project open,
the IDE is asking me if I want
to replace the project in this window
or open a second window,
we don't need this test project so I'm gonna replace it.
And there we go, we have our new project.
I'm gonna pull this back a little bit to give us some space.
So let's create an int array just to get ourselves going.
So we'll say int, int array = new int,
and I'm going to make one of size seven.
Now if we look at this,
so we were creating an integer array.
So these two square brackets
are telling the compiler we want an array
and then when you create an array,
you have to specify the size that you want.
Arrays are not a dynamic data structure,
we'll see some dynamic data structures later.
By not being dynamic, I mean
that once you've created an array instance,
you cannot change it size.
So this array will have enough room to hold seven integers.
And that's all it's ever going to be able to hold.
We can't increase it size and we can't decrease it size.
And as you'll see later, this leads to some disadvantages
for a raise when we compare them with other data structures.
So we have enough room in this array for seven integers.
So let's add some integers.
So I'm going to set,
int array[0] to 20.
Now just a quick reminder, the indices are zero based
so if you have an int array that can hold seven integers,
the valid indices will be zero to six.
Seven will get you in array index out of bounds
and we'll see in a minute why there is zero based
if you've ever wondered why they're Zero Based
rather than one based you're gonna find out shortly .
So this is saying that in the first slot
if we can imagine an array having seven slots
or seven buckets or however you want to look at it,
seven boxes, seven containers that can hold integers.
We're saying in the first position
we want to assign the integer 20
(keyboard clicking)
in the second position which would be at array index one
we're going to give that the value 35.
In array index two will give that one, -15.
In three will give that one seven.
The fifth position which would be at a rate index four,
is going to get 55.
Only got two more to go,
so intArray[5] will get one
and into intArray[6],
will get -22 no -11.
So we've now filled the entire array
you don't have to fill the entire array
but we have and as you can see the valid indices go
from zero to six and that seven positions, seven slots
whatever you want to call them.
So let's print this array out now.
I'm going to use a classic for loop
so we can clearly see what happened, what's happening.
so I'm gonna say,
for (int i = 0 i&lt;intArray.length i++)
and we're going to print out, intArray[i].
Let's go ahead and run.
(mouse click)
If you by any chance get this error.
I've noticed sometimes get this when I changed the SDK,
you need to come up to Run, Build actually,
and say to rebuild the project.
And I think now it should run.
There we go.
So if you ever run into that error,
because you've changed the SDK,
like I did just come up to Build and just rebuild.
Okay, so we've printed out 20, 35, -15, 7, etc.
Let's take a look at the print statement for a minute.
Once again, just as a brief review,
you'll see that we're starting i
at the first index in the array
and we iterate around until i is equal to the length.
Now remember, the length of the array
is the number of integers that can hold
and we specified that to be seven.
But the valid index the last highest,
the highest valid index is six.
And so i, we wanna loop around and have i go,
zero one two three four five six
when it hits seven.
So when it equals the length of the array
we wanna try drop out of the loop
because seven is actually an invalid index.
So that's why when we loop around, iterate over an array,
we start i at zero and we always wanna stop
when whatever variable variable we're using
to do the looping we wanna keep going
while it's less than the length,
when it's equal to the length then we stop
because at that point, we know we've iterated over the array
and of course, we're adding one
to the variable each time we loop.
Okay, so that was a very quick review of arrays.
As I said, you've probably worked with them before.
In the next video, we're going to start considering
the array as a data structure.
And so I'll see you in the next video.