(upbeat, airy music)
Alright, so hashtables exist
to provide speedy retrieval of data,
and we accomplish that by taking a key.
We take that key-value,
and we use a hash function
to map it to an integer,
and then we use that integer to retrieve the item.
Now, obviously, one data structure
that would land itself really well
to this is the array.
Because when we hash the key to an integer,
we can use that integer as the index into the array,
and so that's what we're going to do
for our simple hashtable implementation.
So we're going to store employees in our hashtable.
So I've created a project.
I've put the code into
academy.learnprograming.hashtable,
and I've copied the usual employee class over.
So I'm now going to add a class for our hashtable.
So new Java Class,
and I'm gonna call it SimpleHashtable
and we're going to need the array
that we're going to use to back the hashtable.
So I'll say private Employee, hashtable
and we'll need a constructor
that's going to create our array.
So we'll say public, SimpleHashtable.
I'm going to set the capacity inside the constructor,
so the caller doesn't have to do that,
and I'm gonna say
hashtable = new Employee,
and we'll just give it a capacity of 10.
We're gonna need a hashing function.
So I'm going to say private
because you don't need to expose
the hashing function to the world.
So private int and I'm going to call it hashKey,
and we're gonna accept a String
because, as I discussed in the previous video,
we're going to use the employee
last name as the key.
Now we're going to return key.length
modded by the length of the hashtable,
and so this is taking a String
and it's hashing to it an int.
That's exactly what a hash functions does.
So let's say we wanna do Jane Jones.
We're gonna, the key.length will be five
and the hashtable length
is 10, and so we're gonna return five
because five divided by 10 is zero
with a remainder of five.
And so we would expect the key Jones
to return a hashed value of five,
and five is what we will use to index
into the backing array.
It's important to use understand
that the key and the hashed value
are not the same thing.
We take the key, and we hash it
to a hashed value.
The key can be anything.
It can be a String.
It could be a character.
It could be whatever you want.
It could be an employee.
The hashed value is always an integer.
Now I'm not claiming that this is
a wonderful hash function.
It's just something that I've made up,
so that we're going to get indices
in the range zero to nine, right?
Because we're modding by the length
of the hashtable.
As I said previously, the hashing function
is gonna play a huge role
in how quick your retrievals are.
I mean if you have a hashing function
that ends up hashing every single key
to the same value, your retrievals are gonna be
pretty slow because all of your values
are gonna go into the same index
in the array, and you're gonna have
to search through all your values
to find the one you're looking for.
If you have a hashing function
that evenly distributes the values
in the array, then your retrievals
are gonna be better.
So, obviously, the ideal case
is you only ever have one value per key.
Now, in the real world, we probably use
the ID as a the key
because they're probably going to be unique,
but we still have to hash them, right?
Because we may be a small company,
and we may only have 20 employees,
but our IDs are five digits long.
Maybe the keycards that we have
require IDs that are five digits long.
So we may only have an employee array
of length 20, but the IDs are in the form
one, two, three, four, five.
So, in that case, we'd still have to hash
the integer because we'd have to map
the IDs to valid array indices.
Okay, so now that we have a hash function
let's add the method that lets callers
put stuff into the hashtable,
and we're gonna call that method put.
So we're gonna say public void put,
and we're gonna need the key
which is gonna be a String
and the value that we wanna add.
Remember that when it comes to hashtables,
we're always dealing with key-value pairs,
and, when you add to a hashtable,
you have to provide the key and the value.
And, as we'll see, when you wanna retrieve
something from the hashtable,
you have to provide the key.
The same key you used to add the value.
So the first thing we're gonna is hash the keys,
so we'll say int hashedKey = hashKey, key.
So the hashedKey will give us the index
into the array, and then we're going
to have a really simple hashtable as I said,
and so this hashtable doesn't handle collisions.
And so, if we try to put an employee
into the hashtable and when we hash the key
the hashed value is the same value
for an employee that we've already added,
we're not gonna add the employee.
We're just gonna print something out saying
sorry that array position is already taken
'cause this hashtable doesn't handle collisions,
and we're gonna say if hashtable
hashedKey is not = to null
meaning that there's already an employee
at that position in the array,
we're just gonna say System.out.print line,
Sorry, there's already an employee
at position,
and we'll include the hashedKey,
so we can see which position it's at.
If that's not the case, we just have
to go ahead and assign the employee
into hashtable indexed hashedKey.
So we'll say hashtable,
hashedKey = employee,
and that's it.
That's our very, very simple put method,
and so we come in, we hash the key,
meaning we map the key they provided
to an integer and then we check
that position in the array.
And, if it's empty, we assign the employee
into that position.
If it's not empty, this first initial
implementation doesn't handle collisions,
so we're just like oops, sorry,
can't add it there.
There's already somebody there,
and that's not gonna be difficult
because all we need is two employees
with last names that have the same length
and we're gonna get a collision.
Now, there's other things we could have done.
For example, we could have had an employee array
of 26, and then we could have looked
at the first letter of the last name.
That would also lead to collisions
because all we would have needed
was two employees with last names
that begin with the same letter,
and we'd have a collision.
So, as I said, in practise
it can be difficult to come up
with a hashing function that's never gonna
give you collisions, so, fortunately,
we have strategies for dealing with them.
Okay, so now that we can put an employee
into the hashtable, let's write the method
for retrieving one.
So we'll say public Employee,
'cause we're gonna return the employee.
Get and, in this case, we need the key,
and the key obviously has to be
the same key you used here.
So, we'll once again, the first thing
we have to do is hash the key
because we need to get the integer value.
We need to get the index into the array,
so we'll say int hashedKey =
hashKey, and we'll pass the key they've given us
and then all we have to do is return
hashtable hashedKey.
Talking about time complexity,
you can see that the retrieval is constant time.
We're just doing good old array direct access,
and we can do that in constant time.
This does not depend on the number
of items that are in the array,
and that's why hashtables are
so good at retrieval.
If you back them an array,
then you can use something like
a String key to get a value that you've
previously added in constant time,
and that's what we want.
That's what hashtables do for us.
All right, so I'm gonna add a print
hashtable method, so I'll say public void
printHashtable, and, since it's an array,
this'll be really straightforward.
We'll just say for int i = 0,
i less than hashtable.length,
i++ and we'll just
say System.out.print line hashtable i,
and that's it.
So let's go to our main method.
I've already added the usual employees
that we work with, and we'll create
a simple hashtable.
So SimpleHashtable.
I'll just call it ht = new SimpleHashtable,
and we don't have to pass a capacity.
And we'll say ht.put.
Now we need a key and a value,
and we're gonna use a last name as the key,
so I'm gonna say Jones,
and we're gonna put janeJones
under Jones and then ht.put.
And we'll put John Doe.
Let's say Doe, johnDoe,
and let's put Mike,
so Wilson
and mike
and then let's put somebody that we know
is gonna cause a collision.
Remember that our very simple hashing function
just looks at the length of the last name.
So we just need to use somebody
that's got a last name as the same length
as janeJones, Doe or Wilson,
so marySmith has five characters
and that's the same as Jane.
So let's add her.
So we'll say Smith, marySmith,
and this should result in the
sorry we can't do it printout.
And, finally, I'll print the hashtable,
so ht.printHashtable.
All right, so let's run.
Okay so this here, sorry, there's already
an employee at position five,
is for when we go to add Mary
because, when we hash Smith,
we're gonna get five,
and Jones also gives us five.
So we already have position five
in our hashtable occupied by Jane,
and then this is the printout of our hashtable.
Let me just pull this up.
So this here is the printout.
So we have John Doe at position three,
so zero, one, two, three,
and that makes sense 'cause he's got
three characters in his last name.
And then Jane is at position five,
and Wilson is at position six,
and so our hashtable's working as we expect.
Of course, it's not a great hashing function
because collisions will be plentiful
if you're adding a lot of people
and we're not handling them at all.
So this is sort of a bare bones implementation
of a hashtable to give you an idea
of how we do the hashing under the covers
when we put and get employees.
So let's go ahead and get an employee.
So I'm gonna say System.out.print line,
and we're gonna Retrieve key, let's say,
Wilson, and we'll say ht.get
and our key is Wilson.
And I'm gonna comment out this here,
so that we're not gonna see all
that printout again.
And let's run,
and there we get Mike Wilson back.
So here's our sorry from when we add Mary,
tried to add Mary here,
and this is our retrieving key Wilson
and we got Mike Wilson back.
And so under the covers here,
on the get, we hashed the key again, Wilson.
We got six and Mike Wilson was
at hashtable six because that's where we put him
when we added him to hashtable,
and so these are the essentials
of a hashtable when you put the employee
you hash the key.
and then, using the key, you put the employee
at the appropriate place.
And then, when you get the employee,
you have to provide the same key.
You have to use the same hash function
to hash that key, and then you use the result
to retrieve the item.
So the beauty of hashtables is
you can use non-integer keys to retrieve items
in constant time.
As I've mentioned, the load factor
in the hashing function that you use
are going to influence that.
So, if you're using a crappy hashing function
or your load factor is really, really high,
so when you're adding you're getting
a lot of collisions, obviously your retrieval
time complexity is gonna start to degrade.
So you might not achieve constant time.
All right, so now that we've looked
at this really simple implementation
that is going to result in a lot of collisions,
we're going to take a look at strategies
that are used to handle collisions,
and we'll do that in the next video.
I'll see you there.