(tinkling music)
(keyboard clicking)
Alright, let's implement the binary search algorithm
and I'm going to do it iteratively first,
and then we'll do it recursively.
So, I'm going to create a method, public static int,
and I'll call it iterative binary search.
And, as usual, we need the array we're searching
and the value that we wanna find.
Now, notice that our int-array is sorted
and so it's okay for us to use binary search.
So we're gonna start by setting up our start and end values,
so we'll say int start equals zero
and int end equals input dot length.
Remember that end will always be one greater
than the partition we're looking at,
and just to remind you in case you didn't realise
from the slides, we're doing logical partitioning,
so we're not actually creating a new array
or every time we partition.
Alright, so we're gonna say while start is less than end,
because when start equals end,
we've searched the entire array and we haven't found
what we're looking for.
We'll say int midpoint equals start plus end over two.
And then we'll say, if input midpoint equals
the value that we're looking for, then we're done, right?
We have found the index of the item we're looking for,
so we'll just return midpoint.
Now, if that's not the case, then we wanna see
if the value at input midpoint is less
than the value we're looking for.
So we'll say else if input midpoint is less
than the value, well if that's the case then we want
to search the right part of the array.
Because, for example, if we're looking for the value 20
and the value at input midpoint is 10,
then because the array is sorted we know that the value 20
has to be at a larger index than midpoint.
And so we want to now search the right part of the array.
And so all we're gonna do here is change the start value,
to midpoint plus one.
So, if our midpoint was, let's say, index five
and we've checked index five and we now wanna search
the right part of the array, while the start value
is going to be five plus one which is six.
Our end would still be the end of the array.
Now, if the element at midpoint is not equal to the value
and it's not less than the value,
then it must be greater than the value.
So in that case, we wanna search the left part of the array.
So, our start value is gonna stay the same,
and our end value will become midpoint,
because midpoint is always one greater than the end
of the partition, and we've already looked at midpoint.
And so we want our partition to run from start
to midpoint minus one.
And so the end will be midpoint.
And that's it.
There's only one thing we have to do.
If we come out of here and we have not found the value,
then we're gonna return minus one.
And so we're gonna keep looping
until our start equals our end,
because that would mean that what happened was we got down
to a partition of one element,
and that element did not equal the value.
And so we're gonna adjust our start and end,
and it's gonna make start equal to end,
and that's when we're gonna drop out,
'cause we've basically gone down to a partition
of zero elements, and so we know
that the value we're looking for isn't in the array.
And so we start out by getting the middle element
and then we compare it against the value we're looking for,
and at some point when we're doing all our partitions,
the middle element will equal the value.
If that doesn't happen, the value's not in the array
and we return minus one.
So, let's go ahead and try this out,
and let's say, system dot out dot printline,
iterative binary search with input,
and let's search for minus 15, that should be int array.
And let me copy this a few more times.
And let's look for 35,
let's look for eight eight eight eight again,
and let's look for the value one,
the example that we did on the slide.
So let's run.
And we'll see that minus 15 is at index one,
that's correct.
35 is at index five, that's correct,
we didn't find eight eight eight eight.
And one is at index two.
So that's all good.
And let's add a line in here to print out the midpoint
on each iteration, so I'm gonna put a line in here
that says, system dot out dot printline,
midpoint equals plus midpoint, midpoint.
Let's go ahead and run this.
And we'll see that the first midpoint was three,
for minus 15, let me bring that back,
I closed it down too quickly.
So for minus 15, the first midpoint was three,
and that's always gonna be the first midpoint right?
Because we start out with the same start and end value.
So, zero, one, two, three, our middle element
that we first compare against is always seven.
And then what happened was the midpoint seven
was greater than minus 15,
and so we changed end to the midpoint,
which would have made end three,
and then when we came around again,
we would get zero plus three over two which is one.
And one is where minus 15 is located.
So, boom, we found it.
Now, for the case we looked at in the slides,
which is the last one, our first midpoint was three,
as we saw in the slide, so we compare one against seven.
One is less than seven, and so we're going to again,
adjust the end, 'cause now we wanna search the left part
of the array, and the new end would be three.
Zero plus three is three over two,
so our second midpoint is one.
And these are always, on each side the midpoints
are always gonna be calculated the same,
because obviously the length of our array isn't changing.
So on the second iteration, the midpoint is one,
and we compare one against minus 15.
One is greater than minus 15,
and so this time we're gonna adjust our start,
and our start becomes two.
Our midpoint was one, and so we add one
to get a start value of two.
Our end remains three, so we get two plus three
is five over two, which is two,
and that's our new midpoint down here,
and then we check, input two, and boom,
we found the value we're looking for.
And so that's iterative binary search.
It's not very complicated.
So now let's write the recursive version.
I'm gonna come down here and I'm gonna say,
public static int recursive binary search.
And we're gonna need the same initial parameters,
so int, input and int value.
But for the recursive version, we're gonna need two methods,
we're gonna need the one that accepts the entire array,
and then of course we're gonna need a recursive method
that takes a start and end point,
because those are what's changing.
So, we're going to say, return, recursive binary search,
and we're gonna say, input,
and our start value will be zero,
our end value will be input dot length,
and the value we're looking for.
So let's go ahead and write this version
of the recursive binary search.
So we'll say, public static int recursive binary search,
and this will take an input array,
it'll take the start value, the end value,
and the value we're looking for.
And so this is the method that's actually going
to be recursive.
I didn't have to break it into two methods,
up here in the main method,
I could just call this method directly,
but normally what you'd have is a method that takes
the entire thing and then you'd call the recursive method.
This is a recursive method,
and so we need a breaking condition,
and our breaking condition is going to be,
if start is greater than or equal to end,
we're gonna return minus one.
And this is basically the same condition as this one.
Here we're saying as long as start is less than end,
keep going.
And here we're saying if start isn't less than end,
then stop, which is essentially what we're saying here.
If start is not less than end,
we're gonna drop out of the loop.
And so it's the same condition, because that means
that we're down to a partition of zero elements,
and that means we didn't find what we were looking for.
Okay, so assuming that's not true,
basically the recursion is gonna do what this loop is doing.
And so we're gonna start out the same way,
int midpoint equals start plus end over two,
and I'll print out what the midpoint is.
Midpoint equals plus midpoint.
And so since the recursion is replacing this,
we don't have a loop, we just basically have to do
what we're doing in here as part of the recursion,
because each call of this recursive method
is pretty much equivalent to a iteration of this while-loop.
And so we're gonna say, if input midpoint equals the value
then we're done right?
So we're gonna return midpoint.
If that's not true, than else, if input midpoint
is less than the value,
we're gonna return recursive binary search,
we're gonna pass the input array,
we're gonna add one to the start point,
midpoint plus one, 'cause we're gonna wanna look
at the right half.
The end will stay the same,
and we're looking for the same value.
Otherwise, we know that the value at input midpoint
is greater than the value we're looking for,
so we wanna look at the left part of the array,
so we'll say, return recursive binary search,
we're gonna pass input.
This time our start will remain the same,
our end will be the midpoint and the value.
And that's it.
Now, if you compare these two things,
you'll see that this here,
or actually this whole thing here is pretty much this.
But, instead of just adjusting the start and end points
and looping around, we're adjusting the start and end points
and then calling the method.
So, as I said, each call of the method is basically
an iteration of this loop.
And that's often how recursion works,
if you write the method recursively and iteratively,
you're basically taking a loop and you're changing it
to a recursive method.
So let's do the same searches,
and I'll copy these first actually.
And then I'll comment out the iterative search,
so that we're not gonna see everything twice,
and I'll just change these to recursive.
Recursive.
And let's run.
Okay, and we'll see that for the first one,
for minus 15, we find it at one.
We find 35 at position five.
We don't find eight eight eight eight,
and we find one at position two.
And you'll see that we have the same midpoints
that we had when we called the iterative version.
And that's it, that's binary search,
not too complex.
In this case, I think the iterative version
is really clear so I would use the iterative version,
because as we discussed when we went over recursion,
the recursive form is usually more expensive
because there's overhead involved with method calls.
And so this one doesn't use any method calls at all,
so on the same hardware, same array everything else,
we'd expect the iterative method to perform a little better
than the recursive method.
Okay, so search algorithms,
not as complex as sort algorithms,
well, not as complex as some of the sort algorithms anyway.
And that's it for search algorithms.
I'll see you in the next video.