(light music)
(typing)
Okay, so let's implement a remove method now,
we haven't done that, so let's do remove.
So I think I'll put it after the get method,
so we'll say public, and we'll return the employee
or null, if there's no such employee in the table, remove,
and as usual, we need the key.
Now remove, just like get,
is gonna have to use linear probing,
because we have to find the employee that we want to remove
and so, we're gonna say,
int hashedKey = findKey(key)
and then we're gonna say, if (hashedKey = -1),
then we're gonna return null,
because there's no employee in the table
with the key of strings, so there's nothing to remove
and if that's not the case, we'll say, Employee
employee = hashtable[hashedKey].employee.
We're gonna null out the position, so we're gonna say,
hashtable[hashedKey] = null,
so that we know there's an empty spot there now
and then, we're just gonna return the employee.
So let's try removing a couple of employees,
so let's come back here and we'll say, ht.remove,
let's remove, I don't know, Mike Wilson
and let's remove Jane Jones,
so that we can try out the linear probing on remove
and then we'll print our hashtable.
So let's run.
Okay, let me pull this up, so we can see what's going on,
so the first printout here is after our adds
and you'll see we have John, Jane, Mike and Mary
and then we do our two retrievals
and then we removed Mike and Jane
and so, here's the second printout
and only John and Mary are left
and so, John is at position three, Mary's at position seven.
You can see that Jane is gone from position five
and Mike Wilson has gone from position six.
Okay so, this is our implementation,
there is one change I wanna make to the find key,
you might have caught this.
So we need to make a change here,
because if we're dropping out of this loop,
because hashtable[hashedKey] is null,
then if stopIndex is not hashedKey,
we're gonna drop here, return hashedKey
and the remove or the get
will then try to use that key,
'cause we're not returning -1 to index into the array
and that's gonna cause a null point or exception.
So I actually wanna change this whole condition here
and we're gonna say, if (hashtable[hashedKey])
is not equal to null
and we have found the key we're looking for,
so hashtable[hashedKey].key.equals
the key we're looking for, then we wanna return hashedKey
and if that's not the case,
if the position at hashedKey is null
or whatever's there doesn't contain what we're looking for,
and that would be the case
when we have looped around and hit the stopIndex,
then we wanna return -1.
Now I discovered that when I was playing around
with trying different adds and removes and things
and we were getting null point or exceptions,
I realised it was because we were assuming
that if we hadn't found the key, that we were dropping out,
because hashedKey had hit the stopIndex,
but of course, that's not true,
we might have dropped out because we've hit a null position.
And so, let's run our main method again,
just to make sure this change hasn't busted anything.
And so, let me just pull this up.
We have the hashtable after we've done our four adds,
we retrieve our two employees
and then we do our two deletes, and there we go.
Now the reason I was playing around
with different adds and deletes,
is because we are dropping out here
as soon as we hit a null position,
this implementation actually does
have a little bit of a bug in it,
if we come to the main method and we try to find Mary again
after we've deleted Jane Jones
and Mike Wilson, let's run.
We're gonna see that we don't find her anymore
and the reason for that is that in
the remove method, we're nulling out removed employees
and so, when we're doing our probing,
we're stopping the first time we hit a null
and because Mike's no longer there,
when we're looking for Mary, we check position five,
actually, in this case,
it would be because Jane isn't there.
We check position five, position five isn't occupied,
so when we're finding the key, position five isn't occupied
and so, we're gonna loop around looking for Mary
and the first time we hit a null, we're gonna stop,
and because positions five and six are null,
we don't get to Mary.
And so, that's the bug, and we're going to take a look
at how to deal with that in another video.
I thought I'd record a quick addition to this video,
because when I reviewed the video,
I realised that I didn't really explain
why we drop out of the loop
as soon as we hit a null position,
because you might be wondering,
well, if we can't find Mary,
why aren't we searching the entire array?
Why are we dropping out when we hit null?
And the reason that we're doing that is,
when we use linear probing, which means
that we're incrementing the index we're checking by one,
we always end up putting the item
in the first available position after the hashedKey value.
So let's say our hashedKey value is five
and we find out that five is full,
so we increment five to one and we get six
and if we find out six is full,
we increment to one and get seven,
we find out seven is full, we increment to one,
we get eight and oh, it's empty.
If any of those previous positions, five, six, seven
had been empty, then we would have put the employee
into one of those positions,
we wouldn't have made it to position eight.
So when we use linear probing,
we always end up putting the item
in the first available position and that's even true
if we have to wrap around to the front.
If all of the positions from the hashed value of the key
to the end of the array are full
and we wrap around to the front,
we're still gonna be putting the item
in the first available position.
And so, when it comes to getting the item back,
so providing the key and we always use linear probing again,
if we hit a null value
before we have found the item we're looking for,
we can be certain that the item is not in the table,
and when I say the item,
I mean that was put in with the key that we were provided.
Now right now, our implementation, as I said,
it doesn't really have a bug in it, but it's not complete,
we're not fully handling removes,
and so, that's why we have the situation
where we can't get Mary,
but as you'll see in the next video,
we're gonna discuss two ways
that we can deal with the problem that I described
and once we've dealt with the problem
using one of those ways,
we're never going to be in a position
when we're searching for a key
that was previously added to the table,
we're never gonna be in the position
where it's possible that there's an empty spot
between the hashed value of the key
and where we ended up putting the item,
due to linear probing.
So once we've fixed this implementation,
or rather, completed this implementation,
we'll never be in a situation where we can have a null value
in between the hashed value of the key
and the index that we located by using linear probing
and you'll learn why in the next video.
And so, that's why it's okay in this loop,
to drop out as soon as we hit null,
because we start at the hashedKey up here
and then our first probe value will either be zero
if we're wrapping around right away
or one greater than the hashedKey
and if that position is null,
then we know that there isn't an employee in the table
with the key that we're looking for,
because if there was, there would be no null values
between the original hashed position
and the position where we inserted the employee.
Now I know that's not true right now with our implementation
and that's why we can't find Mary,
it's because we have to do more in our remove method
and so, in the next video,
hopefully this will become clearer.
And so, the moment we hit a null value,
we don't have to keep searching the entire array,
we don't have to say, okay, well Mary's not in position six,
but maybe she's in position seven,
because once we fix the remove method,
so it's doing more work, that'll never happen,
we'll never have a null value
between the original value of the hashedKey
and the position where we ultimately placed Mary.
Okay, so that's just a quick addendum.
Let's move on to the next video
where we're going to do more work in the remove method,
so that this part of the loop is actually valid.