(gentle music)
(keys clacking)
In this video,
we're going to begin our look at linked lists.
A linked list is a data structure.
It's a sequential list of objects,
but this time, arrays aren't involved.
In a linked list, each item in the list
is aware of another item in the list,
because each item in the list
contains a link to the next item in the list.
Now this is different from arrays
and lists that are backed by arrays.
With an array, each item in the list is completely unaware
of other items in the array, but items in a linked list
know which item comes after them,
and that means that we have to store
some extra information with each item.
When we have an array of integers,
we just have to store the integer value in each position,
but when it comes to a linked list,
we have to store the integer value
and we have to store a reference
to the next integer in the list.
So when we get to the implementation,
I'm going to use the employee class we used
when we looked at array lists,
and so on the screen here, I have a linked list,
and this would be Jane, John, Mary, and Mike.
And as we can see, this blue block
would be the employee object,
and then there'll be a field
that contains a reference to the next item in the list.
Each of these items is referred to as a node,
and the first item in the list is the head of the list,
and the last item in the list always points to null,
because nothing comes after it.
And so what we'll have is a node class
that contains a field for
whatever data you're holding in the node.
In our case, we'll have an employee field.
And then we'll have a next field,
and that next field will be of type node,
because each node points to the node that comes after it.
Now I'm going to insert a spoiler here.
In Java, you wouldn't implement a linked list yourself.
There's a linked list class, but to help us understand
what a linked list is and what its advantages are,
we will code a simple implementation.
So as I said, when it comes to a linked list,
there will be a head field,
and the head will point to the first item in the list.
So if you have a reference to the head,
you can traverse the entire list.
You would start at the head
and then you'd go to head.next,
and then you'd go to that next field, that next one,
until you hit null.
So for a linked list, the only thing you have to store
is a reference to the head or the first node in the list.
And from that, you can get to every item in the list.
So let's talk about what we'd have to do
to insert an item into this list.
So let's say we wanted to insert Bill.
Well, the first thing we're gonna have to do
is create a new node for Bill.
So we'd have a box somewhere that has Bill in it.
When it comes to linked lists,
you always insert a new element at the front of the list.
And you can understand why.
We only ever store a reference to the first element,
and so if we wanted to insert an item
anywhere other than the front,
then we'd have to traverse the list to get there.
And one of the advantages of using a linked list
is that if you insert items at the front of the list,
you can do it in constant time complexity,
because the steps you have to do
don't depend on the number of items in the list.
You're always gonna do the same number of steps.
So we create a new node for Bill,
and we're gonna wanna put Bill here, or up here in front.
Bill is gonna wanna point to Jane.
So after we've created the new node,
we'll assign the next field Jane,
and then we're gonna assign head to Bill,
because Bill will be the new head of the list,
and so that's all we have to do to insert a node.
We create the actual node instance.
We point the next field at the current head of the list
because the new node is gonna become the new head,
and then we point the head field at the new node.
And that's gonna always be constant time complexity,
because it doesn't matter.
You could have three items in the list
or a million items in the list,
and you're just gonna do the same number of steps,
as long as you're inserting at the front of the list.
And so after the insertion,
this is what the list would look like.
Bill's next field points to Jane,
and the head field now points to Bill
because he's at the front of the list.
So how about deleting?
Now what if we wanted to pull Bill off?
And once again, we'll want to delete
from the front of the list.
Otherwise, we're gonna have to traverse the list
looking for the node we want to delete.
Now in the implementation, I'll show you,
when we do a deletion, we return the node that we deleted.
So we're first gonna assign Bill to a temporary variable
called removedNode, and then what do we wanna do?
Well, all we're gonna do is move the head to Jane,
because that effectively removes Bill from the list.
Because for a linked list, the only sort of information
that we're holding is this head field.
And so if we break this link to Bill
and we change heads so it's pointing to Jane,
Bill has effectively been removed from the list.
There's no way we can get from head to Bill.
And then at that point, we would return the removedNode,
which we previously stored Bill into that field.
And that's all we have to do to delete a node
from the front of the list.
Once again, this will be constant time complexity,
because it doesn't matter how many items are in the list.
You're gonna do the same number of steps.
So after we've deleted Bill, this is the situation.
We have, Bill will be hanging off here.
He'll still be pointing to Jane,
but there's no way for us to reach him
from the head of the list.
And if we wanted to do clean out,
we could set Bill's next field to null if we wanted to.
And so that's it for sort of the theory for linked lists.
They're not that complicated.
They're the second data structure we've looked at,
the first one being arrays,
and they differ from arrays in that,
as long as you're inserting and deleting
from the front of the list,
the insertions and deletions are done in constant time,
and that's because there's no shifting involved.
And this type of list is called a singly linked list
because we have one link between every node.
In a little while, we're going to look at a list
that's called a doubly linked list.
But we're starting out with a singly linked list,
and when you're working with a singly linked list,
you want to insert and delete items at the front of the list
because you only have a reference to the head of the list,
and so if you want to insert and delete items anywhere else,
you'd have to start at head
and you've got to traverse the entire list
to find what you're looking for.
All right, so now that we know a little bit
about singly linked lists, let's implement one.
I'll see you in the next video.