(futuristic electronic music)
(keyboard keys clack)
All right, so let's play around
with stacks a little bit.
So in this challenge, I want you to determine
whether a string is a palindrome,
and your solution should use a stack.
So what's a palindrome?
Well, a palindrome is a string
that reads the same way backwards as it does forwards,
and so, for example, racecar is a palindrome
because if we read it from left to right, it says racecar,
and if we read it from right to left, it says racecar,
R-A-C-E-C-A-R.
Now for this challenge,
the strings may contain punctuation.
I want you to ignore the punctuation,
so I did comma did I is a palindrome
because if you remove the comma and the question mark
and also ignore spaces, so remove the spaces,
this reads the same from left to right
as it does from right to left.
We have I did, did I and I did, did I going the other way.
I also want you to ignore case,
so if we had a capital I and a small I here,
that would still be a palindrome.
So the strings may contain punctuation and spaces.
They should be ignored, and case should be ignored.
Now there's a starter project in the resources section
that contains these strings that I'd like you to test,
and there's also a stub for a checkForPalindrome method,
and so, you can code it however you want,
as long as your solution uses a stack.
Now, when I say a stack,
I don't mean that you have to use our stack implementation,
though you could.
I mean you can use any class you want,
including classes we looked at in the JDK,
and I'll tell you that my solution uses a JDK,
as long as you're using the LIFO behaviour of stacks,
and so, somehow, you have to use
the last in, first out behaviour,
and so, good luck,
and I'll see you in the solution video.