[Autogenerated] If you have an application running in production,
that's important for your business,
then you want to be able to see how it's doing so that you can
respond quickly to fix problems if they occur.
The spring Framework and Spring Boot, in particular,
provides very useful features for monitoring applications and for gathering.
Metrics in this module will take a look at these features
and add them to the demo application.
You will first learn about Spring Bootstrap curator,
which is spring boots main mechanism for monitoring
and managing running applications.
Then we'll focus specifically on gathering metrics,
which is useful for monitoring how an application is doing overtime,
spring boot and spring integration.
Use a library name to micro Media.
For this,
we'll take a look at how we can use micro meter in the demo application.
Most of what you'll be learning in this module isn't
specific to spring integration.
You can use Springwood actuator and micro meter in any Springwood application,
but spring integration does provide some specific metrics about message
channels and other spring integration components.
So we'll take a look at what these are to see.
It'll work and make it more realistic.
We'll finish with the demo where we build a monitoring dashboard with
influx TB and Grafana so that you get a clear idea of how you would
use this in a production application. Let's start with spring boot actuator.