[Autogenerated] spring.
Bootstrap actuator is a spring Bootstrap module that you
can add to your application that enables you to monitor
and manage your application.
Let's take a closer look and added to the demo.
When you add Springwood actuated to your application,
it will enable you to monitor the application via HTTP endpoints or via J M X.
You will be able to see many different types of
information in the running application.
For example, health information,
which tells you of the application and it's subsystems are all working normally.
Configuration information,
which tells you exactly what configuration settings The
application is using metrics such as how much memory and CPU the
application is using and security audit events.
For example, if there are authentication failures,
this will, for example,
help you to reject if someone is attacking the
system by trying to guess passwords.
Besides what I just mentioned,
there are many more things you can monitor with Springwood actuator,
and it's also very customizable and extensible,
so you can also add your own application specific
information towards already provided.
This will be easier for me to explain,
and for you to understand if I show you how it works in practice.
So let's add Springwood actuator to live demo application.
Before we go to the demo,
I want to mention that there's a course named Spring Framework Spring Boot.
A actuator by Dustin Schultz.
Off course here on Pluralsight.
That's a good course to follow if you want to know more about Springwood actuator.