[Autogenerated] Let's get into the code again to learn about the main concepts
of micro meter and how you can use them in an application.
Open example.
Project number three in your IDE to use micro meter,
we don't have to add any dependencies.
Springwood Actuator already has a dependency on the core model of micro meter,
so it's already available for use.
Let's use micro meter in the registration service.
What we want to do here is at meters to the code.
Meters are what you used to record metrics.
Micro meter manages its meters in a meter registry.
The first thing we need to do is inject a media registry in the
registration service by adding a constructor parameter for it.
Note that the meter registry is created as a spring bean in the
application contacts by spring boot auto configuration,
so it's available for us to inject here.
Now we can use it in the constructor to create different kinds off meters.
Perhaps the simplest type of meter is the counter.
Let's create a counter by calling the counter method on
the meter registry and give it a name.
Globomantics stopped registration, not count.
Let's also create a field in the class to store the counter.
Now we can use the counter in the register method.
Let's add a line to increment the counter every time
the register method is called.
That's our very first, very simple meter.
Let's see it in action.
As with all these demos,
make sure you have Green Mill running in Docker and then
start to spring Bootstrap services.
Then take a look again at the actuator metrics endpoint.
Our Globomantics start registration or count metric
now shows up in the list of metrics.
Let's copy the name and paste it after the URL.
Here we can see the value of the counter,
which is, of course, zero At the moment in the code for this demo,
I've included a JUnit test named Low Generator.
When you run this test,
it's going to submit 1000 registrations with the random
names and email addresses to the service.
Let's start this test.
Go back to the browser and refresh the metrics page.
You will see the counter go up as test is running.
Besides counters, micro meter has other types of meters.
Let's add another meter to the registration service.
Let's stop the low generator test and go back to the
constructor off the registration services.
We'll create a timer, which is a media for recording amounts of time,
just like the counter we created from the meter registry.
By calling the timer method, let's name this one.
Globomantics stopped registration or time and also
create a feel for it in the class.
The next step is using the timer in the register method to
record how long it takes to execute the method.
The timer has different record methods,
and we're going to use the one that takes a supplier.
What we're going to pass as the supplier is the whole body
off the method in a Lambda expression.
The record method is going to measure the time it
takes to execute the code in Islam.
The expression.
And then it will return whatever the Lambda expression returns.
In this case,
that's the registration event object that we want to return
from the register method so we can just put return in front
off a call to the record method.
Let's restart to spring good service to let our code changes take effect
and also run the low generated test again at the metrics,
endpoint.
Our timer is now, of course, also listed.
And we can take a look at the details by a pending its
name to the metrics and point URL.
Here,
you'll see that the timer provides three measurements count total
time and max the same as you saw earlier when we looked at the
HTTP dot server dot requests metric.
Now you understand that the HTTP do serve able to
requests metric is also a micrometer timer.
Each type of metric produces its own particular set of measurements.
As we saw, a counter just produces account value.
A timer also provides account and total time and max
measurements in addition to the count.
Besides counters and timers, there are other types of metrics.
But I'm not going to explain them all in depth here.
The three main types of metrics are counter SSHD timers engages We'll use engage in one off the next demos