[Autogenerated] when you use micro meter in the spring boot
application than a media registry is conveniently created
for you by auto configuration.
But what if you need to configure the meter registry?
You can do that by providing a meter registry.
Customize your bean.
Let's add the media registry customize error being to the main
application class Globomantics service application.
We'll add a method with the being a notation that will return a meteor registry.
Customize er,
the media registry customize er interface defines a
single method named customize,
that we have to implement instead of implementing it as an anonymous glass,
we can, of course, use the Lambda expression.
The method gets past the meter registry to customize as an argument.
One purpose we can use this for is to define common tax that
you want to appear on all your metrics.
Suppose, for example,
that are application will run on multiple machines and that we
want to add a host name tag to all metrics so that we can real
down to the metrics for specific machine.
We can do that by defining a common tack on the registry by calling registry
do conflict or common tax real pass this method attack,
name and value.
The tech name is just as string host name,
and the value is the actual host name off the machine
that the application is running on.
Since determining the host name is unfortunately,
not a short statement,
I've put that code in a separate component that will inject
and call here to keep this example simple.
When you now restart the spring boots service and look at any of the metrics,
you'll see that they all have a host name tag listed under available tax. This allows you to select the metrics for a specific machine.