[Autogenerated] you've learned a lot in this module.
Let's do a quick summary.
First we looked at Springwood Actuator,
which provides us with a way to look at what's going on in the
running application through the actuator and points we've added
Springwood actuated to the demo application,
and you've learned about a different endpoint.
Then we focused on micro meter and the metrics.
Endpoint Micro meter is the I'll for J for metrics.
It enables you to record metrics using different kinds of meters,
such as counters, timers, engages.
My Chrome media provides dimensional metrics,
which means that you can define tax on your metrics so that you can
drill down on the metrics in different dimensions.
We took a look at how you can customize the media
registry with the meter registry,
customize her and how you can use a meter binder to ad metrics.
Then we have looked into the metrics that spring integration provides.
The most interesting of these is the spring got to integration not sent metric,
which provides a lot of information on the messages that are being
sent to message channels and message Chandor's.
Finally, we used influx DB and Grafana,
and you've gotten an idea of how you would use this to create a monitoring
dashboard for production application in this module.
You've learned how to monitor what's happening in the spring
integration application in the next module.
We're going to focus on managing and remotely controlling the application. Let's learn how to do that in the next module.