[Autogenerated] When you want to learn how to swim,
you know you'll have to get into the water.
And with yourself,
you don't really learn how to swim just by reading a
book or watching a presentation.
The same thing goes for programming.
So I highly recommend that you download the example code that goes along with
this course and work with it yourself on your own computer.
You don't need a lot of software, and if you're Javadi helper,
you'll most likely already have all the tools you need.
But for completeness, I'll quickly mention the tools that you should have.
First of all, you off course needed you have a development kit.
You can download it from Oracle or from another provider,
such as Adopt Open JD Gay real use Jaedicke 11 for this course,
which is the current long term support version of Java.
All the examples in this course are may even projects.
So to build them from the command line,
you'll need Apache may even you are free to choose your favorite i e.
I will be using IntelliJ IDEA.
Finally, we will use Docker in this course to run some software.
Docker is very convenient for software development as it enables you to run.
For example, database is email servers,
message brokers or whatever other software you need in a container so that
you don't have to install and manage it on your machine.
I'm running Ubuntu Linux on my machine,
but almost everything I'll show will work the same way on Windows or macOS.
If there are any operating system, specific differences for the demos, I'll mention them.