This section is very important because we are going to discuss a very useful and logical topic called
regular expression.
Regular expressions are very powerful way to search, replace or manipulate strings using pattern matching.
Regular expression patterns are supported in various programming languages.
Regular expression can be applied either with simple JavaScript string patterns in methods like search,
replace, split, etc. or the patterns can be built using reg X class in JavaScript.
Before diving deep in the concept, we will begin with very basic example.
Let's take a variable.
Let MSG is equal to.
I will just say this is case sensitive.
This is the string I'm assigning here.
I'm making word cases C capital.
Now I want to get the index or position of the word case in a variable.
So I will say let price is equal to MSG dot search.
And of course I'm going to search the Capital C case.
Let's try to display the position.
So I'll say console or log POS.
Let's run the code.
As you can see, that the output is eight.
That means the word case is found at position eight in string MSG.
Now let's change this uppercase C to lowercase.
And run the code.
Now you see that the search method is unable to find.
So it returns minus one.
It means the search is case sensitive by default.
Let's assume that we want to make case in sensitive search.
Meaning regardless of the case, if the word matches, then search method should find it.
So let's try regular expressions for case insensitive search.
I will add regular expression pattern.
The patterns begin with Slash.
So I'll say slash case.
And I will add slash I.
Now let's run the code.
Now again, it returns eight.
It means the case world.
I can write in any case, even toggled case like this.
Let's run the code.
Still, it works fine.
So with a search method of string, we have used regular expression pattern.
Now let's talk about the syntax of regular expression.
So when it comes to syntax of regular expression pattern, it is very simple.
It begins with a forward slash.
And then the pattern that is word or character, along with some search pattern like square brackets,
star, etc..
And then again one more slash and you give the modifier or flag If the same pattern is to be used using
Reg X class, then one can write like this.
First you specify the pattern and the second is flag or modifier.
So if the same code is to be returned with the regular expression class of JavaScript, it will look
like this.
We will create the pattern using Reg X class, which takes two parameters.
First is the pattern and second is the flag or the modifier.
So here, because we want to perform case insensitive search, we are going to say I now we'll search
the pattern.
So I'll say pattern.
Let's run the code and see the output.
It still returns eight.
So here I have taken beta and variable, which contains the pattern and flag details.
So now we know that we can define patterns with two syntax.
First is we use the pattern and the flag or modifier.
Or we can use the regexp class that is the constructor where we specify the pattern and flag or modifier.
Here in the example we saw that we did not give any complex pattern.
It was just a simple word for a modifier.
We have used AI, which is for case insensitive search.
So before we dive deep into patterns, let's begin understanding flags or modifiers.
Let's take a look at this table which contains list of modifiers or flags.
We have already seen AI which performs the case insensitive search.
G performs a global match and performs multi line search.
S allows DOT to match new line characters and that is introduced after is 2018.
Of course, it doesn't work with Firefox at the moment.
You switches on the Unicode pattern matching and y switches on the sticky mode.
Don't worry about these Unicode or sticky words we are going to discuss in detail about each and every
modifier.
So this is the table of all flags, but we need to understand all the flags individually.
We have already seen case insensitive search using flag, i.e. let's start exploring other flags or
modifiers.
We will begin with g.
G performs global match.
It means it does not stop the search after the first occurrence.
Let's try performing it practically.
We will use the match method to try modifier g.
Match method returns an array which contains matching string in an array.
If we don't use G, then it returns additional information like index, original input, string, etc.
So let's try the code.
I will use the same code here, but instead of search I'm going to say message dot match and I'm specifying
the pattern.
Of course we want to search the case keyword.
Also the match method and adding a pattern case without any flag at the moment.
And let's print the str.
Let's try to display the value of SDR.
As you can see in the output that match returns error and first value is found.
That is case word is returned as first element of the returned error.
Now let's try to add more occurrences of case.
I will add case word at the end of string and we will run the code again.
Still, the output is the same because the search stops as soon as the first case word is found in the
string.
So here we want that.
It should keep on searching through the entire string that is global search, which we can do by modifying
that is using the G flag.
So let's add g modifier and run the code.
Here.
I'll say slash G.
Let's run this.
Now, as you can see, by simply adding G, now it returns all occurrences of word case.
In case if you want to apply two or more flags or modifiers, you can do that as well.
Let's try.
Case insensitive global search.
Let's make last case with a capital C and run the code.
Now you see that in the output in the array, it returns only one case because that is no case in sensitive
search.
Now, I want to add global as well as case insensitive search.
So I'm going to say G and I.
Now, let's run this score.
So now it is performing both global and case insensitive search.