The question we are discussing is explain Adi and traversal in ADI.
Now this is added a related question.
So the category is area, of course, and there will be three related questions.
Normally when you have a variable, it can store only one value.
For example, we have a variable like this where I say Let I is equal to ten.
It means that is one location in which value ten is stored.
If I say I is equal to 20 in the next line, it means the value is overwritten.
So at a time only one value is stored.
When you feel that you want to store more values under one name, then you can use an ADI.
Adi is available in all programming languages.
Few languages support only specific type of ADI.
Let's say an array of integer cannot have a string value.
But in JavaScript we have ADI, which can store any type of value.
In fact, we have added class and eddies are the prototype of this class.
Let's create an ADI and see a few fundamentals quickly.
How do we create an ad in JavaScript like this?
Let error is equal to.
We have this square bracket.
This is a shorter way to create an ad.
Of course we can write like this.
Also let error is equal to new Adi because Adi is the main class.
But this is a better way.
When we say square brackets and we give a list of data here, for example, I give four, comma seven,
comma, nine.
Let's create another ADI.
Everyone here, I want to show that we can have any type of data in it.
Like I have a string, then a boolean value and let's see some number.
Let's print both the ads here and here are one.
I will just run this code.
As you see that both the ads are displayed here.
Let's try to understand internally what actually happens internally.
This ad, for example, where we have high tru and 900 looks something like this.
Each location has this value.
Now this location is given a number.
This number is called as the index number.
So this is the lower index.
And here zero one and two two is the upper index or upper boundary.
If you see each location like this high or maybe true or 900, this, each location is called as an
element.
So this area is of three elements.
In fact, we can have console.log.
What I can say at our at our one not length.
This length property gives me total number of elements in an ad.
So if I run this, we'll get three here because we have three elements in this ad.
Now, if you want to refer only one element, then you can use the square bracket and the index number.
So let's say I just want to have the first element of this ad.
So I say added one of zero, that is square bracket and the index number.
So if I save this and run.
I'll get only the high value, not the entire Adi.
So these are different indexes we use.
Right.
We can also see here, if I want to get the last element of every Adi, I can say console.log.
Era off.
Now here.
What I'll do is I'll say error, not length minus one.
Right?
So this is going to refer the last index number.
So this will display the last value.
That is nine of the first ADI.
So this is a common way to declare an area or access individual elements.
We can, in fact have an array of object, literally.
Say, for example, I'll declare one area where I just see that there will be multiple elements and
each element will be an object literal.
For example, as a particular product code, for example, value one product name, I'll say, for example,
Apple, I'll copy this two more times.
Now I'm going to assign different values here.
Let's say instead of apple, I'll say banana.
And orange.
And he had in the picture.
I'll say two and three.
What does this mean?
It means now each element of Eddie is an object literal.
So let's try to print the value of this, Eddie.
I'll say console.log era.
And we run this.
You see that this center ETA is displayed.
It means if I see error of zero, let's say here I'm going to refer individual element.
Right.
So this will display the first object itself.
Only the apple and product code is one.
In case if you just want to refer the product name so you can say dot B name, let's see the output.
Only apples return.
So these are difference in taxes.
We can try with Adi.
Now let's talk about traversal.
Traversal means we are going to navigate through an ADI.
We will begin with the most traditional way.
That is loop till the last element.
How do we do that?
For example, I create an added, let's say let error is equal to I'll create an area of few strings
only.
Let's say yes file we have E6 is seven and I put s eight.
Now we have four elements here.
If I want to traverse through this, Adi, the most common way is we declare a variable which begins
with the zeroth index.
We go to the last element and we increment this I by one.
For example, this is the index number.
And here let's try to refer so I'll say console.log area of I.
So every time this statement is displayed right, it's going to refer zero, one, two, three and so
on.
So if I run this, we are going to add all the elements individually.
This is one of the very common way to traverse through.
But each language has its own way or method also to loop through the ADI.
For example, in JavaScript E6 onwards we have far in and far off.
There are two ways to look through an ADI.
So let's try those two ways also.
I'll save our loop, then let an element.
At the moment I am not seeing element because this is kind of index number.
So I'll say or let's say element only let element in error.
So now this is going to look through individual element.
But the thing is, when you use the in operator, it is going to return the index number and not the
value.
Let's try this.
I'll say console.log element.
I'll save this and run the code.
As you see that it is zero, one, two, three and so on.
If we have more values, it'll be more.
But ideally it doesn't display the value.
So in is not a very preferable we are not a very common way to use because generally when you look through
the ADI, the concern is the value and not the index number.
So you have the of operator.
So if you use off, it's going to refer the value directly and not the index number.
So right now, if I run the call now you see all the elements are displayed.
So this is the difference between far in and far off in will display the index number and off will return
the element directly, which is a faster way to loop through.
But in our off, when you run with this kind of code, you are not going to see any difference as long
as the speed is concerned.
Right.
But still, when it comes to referring the value you go with off also.
So so far we have seen all the drivers always using loop.
There are many methods who loop through the array and return a new array like map or filter, which
we will discuss in some other questions.
But at the moment we will see one method which is there to only traverse through the array and that
matter is the for each method in this code I'm going to use for each, so I'll see added dot for each.
Now this actually takes a callback function as an argument.
At the moment our concern is that I write the function here.
Now I'm using the traditional syntax, but I can use the arrow syntax also.
Let me use arrow syntax so I'll remove this function and put an arrow.
So we have the arrow here.
Now this callback function is filled with a few parameters.
The first parameter is the element itself.
That means every time the for each is executed, the element that is this value is passed to element
here.
And if you want to refer the index number that is also passed.
So every time the loop is executed, the element is parsed in first parameter.
And if you have return index, let's say right index here, then the index is parsed here.
We can illustrated like this that this value is passed here.
Every time an index passed here, let's try to display both the values, I'll say console.log element
and also the index number I want to display.
Let's loop through the edit now let's see the output.
As you see that we have both the element and index number return.
In fact, it also takes two more arguments adding on which the four each is called.
And this argument which is a dis for the callback function.
But now when you add using arrow function, this will not refer to itself.
Right?
So you have to take care of which function you are using.
You are going with the traditional function or arrow function.
So it does matter with this argument for each cannot be stubbed in between.
Like you break the loop.
So if you have a situation where you want to come out of a loop in between, then for each is in the
matter you should use.
Now let's discuss related questions of this topic.
The first question is what is the difference between far in and far off?
We have already seen that far in will display the index, whereas far off will refer the value.
What will be the output of the below code?
Now see, as I mentioned earlier, you cannot break the for each loop.
It's going to go through the entire ADI.
So when you say index is equal to two, for example, then I want to come out.
If you say break statement, it is going to give you an error.
Let's try this here.
I'll simply say if index is equal to two, then what happens?
I want to come out.
That's what my wish is.
But it's not going to happen.
Right.
It gives you the error.
It won't work.
It's illegal.
Break statement.
The third question is what will be the output off below statements?
So in this case, what are we trying to display is added or lended that is added off three because added
or length will return three because there are three elements.
This will display undefined because there is no such thing our array of three because we have zero one
and two because index starts with zero.
So if this code is run, then it's going to say undefined.
So we have discussed various possibilities and questions of looping through the ADI in JavaScript.
Next questions.
We are going to deal with more advanced topics of ADI.