This section is all about the bouncing and throttling.
Before we begin, let me also tell you that the bouncing and throttling is not a JavaScript keyword
or a command.
It is the approach or the way you handle events.
So basically it is a concept to improve the event handling and the application performance.
Let's look at this sample application to get some idea.
In this application, I have placed a division.
There is a mouse mode event configured on this division.
Every time a mouse move event is fired, I'm incrementing a counter to know how many times the event
is fired.
I have also implemented throttling and d bouncing with the same event to check the number of executions.
Now let's check by moving the mouse and see how the counter gets incremented.
The moment I start moving the mouse, you see that the normal count says 65.
Throttle count stays eight and the bounce count is four.
Let me again move the mouse for some time.
And you see that the number differs a lot.
This particular count shows that how many times the actual mouse move event is fired, that is 114 times.
The total count shows.
14.
That means with the approach of throttling the mouse mode event fired only 14 times as compared to 114
with normal count.
At the same time, if you observe the bounce count, it just says eight times.
It means that by implementing the bouncing approach, the mouse move event was executed only eight times.
This is just an example to understand that you are controlling the events fired like a mouse moon event
or maybe a scroll event or even a key press event.
Throttling and d bouncing help you to control or to improvise the performance while the events are executed.
Here.
I have just shown the counter increment, but imagine that on an event you are making a call to an API,
making an S&P call, or you may have some huge process to execute within a function.
In such cases, if you use throttling or bouncing, it's going to improvise the overall performance.
So this is what the bouncing and throttling is all about.
We will create the same application step by step to master this concept.
And also we will see use cases of the bouncing and throttling in detail.
So let's begin with the conceptual understanding of throttling and the bouncing first.