Before I start discussing Dom, let us see a practical example.
Suppose we have this HTML section which contains a heading and a button inside the division.
The heading has been assigned with a unique ID that is message, and the button contains a function
that is update message function.
Then we have a JavaScript section that contains the related JavaScript coding.
Now the output of this code will look something like this where when the button is clicked, the heading
gets changed.
What you need to understand here is that this is the HTML section, that is the interface, and this
is the JavaScript section which contains the coding part.
Now that is something which is allowing this JavaScript section to access these HTML elements.
What I mean here is all these HTML elements which you see beat head, body H1, this division, all
these elements can be accessed by with this JavaScript section.
If we take a look at the browser, this section is the document section inside this browser window.
So we have the window and the document.
These are two different objects.
The structure of the document is designed using HTML and CSS.
That is the web page.
The important point here is this section of the browser, which is called as the document is available
internally in some way.
And that internal presentation inside memory is the DOM.
It means the document object, which you can see here in the code, this document object which has method
that allows to access this when inside the HTML programmatically.
So basically Dom is an interface which is accessible by programming languages like JavaScript or even
Python.
It means that the DOM is independent of any language.
It is a structural presentation of the web page inside memory and is provided by the browser in the
form of an object called document, which is also known as the DOM API.
As it gives you the interface to access the DOM.
I hope you know API is application programming interface and this gives you an interface that JavaScript
or Python like languages can use and can access the HTML page.
The DOM is the internal part.
It is inside the memory which is allowing you to access these HTML elements inside the programming language.
In our case, it is the JavaScript.
Let's have a look at a different example, where you have a web page designed like this.
You have the HTML head title body.
Inside body, there are two divisions.
One is having a heading and a button, whereas the second Dave has an input.
Now if you consider this particular page internally, the document is created somewhat like this.
You actually have the window as the topmost object, but the DOM does not start from that place.
In the newer terminologies.
The bomb that is the browser object model can start from window, but that's something which we will
discuss later on.
Right now the dome starts here and you see the structure where we have different elements.
Every element has a parent child relationship.
For example, you can see inside this division we have H1 and Button.
And inside this division, we have input.
These two divisions are at the same level.
That means they are siblings, these objects of the HTML page and thats what we call the DOM tree.
Also with this document object model, which is available inside the programming language, you can
either remove an element or insert an element.
You can change the text of an element.
You can traverse through the tree.
That is, you can search an element.
All these things you do with the programming and that process, that action of performing various operations
is also known as the DOM manipulation in shard searching, adding, removing through the DOM tree.
All these is known as the DOM manipulation.
So Dom is an internal model of document that is your web page, where every element of the document
is an object and available for programming languages to access.
Let's talk about few questions or a few terms which are related to Dom, and you should know that.
So the question is what is Dom or the DOM API?
So basically it gives you an interface, the browser in fact gives you the interface.
And that interface is actually the document object which is available inside your programming language
through which you can access the HTML page, you can change the color of elements, maybe you can remove
elements, add elements, all these things you can do through this document object.
That's what the DOM is or that's what the DOM API is.
Second what is a DOM tree.
So basically the DOM which we have.
Does have parent child relationship.
So when you try to draw it on the page or maybe somewhere you will see that there is always a kind of
hierarchical presentation and when something comes in the hierarchical format, it becomes the tree.
So DOM structure itself is also known as the DOM tree.
The next question, what do you mean by dumb manipulation?
So as I have mentioned just now, that performing various types of operations through programming language
on the web page, through programming language, that is what the DOM manipulation is.
That is always a need of adding removing elements at runtime.
All those things are known as DOM Manipulations.
That is also a term called DOM Traversal.
Generally that happens when you loop through the entire tree in case when you want to search an element.
For example, I give you one exercise where you have to remove an element.
Then certainly, first of all, you need to search through that is you will have to traverse through
the DOM tree.
All these operations are also known as DOM manipulation.