The second question in audience category is about what is this object?
And there are two related questions for this topic that this object is a common object used at many
places in day to day programming.
The definition of this object is that it contains the current context.
That this object can have different values depending on where it is placed.
Let's check one simple example in the browser window.
I will simply say cancelled out loud.
And will try to display value of this letter on the code.
As you can see right now, it is displaying the window object that is by default.
If you refer to this object in the browser window, it is going to display the window object only.
The reason is that this refers to the current context, the current context, or where exactly it is
pointing to is the window object because window is the global object in the browser.
Let's say, for example, I put this statement inside a function.
For example, I create a function called test and I shift this in this function.
Now, if I run the function test and if I run, this still uses the window object.
Again.
The reason is the test function is actually part of the window.
Object window is the global object.
So for example, if I just see window dart e is equal to five.
This means I'm declaring one property e, which has value five.
Now, in case if I try to display even in this function, for example, this dot e, it displays fi
only.
So because this binds to the window object, it is going to get the value of a the very same.
E So at the moment the function test is also part of window object and this member is also part of window
object.
And this refers to the global scope in this case.
Let's try to shift this.
That is the object this into object literal.
We have already seen object literally in the previous section.
I hope you are clear with it.
So if you haven't gone through the object literally video, please make sure that you do refer.
Very well.
Now I am creating an object literal here which has a method.
For example, the test method.
And here, if I try to display value of this, let's say object art test.
Now the test function is actually part of this object.
So now if I try to refer to it, it displays the value of object.
That means.
Now this is pointing to object at the same time.
In case if I convert this test into arrow function, then the behavior of this will change in the traditional
function.
For example, I write the traditional way that is test is equal to I'm using colon for equal to right
because we are an object literal.
Now here if I say function and if we run this, it still sees the object.
Imagine if you convert this into arrow function, let's say remove this function and put an arrow here.
Now, if I run this again, it displays a window.
So earlier when we did not use the arrow function, it was showing the reference off object.
But the moment we converted the matter into arrow function, it started displaying window object.
This means that this object does not work with arrow function.
That is also a reason which I have already discussed in arrow function tutorials.
But just to brief about it that earlier the function had a duty to behave as a class.
This arrow function doesn't have to behave as a class.
We are going to see what classes are in forthcoming questions.
But here the arrow function is free from playing a role of class so it doesn't have to worry about handling
the this with the current context.
So when you say arrow function, this will not work the way you are expecting if you are comparing it
with the traditional function.
So you can see that this doesn't work with arrow function.
And I have already mentioned the reason why.
Let's discuss related questions of this topic.
The first question is what will be the output of discord if you run in the browser and why now?
Discord is same.
What we tried here.
The code is that you have a function test.
You try to display the value of this and if you run this, it displays window.
The reason is the current context.
Whatever you declare in the browser window, if it is not inside any function, either wrapper or object
literal or be a class, then it's going to refer the window object only.
So when you try to display a value of this in a function which is written inside a browser window,
it is going to refer the window object, which is actually the global object in the browser about the
global object and the browser architecture we have already discussed in DOM related questions.
The second question is what is the context of this inside arrow function or what will be the output
of this core?
We have already discussed that this object doesn't work with arrow functions, so actually it refers
the global object, which our global reference is in their context.
Say, for example, if I put this code in Node.js environment, then it will refer to the global this.
So arrow function doesn't work with this object with a current context.
So it's going to refer the global wrapper, whichever is the topmost global object that will be referred
with this object.