In this section, we are discussing a newer way to declare a string, which is introduced with the newer
version of Act Musgrave six.
That is Essex.
It is known as the template string or template literal.
Let's talk about how can we declare a template string or template literal?
If you have to declare a string variable with template literal, then you can use the back ticks.
So I will say let STR is equal to and I am not new to JavaScript.
Let me just display this.
I'll say console.log.
SDR So if I run this, it'll display the string as we normally expect.
Then what's the advantage of using this?
As long as the advantage of template string is concerned as it sees that it is a template literal.
It gives you a way to display the expression inside the back itself.
Let me show you that if I have a variable here, let's say I have a variable which is having a value
90.
Now I just want to display the value and let's say here I have some string.
That value of a is ideally what happens when you have double quarter single code, you try to end and
then you try to either put a comma or maybe you join it.
If you are putting it inside console.log, you will add a comma, but if you have to join the string,
you are going to use the plus sign or in a way you are going to concatenate the string.
But here you don't need that inside the back date.
If you have to display the value of E, you can write the E here.
But if I write this way, it won't refer to the value.
So what you have to do is you have to cover the expression inside the curly brackets and use a dollar
sign before the curly bracket.
If I run this, let me clear the console and run.
You see that it displays value of a is 90.
So this is one advantage that you can display the expression inside the back.
You don't need to end the back dig and then you join the value.
This is one advantage.
The second advantage with back take that is the template literally is the way you have return inside
of the string or inside a variable.
It will appear as it is.
Let me show you that as well.
Say, for example, here, I'll say I'll remove.
This is now.
This is a line where I just want to say this is.
Then I press enter, observe this in between.
I have not yet closed it on the same line.
I pressed Enter in between.
Now I am not giving any space.
So let's say you just two spaces here.
This is second line.
And now I give some space here.
I say this is the third one, clearing the console and running this code.
Again, as you see the way I have done, whatever spaces I give, whatever new line scatters, return
stabs or whatever.
Each and every format you have assigned to the string in the very same format, the string is displayed.
So when you have to store the format, the special characters like spaces are new lines as it is.
You don't need any skip sequence.
Still, it works fine.
So this is another advantage when you are using the template string.
Ideally you see that when we followed the E6 index, programmers prefer to have this syntax that is
using the back tick.
It's easy to deal with the expressions and the string format as it is it refers.
Let's discuss a few questions here.
Anyway, I have answered the questions inside the call itself.
The first question is what is a template literal?
You call it template literal or template string.
So it is basically a newer way to declare the string variable in JavaScript.
Not only declaring a string variable, you can directly display a string with back to say.
For example, let's say I don't declare any variable here this very string I just cut.
And based inside this console log.
I don't have any variable.
That's fine.
Let me clear this again.
I run.
The output is going to be the same.
So the point is when you have to deal with strings, this is a newer way and that is the template literal
or template string.
The second question is how will you display a value or an expression inside a template string?
Now, as you see in this piece of code that when you have to refer the value of a, you use the dollar
and the curly brackets.
So it will execute the expression.
The third question is what is the advantage of using the template string?
As I mentioned, these are the two advantages.
One is that you can execute the expression without the end of the back deck.
And the second is this one where the string was in a different format, the exact format of string,
the way you have returned, the string it displays as it is.