This section has an important question.
What is the difference between window and document object?
The category of this question is DOM and web related question.
And we will have around 6 to 7 related questions which are connected with this topic.
Let's begin the answer.
If you want to quickly visualize window and document, then let me show you.
With the help of browser.
Now, as you see that the entire browser window is actually window object and the inner part where the
content is displayed, all the content can be accessed using the document object.
This also means that window is the main container or patterned or global object and document is child
of window object operations related to entire browser.
Window can be part of window object, like opening a new window for that matter.
Alexi Accessing this address bar.
Let's I want to see what is the value inside this address bar.
So this is beyond document, but under window.
Let's try to see the content of both the objects in console of developer tool.
Let me expand the window object.
You see that there are various values we have underpin the object actually we have various events,
various objects.
Document is also an object of windows, so let's try to refer the document as well.
Now you see that the moment I type document, the document section is automatically highlighted.
And if we expand this document object that also has that HTML and various other things.
The way I have type document, I can also say window dot document.
That's also a valid way to refer the document object, but because window is a global object and document
is child of it, we do not need to say window to document all the time.
All the members meet object method are properties.
If they are part of window object then you do not need to refer the window object again because window
is a global object like for example, set interval or for that matter set time method.
All these methods are part of window object.
So ideally you would write a window, not set interval or window not set time out.
Then it is not wrong.
But because window is global, you avoid using the window term all the times.
Rather you use set interval are set time out directly, so set interval or set timeout etc. are methods
of window, whereas document is an object of window.
Of course, further document object does have various other objects.
Methods are properties as well like document or get element by ID.
So get element by id is part of the document object.
Window object also has properties like inner height or inner weight.
Let's try it practically.
To see this, let's say or log window, not inner height.
And now, just to prove that that innervate is part of window, I do not need it.
I will write Innervate without the window object.
Let's try to run this.
So display some value.
That is the height and width of the browser window.
Now let's run the same code by resizing the browser window.
As you see that it displays the current inner height and weight of a window in pixels.
So these types of settings, the window object has let's try a few more properties of window like location.
I'll say cancel or log window that location.
Now when I run this, you see that it displays the object literal, which has various values like hostname,
adjective and other values.
Also, let's try to refer only the adjective.
Now I will not write window, not location.
I will simply say console or log location, not adjective.
Let's run the code.
Now you see that the atrophy is displayed separately.
In fact, there are few terms which are related to this concept, like Dom and the Bomb.
Dom is document object, model and bomb is the browser object model.
We can think of bomb and dom as shown in the figure.
So the window has various objects like location, screen, navigator, frames, history, etc. so all
related information to these things, if you have to use it, is the window object which gives you the
access to it like we have already seen window location.
But when it comes to elements placed inside of the HTML, all the elements are part of the DOM.
That is the page which you see inside the HTML.
So if you want to access that, you will say document dart.
The member name of course, window is the main umbrella where all other elements are part of it, but
that is a classification for each and every segment displayed inside the browser window.
So when you refer the term bomb, that means it is the browser object model.
It means it has objects like these, and DOM allows you to access entire content which is played by
HDMI links.
So now you know both window and document object and it's usage as well.
Let's discuss different ways of asking this question are related questions to this topic.
The question can be Is there any difference between window and document?
So we have already discussed this.
The next question, what is Dom or what is DOM API?
So the answer can be it is the document object model.
That means the browser is giving you the document object, which helps you to access the elements through
JavaScript.
It is also referred to as the DOM API.
Next question is what is BOM?
That is browser object model.
So it is basically giving you a few objects related to window and using that we access location, history,
screen the height and width of window, etc..
So bom actually refers to the window elements only.
The next question can be explained.
The difference between dormant bomb.
So you already know now.
Next question, which is a global object in the browser.
So the answer is window is the global object in the browser.
Next question.
How will we check the inner weight or inner height of a window so you can see window, not inner height,
ordinary weight.
Next question.
How will you get hostname or value typed in the address bar?
Again, you use window dot location and the related properties to have access to it.
So that's on for this topic.