In this date and time category.
Now I'm discussing about various date methods.
There will be three related questions to this topic as well.
We have already seen that the date object helps you to create the dates and also the time.
We do not have a separate object for time.
We use the date object only for better understanding of time.
We are going to have one more session.
That will be the very next session.
So the date object has various methods for date and time related operations.
In this section we will go through a few date related set and get methods.
Let me first of all, create contact date is equal to new date.
Then I just see console date log and.
So when we run this, you see that the data is displayed.
Now that is a matter called get full year.
The get full year returns the four digit year.
Similarly, let's also try console dialogue.
They don't get month.
This matter returns the month of the given date.
So now you see that it returns seven.
The reason we have already discussed in a previous section that the months are indexed from 0 to 11.
Now let's also try one more method.
Did not get date.
Now this returns the day of the month.
The value generally you will see between one and 31 and the next method we are trying is console.log.
Did not get de.
So this method, as you can see, it returns day of the week the way we have these get matters.
We do also have get UTC matters.
See for example, get UTC year, get UTC month and so on.
So they return the UTC date and time values.
Now let's also go through a few of these set methods which can be used to set the date values.
The first method is set full, yet the syntax of this matter is like this.
We have the date component, date date set full year.
Now this method can have three parameters the year, month and the month, and they both are optional.
So let me just type this call.
I'll say let date is equal to new date.
I'll have a console.log for the.
Then I'm seeing that did not set full year.
I'll simply say 2021.
And again, I will display the value that is the date.
Now let's run the code and see what happens.
As you can see now, the date, the year is change and now it is 2021.
We do also have set month.
The syntax of said month is like this that we have a date component that is date date segment and then
we have the month of it is not optional and here D is optional.
So this helps you to set the month.
Let's try to set the month in same coding after this console.log.
I say did not set month and I will change the month again.
We will say console.log d.
And now you see that the money's different.
The way we have settlement, we do also have set date.
Here you can give a day and that will be the new day for this particular date.
So let's do that.
I'll say dot set date in the bracket.
I'll you let's say 12.
And now we run the code.
Now you see that every time, said Fuller.
Set month and set day changes the date and every time there are different values displayed.
Another useful method is Date Dart Pass, which passes a string of date and returns milliseconds.
This is how those indexes date dart pass and in the brackets you have the date string.
You can also have another syntax where you can say new date and in the brackets you can have the pass
date.
Let's try a small example with this as well.
I'm going to say let b t is equal to date.
Dart Pass 2020, dash zero seven, dash 24.
Let's just say console.log and you get the date value after the string has been passed.
So these are the few getter and set methods.
Now let's discuss relative questions of this topic.
The first question is that get a character month now for any date if you want to get a character month.
This is how you can do it.
Let's try the code.
I'll declare a variable saying ladies is equal to new date.
So that's the current date we are going to get in the deep variable.
Then I'm going to say let's add a months is equal to let's create the enter adding.
Now the next thing is the get month returns index number of the month and fortunately starts with zero
only, which actually is very much useful with ADD.
So here now I'm going to say add a months the square bracket and I'll say did not get month.
Now the get month will return the current month.
So in this case, it will return the seven.
That is the seventh element will be displayed.
So we get the August as the output.
As you can see here.
The second question is find the date before 50 days of given date.
Now, this question is that what was the date before given number of days.
Right.
That's again, very simple.
I'll declare one date variable.
I'll say let date is equal to new date.
Then I'll say dot set date.
I'm changing the date.
Now what am I doing here is I'm changing the day.
That is the target date.
Now this what?
This will return the get.
It will return the day, for example, it is the current day and that we are detecting by the given
number of days.
Now this component can be variable, but at the moment I am fixing it because the question is, are
50 days right?
So what will happen?
The set date is from the current day it is going to -50 days.
Right.
So that will automatically give you the new date before 50 days.
So this is how you can find the date before given number of days.
The third question is what will be the output if you add 35 as number of days or maybe date in date
constructor?
For example, what if you write like this, let data is equal to new date.
I say 2020, August month, that is zero seven and I just had 35.
Now here you do not have 35 days in a month.
Still, it is going to go to the next month and it will add.
So here you will have the output that is you will have for September as the output.
Let's try this.
As you can see here, this actually happens because of the auto correction feature of date object.
Even if you have leap year, let's say you have February month, right, or whichever month you have
it, does the validation automatically it does the auto correction and it adds the number of days and
gives you the validate always.