So this coding exercise is about removing duplicate values from and adding.
Will be using two methods.
There are many ways to remove duplicate values and also we are using six features as well.
The first way to remove duplicate is we can use the filter and the index of methods.
I hope you have checked the filter and index of method in every section of this tutorial.
First of all, let's declare an add.
So here I have an added.
It might be a numeric character or string added.
That doesn't matter.
At the moment I am taking the numeric array for the example where we have three and five as duplicate
values because we are going to use the filter method.
Filter is a matter which returns a new ADI.
At the moment I'm not taking any new ADI.
It takes a callback function which we have already discussed in the ADI section.
This callback function has two parameters.
The first is the value, and second is the index number.
At the moment I am not returning anything.
Instead, to understand it clearly, I'm going to display a few values.
The first thing I am going to do is I'm going to display the value V Then let's also display the index
of let me have a separator in between.
The second is I'm going to find the index of the value.
Let's also display the I that is the index of that value.
This will give you the idea that what type of validation will help to put.
Let me just run the code.
Now the first thing.
The first one which you see is the value we.
The second zero is index of value v that is one and the last is the index, the actual index of that
value in the ADI.
If you observe the duplicate value we have, let's see, three and five is the duplicate value in both
the cases that is here also three and five.
If you observe index of and I is not seen whenever there is a unique value because index off is always
going to find the first occurrence.
I do insist that you go through the index of explanation in the tutorial of add section.
So here, whenever there is a change in the index of value and index, that means that value is duplicate.
This also means that if I just return.
By comparing the index off and i.e. with an equal to sign.
That means I'm going to get all unique values so I can just stick new.
Adding here let's a unique ADI and I display the value uader let's run the code.
As you can see, we have all the unique values returned.
So return statement in filter method will return the value which matches the condition that is when
it returns true.
If I just put an exclamation here, then it will display only the duplicate values of the ADI, like
three and five.
So this is the explanation for getting the unique value Adi.
Now let's also try the second way.
That is the E6 way and it is very easy to deal with.
Again, that is a set and mapped section in this tutorial.
You must go through the tutorial first, then you will be able to understand.
But here.
Instead of writing this filter or anything else I can simply do is I can use the spread operator and
create a new set of the ADI.
So now here you have the new set of ADI that gets converted into Adi and I'm assigning it to you area.
That's it.
So just three line code and you get the unique values.
Apart from this two methods, there are many other ways you can find using that include.
You can have a for each loop and then you can compare and return a new element.
That's also possible, but these two are the basic ways to find the unique values from an ADI.