Before I start the call, let me explain the difference between deep bouncing and throttling, as they
both are used to improve the performance.
Let's see your mom brought cookies at home.
The moment you came to know you started eating after every few minutes.
So your mom put a condition that after every two hours, you can have one cookie.
In between, if you ask, you won't get it.
That is the event will not fire every time.
It's going to fire after every two hours.
For example, you had a cookie at eight a.m., then the next cookie you can have at 10:00 only if you
ask at 9:00 to have one.
You cannot have it, but you will get it at 10 for sure because you had the last cookie at eight.
Why am I emphasizing on timings?
Well, you'll come to know in a few minutes when I discuss the bouncing.
In fact, this timing thing is the key to understand the bouncing bill.
Anyways, so this is throttling where events occur after a certain time only regardless of when and
how many times they actually fired.
For example, the mouse event may occur 100 times in a second, but you configure the code in such a
way so that it gets executed only after two seconds and not 200 times.
Now, let's talk about the bouncing.
So in the same kooky example, your mom says that I will give you a cookie if you did not ask for last
two hours.
You get it at eight and then 10.
But if you ask at nine for the cookie, then you will have to wait for two more hours.
That is, now you will get the cookie at 11.
Now, assume that you get the cookie at 11:00, then the next cookie you are supposed to get at one.
But if you ask at 12:30, then poor, you now wait for two more hours.
Your next cookie time is two 30.
So, for example, mouse event is configured to fire at every one second, provided there was no mouse
move for one second.
If the mouse moves in half a second, that is 500 milliseconds, then again, wait for one more second.
Seems complicated, but it's not the moment we implement the code, it becomes easy.
But if you understand this cookie example, it will really help you to quickly get the idea.
Let me summarize both the concepts once again, throttling is about firing event after every certain
time.
That is bouncing will execute after every certain time provided in between.
There was no call of the event.
Now, let's begin with the throttling first, and that's what we are going to check with mouse more
event.