Now, let's start implementing the normal count and throttling functionality in this lecture.
Let me, first of all, show you some code where I have implemented the CSIS for the division and for
each student body, it's easy to understand.
Also, I have placed a division and on the division, the on mouse event is configured with a function
called show counts, getting called on every mouse small.
Also, there are two actors I have already taken four total and rebounds.
And for each edge, too, I have given normal count that is N.S.A. total count, that is D.C. in the
end, the bounce count that is D.C. and.
There are three variables which are going to keep the counter, I'm going to increment these counters
when we implement title and bonds, respectively.
But first of all, let's configure the normal count.
Very simple.
I'm going to create a function called normal count.
And inside of this, I'm implementing the value of N.S.A. now I can either write, document or get element
by I.D. to refer this edge to what I can take a separate variable as well.
Let me take a variable that is an object I'll say normal edge to.
This will contain the normal count and I'll say document art.
Get element by I.D. and CMT.
Let me also configure this for throttle and bounce as well.
So I'll it two and two, and here, let me just say D.C. MP and DC A..
All right.
So now we have some configuration here.
Now, when the normal count function is executed, I warned that and I stood out in our estimate should
contain the value of N.S.A..
Let me also assign the same label so it doesn't change it.
I'll say normal, not normal, of course.
Normal count and N.S.A..
All right, now, this function needs to be called, and I'm going to use the Showgrounds method, which
is called on mouse model of the division.
So I'll say normal count, that's it.
Let's save this and check the output.
Now let me refresh and just moving the mouse and you see that on the mouse move, the normal counties
getting incremented.
Now, let us implement the total count.
The important point you need to remember about Hertling is Turtle will execute the code after a certain
period of time.
That is after a certain duration.
So let me, first of all, create the throttle count function.
So I'll function total count.
Certainly, the TCN should be incremental here as well, and the to ordinary HDMI should have throttle
count value in it.
So TXNIP, but if you observe this code, it is similar to normal.
What's the difference?
No difference.
Let's make the difference now.
Total count, whenever it is executed, I'm going to generate a timer.
Now, if you remember, I mentioned that when throttling is to implement, the process should be executed
after every certain period or duration.
For that, I'm going to use the said timeout.
So what I'll do, I'll say, said timeout.
I'm going to call the function here.
And also put the milliseconds, let's after every 500 milliseconds, I want this process to execute.
But I'm not going to put this process inside this time out.
Instead, let me show you another way I'll say fire throttle, which is initially true.
Now.
When this turtle count is executed, I'll say, if Firestarter is true, then we want to execute this
process.
Not only that, I just switched the Firestarter off, that is I'm going to assign false.
Now practically this means once the event is fired, I'm setting the value of Firestarter to false.
So next time, this will never execute.
When do you want this fire throttle to be true again?
That is where I use the set timeout.
I'll say after 500 milliseconds, only make this fires are true.
Now this means initially the fire throttle is true.
It's going to increment the value, but then it will make it false.
Also, the time out has been set after five hundred milliseconds.
Next time, whenever the mouse moves, fire, throttle anyway contains value falls, so it will not
execute.
But because we have the set timeout which is going to execute after 500 milliseconds, it will switch
the value of Firestarter to true.
So let's save this and check the output again and refresh.
Now, if you observe the code, the normal count is incremental at a very high rate, whereas total
count is just incrementing only after 500 milliseconds.
The advantage of this is right now we have very less score.
But imagine you have API calls placed instead of these lines.
That's where the difference will be very noticeable.
This is how throttling can be implemented.
You use the timer and you just switch on the fire throttle flag to true after 500 milliseconds.
Imagine I make this as 1000.
Then it will be even lesser, because now after every 1000 milliseconds, there is after one second,
if the mouse is moved, then it is going to fire the event.
Let me change this back to 500.
And save this.
Go back to the code refresh and throttling is implemented.