That is one more important topic called automatic semicolon insertion, which we are discussing in this
lecture.
The question I'm raising here is what is automatic semi colon insertion or what is a ACI in JavaScript?
The category of this question is just programming language that is just language.
And there will be three related questions with this topic.
You must have used semicolon many times in JavaScript code.
Almost all lines are terminated by a semicolon if you have practice of ending with a semicolon.
Of course.
Also you must have observed that when you do not write a semicolon, I mean if you forget to write then
also JavaScript is not going to give you any error.
And the reason for not showing error is that the compiler automatically adds a semicolon at the end
of those lines.
Let's try a simple code here.
I will simply say console.log.
Hi.
Now, I don't write a semi-colon here.
The next line is console.log test.
And I put a semicolon here.
So here in this code, both the lines are executed properly after the end of first line.
A semicolon is automatically inserted.
This means writing a semicolon at the end of line is optional in JavaScript, and it also means that
when there is a line break like on this line console.log, JavaScript inserts a semicolon at the end
of line and this very feature is called as automatic semicolon insertion.
Or as I remember, JavaScript does not insert a semicolon on every line break that is on every new line.
Let's try one more example To understand that I will declare a variable.
I'll say let a is equal to I will say four into the multiplication sign.
Now I press enter here and I say five and console.log I try to display value of a.
Here the output is 20, which is correct without any error, whereas I have already added a line break
after the multiplication sign as it finds an operator alone.
It understands that there is something more remaining.
So this means in some cases JavaScript does not add a semicolon.
And that's where JavaScript creates a problem.
And as a developer, you must know this behavior.
Let's create one more code to understand.
I'm going to create a function function test.
Now, here I want to return an object literal, right?
So I'll say return, but I'm pressing an enter here and opening the curly bracket on a new line.
I'll say a colon five.
That's it.
And I'll say const obj is equal to test.
I'm calling the function.
So now the function test should return the object literal and we try to display it.
Let's say console.log object.
Let's run the code.
But now the output is undefined, whereas the function is returning the object literal.
The output is undefined because internally a semicolon is added after return statement, which means
this function does not return anything.
Now let's bring this opening curly bracket on same line of return and run the code.
Now you see that it is working as we want.
It is returning the object literal.
So test is returning proper object literal which is received by object and we are displaying it.
So this is the overall behavior of AC and you have to take care if you don't have practice to terminate
lines with semicolon or even in this case where we use a curly bracket on new line while returning an
object literal.
Now let's discuss a few relative questions of this topic.
The first question is should you terminate all lines by a semicolon?
Now, as I mentioned, it's a good practice to have a semicolon at the end, though it is optional because
JavaScript does insert a semicolon, but if you put it, it's a good practice.
At least you have to make sure that if you do not put semicolon, then also the line should not be terminated
in an improper way like return.
And then if you are returning an object literal, then put a bracket.
Even this is a common practice that when we write if condition, then we open the curly bracket on the
same line.
The second question is a piece of code is shown like this, which we have already tried.
And the question can be that why this code is returning undefined in spite of function, returning a
valid object literal.
So we have already discussed why this happens.
Or there can be another question that what will be the output for this piece of code?
The third question we can think of is can use strict statement or the strict mode change the behavior
of ACI.
No, it doesn't change the behavior if you write you strict.
That does not mean that you have to end all lines with a semicolon.
I mean the respective lines anyway.
Like if condition is never terminated with a semicolon, but lines which are to be terminated with a
semicolon that also even if you use use strict, it doesn't force you to put a semicolon on all lines.