In this calling exercise, we are going to remove false zeros, not a number values undefined or may
be blank spaces from an ADI.
So eventually the ADI should contain only the values which are more than zero are proper data in element.
Now there is a very simple way to do the same thing.
We can use a loop, we can search for various values, we can compare it, but I'm going to use the
filter method.
So let me first of all just display the values using the filter, the value and the index number.
Now inside of the filter method.
What you can do is you can check whether the element has false, maybe zero nine instead of checking
individual values like this, there is a mechanism in JavaScript which we call as the true the expression
and false expression.
Whenever there is a false zero nan undefined or blank, the JavaScript expression returns false.
Otherwise it returns true.
The So in case if I just write, let's see if v that means if it is true the then I'm going to display
the value of v remember, I'm not saying V equals to true or false or anything.
If I just say if V by default it means if it is true the expression, then only this condition will
be executed.
Now, when the value is false or any other like undefined or nan, certainly it will be false and this
expression will not be displayed.
Let's run this and see what is the output.
As you can see from the ADI, though, there are many elements.
It displays 690 and high only because for rest of the cases the V generate a false expression.
So now this means if I just right.
Return V.
And if I take it in a new ad it because filter always returns a new ad let's say new ad and this new
ad I'm going to display at the end.
The very nature of filter is like this, that if the expression is true, then it will return.
In case of false expression, the value won't be returned.
It will be ignored.
So here, if I run.
You see that the NRA now has only those values which are valid values?
I wouldn't say either values are invalid.
It's just that the elements which has nine or undefined are such values.
And let's say you want to remove from ADI, you don't have to write a lot of code.
It is the true the end fallacy technique of JavaScript which will take care.
The only concern is you use a filter like my third order.
You can put a loop and check the values for true or false.