In this date and time section.
Now I am discussing about the time related methods.
There are two related questions to this topic.
For time.
JavaScript gives the very same date object only, but there are methods which are related to the time
part.
Also, that is a unique static method called data not now, which returns or timestamp in milliseconds
elapsed since 1st January 1970 UTC.
Let's also try just a simple statement.
I'll say long day dot now and you see that?
It displays the milliseconds.
Now let us also try a few matters of time.
First of all, I am going to declare a variable as select data is equal to new date.
And then I will try to use a method called get time.
So I also console.log did not get time.
Let's also try a few more matters here, then we'll try to check it everything together.
I will say cancelled out loud.
Did not get hours.
Same.
We get minutes, get seconds and get milliseconds.
Now let's try to run the call and see what is the output.
Now you see that the get time returns, the milliseconds, the get hours returns a value between zero
and 23, whereas they get minutes and seconds, both return value between zero and 59 and milliseconds
will always be between zero and 999.
The way we how get matters that are set matters to said the time.
So by giving the set time milliseconds it will set the time.
And the value is started since January 1st, 1970.
Let's say, for example, I'll say data is equal to new date.
Then I display the value of die.
Now I'm going to say not set time.
Here I'm seeing zero.
And again I say console.log date.
So now you see that the first date is the current date, whereas the second is the first January.
The reason is because milliseconds given in set time is zero.
So it gives the very first.
That is the start date.
The other set methods like set hours, set minutes, set seconds are set milliseconds, set the respective
time component in the given date.
Now let's discuss related questions of this topic.
The first question is calculate the day difference in days.
Now that means there are two dates and you have to count.
What is the difference in terms of days between two dates?
So here I'm going to take one date.
I'll say that it's equal to New Date.
This lecture defined 2020 August 25th.
Then I take another date that is D1.
I'll say New Date 2020 August 23.
Now I'll take one variable just to get the difference between both the dates.
I say D don't get time minus D one don't get time.
Now the value which will get will be in milliseconds.
So what you can do now I can see the number is equal to first of all, because I have the value in milliseconds.
I'm going to divide that value by 1000 and this entire value I can divide by 3600 because 3600 is number
of seconds we have in an hour.
So right now, we are converting the value in hours.
So let's display console.log.
So you have this value.
That is the number of hours.
Now, if I further divided this value by 24, then you get the number of days.
The second question is how can you change hours or minutes in time?
So we have the set hours and set minutes method to set the hour part only or maybe minute section,
maybe second or millisecond also can be changed using the set methods.