In this section, we are discussing a very important concept related to domain verb.
That is what is even bubbling and even capturing the category of this question is DOM or web?
We will have five related questions related to this topic.
Let's begin with the answer.
To understand bubbling or capturing, I will create a simple program and then we try to explore.
Here I have written a code where there is a division, and inside the division I have just a simple
button on division.
Click.
I am calling a function called Div click and on button click.
I'm calling a function called BTN and click.
Both the functions are just displaying alert.
That division is clicked, our button is clicked.
If we observe the output here we have this division and the button button is actually a child element
of division and both division and button have on click.
Now when I click on this button, I get that message.
That button is clicked.
But when I proceed further, I see that division click is also called.
Remember here I'm just clicking on the button, not on the division.
Still the division click is called.
Let me go back to the coding once again and show you that.
What have we written here?
Button on click.
This function is getting called division on click.
This function is gone and when I clicked on this, it actually called both the functions.
So why this thing is happening?
In the output.
It executes the buttons click event, but immediately after that it executes divisions.
Click your end as well.
This is the babbling.
Let's try to understand this with reference to DOM event architecture.
This figure is a replica of the code we have written here.
The button which is raising the event is called as the target.
The event object does have a property with the same name.
That is Event Dart target, which returns the reference of the element which generated the event, or
in other words, which dispatched the event object.
That means the event object is dispatched to get the clear idea.
Let's try a to sample.
I will just give a name to this button.
I'll see BTN one.
And here, when the button is clicked, I will display that I say alert event, dart target, dot name.
Now we have given the name property here, so let's see what happens here.
I'll just refresh the code.
I'm clicking the button.
Now you see that it displays BTN one and then the rest of the behaviour, of course.
So event dot target returns the reference of element which raised the event.
And that's the place from the event.
Object is dispatched to its ancestor.
Now I'm coming to that.
What ancestor is.
All right.
So coming back to the figure, this button is the event target.
This division is called ancestor or parent, which goes till window and window is the topmost ancestor
or actually it's an object.
You can see that window is part of Dom.
It is about it.
But we need here far more clarity.
So from target to ancestor, the event object traverses and this traversal is called as propagation
or event propagation.
Now how is the event propagation happening?
Ah, which is the path of event propagation?
Of course.
Bottom to top.
And that's what we saw.
First the button was clicked, then the button click was fired, and then the division click was also
fired automatically.
So this button's event is executed and then it goes on the ancestor, because the propagation is dispatched
from bottom to top.
And that's what is a bubble.
A bubble has a tendency to go up from the bottom.
And that's why we say that this is event bubbling.
And the default part of event propagation is bottom to top.
This is the behaviour of event management in JavaScript.
In case if you want to stop this behaviour, that is, you warned that when the button is clicked it
should not propagate the event to its ancestors.
You can use this using a method called stop propagation, which is a matter of event object.
So you can say event or stop propagation.
Let's try that practically.
I'll just remove this.
Saving it, going back to the output, refreshing and just bringing the previous chord again where when
you click on the button, the button event is fired and the division event is also fired.
Now let's say we do not want this propagation to happen.
Then here I will say event, not stop propagation.
That's it.
I'll save it here.
Coming back to the browser.
Refreshing and.
Button.
Click the button.
Click this file.
And no division.
Click is available now because we have stopped the propagation behavior.
So again, the default propagation path is bottom to top are bubbling.
And that's what even bubbling is.
That is the event object is dispatched on a path that is bottom to top.
In case if you want to change this default propagation path that is instead of bottom to top, we make
it top to bottom.
Then that will be called capturing.
And for capture phase, you have to use add event listener method to configure or bind the event.
Capturing phase means top to bottom that is reverse to the bubbling.
This also means in our code, when the button is clicked first the division click will be fired and
then the button click.
Let's do this practically.
Here I will see window dart on load because I'm going to bind the events using active and listener.
This is one of the way to write the event.
Now we do not need this on click any more here, so I'm going to remove these things both the click
events we don't want.
I don't even want this name here.
We will take two variables.
I'll say contact between one and inside of that I'm going to get the reference off button.
So again, I'll say button one here and I'll set this one.
And that will be again day one.
Now, we need to give you these ideas as well.
So for day I will say it is equal to day one.
And for button, I just say button one.
So we have a difference of both between one and the one in these objects.
Now comes the event binding part.
Using Add event listener I submit the end one not add event listener.
Now this method takes three parameters.
First is the event.
Remember we right click.
We do not right on click here.
That's how this index is.
The second is which function you want to call.
So this is the button.
So I want to call a function, call beaty and click.
So that will come here.
And the last parameter is true or false.
This actually decides the last parameter that you want to have the bubble phrase or you want to have
the capture phase by default.
If you do not specify, let's say you pass only two parameters, then it will be bubble phase by default.
But if you want to make it capture phase, then you will say true here.
Let's also attach the event with division for this all sides a click and do click is the function I
want to call.
And here also I just want to say true.
So now there are two events and both are going to execute from top to bottom.
This means when I click on the button, the capture phase will start, event object will be dispatched
from top to bottom.
So the first will be do one click and then the button click.
Right, let's save this.
Go back to the output.
I will just refresh the browser and clicking on the button only.
Amazing.
It displays this click first and then it displays the button clicked because the event object is dispatched,
the propagation path is changed.
Now it is from top to bottom that is capturing.
So this is event capturing and by default it is event babbling in chart.
All these concepts are related to event propagation path.
There are few events which do not get propagated like focus events, but it's a kind of exception.
Otherwise events do bubble by default.
Do not think that this bubbling or capturing behavior is weird or bad.
It is designed intentionally.
This type of behavior can also be useful when you have deep level elements and assumed that you want
to handle event.
At one point only babbling or captioning actually facilitates you with one of the most powerful event
handling pattern called event delegation, which will be our next section stopping.
Now let's discuss related questions of this topic.
The first question is, which is the default propagation path?
So now, you know, first of all, you should know what is propagation and then which is the default
path.
It is, of course, bottom to top that is babbling.
The second question, how can you stop event propagation?
So we have seen that event, our stop propagation method that helps us to stop the propagation.
The third question is how can you change the default propagation path?
So this is where we use the ADD event listener and the third parameter of ADD event listener.
We make it true to make sure that instead of going bottom to top, it goes top to bottom.
That is the capturing phase.
The fourth question is how can you get the reference of element on which the event is fire or the reference
of Element which raised the event so that we get using event or target, we can use event or target,
date name, event or target dot value for that matter.
So whichever element has the focus that elements value, we can refer to using event or target or value
as well.
And the fifth question can be that the code which we saw earlier that can be given and then one can
ask you that what will be the output of this call and why?
So you can discuss about the bubbling happening by default in the DOM architecture.