Now, let's implement the bouncing in this goal.
Again, I'm going to take a function seeing the bounce count.
Let's also copy at least these two lines and pasted here.
And of course, I'm going to remove this D.C. empty and keep D.C. empty here.
Also, I'll say the edge.
These are the objects we have already declared here in the previous lectures, and here I'll see the
bounce count.
Again, the code is similar.
Now, when it comes to bombs, the logic was that it also executes, for example, after every 500 milliseconds.
But that is one added condition and that condition is if in the last five hundred milliseconds, if
you try to move the mouse, the waiting period is reset.
Let me again emphasize on the explanation, for example, the mouse model should be fired after every
10 minutes, provided that in last 10 minutes, the mouse was not moved.
It means, let's say, for example, on the eighth minute, if the mouse is moved again, it has to
wait for 10 more minutes.
Right now, we are going to implement the 500 millisecond situation with the bounce as well, but you
will see that the rebounds will keep on resetting the weight.
So that will be even so the count will be even lesser compared to 30.
And for that, we'll also take one variable because in case of Dearborn's, if the mouse is moved and
it is not to execute, then the timer needs to reset, the timer needs to clear and to clear the timer.
We need an object.
So I'll say, for example, the bounce timer.
And this timer is going to contain the reference of the time in which we created also said time out
will have a function and after every five hundred milliseconds, something is going to execute.
But still, the purpose is not solved.
Why is it not hard?
Because this is more or less like total, where after every 500 milliseconds, it's going to execute
something.
We want that, first of all.
If that is a timer, then clear the timer.
We are using timeout as a clear timeout and the D-dimer, if it is existing, we do not want that timer.
Remove the timer.
That is the first thing we are going to do in the bombs.
Why?
Because the mouse is moved.
We are clearing.
Now, let me just shift this inside the set time out.
Now, let me just call this the bounce count function here.
Let's check the output, and again, I'll explain how this entire process is happening.
Let me just refresh.
And you see that.
The throttle is nine and bounds is five, in normal count is ninety three.
So now you can imagine the difference between the execution.
You see that after five hundred milliseconds, only the event is executed and provided that within that
five hundred milliseconds range, I did not move the mouse.
So I moved the mouse stop for five hundred milliseconds and then I move it.
But let's say I keep on moving the mouse, then it is not going to execute the rebound.
So you see that because five hundred milliseconds span is something which it is waiting for.
And let me just stop here just 500 milliseconds, and then it has started incrementing.
Let me go back to the cold again, let me explain what is happening here when you move the mouse.
The first thing is we are clearing the timer, if at all that is any assumed that there was a timer
or assume that there is no timer existing in any case.
First of all, it resets the timer.
That means, for example, you are 500 milliseconds.
Timer is set.
The moment the mouse is moved, the bounce count is executed, the timer is reset.
Then it set the timer, the new timer, and that has the counter incremental as well.
Now this said, timeout will be executed only after 500 milliseconds.
Now, if your mouse is not moved, then this will be executed.
But imagine that before this set timeout is executed, your mouse was moved.
Naturally, it clears the timer again.
It sets the new timer and it is to wait for 500 milliseconds.
If you move the mouse before 500 milliseconds, it's going to again clear the timer.
This is the logic behind implementing the bouncing.
There are many ways there are various ways of programming and approach, setting the timer, setting
the interval.
This is one of the way commonly used, and this is what I have explained here with the syntax in the
forthcoming lectures, we are going to see the use cases, the practical implementation, a small scenario
to see in which case you use throttling and in which case you use the bouncing.