Hello, everyone.
In this video, we are going to solve the factorial problem.
The problem when you have to get a number from the user and display it's factorial.
The program will run something like this.
When you run it, it'll say enter a number the user enters for and the output is four factorial is equal
to 24.
All right.
So to solve this problem, first we will understand what is a factorial of a number.
When you say four factorial, which is written like this is basically.
You multiply the number with its previous number.
So here what actually happens is four into three into two into one, something like this process gets
executed.
If I say I want to find five factorial, it means five into four, into three, into two into one.
So to find a factorial of a number, what you actually do is starting from the number, you start multiplying
with a previous number that is.
And into n minus one.
And this process keeps on repeating unless you reach two one.
So to find four factorial, this is the process actually we have to execute.
So for example, if we take N is equal to four for which we need to find a factorial and the multiplication
goes till the end.
We can write the pseudocode something like this.
So now we take two variables here.
One is factorial and the second is N and is the number for which we want to find the factorial.
We say end is equal to 4 to 1.
I will say step minus one.
This is the pattern of pseudocode.
Whichever language you use, you are going to decrement the value accordingly.
But when we write pseudocode we use this syntax.
So here factorial is initialized with one.
Now let's try it on this.
Let's check step by step and let's check the output table.
Also, at the moment in the output table, as you can see, factorial is one and is four.
Now the next step is factorial into N.
This step gets executed.
That means one into four and the result is stored in two factorial.
So now in this table the factorial value is updated.
We keep the previous value and we add a new value here.
So the this table we are going to constantly watch.
Now this factorial is four it goes on the for loop and n is decrementals by one.
So N is three as you can see in the table and the factorial is four.
So we see four into three.
Now next step it will be four into three.
That means straddle.
So 12 is stored in the factorial.
Again, the factorial value is updated in the table and and is also reduced by one.
So now factorial becomes 12 and and becomes two again.
This process is going to repeat and the factorial will be factorial into n that is 12 into two.
It will be 24 still and is two so factorial is 24 and and now gets decrement by one.
So end is one.
And when you say 24 into one, it will be 24 only.
And at the end we just say bring factorial.
This is how the factorial is achieved.
You may also run this loop from 1 to 4.
That's also fine, but ideally when we say four factorial, that means four into two into three into
one.
If you say five, that means you got till one from 5 to 1.
That's why we are following this pattern.
Otherwise the same thing can be achieved with one to end the loop, starting with one and ends at end.
That's also possible.
That is also another way to find the factorial.
We can write a recursive function.
So now we have discussed how to achieve.
What can be the logic.
Let's try to go to this.
We are going to take n variable that we we have discussed in the pseudocode will say n is equal to.
Of course we are going to convert that into number.
So first thing I'm going to write is pass int.
And then I will say enter a number.
We also take a variable, Carl Factorial, where I'm going to assign one to it and let's put a our loop
here.
Now, we do not need to initialize anything to end because we are taking the value from the user.
So I'll keep this blank so I'll put a semicolon for the initialization.
There is nothing to write here.
We are going to put a condition and is greater than equal to one.
And of course we want to minus the value of N.
And the way we wrote in the pseudocode we are going to say factorial is equal to factorial into n.
And at the end we just want to display console.log log I would say.
Factorial is equal to.
Victoria.
I missed the prompt command here, so let me write that.
Now later on, this court is going to ask a number.
I'll say full and output is four factorial.
Let's run it again.
We try to find five factorial.
It says 120.
So this is how you find a factorial of a number.