In this section, we will learn how to navigate through the code while debugging using the debugging
pane tools.
The category is debugging techniques and this itself is a question that how to navigate through the
code at the time of debugging.
While remaining inside the sources panel and debugging the code is made convenient using these navigation
tools.
Inside the debugging pane, let us practically implement them.
Let me provide the values and click on the button.
Once the debugger has paused, you can start navigating throughout the functions and code to resume
the execution.
Click on this resume script execution icon and it will continue execution until it encounters any other
breakpoint, if at all.
You have given it.
When the debugger has paused on a particular region of code.
And if it seems bug free and you skip that and jump to the next function, then click this step over
the next function call option.
It will navigate like this.
Let's.
There is a breakpoint on this line and I run the code.
The debugger pauses, and when you click on this icon that is to step inside the next function, it
will jump into the next one like this.
If you want the debugger to leave or step out of the current function, then click this icon.
In case you want to debug the code step by step and monitor the code flow.
Press this step option which will navigate line by line code.
Then there are various break points in the code and you want to deactivate them all at once.
Then click this deactivate all breakpoints option.
Observe here when you deactivate them and let me resume the execution.
And when I click on the button now, the debugger does not pause.
So the breakpoints are deactivated.
This is how you can navigate code and debug in the browser itself.
In the forthcoming sections we will learn debugging with different types of breakpoints.