This question is what is the use of map method?
The category of this question is at ease and there will be three related questions.
I have raised this question to highlight usage of the map method.
Map method is one of those methods like find filters, splice, etc., which are must know methods.
So let's begin with the map method.
I will start with an example of it and then we will see the syntax as well.
I will create and add a few values.
Let's say two, maybe three, four and five.
That said one more element in between.
Now I will say added dot map.
It takes a callback function, I can say function.
And as we have seen in few questions where the callback function receives parameters here also we receive
the element.
We do also receive the index number and the array itself.
It is the same thing element will receive, the individual value index will receive the index number
and the ETA is the added reference itself.
At the moment I just try element and index.
Let's try to display the value of it and see what happens.
Element and index.
The map method will loop through the entire added and every element will be passed to this variable
and index will receive the index number.
Let's run this and see how it works.
As you see that it shows all the elements along with the index number.
Ideally, this method also returns a new ADI and that's where the charm comes in picture.
Let's see with this Adi, I just want to get squared off all elements, right?
So I can see return the value we will have in the elements.
I'll say element into element.
This means it is going to multiply the value with value itself and it will return.
So it will return the square of it.
Here, I'll get a new Adi.
At the moment I don't need this index number and I will add the console.log here and will display the
new ADI.
Now let's see.
What is the output?
Just a single line code which is going to give you squared off all the elements.
Isn't it fantastic?
The map method does this.
It returns the new added.
Remember, it's very useful because map does not mutate or change the original added.
It does return a new adding.
So you can imagine the kind of functions you can implement with this kind of syntax.
With the map method, I have used just the function, but you can use the arrow function also.
Let's try arrow function.
Let's see this.
I'll put an arrow here and that's it.
So now if I run the output, it's going to be the same.
But the syntax has changed.
As you all know, that arrow function can live with a single line because return when you have only
one return, you don't need to write return or these brackets.
So let's change that.
Also, I'll remove these brackets will also remove the return statement and we don't even need this.
Curly bracket will have this bracket only.
That's it.
You see single line and this is going to return square of all elements.
Even we can remove this parentheses as well with arrow function.
So this is how it is going to be.
So the map method is very useful.
That is a function, a callback function which receives the element index number and the edit also and
it returns the new added.
Right.
This is how it works.
Let's see the syntax of it.
So the syntax is like this that we have the new added return.
We say add a name dart map and it takes a callback function.
So it can be an arrow function also.
But we are writing function like this only at the moment.
The first parameter is every element passed to the added optional is the index and the added self.
It also takes this argument after the function, after the callback function.
So this is also a reference of the callback function, but you have to take care whether you are using
the arrow function or the traditional function depending on that.
This value can be different directly.
If you try to refer this argument, it is going to be undefined.
Now let's discuss related questions of this topic.
The first question is find length of each element in a new ADI.
Let's say we have array of few elements.
I'll say apple, banana and oranges.
Now we want to find length of every element.
Very easy.
Let's try this with map method.
I select land of array.
I'll create a new article LIRR and here I'll say added or map.
Now I'm not going to write the function the long way, but instead we will go with the sharpness index.
So I'll say element arrow function.
Right.
And I'm not writing a return statement.
Also, we have already seen in the example just before a few seconds.
So I'll say element dot length.
That's it.
And I will display the LIRR that is length.
Let us see what is the output here?
You see, every element's length is displayed.
The second question is find the square root of every element and store it in a new ADI.
This again can be very easy.
Let's say instead of these string values, let's make 25, maybe 16.
Let's say 144 and 36.
Right now, what we want is we want to have square root of each element and that we want in the new
ADI.
So instead of this element length, now I will say mad, not square root.
And the only thing you have to pass is the element which is received.
This is the received value which I'm passing here, and it will return the square root and it will create
the new ADI.
Let's run this and see whether we get the desired output.
Right.
So the square root of 25 is five and respectively it has displayed all the square roots.
Third question is that is an addict called products as shown here get all product names that is p names
in a new addict.
Now here the question is that one wants to fetch all the products or a single key, in fact, of this
object literally that is P name in this case in a separate addict.
How can we do this again?
We can use the map method to fetch all product names or all product codes or any key for that matter,
and store it in a new A-D.
Let's try this.
I will have this in the court window.
Let's go to the go to window and let's say we create this ad.
If you have this ad it ready.
Now, what I want is I just want to get this p names in one ad so I will create a new article B names,
for example.
And there I will say products dot map.
Right?
Every element is passed.
Now, remember, when this every element is passed here, each element is an object literal.
So this entire p gordon p name is passed in element.
So in other words, element will have something like this one object literal every time till the end
of adding.
And now what it should return is.
It should return the element.
Not by name, isn't it?
Because it's an object literal and we do not write this written statement because it's a single line.
So I'll remove this written.
That's it.
And then we display the entire addy.
So I'll say P names.
That's the area we want to display.
That's the new Adi created by Mad Method.
Now if we run, we get all the P name that is a key from an object literal and we have assigned to the
new ADI.
We do also have B structuring in S6, which is already discussed in one of the section.
But this is also kind of the structuring we have done.
The only thing is we have changed from one structure to another that is object literal to ADI.
Do make sure that you are clear with matter.
It is a very useful matter and used in most of the real world applications.
When we have to look through the ADI and we, we have to display the data maybe on a page or we draw
the DOM at that time.
We use map a lot.