So in this topic, we are going to discuss questions like how the class is created.
What is class expression?
And we are going to discuss starting members.
There will be six related questions to these topics.
I assume that you have already gone through previous questions of object literal and this object before
you move on this section.
Classes are very commonly used in various languages in JavaScript.
Also, you can create classes.
The whole concept of class is to create a blueprint or design, commonly referred as a prototype.
Then off this prototype, you can create as many instances as you want.
For example, on paper, you design a house which has a number of rooms, windows, doors and color
properties.
Now, in the actual houses created from this design, there can be different values for each of the
actual house.
Like this object has five rooms and different values.
Gray color.
And this house has seven rooms, different windows, doors, and let's say calories, maybe blue.
Here.
Each house is called as an object or instance of class house.
This is the instance.
Or you can say that you have created this house from this blueprint.
The advantage of this pattern is reusability, but it's not something you can understand unless you
implement it practically in a project which you will realize at a later stage of this tutorial.
But in this section, we will still go through many concepts of classes and basics.
In ESX we have a class keyword to create a class, whereas in S5 we were using a constructor function.
We will at least once go through the S5 syntax, but let's concentrate on Essex at the moment.
So let me create a class called House Itself.
Now there is something called constructor.
This constructor is basically a kind of method which is executed automatically when you create the instance
of this class.
Let's say I just want to put console.log and constructor called.
Now how we like create the object of this class.
I will say constructor may be led.
Object is equal to new house.
That means I'm creating a new instance of class house.
I can create as many instances as I want, so I'm going to create a few more instances here.
So I have two instances now.
O'Bagy and O'Bagy.
That's fine now because I'm creating two instances every time this new house is called.
It's going to call the constructor.
Constructor is a matter which is executed immediately.
You create the instance of a class.
Let me run this code.
So you see that the constructor is called two times.
For example, I warned that that has to be property as well, or maybe more properties.
Then what I can do, I can say this door, let's say number of doors is equal to now I can say five
here maybe.
And I'll say this dot, let's say windows.
Is equal to, for example, ten.
Now, instead of giving fixed value, what I can do, I can pass parameters, I can pass arguments to
the constructor.
So what I will do, I will say A comma, B, for example, and then I say here and maybe B here instead
of this.
Generally, the practice is we use the same name, let's say number of doors and windows.
So when you say this dot and doors and this dot windows, that means this is a property of class house.
Right?
And this is just a value which is received by the constructor, which I'm applying in a moment.
But I'm going to say.
And doors here and windows here.
So remember this.
And doors, this right hand side is this variable.
And this left hand side that is member of Class House.
So now I'm going to pass, let's say in the first house, there are five doors and ten windows.
And in the second house, we have seven doors and 12 windows.
That's it.
Let's also create a matter here.
Now we already know what is a property and matter because we have already seen all these things in object
literal section.
I'm going to create a method called show data.
I say console.log and those number of doors come out this door.
Number of windows.
That's it.
So now the prototype looks something like this.
Now let me just say object or show data and object one art show data.
Let me run this code now.
So here we have two different values five and ten, seven and 12.
So as you can see that both object and object one, they have different data set here.
So that's how a basic class is created.
And this is what the constructor is in the E6 syntax.
The way we discussed about dynamic properties and dynamic method names that we can do with classes.
Also, we have already discussed that in object literally that how can we have dynamic properties?
Let's say here you want to have dynamic method name.
So what you can do, for example, I can say let's get data is equal to the value I want to have is
show data only.
So now instead of.
Show data.
I want to write a variable here.
I'll say get data.
So this is great data.
It is a variable and that has a value card show data.
Now here I am calling show data only.
Right?
So if that is get it, I should display an error.
Let's see what happens.
It is still executing.
The reason is this guard data is dynamic.
That is because we have covered it into square brackets.
It is going to consider that that is a variable which contains some value and that name is actually
the valid name.
Let's remove this air here and run it again.
You see, now it has stopped working.
So it is currently working because we have that dynamic matter.
Similarly, you can have dynamic members this dot, you can put a square record and you can deal with
it.
Easy to understand that here you see that these are the members of the class and those is a numerical
value.
Of course, windows is also numeric, but these are the properties very this is the matter of a class.
Let me remove this dynamic thing now.
I'll just say show data and I don't need this data here.
So here we have different types of members.
That is, we have a method and also these numeric values we may have any type of value doesn't matter.
What I want to highlight here is that the member that is, let's say I wanted to call may be show data
or any other method or any other member for that matter.
I have to instantiate the class.
If I do not create an instance, I cannot access members of the class.
There are situations where you want to have members, but you do not want to instantiate the class.
The situations which you may not get right now, if you have exposure with Angular or maybe React,
you get the idea that we create services, services which are called directly and we do not want to
instantiate.
In such case you can create static members if you cannot correlate with a practical situation.
Doesn't matter at the moment, but at least you should know how to create a static member.
So let's try to create a static member here.
In this particular example, I will say static.
Let's say the matter name is test.
That's it.
Now I will display any method inside.
Let's say static method call.
That's it.
I do not need to instantiate these at the moment.
Certainly I can remove the constructor as well if I want to and ensure that I matter also.
So imagine that this is just the static method we have here.
We are not going to instantiate this.
See this?
How am I calling?
I'm using the class name and I'll say Test.
That's it.
So last name, dot method name.
Our member name in short.
That's how you access the starting member.
Now, if I run this, you see that the output is there.
So we don't need to have an instance of a class to refer a static member.
Let me also create a static property, also a static maybe, let's say, application version.
These are the things we put as static, maybe 1.2.
So now if I want to refer it, I simply say console.log.
How's dart the app version?
That's it.
We don't need to instantiate class yet.
If you have a static method, let's say test one.
One more static method inside the class.
New method, for example.
In case if you want to call this test one from this static method itself, then you can certainly write
like this.
This door test one.
You can do that.
See, generally this refers to an instance.
But here, even though the instance is not that, certainly you can write how you start test one.
But do you?
Even if you write this door test one, it's going to work.
So if I run this, you'll see that the starting matter card is displayed.
New method and of course the version.
So this test one is called with that this object also.
So before we move to related question, in the beginning, I mentioned about constructor function syntax,
as I say that the class keyword was introduced in E6, but before that that is in EA's file, the function
was acting as a class.
So let me show you that.
Also, this is the E6 index.
You have a function house right here.
We don't need a constructor.
If you write a line here, let's say console.log, then this is going to be the constructor itself,
let's say called.
Now if I just call like normally you see that we call the function like this.
Right.
But instead of writing the name of the function, if you call it with new keyword, let's say I would
prefer s five syntax only.
So I'll say var var obj is equal to new house.
So if I do this, this means it's just the way you call the function.
It changes the behavior.
Now it is acting as a constructor function and this itself is a class.
So I can see this dot, let's say windows at the moment, right, is equal to maybe you have parameters
to the constructor so you can write windows here, right?
And here you are passing the values again.
Say var obj one is equal to new house and different number of windows.
So the code which we saw with class in this case we have it with the constructor function syntax.
This is S5 syntax, so just get the idea about it.
That's why I mentioned it here.
No, it's not needed now to know how it works.
But still you have this way of writing function.
So if you say new in function name, that is going to act as a class.
Let's discuss related questions of this topic.
The first question is how can you create a class?
So this is how you create a class.
The second question is when is the constructor called?
So the constructor is called as soon as an instance of a class is created.
So whatever you want to initialize, whatever process you want to have as initialization that you can
put in the constructor method.
The third question is, can we have dynamic property or matter names in a class?
Yes, of course we can have it.
This is how you can have it.
Just put a square bracket and that matter name or a property name can be dynamic.
First question what is a class expression?
We have already seen.
Function expression.
So that is a function, for example, like this.
Then if we want to convert it into function expression, then how do you do that?
You put the name before the function keyword, right?
And you write it like this.
Of course, if you write an arrow function, that is a function expression only.
Now here, when I say const test is equal to function.
This is a function expression.
Similarly, ES6 gives you class expression as well.
When you say class expression, it means you write a class like this.
You say class house.
You write like this.
This is what we have seen.
Instead of this, you can say let house is equal to class.
Maybe test.
You can remove this name also doesn't matter.
How do you give a name?
It is one and the same thing.
So here he said of late.
I would prefer to have contact.
Now let's say constructor and I'll say console.log only and got a message.
Let's create an instance of this now.
I'll say konst obj is equal to new house.
Let's run this.
So this is a class expression.
Normally you do not write this way, but yes, you do have class expression, like a function expression
in Essex.
Fifth question is what are static members in a class?
What is the purpose of defining them as static?
So we have already seen that we write just a static keyword and we can create static members.
And the purpose, as I mentioned, that when you are creating a module which has services where you
do not need to instantiate the class, you do not need an object like application version or maybe few
other services related to versioning or application name.
Then generally we do not want to instantiate those classes.
So we create a class and we create those members as static members.
The sixth question is how can you call another static method from a class?
So this we have already seen that you can say class named our method name or even this dart like in
this case this dart test one did call the test one method.