Hello, everyone.
In this section we are going to discuss about prime number problem.
When the program is executed, it is going to ask a number.
It will say enter a number.
For example, user enters seven.
Then it'll say seven is a prime number.
For example, the user enters ten here that it'll say ten is not a prime number.
Let's discuss this solution through logic and pseudocode first.
First question is what is a prime number?
So by definition, a prime number is a kind of number which is divisible by one and itself.
Let's take an example of seven.
Seven is a prime number.
That is it is divisible by one and seven.
No other number can divide seven other than one and seven itself.
If you consider 13, it also cannot be divided by any other number.
But if you say ten then it is divisible by two and it is divisible by five as well.
So ten is not a prime number.
So if we look at this discussion, we can make out that the numbers which are not divisible by any other
number, they are the prime numbers.
This now we know, but how to achieve the same thing programmatically.
Let's try to put a few steps to check whether a number is prime or not.
Consider file, for example.
If I want to check that file is prime or not, then first I will check.
Is file divisible by two because one any way can divide any number.
So I'm going to start checking with two that is five divisible by two.
Now here I am going to use a personal date sign, even in the logic and even in the pseudocode, because
percentage is a most commonly used operator known as the modulus operator, which returns the remainder.
So Modulus Operator, the percentage operator can be used to check the visibility.
So here the first question is five divisible by two.
If it is not divisible, then for two it is prime.
But I need to check below and minus one.
So what I will have to do is I will check is five divisible by two.
No good.
Then I will check with the next number.
Is five divisible by three.
No good is five divisible by four?
No.
Then only it is a prime number.
It means starting from two to end minus one.
In this case, the number is five.
We have taken example of five, so we are going to check till four.
So starting from two to end minus one.
If no number can divide, then only it is a prime number.
So this means we will have to put a loop which starts at two and ends at end minus one.
Assume that this end is 13.
That means from 2 to 12.
You want to check?
Of course you can reduce the number of repetitions, but that we are not discussing at the moment.
We can improvise the coding, but that we will see at a later stage when we can reduce the number of
repetitions and the code can execute faster.
But right now, fundamentally, when you check about prime number, you start with two and go till and
minus one.
Let's try this with pseudocode.
For value phi we consider variable n which has value five and and is the variable which we want to check.
Whether it's prime or not.
We are going to put a loop using a variable called counter which will begin at two and it will go till
four.
That is actually and minus one and step will be one.
That means every time it gets incremented because we need to check whether end is divisible by counter
we are going to use and if condition.
So ideally you may think of writing something like this if and Modulus C and D that is if it is divisible
then it is not prime.
And if it is not divisible in the L spot, you will say it is prime.
So ideally when you run, this end will be five.
And counter is two.
So is file divisible by two?
It is not.
That means it will say it is prime.
But if you put this inside the loop, the core will not work the way we are expecting.
Let's try to run this practically here on the page to see what will be the issue.
So five modulus, two it'll say it is prime because it is not divisible.
Now counter will be incremented by one.
So counter will become three.
Is five divisible by three?
No, it is not.
Again, it will say prime.
The counter will become four.
Is five divisible by four?
No, it is not.
Third time it will say prime.
So you wanted that it should show prime only once.
Let's take an example of number six.
So now your loop will run from 2 to 5.
Is six divisible by two?
It is so it will say not prime counter will become three.
Is six divisible by three?
Yes, it is divisible.
Again, the message will be not prime.
Now the counter will become four.
So is six divisible by four?
No.
So it'll say prime.
So if the number is six, sometimes it will say prime.
And sometimes it will say it's not a prime number.
That is something which we do not want.
What we want is that from 2 to 5, no number should divide this given number.
Then only it is a prime number in such case.
What you can do is you can take an additional variable in programming.
This is called as a flag variable.
You can name this flag variable whatever you want to, but this flag is going to keep some status.
It is going to store some value that will determine at the end whether it was prime or not.
You can name this flag variable anything, right?
You can name, test or anything you want to.
That doesn't matter.
What matters is the concept of flag variable.
Whenever we say it's a flag variable, that means it's a kind of variable which is going to keep a state
for certain things.
So here, let me take a variable called is prime.
Now in various programming languages, you have data type called boolean where you can keep this.
True or false?
But at the moment, because we are writing pseudo code and we do not want to deal with complex data
types here, let's say in is prime.
I'm going to say one that means I assume from the beginning that the given number is a prime number.
You can assign the value you want.
Let's say you decide that six means prime and seven means not prime.
It's fine.
But we are going to take zero and one one means we are going to consider it as a prime number.
So now what will I do if the end was divisible by counter at any point of time?
That means it is divisible like this.
Then I'm going to assign value zero in prime.
Not only that now, because one number could divide that.
I do not want to continue the loop.
I will come out of the loop.
So I will say exit 40 in the language, in the programming language term.
You are going to break the loop.
But because we are writing pseudocode, I am trying to write simple English language.
So here, once the number that is the end was divisible by any value of the counter that is from two
to MN minus one, any number could divide.
That means I'm going to assign is prime, is equal to zero, and then I'm going to come out of the loop
because now it is decided that the number was divisible by some number and because it was divisible,
it is not a prime number anymore.
So now after the loop is over, the only thing you will have to do is you'll just put a condition.
If is prime is equal to one, then you will print.
That number is prime.
Else is prime, value is zero.
Then you will say number is not prime.
So the loop is very simple to understand, but you need to understand the concept of the flag variable.
Flag variable is a kind of variable you use to keep the status of the situation here.
The situation was it was divisible.
So you made it zero.
Let's try to code this.
I'm going to take similar variables here.
Let's say we'll use variable and.
Where we are going to get the data.
So I will say prompt here.
And enter a.
Number.
We'll also take a counter.
Of course, we can put this in a follow up only.
So I will say follow led counter is equal to two.
Counter less thin and right.
I don't have to say to counter less than equal to n minus one, I can say less than.
And so if NN is five it will go till four only and counter plus plus.
Let's try the first way where it is going to show me prime or not prime, but the things.
So I'll just put an if condition here where if number is divisible by counter.
That means it is a prime number.
It's not a prime number.
Not Prime.
Else.
It is a prime number.
Let's run this.
I enter five year.
It says Prime three times.
As you can see, that is a counter.
Let me type six in this case.
So it says non-prime two times and prime two times.
Right.
This is the problem.
So we took a flag really.
But let me take is prime.
Now JavaScript has boolean value so I'm going to say is prime true.
So from the beginning I'm assuming that the number is a prime number.
Now when this was divisible, that means any number could divide.
I'm going to say is prime is equal to false.
I'll make it false.
And of course I'm going to come out of the loop because I do not need to check more iterations.
Like this.
And outside the loop.
I'll put the condition.
That is prime.
It's true.
Then I'll display a message saying.
That and.
Is a prime number.
And it's.
And is.
Not a prime number.
Let's try to run this code now.
I'll say five.
It says five is a prime number.
Let's try six.
It's a six is not a prime number.
Let's try 13.
13 is a prime number.
I'll say 21.
So 21 is not a prime number.
In short, you check the prime number possibility with this kind of logic.
Remember, even if you repeat the loop.
Still and by two.
Then also you will get the correct answer.
See, for example, you have value 100.
Then you need to check till 50 only because by the time if it is divisible, some number will divide.
This is to reduce the iterations and to execute the code faster.
But at the moment we do not want to improvise on the prime number logic or we do not want to make it
more perfect.
We just want to target that.
We understand the logic and we try this simpler code of finding a prime number.