In this section, I'm going to discuss two methods which help you to convert the case.
That is, you can convert from lower to upper or upper to lower case.
There will be one related question regarding these matters.
The syntax of these two matters are.
These methods are very useful when you are comparing strings.
Let's take an example of both the methods.
I'm going to declare a string here and say let str is equal to test.
Now I'm going to say console.log because both the method that is to uppercase and to lowercase return
a new string.
So I'll say str dot that is the string variable dot to.
Uppercase.
And to lower case and say lower case.
So when I run this.
You'll see that in the first case the entire string is converted into uppercase, whereas in the second
it is converted into lowercase.
The main advantage of using these methods is when you are comparing a value.
It's always good to have uppercase or lowercase.
For example, I just want to compare if the value SDR is test or not.
Now in the condition I'm writing it in lowercase.
Now the user may enter this test value in any case, but you just want to make sure that when you have
fixed a value like lowercase this way and you want to avoid the case sensitivity.
Simple is that you convert the string into lowercase.
Now before I convert, let me just run this.
I'll say equal to the strict equality that is.
Or rather I'll write console.log here.
I'll say string is equal to test that that will return true or false.
So let me run this.
Now you see that it says it is false.
Now you want to implement this into case insensitive condition checking.
So I'll say to lower case.
Now, regardless of what the value is inside the SDR, it's going to return the true because to lower
case is converting the value in lower case.
And here you have even the lower case value only.
You can do the reverse way as well.
I can say test here and here.
I simply convert into uppercase.
This will also give me the true result.
Let me change the values so you can see that the value is not matching.
It will return the funds.
So this is the purpose of using two upper and lower case.
There is also one more method replace method which is used to replace the character or substring, but
it also returns the new string only.
The replace method is wonderful method to find and replace a value.
It can take a regular expression or a substring to understand how it works with regular expression.
You can check my regular expression tutorial.
There is a lecture on replace method which explains the regular expression and replace method in detail.
So right now I am not discussing those things here, but certainly I am going to show you one simple
example that it shows how we can replace a string so it automatically finds and replaces the value.
Say.
For example, I just want to say console.log.
And here I'll start out replace.
That string I want to find is, let's say, 23.
And I want to replace it with exclamation.
Let me run this.
I'll clear the console and run it.
Now you see that T3 is replaced by an exclamation.
So this is a very useful method when you want to find and replace values in a string, but certainly
it is extensively used with regular expression.
We have only one question here, and the question is get a character from the user and check whether
the character is a vowel or consonant.
This is one of the example where we can use to lower our to upper to avoid the case sensitivity.
This is how the program will be.
When we run the program, it will ask users to enter a character.
Let's say the user enters EA, then there is a message displayed that is a vowel.
If a user enters are, then the output will be r is a consonant.
Same goes for all vowels or consonants.
We'll take a variable and will have a function to get the value.
We'll have the prompt statement to get the character.
Now we are going to put an if condition.
Variable switch, we are going to check whether it is e e I or you.
Then we print c is vowel.
Otherwise it's consonant.
So now let's try the lowercase values.
So as you can see, let's enter a.
It says it is Volvo.
Let's enter you.
Let's enter via.
It says it's a concern.
Now, these values which we have entered so far are small cases.
That is lower cases.
Let's try to enter a value capital a.
Now it's this consonant.
Now let's try to apply the lowercase logic here.
So after the input of character, I will convert the character into lowercase.
So now let's try see it not to lowercase to convert the value into lowercase.
Now let's run the code again and we will try to enter capital E that says it's available.
So this is a basic logic to convert the value into lowercase because you are checking lowercase in if
condition.
If you can write capital in if condition or capital values, uppercase values that is, then you can
convert it into uppercase.
That's the whole idea behind keeping the single condition and converting the value smartly in respective
cases.