The next question is how to flatten a two dimensional eddy.
Now, the purpose of this question is that we are going to use the reduced method.
The question is of Adi's category, and there will be five related questions to this topic.
Now flattening and adding is basically converting multi dimensional, maybe two dimensional, three
dimensional area into a single dimensional eddy to flatten and eddy.
We have to use the reduce method.
We will begin with the basics and then I will discuss the flattening process as a first question in
the related questions section.
The reason is you need to know the basics of the reduce method, like the MAP method.
Reduce is also asked in almost all interviews, and the reason is it's very useful in many places.
We saw one example in map method about finding square, square root or length of each element in all
these operations.
That is one thing common.
If you have ten elements, there will be ten results.
But let's see.
I ask you to get the sum of all elements.
Then it's kind of an aggregate or accumulative operation that is the result is combined.
So reduce method loops through all the elements and helps you to get one combined result like some or
other accumulative calculations, for example, product or average.
Let's check with an example.
I will declare an array, for example, which has two, four, six, eight.
That is four values we have here.
I missed an equal to sign.
I also like the result is equal to adequate reduce.
Now this method also takes a callback function as an argument, but there is a major difference if you
compare it with map or wattage.
And this this has a different way to deal with the parameters.
Yes, it does have a callback function.
The first parameter is the accumulator.
Now you name it, whatever you want to.
But we call this as a kind of accumulator y because it accumulates all the values in it.
Then comes the element value or the current value.
We can name it element.
Our current.
Let's say I name it.
Current value.
Current value are just current.
This means that every element of ETA goes to the current variable and accumulator will actually accumulate
all the returned values, which I'm going to show you in a moment.
So we are taking the arrow function.
Let's see.
What I want to return is I want to return whatever is the accumulator.
I just want to add the current value in it.
Right, and just display the result.
I'll say console.log.
And the result I want to display.
Let's check what happens.
It says 20, right?
So accumulator holds the accumulator values.
There are other parameters with this.
The next parameter is actually the index of the current value and also it passes the ADI array on which
this loop is going.
Right.
So we have these parameters.
We also have one more parameter here.
Not that this argument, but this is actually the initial value.
Now there is a difference in this.
Let's try this also and remove this add it and index because at the moment it is not needed and you
can easily understand that if it is needed, you can use it wherever you want to index and added that
is.
But the initial value is something which we need to discuss.
Earlier we did not give any initial value.
This initial value parameter is for the accumulator.
When it started, the accumulator was zero and then it started adding two, four, six and eight.
Let's say I initialized the accumulator with ten.
Then what will happen?
It will give us the result 30 instead of 20 y because this total was anyway has to be 20.
But then we initialize the accumulator with ten.
So ten plus two plus four plus six plus eight.
That's how it has gone.
So this parameter is very useful.
You may argue like this.
That means from the beginning accumulator has become an object literal.
If you give like this, only like this, the scribe records, the accumulator becomes an array.
So you do take a value, assign that initial value.
So we have seen that initial value makes the difference.
Let's also practically understand that how this process goes on.
So I will just show you the dry run off with and without initial value.
Then there is no initial value given this is how the output will be.
Let's check that run.
Accumulator is zero on the first call.
The current value will be two.
Similarly, it goes on like this on second call, on third call and on the fourth call we have the current
value eight and the output is 20.
If we give this initial value, then the output will look something like this.
So now the accumulator will begin with ten instead of zero.
So that's how the initial value works.
Now this is just adding some.
How about getting product?
If you want product, only thing you need to do is just put an asterisk sign here that is a multiplication
sign and instead of showing the sum, it is going to give you the product of these values.
In fact, we can calculate the average as well.
Let's say we have four elements here and the sum is 20, so the average is actually 20 by total number
of elements, so 20 by four.
So the average should be five.
There might be different values.
So we will consider added length as number of elements.
How we look down the average here, let's try that.
We have the code inside this reduce method.
We can put a condition.
Now here I need the index number and I will take the add also to make sure that because this function
may be part of some other process, right?
So I'm passing the added and that array I'm going to check for example if index.
Is equal to added length.
Added Art lent minus one.
That means when it reaches to the final stage, I want to return the accumulator by added length.
Now every time your accumulator will have a total of new elements added to it.
So at the end I want to return.
Like I said, this will have 20 and I'm dividing it by the length that is four, so it should return
me five.
Now the only thing is when it comes to adding the value, right?
How will you write?
You'll say accumulator every time.
Add accumulator.
With the current value.
The important point here is it should return the accumulator every time like this, right?
So accumulator is return to the function.
So it will have the sum all the times.
But here we are not writing, plus we are just adding it separately so that after the last element is
added to it, if this condition matches, then we are not going to return only accumulator.
Instead we are going to return the average value saving it.
Let's try this.
Clearing the screen.
There it is.
Just to try one more thing we can add.
Let's add ten.
Right?
So now we will have the sum as 30 and there are five elements.
So that has to be six as an average.
So there are various combinations you can try inside the reduced methods column.
That is also a reduced right matter.
The only difference is reduce loops through adding from left to right.
That is from zero IT index to add a length minus one, whereas reduce right moves right to left.
That is, the loop begins with added length minus one index and go still zero at the index.
Now let's discuss related questions of this topic.
The first question is, which was our main question, how will you flatten and add a that is, for example,
we have an array like this which is a two dimensional addy and we want to convert it into a single dimensional
addy.
Let's first of all print this add to itself so you get the idea that this is a two dimensional area.
So you see that every element itself is an Eddie.
Now we want to convert it into a single dimensional ADI.
This is where reduce can be used.
So I can say let flatten Eddie.
This process is also called less flattening and at a rate we are making it flat.
So that's why I just take a variable F error that is flatten Eddie is equal to I'll say added or reduce.
Now here I'm going to take the callback function with arrow only.
Now there will be two parameters, as we have discussed.
There will be an accumulator.
And there will be a current value.
All right.
Now, the only thing you have to do is you just have to say return the accumulator with a concrete.
That is, you want to upend the current value in it.
That's it.
So every time.
The accumulator will make sure that a new value is added to it with a concrete method.
Now the only thing remaining is that we just display the flattened add.
That's it.
So if I run, you get that it is a flat, an attic.
Sometimes we also take care that accumulator is for short converted into an add.
So initializing with a square bracket.
That is, we make sure that from the beginning the accumulator is an.
This will also give us the same output.
This is a better practice when you are flattening an attic.
So this is how you flatten and add a using the reduce method.
The second question is get some of a key feel of an object literal.
For example, this is the object literal employees.
And you want to get salary of all the employees.
How will you do this?
Let's try in the court window.
I have already declared the edit here.
Let's say LED total salary is equal to employees, not reduce.
Now again, the accumulator and the current value.
And I'll put an arrow function.
What will it be?
Now, as we have seen the syntax, you might be thinking that writing the accumulator, right, and
we are adding the current, which is going to be an object literal, not salary should style our purpose.
Let's see what happens in this case.
We will display the total salary and say total salary.
See what happens.
It has joined all the values.
The reason is accumulator is filled with the first element.
Right.
It is initialized with the first element.
And every element of this add is an object literal.
So Accumulator joins the current large salary.
So this itself is an object object plus current salary.
This keeps on going so we don't get the output.
So we have to make sure that the accumulator should be zero in the beginning.
So it's going to handle the numeric operations now.
Right.
So now because we have given zero as initial value.
Now let's try and see what happens.
Now we have the sum of all the values.
So you do have to take care using initial value when you have the object literal.
Especially the third question is find average of all elements of an array.
This we have already seen.
This is the code we tried.
So this is again an important question to deal with.
The fourth question is find some or maybe product of all elements which we have seen while understanding
this index of reduce.
The fifth question is what is the difference between reduce and reduce?
Right.
So this we discussed that the reduced loops from the zeroth element till the last element but is reduced
right starts the loop from the right side.
That's the only difference between these two methods.