If you observe the original component we want, which has this beautiful interface.
Certainly it will need a lot of HTML and CSS.
Now the code you see where we have used the inner edge HTML.
That's the place where we need to write the HTML and CSS required for the entire component, which is
very impractical.
Ideally the HTML and CSS, that is the design or interface of the component should be written separately
and we assign it later.
We actually define a template to write the design of the component.
When I say design, I mean the HTML and CSS.
That is the interface.
Like in this component, we need an image, a button, some text, etc..
So let's create a template first for the existing component.
But before we start it in JavaScript, you must know a template tag.
So let me separately explain what a template tag is with a practical example.
As the name says, this tag allows you to define the HTML template.
Template means there is a design which you can use by making a copy or clone of it.
Let me open a temp html file here and add some prerequisite HTML with exclamation tab.
Let me add the script tag here and also an H1.
Inside this, I'll say the template tag.
Now let me add a button just after the H1.
I'll say button here.
And sure is the text I want on the button.
Let me also have an on click event.
When I click on the button, I want to show the template.
So I'll say on Click Show Function, I'm going to call at a later stage.
Let me also define the function in the script.
So here I'll say function show and just have the parentheses and brackets.
Now on a click of the button, I want to show some HTML and that HTML.
I'm going to define inside the template.
So I'll add a division here.
I'll say div.
And let me give an I.D. to this division so ID.
I'll keep it.
Log in.
Now let me add a template with a division.
I'll say template inside I'll say a div in which let me add a label.
Log in and let me also add an input.
Type equal to text.
If you observe the output, the HTML written inside the template is not displayed.
Remember template tag contains the HTML which is not rendered on the page load but is displayed only
through JavaScript.
Now when the button is clicked, we need to show the template design in the login division.
So in the script section we have already given the function show.
I will get the reference of login division using get element by ID in an object called login.
I'll say const login is equal to document.
Dot get element by id inside.
I'll say login.
Now I'll say Konst.
Template is equal to document dot get element by id tmp.
This is where I'm getting the reference of the template.
As a temp and concert clone is equal to template dot content.
Darth clone nor.
In the brackets, I'll say true.
I'm explaining these in a moment, but let's append this template to the division.
I'll say log in, dot, append child.
Clone.
Clone is the copy of the template.
As I mentioned, template is just the template, the design and when you want to apply it, you make
a copy of it and then you add.
So here we have created a clone using the template dot content dot clone method and that's a deep copy.
When you say true, that means all the child nodes will also be included and then we are appending it
to the division.
Let's save this and click on the show button.
And you can see that the content, the template is being displayed.
Now let me run this score in the separate browser window and open the developer tool.
You can see there is nothing inside the division.
Now let me click on show and let's expand the division.
Now we have the template added as a separate copy, but this is an individual division inside the main
division.
Clicking on the show button every time will create a clone of the template and add it to the dom.
Instead of this fixed template in the HTML section, we can create a template at runtime using JavaScript
with the help of document dart create element.
Let me first try that here in this code.
Here instead of get element, buy ID, I'll say create element.
And let me create the template element.
So I'll say template here.
So this is creating a new template.
Now here I'm going to say template dot in html is equal to bektic.
Let me press enter and in between.
I'm going to cut this cord.
And paste it inside the inner HTML.
Now let me remove the template from this place.
Let's save this and run it again.
And we still have the same output.
Now in the previous call we had the template created with the HTML, whereas here we are using the JavaScript.
That is, we are creating the template at runtime.
You can still fine tune the score by avoiding the clone object.
You don't need to create it separately this way.
What you can do, you can just cut this line and paste it inside the append child and let's remove this
const clone.
Whether you write it in the previous way or you write it this way, it is one in the same thing.
It's just that you are using lesser lines.
Now let's talk about related questions.
So the first question is, what is the purpose of the template tag?
The purpose of the template.
Tag is very simple.
It's like you assign a value to a variable.
But how about assigning a lot of HTML and CSS to a variable template?
Does exactly the same job.
It contains the html CSS page itself, which you can show as in when required.
You just have to make sure that you use the clone node method, which basically creates the clone that
is copy of a template.
That itself is an element which you can add to any other parent element using append child.