Hello, everyone.
Welcome to the Algorithm Series.
In this section we are going to discuss about how to check a character is a vowel or a consonant.
This is how the program will be when we run the program.
It will ask user to enter a character.
Let's say the user enters E, then there is a message displayed that is a vowel.
If a user enters are, then the output will be r is a consonant.
Same goes for all vowels or consonants.
Let's discuss the solution and the pseudocode.
So first we will get a character.
Now what we have to check is that enter character is eei0 or you.
Then it is a vowel.
Otherwise it is a consonant.
Because we have to check conditions here.
We can use F or switch case in the respective programming languages.
But here we are going to try the pseudocode.
So we are using the F condition.
And because we want to check more than one condition, there is actually five conditions to be precise.
For a e, i or and you.
So we are going to join each condition with or why are we using R?
Because here we have to check that character.
That is the variable C which has E or I or you are any other value.
So at the time, not all values can be inside this variable.
So we are joining the condition using order here.
So we'll see if it is equal to a r e or I, r o or you then will print.
It is a vowel, otherwise it's a consonant.
So this is a very simple logic behind it.
Of course, there is a possibility that when the user enters a character, it may not be small keys.
Let's say the user enters capital E.
Now here we do not have any condition which checks in the pseudocode that risk capital are not to implement
that in respective programming languages.
There are various functions which can convert the value of variable into uppercase or lowercase.
Let's say I can update this pseudocode for the moment, I'll simply convert c it is equal to two lower.
Assume that there is a function called to lower of c it.
So whether the user enters small case or capital that will be always converted into small case.
So here you have checked all the conditions for small case only that is lower case only.
So depending on the programming language, you can also apply this lowercase function to convert the
value into lower and then you check the lower case value only.
So now let's try the coding practically.
We'll take a variable and we'll have a function to get the value.
We'll have the prom statement to get a character.
Now we are going to put an if condition variable sketch.
We are going to check whether it is e, e, i or u.
Then we print C is vowel.
Otherwise it's consonant.
So now let's try the lowercase values.
So as you can see, let's enter a.
It says it is Volvo.
Let's enter you.
It says it is woven.
Let's enter via.
It says it's a concern.
Now, these values which we have entered so far are small cases.
That is lower cases.
Let's try to enter a value capital a.
Now it's this consonant.
Now let's try to apply the lowercase logic here.
So after the input of character, I will convert the character into lowercase.
So now let's try see it not to lowercase to convert the value into lowercase.
Now let's run the code again and we will try to enter capital here.
Now it says it's available.
So this is a basic logic to convert the value into lowercase because you are checking lowercase and
if condition, if you can write capital in if condition are capital values, uppercase values that is,
then you can convert it into uppercase.
That's the whole idea behind keeping the single condition and converting the value smartly in respective
cases.