This question discusses about the structuring of object littoral.
There are two related questions.
We have already seen the concept of this structuring in the address section, but I will still repeat
the same thing for clarification that what is the structuring?
As the name structuring sees that something is getting the structure.
It also means there is already a structure which is getting broken.
When I say structure, it means the data structure.
So restructuring is a concept of breaking data structure like eddy or object literal into data pieces
or in other words, individual variables.
In this section we are discussing the structuring of object literal for added structuring.
You can check the add section.
Object literal structuring will look something like this.
For example, you have an object which has bigger than P name.
That is product code and product name where we have values also 1001 and Apple.
Now the thing is, if you want to bring product code and product name out of the structure and want
to assign to individual variables, then you will write something like this.
You will say let be code is equal to object becau or maybe p name is equal to object or be name.
Now there are only two members at the moment, but when you have more members it is a cumbersome job.
So instead of that you have an easier way in E6 like this where you can select in the curly brackets,
you put list of all the variables and then you assign the object.
You do have to take care here that the key name and here the variable name is similar.
For example, in this figure you see that I have already given speaker and P name, which is the same
key in the object as well.
Let's try practically to get the clear idea.
So here I can create const object is equal to and the same thing.
I'm going to write b code and of course b name.
After this.
I just want to distract you.
Remember the left hand side.
What you are writing in curly brackets is not an object.
Literally.
This is just a list of variables which I am giving that is speaker and P name that equals two objects.
You are giving these curly brackets to show that you are trying to structure an object literal.
If it is an array, you put a square bracket which we have already seen in the added restructuring inside
add a section.
So now the only thing we have to check is whether this thing is destructor or not.
So I will say console.log will try to display individual variables now.
So product code and product name and let's run this.
I added a semicolon by mistake.
Let me do it again.
I'm running the court again.
So now you see that we have individual variables where 1001 and Apple, that is two values are the structure.
So this is the whole concept of restructuring.
Of course, in this case, right now we are de structuring an object literal.
Same thing.
A function can return an object and that can be the structure.
Say, for example, I put this object inside a function.
So as a function, let's say test and shift this object inside the function.
And let's say this is returning an object that is the object.
So now if you call the function, it is going to be the same thing.
The similar example we tried with added restructuring as well.
Right?
So here I will have the same output.
That is the value of individual variables.
Even while restructuring the object literal, we do have default value assignment.
For example, if there is no value assigned to pick or then what should be the default value?
So if I say for example, 12 is the default value or maybe zero is the default value.
So if that is no picture inside this object literal, let's see this.
As you can see, if there is no value, then the peak is zero.
But the moment I add a value, let's say Beaker is equal to 1002 at the moment and I'll put a comma.
Now if I run, then yes, we do have the value which was assigned in the object literal.
So this is a very basic idea of breaking the data structure like object literal or adding and getting
the data pieces out of that data structure.
Let's discuss the relative questions of this topic.
The first question is explain a practical scenario of object literal restructuring.
Object literal restructuring is often used in all programs.
The reason is that you get the data from the server in adjacent format.
When you receive it, you will always have that data assigned to a JavaScript object literal something
like this.
Now the data which is retrieved here that will always be needed to be de structure because you would
not want that entire object literal like this.
For example, you have, let's say, product detail, these many details you have like product code
date, manufacturing date, I mean name price, vendor and what not.
The data which you retrieve like this, that needs to be the structure because only few variables you
want to use.
So it's a very common way.
So the practical scenario is like this that value how to use the restructuring of object later.
The second question is explain the output of this call.
So well.
This is about default value assignment, which is possible with object later.
So here we have the default value functionality with a so it will be 90 and B is going to be empty.
That means it will not have any value.
And by default inside JavaScript, if variable is not assigned with a value, it's going to be undefined.
So if I run this, it should display as 90.
That is the value of it.
That is the default value and undefined for B.