In this section we are going to discuss about the next modifier or flag and that is slash you.
This modifier is used with Unicode values.
So before we start discussing about this modifier, let's get clear with the Unicode concept.
Why do we need Unicode?
Imagine character a pressed on keyboard.
Does it really say a directly to the computer?
The answer is no.
Let's look at some illustrations.
Character A is stored in binary format.
So actually the value of A is this binary value internally.
Now the bigger question is how this binary value is derived.
So we have Unicode table where each character is given a unique hexadecimal number.
Double zero for one is the number of a in Unicode character table and the binary of double zero for
one is this binary value.
Before Unicode.
There were many characters and coatings, but they were conflicting with one another.
By accepting a standard or universal character encoding, it has become easy to manage various languages
across various platforms.
Unicode encoding covers letters of various languages, currency symbols, emojis, and much more.
This means in the Unicode table that is a hex number given to each character.
Let's check Capital A.
And also check small a.
Let's also try currency symbol.
For example.
If I select currency symbol from this list, it will show me all the symbols and also showing the range
below the dropdown of category.
In short, a letter in a language is a symbolic or pictorial presentation anyway, so there are many
characters or symbols you see, like the one you see in the figure saying letting capital letter A.
Other languages, currency symbols and various emojis like smileys or other emojis.
You can also check Unicode dot org for Unicode characters and other details.
So now we get some idea that Unicode is universal set of characters used by all programming languages,
various platforms and software applications.
There are few more terms which should be known to a programmer who wants to claim that.
Yes, I know what is Unicode.
Let's begin with first term known as Code Point.
Gold Point is nothing but the hexadecimal number assigned to each character.
We saw that for character A the number is you +00 for one.
So this U +00 for one is called point.
Normally we see that code point has the syntax of u plus the hex value.
U plus prefixed code shows that it is a unicode and hex is the unique number given to respective character.
Of course, not all code points are assigned a character as some are empty and can be assigned in the
future.
The next term, which we need to know is character and properties.
It is a character assigned to each core point.
You must have observed that with character A.
It is also displaying Latin capital letter A.
In a way it is kind of category.
Another example you can observe in currency where the category is currency sign.
So it is about the category and the property of a character.
The next topic we are going to discuss is Unicode planes.
A plane in Unicode standards is a group of 65,536 code points.
There are 17 planes and each plane is given a number starting from 0 to 16.
That is a hexadecimal number given to each plane.
So first plane will be like you plus zero and the hexadecimal value.
The zero is also a hexadecimal and the rest of the values are individual code points.
For example, for second plane, it should be U plus one and then four zeros where one is the second
plane number.
Plane zero is called basic multilingual plane that is BNP.
This plane contains most commonly used characters and symbols.
Developers need characters from this plane most of the time.
Higher planes above BNP are called supplementary planes or astral planes.
So it means the last code point in 17 planes is U plus ten, which is a hexadecimal 16 and four FS.
So code units of supplementary planes are called supplementary or astral.
Code points.
Another topic is code units.
It is the number of bits used for the respective character encoding.
We have UTF eight that is eight bits or one byte, UTF 16 that is 16 bits or two bytes and UTF 32 that
is 32 bits or four bytes encoding available.
It means a code unit can be off one, two or four bytes, as we now know that a code point is a character
and each character can be represented by one or more code units depending on the type of character encoding.
This also means when we consider character A in UTF eight, the core unit will be for one that is 41
hexadecimal value.
For UTF 16, it will be double zero for one that is for bytes hexadecimal value, and for UTF 32 it
will be total eight bytes of course.
41 hexadecimal value.
The next concept in Unicode is surrogate pairs.
So now we know that a code point represents one character and depending on the character encoding,
a number of bytes are used.
There are some characters who belong to the supplementary or astral plane.
Normally, programming languages deal in UTF 16.
That is 16 bits.
A character which is in the astral plane needs 21 bits.
For example, Smiley, which is in the second plane.
It means it will require two UTF 16 code units to store Smiley.
Smiley scored point is 1f600 where one is the plane number and f600 is the code point.
Because this character needs 21 bits, it will need a pair of UTF 16 code unit.
And this pair is known as a surrogate pair.
The first section is leading our high surrogate code unit and second is trailing or low surrogate code
unit.
So if I try to print Smiley and because it belongs to astral plane or supplementary plane, which requires
two code unit or a surrogate pair in UTF 16 for 1f600, the surrogate per used is D, 83d and de00.
That is also a logic where you have a provision to convert the core unit into surrogate value.
But that's a different topic to be discussed at the moment.
You can imagine these values we already know.
So let's try to print smiley using surrogate pair in GS fetal.
I'll just say console.log and the high and low surrogate pair I'm going to mention here.
Let's try to run the code now.
As you can see, a smiley is displayed.
BNP has unused code points so far, high surrogate.
The range is da002 db, double F and for low surrogate code unit the range is DC 002df double F in sharp
surrogate pair is used when we have characters above BNP plane.
The next concept you need to know is graphing and glyph.
A graffiti is actually a character, or you can say a code point, but sometimes you see sequence of
characters for a graffiti.
For example, we display console or log E and of course console log log E, and then I'm adding one
more character which will be displayed on top of E.
Here.
The first line is a single character or code point, whereas the second takes combination of characters
or code points to display a single graffiti.
So both the displayed values are called graffiti, but the second is displayed using combination mark.
If you think graphene as a character, then the actual image displayed, maybe with different formatting,
is called a glyph.
For example, graphene A may have glyphs like this.
A.
This one are like this.
So glyph is the actual image which you see on the screen.