In this lecture, we will learn about the DOM breakpoints.
This itself is a question that what are DOM breakpoints and how do they function?
DOM stands for document, object, model, and every element in the web page is called the DOM Node.
This I have explained descriptively in a dedicated section on Domain Web.
To break the execution in case of the dome structure, mutation or modification.
We used the dam break points where the dam mutation can be subtree.
Change.
Change in the attributes or removal of nodes.
Let us practically see these cases.
Adam Breakpoint is set on a particular node or element.
To put a down breakpoint.
I will right click on the element.
I will select inspect and it score gets highlighted here in the Elements panel.
Let me right click on it.
Now, however, on the brake on option, which shows the three types of DOM breakpoints that we can
select as our requirement.
The blue dot on the side shows that the breakpoint is set.
The first type that is subtree modification breakpoint will be triggered whenever there are changes
like adding, moving or removing the child nodes.
That is modification in the subtree.
In this code, that is a button that will add a child node on the click event.
Going to the browser.
I will right click on this and select inspect.
It is highlighted here and now I'm setting the subtree modification breakpoint.
In this side navigation here clicking on the DOM breakpoints shows the state offered before and after
triggered.
And let me click on add node.
So the subtree modification breakpoint is triggered.
In the debugging pane.
It shows the call stack and the enabled state that is subtree modified.
So the debugger parses when that is a modification in the subtree.
Resuming the execution and a child is added.
So this is how subtree modification breakpoints work.
To remove the break point.
You can deselect or simply right click and remove it.
Moving on to the second time that is to break on attribute modifications implies that the debugger pauses
when there are changes in the attributes of the node or elements that reboots of this paragraph change.
When I click these buttons, let me expand these divisions to set a breakpoint right clicking and selecting
the attribute modification option.
And it is set now.
As soon as I click on this button, the debugger pauses as the attribute of the selected element has
changed.
Let us resume and see.
Similarly when I click on Bold.
And also on reset the debugger positives.
So attribute modification breakpoint is triggered when the attributes of the selected element change.
The third one is the node removal that pauses the execution when a selected element or node is removed.
Let me go back to the first example.
Now I click here to add a node.
Selecting this element.
I will set a break point and select node removal.
So in a click on the added node to remove it, the break point is triggered.
I will resume the execution and the node is removed.
This was all about how the DOM breakpoints work and help in debugging in relation to the DOM mutation.