In this section we are trying slash p that is trying Unicode property.
We have already seen various fundamentals of Unicode.
Now let's try practically slash you modifier.
To use slash modifier.
We will also make use of property class called slash p slash p takes unicode property or symbol as an
argument like capital L for letter and for number and S for symbol.
The syntax of using slash P is we use slash P and then we give the Unicode property.
For example, you want to search all letters in a string, then you can use pattern slash P and uppercase
l l is instruction to the class slash P that search for all letters.
Similarly, there are many options like N for number and S for symbol, etc. Let's create a simple example
to try both Unicode property class slash P and modifier slash u.
Let's create a string which has few letters and symbols as well.
I'll say this is my face.
Tell me how do I look?
And we'll try to display it.
As you can see, the output is null because we haven't used slash U, which specifies to deal with unique
core values.
So let's add slash U after G.
Now it is able to find letters, but of course there is no search for symbols.
So let's try that too.
Using uppercase as property.
Now you can see that there are two symbols searched and displayed.
If you try to remove slash you, then the unique search won't happen.
In case you want to search for currency symbol, then you can write uppercase S and small C Let's try
it practically.
Let's say I have a string.
I found 300 and displaying with the match method.
So here are two values are returned.
Now let's add C with SE, which will return only currency symbols.
Now you see that that is only currency symbol return.
So like this, there are multiple options for every Unicode property to implement variety of patterns
to get unique code values.
So now you know that.
Why do we use modifier slash?
You remember JavaScript uses UTF 16 encoding and that is a lot you can do with Unicode characters and
its search with various encoding.