This section is about getting the reference or searching the elements using the get element by I.D,
by tags, by class or by name method.
This topic is of dumb and web category, and there will be three related questions of this topic.
We have already discussed that what is dumb and how the nodes are placed inside the dome.
Now, when do you think that you have to search or get the reference of a specific element?
Let's take an example.
We have this each one here, which is showing content when page loaded message and there is a button.
Now let's say I want that when I click on the button, I want to change the content of this action.
That means you need to get the handle of this action to get the handle of this particular element.
We have to give you an idea and then we can get the reference.
Let's try this example.
I have the code ready here.
First thing is that I'm going to give some identification to this age when, let's say you may be C
and D.
Now when the button is clicked.
I have already configured a function called BTN plugged.
So on click I want to call this function called.
BTN clicked.
Now, when you want to change the content of this one.
It means you need to get the reference off it.
Then only you can change it.
So let's take an example here.
That is an object called document, which we have discussed in few of our previous sections.
The document object has a method called get element by ID.
So this says that it is going to get the element by ID.
So the issuance I.D. is right now.
See, and this I'm going to say CND now H1 is an element which has a content.
So that is a property called enriched DML, which we can use.
Let's say I want to change the content that is content after button clicked.
Let's go back to the browser.
I'll just refresh.
And now when I click on this, you can see that the content is changed.
So the get element by IED is one of the material which you can use to get a specific element.
Only remember that in fact the same code can be redone in one more way.
Let's try that also.
What I can do is I can create a variable saying C and D, for example.
This is a kind of element.
So I will say a CND element, right?
That equals two.
I'm going to.
Just shift this thing.
And keep it on the separate line.
Now, this C.R.A. element has a reference of this entire element.
It means that now I can say that, see, and the element that generates HTML equals to the value.
Let's try this now.
See the output is still the same.
In the previous way, we tried this statement that this document our get element by it directly, whereas
here now we are using the object.
This object can further be used to represent this entire element.
You must remember that whenever this document or get element by idea method is used, it is used to
get the reference directly.
So the get element by ID is something which gets a reference off a particular element.
There are also other methods which can be used to get references.
Let me change this code and then we will discuss.
Now this page has a division three paragraphs, two edge trees and a button as well.
Let us, first of all, check the output.
So here is the output.
We have the paragraphs and the trees here.
Now let's try a few more matters to get a reference.
Now on a click of a button, I'm seeing concert elements is a call to document art, get elements by
tag name.
Remember here, elements is plural.
So there are multiple values can be returned.
Let's say I will write be here.
That means the tag paragraph, whichever paragraph it finds in this document that we want inside this
elements.
So naturally, because there are multiple values, it's going to return and add it.
And that added we are going to display so I'll say console.log elements.
I'll just refresh the page and clicking the button.
So here you see that we have three paragraph references returned.
So in case if you want to refer to the first paragraph, you can see elements of zero which will refer
to this element.
So this is the kind of matter which searches the elements by the tag name.
Similarly, we have a matter which searches by the last name as well.
Right.
So instead of by tag name, if I just say class name here.
But then we need to give the CSIS glasses.
So let's try with each three.
I'm going to say class is equal to maybe eight and the same I will apply for, let's say, the other
paragraph.
Also here, I'm going to say class is equal to E, so all the elements which have the class name E,
those classes will be returned in two elements.
Let's write this also.
And just click on this.
So now you'll see that we have Dart and Edge three Dart.
So now we have reference of a paragraph and H3 like last name.
We do also have only name that is elements by name.
So in case if you have given the name property, let's say here the name attribute, I mean, let's
say the name attribute, I say name is equal to better.
That is paragraph.
And this also, I guess you name is equal to.
Better.
Most of the time you will see that the same name creates a group.
I'll just ship this here.
The same name you see with radio buttons more often.
But here also, we can try this.
Now we start off air.
I'm going to say baton here.
So whichever element has the name Para will be returned.
As the output.
So there are two paragraphs which are having the same name.
So now we have seen that we have a get element by ID, get elements by tag name.
Get elements by class name and get elements by name method to find the element.
References.
Get element by ID is a kind of method which can only work with the document object.
You cannot say element dot and then get element by it.
Let's try this division here.
I'll say division is equal to I.D., for example, test.
So this is a test.
Division instead of document, you can have reference of that division only say for example, I'll get
const test division is equal to document dot get element by ID and you give the test here.
So now the T2 is the reference of this entire division.
Now what you can do, you can see, for example, let's say I change this method, I'll say get elements
by tag name, let's do that and I want to search for all the paragraphs.
Now, if you write this, it means it is going to search for all the paragraphs in a document.
Assume that you have one more division here, which again has one more paragraph.
Right.
This is a.
Next Division paragraph, for example.
Let's try this.
First of all, I'll just save this and refresh.
Now how many paragraphs you have?
You have the three paragraphs of the first division, right?
And the fourth paragraph of the next division.
We have four elements that are done by this method.
Now, instead of document, I'll just say T do, d do, which represents the first division.
So in this case, what will happen if I refresh and click on this?
Now it represents only three paragraphs.
The reason is we have applied the method on element.
So you can always have element art.
That means in this case D do, but the element which are element you have that dot the get elements
by tag name by class name or even by name.
Matter though by name doesn't make much sense, but get element by ID is a kind of method which is always
applied with documents.
So you are always going to write like this document out get element by 80.
If you write element dot get element by ID, it is invalid.
So these are a few get element by that is tag class or even IED and name.
These matters help you to get references of the elements from a document.
The reason behind getting a reference is because like we tried to change the content of iTunes.
So from JavaScript, when you are trying to change something inside the JavaScript section, you need
to have reference of those HTML elements, and that's where these methods are useful.
Now let's discuss relative questions of this topic.
The first question is can you use document dot, get element by ID and element dot get element by I.D.
The get element by ID with document is possible, but with element it's not possible because the searching
of element by ID is always for the entire document and not for a specific region.
The second question is what does the get elements?
My tag name return the get elements buy tag name returns the array of elements.
Like this.
We tried the example and it return all the paragraphs of the document.
The third question is what is the difference between get elements by blast name and get elements by
name?
So the class name and name are different methods.
The class name refers to the class of an element, whereas the elements by name refers to the name which
is given to the element.
Remember, never get confused with ID and name because name can be a duplicate value.
But in case of ID, you should never keep a duplicate I.D..