So in this section we are going to try one more exercise about Adi.
There are two ads, for example, like this one you have at a one and added two.
Both are numeric added, but they can be of any data type.
The exercise is about finding the intersections.
That is all the values which are present in both the ads.
And the second question with this exercise is finding union of two ads.
Now, when I say intersection, that means values which are present in both.
The ad is so in this case it will be eight and two, which is present in both the ad.
So that is the intersection.
And if I say union, that means it's about all these elements.
That is one, three, five, two, seven, eight, nine and ten, of course.
But in case of union, it should not repeat the value.
That means eight and two should not come multiple times.
So let's try to practically implement.
We have many ways again to do the same thing, but we are going to try more of the E6 we the shortest
way to find the intersection and the union as well.
We will begin with the intersection.
So here we already have these two ads that is added one and added two.
Now I'm going to declare another ad which is going to have the intersection values.
The important point here is I'm going to use added one.
Dart filter matter inside the filter.
You already know that there are two parameters.
One is the value, and the second is index number.
I'm going to take the value here.
And here I just want to return the value only if that value exists in the attic.
So I can use the includes method and I can see why this means each value is passed to this V and that
we are checking with.
Added to that is if that value, this value which is of everyone existing in added to then it should
be returned.
Otherwise it should not be returned.
So now all values of additive and if exist in additive, then only it will be part of every intersection.
The only thing you will have to do now is you just display the adda intersection to see whether we have
the intersection values or not.
So if I click here, we have eight and two.
These two values are also present in added to.
All right, so this is a very easier way to deal with intersection.
Now let's talk about union.
As I mentioned in the beginning that when you find a union, that means it should find all the values.
So actually, you can say that the ATI Union should have all the values.
Let me just change this to add a union.
Now it should actually have all the values.
That means I can use the spread operator.
I can say Dada Dot.
They are one that is added one and added two as well.
If you do this, then it actually joins both the ads.
But the problem will be that it's going to join all the elements where eight 2 to 8 is actually a repeat
value.
This is something we do not want.
When you say union, it does include all the values, but any value which is existing in first and second
area should appear only once.
Now you can use the logic to check if it exists.
Then you push it to the ADI so you have various way to do that.
But I did promise you that we are going to see the shortest way and with the E6 we.
So I'm going to use the set that is the set collection here because set is something which keeps unique
values only.
So here I'm going to say new.
Let me just use the spread operator here first.
I'll say new.
You can certainly check the set and map category for getting more information about this functionality.
So I'm going to say new set and inside the set I'm going to pass these ads.
So set will make sure that it creates a unique value collection.
These two areas are passed inside of these set, and then I'm going to close it.
Let's run this now.
You already have two elements here.
I'll keep it as it is.
Not clearing this and running it again.
There you are.
Now you see, there are only ten elements.
So this is how you can get the union of two eddies.