Now I'm discussing query selector enquiry selector all method.
There will be three related questions to this dormant web category topic.
The way we have get element methods which search elements using their I.D., name tag, etc. that is
also graffiti selector methods which search using the CSA selectors.
There are two such methods commonly used and one must know as a JavaScript developer, and these two
methods are gratis selector and gratis selector.
All the query selector method returns the first element that matches a specified CSA selector inside
the method.
Given as an argument, it searches in the entire document instead of the first element.
If you want all the elements, then you can use the query selector all method.
Let's see a practical example for both the methods.
I'm going to refer the same code which we have seen by learning the get element methods.
So this was the code where we have the division.
I'm just going to remove this additional thing.
We don't want it even this name.
Now we have one paragraph with Class A and Edge three as class A though there is no such class, but
that's fine at the moment.
Now I'm declaring a variable called I'll say element and document or query selector.
Now I want all the elements where the class name is a so I'm going to say dot e when you do this, it
is going to search in the end document and it will get the first element where this condition matches.
So let's try to display the element only at the moment.
I'll just save this and let's try what is the output?
So now you see that the enter element is return.
And this paragraph, the one which is having the third value, is the first element which satisfies
this condition.
Now insert of this query selector.
If I simply give, all right, now, it doesn't matter whether I change the name or not, but let's
say elements even we keep element.
That's also fine, but we declare more meaningful variables.
Let's go back to the browser and just refresh and I click the button.
Now it has returned two elements.
Both are having the class A so we have beat out an edge three dot E So the query selector and selector
all both the methods are very useful when you have to search to document and find the elements on the
basis of CSS selector.
You can also use these pseudo classes, say for example, instead of dot e, you will have.
However, it means that all the elements which are having the pseudo class hover will be returning to
the elements.
Variable Graddy selector is also a very useful search method though all these DOM search methods are
less in use as Dom searching and DOM manipulation is very well handled nowadays by JavaScript frameworks
like React, JS, Angular or even Vue.js.
But still as a JavaScript developer, you should know what all methods you have to search through the
DOM.
Let's discuss the relative questions of this topic.
The first question is explain the difference between grade selector and query selector all.
So we have already seen that the query selector returns the first matching value, whereas the query
selector all will return all the elements.
The second question is how can you search elements using pseudo classes?
So the query selector or query selector all both the methods you can use to search the elements through
pseudo classes like this one.
For example, you want that all the elements with whoever class, whoever pseudo class should be returned.
Then you can write this statement.
The third question is between get element by methods and gratis selector matters, which is better to
use.
Now, that's a tricky question, actually.
The reason is when you see that element by all the methods have like for example, get element by ID
is one of the most perfect method to search a specific element.
But when it comes to the class name or maybe selectors, then query selector matters are equally useful.
As long as the performance is concern, you will get better result with get element by it kind of method.
But as long as other get element by methods are concerned, they also loop through the same document
and the query selector also does the same thing when more differences query selector was introduced
at a later stage.
So Internet Explorer eight, that is IEEE eight and above will definitely work with query selector,
but below IEEE eight.
That is a problem while using it.
So you need to take care of this when you are using the query selector methods.