Before I talk about events with a web component, it's essential to know the concept of life cycle methods
or callbacks.
As we have seen the constructor method getting called automatically when the component is initialized.
There are other methods getting called automatically on different phases of a web component if you give
them.
In fact, when I say lifecycle of a component, it means from components initialization.
Attaching to Dom.
Modification in between.
Til it gets removed from the dom.
When the component is initialized, the constructor method is invoked.
Next step component gets attached to the documents.
Dom and at that time the connected callback is invoked.
When the custom element is disconnected from the documents Dom, the disconnected callback is invoked
during the existence of component.
If an attribute is added removed or even value changed, then the attribute changed.
Callback method is invoked.
When the component is moved on, a new page or a document, then adopted callback is invoked which is
very rarely used.
Let's practically check one such method connected callback.
This method, as I mentioned, gets executed or invoked when the component or custom element is connected
to the DOM.
So let's write this method.
Remember, it is a predefined method.
So the name should be exactly the same here after the constructor.
I will say connected callback.
And let me just have a console.log here.
I'll say console.log.
Method called.
Let's save this and run the code.
As you can see, the message method call is displayed four times.
Reason is for each component.
The connected callback method is automatically called when it is attached to the DOM.
Before moving further.
I will just rename the attributes with lowercase.
Otherwise it does not work in some cases when we make the components more dynamic.
So let me just say B status in small case.
And accordingly I'll change the p name and P image as well.
Let me also go to product card JS and here also I will change the attribute with the lowercase.
And we are done with this small change.
Now we will extend the discussion of the web component by adding events to it in the next lecture.