In this JavaScript language category, we are discussing one more question related to functions.
The question is how does a closure work in JavaScript?
There will be two related questions.
So let's begin.
Ideally, when a function comes under another function, a closure is created.
Closure button remembers outer variable and also helps to access outer scope members.
These terms might sound a little confusing, but as we go on, you will have a clear idea on it.
We will start with a simple example.
I will create a function called output and another function I am creating is in it.
Let's try to display some value, let's say inner card.
Now, if I want to call this function outside the outer function, this is not possible.
The reason is outer function we have in the current scope.
But inner is actually the child of outer.
So even if you try to call this function outside outer, it won't be possible.
Let's check this.
What actually happens?
As you see that it gives an error.
It says that inner is not defined because the current scope for inner function is inside the outer.
In any case, if you want to call this, you might write the inner function here.
So what happens that when you call the outer function, it is going to call the inner and that will
give you the output.
Let's say I run the call and yes, it does execute.
There is also another way to call the inner function here.
Let's try that.
In previous question, we discussed about function expression also.
It will be somewhat like function expression and removing this inner.
And what will I do is I will return the reference of inner function.
Remember, I'm not writing parentheses here.
Instead, I'm just seeing that I want to return that inner function and that function I can take in
a variable called C, l, which is actually a constant.
It is an object and I call the outer function.
Now what outer does is outer calls the function and it returns the inner function to c l so you can
see in other words, it is something like this that commands to c l is equal to function inner like
or function expression.
So now you can call this inner function using seal, isn't it?
The same thing is happening then this line number seven is executed.
Now I'm going to call the function c l.
Let's run and see what happens now.
Now the inner function is called.
So what have we done here?
We just try to return the inner.
So inner was actually a private member, but we returned it in such a way that it can have access outside
the outer functions school.
The same thing you can write without a name as well.
Like you can remove this name and even you can remove this return statement.
We can say that I'm going to return the anonymous function.
I can see the return here.
This is also a valid syntax.
Return, that is.
So if I run, it's going to be the same.
You can also try the ES6 syntax that is arrow function with this entire code.
Let's convert this into E6.
I'll say output is equal to we don't need function here.
We don't even need the name here.
I'll put an arrow here.
In this return also, we won't need the function.
And again, an arrow.
If you compare the previous or this score, at least for this execution, that is no change.
The output is going to be the same.
But now we are using the S6 index.
So these are the different ways of writing the same thing.
But this returning the function is important to know.
Now, in the beginning, I mentioned that the closure pattern can remember outer variables.
How is it?
So let's check with an example.
I'm going to create a function called add counter where I have a counter zero and then I try to increment
the value of counter and I want to return the counter.
Let's also put a console.log.
And because this function is returning the counter, I'm just going to call the function.
So every time a console.log is executed with our counter, it's going to add the counter and it should
give me the new reserve.
That's what I'm expecting.
Let's run this as you see the output every time it sees one.
The reason is when you call the function, it's going to re initialize this counter with value zero
and then we increment it and we return.
So zero one is added and we return the counter.
So every time we are going to get the same result.
Now if you want that every time it should be added.
Then what you can do?
You can put this variable about all the functions.
That is, you can make it global variable.
But imagine that you do not want to make this variable global and still you want that the output should
be 1 to 3 and so on.
How can you do this?
So this can be achieved using a closure?
If we create an inner function, we can make a private variable counter act as a global variable.
Let's implement this.
I'm going to say return.
So the function I'm returning.
Remember that I'm using arrow functions in text, but it can be the traditional way.
Also doesn't matter.
I'm just putting these statements inside the inner function and here what will I do?
I'll say const closure is equal to ad counter and instead of calling the add counter, I'm going to
call now the seal.
That is the inner function.
You name it, whatever you want to.
It's just a simple function.
This is what the code is.
Now I will run and see what is the output.
Now you see that we have one, two and three.
So in the beginning I mentioned that you can make local variables act as a global variable, which you
see that it happens here.
What exactly is happening?
This function, which is the inner function of ad counter?
Certainly this counter variable for this function is a global variable because the counter is above
the inner function, because this is a global variable for inner function.
Every time it increments, it is going to keep the value in the JavaScript environment.
In fact, that is something like this environment.
It's a variable which keeps the detail of current environment.
So the variable is stored there and every time we call S.l, we are going to get the new value.
So now the value is not reset.
It is the previous value.
It remembered the value.
So ideally, when you use closure, that means you are making the private members globally available
but with a cause.
Right?
You should have some idea why you do it.
Not every time you put closure.
Closure is useful when you have a few private members which you do not want.
That outer function should access you keep it private and only when needed.
Only in few situations you write a closure and you make the value global this way.
Let's discuss about the related question.
The first question is how can you access private variable or a function outside of the scope?
So we can do that using closure.
We have already seen earlier that we return the function without parentheses and we can achieve it.
The second question is explain the advantages of a closure.
Now, this is a very important question.
You should have a clear idea about what a closure is, how we could achieve a few things, how we could
achieve accessing of global variable that you can explain.
That is the main advantage of closure is that any member, which is private for certain scope, can
be accessed, keeping it private so that the variable is away from any accidental change of value.
Accessing private members with a closure pattern.
A sure better approach of making a variable global.