Now let's talk about the event handling.
We want to implement a functionality where when the button is clicked, it should update the status
from not sold to sold.
Now this is where we use the connected callback method.
Here I will say this dot shadow route dot query selector.
I'll say button dot on click.
Is equal to arrow a function.
Now, let's say console.log.
Button clicked.
Let's save this and check the output on click off buy button.
It says button clicked.
So on click of the button.
The event is getting fired.
Of course, this isn't what we want.
We need to update the status.
So let's do it back to the code.
Let's remove this console log.
Now on click of this button.
We have to change the status from not sold to sold.
You can directly write this dot shadow route dot query selector.
And I'm going to change the paragraphs.
I'll say P here.
Dot inner text is equal to soul.
Let's save this and check the output.
I'll click here on the buy button.
You see that it changes the status.
But this is not the right way.
It is updating on the interface, but the status actually is unchanged.
The status attribute is unchanged.
Ideally, we should change the property.
That is the attribute of the component.
So it should be component dot set attribute or element dot set attribute.
So instead of this inner text line.
I will say this dot set attribute in the brackets, the property, the attribute we want to change is
p status and we want to change it to soul.
So I will say sole.
Now.
Let's save this.
Now let's click on the buy button.
And you see that it stopped working.
It is not changing the status.
In fact, the attribute is changed.
But we need to render the changes.
We need to update the interface when there is a change in the attribute that is attribute added, removed
or modified.
That is an attribute changed callback method which gets executed.
So let's add that also here, I'll say attribute changed callback.
Now in the matter, there are three parameters passed.
The first parameter is the attribute itself.
So I'll say attr.
The second is the old value of the attribute.
And the third is new value, which is passed in the method parameter.
Now, let's say alert.
Here, I'm going to display the attribute itself.
So at year.
I'll put a plus sign to join.
Again the old value.
Let me also have another plus sign and the new value.
Let me change this to single quotes.
Well, it doesn't make any difference.
Let me also add a comma in the codes.
Let's save this.
And now I'll click on the buy button.
But you can see that it is not working.
That is one static method which we need to add to make it working.
So here I will say.
Static get observed attributes.
Now this is a method which basically returns an array of all the attributes which you want to keep a
watch on.
At the moment, the system, the component is not watching any attributes.
So regardless of what changes you make to attributes, it's not going to update it.
But if you want that the attribute change callback event should be executed, then you need to put the
observed attribute method.
Here I'm going to say return.
Inside this you always have to return an array of the attributes which you want to keep a watch on.
At the moment we just want to keep a watch on the status.
So I'll say P status.
That is the attribute we want to watch.
Let's save this and refresh.
And you can see the first time itself, the attribute changed, callback is executed and that's the
reason why you see p status.
That is the attribute name null is the value, initial value and then it is changed to not sold because
at the time of component first time loaded at the design time, that is we have added the component
with this attribute not sold.
Let me click okay four times because this is executed for each component.
So here in this method we will update the interface.
So new value is a value which we are going to assign to the inner text of the paragraph.
So here I'll say this.
Dot Shadow root dot query selector p.
Inner text is equal to new value.
Let's save this and now refresh.
Now click on Buy Button and we have the status updated.
Now this approach still has scope of improvement.
We can use the getter and setter methods for defining attributes, but that we will see in the forthcoming
lectures.
In the next lecture.
At the moment, we are going to add the delete the trash button for each component.
Now let's talk about related questions.
So the first question is what is observed attributes, methods, functionality?
Well, if you do not put this method, the attribute changed callback event is not executed.
That event, that lifecycle method is ideally executed when there is a change addition or removal of
an attribute.
But if you have not listed out the array inside observed attributes, then that particular attribute
will not be watched by the component.
So if you do not give this method, you won't be able to execute the attribute change callback for each
attribute.
The second question is when will the attribute changed callback method be invoked?
Well, any attribute change or addition of the attribute or any removal of attribute will make a call
to this attribute changed callback method, provided that attribute is configured in the returning array
of observed attributes method.
How can you improve rendering with the help of attribute changed callback?
Well, this is just a discussion where we already have old value and new value you can see in the code.
Now, if you do not want to call this P in a text unnecessarily when there is no value change, you
can put an if condition before this.
You can compare the old and new value.
If that is a change, then you can update the interface.
Otherwise you can skip it.
That is just a way to make sure that you avoid unnecessary interface updates.
That's how you can improve the rendering of component.