Now we are discussing this question where how can some five six return 11?
Ideally, you see that five comma six.
That is, we pass parameters in single set of parentheses, but here we have two different parentheses.
So how can we have 11 in this kind of function call?
The category of question is again JavaScript language, and there will be three related questions.
All right.
So this way is actually called as cutting.
Cutting is supported by many programming languages.
It's a unique way to call inner functions, where you can pass arguments partially or pass multiple
arguments in a function, but one argument at a time.
Now, this statement, which I mentioned, might be confusing, but you will be clear with this in just
a moment.
For example, when we see some five, comma, six, if this returns 11, it is logical.
But how about some you have five and six.
This returns 11.
It means that here we have two arguments, but here we have one argument at a time.
We will begin with exploring the carrying syntax and the basic steps.
Make sure you have gone through arrow function and closure related sections before you proceed further
with this explanation.
I'm going to create a code where I implement the same thing, which I mentioned in the question.
We are going to write function.
Then we will see what is the practical use of cutting?
Here I am writing a function called sum.
Now the function has one parameter pass to it and that is an inner function which takes the second argument.
That is one argument only as such.
But at the end of this function, that is the inner function, it returns A-plus.
B Now almost the same pattern we have already seen while discussing closure in a question.
So here, if I just write, let's say closure only at the moment where I'll say sum.
Now if I pass five here, it means in the first function that is this function.
This file is pass to E.
The next thing is because now this seal has a reference of this function that is inner function.
Because when we call the sum function five is passed to E, and then this function also returns another
function so that is assigned to seal.
Now if I say c l, that means I am going to call this second function.
So I will say c l I'll create a variable.
Constant answer is equal to c l.
Now that inner function is also taking one parameter.
So let's say I passed six here when I write these two lines.
It means that this function is this one that is we are calling this function.
And when you are calling line number seven, you are actually calling this function.
This means six is passed to B and then it should return A plus B.
So the answer five plus six is assigned to this end as variable.
That is answer.
Let's try to display and see what is the output.
I'll save this.
And the me scurried out just so I run it here.
Now you see that we have 11 as output.
This means the first function that is the pattern function is called and it has returned the inner function
and that is stored in the lexical environment in JavaScript.
And then we are calling it now the same thing we can write with some change in the syntax, and that's
where coding actually shows its own strength.
What we can do is we can call this inner function like this only.
So instead of writing some file, I can add another parentheses and I can say six here.
Now, this also means that I am calling the pattern function and I am calling the child function.
So pattern function is called and that returns this function also, right?
This inner function that is stored in the lexical environment.
And then eventually all these statements which we see here are called one by one.
So ideally, if you write like this, let's say I'll remove this line now instead of C, a better right
answer here saving it.
Let's check the output once again and see what happens.
It still says the output is 11.
The reason is this some is calling the pattern function.
And the second parentheses, which we have given here, actually calls the inner function.
This is the carrying pattern.
We will go to the advantage of carrying.
But before that, the syntax which I have used right now is a kind of s five syntax.
Of course I have use const that is off e6, but this function is of this weekend.
Right.
Arrow functions.
So let me convert this same code into arrow function.
As you all know that we do not need the function keyword and we put an arrow here.
So let's first of all do that.
We do not need the function keyword and I'll put an arrow here.
I'll save this and check whether this thing is working fine or not.
Yes, it does work.
Now, we also discussed in arrow function question that we can avoid these brackets if we have a single
line.
So for the output function, this is just a single line.
And for the inner function, this is the single line.
So we don't need to write the return statement.
What if I do that?
See this now and remove this bracket and remove the return?
Also, the first function is set.
Now let's go to the inner function.
We don't need the return statement.
Also, that's it.
We can also avoid these parents as we have just one parameter.
So I can write just A and B.
I'll save this.
I run it here.
Amazing, isn't it?
Now we just have a single line.
So looking at this line, if you have no exposure with inner functions are carrying.
This is very confusing that you have two arrows here.
Right.
What does this mean?
See, when you have two arrows, that means you have one inner function.
One is the pattern function.
Every arrow after the first arrow is the inner function.
Imagine that you have three arrows.
That means you have two inner function.
That is parent, child and grandchild.
That kind of pattern you will have.
This is just about the syntax, but cutting is implemented here.
But the question is, what is the practical use of it?
For that, I'm going to create a piece of code where we are calculating product price and discount calculation.
First of all, let's say I create a function called price calculation.
Now, this function takes price as a parameter.
And inside of this I'm defining discount percentage.
Now I'll explain what exactly I'm doing.
Once you see the output and here, what I'm going to do is I'm going to return the calculated discount.
That is the discount amount return.
If I just give you one example, let's say discount amount calculation I want every time I pass price,
let's say I have a function which is going to get the product price from some API.
And that price, once I have received here that I want to pass in discount amount.
But first case I want to pass, let's say 3% discount.
In second case, I want to pass 5% discount.
So there are various percentage you are going to pass, but this price remains same.
Now I'm giving one example where we have just single value, but there can be multiple parameters you
want to pass with only one different value.
This is where currying can be useful.
Let me show you that.
Let's say we have this discount amount as a function.
I'm not having any get price function at the moment.
So we assume that there is a fixed price called 300.
So I'll say cons to discount amount is equal to the price calculation.
I'm going to call that I'm passing just one value that is 300.
Now this trio.
Imagine that we received my get price that is calling some API and we are getting this data.
So discount amount becomes a function which is going to return various discount amount depending on
the percentage.
But the price will remain 300 only.
Let's try this in console.log.
I'll save discount amount.
See this now?
I'm not passing any price now price is already given only once in the beginning this is carrying.
I mentioned earlier that you are calling the function partially this is what it is.
So we say discount amount which is going to return the discount amount.
You can take it in some other variable and process it.
But at the moment I just want to say 0.5, that is 50%, five or 50, whatever.
I want to have 50%.
So that's 50%.
Now again, I put another discount amount.
When I just say 30%, again, I say I want to have 20%.
So now every time you call this discount amount, you are going to get percentage depending on the price
which you earlier called.
So the same thing is getting called here.
That is price.
Kelsey is called here, but every time you call discount amount, you're going to get the discount amount
depending on this price.
Let's save this and run the code.
As you can see now that every time this is called, we have different values.
So this is where cutting can be used.
This is one simple situation.
There can be multiple parameters you have.
We just have price here.
There can be multiple parameters and only one parameter is changing.
So what you do is you just pass those parameters here once, which will return the inner function and
rest of the partial execution is done by the return function.
This is the advantage of cutting.
Now let's discuss the latest questions of this topic.
The first question is what is function carrying?
So carrying is basically calling it partially.
We have the inner function returning the function where we use this, some function like this, or we
can have some advantage of using it in this way about we just call the main function once and then the
rest of the functions are called again with different values.
The second question is what will this statement do?
Explain in detail.
So this when you see this statement, it means you have one main function, then inner function, and
inside that you have one more inner function like this, and that has a written statement.
So in a way this is function carrying only, right?
But with one more inner function then we saw earlier and it is going to return the multiplication of
whatever value you pass.
The third question is explain practical usage of function carrying.
Well, carrying is an incredibly useful technique of functional programming which solves various purposes
like parsing partial parameters or avoid unwanted reputations.
Like we tried with product price, where price was passed only once.
So it is very useful in such cases.