Let's add the delete functionality in our component.
For that, I'm going to add a button.
I'll say button here.
Let me also give the class BTN and ID trash.
Now I'm going to add an icon here.
Let me also end it now with Icon.
I'm going to say class FAA that is found awesome.
And I'm going to use the FAA trash hyphen.
Oh, let me also give an ID icon and now I'm ending the button tag as well.
The next step, I'm going to paste the font.
Awesome link.
Now let me also update some CEUs related to this button.
Now let's check the output.
And the button is getting displayed with the trash icon.
Now the next step is to bind the event inside connected callback.
So I'm going to say this dot shadow route dot get element by ID.
The idea I'm going to choose is trash dot on click.
Is equal to.
I'm going to have the arrow function now inside this.
I just want to remove the components.
I'll say this dot remove.
It means the instance.
The current instance will be removed.
Let's save this and check what happens.
Now I'm going to click this button and you can see that it is getting removed from the DOM also.
Now when the component is removed, it is actually being removed from the DOM and at that time the disconnected
callback method is invoked.
Let's check that practically.
So I will add disconnected callback.
I'll say the method name.
And inside let me just say alert and here I'll say this dot get attribute.
I'm going to get the name of P name that is the product name.
Let me join that with component removed.
Now let's save this and check the output.
I click on the delete and you see that the grapes component removed message is displayed.
The reason is this alert is written inside the disconnected callback and when you remove it from the
DOM, that event is invoked.
That lifecycle method is invoked.
Normally inside this disconnected callback, you can write the code you want to run at the time of detachment
of the component from the DOM.
For example, if you add an event with add event listener method, then you can write remove event listener
in disconnected callback to check that practically.
Let me just remove this on click and instead of that I'm going to use the add event listener.
This is another way to attach the event.
I'm going to open the parentheses.
The first parameter in the parentheses will be click.
This is the event name.
Now I'll put a comma here.
Let me remove this bracket at the moment and this equal to sign as well.
And I will close it here as a second parameter.
So the function is the second parameter.
On click this function will be executed.
So now the event is configured with the add event listener.
When this is the situation, what you can do is you can write the remove event listener inside the disconnected
callback so that you clear the environment.
You clear the garbage when the component is removed.
Let me just copy this and paste it inside the disconnected.
And here I'll just say dot remove event listener.
Let's save this and refresh.
Now when I click on the trash button, the disconnected event is executed.
And when we close, it actually clears the event for that particular component.
So this is just the basic idea of disconnected callback method.
Let's talk about questions.
So the question is explain the purpose of disconnected callback lifecycle method.
So this method is basically executed when the component is getting removed from the DOM.
So normally the code which is related to garbage collection or the code which you want to execute at
the time of removal of the component from the DOM that you configure inside this method.