In this domain web category section we are discussing mouse event object.
There will be four related questions to this topic.
Now we are focusing on various mouse related events.
We have already seen a click event in the previous section.
Let's try a few of the events practically.
First we will see Click, Right Click and the double click event.
At the moment I have created one division and just a function.
The division has an ID that is the E and I have taken the reference and I'm assigning the message to
this division.
Let me also show you the output quickly.
This is how it looks.
Now I'm going to configure the click, double click and the right click event to write it in a more
clear way.
I'm going to write each unit on a next line.
So this closing of division, I'm going to bring it on new line here.
I'm going to say on click.
And the function I'm calling is the E handler function that is event handler.
So I write E handler here and I'm going to pass a message that click the message which is passed to
this function that I will write here at the moment.
Let's say remove this.
I don't need a message here.
So whenever an event is clicked, that is a specific string I'm passing to this message and this message
is assigned to the division.
Let's configure rest of the events.
I will say on.
Context menu.
Now, this is an event which is executed when the user presses the right mouse button.
So here also I'm going to call the event handler function and here I will pass right click.
And the next event is on double click.
Again, I'm going to say event handler and here I'll pass double click.
So every time when an event is fired, we are passing the respective string and that we are displaying
in the division.
Let's try with these three events.
First, I'm saving this.
Now let's go to the browser.
I'll just refresh these changes.
Now, if I click here, you see that the click event is fired.
When I right click, as you can see that the right click message is displayed and also the context menu
items are also displayed.
And if I double click here, then it displays double click.
So on context, menu item is also one of the event which you can use to handle the right click.
Imagine that you want to disable that right click on this particular element that is on this division.
You don't want to have the right click.
What you can do, you can simply return.
False.
I'll say.
Return false.
So this will cancel the event.
In fact, this can happen to any event.
Let's say you want to cancel the mouse down event or maybe mouse up event, then you can just return
false.
So that related event is not executed.
So now for example, I right click then I do not see the context menu or the event is not executed at
all.
If you click, you have this event here and double click also has the event.
So these are the click events.
Now let's try the mouse down and mouse up event as well.
So here instead of on click, I'll say on mouse down and here I'll say on mouse up.
Now I'm going to change the messages and just leave this as it is.
And this last event, let's say I do not want it, so I'm going to remove that here.
I'll say mouse down and here, mouse up.
Let's go to the browser refresh.
Now I'm holding down the mouse key.
You see it says Mouse down.
The moment I release it, it says mouse up.
So you have two more events like this, mouse up and mouse down.
Apart from this mouse up and down, there are various events on mouse movement as well.
I'm just going to discuss two events that is mouse out and mouse over.
There are also mouse enter, mouse live and various events you see related to mouse, but they are easy
to understand.
So let me just discuss two events here.
I will say mouse out and here, mouse over on, mouse over.
I'm going to call this.
So this function is called when you roll rollover on this division.
So let me just save this and go back to the output and refresh.
You see, now mouse over is constantly getting executed, right?
The moment I move the mouse out of the region, it says mouse out so you can handle the mouse more events
as well.
With the event object, we have various properties, few of the properties we have discussed in previous
section as well.
So now we are discussing one more useful property that is event dot button.
And for that, what I'm going to do, I'm not going to pass any string here.
Instead I'll declare this MSE that is the variable and instead of on mouse out let me just have only
one event that is on mouse up and I'm going to call the event handler, but without any parameters.
We don't need any other events.
So I'll remove this now when the mouse button is released, then the event handler is fired.
Here, I'm going to put a condition that if event dot button if the button is let's to the value is
zero, that means the left mouse button is pressed so I can say a message is equal to left button pressed.
Similarly, I can put more conditions.
I can say elseif event dot button is equal to one.
That means the middle button, the will button is pressed so I can see message is equal to middle button
pressed and if the value is the value of button property is two, that means right click is pressed.
So I'll say right click or right button.
That's it.
So now we will check the output.
I'll just refresh mouse up, will update the data.
So here you see that left button is pressed.
If I just hold down the right click and release it, you can see that it is right button is pressed
so the button property is very useful when you want to check that which button was pressed apart from
the button press, there are also various key values available.
For example, you want to check whether any special key was pressed while a specific mouse event was
executed.
That is special keys like alter control shift, etc. So let's try that as well.
So with event we do also have all the key which will return.
True.
So I can write like this.
I can say if event dot alt key if this was true so I can write like this or I can simply say all key.
That means it is by default.
It is true.
So this will check.
If it is true, then let's say in message.
I want that I want to display the key press was alter key or I want that if the key was, let's say
control key, that means Ctrl key.
If that was true, then the message will be Control Key was pressed.
Similarly, you can check for shift key.
Also, let me just quickly copy this thing and here I am going to say shift if shift.
She was pressed.
Then I'll say, shaped.
Now when the mouse up is executed.
It will also check whether there was any key pressed or not.
Right.
Let's see here.
By default, I say no key.
Let's refresh now.
Now, when mouse up is fired, there is no key press.
Now I'm holding down the control key and I'm releasing the mouse.
So you can see that the Ctrl is displayed.
Similarly, if I say shift and if I just release the mouse, you see that it says shift and for alter
it will display the LG.
So while an event is fired, if you are willing to check whether any special key was pressed or not,
you can write like this.
You also have a choice in this.
For example, I want to check whether control and alter if both were pressed.
Then I want to have some code which is to be executed.
You can join that as well.
For example, I can say if event dot, let's say alt key was pressed and at the same time he went dark
next to the control key.
Ctrl key was also pressed.
Then I want to display a message that there are two keys pressed.
I'll say alter plus control.
Something like this.
I forgot the strings.
Right.
So now let's try this also.
Now I'm holding down both alter and control and executing mouse up.
So it is able to see as long as the control keys concern on the Mac machine, you have the command button
right instead of control.
So far Mac machine, you also have the matter key.
That is, you write like this.
If you have an if condition, for example, then you write event not matter key like this.
So this is going to check the command button on Mac machine.
So in that case, if you are dealing with the control keys for all the machines, your condition should
be something like this.
If event dark control key or event dark matter key, then you have some statements to execute.
You can write like this.
So Event Object has various properties like this when the mouse events are executed.
Event Object also gives you the coordinates that is x and y coordinates.
But that topic is for some other session as we have client x, y and PDX way.
So we are going to discuss the difference and then we'll try to implement it.
So now let's discuss a few related questions to this topic.
I mean, whatever we have discussed so far, we are going to get a few questions out of this.
The first question is how will you disable right click on an element?
So as we have discussed on the on context menu, we just right return false.
So that will disable the right click for that element.
Do also remember that generally when you disable the right click, that means you do not want someone
to copy the content.
I mean the end user.
As long as developers are concerned, they can open the view source and they can copy the source anyway,
but at least you can disable the right click that way.
So that is also one more event on copy that can also be redone, which disables the copy feature for
the element.
The second question is how can you check whether a special key that is all shift or control key is pressed
while an event is generated or not?
So we have already seen that we can use event dot ctrl key.
Shift key.
All key, matter key.
These are the various properties we have with event object which can be used to check the special key
status.
The third question is how do you check mouse button value while an event is generated?
So it's about checking which mouse button is pressed.
So we have the button property.
So we wrote Discord to check whether right, maybe left or middle button is pressed or not.
So you when that button can be used to check the mouse button value.
And the fourth question is for Control Key and CMT on Mack.
How will you write the condition to check the key press?
So this is the code which you can write with checks, CTRL, that is the control key and my keys for
the CMT.
But this code is helpful by writing the control or command button validation.