Now as such we are done with the component, but the code can still be improved.
One improvement, which I can think of here is using setter and getter method.
You can check the setter and getter method related lecture in the O'Jays section if you need to understand
the basics.
Here.
I am not adding the getter method, but let me add this setter method.
Instead of this set attribute, I will rather assign to a property of the component.
Let me bring this on new line.
Now I'm going to say this dot B status is equal to sold.
Now, important point is when the value is assigned to the property that is here, when the sole is
assigned to p status, that has to be the setter method which sets the attribute.
So now I am going to add one setter method.
I'll say set p status.
That is the property.
Inside this method, I am going to put the set attribute line.
And because it's a settled method, I need to have a value because there will always be the value passed
and the value passed should be assigned to the property.
So here I'm going to say, well, now this is the actual way.
You should also have a getter method.
But right now we just need to understand the concept.
Let's save this and check whether the functionality is still working or not.
I'm going to click on the buy button and you can see the attribute.
The value of the attribute is changed, but this time we are using the correct way.
That is using the setter method.