Let us see few console object methods that are related to time and timestamps in JavaScript code.
The code requires a specific time in executing.
We can set a timer in the JavaScript code that will display the time taken for execution.
But this time is not your set interval, not the timer in the actual code, but this timer is related
to the console.
This is also a timer only, but all the matters which we are going to see are related to the console
object.
The Controller time method sets a timer and takes a specific name or a label for that timer as a parameter.
The syntax is like this where you have the console, the time, and inside that let's say we give a
label timer when this is the timer start.
I will define two variables x and Y with their values and let's console.log x into y.
And then end the time using the console that time and.
And again provide a label of the timer that I want to end as it's parameter.
This statement will end the specified time.
Let me save this and.
As you can see, it displays the time taken for executing this piece of code.
This technique can be used when you want to check the response time of your code and manage it.
Another matter related to timer is cancelled out time log that provides the current value of the timer
set by using the console log time method.
Let me use the short time lag method here somewhere before it performs multiplication.
Now here I give the timer name and let me run the call.
So it displays the time of the timer when it reaches the line with this statement.
Let me run it twice.
And time varies.
Let us see related questions for this topic.
The first question is what does the console.log time method do?
So the canceled are time method set timer in JavaScript which returns the time taken by the code to
execute.
As we saw in this example here, the timer one is started and it stops when this console dart time and
statement is encountered.
The second question is how to check the current execution time.
So the console, the time lag method is used to check the current time.
That is time at a particular point where the statement is found.
Like we did here.
And it will vary every time we run.