In this section, we are discussing another important and commonly used character class or meta character
called Slash B.
It is used like anchors.
That is the carrot and dollar signs.
Let's begin with an example to understand it in an easier way.
I'm taking a variable here, SDR, where I say testing a test to testify.
Now let's create a pattern to search a word test.
So I will write the pattern test and try to print.
Using console.log.
Let's run the code.
So here on index zero, the test word exists and it is returned in the output.
Of course, we should search for all the test words existing in the string, so we will add the slash
g that is global search modifier.
So let's add slash g and run the code again.
Now we have all the test words existing in the entire string.
But here I want only those values which are complete words.
That is, I just want test word to be returned.
And as you can see, that is only one search word in the string.
Here comes slash B in rescue.
We are now going to apply the boundary for the word in pattern.
So the pattern will be slash B test and slash B.
Let's run the code.
Now you see that only one word satisfies the pattern.
Matching the slash B gives a boundary that a word should be test.
In case if I remove the last B, then it will search for all the words beginning with test.
Let's remove the second slash B and run to see the output.
So again, we have all the words starting with test in the output.
We can also apply the reverse logic.
Let's say we want to find all words ending with SD.
In that case, we can use pattern SD and slash B.
So in the beginning, I'm not giving slash B.
I'm adding one more word best before the word test in the string.
And run the code.
Now you see that there are two such words which end with the word SD.
You can also use the same pattern to find numbers.
For example, we want to search 45 in a string of digits.
Let's write the code for it.
I'll say let STR is equal to some numbers.
Now the pattern will be.
Slash be 45 and of course, the global search.
Let's try to console.log.
And run the code.
So now it has returned 45.
Of course, it is a string value which is searched and nothing numeric about it.
But let's say we want to find all values which are of three digits.
Here you can use the slash DX character class, which we have already seen in previous section.
In this case, the pattern will be I will use the slash B to begin.
Then I need three digits.
So I'll write slash the three times and I will have slash B at the end, which is the end of the boundary
that is three times slash d1/d for each digit and place between the slash B word boundary.
So now you have two such values, which are of three digits.
You can also search for values where you have the decimal place like 56.67 or maybe a dash between numbers
and so on.
There can be many combinations which you can think of.
So Slash B allows you to search with a boundary for a word.