In this section we are discussing about error handling in JavaScript.
There will be six related questions to this topic.
Error handling is one of the very important concepts in any programming language.
When you write the code, it may have errors at runtime.
In case if error appears, the program will break.
It will stop the execution in between.
Ideally, you should write the code with proper validations, but still there are some unforeseen situations
where the program breaks in between.
In such cases, the end user is stuck.
Ideally, what should happen is that when the program faces errors, even after validations, it should
handle it and notify the user with proper error details like add a number and description.
Enough of lecture.
Let's practically try a few codes here.
Say for example, I am writing let is equal to ten.
Then I'd say console.log.
I want to display the value.
Now here I select like B is equal to 50, but there is a space missing.
Again.
I say console.log and.
We display the value lecture on the call.
Now, as you can see, that the error is displayed.
The code is broken in between.
The code stops, the execution in between.
To handle this kind of situation where you do not face any error at the compile time.
But let's say at runtime, if you face any error, then you can use the try catch block.
The syntax of try catch block is like this.
So let's try the same thing here also.
I'm going to use the Tribe blog here.
Now I'm going to shift the call in the tri block and then we will have the catch.
And here I just display a message that added found the error object is always passed with the catch
block that we will see in a moment.
Let's run the code and see now what happens.
Now, as you can see, that it has displayed a message that the adder is found here.
The catch block has one parameter past, which is an object.
This we call as the added object.
This object also has properties like name, message or even stack.
Let's check all the properties here.
I will say console.log.
Added our name.
Edited out message and.
I did not stack.
Now let's run the code.
This displays the error name.
This is the error message and this is the error stack where it gives you the idea, the link of all
the codes executed.
Now, in this case, still the error is of the language that is the JavaScript language, and it is
generated by the system which you are handling using the tri catch block.
It might also happen that you have a validation in the program, a custom validation which should generate
the error.
In short, you want to generate or throw your own custom errors.
You have the true operator, which you can use to generate your own error.
The syntax is like this we use the true.
Then we have the error object where this added object can be of class error type error, syntax error
or any other predefined error.
Let's try this practically as well.
For example, we need to have age greater than or equal to 18.
If it is less than 18 then we want to generate a new error.
Seeing Edge added so I'll select a is equal to eight late age error.
Now this is going to be the object where I'll say equal to new error.
Error is the class from which this age error object is created.
Now I am going to put this code in try block.
I will say try if it is less than 18, I'm going to say throw edge added else I'm going to display a
message saying that it's a valid age.
Let's have the catch block and inside this I'll say console.log invalid age it.
Let's run the code and see what happens.
Now.
This is the new error raised by the true statement.
You can also pass error message inside the error class constructor.
Let's say instead of having this invalid age error here, I will pass a message saying invalid age,
but I'm passing it in the constructor of error plus and then I'm going to display error, not message.
Let's run the call.
Now you see that the next which we passed in the outer class is the message of this ad.
It instead of creating the object, you can directly use the true statement to generate an ad it.
Let's try a type error example.
Now I'm going to remove this age, add it through age error as well, and then I'll write here through
new type error.
And here I'm going to say invalid age.
It's just that we are writing everything with the inline syntax and we are not creating any new object
for this.
So I'll say throw new type error.
That's it.
Let's also add one more statement here.
Console.log.
Added dot name.
Now type error is a JavaScript error.
So we will get both the name and message together.
Let's run the code.
Here it is.
All right.
The way we have tried the trai catch block.
That is one more block which can be added with try, catch or even without catch.
And that is the final block.
The syntax is like this.
You can have the try statements, catch statements, and finally or even without catch, that is something
like this where we have try and finally block the code placed in the final block is executed at the
end of the block and it is always executed.
Let's try the same thing here.
I'm going to add it just to finally block here and writing finally code.
Now let's run the code.
As you see, that error is thrown.
But at the same time, after everything is done, the final block is executed.
So finally is something which we use when we have the finishing code.
Write the finalizing code.
At that time we use the final block code.
You can also put nested tri sketch if needed.
Like this.
Mostly try sketch is always handled at a specific code level.
It's not advisable to have a global tri sketch though all the code structures and programmers approach
vary, but generally we see that more and more validations we put in our program and then in some unexpected,
unforeseen situations we try to have the try and catch.
Sometimes we also see that we create an error log inside the catch block as well.
Let's discuss the relative questions of this topic.
The first question is when do you need try catch.
So try catch something.
Which of course, first of all is handled at runtime, right?
So when you see that the code executed is expecting some unforeseen situations, some portion of code
needs to be managed properly so that the program doesn't stop in between.
Then you use the try catch block.
It's all about handling the error without breaking the code execution.
The second question is how can you generate an error so you can generate your custom edit using this
true statement?
Right.
As I mentioned, error type error, syntax error, all these.
So you have your customer with the error plus like this one or the type error and syntax error or any
predefined JavaScript error class can also be generated using true statements.
The third question is, can you generate syntax error or reference error kind of predefined JavaScript
errors?
Yes, as I just mentioned, these are the predefined JavaScript errors, but you can use the true statement
to raise the JavaScript builtin errors as well.
The fourth question is what is the purpose of the final block?
So the final block contains the core, which is always executed.
Whether that is an error or that is no error in the code.
So if there is an error, the catch code is executed.
But finally, code is something which is always executed.
So finally contains code which does some finishing work or some code which ought to be executed.
We put it in finally block.
The fifth question is how can you refer to the name or description of added?
So inside the Cat blog, we have seen that this is the era object or whatever you name it inside this
that is always the added details past.
So you can say add a dot that is this object dot name or object dot message to get the name and description.
The sixth question is, can we have finally block without a catch block?
Of course we can have, not necessarily that we always have a catch block.
Now, when this kind of situation happens, let's say you have some piece of code where you just want
to let go with the added right.
You do not want the catch block to handle it.
And then finally is there to execute something so you can have like this try.
And finally, this is how you can write it without a catch block as well.