There are three more events on Uncut, on copy and on paste, which we can use with input elements.
There are two related questions with this topic, so let's start discussing it.
I'm again using the same layout where we have a text box and I have an H1 where I am displaying if that
is an event occurred.
So let's go to the coding.
We have this division here, some CSS as applied and also for input.
I have font size and margin.
Now here, what I have done is I have an input box, but I am going to configure the three events which
we are talking about.
So the first year and I am talking about is on cut event.
So I'll say on card, what I want to configure is I want to call the function E handler.
And inside of this I'm just passing that on.
Got fired or something like this.
The next event I'm going to configure is on copy and then on paste.
So let me just paste the event.
So I'll say on copy where I'm going to pass the string on copy and on based.
I will say on paste is fire.
That's it.
And we have this e handler where every string is passed, then the message is assigned.
Let's go to the browser and I refresh the screen.
Let's type.
This is a test.
Now I just select the test word and if I press control C then you can see that it says on copy.
If I just say control X, then the anchor is fired.
And if I press control V, the on paste event is fired.
This is a common practice that we have got paste and copy kind of actions for any text boxes.
We don't actually write anything to make it happen, but in case if we want to stop this cut, copy
or paste behavior, which is the default behavior of text box, we can stop that as well.
If you want that.
What you can do, let's say I do not want this guard event to be fired for this text box that is for
this element.
So when we is that I can say return false.
This will cancel this event or let's say in case of paste, I don't want that the paste should happen.
So another way is that the event object has a method called prevent default.
If I do this, then this will also stop the event execution.
This shows that the default event is prevented.
So two ways.
You have to stop the event execution.
Remember, you can cancel only those events which are cancel label.
There are few events which are not cancel label so you can't write return false for those events.
Let me just save this and I will refresh and again I'm going to type.
This is a test.
Now if I press control C, then the copy event is executed because we have configured it.
But if I just press control x here then there is no event executed.
Or even if I say control V, that also doesn't execute the UN.
So both the cut and paste events are stopped.
So it's easy to understand this cut, copy and paste event.
But this is a tricky one that how do we stop the event execution?
Let's discuss do questions of this topic.
Now the first question is just that.
Somebody may ask you what is a card event or how do you manage some code when something is copied in
the element or maybe based event?
Right.
So the question can be related to that.
So now you know that that is on copy on Carter on paste event which can be used, which can handle the
card.
Copy paste.
Action coding.
The second question is how can you stop an event of card copy are based for an element.
So the way to do it is like this that you return false either or you just say event or prevent default.
Then it will certainly stop that particular event to be executed for that particular element only.