The next method we are discussing is the match method.
Match method returns an array containing matched value all matching values in an array if slash g modifier
is given.
And null if that is no match.
The syntax is we apply the match method on the string and we give the pattern in the brackets of match
method as a parameter.
Let's try it practically.
I will again have the same string.
The pattern I'm using here is the word is, which we want to find.
Let's try to call the match method with console.log.
And run the code.
So at the moment there is only one word found in the output.
In spite of more is word existing in the STR variable.
And the reason is we have not given the g modifier.
So let's add and see the output.
Now we have all the words in the output.
Let's change the pattern from is to is and see the result.
So now the output is null because there is no match.
So we have seen that if there is one match found, then it returns this way.
If there were more than one matches, then it returns the error.
If the error with all the words matched and it returns null in this case where there is no match found
like the match method, we do also have match all method.
This method is an improved new version of match method.
It returns an iterator of all matching results.
Let's see the syntax we give the string then match all.
And here in the parentheses we give the pattern.
Let's try to apply match all practically to get a better understanding.
First, we will try to use this method with one of the simple codes we used with match method.
I'll declare the string variable.
Of course, I'm trying to find the word is with global modifier and I'll say match all.
Now you see that in the output we have regular expression iterator returned.
You can expand this iterator object and check the details, but we will try to make it more simple.
Let's take an iterator object and try to put the for off loop to see the output in a better way.
So we are keeping the first two lines of the code as it is.
Now I'm going to say const I object, which is an object is equal to string, dot match all.
And here I'm passing the pattern.
This returns and iterable object.
So I object becomes an object which has various items return by the match all method.
So I'll say for loop item off.
I object and I'll try to display each and every item.
Now you can see that each item contains the array, which has found word index and other details.
This also means we can use item and get the word or index separately as well.
Let's try to display words along with index value using the return iterator object.
So in this far loop I'll say console.log.
We already have an item which is an array.
So I'll say the zeroth element, which is the word itself.
I'm going to join it with a string, a constant that is found at now because it has an index number.
I'll say item or index.
Let's run the code now.
Now you see that we have the desired output in a more appropriate manner.
Match All is a newer and improved way of match method and may not work in all the browsers as it is
not working in all the browsers at the time of creating this tutorial.