The next method we are going to look at is the search method.
This method helps to check whether a pattern is existing in a string or not, and if exists, then it
returns the index number.
Let's see the syntax string dot search and we give the regular expression pattern.
This is a very simple method which searches for the first occurrence and returns the index number.
Let's practically see a code sample.
To understand this, we'll use this string variable, a pattern and console.log.
Let's run the code.
You see that the value is two.
That means on the second index number, second position that is zero one and two is is found.
Let's try to find a value which is not existing in the string we replace is with that in the pattern.
And let's run the code.
So now it returns minus one.
This means when and there is no match found, it's going to return minus one.