Now we are going to see one more method used with regular expression.
This method not only finds a value, but it replaces, so it does both fine and replacement functionality
together.
It returns a new string.
Let's check the syntax first.
In this syntax, the new string is a new string returned by the replace method.
After search and replace is performed on the string.
A string, which is actually a value in which you want to perform the search.
It takes two parameters, so you pass the search regular expression pattern or the search string itself.
And the second is the string you want to replace, which can be returned directly.
Or you can have a function which is invoked when the replace operation is performed.
At the end, it's going to return a new string.
So when you use the replace method, there are various combinations which you can try.
We are going to check each and every syntax one by one.
First, we will try a simple example without regular expression.
I'll say that SDR is equal to this method is working.
This is a string.
Of course I'm going to create a new string also where I say string struct replace.
I want to find the is word and I want to replace each is word with it.
Now let's try to display the value.
I'll say console.log new string.
Let's run the code.
As you can see, the first word which we had this.
Now it is converted into that because is is replaced with ADD.
Now, in the very same example, we will try regular expression pattern.
I will simply change is with a pattern and also apply the global modifier.
Let's run the code now.
So the pattern with the global modifier has done the job.
All the is words are now replaced with ET.
So the second is word is also changed.
Now we will see a very important way of using the replace method that is giving a function as an argument.
To understand clearly, we will change the code step by step in the existing code.
Let's try to first give a function instead of add.
Now let's define the function.
I will add a few arguments in the function.
Let's say A, B, and C, and also we will display all arguments.
Don't worry about what this A, B, and C should be or will be.
You will get it in a moment.
Let's examine the output.
First of all, there are two console log executed.
It means function r is called for each match found.
That is for this is and this is because there are two is matches found.
You can see two lines of output.
Here.
If we compare the output, then each argument is filled with some value automatically in function.
R Let's examine each argument.
A Is the search string or pattern that is passed as first parameter B is two or 12 shows the index or
position on which the word is found and C contains the actual or input string.
So by passing the function as an argument, it will automatically receive arguments.
There can be more arguments in the function if there are multiple search patterns.
So it is not necessary to have just three arguments.
For example, it can be function r you may have a BCD anything where each argument can have different
information pieces.
Those pieces where we have given A, B and C can have more meaningful names.
It actually looks something like this.
You have a function, let's say.
R The first parameter is the match.
Match is the matched substring.
Then you can have multiple parameters like P, one, p two up to p n.
These are the contents of captured group.
If that is any captured group available, then we have the offset.
That is the position of the match and of course we do have the input string as well.
So all the parameters are automatically generated when you give that function as an argument inside
the replace method, let's now try to print the value of new string.
Also, let's add console.log new string.
Now, if you see the output there is word is replaced with undefined and the reason is the function
r should return a value which will be a replacement of A's world.
So let's do that.
I will say return at.
Now let's run the code.
Now we have the desired output.
Of course, this code does not make much sense for a practical world example, but it is important to
understand the behavior of replace method with a function as a parameter.
We will be looking at more practical examples as we move on in this series of tutorial.