In this section we are going to discuss about capturing groups.
Capturing group is one of those concepts of regular expression where developers think to find the solution
online and paste it rather than understanding the workings or mechanism of it.
But I assure you that after going through this section, you would not only love the capturing group
concept, but you will realize that you can achieve very complex search and replace functionalities
using it.
Let's create a core sample and then we try to understand the whole concept.
I am declaring a string where I want to find a number, where number is divided into two parts, separated
with a dash like one, two, three, four, five, six, seven or 56789045.
Naturally, the pattern for the same will be slash D for a digit plus quantifier for one or more digits,
a dash and again slash D and plus sign.
Let's first achieve this programmatically.
I'll declare a variable where I say let string is equal to here.
Any number is to test the pattern will be slash D plus dash, slash D plus, of course, I'm applying
a global modifier as well.
I'll say console or log pattern dot exec that is XY and the string.
As you can see, the output, it found the number with a dash sign in the string.
But if I expand the error result, there is a zero and the found value, the zeroth element is containing
the entire pattern you want to search for.
At the moment there is no group defined using parentheses, and that means there is one default group
group number zero.
That is the entire pattern.
Now, without more discussion, let's create two groups in the search pattern.
I'm simply adding parentheses around slash D plus and running the code again.
Now you see zeroth element, which has the entire pattern.
First element shows the first group that is the first slash, the plus and second element shows the
second group that is the second slash D plus.
So when you give parentheses, it creates a group and each group can be accessed using a dollar sign
curly bracket.
And you put the group number N where PN is the group number.
Let's try it practically.
Assume that we want that number before and after we have that we want to swap.
So the code will be like this.
Let's try the replace method here.
So after the pattern, I'll say let new string is equal to string dot replace the pattern.
And here I'll say dollar to dash dollar one.
That means the second group should come first and the first group should go second.
That is after the dash.
Let's try to print the new string.
And run the code.
Now you can see that four, five, six, seven is shifted before the dash and one, two, three is shifted
after the dash.
Let's take a more practical example.
Imagine you have a string of names where you have first name and surname, for example, like this.
You want to bring the surname first with regular expression groups.
It is really easy.
The pattern will search for any word that is slash W having at least one value using quantifier plus.
So the search of any word we use slash W plus and that we put inside parentheses to make a group.
Then we use the replace method where we just mention that the second group will come first and then
the first group, of course to change the value.
I will also use the replace method, so let's write the code and see the output.
I'll say let string is equal to first name.
Putting a comma and surname the search pattern will be.
Parentheses and w plus again after comma I put the same.
Now I'll say string dot replace pattern.
Dollar to dollar one.
I'm not putting a comma inside the pattern.
This means initially the string we have is first name, comma, surname, but because we are replacing
it with dollar two space dollar one that means it'll come surname space first name.
That will not be any comma.
But if you want to put a comma, you can write it like this.
Anyway, we do not want that.
Let's run the code.
As you see that we have the surname and first name without comma.
Of course.
Remember that the Zero Group is the entire pattern.
Then we keep on adding parentheses.
It creates new groups in the above code.
The entire pattern is the zeroth group, which is by default first W plus reference dollars one second
slash W plus is the second group referred as dollar two and so on.
At the moment we see that each group is given a number automatically.
We do also have a provision where we can name these groups.
So that is a concept called named groups.
Okay, So dollar number is sometimes difficult to remember.
You can also give a name to each group.
To give a name you can use question mark, angle brackets, and in the brackets you have to give the
group name.
Remember, these angle brackets are not to show the syntax they are required while you give the group
name.
You have to give the group name after opening parentheses.
For example, I want to give a F name and s name group name respectively to first name and the surname.
I'll use a question mark and giving F name here.
Same is the case with s name.
Let's also do the same with replace matter.
Instead of saying dollar two, I will say s name and of course F name.
As you can see, using dollar SE name and dollar F name.
Now we can access the group values, which is easier when working with more groups.
As the group names can be given, all groups can be referred by names using groups, property, the
match and match all method return groups with groups property.
Let's check it with some modification in the existing code.
We will remove replace method and take a separate variable to retrieve groups using match method.
I'll use the variable called group value is equal to string.
Don't match the pattern dot groups which is a property returned by match method.
Let's display the group value and also I'll say group value dot F name.
As you can see that the group value is an object littoral with key of named group and value of the search
string.
You can certainly refer individual keys using object little dot key name that is group value F name
here which returns the first name.
In case if you want to exclude any of the group from being captured, then you can use a question mark
and colon.
In such a case, the search will execute.
But the group, starting with question Mark Colon, will not be captured.
Let's learn this using the replace code.
We tried.
I'm just going to add a question mark and Cologne before the second slash plus.
That means I do not want to capture the second group.
So there will be only one group which will be captured.
And the second group is included in this search but not captured.
So Dolor two will not have any value.
As you see, that is only one group captured and that is why dollars two becomes a string as there is
no second group created.
So question mark and colon is generally useful when you want to search a string, but do not want to
capture it as a group.
So this is all about capturing name and non capturing groups.
As we go on with the practical examples, you will have a better idea where exactly this is used.
But one practical example we have seen is about shifting or swapping the values.
So that is a very common practice we need in practical programming world.