In the previous section, we understood the concept of group capturing.
We also learned about how do we access a captured group and refer to it with dollar and the number or
with question mark and the group name that is the named group.
Now, in this section we will see one more excellent feature called Back Reference of a captured group.
Let's create a core sample and work on the concept.
We will search for number divided by a dash, also creating a group as we want to try back references
later on.
Otherwise, group is not needed.
In this example, I'll declare a variable.
I'll say let str is equal to code is one, 235678.
And here I say four or five six.
Dash four, five, six.
Let's first of all create a simple pattern where I have a group four digit before a dash and after the
dash.
And I'll try to console.log with the match method.
Let's run the code.
So it searched for two numbers and returned the output.
The groups are created.
And if we want to refer to a group on the next line, in any method, we use dollar and group number.
But what if we want to use the group in the pattern itself?
Let's say we want to find only those numbers where the digits before dash and after dash are same.
For example, in the above code it should return only 456-456.
That is, both the values before and after dash should be same.
It means whatever is found with the first group should be there after the dash.
It means the value of group one needs to be back referenced in the pattern itself.
In such a case you can use backslash and the group number.
So here we want to refer to the value of the first group.
So we will write slash one.
Let's change the pattern instead of second slash D Plus we will refer to the value of the first group
in the pattern itself.
So the pattern will be slash D plus dash backslash one where one is a back reference of value captured
in group one.
Now let's run the code.
Now it finds only one number.
As a result, in spite of two numbers existing in the string, because that is only one number which
is having the same value before and after Daesh and this kind of search we can achieve using regular
expression.
If we have a back reference facility, remember using group with a number that is dollar curly brackets
and the number is different as it cannot be used in the pattern itself, whereas the back reference
allows you to refer the value found by the first group or the captured group in the pattern itself.
You can also use the back reference feature with the named group as well.
Let's check that too with a practical example.
Assume that we give a name, zip code to the first group, then to refer the group name, we will use
backslash K in the angled brackets.
We are going to provide name of the group.
So in our case it will be zip code.
Let's change the pattern and run the code here in the pattern.
What will I do?
I'll use a question mark if you remember to name a group.
So the group will be captured with zip code.
That is the name of the group.
Dash Now, instead of writing backslash one, I will say backslash K, and then I'm going to mention
the name of the group here.
That's it.
Let's run the code.
Still, the output is the same, whereas we have used group name instead of the group number.
So this is how back reference facility can be useful when we capture the group and we try to use the
search value by the captured group in the pattern itself.