The second problem we are going to see is we are going to validate that a string should begin with a
digit.
Here we will use the anchor for beginning.
That is a carrot sign and we'll check for the digit.
Now, there are two ways to check for a digit.
Either we use the range that is 0 to 9 in square brackets, or we can use the slash DX character class.
Let's try both the ways, but we'll begin with giving a range from 0 to 9 in square brackets.
First of all, I'll declare a variable.
I'll say 88 New Street.
I'm going to define the pattern where I'll say a carrot that is for the beginning.
I want to give a range that is 0 to 9.
So I'll put in square bracket and let's try to apply the test method on the pattern.
As you can see, it displays true.
Let's remove this 88 and run the code again.
Now you can see that it displays false.
The second way is we use the slash D character class.
So in the same code again I will add 88 and in the pattern, instead of giving this range, I'll say
slash D.
Let's run the code again.
And now you see that the output is true.
That means the first character of this string is a digit.
We can also remove 88 from this and run it again to check whether it is working fine for the false situation
or not.
As you can see, it returns false.