In this coding exercise, we'll try to resolve a problem where you are supposed to find two words present
in a string.
That means you are going to find all double words in a string.
For example, in a string like this is two times a string and two times test.
That is test, test.
It should find a a and test test.
In this example, we will have to use a capturing group and back reference facility of regular expression.
Because we will find a word in a string first and we'll check.
Is it the same word found for next value or not?
So we will capture the group using parentheses, and inside those parentheses we are going to put slash
W plus there will be a space in between.
And then the other word.
So we'll use slash.
As for space in between and again, the same word found using slash one for back reference.
So the pattern will be parentheses, slash W plus slash s and slash one.
This will also not work for the absolute desired result.
So there will be a word boundary needed and we can use slash B for word boundary, but we will add it
later on after watching the output.
So let's begin the coding.
I will declare a variable where I say this is a string test test.
Let's create the pattern.
So the first thing I do is I create parentheses slash w plus for the word putting slash s for whitespace.
And because I want to search for the same value which was found by slash W plus.
So I'm going to use the back reference here.
So I'll say slash one.
Let's try to display using the match method.
As you can see in the output, it has searched for all double words in the string, but the output also
contains double is and the reason is very obvious.
That is such combination of found word appearing immediately.
That is this is where is word is repeating immediately after the is word of this.
We do not want such cases.
What we really want is if there is a whole word, then only it should consider as a result.
So we will use slash B to define word boundaries.
Let's add slash B at the beginning and end of the pattern and run the code again.
Now we get the desired output.
So word boundary is very essential to get complete words.
Also back referencing is a tricky part, so make sure you have gone through my explanation on back reference
of captured groups.
But here we are now able to get all the double words in the given string.