In this exercise, I'm explaining a way to check the valid date format.
Using regular expression, we can not only check the format, but can also validate for year, month
and day values.
But we will achieve it in the next exercise.
In this course sample we will simply try to check mdd.
Y.
Format where m is month and d d is day, which can be one or two digit long and the year which has to
be four digits and each value is separated by a forward slash.
If we talk about the pattern, I will use a carat and slash D with curly brackets, and in the brackets
I will use one or two.
That is the first value can be number having one or two digits.
The curly brackets are the qualifiers which we have already seen in one of our quantifier tutorial.
Next, I want a forward slash and because it is a special character, I will use escape sequence that
is a backslash.
And then I will write the forward slash for next two digit value format.
Again, I will use slash dx, curly brackets, one comma two.
That is one or two digits again for the separator.
I will be using backslash and forward slash.
Now comes the year.
I want to set a year for four digits, so I will use slash DX four, but only using the four in curly
brackets will not force for fixed four digits at the end.
So I will add one more anchor.
That is a dollar sign.
So this is how the entire pattern will look like.
Let's practically try this.
I will use a date value here.
I'll say let string is equal to d, d is zero to month is zero three.
And here I'm going to write 2020.
Now, the pattern here, which we have already discussed, I'm going to put it here.
That is a correct sign slash dx one comma, two forward slash again slash D, one comma, two forward
slash again slash D, four digits.
Now here I say four digits we want.
And at the end we do not want more than four digits.
So I'm adding a dollar sign at the end.
Now here I'm using a test method which checks whether the pattern matches with the value or not.
Let's run the code.
As you can see, the output is true.
That means we have the valid date format.
Let's try to change the value here instead of slash.
I will use dash sign and let's run the code again.
Now you see that the output is false because the pattern is not matching with the value in case, let's
say instead of a forward slash, you want to have a pattern where one can put a dash or slash.
The format will be d, d slash and slash year part or a mm dash de dash.
And then here, if you want to achieve this, then instead of this forward slash what we can do, we
can use the set where I can decide that there can be a forward slash or there can be a dash.
These two characters are valid.
So now what will happen if you give Dash as a separator or forward slash as a separator?
Then also the output will be true.
So in this example, we just try to check the valid date format.
Of course, if the user enters 14 in the month section, then it will not be validated because in that
case we are expecting the pattern to validate the value and not only the format.
So to check the value and format both, we are going to use various other patterns which we will see
in the next coding exercise.