In the previous exercise, we tried to validate the date format.
Now, in this exercise, we are validating the value entered as a date along with its format.
Let's take the format for Wise three M's and D D where Y represents year and can start with 19 or 20
because we are validating the value as well.
We are considering character month in this example and d d is the date validation.
So we are going to check the value of date as well.
Let's take the year part first.
Here we want to fix that.
The year's first two digits can only be 19 or 20.
Then the rest of the value can be two more digits.
So for that I will use a correct sign, put a parentheses, and will use a pipe sign between 90 and
20.
So we decide that the first value will be either 19 or 20.
Then we have two digits.
So I'm going to use slash D two times.
Then the next value can be a dash or a space.
For space we can use slash s.
So for this pattern we are going to add one more parentheses in square bracket.
I will say dash or slash as that means after the year section there might be a dash or a white space.
After the separator we need to have a character month which can be Jen February, March that is Ma,
may y and so on.
In short, it will be any three character valid month.
Here we will use parentheses and we will put a list of 12 months separated by a pipe sign.
In case, if you want to put these values in a variable, you can use the regex class itself and you
can instantiate.
But anyway, we are going to write it in the pattern.
At the same time we will add modifier AI to ignore the case that we will see practically in one of the
example.
Now we need the separator again.
That is a dash or maybe a whitespace after the month section.
So we will use the very same pattern that is inside the square.
Brackets will say dash or slash TSS.
Remember this very same pattern we have used to segregate the year section and month section.
So if you want you can use the back reference that is this pattern itself has back reference number
two, because this is going to be the captured group because we have placed the parentheses here so
we can use slash tool instead of writing dash and slash as again.
But anyway we'll go with dash and slash as only and then we want to put this pattern.
Of course there will be a one or two digit value so we can use slash DX, but that will not allow us
to validate the value given as a date.
It will just allow us to check the format.
But in this example, we are trying to check the value as well.
So in that case we will use few value validations with alteration.
That is a pipe sign out of two digits of date.
The first digit can have zero and then any number between one and nine.
This is the first possibility.
Or it can begin with one or two that is one to inside the square bracket and then the next digit can
be between zero and nine.
Or it may start with three and next digit can be zero or one.
Hmm.
So now the pattern looks quite something.
Let's check it practically.
I will use a variable where I'm going to add a valid date.
Now, this is the pattern.
And I'm using a test method to check whether it has successfully validated the value and format or not.
Let me run this code.
So now you see the output.
It says true as there are valid values entered now instead of lowercase.
Jan, let's try to make Jan an uppercase and run the code instead of making it in uppercase.
You can simply make the j that is the first letter in uppercase.
Then also it will run as the false test.
Let's execute this and see the output.
So now the pattern is not working as the month is a different case than expected in the pattern.
To resolve this, we will add modifier AI which will ignore the case.
Let's add AI and run the code.
Now you see that because we have a case ignoring modifier.
Now month name can be in any case.
Now let's try to fail the output by adding invalid date.
That is, I'm adding 45 in the day section and run the code.
As you can see, it returns false when the day is invalid.
So this is how you can check values of date along with the format.
Of course, there are many other validations you need to check, like a leap year validation.
Maybe for February you need to check that a number of days are correct or not, so there can be many
date validations you will want to add in the very same example.
But this core sample can be extended for more complex validations once you know the basics of this implementation.